<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Annual Review of Economics1</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Behavioral Economics and Psychology of Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamenica, Emir
Monetary incentives can backfire while nonstandard interventions, such as framing, can be effective in influencing behavior. I review the empirical evidence on these two sets of anomalies. Paying for inherently interesting tasks, paying for prosocial behavior, paying too much, paying too little, and providing too many options can all be counterproductive. At the same time, proper design of the decision-making environment can be a potent way to induce certain behaviors. After presenting the empirical evidence, I discuss the relative role of beliefs, preferences, and technology in the anomalous impacts of incentives. I argue that inference, signaling, loss aversion, dynamic inconsistency, and choking are the primary factors that explain the data.</description><author>Kamenica, Emir</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Promises and Pitfalls of Genoeconomics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benjamin, Daniel J.; Cesarini, David; Chabris, Christopher F.; Glaeser, Edward L.; Laibson, David I.; Gudnason, Vilmundur; Harris, Tamara B.; Launer, Lenore J.; Purcell, Shaun; Smith, Albert Vernon; Johannesson, Magnus; Magnusson, Patrik K. E.; Beauchamp, Jonathan P.; Christakis, Nicholas A.; Atwood, Craig S.; Hebert, Benjamin; Freese, Jeremy; Hauser, Robert M.; Hauser, Taissa S.; Grankvist, Alexander; Hultman, Christina M.; Lichtenstein, Paul
This article reviews existing research at the intersection of genetics and economics, presents some new findings that illustrate the state of genoeconomics research, and surveys the prospects of this emerging field. Twin studies suggest that economic outcomes and preferences, once corrected for measurement error, appear to be about as heritable as many medical conditions and personality traits. Consistent with this pattern, we present new evidence on the heritability of permanent income and wealth. Turning to genetic association studies, we survey the main ways that the direct measurement of genetic variation across individuals is likely to contribute to economics, and we outline the challenges that have slowed progress in making these contributions. The most urgent problem facing researchers in this field is that most existing efforts to find associations between genetic variation and economic behavior are based on samples that are too small to ensure adequate statistical power. This has led to many false positives in the literature. We suggest a number of possible strategies to improve and remedy this problem: (a) pooling data sets, (b) using statistical techniques that exploit the greater information content of many genes considered jointly, and (c) focusing on economically relevant traits that are most proximate to known biological mechanisms.</description><author>Benjamin, Daniel J.; Cesarini, David; Chabris, Christopher F.; Glaeser, Edward L.; Laibson, David I.; Gudnason, Vilmundur; Harris, Tamara B.; Launer, Lenore J.; Purcell, Shaun; Smith, Albert Vernon; Johannesson, Magnus; Magnusson, Patrik K. E.; Beauchamp, Jonathan P.; Christakis, Nicholas A.; Atwood, Craig S.; Hebert, Benjamin; Freese, Jeremy; Hauser, Robert M.; Hauser, Taissa S.; Grankvist, Alexander; Hultman, Christina M.; Lichtenstein, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probability and Risk: Foundations and Economic Implications of Probability-Dependent Risk Preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fehr-Duda, Helga; Epper, Thomas
A large body of evidence has documented that risk preferences depend nonlinearly on outcome probabilities. We discuss the foundations and economic consequences of probability-dependent risk preferences and offer a practitioner's guide to understanding and modeling probability dependence. We argue that probability dependence provides a unifying framework for explaining many real-world phenomena, such as the equity premium puzzle, the long-shot bias in betting markets, and households' underdiversification and their willingness to buy small-scale insurance at exorbitant prices. Recent findings indicate that probability dependence is not just a feature of laboratory data, but is indeed manifest in financial, insurance, and betting markets. The neglect of probability dependence may prevent researchers from understanding and predicting important phenomena.</description><author>Fehr-Duda, Helga; Epper, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Reduced-Form Approach to Behavioral Public Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mullainathan, Sendhil; Schwartzstein, Joshua; Congdon, William J.
Research in behavioral public finance has blossomed in recent years, producing diverse empirical and theoretical insights. This article develops a single framework with which to understand these advances. Rather than drawing out the consequences of specific psychological assumptions, the framework takes a reduced-form approach to behavioral modeling. It emphasizes the difference between decision and experienced utility that underlies most behavioral models. We use this framework to examine the behavioral implications for canonical public finance problems involving the provision of social insurance, commodity taxation, and correcting externalities. We show how deeper principles undergird much work in this area and that many insights are not specific to a single psychological assumption.</description><author>Mullainathan, Sendhil; Schwartzstein, Joshua; Congdon, William J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corruption in Developing Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Olken, Benjamin A.; Pande, Rohini
Recent years have seen a remarkable expansion in economists' ability to measure corruption. This in turn has led to a new generation of well-identified, microeconomic studies. We review the evidence on corruption in developing countries in light of these recent advances, focusing on three questions: how much corruption is there, what are the efficiency consequences of corruption, and what determines the level of corruption? We find robust evidence that corruption responds to standard economic incentive theory but also that the effects of anticorruption policies often attenuate as officials find alternate strategies to pursue rents.</description><author>Olken, Benjamin A.; Pande, Rohini</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Developments in Aggregation Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiappori, Pierre Andre; Ekeland, Ivar
The goal of this article is to provide a general characterization of the aggregate behavior of a group in a market environment. We allow for public and private consumption, intragroup production, and consumption externalities within a group; we only assume that the group always reaches Pareto-efficient decisions. We show that aggregation problems involve a simple mathematical structure: The aggregate demand of the group, considered as a vector field, can be decomposed into a sum of gradients. We briefly introduce exterior differential calculus as a tool to study this structure. We analyze two main issues. One is testability: What restrictions (if any) on the aggregate demand function characterize the efficient behavior of the group? The second issue relates to identifiability; we investigate the conditions under which it is possible to recover the underlying structure-namely, individual preferences, the decision process, and the resulting intragroup transfers-from the group's aggregate behavior.</description><author>Chiappori, Pierre Andre; Ekeland, Ivar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender and Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niederle, Muriel; Vesterlund, Lise
Laboratory studies have documented that women often respond less favorably to competition than men. Conditional on performance, men are often more eager to compete, and the performance of men tends to respond more positively to an increase in competition. This means that few women enter and win competitions. We review studies that examine the robustness of these differences as well the factors that may give rise to them. Both laboratory and field studies largely confirm these initial findings, showing that gender differences in competitiveness tend to result from differences in overconfidence and in attitudes toward competition. Gender differences in risk aversion, however, seem to play a smaller and less robust role. We conclude by asking what could and should be done to encourage qualified males and females to compete.</description><author>Niederle, Muriel; Vesterlund, Lise</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Studying Discrimination: Fundamental Challenges and Recent Progress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charles, Kerwin Kofi; Guryan, Jonathan
We discuss research on discrimination against blacks and other racial minorities in labor market outcomes, highlighting fundamental challenges faced by empirical work in this area. Specifically, for work devoted to measuring whether and how much discrimination exists, we discuss how the absence of relevant data, the potential noncomparability of blacks and whites, and various conceptual concerns peculiar to race may frustrate or render impossible the application of empirical methods used in other areas of study. For work seeking to arbitrate empirically between the two main alternative theoretical explanations for such discrimination as it exists, we distinguish between indirect analyses, which do not directly study the variation in prejudice or the variation in information, the mechanisms at the heart of the two types of models we review, and direct analyses, which are more recent and much less common. We highlight problems with both approaches. Throughout, we discuss recent work, which, the various challenges notwithstanding, permits tentative conclusions about discrimination. We conclude by pointing to areas that might be fruitful avenues for future investigation.</description><author>Charles, Kerwin Kofi; Guryan, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bargaining with Optimism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yildiz, Muhamet
Excessive optimism is a prominent explanation for bargaining delays. Recent results demonstrate that optimism plays a subtle role in bargaining, and its careful analysis may shed valuable insights into negotiation behavior. This article reviews son-le of these results, focusing on the following findings. First, when there is a nearby deadline, optimistic players delay the agreement to the last period before the deadline, replicating a broad empirical regularity known as the deadline effect. Second, there cannot be a substantial delay under persistent optimism; i.e., excessive optimism alone cannot explain delays. Third, when optimistic players are expected to learn during the negotiation, they delay the agreement in order to persuade their opponents. The delays in these results can be quite costly, Pareto inefficient, and common knowledge at the beginning of the game.</description><author>Yildiz, Muhamet</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Health Behavior in Developing Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dupas, Pascaline
The disease burden in low-income countries is extremely high. Malaria, respiratory infections, diarrhea, AIDS, and other diseases are estimated to kill more than 15 million people each year, most of them children. Yet the great majority of these diseases can be prevented or treated. This article reviews microeconomic studies of health-seeking behavior in low-income countries. Factors examined include information, peers, liquidity constraints, and nonrational preferences, such as present bias. I then discuss the implications for policy, including the scope for mandates, subsidies, and incentives.</description><author>Dupas, Pascaline</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Practical Methods for Estimation of Dynamic Discrete Choice Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arcidiacono, Peter; Ellickson, Paul B.
Many discrete decisions are made with an eye toward how they will affect future outcomes. Formulating and estimating the underlying models that generate these decisions is difficult. Conditional choice probability (CCP) estimators often provide simpler ways to estimate dynamic discrete choice problems. Recent work shows how to frame dynamic discrete choice problems in a way that is conducive to CCP estimation and demonstrates that CCP estimators call be adapted to handle rich patterns of unobserved state variables.</description><author>Arcidiacono, Peter; Ellickson, Paul B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sparse High-Dimensional Models in Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, Jianqing; Lv, Jinchi; Qi, Lei
This article reviews the literature on sparse high-dimensional models and discusses some applications in economics and finance. Recent developments in theory, methods, and implementations in penalized least-squares and penalized likelihood methods are highlighted. These variable selection methods are effective in sparse high-dimensional modeling. The limits of dimensionality that regularization methods can handle, the role of penalty functions, and their statistical properties are detailed. Some recent advances in sparse ultra-high-dimensional modeling are also briefly discussed.</description><author>Fan, Jianqing; Lv, Jinchi; Qi, Lei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Trade, Foreign Direct Investment, and Security</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dixit, Avinash
The main focus of this review is on international trade and foreign direct investment when the institutions that provide the security of property rights and enforcement of contracts are imperfect. Some issues of national security related to poor governance of international transactions are also considered. The discussion organizes a selective overview of the literature and offers some suggestions for future research.</description><author>Dixit, Avinash</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Gravity Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, James E.
Gravity has long been one of the most successful empirical models in economics. Incorporating deeper theoretical foundations of gravity into recent practice has led to a richer and more accurate estimation and interpretation of the spatial relations described by gravity. Wider acceptance has followed. Recent developments are reviewed here, and suggestions are made for promising future research.</description><author>Anderson, James E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Confronting Prior Convictions: On Issues of Prior Sensitivity and Likelihood Robustness in Bayesian Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lopes, Hedibert F.; Tobias, Justin L.
In this review we explore issues of the sensitivity of Bayes estimates to the prior and form of the likelihood. With respect to the prior, we argue that non-Bayesian analyses also incorporate prior information, illustrate that the Bayes posterior mean and the frequentist maximum likelihood estimator are often asymptotically equivalent, review a simple computational strategy for analyzing sensitivity to the prior in practice, and finally document the potentially important role of the prior in Bayesian model comparison. With respect to issues of likelihood robustness, we review a variety of computational strategies for significantly expanding the maintained sampling model, including the use of finite Gaussian mixture models and models based on Dirichlet process priors.</description><author>Lopes, Hedibert F.; Tobias, Justin L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Theories of Heterogeneous Firms and Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Redding, Stephen J.
This article reviews the recent theoretical literature on heterogeneous firms and trade, which emphasizes firm selection into international markets and reallocations of resources across firms. We discuss the empirical challenges that motivated this research and its relationship to traditional trade theories. We examine the implications of firm heterogeneity for comparative advantage, market size, aggregate trade, the welfare gains from trade, and the relationship between trade and income distribution. Although a number of studies examine the endogenous response of firm productivity to trade liberalization, modeling internal firm organization and the origins of firm heterogeneity remain interesting areas of ongoing research.</description><author>Redding, Stephen J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Models of Consumer Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nevo, Aviv
Models of consumer behavior play a key role in modern empirical industrial organization. In this review, I survey some of the models used in this literature. In particular, I discuss two commonly used demand systems: multistage budgeting approaches and discrete choice models. I motivate their use and highlight some key modeling assumptions. I next briefly discuss key issues of estimation and conclude by summarizing some extensions.</description><author>Nevo, Aviv</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rent Seeking and Corruption in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khwaja, Asim Ijaz; Mian, Atif
We describe recent advances in the study of rent seeking and corruption in financial markets. We outline three areas of inquiry: (a) conceptualizing rent seeking, (b) identifying rent-provision channels and their general equilibrium impact, and (c) designing feasible remedial mechanisms. We provide suggestions for making further progress in these areas and review a variety of approaches taken in the recent literature.</description><author>Khwaja, Asim Ijaz; Mian, Atif</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing Bubbles: A Survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mayer, Christopher
The past 25 years have represented two periods of extreme movements in U.S. and global house prices that appear to be much larger than can be easily explained by changes in fundamentals. These episodes spurred research on housing bubbles that focused attention on the role of outsized expectations in excessive house price appreciation. By contrast, some economists pointed to alternative explanations for excess volatility, including liquidity constraints, lending cycles, search externalities, and zoning delays. Empirical work supports the role of these factors in explaining at least: some of the cyclical variation of house prices and inventories of homes for sale. Existing research does not yet provide a crisp definition of a housing bubble nor does it allow researchers to predict where or when bubbles can occur.</description><author>Mayer, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News and Aggregate Demand Shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lorenzoni, Guido
In this review, I look at the recent literature on news as a source of economic fluctuations. The main question in this literature is: how does the aggregate economy respond to a shock that raises consumers' and firms' expectations about future productivity growth? I discuss how different papers have addressed this question, emphasizing the mechanisms at work under different specifications of preferences and technology, under different assumptions about nominal and real rigidities, and under different assumptions about the agents' information structure. I also briefly discuss some challenges faced by the empirical literature on the topic.</description><author>Lorenzoni, Guido</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Mechanism Design Approach to Student Assignment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pathak, Parag A.
The mechanism design approach to student assignment involves the theoretical, empirical, and experimental study of systems used to allocate students into schools around the world. Recent practical experience designing systems for student assignment has raised new theoretical questions for the theory of matching and assignment. This article reviews some of this recent literature, highlighting how issues from the field motivated theoretical developments and emphasizing how the dialogue may be a road map for other areas of applied mechanism design. Finally, it concludes with some open questions.</description><author>Pathak, Parag A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear Panel Data Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arellano, Manuel; Bonhomme, Stephane
Nonlinear panel data models arise naturally in economic applications, yet their analysis is challenging. Here we provide a progress report on some recent advances in the area. We start by reviewing the properties of random-effects likelihood approaches. We emphasize a link with Bayesian computation and Markov chain Monte Carlo, which provides a convenient approach to estimation and inference. The relaxation of parametric assumptions on the distribution of individual effects raises serious identification problems. In discrete choice models, common parameters and average marginal effects are generally set identified. The availability of continuous outcomes, however, provides opportunities for point identification. We end by reviewing recent progress on non-fixed-T approaches. In panel applications in which the time dimension is not negligible relative to the size of the cross section, it makes sense to view the estimation problem as a time-series finite-sample bias. Several perspectives to bias reduction are now available. We review their properties, with a special emphasis on random-effects methods.</description><author>Arellano, Manuel; Bonhomme, Stephane</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Imperfect Credit Markets, Household Wealth Distribution, and Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Matsuyama, Kiminori
This article discusses some key results in the theoretical literature on credit market imperfections, household wealth distribution, and development by conducting three types of analysis, which progressively build on one another. The first, a single dynasty model, explains how a household may be caught in a poverty trap because of credit market imperfections but says little about the effects of distribution on development. The second, a model of interacting dynasties with a fixed threshold, explains a collective poverty trap, with path dependence in the wealth distribution dynamics, but says little about the effects of inequality on development, owing to its absolute notion of the rich and the poor. The third, models of interacting dynasties with variable thresholds, offers a richer framework for understanding the dynamics of inequality and development under credit market imperfections, owing to its relative notion of the rich and poor.</description><author>Matsuyama, Kiminori</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Frictional Matching Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smith, Lones
This article reviews the developments in frictional matching models from 1990 to 2010, exploring how search frictions skew the matches that occur. This research succeeded by exploiting new tools from monotone methods under uncertainty. Seeing how this journey plays out is instructive in itself for economic theory. The article also describes in detail the different attacks on the existence of equilibrium required for these search and matching models.</description><author>Smith, Lones</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Perspectives on Trade and Inequality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harrison, Ann; McLaren, John; McMillan, Margaret
The 1990s dealt a blow to traditional Heckscher-Ohlin analysis of the relationship between trade and income inequality, as it became clear that rising inequality in low-income countries and other features of the data were inconsistent with that model. As a result, economists moved away from trade as a plausible explanation for rising income inequality. In recent years, however, a number of new mechanisms have been explored through which trade can affect (and usually increase) income inequality. These include within-industry effects due to heterogeneous firms, the effects of offshoring of tasks, effects on incomplete contracting, and the effects of labor-market frictions. A number of these mechanisms have received substantial empirical support.</description><author>Harrison, Ann; McLaren, John; McMillan, Margaret</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Norms and Social Assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Postlewaite, Andrew
Social norms are often posited as an explanation of differences in the economic behavior and performance of societies that are difficult to explain by differences in endowments and technology. The successful integration of social norms into economic models requires an understanding of the basis of the differences in preferences that lead to different behaviors. I explore the difference between deep and reduced-form preferences and how both can differ across societies.</description><author>Postlewaite, Andrew</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Informed Voters Enforce Better Governance? Experiments in Low-Income Democracies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pande, Rohini
This article evaluates a body of recent work that uses field and natural experiments to answer the question of whether informed voters can enforce better governance. A common finding in the literature is that voter behavior is malleable and that information about the political process and politician performance improves electoral accountability. Limited availability of information thus provides one explanation for the persistence of low-quality politicians and the existence of identity politics and electoral malpractices in low-income democracies. Understanding how voters can gain access to credible sources of information and understanding how politicians react to improved information about their performance are promising avenues for future research.</description><author>Pande, Rohini</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Political Economy of Public Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battaglini, Marco
We survey recent theories of public debt that incorporate political decision making in rich dynamic environments. These theories provide a new framework with which to interpret empirical evidence and to assess institutional reforms that may help control political inefficiencies. We discuss the inefficiencies that lead to overaccumulation of debt and their implications for the long-run distribution of debt.</description><author>Battaglini, Marco</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choosing Treatment Policies Under Ambiguity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manski, Charles F.
Economists studying choice with partial knowledge typically assume that the decision maker places a subjective distribution on unknown quantities and maximizes expected utility. Someone lacking a subjective distribution faces a problem of choice under ambiguity. This article reviews recent research on policy choice under ambiguity, when the task is to choose treatments for a population. Ambiguity arises when a planner has partial knowledge of treatment response and does not feel able to place a subjective distribution on the unknowns. I first discuss dominance and alternative criteria for choice among undominated policies. I then illustrate with the choice of a vaccination policy by a planner who has partial knowledge of the effect of vaccination on illness. I next study a class of problems in which a planner may want to cope with ambiguity by diversification, assigning observationally identical persons to different treatments. Lastly, I consider a setting in which a planner should not diversify treatment.</description><author>Manski, Charles F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robustness and Macroeconomic Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barlevy, Gadi
This review considers the design of macroeconomic policies in the face of uncertainty. In recent years, several economists have advocated that, when policy makers are uncertain about the environment they face and find it difficult to assign precise probabilities to the alternative scenarios that may characterize this environment, they should design policies to be robust in the sense that they minimize the worst-case loss these policies could ever impose. I review and evaluate the objections cited by critics of this approach. I argue further that, contrary to what some have inferred, concern about worst-case scenarios does not always lead to policies that respond more aggressively to incoming news than the optimal policy would respond absent any uncertainty.</description><author>Barlevy, Gadi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Questions in Decision Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilboa, Itzhak
This review surveys a few major questions in the field of decision theory. It is argued that a re-examination of some of the fundamental concepts in decision theory may have important implications to theoretical and even empirical research in economics and related fields.</description><author>Gilboa, Itzhak</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural Estimation and Policy Evaluation in Developing Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Todd, Petra E.; Wolpin, Kenneth I.
This review discusses the use of discrete choice dynamic programming (DCDP) methods for evaluating policies of particular relevance to developing countries, such as policies to reduce child labor and increase school attendance, improve school quality, affect immigration flows, expand old-age pension benefits, or foster small-business investment through microfinance. We describe the DCDP framework and how it relates to static models, illustrate its application with an example related to conditional cash transfer programs, consider numerous empirical applications from the literature of how the DCDP methodology has been used to address. substantively important policy issues, and discuss methods for model validation.</description><author>Todd, Petra E.; Wolpin, Kenneth I.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hypothesis Testing in Econometrics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Romano, Joseph P.; Shaikh, Azeem M.; Wolf, Michael
This article reviews important concepts and methods that are useful for hypothesis testing. First, we discuss the Neyman.-Pearson framework. Various approaches to optimality are presented, including finite-sample and large-sample optimality. Then, we summarize some of the most important methods, as well as resampling methodology, which is useful to set critical values. Finally, we consider the problem of multiple testing, which has witnessed a burgeoning literature in recent years. Along the way, we incorporate some examples that are current in the econometrics literature. While many problems with well-known successful solutions are included, we also address open problems that are not easily handled with current technology, stemming from such issues as lack of optimality or poor asymptotic approximations.</description><author>Romano, Joseph P.; Shaikh, Azeem M.; Wolf, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency Unions in Prospect and Retrospect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Silva, J. M. C. Santos; Tenreyro, Silvana
We critically review the recent literature on currency unions and discuss the methodological challenges posed by the empirical assessment of their costs and benefits. In the process, we provide evidence on the economic effects of the euro. In particular, and in Contrast with estimates of the trade effect of other currency unions, we find that the euro's impact on trade has been close to zero. After reviewing the costs and benefits of joining a currency union, we conclude with some open questions on normative and Positive. aspects of the theory of currency unions, emphasizing the need for a unified welfare-based framework to weigh their costs and gains.</description><author>Silva, J. M. C. Santos; Tenreyro, Silvana</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Advances in the Empirics of Organizational Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloom, Nicholas; Sadun, Raffaella; Van Reenen, John
We present a survey of recent contributions in empirical organizational economics, focusing on management practices and decentralization. Productivity dispersion between firms and countries has motivated the improved measurement of firm organization across industries and countries. There appears to be substantial variation in management practices and decentralization not only between countries, but also especially within countries. Much of the poorer average management quality in countries like Brazil and India seems to result from a long tail of poorly managed firms, which barely exist in the United States. Some stylized facts include the following: (a) Competition seems to foster improved management and decentralization; (b) larger firms, skill-intensive plants and foreign multinationals appear better managed and are more decentralized; (c) firms that are both family owned and managed appear to have worse management and are more centralized; and (d) firms facing an environment of lighter labor market regulations and more human capital specialize relatively more in people management. There is evidence for complementarities between information, but the relationship is complex, and identification of the productivity effects of organizational practices remains a challenge for future research.</description><author>Bloom, Nicholas; Sadun, Raffaella; Van Reenen, John</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Persuasion: Empirical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DellaVigna, Stefano; Gentzkow, Matthew
We provide a selective survey of empirical evidence on the effects as well as the drivers of persuasive communication. We consider persuasion directed at consumers, voters, donors, and investors. We organize our review around four questions. First, to what extent does persuasion affect the behavior of each of these groups? Second, what models best capture the response to persuasive communication? Third, what are persuaders' incentives, and what limits their. ability to distort communications? Finally, what evidence exists on the way persuasion affects equilibrium outcomes in economics and politics?</description><author>DellaVigna, Stefano; Gentzkow, Matthew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commitment Devices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bryan, Gharad; Karlan, Dean; Nelson, Scott
We review the recent evidence on commitment devices and discuss how this evidence relates to theoretical questions about the demand for, and effectiveness of, commitment. Several important distinctions emerge. First, we distinguish between what we call hard and soft commitments and identify how soft commitments, in particular, can help with various dilemmas, both in explaining empirical behavior and in designing effective commitment devices. Second, we highlight the importance of certain modeling assumptions in predicting when commitment devices will be demanded and examine the laboratory and field evidence on the demand for commitment devices. Third, we present the evidence on both informal and formal commitment devices, and we conclude with a discussion of policy implications, including sin taxes, consumer protection, and commitment device design.</description><author>Bryan, Gharad; Karlan, Dean; Nelson, Scott</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and Productivity: A Review of Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holmes, Thomas J.; Schmitz, James A.
Does competition spur productivity? And if so, how does it accomplish this? These have long been regarded as central questions in economics. This article reviews the literature that makes progress toward answering both questions.</description><author>Holmes, Thomas J.; Schmitz, James A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regional Trade Agreements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Freund, Caroline; Ornelas, Emanuel
This article reviews the theoretical and the empirical literature on regionalism. The formation of regional trade agreements has been, by far, the most popular form of reciprocal trade liberalization in the past 15 years. The discriminatory character of these agreements has raised three main concerns: that trade diversion would be rampant, because special interest groups would induce governments to form the most distortionary agreements; that broader external trade liberalization would stall or reverse; and that multilateralism could be undermined. Theoretically, all these concerns are legitimate, although there are also several theoretical arguments that oppose them. Empirically, neither widespread trade diversion non stalled external liberalization has materialized, whereas the undermining of multilateralism has not been properly tested. There are also several aspects of regionalism that have received rod little attention from researchers, but which are central to understanding its causes and consequences.</description><author>Freund, Caroline; Ornelas, Emanuel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Changing Nature of Financial Intermediation and the Financial Crisis of 2007-2009</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adrian, Tobias; Shin, Hyun Song
The current financial crisis has highlighted the changing role of financial institutions and the growing importance of the shadow banking system, which grew on the back of the securitization of assets and the integration of banking with capital market developments. This trend has been most pronounced in the United States but has had a profound influence on the global financial system as a whole. In a market-based financial system, banking and capital market developments are inseparable, and funding conditions are closely tied to the fluctuations in leverage of market-based financial intermediaries. Balance-sheet growth of market-based financial intermediaries provides a window on liquidity in the sense of the availability of credit, whereas financial crises tend to be associated with contractions of balance sheets. We describe the changing nature of financial intermediation in the market-based financial system, chart the course of the recent financial-crisis, and outline the policy responses that have been implemented by the Federal Reserve and other central banks to counter it.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Shin, Hyun Song</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Partial Identification in Econometrics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tamer, Elie
Identification in econometric models maps prior assumptions and the data to information about a parameter of interest. The partial identification approach to inference recognizes that this process should not result in a binary answer that consists of whether the parameter is point identified. Rather, given the data, the partial identification approach characterizes the informational content of various assumptions by providing a menu of estimates, each based on different sets of assumptions, some of which are-plausible and some of which are not. Of course, more assumptions beget more information, so stronger conclusions can be made at the expense of more assumptions. The partial identification approach advocates a more fluid view of identification and hence provides the empirical researcher with methods to help study the spectrum, of information that we can harness about a parameter of interest using a menu of assumptions. This approach links conclusions drawn from various empirical models to sets of assumptions made in a transparent way. It allows researchers to examine the informational content of their assumptions and their impacts on the inferences Made. Naturally, with finite sample sizes, this approach leads to statistical complications, as one needs to deal with characterizing sampling uncertainty in models that do not point identify a parameter. Therefore, new methods for inference are developed. These methods construct confidence sets for partially identified parameters, and confidence regions for sets of parameters, or identifiable sets.</description><author>Tamer, Elie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intergenerational Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asheim, Geir B.
Axiomatic analysis of intergenerational social preferences over infinite streams of well-being faces the following dilemma. Equal treatment of generations combined with sensitivity for the interests of each generation rules our explicitly defined preferences that can rank any pair of infinite well-being streams. Hence, either intergenerational social preferences must be incomplete or equal treatment and sensitivity must be compromised. This critical review of axiomatic analyses of preferences over infinite streams evaluates different kinds of intergenerational social preferences by comparing their axiomatic basis as well as their performance in simple present-futuer conflicts. The scope for application is discussed, using real-world intergenerational conflicts (such as global warming) as a backdrop.</description><author>Asheim, Geir B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The World Trade Organization: Theory and Practice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bagwell, Kyle; Staiger, Robert W.
We consider the purpose and design of the World Trade Organization (WTO) and its predecessor, the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT), and review recent developments in the relevant theoretical and empirical literature. We describe the GATT/WTO architecture and briefly trace its historical antecedents. We suggest that the existing literature provides a useful framework for understanding and interpreting central features of the design and practice of the GATT/WTO, and we identify key unresolved issues.</description><author>Bagwell, Kyle; Staiger, Robert W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How (Not) to Do Decision Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dekel, Eddie; Lipman, Barton L.
We discuss the goals and means of positive decision theory and the implications for how to do decision theory. We argue that the goal of positive economic theory generally is to provide predictions and understanding and that representation theorems and other results of decision theory should be seen as ways to achieve these goals. We also argue that the interpretation of a model is relevant to whether and how we use the model, that psychological considerations are not necessary for useful decision theory but can be helpful, and that nonchoice data, interpreted properly, can be valuable in predicting choice and therefore should not be ignored.</description><author>Dekel, Eddie; Lipman, Barton L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Health, Human Capital, and Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bleakley, Hoyt
How much does disease depress development in human capital and income around the world? I discuss a range of micro evidence, which finds that health is both human capital itself and an input to producing other forms of human capital. I use a standard model to integrate these results and suggest a reinterpretation I of much of the micro literature. I then discuss the aggregate implications of micro estimates but note the complications in extrapolating to general equilibrium, especially because of health's effect on population size. I also review the macro evidence on this topic, which consists of either cross-country comparisons or measuring responses to health shocks. Micro estimates are one to two orders of magnitude smaller than the cross-country relationship but nevertheless imply high benefit-to-cost ratios from improving certain forms of health.</description><author>Bleakley, Hoyt</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Testing: Empirical Models of Insurance Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Einav, Liran; Finkelstein, Amy; Levin, Jonathan
We describe recent advances in the empirical analysis of insurance markets. This new research proposes ways to estimate individual demand for insurance and the relationship between prices and insurer costs in the presence of adverse and advantageous selection. We discuss how these models permit the measurement of welfare distortions arising from asymmetric information and the welfare consequences of potential government policy responses. We also discuss some challenges in modeling imperfect competition between insurers and outline a series of open research questions.</description><author>Einav, Liran; Finkelstein, Amy; Levin, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inside Organizations: Pricing, Politics, and Path Dependence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gibbons, Robert
When economists have considered organizations, much attention has focused on the boundary of the firm, rather than its internal structures and processes. In contrast, this review, sketches three approaches to the economic theory of internal organization-one substantially developed, another rapidly emerging, and a third on the horizon. The first approach (pricing) applies Pigou's prescription: If markets get prices wrong, then the economist's job is to fix the prices. The second approach (politics) considers environments where important actions inside organizations simply cannot be priced, so power and control become central. Finally, the third approach (path dependence) complements the first two by shifting attention from the between variance. to the within. That is, rather than asking how organizations confronting different circumstances. should choose different structures and processes, the focus here is on how path dependence can cause persistent performance differences among seemingly similar enterprises.</description><author>Gibbons, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identification of Dynamic Discrete Choice Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abbring, Jaap H.
Econometric models of dynamic discrete choice processes are applied to a wide variety of economic problems. Recent research on their empirical content has brought important new insights. It has clarified the conditions for their identification from choice and covariate panel data in the absence of dynamic selection on unobservables. It has provided important new identification results for discrete-time models with unobserved heterogeneity and unobserved states. Finally, it has enhanced the attractiveness of continuous-time models, by developing new insights on the identification of continuous-time optimal stopping models. Current developments in the literature promise to shed further light on the specification and identification of models with unobserved state variables, theory-based non-proportional hazard models, continuous-time optimal stopping models with time-varying covariates, and dynamic games in discrete and continuous time.</description><author>Abbring, Jaap H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Microeconomics of Technology Adoption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foster, Andrew D.; Rosenzweig, Mark R.
Differences in technology levels across countries account for a large component of the differences in wages and per-capita GDP across countries worldwide. This article reviews micro studies of the. adoption of new technologies and the use of inputs complementary with new technologies to shed light on the barriers to technology diffusion in low-income countries. Among the factors examined affecting decisions pertaining to technology choice and input allocations are the financial and nonfinancial returns to adoption, one's own learning and social learning, technological externalities, scale economies, schooling, credit constraints, risk And incomplete insurance, and departures from behavioral rules implied by simple models of rationality.</description><author>Foster, Andrew D.; Rosenzweig, Mark R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneity, Selection, and Wealth Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blume, Lawrence; Easley, David
The market selection hypothesis states that, among expected utility maximizers, competitive markets select for agents with correct beliefs. In some economies this hypothesis holds, whereas in others it fails. It holds in complete-markets economies with a common discount factor and bounded aggregate consumption. It can fail when markets are incomplete, when consumption grows too quickly, or when discount factors and beliefs are correlated. These insights have implications for the general equilibrium modeling of asset prices and macroeconomic phenomena.</description><author>Blume, Lawrence; Easley, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Interactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durlauf, Steven N.; Ioannides, Yannis M.
The study of social interactions has enriched both the domain of inquiry of economists and the way economists conceptualize individual decision making. The review aims to introduce the classes of models that accommodate estimation of social interactions and to examine the key areas where significant advances have been made in the identification of social effects. It surveys linear and nonlinear models and their applications, including results regarding partial identification. The review also examines conceptual, and methodological links with the spatial econometrics and the social networks literatures. It considers empirical applications in the context of our methodological overview.</description><author>Durlauf, Steven N.; Ioannides, Yannis M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Consumption Response to Income Changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jappelli, Tullio; Pistaferri, Luigi
We review different empirical approaches that researchers have taken to estimate how consumption responds to income changes. We critically evaluate the empirical evidence on the sensitivity of consumption to predicted income changes, distinguishing between the traditional excess sensitivity tests and the effect of predicted income increases and income declines. We also review studies that attempt to estimate the marginal propensity to consume out of income shocks, distinguishing between three different approaches: identifying episodes in which income changes unexpectedly, relying on the covariance restrictions that the theory imposes on the joint behavior of consumption and income growth, and combining realizations and expectations of income or consumption in surveys in which data on subjective expectations are available.</description><author>Jappelli, Tullio; Pistaferri, Luigi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Structure and Economic Welfare: Applied General Equilibrium Development Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Townsend, Robert
This review provides a common framework for researchers thinking about the next generation of micro-founded macro models of growth, inequality, and financial deepening, as well as direction for policy makers targeting microfinance programs to, alleviate poverty. Topics include treatment of financial structure general equilibrium models: testing for as-if-complete markets or other financial underpinnings; examining dual-sector models with both a perfectly intermediated sector and a sector in financial autarky, as well as a second generation of these models that embeds information problems and other obstacles to trade; designing surveys to capture measures of income, investment/savings, and flow of funds; and aggregating individuals and households to the level of network, village, or national economy. The review concludes With new directions that overcome conceptual and computational limitations.</description><author>Townsend, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Models of Growth and Firm Heterogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luttmer, Erzo G. J.
Although employment at individual firms tends to be highly nonstationary, the employment size distribution of all firms in the United States appears to be stationary. It closely resembles a Pareto distribution. There is a lot of entry and exit, mostly of small firms. This review surveys general equilibrium models that can be used to interpret these facts and explores the role of innovation by new and incumbent firms in determining aggregate growth. The existence of a balanced growth path with a stationary employment size distribution depends crucially on assumptions made about the cost of entry. Some type of labor must be essential input in setting up new firms.</description><author>Luttmer, Erzo G. J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor Market Models of Worker and Firm Heterogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lentz, Rasmus; Mortensen, Dale T.
Microeconomic data on individual firms and employer-employee matches reveal substantial and persistent dispersion in firm size, productivity, and average wage paid and a positive correlation between each pair. To the extent that intrinsic differences in firm productivity explain these facts, there are several important consequences. First, the reallocation of employment from less to more Productive firms will yield efficiency gains. Second, workers will find it in their interest to seek out higher-paying employers. Recent research has provided support for both hypotheses. Third, the existence Of worker and employer heterogeneity offers possible gains from sorting. However, because the problem of identifying the presence of sorting is model dependent, it is too early for conclusions about its significance.</description><author>Lentz, Rasmus; Mortensen, Dale T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Networks and Economic Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jackson, Matthew O.
Recent analyses of social networks, both empirical and theoretical, are discussed, with a focus on how social networks influence economic behavior, as well as how social networks form. Some challenges of such research are discussed as are some of the important considerations for the future.</description><author>Jackson, Matthew O.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subjective Probabilities in Household Surveys</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hurd, Michael D.
Subjective probabilities are now collected on a number of large household surveys with the objective of providing data to better understand intertemporal decision making. Comparison of subjective probabilities with actual outcomes shows that the probabilities have considerable predictive power in situations where individuals have considerable private information, such as survival and retirement. In contrast, the subjective probability of a stock market gain varies greatly across individuals even though no one has private information and the outcome is the same for everyone. An explanation is that there is considerable variation in accessing and processing information. Further, the subjective probability of a stock market gain is considerably lower than historical averages, providing an explanation for the relatively low frequency of stock holding. An important research objective will be to understand how individuals form their subjective probabilities.</description><author>Hurd, Michael D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Preferences: Some Thoughts from the Field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>List, John A.
This review steps back from the burgeoning economics literature on measuring social preferences and considers more carefully the empirical evidence from the lab and the field. I place the claims from the ardent supporters of the literature into three bins: one for claims that are supported by the data upon closer scrutiny, one for claims that are not supported by the data upon closer scrutiny, and one for claims that may or may not be true. The third set of claims highlights important theoretical and empirical investigations that need to be done to further our understanding of the nature and import of social preferences. [W]hen self-interest and ethical values with wide verbal allegiance are in conflict, much of the time, most of the time in fact, self-interest theory...will win. Stigler (1981)</description><author>List, John A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving Education in the Developing World: What Have We Learned from Randomized Evaluations?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kremer, Michael; Holla, Alaka
Across a range of contexts, reductions in education costs and provision of subsidies can boost school participation, often dramatically. Decisions to attend school seem subject to peer effects and time-inconsistent preferences. Merit scholarships, school health programs, and information about returns to education can all cost-effectively spur school participation. However, distortions in education systems, such as weak teacher incentives and elite-oriented curricula, undermine learning in school and much of the impact of increasing existing educational spending. Pedagogical innovations designed to address these distortions (Such as technology-assisted instruction, remedial education, and tracking by achievement) can raise test scores at a low cost. Merely informing parents about school conditions seems insufficient to improve teacher incentives, and evidence on merit pay is mixed, but hiring teachers locally on short-term contracts can save money and improve educational outcomes. School vouchers can cost-effectively increase both school participation and learning.</description><author>Kremer, Michael; Holla, Alaka</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sufficient Statistics for Welfare Analysis: A Bridge Between Structural and Reduced-Form Methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chetty, Raj
The debate between structural and reduced-form approaches has generated substantial controversy in applied economics. This article reviews a recent literature in public economics that combines the advantages of reduced-form strategies-transparent and credible identification-with an important advantage of structural models-the ability to make predictions about counterfactual outcomes and welfare. This literature has developed formulas for the welfare consequences of various policies that are functions of reduced-form elasticities rather than structural primitives. I present a general framework that shows how many policy questions can be answered by estimating a small set of sufficient statistics using program-evaluation methods. I use this framework to synthesize the modern literature on taxation, social insurance, and behavioral welfare economics. Finally, I discuss problems in macroeconomics, labor, development, and industrial organization that could be tackled using the sufficient statistic approach.</description><author>Chetty, Raj</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning and Macroeconomics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evans, George W.; Honkapohja, Seppo
Expectations play a central role in modern macroeconomic theories. The econometric learning approach models economic agents as forming expectations by estimating and updating forecasting models in real time. The learning approach provides a stability test for rational expectations and a selection criterion in models with multiple equilibria. In addition, learning provides new dynamics if older data are discounted, if models are misspecified, or if agents choose between competing models. This paper describes the expectational stability (E-stability) principle and the stochastic approximation tools used to assess equilibria under learning. Applications of learning to a number of areas are reviewed, including the design of monetary and fiscal policy, business cycles, self-fulfilling prophecies, hyperinflation, liquidity traps, and asset prices.</description><author>Evans, George W.; Honkapohja, Seppo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Some Developments in Economic Theory Since 1940: An Eyewitness Account</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arrow, Kenneth J.
Any psychologist who has studied eyewitness accounts knows first of all how unreliable they are. I therefore submit this informal account of some developments in economic theory without research, just as a set of recollections. It is also not ail autobiography, nor a systematic account of my own work. Rather, I consider primarily those developments in economic theory that have had both general interest in the field and special concern for me. For example, as social choice theory is still a specialized field, I am not going to discuss it at all. Further, as it has turned out, I emphasize the developments of technique, although to some extent I refer to some of the underlying visions of the economy to which they are applied. To evaluate my eyewitness testimony, I give the reader some idea of my background and, in particular, the path that led me to be an economist and that has influenced my work and my perception of the development of economics in general. (As my friend Paul David keeps on reminding me and the rest of the world, all development is path-dependent.) I then follow up with four major aspects of economic research in the last 60 years, the period of my scholarly activity. One, econometric methodology and practice, is of such fundamental importance that it cannot go unnoticed, although I played no role in it. With the other three, general equilibrium, dynamic processes, and uncertainty and information, I was more intimately involved.</description><author>Arrow, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preface</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arrow, Kenneth J.; Bresnahan, Timothy
nan</description><author>Arrow, Kenneth J.; Bresnahan, Timothy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>School Vouchers and Student Achievement: Recent Evidence and Remaining Questions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rouse, Cecilia Elena; Barrow, Lisa
In this article, we review the empirical evidence on the impact of education vouchers on student achievement and briefly discuss the evidence from other forms of school choice. The best research to date finds relatively small achievement gains for students offered education vouchers, most of which are not statistically different from zero. Furthermore, what little evidence exists regarding the potential for public schools to respond to increased competitive pressure generated by vouchers suggests that one should remain wary that large improvements would result from a more comprehensive voucher system. The evidence from other forms of school choice is also consistent with this conclusion. Many questions remain unanswered, however, including whether vouchers have longer-run impacts on outcomes such as graduation rates, college enrollment, or even future wages, and whether vouchers might nevertheless provide a cost-neutral alternative to our current system of public education provision at the elementary and secondary school level.</description><author>Rouse, Cecilia Elena; Barrow, Lisa</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizations and Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antras, Pol; Rossi-Hansberg, Esteban
We survey an emerging literature at the intersection of organizational economics and international trade. We argue that a proper modeling of the organizational aspects of production provides valuable insights on the aggregate workings of the world economy. In reviewing the literature, we describe certain predictions of standard models that are affected or even overturned when organizational decisions are brought into the analysis. We also suggest potentially fruitful areas for future research.</description><author>Antras, Pol; Rossi-Hansberg, Esteban</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Importance of History for Economic Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nunn, Nathan
This article provides a survey of a growing body of empirical evidence that points toward the important long-term effects that historic events can have on economic development. The most recent studies, using microlevel data and more sophisticated identification techniques, have moved beyond testing whether history matters and attempt to identify exactly why history matters. The most commonly examined channels include institutions, culture, knowledge and technology, and movements between multiple equilibria. The article concludes with a discussion of the questions that remain and the direction of current research in the literature.</description><author>Nunn, Nathan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technological Change and the Wealth of Nations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gancia, Gino; Zilibotti, Fabrizio
We discuss a unified theory of directed technological change and technology adoption that can shed light on the causes of persistent productivity differences across countries. In our model, new technologies are designed in advanced countries and diffuse endogenously to less developed countries. Our framework is rich enough to highlight three broad reasons for productivity differences: inappropriate technologies, policy-induced barriers to technology adoption, and within-country misallocations across sectors due to policy distortions. We also discuss the effects of two aspects of globalization, trade in goods and migration, oil the wealth of nations through their impact on the direction of technical progress. By doing so, we illustrate some of the equalizing and unequalizing forces of globalization.</description><author>Gancia, Gino; Zilibotti, Fabrizio</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertrand, Marianne
This article starts with an overview of the characteristics of chief executive officers (CEOs). I discuss the rising importance of general skills over firm-specific skills and the growing share of externally recruited CEOs. I also discuss possible reasons for the underrepresentation of women and the overrepresentation of family members in the corporate suite. I then review the three main explanations that have been put for-ward to explain the surge in CEO compensation over the past 30 years: principal-agent view, rent extraction view, and market-based view. I assess the strengths and weaknesses of each of these explanations in light of the existing empirical research. Finally, I review work on how entrenched CEOs or cognitively biased CEOs may cause corporate practices to deviate from the maximization of firm value.</description><author>Bertrand, Marianne</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Experimental Approach to Development Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Abhijit V.; Duflo, Esther
Randomized experiments have become a popular tool in development economics research and have been the subject of a number of criticisms. This paper reviews the recent literature and discusses the strengths and limitations of this approach in theory and in practice. We argue that the main virtue of randomized experiments is that, owing to the close collaboration between researchers and implementers, they allow the estimation of parameters that would not otherwise be possible to evaluate. We discuss the concerns that have been raised regarding experiments and generally conclude that, although real, they are often not specific to experiments. We conclude by discussing the relationship between theory and experiments.</description><author>Banerjee, Abhijit V.; Duflo, Esther</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Consequences of the International Migration of Labor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanson, Gordon H.
In this paper, I selectively discuss recent empirical work on the consequences of global labor mobility. I examine how international migration affects the incomes of individuals in sending and receiving countries and of migrants themselves. Were a social planner to choose the migration policies that Would maximize global welfare, she would need to know, among other values, the elasticities of wages, prices, taxes, and government transfers with respect to national labor supplies as well as how these parameters vary across countries. My goal is to evaluate the progress of the literature in terms of providing these inputs.</description><author>Hanson, Gordon H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The State of Macro</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blanchard, Olivier
For a long while after the explosion of macroeconomics in the 1970s, the field looked like a battlefield. Over time, however, mainly because facts do not go away, a largely shared vision both of fluctuations and of methodology has emerged. Not everything is fine. Like all revolutions, this one has come with the destruction of some knowledge, and it suffers from extremism and herding. None of this is deadly, however. The state of macro is good.</description><author>Blanchard, Olivier</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Racial Profiling? Detecting Bias Using Statistical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Persico, Nicola
We review the economics literature that deals with identifying bias, or taste for discrimination, using statistical evidence. A unified model is developed that encompasses several different strategies studied in the literature. We also discuss certain more theoretical questions concerning the proper objective of discrimination law.</description><author>Persico, Nicola</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Power Laws in Economics and Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gabaix, Xavier
A power law (PL) is the form taken by a large number of surprising empirical regularities in economics and finance. This review surveys well-documented empirical PLs regarding income and wealth, the size of cities and firms, stock market returns, trading volume, international trade, and executive pay. It reviews detail-independent theoretical motivations that make sharp predictions concerning the existence and coefficients of PLs, without requiring delicate tuning of model parameters. These theoretical mechanisms include random growth, optimization, and the economics of superstars, coupled with extreme value theory. Some empirical regularities currently lack an appropriate explanation. This article highlights these open areas for future research. "Few if any economists seem to have realized the possibilities that such invariants hold for the future of our science. In particular, nobody seems to have realized that the hunt for, and the interpretation of, invariants of this type might lay the foundations for an entirely novel type of theory." Schumpeter (1949, p. 155), discussing the Pareto law</description><author>Gabaix, Xavier</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing Supply</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gyourko, Joseph
Research on housing supply has grown owing to improved data combined with heightened interest in policies such as local land use regulations. Heterogeneity in supply conditions across markets is shown to be essential to understanding the growing price dispersion across metropolitan areas, as well as to understanding whether positive growth shocks to a metropolitan area manifest themselves more in terms of expanding population and homebuilding or in terms of higher wages and house prices. The nature of supply obviously also influences local housing-market dynamics. Recent research has shown that differences in the elasticity of housing supply can account for the wide variation in new construction volatility (but not price volatility) across markets over time. The extraordinary nature of the recent boom only increases the need to understand how housing-market fundamentals and supply and demand affect the functioning of this huge asset market.</description><author>Gyourko, Joseph</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantitative Macroeconomics with Heterogeneous Households</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heathcote, Jonathan; Storesletten, Kjetil; Violante, Giovanni L.
Macroeconomics is evolving from the study of aggregate dynamics to the study of the dynamics of the entire equilibrium distribution of allocations across individual economic actors. This article reviews the quantitative macroeconomic literature that focuses on household heterogeneity, with a special emphasis on the "standard" incomplete markets model. We organize the vast literature according to three themes that are central to understanding how inequality matters for macroeconomics. First, what are the most important sources of individual risk and cross-sectional heterogeneity? Second, what are individuals' key channels of insurance? Third, how does idiosyncratic risk interact with aggregate risk?</description><author>Heathcote, Jonathan; Storesletten, Kjetil; Violante, Giovanni L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Behavioral Account of the Labor Market: The Role of Fairness Concerns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fehr, Ernst; Goette, Lorenz; Zehnder, Christian
In this paper, we argue that important labor market phenomena can be better understood if one takes (a) the inherent incompleteness and relational nature of most employment contracts and (b) the existence of reference-dependent fairness concerns among a substantial share of the population into account. Theory shows and experiments confirm that, even if fairness concerns were to exert only weak effects in one-shot interactions, repeated interactions greatly magnify the relevance of such concerns on economic outcomes. We also review evidence from laboratory and field experiments examining the role of wages and fairness on effort, derive predictions from our approach for entry-level wages and incumbent workers' wages, confront these predictions with the evidence, and show that reference-dependent fairness concerns may have important consequences for the effects of economic policies such as minimum wage laws.</description><author>Fehr, Ernst; Goette, Lorenz; Zehnder, Christian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning and Equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fudenberg, Drew; Levine, David K.
The theory of learning in games explores how, which, and what kind of equilibria might arise as a consequence of a long-run nonequilibrium process of learning, adaptation, and/or imitation. If agents' strategies are completely observed at the end of each round (and agents are randomly matched with a series of anonymous opponents), fairly simple rules perform well in terms of the agent's worst-case payoffs, and also guarantee that any steady state of the system must correspond to an equilibrium. If players do not observe the strategies chosen by their opponents (as in extensive-form games), then learning is consistent with steady states that are not Nash equilibria because players can maintain incorrect beliefs about off-path play. Beliefs can also be incorrect because of cognitive limitations and systematic inferential errors.</description><author>Fudenberg, Drew; Levine, David K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>