<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Annual Review of Financial Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 21:54:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Capital Structure and a Firm's Workforce</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>While businesses require funding to start and grow, they also rely on human capital, which affects how they raise funds. Labor market frictions make financing labor different than financing capital. Unlike capital, labor cannot be owned and can act strategically. Workers face unemployment costs, can negotiate for higher wages, are protected by employment regulations, and face retirement risk. I propose using these frictions as a framework for understanding the unique impact of a firm's workforce on its capital structure. For instance, high leverage often makes managing labor more difficult by undermining employees' job security and increasing the need for costly workforce reductions. But firms can also use leverage to their advantage, such as in labor negotiations and defined benefit pensions. This research can help firms account for the needs and management of their workforce when making financing decisions.</description><author>Matsa, David A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shadow Banking in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shadow banking and the Chinese economy are two subjects that have independently garnered much attention. A new but actively growing literature is now emerging at their intersection. I review this literature and argue that shadow banking in China is not fundamentally different from the textbook definition of shadow banking, namely credit intermediation with maturity mismatch that is structured to avoid regulation. I emphasize maturity mismatch because that is what creates run risk and makes any shadow banking system inherently fragile. I explain how the rise of shadow banking in China can be traced back to stricter liquidity regulation, how shadow banking has changed the financial landscape in China, and what the current state of the industry is. Interactions between shadow banking and the rest of the economy have some characteristics that reflect China's unique politico-economic structure, but this is because the rest of the economy has these characteristics, not because there is something fundamentally different about the forces behind shadow banking in China.</description><author>Hachem, Kinda</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risks in China's Financial System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Motivated by growing concerns about the risks and instability of China's financial system, this article reviews several commonly perceived financial risks and discusses their roots in China's politico-economic institutions. We emphasize the need to evaluate these risks within China's unique economic and financial systems, in which the state and nonstate sectors coexist and the financial system serves as a key tool of the government to fund its economic policies. Overall, we argue that (a) a financial crisis is unlikely to happen in the near future and (b) the ultimate risk lies with China's economic growth, as a vicious circle of distortions in the financial system lowers the efficiency of capital allocation and economic growth and will eventually exacerbate financial risks in the long run.</description><author>Song, Zheng; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Housing and Mortgage Markets in the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ten years after the financial crisis of 2008, there is widespread agreement that the boom in mortgage lending and its subsequent reversal were at the core of the Great Recession. We survey the existing evidence, which suggests that inflated house-price expectations across the economy played a central role in driving both the demand for and the supply of mortgage credit before the crisis. The great misnomer of the 2008 crisis is that it was not a subprime crisis but rather a middle-class crisis. Inflated house-price expectations led households across all income groups, especially the middle class, to increase their demand for housing and mortgage leverage. Similarly, banks lent against increasing collateral values and underestimated the risk of defaults. We highlight how these emerging facts have essential implications for policy.</description><author>Adelino, Manuel; Schoar, Antoinette; Severino, Felipe</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity, Leverage, and Regulation 10 Years After the Global Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The financial system has undergone far-reaching changes since the global financial crisis of 2008. We cast those changes in terms of shifts in the manner in which financial intermediaries manage their balance sheets. We also discuss the regulatory reform agenda, and we review the impact of regulations on market liquidity and credit availability. Current evidence suggests that the financial system has become safer, at limited unintended cost.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Kiff, John; Shin, Hyun Song</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recurring Firm Events and Predictable Returns: The Within-Firm Time Series</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We review the literature on recurring firm events and predictable returns. Many common firm events recur on a predictable basis, such as earnings and dividends, among others. These events tend to be associated with large positive returns in the period when the events are predicted to occur (without conditioning on the outcome or existence of the event itself). These returns occur mainly on the long side of the portfolio, are statistically and economically large when value weighted, and replicate internationally. It is difficult to explain the observed patterns with a unified risk theory. Some of the underlying causes seem to be related to idiosyncratic risk, predictable attention, probability mistakes, and demand for corporate distributions.</description><author>Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Financial crises are runs on short-term debt. Whatever its form, short-term debt is an inherent feature of a market economy. A run is an information event in which holders of short-term debt no longer want to lend to banks because they receive information leading them to suspect the value of the backing for the debt, so they run. When runs are system-wide they threaten the solvency of the entire financial system, which then requires either public or private intervention to remedy. Runs, which most likely follow credit booms, are integral parts of movements in the macroeconomy.</description><author>Gorton, Gary</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variance Risk Premia, Asset Predictability Puzzles, and Macroeconomic Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews the predictability evidence on the variance risk premium: (a) It predicts significant positive risk premia across equity, bond, currency, and credit markets; (b) the predictability peaks at few-month horizons and dies out afterward; (c) such a short-run predictability is complementary to the long-run predictability offered by the price-to-earnings ratio, forward rate, interest differential, and leverage ratio. Several structural approaches based on the notion of economic uncertainty are discussed for generating these stylized facts about the variance risk premium, which has broad implications for various empirical asset pricing puzzles.</description><author>Zhou, Hao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting Methods in Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Our review highlights some of the key challenges in financial forecasting problems and opportunities arising from the unique features of financial data. We analyze the difficulty of establishing predictability in an environment with a low signal-to-noise ratio, persistent predictors, and instability in predictive relations arising from competitive pressures and investors' learning. We discuss approaches for forecasting the mean, variance, and probability distribution of asset returns. Finally, we discuss how to evaluate financial forecasts while accounting for the possibility that numerous forecasting models may have been considered, leading to concerns of data mining.</description><author>Timmermann, Allan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common-Ownership Concentration and Corporate Conduct</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The question of whether and how partial common-ownership links between strategically interacting firms affect firm objectives and behavior has been the subject of theoretical inquiry for decades. Since then, the growth of intermediated asset management and consolidation in the asset management sector has led to more pronounced common-ownership links at the level at which corporate control is exercised. Recent empirical research has provided evidence consistent with the literature's prediction that common-ownership concentration (CoOCo) can affect product market outcomes. The resulting antitrust concerns have received worldwide attention. However, because CoOCo can change the objective function of a firm, the potential implications span all fields of economics that involve corporate conduct, including corporate governance, strategy, industrial organization, and financial economics. This article connects the papers establishing the theoretical foundations, reviews the empirical and legal literatures, and discusses challenges and opportunities for future research.</description><author>Schmalz, Martin C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Reallocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Capital reallocation is procyclical, despite measured productive reallocative opportunities being acyclical or even countercyclical. This article reviews the advances in the literature studying the causes and consequences of capital reallocation (or lack thereof). We provide a comprehensive set of stylized facts about capital reallocation for the United States and an illustrative model of capital reallocation in equilibrium. We relate capital reallocation to the broader literatures on business cycles with financial frictions and on resource misallocation and aggregate productivity. Throughout, we provide directions for future research.</description><author>Eisfeldt, Andrea L.; Shi, Yu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-Neutral Densities: A Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trading in options with a wide range of exercise prices and a single maturity allows a researcher to extract the market's risk-neutral density (RND) over the underlying price at expiration. The RND contains investors' beliefs about the true probabilities blended with their risk preferences, both of which are of great interest to academics and practitioners alike. With a particular focus on US equity options, I review the historical development of this powerful concept, practical details of fitting an RND to options market prices, and the many ways in which investigators have tried to distill true expectations and risk premia from observed RNDs. I briefly discuss areas of active current research including the pricing kernel puzzle and the volatility surface, and offer thoughts on what has been learned about RNDs so far and fruitful directions for future research.</description><author>Figlewski, Stephen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity, Risk Premia, and the Financial Transmission of Monetary Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>In recent years, there has been a resurgence of research on the transmission of monetary policy through the financial system, fueled in part by empirical findings showing that monetary policy affects asset prices and the financial system in ways not explained by the New Keynesian paradigm. In particular, monetary policy appears to impact risk premia in stock and bond prices and to effectively control the liquidity premium in the economy (the cost of holding liquid assets). We review these findings and recent theories proposed to explain them, and we outline a conceptual framework that unifies them. The framework revolves around the central role of liquidity in risk sharing and explains how monetary policy governs its production and use within the financial sector.</description><author>Drechsler, Itamar; Savov, Alexi; Schnabl, Philipp</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Investor Sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Investor sentiment indicates how far an asset value deviates from its economic fundamentals. In this article, we review various measures of investor sentiment based on market, survey, and text and media data. There is ample evidence that sentiment can explain returns on stocks that are difficult to value and costly to arbitrage, such as unprofitable stocks, non-dividend-paying stocks, extreme growth stocks, and distressed stocks. However, much remains to be done. We discuss three issues for future research: aggregating measures over various sources and various time horizons, linking investor sentiment to technical analysis, and statistically modeling the evolution of investor sentiment.</description><author>Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deglobalization: The Rise of Disembedded Unilateralism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>There is some evidence of deglobalization in the aftermath of the 2008 financial crisis. The economic data are mixed and indicate a stall, but not a collapse, of globalization. Cross-border financial flows have been reduced, but the overall outcome mostly reflects changes in European banking. Trade is not growing as quickly as before the crisis, but that may be the consequence of technology shortening supply chains. There are more protectionist measures, but they have not radically cut trade. But political deglobalization has advanced much further, and consequently, there is the prospect of more intense conflicts over trade and financial regulation in the future, as well as one of an increasing backlash against migration. Globalization depends on a complex system of regulating cross-border flows and on embedding domestic rules in an international order. The political momentum is directed against the existing methods or regulation and against the complex rules that had been established to manage globalization. The promise given by populist myth builders is that eliminating international entanglements can make life simpler, less regulated, and above all, less subject to the dictates of an administrative class. Modern economic nationalism or unilateralism can be understood as a reversal of the process of embedding and may thus be termed "disembedded unilateralism."</description><author>James, Harold</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deregulating Wall Street</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We argue that implementation of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act has contributed significantly to the reduction of systemic risk in the United States. However, Dodd-Frank also introduced burdensome rules that have little to do with systemic risk. This article evaluates the trade-off between capital regulation and regulation of scope in the context of Dodd-Frank, with a particular emphasis on the Volcker Rule. Recent regulatory reforms aimed at rolling back Dodd-Frank are evaluated and discussed.</description><author>Richardson, Matthew; Schoenholtz, Kermit L.; White, Lawrence J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intermediary Asset Pricing and the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Intermediary asset pricing understands asset prices and risk premia through the lens of frictions in financial intermediation. Perhaps motivated by phenomena in the financial crisis, intermediary asset pricing has been one of the fastest-growing areas of research in finance. This article explains the theory behind intermediary asset pricing and, in particular, how it is different from other approaches to asset pricing. This article also covers selective empirical evidence in favor of intermediary asset pricing.</description><author>He, Zhiguo; Krishnamurthy, Arvind</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory Reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>In the wake of the global financial crisis (GFC), many nations embarked on reform to the financial regulatory system. This reform, unprecedented in its scope, touched virtually every part of the financial system in the United States and Western Europe. This article summarizes the key reforms, explains how these reforms fit together, assesses the relevant scholarly literature, and suggests six significant areas of open questions for researchers. These six areas are (a) liquidity rules, (b) central clearing of swaps, (c) shadow banking, (d) lenders of last resort, (e) extended guarantees, and (f) resolution and restructuring.</description><author>Metrick, Andrew; Rhee, June</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic Risk 10 Years Later</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ten years ago, the financial crisis spurred research focused on systemic risk. This article examines the history and application of the SRISK measure, which was developed at that time and is now widely used in monitoring systemic risk around the globe. The concept is explained and a variety of ways to measure SRISK are developed. In this article, new results are presented on the uncertainty associated with the SRISK measure and on how it compares with other related measures from both academics and regulators. By focusing on the mechanism by which undercapitalization of the financial sector initiates a financial crisis, new research examines how the probability of a financial crisis is affected by the level of SRISK and, consequently, how much SRISK a country can stand without having a high probability of crisis. The model used to evaluate this probability recognizes the externalities between financial institutions that make an undercapitalized firm or country more fragile if other firms and countries are also undercapitalized.</description><author>Engle, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Research on Banks' Financial Reporting and Financial Stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banks' financial reporting requirements and discretionary choices may affect financial stability by altering one or more of the likelihood that banks violate regulatory capital requirements, banks' internal discipline over risk management and financial reporting, and external market and regulatory discipline over banks. In this article, I discuss five recent empirical papers that examine these channels linking banks' financial reporting to financial stability. I explain how these papers identify economic contexts and associated financial reporting constructs that enable powerful examinations of these channels, and how they employ research designs that meaningfully address the issues regarding valid causal inference raised by Acharya &amp; Ryan (2016). I conclude that, while each study examines a specific channel or two in a specific setting, collectively the literature is making steady progress in enhancing our understanding of the causal forces at play in the channels linking banks' financial reporting and financial stability, the goal set forth by Acharya &amp; Ryan (2016). I also identify open questions that these papers suggest for future research on the effects of banks' financial reporting on financial stability.</description><author>Ryan, Stephen G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage-Default Research and the Recent Foreclosure Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews the surge in research on mortgage default inspired by the recent foreclosure crisis. Economists already understood a great deal about default, both theoretically and empirically, when the crisis began, but new research has moved the frontier further by improving data sources, building dynamic optimizing models of default, and explicitly addressing reverse causality between rising foreclosures and falling house prices. Mortgage defaults also featured prominently in early papers that pointed to subprime and other privately securitized mortgages as fundamental drivers of the housing boom, although this research has been criticized recently. Going forward, improvements to data and models will allow researchers to make progress on the two central questions in this literature. First, what are the relative contributions of adverse life events and negative equity to mortgage default? Second, why is default so rare, even among people with deep negative equity or acute financial distress?</description><author>Foote, Christopher L.; Willen, Paul S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Primer on Portfolio Choice with Small Transaction Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review is an introduction to asymptotic methods for portfolio choice problems with small transaction costs. We outline how to derive the corresponding dynamic programming equations and how to simplify them in the small-cost limit. This allows one to obtain explicit solutions in a wide range of settings, which we illustrate for a model with mean-reverting expected returns and proportional transaction costs. For more complex models, we present a policy iteration scheme that allows one to numerically compute the solution.</description><author>Muhle-Karbe, Johannes; Reppen, Max; Soner, H. Mete</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forward-Looking Estimates of Interest-Rate Distributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews methods for extracting both risk-neutral and physical density forecasts for interest rates. It presents some applications, with particular focus on issues pertaining to forward guidance and the zero lower bound. Several important applied questions in macroeconomics and monetary economics can be very directly addressed using the wealth of information in interest-rate derivative securities.</description><author>Wright, Jonathan H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Firm's Cost of Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>To create value, a firm must invest in projects that provide a return greater than the cost of capital. The cost of capital is not observed and its estimation requires assumptions on investors' consumption, savings, and portfolio decisions. We review the academic literature on firms' cost of financial capital and the estimation of the different components: cost of equity, cost of debt, and their relative weights. We also review various approaches to estimating the cost of capital and the assumptions justifying these approaches.</description><author>Jagannathan, Ravi; Liberti, Jose; Liu, Binying; Meier, Iwan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Fundamentals Underlying Oil and Natural Gas Derivative Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>What determines the range and boundaries of energy derivative markets? Why is the oil futures trade dominated by contracts on two grades and locations when the global trade encompasses many grades and locations? Should we expect change in the near future? We review research on the establishment and performance of energy derivative markets, focusing on the two major energy commodities: oil and natural gas. For both commodities, trade in derivatives arose at the conclusion of a historical process in which production along the value chain that had been coordinated by vertically integrated companies or similar institutional structures switched to being coordinated through markets. Consequently, much of the research reviewed here is about the structural changes that made it possible for markets to assume this role. This review encompasses research into the price discovery function, which determines how many successful futures contracts are needed for each commodity.</description><author>Parsons, John E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Overview of China's Financial System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We provide a review of China's financial system and consider the challenges it faces and future reforms. The formal sectors of the financial system, which include a fast-growing stock market and are dominated by a banking sector with large state-owned banks, have played a critical role in financing the state sectors and the investment-driven economic growth model. However, the formal sectors have not served the needs of the private sectors or of households; these dynamic sectors have been financed by alternative finance sectors operating largely outside the markets and formal institutions. Going forward, financial markets need to be further developed to provide more support for the private sectors, including technology and services industries; the formal and alternative sectors should work together to improve the efficiency of resource allocation to better support the new model of consumption-and innovation-driven growth. Finally, the financial system needs to reduce the likelihood of damaging financial crises, which have included a real estate crisis, a banking crisis triggered by defaults on corporate and local government debt, and a twin crisis in the currency market and the banking sector.</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Qian, Jun Q. J.; Gu, Xian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange-Traded Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Over nearly a quarter of a century, exchange-traded funds (ETFs) have become one of the most popular passive investment vehicles among retail and professional investors because of their low transaction costs and high liquidity. By the end of 2016, the market share of ETFs exceeded 10% of the total market capitalization traded on US exchanges, representing more than 30% of overall trading volume. ETFs revolutionized the asset management industry by taking market share from traditional investment vehicles such as mutual funds and index futures. Because ETFs rely on arbitrage activity to synchronize their prices with the prices of the underlying portfolio, trading activity at the ETF level translates to trading of the underlying securities. Researchers have found that although ETFs enhance price discovery, they also inject nonfundamental volatility into market prices and affect the correlation structure of returns. Furthermore, ETFs impact the liquidity of the underlying portfolios, especially during events of market stress.</description><author>Ben-David, Itzhak; Franzoni, Francesco; Moussawi, Rabih</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What to Do About the GSEs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, the two large government-sponsored enterprises (GSEs) that are at the center of US residential mortgage finance, are "elephants in the room" that are being ignored as part of broad-brush financial sector reform. Neither the Dodd-Frank Act nor recently proposed overhauls of Dodd-Frank have addressed reform of the GSEs' structures, although the GSEs were placed in government conservatorships in early September 2008 and have remained in that state since then. In this article, we review what the GSEs do and how they got themselves into financial difficulties, and we provide an overview of some of the major proposals for reforming the US residential mortgage finance system. We conclude with our own ideas and suggestions for how housing finance, as well as housing policy more generally, should be reformed.</description><author>Richardson, Matthew P.; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; White, Lawrence J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Development of China's Stock Market and Stakes for the Global Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The rise of China and fivefold growth of its stock market over the past decade have fueled a growing literature on this market in financial economics. On the corporate side, researchers have evaluated the progress of China's stages of privatization, analyzed biases in the selection of firms for listing, and documented massive underpricing of initial public offerings. On the asset pricing side, researchers have studied the price premium of domestic A shares over their foreign-share counterparts, analyzed the firm-specific information content of prices, provided new evidence on informational and behavioral effects in prices, and begun to identify systematic cross-sectional patterns in returns. Numerous areas are ripe for future research as China's stock market continues to grow in global influence and as ongoing reform provides new natural experiments. Challenges for the field will be to gain familiarity with China's distinctive financial system and to avoid overapplying research paradigms developed for the US setting.</description><author>Carpenter, Jennifer N.; Whitelaw, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do the Effects of Accounting Requirements on Banks' Regulatory Capital Adequacy Undermine Financial Stability?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>During the 2007-2009 financial crisis, many parties criticized aspects of accounting requirements for banks as undermining financial stability. These criticisms generally reflect the view that these requirements primarily affect stability through their effects on banks' regulatory capital adequacy. I critically evaluate whether this idea can be sustained on logical and evidential grounds. I explain how accounting requirements typically have quite small effects on banks' regulatory capital adequacy. I discuss the plausibility of the alternative view that accounting requirements primarily affect stability by improving banks' understanding of their risks and their transparency to markets and regulators. Because securitization is the setting in which banks' regulatory capital adequacy is most likely to be significantly affected by accounting requirements, I describe empirical research on significant changes in securitization accounting effective in 2010. I explain how even in this setting regulatory capital adequacy incompletely explains how accounting requirements for banks affect stability.</description><author>Ryan, Stephen G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Liquidity After the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article examines market liquidity in the postcrisis era in light of concerns that regulatory changes might have reduced dealers' ability and willingness to make markets. We begin with a discussion of the broader trading environment, including an overview of regulations and their potential effects on dealer balance sheets and market making, but also considering additional drivers of market liquidity. We document a stagnation of dealer balance sheets after the financial crisis of 2007-2009, which occurred concurrently with dealer balance sheet deleveraging. However, using high-frequency trade and quote data for US Treasuries and corporate bonds, we find only limited evidence of a deterioration in market liquidity.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Fleming, Michael; Shachar, Or; Vogt, Erik</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agent-Based Models for Financial Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article describes the agent-based approach to modeling financial crises. It focuses on the interactions of agents and on how these interactions feed back to change the financial environment. It explains how these models embody the contagion and cascades that occur owing to the financial leverage and market concentration of the agents and the liquidity of the markets. This article also compares agent-based models to the standard economic approach to crises and shows the ways in which agent-based models overcome limitations of economic models when dealing with financial crises. In particular, this article demonstrates how agent-based models replace homogeneous, representative agents with heterogeneous agents and optimization with heuristics, and how such models move away from a focus on equilibrium, allowing non-ergodic dynamics that are manifest during financial crises to emerge.</description><author>Bookstaber, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Disclosure in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Information disclosure is an essential component of regulation in financial markets. In this article, we provide a cohesive analytical framework to review certain key channels through which disclosure in financial markets affects market quality, information production, efficiency of real investment decisions, and traders' welfare. We use our framework to address four main aspects. First, we demonstrate the conventional wisdom that disclosure improves market quality in an economy with exogenous information. Second, we illustrate that disclosure can crowd out the production of private information and that its overall market-quality implications are subtle and depend on the specification of information-acquisition technology. Third, we review how disclosure affects the efficiency of real investment decisions when financial markets are not just a side show, as real decision makers can learn information from them to guide their decisions. Last, we discuss how disclosure in financial markets affects investors' welfare through changing trading opportunities and through beauty-contest motives. Overall, our review suggests that information disclosure is an important factor for understanding the functioning of financial markets and that there are several trade-offs that should be considered in determining its optimal level.</description><author>Goldstein, Itay; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Shapes Consumer Choice and Financial Products? A Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Central to the field of consumer finance is that consumers make financial decisions that do not always coincide with the financial decisions ideally depicted in optimal economic models. In this review, we discuss developments in the field of household finance, focusing on how consumers make suboptimal financial decisions across different types of settings and factors that affect their decisions. Rather than conducting a comprehensive survey, we focus specifically on consumer choice in the context of research on credit card borrowing, housing and mortgage debts, investment and savings decisions, and spending and consumption. Wealso discuss financial product design and marketing, as well as the regulatory landscape of lenders of consumer financial products. We present five future research directions and considerations for researchers and policymakers.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Chomsisengphet, Souphala; Lim, Cheryl</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Funds in Equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Historically, the literature on money management has inconsistently applied the rational expectations equilibrium concept. We explain why and summarize developments in the money management literature that do apply this concept correctly. We demonstrate that the rational expectations equilibrium approximates the observed equilibrium in the money management space at least as well as it does in the stock market. Recent work reveals that there is little support for the common conclusion that, as a group, investors in the money management space are naive and that mutual fund managers are charlatans. Even today, equilibrium thinking is not nearly as prevalent in mutual fund research as it is in the rest of asset pricing. This state of play provides a multitude of opportunities for future research in the area.</description><author>Berk, Jonathan B.; van Binsbergen, Jules H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Education Financing and Student Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>As the cost of education rises and student debt reaches new highs, more research has focused on financing the acquisition of human capital. Most research has had a positive focus, examining the effect of debt on student choices and outcomes. However, because education financing involves many public policy choices, normative questions have become more prominent. We discuss the trade-offs involved in these choices and propose simple models to help shape these questions. We first develop an overlapping generations framework of student debt to examine the macroeconomic impact of shifting from a parent-funded to a student debt-based financing system. We then consider a framework that includes the supply-side response to different funding regimes; that is, how do enrollment and tuition decisions of schools respond to changes in education financing? We show that shifting from parent-based funding to a student loan program can lower aggregate savings, although welfare still improves if education has a higher return than physical capital investment. A public student loan program also tends to promote enrollment at the cost of higher tuition at for-profit schools and deteriorating loan performance, paid for by taxpayers. Alternative contract designs, with school participation in the lending program, tend to ameliorate these issues.</description><author>Amromin, Gene; Eberly, Janice</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of High-Frequency Trading: Taking Stock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>I review the recent high-frequency trader (HFT) literature to single out the economic channels by which HFTs affect market quality. I first group the various theoretical studies according to common denominators and discuss the economic costs and benefits they identify. For each group, I then review the empirical literature that speaks to either the models' assumptions or their predictions. This enables me to come to a data-weighted judgement on the economic value of HFTs.</description><author>Menkveld, Albert J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money Market Funds and Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article examines money market funds and the regulation that was promulgated in the wake of the Lehman Brothers bankruptcy during the financial crisis of 2007 and 2008. Various explanations for the ensuing run-like behavior are discussed, including a first-mover advantage related to potential fire sales, the ability to redeem shares at a stable $1.00 when funds are valued below $1.00, and flights to quality and transparency. We then discuss regulatory reform, beginning with the SEC's 2010 amendments and concluding with its 2014 Money Market Fund Reform rules, which require (a) all funds to implement liquidity fees and redemption gates and (b) institutional prime funds to price at their floating net asset value. The economic underpinnings of the SEC's final policy choices are discussed and compared to alternatives, such as capital buffers, that were considered but not adopted.</description><author>Lewis, Craig M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency Dynamics in Corporate Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We describe a framework for analyzing the dynamics of investment, borrowing, and payout decisions by public corporations. We assume that managers act entirely in their own long-run interests, subject to a governance constraint that limits their rents. Risk-neutral managers invest to maximize value but wait too long to disinvest. Efficient disinvestment can be forced by the right level of debt or by takeovers. Risk-averse managers underinvest; they do not waste free cash flow, because the governance constraint is binding. They smooth rents and consequently payout, so that changes in borrowing become a shock absorber for volatility of operating income. We obtain the Lintner model of payout if risk-averse managers have a utility function with habit formation. We show how to adapt the dynamic framework to analyze several other issues, including the effects of asymmetric information. We show that Lintner-style payout smoothing can also arise when risk-neutral managers are better informed than outsiders.</description><author>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Myers, Stewart C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Supply Disruptions: From Credit Crunches to Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>It is useful to reflect on how the financial environment changed between the credit crunch episode of the early 1990s and the recent financial crisis. What did we learn from the earlier crisis, and how did the credit crunch literature help guide policy in the more recent crisis? Two important changes were the consolidation of the banking sector and the dramatic growth in nonbank financial intermediaries, which are much more susceptible than banks to liquidity risks because of a lack of deposit insurance. This article highlights that, although security broker-dealers, money market mutual funds, and issuers of asset-backed securities were not particularly important in the early 1990s, when the bank credit crunch occurred, they grew dramatically to become both major sources of financing and key elements in exacerbating the problems experienced during the recent financial crisis.</description><author>Peek, Joe; Rosengren, Eric</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposit Insurance: Theories and Facts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Economic theories posit that bank liability insurance is designed to serve the public interest by mitigating systemic risk in the banking system through the reduction of liquidity risk. Political theories, however, see liability insurance as serving the private interests of banks, bank borrowers, and depositors, potentially at the expense of the public interest. Empirical evidence-both historical and contemporary-supports the private-interest approach, as liability insurance has been associated with increases, rather than decreases, in systemic risk. Exceptions to this rule are rare and reflect design features that prevent moral hazard and adverse selection. Prudential regulation of insured banks has generally not been a very effective tool in limiting the systemic risk increases associated with liability insurance. This likely reflects purposeful failures in regulation; if liability insurance is motivated by private interests, then there would be little point to removing the subsidies it creates through strict regulation. The same logic explains why more effective policies for addressing systemic risk are not employed in place of liability insurance. The politics of liability insurance thus should not be narrowly construed to encompass only the vested interests of bankers. Indeed, in many countries, liability insurance has been installed as a pass-through subsidy targeted to particular classes of bank borrowers.</description><author>Calomiris, Charles W.; Jaremski, Matthew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity Capital, Internal Capital Markets, and Optimal Capital Structure in the US Property-Casualty Insurance Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews the most pertinent literature on the sources and uses of equity capital in the US property-casualty (P-C) insurance industry. P-C insurers serve risk management and risk-bearing functions in the economy. Insurers create diversified risk pools consisting of large numbers of exposures. However, even in the most highly diversified risk pools, uncertainty is not reduced to zero, and insurers must hold equity capital to credibly promise that claims will be paid even if losses are higher than expected. We begin with a financial overview of the industry. Insurers are well capitalized and financially stable, withstanding large catastrophic events and economic crises. Analysis of capital regulation further shows that regulation is not binding for the vast majority of insurers. We then review the theoretical and empirical evidence on the most important economic phenomena impinging on capital in P-C insurance: underwriting cycles, internal capital markets (ICMs), and optimal capital structure. P-C insurers are heavy users of ICMs, and insurer ICM transactions are efficient. According to available evidence, P-C insurers have optimal capital structures and behave according to the trade-off theory of capital structure.</description><author>Cummins, J. David; Weiss, Mary A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Life Insurance Industry and Systemic Risk: A Bond Market Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The 2008 financial crisis brought a focus on the potential for a large insurance firm to contribute to systemic risk. Among the concerns raised was that a negative shock to insurers could lead to a fire sale of corporate bonds, a market where insurers are among the largest participants. This manuscript discusses the existing evidence on life insurance firms and systemic risk, with a focus on the investment-grade corporate bond market. We provide some tentative evidence that life insurers tend to absorb liquidity risk by purchasing bonds when the bonds are less liquid than average. However, we do not find evidence that insurers increased bond purchases specifically during the financial crisis, leaving open the question of whether insurers would play a stabilizing role in a future crisis.</description><author>Paulson, Anna; Rosen, Richard</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Default Swaps: Past, Present, and Future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Credit default swaps (CDS) have grown to be a multi-trillion-dollar, globally important market. The academic literature onCDS has developed in parallel with the market practices, public debates, and regulatory initiatives in this market. We selectively review the extant literature, identify remaining gaps, and suggest directions for future research. We present a narrative including the following four aspects. First, we discuss the benefits and costs of CDS, emphasizing the need for more research in order to better understand the welfare implications. Second, we provide an overview of the postcrisis market structure and the new regulatory framework for CDS. Third, we place CDS in the intersection of law and finance, focusing on agency conflicts and financial intermediation. Last, we examine the role of CDS in international finance, especially during and after the recent sovereign credit crises.</description><author>Augustin, Patrick; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Tang, Dragon Y.; Wang, Sarah Q.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysts' Forecasts and Asset Pricing: A Survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This survey reviews the literature on sell-side analysts' forecasts and their implications for asset pricing. We review the literature on the supply and demand forces shaping analysts' forecasting decisions as well as on the implications of the information they produce for both the cash flow and the discount rate components of security returns. Analysts' forecasts bring prices in line with the expectations they embody, consistent with the notion that they contain information about future cash flows. However, analysts' forecasts exhibit predictable biases, and the market appears to underreact to the information in forecasts and to not fully filter the biases in forecasts. Analysts' forecasts are also helpful in estimating expected returns on securities, but evidence on the relation between analysts' forecasts and expected returns is still scarce. We conclude by identifying unanswered questions and offering suggestions for future research.</description><author>Kothari, S. P.; So, Eric; Verdi, Rodrigo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Globalization and Asset Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We provide a comprehensive analysis of the impact of economic and financial globalization on asset return comovements over the past 35 years. Our globalization indicators draw a distinction between de jure openness that results from changes in the regulatory environment and de facto or realized openness, as well as between capital market restrictions across different asset classes. Although globalization has trended positively for most of our sample, the global financial crisis and its aftermath have provided new headwinds. Equity, bond, and foreign exchange returns often have different responses to globalization. We generally find weak evidence of comovement measures reacting to globalization and often find other economic factors to be equally or more important determinants.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Harvey, Campbell R.; Kiguel, Andrea; Wang, Xiaozheng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Small Business Bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bankruptcy is the legal process by which financially distressed firms and individuals resolve their debts. It is an important part of the legal environment for small business owners and their lenders because small businesses are very risky and often fail and because bankruptcy law affects how business owners and their lenders are treated in the event of failure. Both personal and corporate bankruptcy law are relevant for most small businesses, as even when businesses are incorporated, lenders often require that business owners personally guarantee loans to the business. This article discusses theoretical models and empirical tests of how bankruptcy law affects small business, including the effects of bankruptcy law on incentives to start and remain in business, how bankruptcy law affects small business credit, and whether bankruptcy law leads to efficient decisions concerning whether failing businesses reorganize or liquidate. Research using small business data from both the United States and other countries is covered in this survey.</description><author>White, Michelle J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance of Family Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We review what the financial economics literature has to say about the unique ways in which the following three classic agency problems manifest themselves in family firms: (a) shareholders versus managers, (It) controlling (family) shareholders versus noncontrolling shareholders, and (c) shareholders versus creditors. We also call attention to a fourth agency problem that is unique to family firms: the conflict of interest between family shareholders and the family at large, which can be thought of as the "superprincipal" in a multi-tier agency structure akin to those found in other concentrated ownership structures in which the controlling owner is the state, a bank, a corporation, or other institutions. We then discuss the solutions or corporate governance mechanisms that have been devised to address these problems and what research has taught us about these mechanisms' effectiveness at solving these four conflicts in family firms.</description><author>Villalonga, Belen; Amit, Raphael; Trujillo, Maria-Andrea; Guzman, Alexander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Estate Price Indices and Price Dynamics: An Overview from an Investments Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews the state of the art in real estate price indexing and the state of knowledge about real estate price dynamics, with a focus on investment property, or income-generating commercial property. Investment properties form a large component of the national wealth and of capital markets and represent a major investment asset class. They are characterized by various types of heterogeneity, including among assets, markets, and data sources, making the study of real estate pricing uniquely challenging. Yet in recent decades, urban economists and econometricians have pioneered major new price indexing methodologies that, combined with new types of data sources, are shedding light on the nature of conimercial property price dynamics, revealing both important con-imonalities and unique differences compared with equities and tixed-income securities pricing.</description><author>Geltner, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Advances in Research on Hedge Fund Activism: Value Creation and Identification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We survey the literature on private equity performance, focusing on venture capital and buyout funds rather than on portfolio companies. We describe recent findings on performance measures, average fund returns, risk adjustments, cyclicality and liquidity, persistence, interim returns and self-reported net asset values, the performance of different types of investors in funds, and the links between management contracts and fund returns. Buyout funds have outperformed the S&amp;P 500 net of fees on average by approximately 20% over the life of the fund. Venture capital funds raised in the 1990s outperformed the S&amp;P 500, whereas those raised in the 2000s underperformed. the results are consistent across a number of data sets and papers. Before the 2000s. buyout and venture capital fund performance showed strong evidence of persistence. Since 2000, buyout fund persistence has declined, whereas venture capital fund persistence has remained equally strong.</description><author>Kaplan, Steven N.; Sensoy, Berk A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Advances in Research on Hedge Fund Activism: Value Creation and Identification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hedge fund activism emerged as a major force of corporate governance in the 2000s. By the mid-2000s, there were between 150 and 200 activist hedge funds in action each year, advocating for changes in 200-300 publicly listed companies in the United States. In this article, we review the evolution and major characteristics of hedge fund activism, as well as the short- and long-term impacts of the performance and governance of targeted companies. Though most of the analyses here are based on a comprehensive sample of over 2,000 activism events in the United States from 1994 to 2011, hand-collected by the authors from regulatory filings and news searches, this article covers all major studies on the topic, including those on markets outside of the United States.</description><author>Brav, Alon; Jiang, Wei; Kim, Hyunseob</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Funds: A Dynamic Industry in Transition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The hedge-fund industry has grown rapidly over the past two decades, offering investors unique investment opportunities that often reflect more complex risk exposures than those of traditional investments. In this article, we present a selective review of the recent academic literature on hedge funds as well as updated empirical results for this industry. Our review is written from several distinct perspectives. the investor's, the portfolio manager's, the regulator's, and the academic's. Each of these perspectives offers a different set of insights into the financial system, and the combination provides surprisingly rich implications for the Efficient Markets Hypothesis, investment management, systemic risk, financial regulation, and other aspects of financial theory and practice.</description><author>Getmansky, Mila; Lee, Peter A.; Lo, Andrew W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Empirical Research on the Design and Impact Regulation in the Banking Sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We review existing empirical research on the design and impact of regulation in the banking sector. The impact of each individual piece of regulation may inexorably depend on the set of regulations already in place, the characteristics of the banks involved (from their size or ownership structure to operational idiosyncrasies in terms of capitalization levels or risk-taking behavior), and the institutional development of the country where the regulation is introduced. This complexity is challenging for the econometrician, who relies either on single-country data to identify challenges for regulation or on cross-country data to assess the overall effects of regulation. It is also troubling for the policy maker, who has to optimally design regulation to avoid any unintended consequences, especially those that vary over the credit cycle such as the currently developing macroprudential frameworks.</description><author>Jakovljevic, Sanja; Degryse, Hans; Ongena, Steven</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Overview of Macroprudential Policy Tools</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Macroprudential policies caps on loan to value ratios, limits on credit growth and other balance-sheet restrictions, (countercyclical) capital and reserve requirements and surcharges, and Pigouvian levies have become part of the policy paradigm in emerging markets and developed countries alike. But knowledge of these tools is still limited. Macroprudential policies ought to be motivated by market failures and externalities, but these can be hard to identify. They may also interact with various other policies, such as monetary and microprudential, raising coordination issues. Countries, especially emerging markets, have used these tools, and analyses suggest that some of those tools reduce procyclicality and crisis risks. Yet, much remains to be studied, including the costs of such tools, as they may adversely affect resource allocations; how best to adapt these tools to a country's circumstances; and preferred institutional designs, including how to address political economy risks. As such, policy makers should move carefully in adopting these tools.</description><author>Claessens, Stijn</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Stability Monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We present a forward-looking monitoring program to identify and track the sources of systemic risk over time and to facilitate the development of preemptive policies to promote financial stability. We offer a framework that distinguishes between shocks, which are difficult to prevent, and vulnerabilities, which amplify shocks. Building on substantial research, we focus on leverage, maturity transformation, interconnectedness, complexity, and the pricing of risk as the primary vulnerabilities in the financial system. The monitoring program tracks these vulnerabilities in four areas: the banking sector, shadow banking, asset markets, and the nonfinancial sector. The framework also highlights the policy trade-off between reducing systemic risk and raising the cost of financial intermediation by taking preemptive actions to reduce vulnerabilities.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Covitz, Daniel; Liang, Nellie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supervisory Stress Tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We describe the background, design choices, and particular details of stress tests used as part of an overall supervisory regime, that is, their formal integration into the ongoing prudential supervision of banks and other large financial institutions. We then describe how the US Comprehensive Capital Analysis and Review (CCAR) and Dodd-Frank Act stress testing (DFAST) regime is designed and what that means for the macroprudential versus microprudential nature of US supervisory exercises. We argue that routine stress tests have the potential to substantially change the nature of the supervisory process. We also argue that a great deal depends on the philosophy underpinning modeling; decisions, which has not received as much attention as scenario design, disclosure, or other stress test design choices.</description><author>Hirtle, Beverly; Lehnert, Andreas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Axiomatic Approach to Risk Measures for Capital Determination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The quantification of downside risk in terms of capital requirements is a key issue for both regulators and the financial industry. This review presents the axiomatic approach, which is based on monetary risk measures. These provide a unifying mathematical framework for the determination of capital requirements, for economic indices of riskiness, and for the analysis of preferences in the face of risk and Knightian uncertainty. In the special case of distribution-based risk measures, we review recent advances in characterizing their statistical properties such as elicitability and robustness.</description><author>Foellmer, Hans; Weber, Stefan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Risk Management in Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Failures of banks' governance and risk management functions have been identified as key causes of the 2007-2008 financial crisis. This article reviews the empirical literature that investigates the relationship between governance structures and risk management functions as well as their impact on banks' risk taking and performance. I first discuss risk management's responsibilities and relevance for a value-maximizing bank. The business nature of financial institutions and their funding structure, together with explicit and implicit government guarantees, set them apart from nonfinancial firms. I argue that conventional governance structures alone may be unable to restrain risk taking in banks and thus the presence of a strong and independent risk management function becomes necessary to monitor and control enterprise-wide risk exposures. Recent evidence shows that a strong risk management function, compatible with the appropriate business model and culture, can restrain tail risk exposures at financial institutions and promote long-term value maximization.</description><author>Ellul, Andrew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analytics of Insurance Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article describes contributions of analytics and statistical methods to our understanding of insurance operations and markets. Specifically, it introduces insurance analytics, the foundations of the discipline, and the supporting literature. It also describes current trends in analytics. Insurance as a discipline has long embraced analytics, and market trends signal an even stronger relationship going forward.</description><author>Frees, Edward W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Price Bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews the theoretical literature on asset price bubbles, with an emphasis on the martingale theory of bubbles. The key questions studied are as follows: First, under what conditions can asset price bubbles exist in an economy? Second, if bubbles exist, what are the implications for the pricing of derivatives on the bubble-laden asset? Third, if bubbles can exist, how can they be empirically determined. Answers are provided for three frictionless and competitive economies with increasingly restrictive structures. The least restrictive economy just assumes no arbitrage. The next satisfies no arbitrage and no dominance. The third assumes the existence of an equilibrium.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value and Risk of Human Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Human capital embodies the knowledge, skills, health, and values that contribute to making people productive. These qualities, however, are hard to measure, and quantitative studies of human capital are typically based on the valuation of the lifetime income that a person generates in the labor market. This article surveys the theoretical and empirical literature that models a worker's life-cycle earnings and identifies appropriate discount rates to translate those cash flows into a certainty equivalent of wealth. We begin with an overview of a stylized model of human capital valuation with exogenous labor income. We then discuss extensions to this framework that study the underlying economic sources of labor income shocks, the choices that people make during their lives (such as about work, leisure, retirement, and investment in education), and the implications of these factors for human capital valuation and risk.</description><author>Benzoni, Luca; Chyruk, Olena</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contributions to Defined Contribution Pension Plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Defined contribution (DC) pension plans are an increasingly important means of financing retirement consumption. Because individuals often have substantial discretion over how much is contributed to their DC pension plan, studying DC contribution choices provides general insights into the determinants of individual economic decision making. The literature has found strong deviations from many predictions of classical frictionless optimizing models. I provide an overview of the US DC pension system and review the literature on the effect of matching contributions, automatic enrollment, active choice deadlines, choice overload, financial literacy, peer effects, mental accounting, and personal experience on individuals' DC contributions.</description><author>Choi, James J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavioral Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Behavioral finance studies the application of psychology to finance, with a focus on individual-level cognitive biases. I describe here the sources of judgment and decision biases, how the affect trading and market prices, the role of arbitrage and flows of wealth between more rational and less rational investors, how firms exploit inefficient prices and incite misvaluation, and the effects of managerial judgment biases. There is a need for more theory and testing of the effects of feelings on financial decisions and aggregate outcomes. Especially, the time has come to move beyond behavioral finance to social finance, which studies the structure of social interactions, how financial ideas spread and evolve, and how social processes affect financial outcomes.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption-Based Asset Pricing, Part 2: Habit Formation, Conditional Risks, Long-Run Risks, and Rare Disasters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Following Part I of this article, which reviews late-1970s to 1990s classic derivations and tests of the consumption capital asset pricing model, here in Part 2 we review more recent developments, some of which are based on utility functions with non-time-separable preferences. Important second-generation consumption-based asset pricing advances are also reviewed, including models with habit formation and long-run risk. These models give large cyclical changes in relative risk aversion and risk premiums as well as lagged impacts of aggregate consumption changes on risk premiums. We review asset pricing with rare disasters and models focused on consumer spending on durables and real estate, as well as the fraction of spending financed by labor income. The second-generation models discussed have more free parameters and fit the empirical data better than did the first-generation consumption-based asset pricing models.</description><author>Breeden, Douglas T.; Litzenberger, Robert H.; Jia, Tingyan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption-Based Asset Pricing, Part 1: Classic Theory and Tests, Measurement Issues, and Limited Participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article, Part 1 of 2, reviews the classical origins, development, and tests of consumption-based asset pricing theory, focusing mainly on the first two decades from 1976 to 1998. Starting with the original consumption capital asset pricing model (CCAPM) derivations, we review both theory and subsequent tests and provide some new applications. The consumption aggregation theorem and CCAPM are derived, and optimal consumption and portfolio strategies are discussed. The term structure of interest rates is derived from the term structures for expected growth, volatility, and inflation. Time aggregation biases in consumption betas as well as the usefulness of the "consumption-mimicking portfolio" are also derived. In addition to various empirical tests, models and tests of limited participation in asset markets as well as models of incomplete markets are presented. When certain measurement issues are taken into account, the CCAPM performs better than the original CAPM and nearly as well as the Fama-French three-factor model.</description><author>Reeden, Douglas T.; Litzenberger, Robert H.; Jia, Tingyan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance, Theoretical and Applied</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Like Caesar's Gaul, corporate finance is divided into three parts: theoretical, empirical, and normative. Important advances in any one of these three typically generate good ideas for the other two. I have been fortunate not to specialize in one part only. This review covers the history of capital structure theories, including the trade-off and pecking-order theories, and takes a skeptical view of how those theories have been tested so far. I give roughly equal space to normative, practical applications, including adjusted present value (APV), the valuation of real options, and the application of modern finance to regulation, insurance, the valuation of R&amp;D, and the role of risk capital in financial institutions. Looking back, I realize that the supply of intriguing financial questions is inexhaustible.</description><author>Myres, Stewart C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer-to-Peer Crowdfunding: Information and the Potential for Disruption in Consumer Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>TCan peer-to-peer lending (P2P) disintermediate and mitigate information frictions in lending so that choices and outcomes for at least some borrowers and investors are improved? I offer a framing of issues and survey the nascent literature on P2P. On the investor side, P2P disintermediates an asset class of consumer loans, and investors may be able to capture rents associated with the removal of a layer of financial intermediation. Risk and portfolio choice questions linger prior to any inference. On the borrower side, evidence suggests that proximate knowledge (direct or inferred) unearths soft information. Thus, P2P may be able to offer pricing and/or access benefits to potential borrowers. Early research suggests that the future of consumer lending will involve more big data and reintermediation of underwriting by all types of financial institutions. I ask many more questions than current research can answer, hoping to motivate future research.</description><author>Morse, Adair</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We review the recent literature on the financing of innovation, inclusive of large companies and new start-ups. This research strand has been very active over the past live years, generating important new findings, questioning some long-held beliefs, and creating its own puzzles. Our review outlines the growing body of work that documents a role for debt financing related to innovation. We highlight the new literature on learning and experimentation across multistage innovation projects and how this impacts optimal financing design. We further highlight the strong interaction between financing choices for innovation and changing external conditions, especially reduced experimentation costs.</description><author>Kerr, William R.; Nanda, Ramana</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disaster Risk and Its Implications for Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>After lying dormant for more than two decades, the rare disaster framework has emerged as a leading contender to explain facts about the aggregate market, interest rates, and financial derivatives. In this article, we survey recent models of disaster risk that provide explanations for the equity premium puzzle, the volatility puzzle, return predictability, and other features of the aggregate stock market. We show how these models can also explain violations of the expectations hypothesis in bond pricing as well as the implied volatility skew in option pricing. We review both modeling techniques and results and consider both endowment and production economies. We show that these models provide a parsimonious and unifying framework for understanding puzzles in asset pricing.</description><author>Tsai, Jerry; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Prices and Earnings: A History of Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Accounting earnings summarize periodic corporate financial performance and are key determinants of stock prices. We review research on the usefulness of accounting earnings, including research on the link between accounting earnings and firm value and research on the usefulness of accounting earnings relative to other accounting and nonaccounting information. We also review research on the features of accounting earnings that make them useful to investors, including the accrual accounting process, fair value accounting, and the conservatism convention. We finish by summarizing research that identifies situations in which investors appear to misinterpret earnings and other accounting information, leading to security mispricing.</description><author>Dechow, Patricia M.; Sloan, Richard G.; Zha, Jenny</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financialization of Commodity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The large inflow of investment capital to commodity futures markets in the past decade has generated a heated debate about whether financialization distorts commodity prices. Rather than focusing on the opposing views concerning whether investment flows caused a price bubble, we critically review academic studies through the perspective of how financial investors affect risk sharing and information discovery in commodity markets. We argue that financialization has substantially changed commodity markets through these mechanisms.</description><author>Cheng, Ing-Haw; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contingent Capital Instruments for Large Financial Institutions: A Review of the Literature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>As the recent financial crisis unfolded, a new financial instrument-contingent convertible (coco) bonds-was widely considered as a mechanism for promptly recapitalizing overlevered financial institutions. Essentially, the conversion feature of coco bonds would replace supervisory discretion about banks' capital adequacy with rules specifying when new equity was required. Academics and regulators conjectured that including sufficient cocos in a bank's capital structure could substantially insulate taxpayers from private investment losses. This potential fostered a literature evaluating the effect of cocos on bank and financial sector stability, risk-taking incentives, and corporate governance. I review this literature and suggest that regulatory capital definitions should be expanded to include substantial amounts of carefully designed coco bonds as a partial substitute for common equity in regulatory capital requirements.</description><author>Flannery, Mark J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Counterparty Risk: A Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review provides formal definitions of the terms credit value adjustment (CVA) and debt value adjustment (DVA). Estimating these quantities requires modeling the probabilities of default and the loss given default, recognizing the dependence structure among all these inputs. In practice, marginal distributions are used and a copula function assumed. Although it has long been known that different copula functions can produce very different price estimates, keeping marginal distributions constant, there is little empirical evidence about the appropriate form of function to use for modeling default dependence. This review discusses the use of collateral for risk mitigation and its effects on CVA. Regulators have argued that standardized contracts should be cleared through central counterparties (CCPs). However, there are arguments against CCPs.</description><author>Turnbull, Stuart M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Industrial Organization of the US Residential Mortgage Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We show that the US residential single-family mortgage-origination market is highly concentrated once account is taken of the contractual coordination that arises from the correspondent-and warehouse-funding channels. We represent these channels as a network, using the flow of loans through three strata of the loan origination market: origination, aggregation, and securitization. We develop a network representation of the origination market and demonstrate that it is a small world, in that most nodes are close in the network. We then rank-order the interlinked aggregators and securitizers using ex post mortgage foreclosure rates as a proxy for performance. Our findings suggest that these significant interlinkages in the mortgage-origination network represent a previously underappreciated source of systemic risk. Many apparently atomistic mortgage underwriters are, in fact, coordinated to act in parallel because of their funding relationships with the large, too-big-to-fail bank holding companies.</description><author>Stanton, Richard; Walden, Johan; Wallace, Nancy</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Flows to Asset Managers: Causes and Consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cash flows between investors and funds are both cause and effect in a complex web of economic decisions. Among the issues at stake are the prospects and fees of the funds, the efforts and risk choices by the funds' managers, the pricing and comovement of the assets they trade, the stability of the financial system and the real economy, and the retirement security and protection of the investors. There is an accordingly large and growing literature on flows that has concentrated on the main retail investment pool, the open-end mutual fund, and has used flows to explore many aspects of retail financial decision making. We survey this literature and, where relevant, describe how open-end flows compare to other investment vehicles. We also identify opportunities both for future research and for refinement of mutual fund design, in particular as suggested by the recent rethinking of retail investment pools in the European Union.</description><author>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Musto, David K.; Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange-Traded Funds: An Overview of Institutions, Trading, and Impacts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Exchange-traded funds (ETFs) have grown substantially in diversity and size in recent years, reflecting a broader shift toward passive, index investing. As a consequence, there is increased attention by investors, regulators, and academics seeking to assess and understand the implications of this rapid growth. This article provides a unified framework to examine these issues and review the research to date, demonstrating that ETFs have extended significant benefits to investors and to the functioning of markets that meaningfully outweigh any perceived or actual weaknesses.</description><author>Madhavan, Ananth</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Transmission in Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Because theories in finance rely critically on what agents know, designing powerful tests of these theories requires measuring information transmission. In this review, I characterize the rapidly growing subfield directly analyzing information in financial markets. Its three hallmarks are the examination of (a) a wide array of informative events, (b) different mechanisms for transmitting information, and (c) measures of information content based on nonnumeric information. Recent research directly measures flows of information to shed light on diverse phenomena in asset pricing, such as market reactions to news and nonnews, investors' portfolio choices, and mutual fund flows and returns, and in corporate finance, such as mergers and acquisitions, initial public offering (IPO) underpricing, and executive compensation. Continued improvements in access to data and computing power are likely to propel this line of research for years to come.</description><author>Tetlock, Paul C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider Trading Controversies: A Literature Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Using the artifice of a hypothetical trial, this article presents the cases for and against insider trading. Both sides in the trial produce as evidence the salient points made in more than 100 years of literature on insider trading. The initial days of the trial focus on the issues raised in the law literature such as fiduciary responsibility, the misappropriation theory, and the fairness and integrity of markets; however, the trial soon transfers focus to issues such as Pareto optimality, efficient contracting, market efficiency, and predictability raised in the financial economics literature. Open issues are then brought up. A jury finally hands down its verdict.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Security Market Manipulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article uses a variety of contemporary developments to address artificial market pricing and market manipulation. It examines a variety of modern trading tactics and manipulation strategies in the context of trading and order mechanics. For example, I raise the connection between so-called best execution, cancellation rates, and manipulation. I explore the connection between manipulation and short exposures as well as potential connections between Federal Reserve policies and artificial pricing. I also examine the nature of market manipulation in different facets of the trading day and the transitions among these.</description><author>Spatt, Chester</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forward Rate Curve Smoothing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews the forward rate curve smoothing literature. The key contribution of this review is to link the static curve fitting exercise to the dynamic and arbitrage-free models of the term structure of interest rates. As such, this review introduces more economics to an almost exclusively mathematical exercise, and it identifies new areas for research related to forward rate curve smoothing.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Exercise for Derivative Securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews the literature on American-style derivatives. The presentation stresses some of the major developments in the field. The focus is on the determination of optimal exercise policies and the structure of derivatives' prices. Illustrative examples highlight the complexity of the optimal exercise decision.</description><author>Detemple, Jerome</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Capital and Financial Stability: An Economic Trade-Off or a Faustian Bargain?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Financial crises impose large and persistent social costs, making banking stability important. This article reviews the central issues surrounding the role bank capital plays in financial stability. Because the socially efficient capital level may exceed banks' privately optimal capital levels, regulatory capital requirements become germane. But such requirements may entail various bank-level and social costs. Thus, despite agreement that higher capital would enhance banking stability, recognition of these costs has generated theoretical disagreement over whether capital requirements should be higher. Empirical evidence reveals that, in the cross section of banks, higher capital is associated with higher lending, higher liquidity creation, higher bank values, and higher probabilities of surviving crises. Moreover, increases in capital requirements are met with modest declines in lending. The overarching message from research is that lower capital in banking leads to higher systemic risk and a higher probability of a government-funded bailout that may elevate government debt and trigger a sovereign debt crisis. Thus, capital regulation reform, as well as tax policy, should seek to increase bank capital. This article discusses the contemporary thinking on these issues and concludes with open research questions.</description><author>Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Pension Plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews the rich and vast literature on defined-benefit (DB) corporate pension plans. The analysis of how firms react to the taxation and regulation of pension plans and to the guarantees provided by the government has allowed researchers to test alternative corporate finance theories, including risk-shifting and risk management. The difficulty in measuring the value of pension liabilities has motivated the study of whether such liabilities are reflected in the cost of capital and in the value of sponsoring firms. The study of the sponsoring firms' reaction to mandatory pension contribution has provided evidence on financing constraints and on the free-cash-flow hypothesis. Pension plan terminations and freezes have shed light on the nature of the employment contract between the firm and workers.</description><author>Cocco, Joao F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Liquidity Management: A Conceptual Framework and Survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ensuring that a firm has sufficient liquidity to finance valuable projects that occur in the future is at the heart of the practice of financial management. However, although discussion of these issues goes back at least to Keynes (1936), a substantial literature on the ways in which firms manage liquidity has developed only recently. We argue that many of the key issues in liquidity management can be understood through the lens of a framework in which firms face financial constraints and wish to ensure efficient investment in the future. We present such a model and use it to survey many of the empirical findings on liquidity management. In addition, we discuss agency-based theories of liquidity, the real effects of liquidity choices, and the impact of the 2008-2009 Financial Crisis on firms' liquidity management.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo; Cunha, Igor; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payout Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We survey the literature on payout policy, with a particular emphasis on developments in the past two decades. The cross-sectional empirical evidence for the traditional motivations behind firms paying out (agency, signaling, and taxes) is most persuasive with regard to agency considerations. Studies centered on the May 2003 dividend tax cut confirm that differences in the taxation of dividends and capital gains have only a second-order impact on setting payout policy. None of the three traditional explanations can account for secular changes in how payouts have been made over the past 30 years, during which repurchases have replaced dividends as the prime vehicle for corporate payouts. Other payout motivations, such as changes in compensation practices and management incentives, are better able to explain the observed variation in payout patterns over time than the traditional motivations. The most recent evidence suggests that further insights can be gained from viewing payout decisions as an integral part of a firm's larger financial ecosystem, with important implications for financing, investment, and risk management.</description><author>Farre-Mensa, Joan; Michaely, Roni; Schmalz, Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>History of American Corporate Governance: Law, Institutions, and Politics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article presents an overview of the history of corporate governance in the United States, emphasizing the period before the advent of federal securities laws and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). Recent research has overturned many widely accepted beliefs about corporate governance during this period. In particular, the evolution of American corporate governance has not followed a simple, linear trajectory, beginning with small, well-governed firms and ending with large, poorly governed ones. Over time, economic and institutional changes have given rise to successive generations of corporations with their own governance problems and their own mechanisms to address those problems. When existing governance mechanisms failed, the United States experienced corporate governance crises-episodes that shattered investors' faith in corporate management and the legal institutions intended to protect their rights. The resolutions of these crises have sometimes been found in legal innovations and, in other cases, in institutional or market-based solutions.</description><author>Hilt, Eric</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blockholders and Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This paper reviews the theoretical and empirical literature on the channels through which blockholders (large shareholders) engage in corporate governance. In classical models, blockholders exert governance through direct intervention in a firm's operations, otherwise known as "voice." These theories have motivated empirical research on the determinants and consequences of activism. More recent models show that blockholders can govern through an alternative mechanism known as "exit"-selling their shares if the manager underperforms. These theories give rise to new empirical studies on the two-way relationship between blockholders and financial markets, linking corporate finance with asset pricing. Blockholders may also worsen governance by extracting private benefits of control or pursuing objectives other than firm value maximization. I highlight the empirical challenges in identifying causal effects of and on blockholders as well as the typical strategies attempted to achieve identification. I close with directions for future research.</description><author>Edmans, Alex</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Takeovers and Economic Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>I review recent takeover research that advances our understanding of "who buys who" in the drive for productive efficiency. This research provides detailed information on text-based definitions of product market links between bidders and targets, the role of the supply chain and industrial networks in driving takeovers, target plant efficiency, and pre- and post-takeover investment in product innovation. Moreover, recent evidence adds to our understanding of "how firms are sold" (transaction efficiency). Almost half of takeovers involving public targets are initiated by the seller and not by the buyer. Targets are strongly averse to bidder toeholds, and the merger negotiation process strongly protects proprietary information. Takeover premiums leave traces of rational bidding strategies, including bid preemption and winner's curse avoidance. Recent tests employing exogenous instrumentation of bidder valuations reject that bidder shares are systematically overpriced in all-stock bids and suggest that bidder synergy gains are much larger than previously thought.</description><author>Eckbo, B. Espen</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short Selling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Short selling plays a unique role in financial markets. Short selling's institutional structure is distinct from other types of trades, and short sellers have been shown to be more informed than other types of traders. This review discusses short sellers' motivation, the institutional mechanics of short selling, the empirical findings on short selling, the regulation of short selling, the connection between corporate events and short selling, and the equity lending market. The review assesses the current direction of research as well as summarizes the current state of knowledge about the subject.</description><author>Reed, Adam V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Law and Finance: The Case of Constructive Sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review illustrates the interaction between law and finance in the particular case of the taxation of constructive sales. The focus is on the treatment of variable prepaid forward contracts and the rules regarding these instruments articulated by Revenue Ruling 2003-7 and the recent case involving Philip Anschutz (Anschutz Co. et al. v. Commissioner of Internal Revenue 2011). Simple models are used to show how the tests established by the law fail to reflect important financial considerations, such as the volatility of asset returns and the riskiness of dividend payments. These models provide examples that form the basis for a critique of the current rules and also indicate a possible path for future reform and improvement of the law, namely the addition of a delta-based test to the existing rules. The analysis presented here aims to encourage future work that applies financial theory to critique and improve legal rules in a wide range of other situations.</description><author>Brennan, Thomas J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Contagion and Network Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Network models of interbank exposures allow the mapping of the complex web of financial linkages among many institutions and address issues of system stability and contagion risk. Although existing models cover a fair amount of ground in explaining how network structure can lead to default cascades and in quantifying the likelihood and the impact of default cascades through balance-sheet mechanics, the literature has shortcomings in explaining how shocks are potentially amplified through the network of exposures. These amplification mechanisms seem to be very important in financial crises. This review discusses the main conceptual ideas behind network models of contagion, the major findings of this literature, as well as some limitations of existing models.</description><author>Summer, Martin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conglomerate Firms, Internal Capital Markets, and the Theory of the Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews the conglomerate literature, with a focus on recent papers that have cast strong doubt on the hypothesis that conglomerate firms destroy value on average when compared to similar stand-alone firms. Recent work has shown that investment decisions by conglomerate firms are consistent with value maximization; conglomerate firms trade at an average premium relative to single-segment firms when value weighting; and the valuation premia and discounts, both for conglomerates and single-segment firms, are driven by differences in the production of unique differentiated products. A profit-maximizing theory of the firm that considers how firms select their organizational structure can explain these recent findings and much of the large variation in findings in the conglomerate literature. We also review the literature showing how market imperfections create additional benefits and costs for internal capital markets and a potential for managerial distortions.</description><author>Maksimovic, Vojislav; Phillips, Gordon M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insurance Risk, Risk Measures, and Capital Allocation: Navigating a Copernican Shift</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We pursue two interrelated lines of thought. The first is a conceptual arc from (a) consideration of the unique characteristics of insurance risk, to (b) the quantification of this risk through risk measures, to (c) the application of these concepts to problems of allocating capital within an insurance company. The second is the identification and analysis of a dichotomy between prescriptive and descriptive approaches that appears in the study of each of the three previous components. In this way, we demonstrate the need for a Copernican shift from prescriptive solutions emphasizing the intrinsic characteristics of insurance loss random variables, to descriptive solutions accounting for both the properties of loss distributions and the economic and regulatory realities faced by insurance companies.</description><author>Powers, Michael R.; Zanjani, George</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Cross-Sectional Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>I review recent research efforts in the area of empirical cross-sectional asset pricing. I start by summarizing the evidence on cross-sectional return predictability and the failure of standard (consumption) capital asset pricing models (CAPMs) and their conditional versions to explain these predictability patterns. Part of the recent literature focuses on ad hoc factor models, which summarize the cross section of expected returns in parsimonious form, or on production-based approaches, which suggest links between firm characteristics and expected returns. Without imposing restrictions on investor preferences and beliefs, neither one of these two approaches can answer the question of why investors price assets the way they do. Within the rational expectations paradigm, recent research that imposes such restrictions has focused on the intertemporal CAPM (ICAPM), long-run risks models, as well as frictions and liquidity risk. Approaches based on investor sentiment have focused on the development of empirical proxies for sentiment and for the limits to arbitrage that allow sentiment to affect prices. Empirical work that considers learning and adaptation of investors has worked with out-of-sample tests of cross-sectional predictability.</description><author>Nagel, Stefan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to Volume 5 of the Annual Review of Financial Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>nan</description><author>Lo, Andrew W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fischer Black</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>nan</description><author>Merton, Robert C.; Scholes, Myron S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Merton's Model of the Firm's Capital Structure with Its Wide Applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Since its publication, the seminal structural model of default by Merton (1974) has become the workhorse for gaining insights about how firms choose their capital structure, a "bread and butter" topic for financial economists. Capital structure theory is inevitably linked to several important empirical issues such as (a) the term structure of credit spreads, (b) the level of credit spreads implied by structural models in relation to the ones that we observe in the data, (c) the cross-sectional variations in leverage ratios, (d) the types of defaults and renegotiations that one observes in real life, (e) the manner in which investment and financial structure decisions interact, (f) the link between corporate liquidity and corporate capital structure, (g) the design of capital structure of banks [contingent capital (CC)], (h) linkages between business cycles and capital structure, etc. The literature, building on Merton's insights, has attempted to tackle these issues by significantly enhancing the original framework proposed in his model to make the theoretical framework richer (by modeling frictions such as agency costs, moral hazard, bankruptcy codes, renegotiations, investments, state of the macroeconomy, etc.) and in greater accordance with stylized facts. In this review, I summarize these developments.</description><author>Sundaresan, Suresh</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Too Big to Fail: Causes, Consequences, and Policy Responses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Governments cannot credibly commit to eschew bailouts of creditors when large financial institutions become distressed. This too-big-to-fail (TBTF) problem distorts how markets price securities issued by TBTF firms, thus encouraging them to borrow too much and take too much risk. TBTF also encourages financial firms to grow, leading to competitive inequity and potential misallocation of credit. This review discusses evidence that such distortions are empirically relevant and also discusses the policy efforts to limit them. In the wake of the Financial Crisis of 2007-2008, it seems increased concentration in the financial industry has worsened the TBTF problem. Nevertheless, markets price the risks of large financial firms more now than before the Financial Crisis.</description><author>Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance: What's Special About Banks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review surveys the literature on the corporate governance of banks. Traditional corporate governance mechanisms, such as concentrated ownership and takeover threats, in principle, also apply to banks. However, banks have special traits and are heavily regulated, preventing natural forms of governance to arise and rendering many of these governance mechanisms ineffective. Financial regulation can in principle compensate for weaknesses in corporate governance but in practice has had limited effectiveness in protecting the interests of banks' stakeholders, because of, for instance, unproductive interactions between regulatory restraints and existing governance arrangements. The review concludes with a discussion of corporate governance and regulatory reforms to enhance the safety and soundness of banks. These proposals range from placing more emphasis on value creation for bank stakeholders other than shareholders to reducing risk-shifting incentives for bank managers and shareholders.</description><author>Laeven, Luc</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Rating Agencies: An Overview</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Credit rating agencies (CRAs) play a central role in the debt (bond) markets of many countries. CRAs have also attracted a considerable amount of public and policy attention during the past decade, especially with respect to their role in the financial crisis of 2008-2009 and their role in the more recent Eurozone difficulties. This article provides an overview of the CRAs: who they are, what they do, how their centrality to the financial markets came about, what their role in the financial crisis was, and the important aspects of the policy measures that have affected the CRAs.</description><author>White, Lawrence J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest Rates and the Bank Risk-Taking Channel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The recent global financial crisis has brought the debate on how interest rates affect bank risk-taking to center stage. Proponents of this new risk-taking channel of monetary policy have argued that the low interestrate environment in the run-up to the crisis may have created incentives for banks to take on excessive leverage and lower their lending standard, thus weakening bank portfolios. There is growing empirical evidence supporting this view. In contrast, this link has been little studied from a theoretical standpoint, leaving somewhat of a hole in our understanding of why (and how) banks' decisions concerning the overall risk of their portfolios, and their capital structures, may be influenced by changes in the interest rate environment and, by extension, policy choices (e.g., monetary policy) that affect it. We summarize some of the emerging literature on this topic (both empirical and theoretical), as well as some of the more classical work on related topics. We also present a simple model that illustrates various channels through which bank risk-taking is affected by the interest rate environment in which banks operate. We use that model to analyze the likely effect of various other forces. Given the wealth of evidence that interest rates may have a real effect through banks' portfolio decisions, it is important for policymakers to better understand the channel through which real interest rates operate on banks' decision-making.</description><author>Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Marquez, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>R-2 and the Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The characterization of firm-specific return volatility as the intensity with which firm-specific events occur reconciles many seemingly discordant results. A functionally efficient stock market allocates capital to its highest value uses, which often amounts to financing Schumpeterian creative destruction, wherein creative winner firms outpace destroyed losers, who could be the previous year's winners. This rise in firm-specific fundamentals volatility elevates firm-specific return volatility in a sufficiently informationally efficient stock market. These linkages are interconnected feedback loops rather than unidirectional chains of causality.</description><author>Morck, Randall; Yeung, Bernard; Yu, Wayne</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Microstructure and the Profitability of Currency Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Currency trading is a vast and highly profitable business. This review examines the profitability of two popular currency trading strategies in light of currency-market microstructure research. The carry-trade strategy involves borrowing a low-interest currency and investing the proceeds in a high-interest currency. Technical trading strategies are determined exclusively on the basis of past asset prices and trading volumes. Under the efficient markets hypothesis, neither of these approaches to speculative trading should produce excess returns. The review shows that the profitability of carry-trade investing and technical trading strategies can represent rational long-run equilibria given the structure of currency markets and the incentives and constraints faced by traders.</description><author>Osler, Carol</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodity Investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews the literature on commodities from the perspective of an investor. We re-examine some of the early papers in the literature using recent data and find that the empirical support for the theory of normal backwardation as an explanation for the commodity risk premium is weak and that the evidence is more consistent with storage decisions. We then review the behavior of the main participants in the commodity futures markets with a particular focus on their impact on prices. Although there is continued disagreement in the literature about the role of speculative activity, our results show that money managers are generally momentum (positive feedback) traders, while producers are net short and contrarian (negative feedback) traders. There is less evidence that index traders and swap dealers trade based on past futures returns.</description><author>Rouwenhorst, K. Geert; Tang, Ke</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Closed-End Funds: A Survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>New theories have emerged over the past 10 years that reveal CEFs to be an important and efficient organizational device. This review surveys the old and current literature on closed-end funds (CEFs) in general and theories of discounts in particular. Among the topics reviewed are liquidity transformation, the effects of tax overhang, the importance of managerial fees, the provision of leverage services, the impact of the potential irrationality of small investors on discounts, and rationality of CEFs' initial public offering (IPO) process.</description><author>Cherkes, Martin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes and Investment Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taxes have a first-order effect on investors' trading decisions and portfolio choices and on the equilibrium pricing of assets. In this review, we investigate how certain features of the tax code impact investors and asset markets. We begin by considering how tax heterogeneity across investors and across securities can lead to market segmentation and discuss the nature of equilibrium prices and allocations with tax clienteles. We then turn our attention to the optimal trading of assets when the tax on capital gains and losses is deferred until the asset is sold. In the absence of portfolio considerations, the optimal trading policies are driven entirely by the desire of investors to minimize the tax cost of owning assets. We next focus on an investor's lifetime portfolio choice problem with capital gains taxes and discuss how the investor's optimal trading decisions and portfolio choices are influenced by both tax and diversification motives. Our discussion includes consideration of nonfinancial income, tax-deferred investment opportunities, and multiple risky assets.</description><author>Dammon, Robert M.; Spatt, Chester S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption-Based Asset Pricing Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>A major research initiative in finance focuses on the determinants of the cross-sectional and time series properties of asset returns. With that objective in mind, asset pricing models have been developed, starting with the capital asset pricing models of Sharpe (1964), Lintner (1965), and Mossin (1966). Consumption-based asset pricing models use marginal rates of substitution to determine the relative prices of the date, event-contingent, composite consumption good. This model class is characterized by a stochastic discount factor process that puts restrictions on the joint process of asset returns and per capita consumption. This review takes a critical look at this class of models and their inability to rationalize the statistics that have characterized US financial markets over the past century. The intuition behind the discrepancy between model prediction and empirical data is explained. Finally, the research efforts to enhance the model's ability to replicate the empirical data are summarized.</description><author>Mehra, Rajnish</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Activity of Firms and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>In this review we survey the recent research on the fundamental determinants of stock returns. These studies explore how firms' systematic risk and their investment and production decisions are jointly determined in equilibrium. Models with production provide insights into several types of empirical patterns, including (a) the correlations between firms' economic characteristics and their risk premia, (b) the comovement of stock returns among firms with similar characteristics, and (c) the joint dynamics of asset returns and macroeconomic quantities. Moreover, by explicitly relating firms' stock returns and cash flows to fundamental shocks, models with production connect the analysis of financial markets with the research on the origins of macroeconomic fluctuations.</description><author>Kogan, Leonid; Papanikolaou, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effects of Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>A large amount of activity in the financial sector occurs in secondary financial markets, where securities are traded among investors without capital flowing to firms. The stock market is the archetypal example, which in most developed economies captures a lot of attention and resources. Is the stock market just a sideshow or does it affect real economic activity? In this review, we discuss the potential real effects of financial markets that stem from the informational role of market prices. We review the theoretical literature and show that accounting for the feedback effect from market prices to the real economy significantly changes our understanding of the price formation process, the informativeness of the price, and speculators' trading behavior. We make two main points. First, we argue that a new definition of price efficiency is needed to account for the extent to which prices reflect information that is useful for the efficiency of real decisions (rather than the extent to which they forecast future cash flows). Second, incorporating the feedback effect into models of financial markets can explain various market phenomena that otherwise seem puzzling. Finally, we review empirical evidence on the real effects of secondary financial markets.</description><author>Bond, Philip; Edmans, Alex; Goldstein, Itay</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implications of the Dodd-Frank Act</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>In this review, we provide an economic assessment of the Dodd-Frank Act of 2010 in terms of the likely efficacy of the financial-sector regulation it proposes. We focus in particular on its ability to contain systemic risk, the risk that many financial firms may fail en masse, and discuss the tools it employs. Namely, we examine enhanced capital requirements for systemically important financial firms, the separation of proprietary trading from bank holding companies (the Volcker rule), the resolution authority for orderly management of large complex financial institution (LCFI) failure, and attempts to contain risks in the shadow banking system. We relate the Act to its most important predecessor, the Banking Act of 1933, and consider the desirability and implications of the Dodd-Frank Act's all-encompassing approach to the reform of financial-sector architecture and regulation.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Richardson, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Annual Review of Financial Economics Preface</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>nan</description><author>Lo, Andrew W.; Merton, Robert C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation of Government Policies and Projects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Governments play a central role in the allocation of capital and risk in the economy. Evaluating the cost to taxpayers of government investments requires an assumption about the government's cost of capital. Governments often take their borrowing rate to be their cost of capital, which implicitly treats the market risk associated with their activities as having no cost to taxpayers. This article reviews the theoretical and practical rationale for treating market risk as a cost to governments, presents an interpretive review of the growing literature that applies the concepts and tools of modern finance to evaluating the costs of government policies and projects, and suggests directions for future research. Examples considered include deposit insurance, Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, the Federal Reserve's emergency lending facilities, student loans, real infrastructure investments, and public pension plans.</description><author>Lucas, Deborah</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impacts of Automation and High Frequency Trading on Market Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>In recent decades, US equity markets have changed from predominantly manual markets with limited competition to highly automated and competitive markets. These changes occurred earlier for NASDAQ stocks (primarily between 1994 and 2004) and later for NYSE-listed stocks (mostly following Reg NMS and the 2006 introduction of the NYSE hybrid market). This paper surveys the evidence of how these changes impacted market quality and shows that overall market quality has improved significantly, including bid-ask spreads, liquidity, and transitory price impacts (measured by short-term variance ratios). The greater improvement in market quality for NYSE-listed stocks relative to NASDAQ stocks beginning in 2006 suggests causal links between the staggered market structure changes and market quality. Using proprietary data sets, provided by two exchanges, that identify the activity of high frequency trading firms, studies show these firms contributed directly to narrowing bid-ask spreads, increasing liquidity, and reducing intraday transitory pricing errors and intraday volatility.</description><author>Litzenberger, Robert; Castura, Jeff; Gorelick, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shadow Banking Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shadow banks conduct credit intermediation without direct, explicit access to public sources of liquidity and credit guarantees. Shadow banks contributed to the credit boom in the early 2000s and collapsed during the financial crisis of 2007-2009. We review the quickly growing literature on shadow banking and provide a conceptual framework of shadow banking regulation. Since the collapse, regulatory reform efforts have aimed at strengthening the stability of the shadow banking system. We review these reform efforts for shadow funding sources including asset-backed commercial paper (ABCP), tri-party repurchase agreements (repos), money market mutual funds (MMMFs), and securitization. Despite significant effort by lawmakers, regulators, and accountants, there has been uneven progress in achieving a more stable shadow banking system.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Ashcraft, Adam B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Narrow Banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review discusses the history of narrow banks, reform proposals involving narrow banks, and theory and empirical evidence regarding whether narrow banks should play a more prominent role in the financial system. Prior to the early-twentieth century, US banks tended to be much narrower than they are today. Common modern banking practices, such as maturity transformation and explicit loan commitments, arose only after the creation of the Federal Reserve and the FDIC. My review of theory and empirical evidence finds it largely supportive of narrow bank reforms. Most importantly, a narrow-banking system could have huge advantages in containing moral hazard and reducing the overall risk and required regulation of the financial system.</description><author>Pennacchi, George</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Federal Reserve Liquidity Provision during the Financial Crisis of 2007-2009</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review examines the Federal Reserve's (or Fed's) unprecedented liquidity provision during the financial crisis of 2007-2009. It first reviews how the Fed provides liquidity in normal times. It then explains how the Fed's new and expanded liquidity facilities were intended to enable the central bank to fulfill its traditional lender-of-last-resort role during the crisis while mitigating stigma, broadening the set of institutions with access to liquidity, and increasing the flexibility with which institutions could tap such liquidity. The review then assesses the growing empirical literature on the effectiveness of the facilities and provides insights as to where further research is warranted.</description><author>Fleming, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Markets and the Law: A Predictable Past and an Uncertain Future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article analyzes the manifold situations in which the efficient-market hypothesis (EMH) has influenced-or has failed to influence-federal securities regulation and state corporate law, and the prospective roles for the EMH in these contexts. In federal securities regulation, the EMH has offered a theoretical construct to accompany the general belief in the value of accurate and complete information that has animated the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) since its creation. Specific applications of the EMH have been straightforward and predictable: For instance, its tenets as to market processing of public information helped motivate the streamlining of procedural requirements as to corporate disclosures and, more controversially, as to private securities class action lawsuits. In state corporate law, the EMH has influenced developments as to takeovers and the corporate objective. In contrast, the EMH and related learning have failed to sufficiently inform governmental actions to address financial illiteracy. Belief in the EMH and the value of efficient markets has weakened in the face of recent market anomalies and stress. The May 2010 flash crash is not easily reconciled with the EMH, and related phenomena such as high frequency trading involve an equity market microstructure far different from the microstructure at the time the EMH emerged. Actions motivated by the global financial crisis (GFC), such as the SEC short-selling ban in September 2008, arguably suggest a greater willingness to subordinate market efficiency in favor of other governmental goals. A range of important EMH-related issues loom beyond those associated with financial illiteracy, the equity market microstructure, and governmental goals. Foremost are those relating to the informational predicate on which market efficiency rests. One key aspect of the informational predicate relates to the disclosure challenges associated with financial innovations (such as asset-backed securities) and business entities heavily involved in financial innovation activities (such as certain money center banks). The "intermediary depiction model" that the SEC has always used is inadequate in financial innovation-related contexts. Another key aspect relates to the massive amounts of information that the Dodd-Frank Act requires to be provided to governmental bodies.</description><author>Hu, Henry T. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance of Financial Institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We identify the tension between dueling expectations of financial institutions as value-maximizing entities that also serve the public interest. We highlight the importance of information in addressing the public desire for banks to be safe yet innovative. Regulators can choose several approaches to increase market discipline and information production. Information production can be mandated outside of markets through increased regulatory disclosure. Regulators can also directly motivate potential producers of information by changing their incentives. Traditional approaches to bank governance may interfere with the information content of prices. Thus, the lack of transparency in the banking industry may be a symptom rather than the primary cause of bad governance. We provide examples of compensation and resolution. Reforms that promote the quality of security prices through information production can improve the governance of financial institutions. Future research is needed to examine the interactions between disclosure, information, and governance.</description><author>Mehran, Hamid; Mollineaux, Lindsay</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Finance and Financial Institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Many corporate finance researchers have avoided analyzing financial institutions, perhaps on the grounds that they are "unique" or "different" from other types of firms. This assessment reflects some unusual features of financial firms' liabilities and a set of governmental regulatory restrictions that have become less pervasive in recent years. In fact, corporate finance theory applies equally well to financial firms, although some modifications are required to recognize the effects of government safety and soundness regulation. Regulated firms' private incentives account for most of the difficulties regulators encounter when trying to craft appropriate oversight mechanisms.</description><author>Flannery, Mark J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Survey of Systemic Risk Analytics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We provide a survey of 31 quantitative measures of systemic risk in the economics and finance literature, chosen to span key themes and issues in systemic risk measurement and management. We motivate these measures from the supervisory, research, and data perspectives in the main text and present concise definitions of each risk measure-including required inputs, expected outputs, and data requirements-in an extensive Supplemental Appendix. To encourage experimentation and innovation among as broad an audience as possible, we have developed an open-source Matlab (R) library for most of the analytics surveyed, which, once tested, will be accessible through the Office of Financial Research (OFR) at http://www.treasury.gov/initiatives/wsr/ofr/Pages/default.aspx.</description><author>Bisias, Dimitrios; Flood, Mark; Lo, Andrew W.; Valavanis, Stavros</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign and Financial-Sector Risk: Measurement and Interactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The complex spillover effects between sectors observed during the global financial crisis and recent European crisis make clear the importance of improving our understanding of the interactions and feedback mechanisms between sovereign and banking-sector risks. To that end, this paper presents a conceptual framework for analyzing the sovereign, banks, and their interlinkages based on contingent claims analysis (CCA). Our bank-by-bank framework uses balance-sheet data plus high-frequency market data in a way that measures risk exposures and can capture key risk transmission and feedbacks with the sovereign in real time. Risk transmission between banks and sovereigns can arise in the framework from several important sources: (a) bank holdings of risky sovereign debt, (b) explicit and implicit guarantees from sovereigns to banks, and (c) spillovers from sovereign spreads into bank borrowing costs. We illustrate the framework with several examples and ways forward to analyze multicountry sovereign and banking interactions.</description><author>Gray, Dale F.; Malone, Samuel W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regime Changes and Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Regime-switching models can match the tendency of financial markets to often change their behavior abruptly and the phenomenon that the new behavior of financial variables often persists for several periods after such a change. Although the regimes captured by regime-switching models are identified by an econometric procedure, they often correspond to different periods in regulation, policy, and other secular changes. In empirical estimates, the means, volatilities, autocorrelations, and cross-covariances of asset returns often differ across regimes in a manner that allows regime-switching models to capture the stylized behavior of many financial series including fat tails, heteroskedasticity, skewness, and time-varying correlations. In equilibrium models, regimes in fundamental processes, such as consumption or dividend growth, strongly affect the dynamic properties of equilibrium asset prices and can induce non-linear risk-return trade-offs. Regime switches also lead to potentially large consequences for investors' optimal portfolio choice.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Timmermann, Allan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payment Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Modern payment instruments can be complex. Yet, many of these can be interpreted as a form of money or credit, which are rather primitive instruments. We use a simple model of a monetary economy to provide an overview of some of the fundamental questions in the literature on payments. Why do agents pay? What are the frictions that prevent or limit the use of credit arrangements? Why is fiat money valued? Why do money and credit coexist? Our simple model can address these basic and important questions, and can be extended to address a variety of issues related to payments.</description><author>McAndrews, James; Nosal, Ed; Rocheteau, Guillaume</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Consequences of Financial Innovation: A Counterfactual Research Agenda</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Financial innovation has been both praised as the engine of growth of society and castigated for being the source of the weakness of the economy. In this paper, we review the literature on financial innovation and highlight the similarities and differences between financial innovation and other forms of innovation. We also propose a research agenda to systematically address the social welfare implications of financial innovation. To complement existing empirical and theoretical methods, we propose that scholars examine case studies of systemic (widely adopted) innovations, explicitly considering counterfactual histories had the innovations never been invented or adopted.</description><author>Lerner, Josh; Tufano, Peter</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Financial markets have become increasingly global in recent decades, yet the pricing of internationally-traded assets continues to depend strongly Upon local risk factors, leading to Several observations that are difficult to explain with standard frameworks. Equity returns depend upon both domestic and global risk factors. Further, local investors tend to overweight their asset portfolios in local equity. The stock prices of firms that begin to trade across borders increase in response to this information. Foreign exchange-markers also display anomalous relationships. The forward rate, predicts the wrong sign of future movements in the exchange rate, implying that traders can make profits by borrowing at lower interest rate currencies and investing in higher interest rate,currencies. Furthermore, the sign of the foreign exchange premium changes over time, a fact difficult to reconcile with consumption variability. In this review, I describe the implications of the,Current body of research for addressing these and other global asset pricing challenges.</description><author>Lewis, Karen K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Microfinance and Social Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review puts a corporate finance lens on microfinance. Microfinance aims to democratize global financial markets through new contracts, organizations, and technology. We explain the roles that government agencies and socially minded investors play in supporting the entry and expansion of private intermediaries in the sector, and we disentangle debates about competing social and commercial firm goals. We frame the analysis with theory that explains why microfinance institutions serving lower-income communities charge high interest rates, face high costs, monitor customers relatively intensively, and have limited ability to lever assets. The analysis blurs traditional dividing lines between nonprofits and for-profits and places focus on the relationship between target market, ownership rights, and access to external capital.</description><author>Conning, Jonathan; Morduch, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and Governance in Developing Economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Classic Big Push industrialization envisions state planners coordinating economic activity to internalize a range of externalities that otherwise lock in a low-income equilibrium, but runs afoul of well-known government failure problems. Successful Big Push coordination may occur instead when a large business group, acting in its controlling shareholder's self-interest, coordinates the establishment and expansion of businesses in diverse sectors. Where business groups play this role, many basic axioms of Anglo-American corporate governance, including the advocacy of shareholder value maximization and contestable corporate control, must be qualified.</description><author>Morck, Randall</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium in the Initial Public Offerings Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>In this survey, I criticize the ability of popular asymmetric information-based models to explain the magnitude of the underpricing of initial public offerings (IPOs) that is observed. I suggest that the quantitative magnitude of underpricing can be explained with a market structure in which underwriters want to underprice excessively, issuers are focused on services bundled with underwriting rather than on maximizing the offer proceeds, and there is limited competition between underwriters. Since the technology bubble burst in 2000, U.S. IPO volume has been low. Although regulatory burdens undoubtedly account for some of the decline, I suggest that much of the decline may be due to a structural shift that has lessened the profitability of small independent companies relative to their value as part of a larger, more established organization that can realize economies of scope. I also discuss the long-run performance literature. My interpretation of the evidence is that except for the smallest companies going public, IPOs have long-run returns that are similar to those on seasoned stocks with the same characteristics.</description><author>Ritter, Jay R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Empirical Capital Structure Research and Directions for the Future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews empirical capital structure research, concentrating on papers published since 2005. We begin by documenting three dimensions of capital structure variation: cross firm, cross industry, and within firm through time. We summarize how well the traditional trade-off and pecking order approaches explain these sources of variation and highlight their empirical shortcomings. We review recent research that attempts to address these shortcomings, much of which follows seven broad themes: (a) Important variables have been mismeasured in empirical tests, (b) the impact of leverage on non-financial stakeholders is important, (c) the supply side of capital affects corporate capital structure, (d) richer features of financial contracts have been underresearched, (e) value effects due to capital structure appear to be modest over wide ranges of leverage, (f) estimates of leverage adjustment speeds are biased, and (g) capital structure dynamics have not been adequately considered. Much progress has been made in addressing these issues, some of which has led to the study of an expanded range of capital structure topics, including debt maturity, loan and covenant characteristics, collateral effects, and alternative financing sources such as leasing and credit lines. We conclude by summarizing unanswered questions and areas for future research.</description><author>Graham, John R.; Leary, Mark T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Intermediary Balance Sheet Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conventional discussions of balance sheet management by nonfinancial firms take the set of positive net present value (NPV) projects as given, which in turn determines the size of the firms assets. The focus is on the composition of equity and debt in funding such assets. In contrast, the balance sheet management of financial intermediaries reveals that it is equity that behaves like the predetermined variable, and the asset size of the bank or financial intermediary is determined by the degree of leverage that is permitted by market conditions. The relative stickiness of equity reveals possible nonpecuniary benefits to bank owners so that they are reluctant to raise new equity, even during boom periods when raising equity is associated with less stigma and, hence, smaller discounts. We explore the empirical evidence for both market-based financial intermediaries such as the Wall Street investment banks, as well as the commercial bank subsidiaries of the large U.S. bank holding companies. We further explore the aggregate consequences of such behavior by the banking sector for the propagation of the financial cycle and securitization.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Shin, Hyun Song</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Credit Default Swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Credit default swaps (CDS) are term insurance contracts written on traded bonds. This paper studies the economics of CDS using the economics of insurance literature as a basis for analysis. It is alleged that trading in CDS caused the 2007 credit crisis, and therefore trading CDS is an "evil" which needs to be eliminated or controlled. In contrast, we argue that the trading of CDS is welfare increasing because it facilitates a more optimal allocation of risks in the economy. To perform this function, however, the risk of CDS seller failure needs to be minimized. In this regard, government regulation imposing stricter collateral requirements and higher equity capital for CDS traders need to be imposed.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government Policy and the Fixed-Rate Mortgage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>A central argument in the ongoing discussion about the fates of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac is the importance of the 30-year, fixed-rate, prepayable mortgage (FRM). The FRM has been held up as the gold standard in mortgage instrument design and as an essential element of the U.S. housing-finance system. Supporters of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac argue that a government guarantee eliminating credit risk is essential to ensuring the FRM remains the main instrument for housing finance. The FRM has benefits for the consumer through payment stability and the right to prepay the mortgage without penalty. But these benefits come at significant cost. The interest rate and prepayment risk in the FR/vI are costly and difficult for investors to manage. There is a premium for both the long term and the prepayment options that are paid by all users of the mortgage. The FRM causes instability in the mortgage market through periodic refinancing waves. The FRM can create negative equity in an environment of falling house prices. And the taxpayers are on the hook for hundreds of billions of dollars in losses backing the credit risk guarantees provided by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to support securities backed by the FRM. International experience suggests that mortgage markets work fine without an FRM (only Denmark has an equivalent instrument). Borrowers rarely stay with the same mortgage for 15-30 years. Shorter-term fixed-rate mortgages would be less expensive than the FRM in most interest rate environments, particularly if lenders were allowed to charge prepayment penalties. The taxpayer is exposed to too much risk in supporting Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to justify continued government support for a product for which the costs outweigh the benefits.</description><author>Lea, Michael; Sanders, Anthony B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation and Risk Management of Collateralized Debt Obligations and Related Securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Over the course of a few decades, asset securitization has evolved into a vast and diverse financial instrument. Bases for the marketability of these securities are valuation and risk management techniques allowing for reasonable pricing formulas and hedging schemes. Therefore, a key issue is the modeling of cash flows of a portfolio of assets as well as the statistical modeling of uncertainties of such cash flows in the future. This article reviews some aspects of so-called collateralized debt obligations (CDOs) and related instruments. The modeling of underlying credit risks plays an important role in this context. As such, this review naturally has a special focus on the modeling of structured credit portfolios.</description><author>Bluhm, Christian; Wagner, Christoph</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Origins and Evolution of the Market for Mortgage-Backed Securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The first mortgage-backed security (MBS) was issued in 1968. Thereafter, the MBS market grew rapidly with outstanding issuances exceeding $9 trillion by 2010. The growth in the MRS market was accompanied by numerous innovations such as collateralized mortgage obligations (CMOs) and the emergence of private label alternatives to MBS issued by government-sponsored entities. We trace the evolution of the MBS market and we review debates surrounding such questions as whether the MBS market has reduced the cost of housing finance, whether the MBS market is a market for lemons, and what role, if any, MBS played in the run-up and subsequent decline of home prices during the decade of the 2000s. We also detail the evolution of models for MBS valuation as developed by academics and practitioners.</description><author>McConnell, John J.; Buser, Stephen A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review surveys the literature on the economics of mutual funds in general, and open-end mutual funds in particular. This mutual fund design has been very successful, though it carries risks that have recently been realized at large scales. If also frustrates the analysis of performance in ways only recently appreciated. Among, the topics reviewed are tax efficiency, transactions costs, risk shifting, window dressing, governance, marketing, price setting, and concerns that arise at the family level.</description><author>Musto, David K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation-Indexed Bonds and the 7 Expectations Hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review empirically analyzes the expectations hypothesis (EH) in inflation-indexed (or real) bonds and in nominal bonds in the United States and in the United Kingdom. We strongly reject the EH in inflation-indexed bonds, and also confirm and update the existing evidence rejecting the EH in nominal bonds. This rejection implies that the risk premium on both real and nominal bonds varies predictably over time. We also find strong evidence that the spread between the nominal and the real bond risk premium, or the breakeven inflation risk premium, also varies over time. We argue that the time variation in real bond risk premia most likely reflects both a changing real interest rate risk premium and a changing liquidity risk premium, and that the variability in the nominal bond risk premia reflects a changing inflation risk premium. We estimate significant time series variability in the magnitude and sign of bond risk premia.</description><author>Pflueger, Carolin E.; Viceira, Luis M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Money markets offer monetary services and short-term finance in; the capital Market with the credit support Of institutional sponsors. Investors finance money market instruments' at low interest because their salability on short notice confers an implicit monetary services yield. Low interest attracts borrowers to money markets. The fragile,equilibrium depends on collective confidence in the credit quality of instruments supplied to the market. Federal Reserve monetary and credit policies have influenced interest rates and credit intermediated in the money market, especially during the credit turmoil. Permissive regulatory rulings' have alllowed borrowers to take increasing advantage of low interest funding in money markets via securitization and structured finance-vastly increasing maturity, credit, and liquidity transformation through asset-backed commercial paper, repurchase agreements, and money marker mutual funds. Funding in such instruments and runs on these instruments, helped to create the credit cycle that culminated, in the turmoil, of 2007-2009.</description><author>Goodfriend, Marvin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rediscovering the Macroeconomic Roots of Financial Stability Policy: Journey, Challenges, and a Way Forward</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The recent financial crisis has triggered a major rethink of analytical approaches and policy towards financial stability. The crisis has encouraged a sharper focus on systemic risk, the inclusion of a financial sector in macroeconomic models, a shift from a microprudential to a macroprudential orientation in regulation and supervision, and questions about whether price stability is a sufficient criterion to guide monetary policy. In the process, it has led to a rediscovery of the macroeconomic roots of financial instability. This paper argues that this development is welcome but has not gone far enough. To substantiate this conclusion, the paper documents this analytical and policy journey before suggesting a way forward.</description><author>Borio, Claudio</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking Crises: A Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review surveys the theoretical and empirical literature on the causes and consequences of banking crises, and summarizes the lessons learned from policy interventions to resolve banking crises. Despite their different origins, banking crises display similar patterns. Their causes lie in unsustainable macroeconomic policies, market failures, regulatory distortions, and government interference in the allocation of capital; they are frequently characterized by boom-bust cycles in credit and asset prices; and they are generally resolved through large-scale government intervention. When not handled effectively and swiftly, banking crises tend to impose enormous costs to society by curtailing the flow of credit to the real economy. The article concludes with a review of proposals to enhance financial stability in an increasingly integrated financial system, which include making banking regulation more macroprudential-focusing on the cycle and systemic risk rather than the risk of individual banks-and improving market discipline by limiting explicit and implicit government insurance of bank liabilities.</description><author>Laeven, Luc</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>My Life in Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>I was invited by the editors to contribute a professional autobiography for the Annual Review of Financial Economics. I focus on what I think is my best stuff. Readers interested in the rest can download my vita from the website of the University of Chicago, Booth School of Business. I only briefly discuss ideas and their origins, to give the flavor of context and motivation. I do not attempt to review the contributions of others, which is likely to raise feathers. Mea culpa in advance. Finance is the most successful branch of economics in terms of theory and empirical work, the interplay between the two, and the penetration of financial research into other areas of economics and real-world applications. I have been doing research in finance almost since its start, when Markowitz (1952, 1959) and Modigliani &amp; Millar (1958) set the field on the path to becoming a serious scientific discipline. It has been fun to see it all, to contribute, and to be a friend and colleague to the giants who created the field.</description><author>Fama, Eugene E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictability of Returns and Cash Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We review the literature on return and cash flow growth predictability form the perspective of the present-value identity. We focus predominantly on recent work. Our emphasis is on U.S. aggregate stock return predictability, but we also discuss evidence from other asset classes and countries.</description><author>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>There is substantial evidence that indicates that stocks that perform, the best (worst) over a three- to 12-month period tend to continue to perform well (poorly) over, the subsequent three to 12 months. Until recently,,trading strategies that exploit this phenomenon were consistently profitable in the United States and in Most developed,markets. Similarly; stocks with high earnings momentum,. outperform stocks with low, earnings momentum. This article reviews the momentum literature and discusses some of the explanations for this phenomenon.</description><author>Jegadeesh, Narasimhan; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Carry Trade and Momentum in Currency Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We examine the empirical properties of the payoffs to two popular currency speculation strategies: the carry trade and momentum. We review three possible explanations for the apparent profitability of these strategies. The first is that speculators are being compensated for bearing risk. The second is that these strategies are vulnerable to rare disasters or peso problems. The third is that there is price pressure in currency markets.</description><author>Burnside, Craig; Eichenbaum, Martin; Rebelo, Sergio</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance Measurement of Mutual Funds, Hedge Funds, and Institutional Accounts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review describes several important recent advances in the measurement of the performance of actively managed portfolios. For returns-based performance evaluation we discuss several innovations, such as conditional performance evaluation, Bayesian approaches, and a new multiple testing approach-the false-discovery rate. For portfolio holdings based performance evaluation, our discussion ranges from extensions of the standard Daniel, Grinblatt, Titman, and Wermers (DGTW) stock return adjustment procedure to conditional holdings-based approaches. Applications of these approaches in the mutual fund, hedge fund, and institutional account universes are presented.</description><author>Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Theory: As I Still See It</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This essay summarizes my views on (a) the foundations of portfolio theory and its applications to current issues, such as the choice of criteria for practical risk-return analysis, and whether some form of risk-return analysis should be used in fact; (b) hypotheses about actual financial behavior, as opposed to idealized rational behavior, including two proofs of the fact that expected-utility maximizers would never prefer a multiple-prize lottery to all single-prize lotteries, as asserted in one of my 1952 papers; and (c) a simple proof of the theorem (which was initially greeted with some skepticism, especially by referees) that investors in capital asset pricing models do not get paid for bearing risk.</description><author>Markowitz, Harry M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bayesian Portfolio Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This paper reviews the literature on Bayesian portfolio analysis. Information about events, macro conditions, asset pricing theories, and security-driving forces can serve as useful priors in selecting optimal portfolios. Moreover, parameter uncertainty and model uncertainty are practical problems encountered by all investors. The Bayesian framework neatly accounts for these uncertainties, whereas standard statistical models often ignore them. We review Bayesian portfolio studies when asset returns are assumed both independently and identically distributed as well as predictable through time. We cover a range of applications, from investing in single assets and equity portfolios to mutual and hedge funds. We also outline challenges for future work.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-Sectional Asset Pricing Tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>A major problem in finance is to understand why different financial assets earn vastly different returns on average. In this paper, we survey various econometric approaches that have been developed to empirically examine various asset pricing models used to explain the difference in cross section of security returns. The approaches range from regressions to the generalized method of moments, and the associated asset pricing models are both conditional and unconditional. In addition, we review some of the major empirical studies.</description><author>Jagannathan, Ravi; Schaumburg, Ernst; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This paper surveys, the recent literature on CEO compensation. The rapid rise in CEO pay over the past 30 years has sparked an intense debate about the nature of the pay-setting process. Many view the high level of CEO compensation as the result of powerful managers setting their own pay. Others interpret high pay as the result of optimal contracting in a competitive market for managerial talent. We describe and discuss the empirical evidence on the evolution of CEO pay and on the relationship between pay and firm performance since the 1930s. Our review suggests that both managerial power and competitive market forces are important determinants of CEO pay, but that neither approach is fully consistent with the available evidence. We briefly discuss promising directions for future research.</description><author>Frydman, Carola; Jenter, Dirk</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder Voting and Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews recent research into corporate voting and elections. Regulatory reforms have given shareholders more voting power in the election of directors and in executive compensation issues. Shareholders use voting as a channel of communication with boards of directors, and protest voting can lead to significant changes in corporate governance and strategy. Some investors have embraced innovative empty voting strategies for decoupling voting rights from cash flow rights, enabling them to mount aggressive programs of shareholder activism. Market-based methods have been used by researchers to establish the value of voting rights and show how this value can vary in different settings.</description><author>Yermack, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Informal Perspective on the Economics and Regulation of Securities Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review uses an economic lens to offer perspectives on securities regulation. We discuss several motives for regulation and highlight some facets of regulatory conflict, competition, and coordination as well as the range of required securities market disclosures. We discuss the roles of economics and cost-benefit analysis in regulation under administrative law as well as "counting" and "line-drawing" exercises and the nature of the "unintended consequences" of regulation. Among the specific examples of securities regulation that the review highlights using economic principles are short-sale regulation (including the economic costs associated with short interest) and enforcement sanctions against corporations. We also note some of the successes (options backdating) and failures (Madoff and mutual fund market timing) of the securities regulator in identifying new enforcement challenges. This review concludes by highlighting the importance of regulatory uncertainty and time-consistent policies and applies this principle to several contexts related to the financial crisis.</description><author>Spatt, Chester S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privatization and Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This paper summarizes research examining how privatization programs implemented by governments over the past three decades have changed the size and efficiency of global financial markets, altered the practice of corporate finance in economies that experienced large privatizations, and impacted the returns earned by individual investors who purchased stock in a privatized company. I show how sales programs have changed during the three historical eras of privatization, describe the principal methods that governments use to sell state-owned enterprises (SOEs) to private investors, and examine how governments choose between selling SOEs directly to existing operating companies or investor groups through direct sales (asset sales) and selling stock to investors through share issue privatizations (SIPs). I document and examine the role privatization has played in increasing the total market capitalization of global stock exchanges from $3.2 trillion in 1983 to over $62 trillion in 2007. I show that investors have benefited from purchasing SIP shares, both in the short and long term, and attempt to answer the critical question: What do governments have left to sell?</description><author>Megginson, William</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This review article describes recent literature on asset allocation, covering both static and dynamic models. The article focuses on the bond-stock decision and on the implications of return predictability. In the static setting, investors are assumed to be Bayesian, and the role of various prior beliefs and specifications of the likelihood are explored. In the dynamic setting, recursive utility is assumed, and attention is paid to obtaining analytical results when possible. Results under both full- and limited-information assumptions are discussed.</description><author>Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment Performance Evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article provides a review of the rapidly developing literature on investment performance evaluation. The goals are to summarize the significant forces and contributions that have brought this field of research to its current state of knowledge and to suggest directions for future research. This review is written for a reader who is familiar with financial economics but not the specific literature and who wishes to become familiar with the current state of the art. Suggestions for future research include refinements to portfolio holdings-based performance measures, a more balanced treatment of costs, and clientele-specific measures of investment performance.</description><author>Ferson, Wayne E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Martingale Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The fact that properly normalized asset prices are martingales is the basis of modern asset pricing. One normalizes asset prices to adjust for risk and time preferences. Both adjustments can be made simultaneously via a stochastic discount factor, or one can adjust for risk by changing probabilities and adjust for time using the return on an asset, for example, the risk-free return. This paper reviews this methodology and the circumstances in which it is feasible. Three examples are given to illustrate the delicate link in continuous-time models between the absence of arbitrage opportunities and the feasibility of martingale pricing.</description><author>Back, Kerry</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limits of Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We survey theoretical developments in the literature on the limits of arbitrage. This literature investigates how costs faced by arbitrageurs can prevent them from eliminating mispricings and providing liquidity to other investors. Research in this area is currently evolving into a broader agenda, emphasizing the role of financial institutions and agency frictions for asset prices. This research has the potential to explain so-called market anomalies and inform welfare and policy debates about asset markets. We begin with examples of demand shocks that generate mispricings, arguing that they can stem from behavioral or from institutional considerations. We next survey, and nest within a simple model, the following costs faced by arbitrageurs: (a) risk, both fundamental and nonfundamental; (b) short-selling costs; (c) leverage and margin constraints; and (d) constraints on equity capital. We finally discuss implications for welfare and policy and suggest directions for future research.</description><author>Gromb, Denis; Vayanos, Dimitri</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic Processes in Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stochastic processes arising in the description of the risk-neutral evolution of equity prices are reviewed. Starting with Brownian motion, I review extensions to Levy and Sato processes. These processes have independent increments; the former are homogeneous in time, whereas the latter are inhomogeneous. One-dimensional Markov processes such as local volatility and local Levy are discussed next. Finally, I take up two forms of stochastic volatility that are due to either space scaling or time changing. An encompassing discrete-time model closes the presentation.</description><author>Madan, Dilip B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity and Asset Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The Ellsberg paradox suggests that people's behavior is different in risky situations when they are given objective probabilities from their behavior in ambiguous situations when they are not told the odds (as is typical in financial markets). Such behavior is inconsistent with subjective expected utility (SEU) theory, the standard model of choice under uncertainty in financial economics. This article reviews models of ambiguity aversion. It shows that such models in particular, the multiple-priors model of Gilboa and Schmeidler-have implications for portfolio choice and asset pricing that are very different from those of SEU and that help to explain otherwise puzzling features of the data.</description><author>Epstein, Larry G.; Schneider, Martin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Modern risk management systems were developed in the early 1990s to provide centralized risk measures at the top level of financial institutions. These are based on a century of theoretical developments in risk measures. In particular, value at risk (VAR) has become widely used as a statistical measure of market risk based on current positions. This methodology has been extended to credit risk and operational risk. This article reviews the benefits and limitations of these models. In spite of all these advances, risk methods are poorly adapted to measure liquidity risk and systemic risk.</description><author>Jorion, Philippe</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preface to the Annual Review of Financial Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>nan</description><author>Lo, Andrew W.; Merton, Robert C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Enjoyable Life Puzzling Over Modern Finance Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This is a terse account of group creation of modern finance theory; and a sampling of my prosaic autobiographical investing and consulting for nonprofit academies. Eschewing 1900 Bachelier and 1905 Einstein white noise randomness, my martingale version of market micro efficiency invoked no violation of economic law. My attempts to establish pricing theory for options fell a bit short of the Black-Scholes-Merton Holy Grail. For life cycle investing, mathematicians' maximum growth Kelly criterion was debunked, as were vulgar notions that necessarily riskiness is averaged downward for long-term investors. Popular Markowitz-Tobin quadratic programming was shown to hold generically only for smallest price variations or for unrealistic risk-aversion functions. Because economic history at best obeys only quasi-stationary probabilities, no sure-thing formulas will ever be definable. Excess returns-excess "alphas"-can result only from early new "insider" knowledge, however acquired-legally or illegally. Boo hoo. An irrational passion for dispassionate rationality can take the pleasure out of life.</description><author>Samuelson, Paul A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Risk Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This paper reviews the literature on credit risk models. Topics included are structural and reduced form models, incomplete information, credit derivatives, and default contagion. It is argued that reduced form models and not structural models are appropriate for the pricing and hedging of credit-risky securities. Directions for future research are discussed.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Term Structure of Interest Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This paper reviews the term structure of interest rates literature relating to the arbitrage-free pricing and hedging of interest rate derivatives. Term structure theory is emphasized. Topics included are the HJM model, forward and futures contracts, the expectations hypothesis, and the pricing of caps/floors. Directions for future research are discussed.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Crises: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Financial crises have occurred for many centuries. They are often preceded by a credit boom and a rise in real estate and other asset prices, as in the current crisis. They are also often associated with severe disruption in the real economy. This paper surveys the theoretical and empirical literature on crises. The first explanation of banking crises is that they are a panic. The second is that they are part of the business cycle. Modeling crises as a global game allows the two to be unified. With all the liquidity problems in interbank markets that have occurred during the current crisis, there is a growing literature on this topic. Perhaps the most serious market failure associated with crises is contagion, and there are many papers on this important topic. The relationship between asset price bubbles, particularly in real estate, and crises is discussed at length.</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Babus, Ana; Carletti, Elena</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Financial Crises and Sovereign Risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>The complex interactions, spillovers, and feedbacks of the global crisis that began in 2007 remind us of how important it is to improve our analysis and modeling of financial crises and sovereign risk. This review provides a broad framework to examine how vulnerabilities can build up and suddenly erupt in a financial crisis, with potentially disastrous feedback effects for sovereign debt and economic growth. Traditional macroeconomic analyses overlook the importance of risk, which makes them ill-suited to examine interconnectedness, risk transmission mechanisms, and contagion. After presenting in overview of the key features of the global 2007-2009 crisis, this review discusses new directions for research on modeling financial crises and sovereign risk, including the need for integrating risk into macroeconomic policy models and enhancing early warning system and financial contagion models through a more comprehensive view of economy-wide risks. Also, new tools to mitigate and control macro risk need to be developed, along with new approaches to,regulate financial sector risk-taking and monitor and manage the interactions between private sector and sovereign risk.</description><author>Gray, Dale E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Never Waste a Good Crisis: An Historical Perspective on Comparative Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Different economics at different times use different institutional arrangements to constrain the people entrusted with allocating capital and other resources. Comparative financial histories show these corporate governance regimes to be largely stable through time, but capable of occasional dramatic change in response to a severe crisis. Legal origin, language, culture, religion, accidents of history (path dependence), and other factors affect these changes because they affect how people and societies solve problems.</description><author>Morck, Randall; Yeung, Bernard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Market-Driven Corporate Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Much of empirical corporate finance focuses on sources of the demand for various forms of capital, not the supply. Recently this, has changed. Supply effects of equity and credit markets can arise from a combination of three ingredients: investor tastes limited, intermediation, and corporate opportunism. Investor tastes when combined with imperfectly competitive intermediaries lead prices and interest rates to deviate from fundamental values. Opportunistic firms respond by issuing securities with high prices and investing the proceeds. A link between capital market prices and corporate finance can in principle come from either supply or demand. This framework helps to organize empirical approaches that more precisely identify and quantify supply effects through variation in one of these three ingredients. Taken as a whole, the evidence shows that shifting equity and credit market conditions play an important role in dictating corporate finance and investment.</description><author>Baker, Malcolm</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Contracting: A Survey of Empirical Research and Future Directions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We review recent evidence and future directions for empirical research on financial contracting in the context of corporate finance. Specifically, we survey evidence pertaining to incentive conflicts, control rights, collateral, renegotiation, and interactions between financial contracts and other governance mechanisms. We also discuss directions for future research, concluding that the financial contracting approach offers a potentially fruitful perspective for empirical researchers seeking to better understand a variety of issues in corporate finance including capital structure, investment policy, payout policy, and corporate governance.</description><author>Roberts, Michael R.; Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Although consumer finance is a substantial element of the economy, it has had a smaller footprint within financial economics In. this review, I suggest a functional definition of the subfield of consumer finance, focusing on four key functions: payments, risk management, moving funds from today to tomorrow (saving/investing), and from tomorrow to today (borrowing). I provide data showing the economic importance of consumer finance in the American economy. I propose a historical explanation for its relative lack of attention by financial economists and in business school curricula based on historic geographic and gender splits between business and consumer studies. I review the literature in consumer finance, organized by its focus on the consumer, financial institutions, and the government. This work is spread out between economics, marketing, psychology, sociology, technology, and public policy. Finally, I suggest a number of open research questions.</description><author>Tufano, Peter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Life-Cycle Finance and the Design of Pension Plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article reviews recent scientific literature on consumer financial decisions over the life cycle, outlining its implications for the design of pension plans. It begins with a review of advances in the theory of rational financial planning and wealth management. It then summarizes the recent empirical literature on the actual behavior of households regarding saving, investing, and insuring their consumption in old age. Finally, it briefly comments on the practical implications of the theory for the design of pension systems and outlines areas of future research.</description><author>Bodie, Zvi; Detemple, Jerome; Rindisbacher, Marcel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and Inequality: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>In this paper, we critically review the literature on finance and inequality, highlighting substantive gaps in the literature. Finance plays a crucial role in the preponderance of theories of persistent inequality. Unsurprisingly, therefore, economic theory provides a rich set of predictions concerning both the impact of finance on inequality and about the relevant mechanisms. While subject to ample qualifications, the bulk of empirical research suggests that improvements in financial contracts, markets, and intermediaries expand economic opportunities and reduce inequality. Yet, there is a shortage of theoretical and empirical research on the potentially enormous impact of formal financial sector policies, such as bank regulations and securities law, on persistent inequality. Furthermore, we lack a conceptual framework for considering the joint and endogenous evolution of finance, inequality, and economic growth.</description><author>Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Levine, Ross</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility Derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Volatility derivatives are a class of derivative securities where the payoff explicitly depends on some measure of the volatility of an underlying asset. Prominent examples of these derivatives include variance swaps and VIX futures and options. We provide an overview of the current market for these derivatives. We also survey the early literature on the subject. Finally, we provide relatively simple proofs of some fundamental results related to variance swaps and volatility swaps.</description><author>Carr, Peter; Lee, Roger</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating and Testing Continuous-Time Models in Finance: The Role of Transition Densities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>This article surveys recent developments to estimate and test continuous-time models in finance using discrete observations on the underlying asset price or derivative securities' prices. Both parametric and nonparametric methods are described. All these methods share a common focus on the transition density as the central object for inference and testing of the model.</description><author>Ait-Sahaha, Yacine</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>We survey the recent literature on learning in financial markets. Our main theme is that many financial market phenomena that appear puzzling at first sight are easier to understand once we recognize that parameters in financial models are uncertain and subject to learning. We discuss phenomena related to the volatility and predictability of asset returns, stock price bubbles, portfolio choice, mutual fund flows, trading volume, and firm profitability, among others.</description><author>Pastor, Lubos; Veronesi, Pietro</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Decision Neuroscience Teaches Us About Financial Decision Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Financial decision making is the outcome of complex neurophysiological processes involving, among others, constant re-evaluation of the statistics of the problem at hand, balancing of the various emotional aspects, and computation of the very value signals that are at the core of modern economic thinking. The evidence suggests that emotions play a crucial supporting role in the mathematical computations needed for reasoned choice, rather than interfering with it, even if emotions (and their mathematical counterparts) may not always be balanced appropriately. Decision neuroscience can be expected in the neat future to provide a number of effective tools for improved financial decision making.</description><author>Bossaerts, Peter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>