<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Annual Review of Economics0</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Experiments on Cognition, Communication, Coordination, and Cooperation in Relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crawford, Vincent P.
This review discusses selected work in experimental game theory. My goals are to further the dialogue between theorists and empiricists that has driven progress in economics and game theory and to guide future experimental work. I focus on experiments whose lessons are relevant to establishing and maintaining coordination and cooperation in human relationships, the role of communication in doing so, and the underlying cognition. These are questions of central importance, where both the gap between theory and experience and the role of experiments in closing it seem large. Humans appear to be unique in their ability to use language to manipulate and communicate mental models of the world and of other people, vital skills in relationships. Continuing the dialogue between theorists and empiricists should help to explain why it matters for cooperation that we can communicate, and why and how it matters whether we communicate via natural language or abstract signals.</description><author>Crawford, Vincent P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robustness in Mechanism Design and Contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carroll, Gabriel
This review summarizes a nascent body of theoretical research on design of incentives when the environment is not fully known to the designer and offers some general lessons from the work so far. These recent models based on uncertainty and robustness offer an additional set of tools in the toolkit, complementary to more traditional, fully Bayesian modeling approaches, and broaden the range of problems that can be studied. The kinds of insights that such models can offer, and the methodological and technical challenges that they confront, broadly parallel those of traditional approaches.</description><author>Carroll, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Wealth Inequality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zucman, Gabriel
This article reviews the recent literature on the dynamics of global wealth inequality. I first reconcile available estimates of wealth inequality in the United States. Both surveys and tax data show that wealth inequality has increased dramatically since the 1980s, with a top 1% wealth share of approximately 40% in 2016 versus 25-30% in the 1980s. Second, I discuss the fast-growing literature on wealth inequality across the world. Evidence points toward a rise in global wealth concentration: For China, Europe, and the United States combined, the top 1% wealth share has increased from 28% in 1980 to 33% today, while the bottom 75% share hovered around 10%. Recent studies, however, may underestimate the level and rise of inequality, as financial globalization makes it increasingly hard to measure wealth at the top. I discuss how new data sources (leaks from financial institutions, tax amnesties, and macroeconomic statistics of tax havens) can be leveraged to better capture the wealth of the rich.</description><author>Zucman, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markets for Information: An Introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergemann, Dirk; Bonatti, Alessandro
We survey a recent and growing literature on markets for information. We offer a comprehensive view of information markets through an integrated model of consumers, information intermediaries, and firms. The model embeds a large set of applications ranging from sponsored-search advertising to credit scores to information sharing among competitors. We then zoom in to one of the critical elements in the markets for information: the design of the information. We distinguish between ex ante sales of information (the buyer acquires an information structure) and ex post sales (the buyer pays for specific realizations). We relate this distinction to the different products that brokers, advertisers, and publishers use to trade consumer information online. We discuss the endogenous limits to the trade of information that derive from the potential adverse use of information to the consumers. Finally, we discuss recommender systems and other information filtering systems that use artificial intelligence to predict ratings or preferences in markets for indirect information.</description><author>Bergemann, Dirk; Bonatti, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Parenting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doepke, Matthias; Sorrenti, Giuseppe; Zilibotti, Fabrizio
Parenting decisions are among the most consequential choices that people make throughout their lives. Starting with the work of pioneers such as Gary Becker, economists have used the tool set of their discipline to understand what parents do and how parents' actions affect their children. In recent years, the literature on parenting within economics has increasingly leveraged findings and concepts from related disciplines that also deal with parent-child interactions. For example, economists have developed models to understand the choice among various parenting styles that were first explored in the developmental psychology literature and have estimated detailed empirical models of children's accumulation of cognitive and noncognitive skills in response to parental and other inputs. In this review, we survey the economic literature on parenting and point out promising directions for future research.</description><author>Doepke, Matthias; Sorrenti, Giuseppe; Zilibotti, Fabrizio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Econometrics of Auctions and Nonlinear Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perrigne, Isabelle; Vuong, Quang
This review surveys the growing literature on the econometrics of first-price sealed-bid auctions and nonlinear pricing. The complexity of the economic models has initiated fruitful collaborations between econometrics and empirical research. We review the benchmark models and their extensions, the identification of the model primitives, and their nonparametric and semi-parametric estimation. We discuss the future of the field, which goes beyond auctions and nonlinear pricing, as both can be viewed as economic mechanisms for price formation, allocation, and market organization.</description><author>Perrigne, Isabelle; Vuong, Quang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Kenneth J. Arrow: A Selective Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maskin, Eric S.
This article reviews Kenneth Arrow's seminal work in economics, giving special emphasis to his contributions to social choice theory and general equilibrium theory.</description><author>Maskin, Eric S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bootstrap Methods in Econometrics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horowitz, Joel L.
The bootstrap is a method for estimating the distribution of an estimator or test statistic by resampling one's data or a model estimated from the data. Under conditions that hold in a wide variety of econometric applications, the bootstrap provides approximations to distributions of statistics, coverage probabilities of confidence intervals, and rejection probabilities of hypothesis tests that are more accurate than the approximations of first-order asymptotic distribution theory. The reductions in the differences between true and nominal coverage or rejection probabilities can be very large. In addition, the bootstrap provides a way to carry out inference in certain settings where obtaining analytic distributional approximations is difficult or impossible. This article explains the usefulness and limitations of the bootstrap in contexts of interest in econometrics. The presentation is informal and expository. It provides an intuitive understanding of how the bootstrap works. Mathematical details are available in the references that are cited.</description><author>Horowitz, Joel L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Experiments and Entrepreneurship in Developing Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Quinn, Simon; Woodruff, Christopher
We discuss the value of experiments in illuminating constraints on the growth of firms in developing countries. Experiments have provided insight into both the value and the difficulty of alleviating capital constraints in small firms. They suggest that urban, low-skilled labor markets appear to work reasonably well for firms, although there is a suggestion that frictions in markets for skilled workers may have more effect on firms. While observational data suggest that managerial training is important, experiments have shown that the traditional methods of delivering this training to small enterprises, at least, are not effective. Finally, while most work has focused on alleviating supply constraints, recent experiments have shown that positive demand shocks can be sufficient to generate firm growth. Experiments have been particularly illuminating in uncovering patterns in individual decision making, showing how agents respond to the specific changes in circumstances or incentives generated by the experiment. They are most valuable when they complement insight driven by theory.</description><author>Quinn, Simon; Woodruff, Christopher</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bayesian Persuasion and Information Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamenica, Emir
A school may improve its students' job outcomes if it issues only coarse grades. Google can reduce congestion on roads by giving drivers noisy information about the state of traffic. A social planner might raise everyone's welfare by providing only partial information about solvency of banks. All of this can happen even when everyone is fully rational and understands the data-generating process. Each of these examples raises questions of what is the (socially or privately) optimal information that should be revealed. In this article, I review the literature that answers such questions.</description><author>Kamenica, Emir</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Production Networks: A Primer</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carvalho, Vasco M.; Tahbaz-Salehi, Alireza
This article reviews the literature on production networks in macroeconomics. It presents the theoretical foundations for the role of input-output linkages as a shock propagation channel and as a mechanism for transforming microeconomic shocks into macroeconomic fluctuations. The article also provides a brief guide to the growing literature that explores these themes empirically and quantitatively.</description><author>Carvalho, Vasco M.; Tahbaz-Salehi, Alireza</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Universal Basic Income in the Developing World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Abhijit; Niehaus, Paul; Suri, Tavneet
Should developing countries give all of their citizens enough money to live on? Interest in this idea has grown enormously in recent years, reflecting both positive results from a number of existing cash transfer programs and dissatisfaction with the perceived limitations of piecemeal, targeted approaches to reducing extreme poverty. We discuss what we know (and what we do not) about three questions: what recipients would likely do with the incremental income, whether this would unlock further economic growth, and whether giving the money to everyone (as opposed to targeting it) would be wise.</description><author>Banerjee, Abhijit; Niehaus, Paul; Suri, Tavneet</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Universal Basic Income in the United States and Advanced Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoynes, Hilary; Rothstein, Jesse
We discuss the potential role of universal basic incomes (UBIs) in advanced countries. A feature of advanced economies that distinguishes them from developing countries is the existence of well-developed, if often incomplete, safety nets. We develop a framework for describing transfer programs that is flexible enough to encompass most existing programs as well as UBIs, and we use this framework to compare various UBIs to the existing constellation of programs in the United States. A UBI would direct much larger shares of transfers to childless, nonelderly, nondisabled households than existing programs, and much more to middle-income rather than poor households. A UBI large enough to increase transfers to low-income families would be enormously expensive. We review the labor supply literature for evidence on the likely impacts of a UBI. We argue that the ongoing UBI pilot studies will do little to resolve the major outstanding questions.</description><author>Hoynes, Hilary; Rothstein, Jesse</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Universal Basic Income: Some Theoretical Aspects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghatak, Maitreesh; Maniquet, Francois
In this article, we review the desirability and feasibility of a universal basic income (UBI) scheme from the theoretical point of view. We first discuss the possible theoretical justifications of UBI, contrasting the unconditionality of UBI with the many conditions that typically accompany other welfare policies. These justifications range from pure normative reasons to practical reasons due to the problem of screening beneficiaries and imperfections in institutions in charge of implementing tax and welfare policies. Next, we explore the conditions that determine the feasibility and size of a UBI. The broad picture that emerges from our review is that both normative and practical considerations make UBI easier to defend as a tool of poverty alleviation in developing countries than as a tool to achieve social justice in developed ones.</description><author>Ghatak, Maitreesh; Maniquet, Francois</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The International Monetary and Financial System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gourinchas, Pierre-Olivier; Rey, Helene; Sauzet, Maxime
International currencies fulfill different roles in the world economy, with important synergies across those roles. We explore the implications of currency hegemony for the external balance sheet of the United States, the process of international adjustment, and the predictability of the US dollar exchange rate. We emphasize the importance of international monetary spillovers and of the exorbitant privilege, and we analyze the emergence of a new Triffin dilemma.</description><author>Gourinchas, Pierre-Olivier; Rey, Helene; Sauzet, Maxime</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Has Dynamic Programming Improved Decision Making?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rust, John
Dynamic programming (DP) is a powerful tool for solving a wide class of sequential decision-making problems under uncertainty. In principle, it enables us to compute optimal decision rules that specify the best possible decision in any situation. This article reviews developments in DP and contrasts its revolutionary impact on economics, operations research, engineering, and artificial intelligence with the comparative paucity of its real-world applications to improve the decision making of individuals and firms. The fuzziness of many real-world decision problems and the difficulty in mathematically modeling them are key obstacles to a wider application of DP in real-world settings. Nevertheless, I discuss several success stories, and I conclude that DP offers substantial promise for improving decision making if we let go of the empirically untenable assumption of unbounded rationality and confront the challenging decision problems faced every day by individuals and firms.</description><author>Rust, John</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary Policy, Macroprudential Policy, and Financial Stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martinez-Miera, David; Repullo, Rafael
This review reexamines from a theoretical perspective the role of monetary and macroprudential policies in addressing the build-up of risks in the financial system. We construct a stylized general equilibrium model in which the key friction comes from a moral hazard problem in firms' financing that banks' equity capital serves to ameliorate. Tight monetary policy is introduced by open market sales of government debt, and tight macroprudential policy by an increase in capital requirements. We show that both policies are useful, but macroprudential policy is more effective in fostering financial stability and leads to higher social welfare.</description><author>Martinez-Miera, David; Repullo, Rafael</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Free Movement, Open Borders, and the Global Gains from Labor Mobility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dustmann, Christian; Preston, Ian P.
Straightforward economic arguments point to the potential for large global output gains from the movement of labor from less to more productive locations. Yet the politics of receiving countries seems resistant, characterized rather by efforts to limit migration or to stop it altogether. In this article we examine the foundations of claims of large welfare gains through free mobility, studying implications of liberalizing migration for world welfare under a variety of models, paying attention not only to overall gains but also to how gains are distributed and reviewing attempts to quantify the benefits. We conclude by asking how far considerations beyond economics motivate keenness to impose restrictions on migration.</description><author>Dustmann, Christian; Preston, Ian P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taking State-Capacity Research to the Field: Insights from Collaborations with Tax Authorities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pomeranz, Dina; Vila-Belda, Jose
No modern state can exist in the long term without effective taxation. Recent research emerging from close collaboration of academics with tax authorities has shed new light on how states can build such tax capacity. Using both randomized and natural experiments, these partnerships have not only opened access to new types of data but have also stimulated new perspectives and research questions. While much of research in public finance has historically assumed that a tax in the law is a tax that is collected, exciting new research takes an empirical look inside the black box of tax administration. It addresses issues ranging from the role of information and digitalization to taxpayer behavior or to the link between taxation and citizens' relationship to the state. This article provides a brief overview of some of this research, as well as practical advice for those interested in implementing research in partnership with tax authorities or other large public entities.</description><author>Pomeranz, Dina; Vila-Belda, Jose</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Weak Instruments in Instrumental Variables Regression: Theory and Practice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrews, Isaiah; Stock, James H.; Sun, Liyang
When instruments are weakly correlated with endogenous regressors, conventional methods for instrumental variables (IV) estimation and inference become unreliable. A large literature in econometrics has developed procedures for detecting weak instruments and constructing robust confidence sets, but many of the results in this literature are limited to settings with independent and homoskedastic data, while data encountered in practice frequently violate these assumptions. We review the literature on weak instruments in linear IV regression with an emphasis on results for nonhomoskedastic (heteroskedastic, serially correlated, or clustered) data. To assess the practical importance of weak instruments, we also report tabulations and simulations based on a survey of papers published in the American Economic Review from 2014 to 2018 that use IV. These results suggest that weak instruments remain an important issue for empirical practice, and that there are simple steps that researchers can take to better handle weak instruments in applications.</description><author>Andrews, Isaiah; Stock, James H.; Sun, Liyang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Machine Learning Methods That Economists Should Know About</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Athey, Susan; Imbens, Guido W.
We discuss the relevance of the recent machine learning (ML) literature for economics and econometrics. First we discuss the differences in goals, methods, and settings between the ML literature and the traditional econometrics and statistics literatures. Then we discuss some specific methods from the ML literature that we view as important for empirical researchers in economics. These include supervised learning methods for regression and classification, unsupervised learning methods, and matrix completion methods. Finally, we highlight newly developed methods at the intersection of ML and econometrics that typically perform better than either off-the-shelf ML or more traditional econometric methods when applied to particular classes of problems, including causal inference for average treatment effects, optimal policy estimation, and estimation of the counterfactual effect of price changes in consumer choice models.</description><author>Athey, Susan; Imbens, Guido W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Theories of Justice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleurbaey, Marc
Social justice considerations are incorporated into welfare economics via properties of the social welfare function and measures of individual utility. The ethical issues underlying various approaches are illustrated through intriguing paradoxes that have emerged in the literature. Such puzzles point to the tensions among certain important values (such as respecting preferences, giving priority to the worse off, personal responsibility, and informational simplicity) and suggest the relevant ways in which reasonable compromise can be sought. Welfare economics is now able to accommodate a large range of conceptions of justice, including utilitarianism and various forms of egalitarianism and libertarianism.</description><author>Fleurbaey, Marc</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>History, Microdata, and Endogenous Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akcigit, Ufuk; Nicholas, Tom
The study of economic growth is concerned with long-run changes, and therefore, historical data should be especially influential in informing the development of new theories. In this review, we draw on the recent literature to highlight areas in which study of history has played a particularly prominent role in improving our understanding of growth dynamics. Research at the intersection of historical data, theory, and empirics has the potential to reframe how we think about economic growth in much the same way that historical perspectives helped to shape the first generation of endogenous growth theories.</description><author>Akcigit, Ufuk; Nicholas, Tom</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transitional Dynamics in Aggregate Models of Innovative Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atkeson, Andrew; Burstein, Ariel T.; Chatzikonstantinou, Manolis
What quantitative lessons can we learn from models of endogenous technical change through innovative investments by firms for the impact of changes in the economic environment on the dynamics of aggregate productivity in the short, medium, and long run? We present a unifying model that nests several canonical models in the literature and characterize both their positive implications for the transitional dynamics of aggregate productivity and their welfare implications in terms of two sufficient statistics. We review the current state of measurement of these two sufficient statistics and discuss the range of positive and normative quantitative implications of our model for a wide array of counterfactual experiments, including the link between a decline in the entry rate of new firms and a slowdown in the growth of aggregate productivity. We conclude with a summary of the lessons learned from our analysis to help direct future research aimed at building models of endogenous productivity growth that are useful for quantitative analysis.</description><author>Atkeson, Andrew; Burstein, Ariel T.; Chatzikonstantinou, Manolis</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Productivity Measurement: Racing to Keep Up</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sichel, Daniel E.
This article provides a nontechnical review of the literature and issues related to the measurement of aggregate productivity. I begin with a discussion of productivity measures, their performance in recent decades, and key measurement puzzles that emerge from the data. The remainder of the review focuses on two important questions. First, how do we make more accurate the measures of prices used to deflate nominal output so as to win (or at least not lose) the race for economic measurement to keep up with a changing economy? I frame the issues and point to the most important and promising areas for further research. Second, what does or should GDP measure? I defend GDP as a valuable measure of production and offer suggestions for improving it. At the same time, I emphasize the importance of measuring economic welfare (well-being) and argue that GDP should be supplemented with a satellite account that measures economic welfare.</description><author>Sichel, Daniel E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Education Consumption or Investment? Implications for School Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>MacLeod, W. Bentley; Urquiola, Miguel
Milton Friedman argued that giving parents freedom to choose schools would improve education. His argument was simple and compelling because it extended results from markets for consumer goods to education. We review the evidence, which yields surprisingly mixed results on Friedman's prediction. A key reason is that households often seem to choose schools based on their absolute achievement rather than their value added. We show that this can be rational in a model based on three ingredients that economists have highlighted since Friedman worked on the issue. First, education is an investment into human capital. Second, labor markets can feature wage premia: Individuals of a given skill level may receive higher wages if they match to more productive firms. Third, distance influences school choice and the placements that schools produce. These factors imply that choice alone is too crude a mechanism to ensure the effective provision of schooling.</description><author>MacLeod, W. Bentley; Urquiola, Miguel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using Randomized Controlled Trials to Estimate Long-Run Impacts in Development Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouguen, Adrien; Huang, Yue; Kremer, Michael; Miguel, Edward
We assess evidence from randomized controlled trials (RCTs) on long-run economic productivity and living standards in poor countries. We first document that several studies estimate large positive long-run impacts, but that relatively few existing RCTs have been evaluated over the long run. We next present evidence from a systematic survey of existing RCTs, with a focus on cash transfer and child health programs, and show that a meaningful subset can realistically be evaluated for long-run effects. We discuss ways to bridge the gap between the burgeoning number of development RCTs and the limited number that have been followed up to date, including through new panel (longitudinal) data; improved participant tracking methods; alternative research designs; and access to administrative, remote sensing, and cell phone data. We conclude that the rise of development economics RCTs since roughly 2000 provides a novel opportunity to generate high-quality evidence on the long-run drivers of living standards.</description><author>Bouguen, Adrien; Huang, Yue; Kremer, Michael; Miguel, Edward</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Econometric Analysis of Panel Data Models with Multifactor Error Structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karabiyik, Hande; Palm, Franz C.; Urbain, Jean-Pierre
Economic panel data often exhibit cross-sectional dependence, even after conditioning on appropriate explanatory variables. Two approaches to modeling cross-sectional dependence in economic panel data are often used: the spatial dependence approach, which explains cross-sectional dependence in terms of distance among units, and the residual multifactor approach, which explains cross-sectional dependence by common factors that affect individuals to a different extent. This article reviews the theory on estimation and statistical inference for stationary and nonstationary panel data with cross-sectional dependence, particularly for models with a multifactor error structure. Tests and diagnostics for testing for unit roots, slope homogeneity, cointegration, and the number of factors are provided. We discuss issues such as estimating common factors, dealing with parameter plethora in practice, testing for structural stability and nonlinearity, and dealing with model and parameter uncertainty. Finally, we address issues related to the use of these economic panel models.</description><author>Karabiyik, Hande; Palm, Franz C.; Urbain, Jean-Pierre</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Networks in Policy Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battaglini, Marco; Patacchini, Eleonora
Recent advances in data collection, computing power, and theoretical modeling have stimulated a growing literature in economics and political science studying how social networks affect policy making. We survey this literature focusing on two main aspects. First, we discuss the literature studying how (and if) social connections in Congress affect legislative behavior. We then discuss how social connections affect the relationship between policy makers and the outside world, focusing on lobbying; the importance of family, caste, and ethnic networks; and social media and public activism. In our discussion, we highlight the key methodological challenges in this literature, how they have been addressed, and the prospects for future research.</description><author>Battaglini, Marco; Patacchini, Eleonora</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Legislative and Multilateral Bargaining</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eraslan, Hulya; Evdokimov, Kirill S.
This review of the theoretical literature on legislative and multilateral bargaining begins with presentation of the seminal Baron-Ferejohn model. The review then encompasses the extensions to bargaining among asymmetric players in terms of bargaining power, voting weights, and time and risk preferences; spatial bargaining; bargaining over a stochastic surplus; bargaining over public goods; legislative bargaining with alternative bargaining protocols in which players make demands, compete for recognition, or make counterproposals; and legislative bargaining with cheap talk communication.</description><author>Eraslan, Hulya; Evdokimov, Kirill S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fair Division in the Internet Age</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moulin, Herve
Fair division, a key concern in the design of many social institutions, has for 70 years been the subject of interdisciplinary research at the interface of mathematics, economics, and game theory. Motivated by the proliferation of moneyless transactions on the internet, the computer science community has recently taken a deep interest in fairness principles and practical division rules. The resulting literature brings a fresh concern for computational simplicity (scalable rules) and realistic implementation. In this review of the most salient fair division results of the past 30 years, I concentrate on division rules with the best potential for practical implementation. The critical design parameter is the message space that the agents must use to report their individual preferences. A simple preference domain is key both to realistic implementation and to the existence of division rules with strong normative and incentive properties. I discuss successively the one-dimensional single-peaked domain, Leontief utilities, ordinal ranking, dichotomous preferences, and additive utilities. Some of the theoretical results in the latter domain are already implemented in the user-friendly SPLIDDIT platform (http://spliddit.org).</description><author>Moulin, Herve</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Auction Market Design: Recent Innovations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milgrom, Paul
Market design applies economic principles to the often messy problems of real-world exchange in which goods may not be homogeneous, the identities of trading partners may matter, contracts may not be executed, and even the formulation of trade as balancing supply and demand may be unhelpful. This article recounts the mostly academic research advancing the analysis and design of such markets. Among the highlighted applications are ones involving financial markets, Internet advertising, electricity auctions, spectrum auctions, cryptocurrencies, and combinatorial procurements.</description><author>Milgrom, Paul</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Approximately Optimal Mechanism Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roughgarden, Tim; Talgam-Cohen, Inbal
The field of optimal mechanism design enjoys a beautiful and well-developed theory, as well as several killer applications. Rules of thumb produced by the field influence everything from how governments sell wireless spectrum licenses to how the major search engines auction off online advertising. There are, however, some basic problems for which the traditional optimal mechanism design approach is ill suited-either because it makes overly strong assumptions or because it advocates overly complex designs. This article reviews several common issues with optimal mechanisms, including exorbitant communication, computation, and informational requirements; it also presents several examples demonstrating that relaxing the goal to designing an approximately optimal mechanism allows us to reason about fundamental questions that seem out of reach of the traditional theory.</description><author>Roughgarden, Tim; Talgam-Cohen, Inbal</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolutionary Models of Preference Formation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alger, Ingela; Weibull, Jorgen W.
The literature on the evolution of preferences of individuals in strategic interactions is vast and diverse. We organize the discussion around the following question: Supposing that material outcomes drive evolutionary success, under what circumstances does evolution promote Homo economicus, defined as material self-interest, and when does it instead lead to other preferences? The literature suggests that Homo economicus is favored by evolution only when individuals' preferences are their private information and the population is large and well-mixed, so that individuals with rare mutant preferences almost never get to interact with each other. If rare mutants instead interact more often (say, due to local dispersion), then evolution instead favors a certain generalization of Homo economicus including a Kantian concern. If individuals interact under complete information about preferences, then evolution destabilizes Homo economicus in virtually all games.</description><author>Alger, Ingela; Weibull, Jorgen W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Echo Chambers and Their Effects on Economic and Political Outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Gilat; Razin, Ronny
In this review, we survey the economics literature on echo chambers. We identify echo chambers as arising from a combination of two phenomena: (a) the choice of individuals to segregate with like-minded ones, i.e., the creation of chambers, and (b) behavioral biases that induce polarization when individuals exchange beliefs in these chambers, i.e., the echo. We summarize the literatures on these two phenomena and suggest how to combine the two literatures to gain insights about the effects of echo chambers on economic and political outcomes. We end by suggesting pathways for future research and discussing policy interventions to alleviate echo chambers.</description><author>Levy, Gilat; Razin, Ronny</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Econometric Methods for Program Evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abadie, Alberto; Cattaneo, Matias D.
Program evaluation methods are widely applied in economics to assess the effects of policy interventions and other treatments of interest. In this article, we describe the main methodological frameworks of the econometrics of program evaluation. In the process, we delineate some of the directions along which this literature is expanding, discuss recent developments, and highlight specific areas where new research may be particularly fruitful.</description><author>Abadie, Alberto; Cattaneo, Matias D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prosocial Motivation and Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Besley, Timothy; Ghatak, Maitreesh
This review explores the role of incentives in providing goods and services that have significant social returns not captured in private returns, and where outcomes and performances are not easy to measure. We discuss how the presence of prosocial motivation among agents involved in the provision of these goods and services changes the design of incentives. The review also emphasises how heterogeneous prosocial motivation puts a premium on selection of agents in this context. We also discuss alternative theories of prosocial motivation.</description><author>Besley, Timothy; Ghatak, Maitreesh</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Development of the African System of Cities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henderson, J. Vernon; Kriticos, Sebastian
Sub-Saharan Africa has experienced high urban population growth over the past half century, dramatically reshaping the economic and spatial profile of the region. Simultaneously, this process has challenged the conventional view that countries urbanize alongside structural transformation, as urbanization in Africa has occurred despite low productivity gains in agriculture and very limited industrialization. While there are large household income gaps between urban and rural areas that induce migration, most cities have very high agricultural employment, blurring the connection between structural transformation and urbanization. Urban income premiums apply equally to farm and nonfarm families. Looking across the urban hierarchy, we discuss how high urban primacy presents problems for economic growth in Africa, how secondary cities are faltering with a lack of industrialization, and how growth of employment in tradable services may signal a different path to structural transformation.</description><author>Henderson, J. Vernon; Kriticos, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Global Value Chains</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Robert C.
Recent decades have seen the emergence of global value chains (GVCs), in which production stages for individual goods are broken apart and scattered across countries. Stimulated by these developments, there has been rapid progress in data and methods for measuring GVC linkages. The macro approach to measuring GVCs connects national input-output tables across borders by using bilateral trade data to construct global input-output tables. These tables have been applied to measure trade in value added, the length of and location of producers in GVCs, and price linkages across countries. The micro approach uses firm-level data to document firms' input sourcing decisions, how import and export participation are linked, and how multinational firms organize their production networks. In this review, I evaluate progress in these two approaches, highlighting points of contact between them and areas that demand further work. I argue that further convergence between these approaches can strengthen both, yielding a more complete empirical portrait of GVCs.</description><author>Johnson, Robert C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economics of Child Protection: Maltreatment, Foster Care, and Intimate Partner Violence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doyle, Joseph J.; Aizer, Anna
Violence within families and child neglect are strikingly common: 700,000 children are found to be victims of abuse or neglect in the United States each year; over the course of childhood, 6% of children are placed in foster care, and 18% witness intimate partner violence. These children are at much higher risks of homelessness, criminal justice involvement, unemployment, and chronic health conditions compared to their neighbors. This article reviews the state of the economics literature on the causes and consequences of child maltreatment and intimate partner violence and calls for greater research into interventions aimed at improving child well-being.</description><author>Doyle, Joseph J.; Aizer, Anna</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Networks and Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernard, Andrew B.; Moxnes, Andreas
Trade occurs between firms both across borders and within countries, and most trade transactions include at least one large firm with many trading partners. This article reviews the literature on firm-to-firm connections in trade. A growing body of evidence coming from domestic and international transaction data has established empirical regularities that have inspired the development of new theories emphasizing firm heterogeneity among both buyers and suppliers in production networks. Theoretical work has considered both static and dynamic matching environments in a framework of many-to-many matching. The literature on trade and production networks is at an early stage, and there are many unanswered empirical and theoretical questions.</description><author>Bernard, Andrew B.; Moxnes, Andreas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sorting in the Labor Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eeckhout, Jan
This review surveys the literature on sorting in the labor market. There are inherent differences in worker ability and across-firm productivity. Two fundamental questions are whether the exact composition of skills of workers and productivity of firms affects output and how this composition determines the equilibrium allocation of workers within a firm and between firms. There has been a surge of research investigating the causes and consequences of the process of allocation of heterogeneous workers to firms. The focus in this review is on theory that sheds light on open questions in macroeconomics, labor, and industrial organization, with a particular emphasis on the role of firm size. Those models allow us to infer from the observed sorting patterns (who matches with whom) what the underlying technological determinants are and how they have evolved in recent decades. Furthermore, they help us understand the technological origins of important labor market trends, such as the increase in wage inequality and the change in labor market and firm dynamics.</description><author>Eeckhout, Jan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Econometrics of Shape Restrictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chetverikov, Denis; Santos, Andres; Shaikh, Azeem M.
We review recent developments in the econometrics of shape restrictions and their role in applied work. Our objectives are threefold. First, we aim to emphasize the diversity of applications in which shape restrictions have played a fruitful role. Second, we intend to provide practitioners with an intuitive understanding of how shape restrictions impact the distribution of estimators and test statistics. Third, we aim to provide an overview of new advances in the theory of estimation and inference under shape restrictions. Throughout the review, we outline open questions and interesting directions for future research.</description><author>Chetverikov, Denis; Santos, Andres; Shaikh, Azeem M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Nowcasting and Forecasting with Big Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bok, Brandyn; Caratelli, Daniele; Giannone, Domenico; Sbordone, Argia M.; Tambalotti, Andrea
Data, data, data .... Economists know their importance well, especially when it comes to monitoring macroeconomic conditions-the basis for making informed economic and policy decisions. Handling large and complex data sets was a challenge that macroeconomists engaged in real-time analysis faced long before so-called big data became pervasive in other disciplines. We review how methods for tracking economic conditions using big data have evolved over time and explain how econometric techniques have advanced to mimic and automate best practices of forecasters on trading desks, at central banks, and in other market-monitoring roles. We present in detail the methodology underlying the New York Fed Staff Nowcast, which employs these innovative techniques to produce early estimates of GDP growth, synthesizing a wide range of macroeconomic data as they become available.</description><author>Bok, Brandyn; Caratelli, Daniele; Giannone, Domenico; Sbordone, Argia M.; Tambalotti, Andrea</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identification and Extrapolation of Causal Effects with Instrumental Variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mogstad, Magne; Torgovitsky, Alexander
Instrumental variables (IV) are widely used in economics to address selection on unobservables. Standard IV methods produce estimates of causal effects that are specific to individuals whose behavior can be manipulated by the instrument at hand. In many cases, these individuals are not the same as those who would be induced to treatment by an intervention or policy of interest to the researcher. The average causal effect for the two groups can differ significantly if the effect of the treatment varies systematically with unobserved factors that are correlated with treatment choice. We review the implications of this type of unobserved heterogeneity for the interpretation of standard IV methods and for their relevance to policy evaluation. We argue that making inferences about policy-relevant parameters typically requires extrapolating from the individuals affected by the instrument to the individuals who would be induced to treatment by the policy under consideration. We discuss a variety of alternatives to standard IV methods that can be used to rigorously perform this extrapolation. We show that many of these approaches can be nested as special cases of a general framework that embraces the possibility of partial identification.</description><author>Mogstad, Magne; Torgovitsky, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Progress and Perspectives in the Study of Political Selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dal Bo, Ernesto; Finan, Frederico
We provide a model of self-selection by candidates in a probabilistic voting environment to shed light on the forces shaping the quality of politicians from both the supply and demand sides of politics. The model highlights the idea that the patterns of selection and the comparative statics of politician quality depend critically on how the costs of running for office vary for candidates with different qualities. The model offers predictions on how the quality of the political class will vary with key parameters pertaining to both the supply and demand for candidates. We use the model to frame a review of the empirical literature on political selection that has emerged over the past two decades. We contrast areas where significant progress has been made with others where important theoretical predictions remain untested or existing evidence does not allow a consensus, highlighting areas for future research.</description><author>Dal Bo, Ernesto; Finan, Frederico</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Macroeconomics of Rational Bubbles: A User's Guide</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martin, Alberto; Ventura, Jaume
This review provides a guide to macroeconomic applications of the theory of rational bubbles. It shows that rational bubbles can be easily incorporated into standard macroeconomic models and illustrates how they can be used to account for important macroeconomic phenomena. It also discusses the welfare implications of rational bubbles and the role of policy in managing them. Finally, it provides a detailed review of the literature.</description><author>Martin, Alberto; Ventura, Jaume</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Incentives in Organizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ashraf, Nava; Bandiera, Oriana
We review the evidence on social incentives, namely on how social interactions with colleagues, subordinates, bosses, customers, and others shape agents' effort choices in organizations. We propose a two-way taxonomy based on (a) whether the social group is horizontal (peers at the same level of the hierarchy) or vertical (individuals at different levels within or outside of the organization) and (b) whether the agent's effort creates externalities for the other members of their social group. We show settings in which social incentives improve productivity and settings in which they reduce it. In most cases, the size of the effect is approximately 10%, which is half of the typical effect of performance pay. We also show that social incentives can interfere with financial incentives, making them ineffective or even detrimental. We conclude that social incentives are a powerful motivator that must be taken into account in the design of organizational policies and that more research is needed to understand how policies can shape the preferences that underpin these incentives.</description><author>Ashraf, Nava; Bandiera, Oriana</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spatial Patterns of Development: A Meso Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michalopoulos, Stelios; Papaioannou, Elias
Over the past two decades, the literature on comparative development has moved from country-level to within-country analyses. The questions asked have expanded in scope as economists have used satellite images of light density at night and other big spatial data to proxy for development at the desired level. The focus has also shifted from uncovering correlations to identifying causal relations, using elaborate econometric techniques including spatial regression discontinuity designs. In this review, we show how the combination of geographic information systems with insights from disciplines ranging from the earth sciences to linguistics and history has transformed the research landscape on the roots of the spatial patterns of development. We discuss the limitations of the luminosity data and associated econometric techniques and conclude by offering some thoughts on future research.</description><author>Michalopoulos, Stelios; Papaioannou, Elias</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Welfare Reform and the Labor Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Marc K.; Moffitt, Robert
This article reviews the basic theoretical models that are appropriate for analyzing different types of welfare reforms, as well as the related empirical literature. We first present the canonical labor supply model of a classical welfare program and then extend this basic framework to include in-kind transfers, incomplete take-up, human capital, preference persistence, and borrowing and saving. The empirical literature on these models is presented. The negative income tax, earnings subsidies, US welfare reforms with features that differ from those in other countries, and childcare reforms are then surveyed in terms of both the theoretical models and the empirical literature surrounding each.</description><author>Chan, Marc K.; Moffitt, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idea Flows and Economic Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buera, Francisco J.; Lucas, Robert E.
We review new theories of learning that posit specific, distinct roles for the learner or innovator and their intellectual environment. We consider applications to the dynamics of individual earnings over the life cycle, the diffusion of knowledge within an organization and firm dynamics, and the role of trade in the diffusion of ideas.</description><author>Buera, Francisco J.; Lucas, Robert E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Does (Formal) Health Insurance Do, and for Whom?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Finkelstein, Amy; Mahoney, Neale; Notowidigdo, Matthew J.
Health insurance confers benefits to the previously uninsured, including improvements in health, reductions in out-of-pocket spending, and reduced medical debt. However, because the nominally uninsured pay only a small share of their medical expenses, health insurance also provides substantial transfers to nonrecipient parties who would otherwise bear the costs of providing uncompensated care to the uninsured. The prevalence of uncompensated care helps explain the limited take-up of heavily subsidized public health insurance and the evidence that many recipients value formal health insurance at substantially less than the cost to insurers of providing that coverage. The distributional implications of public subsidies for health insurance depend critically on the ultimate economic incidence of the transfers that they deliver to providers of uncompensated care.</description><author>Finkelstein, Amy; Mahoney, Neale; Notowidigdo, Matthew J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implications of High-Frequency Trading for Security Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linton, Oliver; Mahmoodzadeh, Soheil
High-frequency trading (HFT) has grown substantially in recent years due to fast-paced technological developments and their rapid uptake, particularly in equity markets. This review investigates how HFT could evolve and, by developing a robust understanding of its effects, identifies potential risks and opportunities that HFT could present in terms of financial stability and other market outcomes such as volatility, liquidity, price efficiency, and price discovery. Despite commonly held negative perceptions, the available evidence indicates that HFT and algorithmic trading may have several beneficial effects on markets. However, these types of trading may cause instabilities in financial markets in specific circumstances. Carefully chosen regulatory measures are needed to address concerns in the shorter term. However, further work is needed to inform policies in the longer term, particularly in view of likely uncertainties and lack of data. This work will be vital in supporting evidence-based regulation in this controversial and rapidly evolving field.</description><author>Linton, Oliver; Mahmoodzadeh, Soheil</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Consequences of Uncertainty: Climate Sensitivity and Economic Sensitivity to the Climate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hassler, John; Krusell, Per; Olovsson, Conny
We construct an integrated assessment model with multiple energy sources-two fossil fuels and green energy-and use it to evaluate ranges of plausible estimates for the climate sensitivity, as well as for the sensitivity of the economy to climate change. Rather than focusing explicitly on uncertainty, we look at extreme scenarios defined by the upper and lower limits given in available studies in the literature. We compare optimal policy with laissez faire, and we point out the possible policy errors that could arise. By far the largest policy error arises when the climate policy is overly passive; overly zealous climate policy (i.e., a high carbon tax applied when climate change and its negative impacts on the economy are very limited) does not hurt the economy much as there is considerable substitutability between fossil and nonfossil energy sources.</description><author>Hassler, John; Krusell, Per; Olovsson, Conny</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cyclical Job Ladder</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moscarini, Giuseppe; Postel-Vinay, Fabien
Many theories of labor market turnover generate a job ladder. Due to search frictions, workers earn rents from employment. All workers agree on which jobs are, in this sense, more desirable and slowly climb the job ladder through job-to-job quits. Occasionally, negative shocks throw them off the ladder and back into unemployment. We review a recent body of theory and empirical evidence on labor market turnover through the lens of the job ladder. We focus on the critical role that the job ladder plays in transmitting aggregate shocks, through the pace and direction of employment reallocation, to economic activity and wages and in shaping business cycles more generally. The main evidence concerns worker transitions, both through nonemployment and from job to job, between firms of different sizes, ages, productivity levels, and wage premiums, as well as the resulting earnings growth. Poaching by firms up the ladder is the main engine of reallocation, which shuts down in recessions.</description><author>Moscarini, Giuseppe; Postel-Vinay, Fabien</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Radical Decentralization: Does Community-Driven Development Work?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casey, Katherine
Classic arguments for decentralization, augmented by ideas about how participation empowers the poor, motivate the widely used approach in foreign aid called community-driven development (CDD). CDD devolves control over the selection, implementation, and financial management of public goods to communities. Until recently, policy enthusiasm has outstripped the evidence. I synthesize findings from randomized controlled trials and find that CDD effectively delivers public goods and modest economic returns at low cost in difficult environments. There is little evidence, however, that CDD transforms local decision making or empowers the poor in any enduring way. Part of this failure may be because some constraints believed to be important-like insufficient social capital-appear not to bind. Others, like exclusive local institutions, are a problem, although not one that CDD remedies. These results present a conundrum: How much participation is enough to safeguard the gains of such extreme decentralization while minimizing the opportunity costs imposed on poor people's time?</description><author>Casey, Katherine</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fixed Effects Estimation of Large-T Panel Data Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandez-Val, Ivan; Weidner, Martin
This article reviews recent advances in fixed effects estimation of panel data models for long panels, where the number of time periods is relatively large. We focus on semiparametric models with unobserved individual and time effects, where the distribution of the outcome variable, conditional on covariates and unobserved effects, is specified parametrically while the distribution of the unobserved effects is left unrestricted. In contrast to existing reviews on long panels, we discuss models with both individual and time effects, split-panel jackknife bias corrections, unbalanced panels, distribution and quantile effects, and other extensions. Understanding and correcting the incidental parameter bias caused by the estimation of many fixed effects are our main focuses, and the unifying theme is that the order of this bias is given by the simple formula p/n for all models discussed, with p being the number of estimated parameters and n the total sample size.</description><author>Fernandez-Val, Ivan; Weidner, Martin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Health, Health Insurance, and Retirement: A Survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>French, Eric; Jones, John Bailey
The degree to which retirement decisions are driven by health is a key concern for both academics and policy makers. In this review, we survey the economic literature on the health-retirement link in developed countries. We describe the mechanisms through which health affects labor supply and discuss how these mechanisms interact with public pensions and public health insurance. The historical evidence suggests that health is not the primary source of variation in retirement across countries and over time. Furthermore, the decline of health with age can only explain a small share of the decline in employment near retirement age. Health considerations nonetheless play an important role, especially in explaining cross-sectional variation in employment and other outcomes within countries. We review the mechanisms through which health affects retirement and discuss recent empirical analyses.</description><author>French, Eric; Jones, John Bailey</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tony Atkinson on Poverty, Inequality, and Public Policy: The Work and Life of a Great Economist</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atkinson, Anthony Barnes; Stern, Nicholas
We are very sad to report that Professor Sir Tony Atkinson died on the first of January, 2017, at the age of 72. Tony Atkinson was an extraordinarily distinguished academic whose works changed our understanding of poverty, inequality, mobility, public policy, and economic growth. His publications, from his first book in 1969 to his last in 2015, showed how he approached his work throughout his career: define the issues, examine the facts, analyze what forces shaped the outcomes, and ask what we can or should do in the way of policy. His longtime friend, Professor Lord Nicholas Stern, interviewed Sir Tony about his life and work on August 17, 2016, in Oxford.</description><author>Atkinson, Anthony Barnes; Stern, Nicholas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantitative Spatial Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Redding, Stephen J.; Rossi-Hansberg, Esteban
The observed uneven distribution of economic activity across space is influenced by variation in exogenous geographical characteristics and endogenous interactions between agents in goods and factor markets. Until the past decade, the theoretical literature on economic geography had focused on stylized settings that could not easily be taken to the data. This article reviews more recent research that has developed quantitative models of economic geography. These models are rich enough to speak to first-order features of the data, such as many heterogeneous locations and gravity equation relationships for trade and commuting. At the same time, these models are sufficiently tractable to undertake realistic counterfactual exercises to study the effect of changes in amenities, productivity, and public policy interventions such as transport infrastructure investments. We provide an extensive taxonomy of the different building blocks of these quantitative spatial models and discuss their main properties and quantification.</description><author>Redding, Stephen J.; Rossi-Hansberg, Esteban</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade and the Environment: New Methods, Measurements, and Results</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cherniwchan, Jevan; Copeland, Brian R.; Taylor, M. Scott
We review recent research linking international trade to the environment, with a focus on new results and methods. The review is given structure by a novel decomposition linking changes in emissions to changes in productive activity at the plant, firm, industry, and national levels. Although some new results have emerged from the application of a Melitz-style approach to trade and the environment, the full potential of this approach has not yet been realized. We discuss existing empirical and theoretical work, introduce three new hypotheses, and suggest paths for future researchers to follow.</description><author>Cherniwchan, Jevan; Copeland, Brian R.; Taylor, M. Scott</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bestseller Lists and the Economics of Product Discovery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sorensen, Alan T.
Innovations in information technology have increased the prevalence of markets with large numbers of products. Each week, for example, an average of over 800 books are published, and an average of over 1,100 iOS apps are released in Apple's App Store. This review summarizes existing research about how consumers learn about new products in such markets, focusing on mechanisms like bestseller lists and user-generated product reviews. In addition to reviewing research findings about how these mechanisms directly influence sales, this article also discusses how these mechanisms affect broader market outcomes, such as the shape of the success distribution and the likelihood that good products are discovered.</description><author>Sorensen, Alan T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Set Identification, Moment Restrictions, and Inference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bontemps, Christian; Magnac, Thierry
For the past 10 years, the topic of set identification has been much studied in the econometric literature. Classical inference methods have been generalized to the case in which moment inequalities and equalities define a set instead of a point. We review several instances of partial identification by focusing on examples in which the underlying economic restrictions are expressed as linear moments. This setting illustrates the fact that convex analysis helps not only for characterizing the identified set but also for inference. From this perspective, we review inference methods using convex analysis or inversion of tests and detail how geometric characterizations can be useful.</description><author>Bontemps, Christian; Magnac, Thierry</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Image and Economic Behavior in the Field: Identifying, Understanding, and Shaping Social Pressure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bursztyn, Leonardo; Jensen, Robert
Many people care about how they are perceived by those around them. Several recent field experiments in economics have found that such social image concerns can have powerful effects on a range of behaviors. In this article, we first review this recent literature aimed at identifying social image concerns or social pressure. We then highlight and discuss two important areas that have been comparatively less well explored in this literature: understanding social pressure, including the underlying mechanisms, and whether such pressure can be shaped or influenced.</description><author>Bursztyn, Leonardo; Jensen, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantile Regression: 40 Years On</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koenker, Roger
Since Quetelet's work in the nineteenth century, social science has iconified the average man, that hypothetical man without qualities who is comfortable with his head in the oven and his feet in a bucket of ice. Conventional statistical methods since Quetelet have sought to estimate the effects of policy treatments for this average man. However, such effects are often quite heterogeneous: Medical treatments may improve life expectancy but also impose serious short-term risks; reducing class sizes may improve the performance of good students but not help weaker ones, or vice versa. Quantile regression methods can help to explore these heterogeneous effects. Some recent developments in quantile regression methods are surveyed in this review.</description><author>Koenker, Roger</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Globalization and Labor Market Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McLaren, John
Historically, the trade research field has usually ignored dynamic adjustment of workers, but a recent wave of work has developed a rich set of theoretical and empirical tools to analyze this factor. Empirical approaches have ranged from reduced-form regressions to the structural estimation of underlying parameters, which is necessary to understand welfare effects. A major distinction is that between models that do and those that do not allow for unobserved heterogeneity across workers; these models are useful for different purposes. Consistent findings across methods and countries indicate that costs of switching sectors and occupations are high and that both switching costs and option value are crucial in computing the welfare effects of globalization for workers.</description><author>McLaren, John</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflict and Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ray, Debraj; Esteban, Joan
In this review, we examine the links between economic development and social conflict. By economic development, we refer broadly to aggregate changes in per capita income and wealth or in the distribution of that wealth. By social conflict, we refer to within-country unrest, ranging from peaceful demonstrations, processions, and strikes to violent riots and civil war. We organize our review by critically examining three common perceptions: that conflict declines with ongoing economic growth; that conflict is principally organized along economic differences rather than similarities; and that conflict, most especially in developing countries, is driven by ethnic motives.</description><author>Ray, Debraj; Esteban, Joan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantitative Trade Models: Developments and Challenges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kehoe, Timothy J.; Pujolas, Pau S.; Rossbach, Jack
Applied general equilibrium (AGE) models, which feature multiple countries, multiple industries, and input-output linkages across industries, have been the dominant tool for evaluating the impact of trade reforms since the 1980s. We review how these models are used to perform policy analysis and document their shortcomings in predicting the industry-level effects of past trade reforms. We argue that, to improve their performance, AGE models need to incorporate product-level data on bilateral trade relations by industry and better model how trade reforms lower bilateral trade costs. We use the least-traded-products methodology of Kehoe et al. (2015) to provide guidance on how improvements can be made. We provide further suggestions on how AGE models can incorporate recent advances in quantitative trade theory to improve their predictive ability and better quantify the gains from trade liberalization.</description><author>Kehoe, Timothy J.; Pujolas, Pau S.; Rossbach, Jack</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Nonmarital Childbearing and the Marriage Premium for Children</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kearney, Melissa S.; Levine, Phillip B.
A large body of literature exists on the impact of family structure on children's outcomes, typically focusing on average effects. In this review, we build on this with an economic framework that has heterogeneous predictions regarding the potential benefit for children of married parents. We propose that the gains due to marriage from a child's perspective depend on a mother's own level of resources, the additional net resources that her partner brings, and the outcome-specific returns to resources. Data from the Panel Study of Income Dynamics are consistent with the heterogeneous predictions of this framework. In terms of high school completion or avoiding poverty at age 25, the so-called marriage premium for children is highest for children of mothers with high school degrees and mothers in their early to mid-20s. For the more advanced outcomes of college completion or high income at age 25, the marriage premium monotonically increases with observed maternal age and education.</description><author>Kearney, Melissa S.; Levine, Phillip B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Formation of Consumer Brand Preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bronnenberg, Bart J.; Dube, Jean-Pierre
Brands and brand capital have long been theorized to play an important role in the formation of the industrial market structure of consumer goods industries. We summarize several striking empirical regularities in the concentration, magnitude, and persistence of brand market shares in consumer goods categories. We then survey the theoretical and empirical literatures on the formation of brand preferences and the ways in which brand preferences contribute to our understanding of these empirical regularities. We also review the literature on how brand capital creates strategic advantages to firms that own established brands.</description><author>Bronnenberg, Bart J.; Dube, Jean-Pierre</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large-Scale Global and Simultaneous Inference: Estimation and Testing in Very High Dimensions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, T. Tony; Sun, Wenguang
Due to rapid technological advances, researchers are now able to collect and analyze ever larger data sets. Statistical inference for big data often requires solving thousands or even millions of parallel inference problems simultaneously. This poses significant challenges and calls for new principles, theories, and methodologies. This review provides a selective survey of some recently developed methods and results for large-scale statistical inference, including detection, estimation, and multiple testing. We begin with the global testing problem, where the goal is to detect the existence of sparse signals in a data set, and then move to the problem of estimating the proportion of nonnull effects. Finally, we focus on multiple testing with false discovery rate (FDR) control. The FDR provides a powerful and practical approach to large-scale multiple testing and has been successfully used in a wide range of applications. We discuss several effective data-driven procedures and also present efficient strategies to handle various grouping, hierarchical, and dependency structures in the data.</description><author>Cai, T. Tony; Sun, Wenguang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Patents Affect Research Investments?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williams, Heidi L.
Although patent systems have been widely used both historically and internationally, there is nonetheless a tremendous amount of controversy over whether patent systems, in practice, improve the alignment between private returns and social contributions. In this article, I describe three parameters-how the disclosure function affects research investments, how patent strength affects research investments in new technologies, and how patents on existing technologies affect follow-on innovation-needed to inform the question of how patents affect research investments, and review the available evidence that has attempted to empirically estimate these parameters.</description><author>Williams, Heidi L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear Panel Data Methods for Dynamic Heterogeneous Agent Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arellano, Manuel; Bonhomme, Stephane
Recent developments in nonlinear panel data analysis allow the identification and estimation of general dynamic systems. We review some results and techniques for nonparametric identification and flexible estimation in the presence of time-invariant and time-varying latent variables. This opens up the possibility of estimating nonlinear reduced forms in a large class of structural dynamic models with heterogeneous agents. We show how such reduced forms may be used to document policy-relevant derivative effects and to improve the understanding and implementation of structural models.</description><author>Arellano, Manuel; Bonhomme, Stephane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mobile Money</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Suri, Tavneet
This review provides an overview of the operations and impacts of mobile money in the developing world. Over the past decade, mobile money has become a ubiquitous tool in some developing economies, allowing individuals to digitally transact money without formal bank accounts. The impacts, where documented, have been sizeable: For example, poverty decreased by two percentage points in Kenya. However, adoption still lags in many economies and, even where there is universal adoption, product innovation over the rails of these digital accounts has been slow. The review concludes by discussing what the future of mobile money in developing economies may look like and, thus, where the most exciting opportunities for research may be.</description><author>Suri, Tavneet</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The History and Economics of Safe Assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, Gary
Safe assets play a critical role in an(y) economy. A safe asset is an asset that is (almost always) valued at face value without expensive and prolonged analysis. By design, there is no benefit to producing (private) information about its value, and this is common knowledge. Consequently, agents need not fear adverse selection when buying or selling safe assets. Safe assets can be easily used to exchange for goods or services or for another asset. These short-term safe assets can be money or money-like. A long-term safe asset can store value over time or be used as collateral. Much of human history can be written in terms of the search for and production of safe assets. But the most prevalent, privately produced short-term safe assets, bank debts, are subject to runs, and this has important implications for macroeconomics and for monetary policy.</description><author>Gorton, Gary</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Liquidity: A Selective Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Benjamin H.; Domanski, Dietrich; Fender, Ingo; Shin, Hyun Song
Global liquidity is a catch-all term that is used to denote the combination of easier financing conditions, capital inflows, and exchange rate appreciation. An approach based on the activities of internationally active financial institutions sheds light on the conceptual underpinnings and the economic mechanisms involved in the transmission of global liquidity. The analysis highlights the role of international funding currencies, especially the US dollar. The analysis also motivates a set of global liquidity indicators based on the size and currency composition of balance sheets.</description><author>Cohen, Benjamin H.; Domanski, Dietrich; Fender, Ingo; Shin, Hyun Song</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-Skilled Migration and Agglomeration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kerr, Sari Pekkala; Kerr, William; Ozden, Caglar; Parsons, Christopher
This article reviews recent research regarding high-skilled migration. We adopt a data-driven perspective, bringing together and describing several ongoing research streams that range from the construction of global migration databases, to the legal codification of national policies regarding high-skilled migration, to the analysis of patent data regarding cross-border inventor movements. A common theme throughout this research is the importance of agglomeration economies for explaining high-skilled migration. We highlight some key recent findings and outline major gaps in the literature that we hope will be tackled in the near future.</description><author>Kerr, Sari Pekkala; Kerr, William; Ozden, Caglar; Parsons, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agricultural Insurance and Economic Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cole, Shawn A.; Xiong, Wentao
This article provides a review of recent research on agricultural insurance (AI) in developing countries. Agricultural producers face a variety of significant risks; historically, only government-subsidized products have achieved widespread adoption. A recent contractual innovation, which links insurance payouts to realized weather rather than farmer indemnity, has spurred substantial research in the past decade. This review begins by describing the experience in developed economies and then turns to developing countries, covering the following topics: farmers' adoption of AI, how AI affects their decision to invest in risky assets, and the extent to which AI helps farmers smooth income and consumption. We conclude with suggestions for future research and practice related to AI in developing countries.</description><author>Cole, Shawn A.; Xiong, Wentao</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonparametric Welfare Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hausman, Jerry A.; Newey, Whitney K.
Exact consumer's surplus and deadweight loss are the most widely used welfare and economic efficiency measures. These measures can be computed from demand functions in straightforward ways. Nonparametric estimation can be used to estimate the welfare measures. In doing so, it seems important to account correctly for unobserved heterogeneity, given the high degree of unexplained demand variation often found in applications. This review surveys work on nonparametric welfare analysis, focusing on work that allows for general heterogeneity in demand, such as that of Hausman &amp; Newey (2016).</description><author>Hausman, Jerry A.; Newey, Whitney K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Unemployment Insurance Benefits: New Evidence and Interpretation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmieder, Johannes F.; von Wachter, Till
The Great Recession has renewed interest in unemployment insurance (UI) programs around the world. At the same time, there have been important advances in both theory and measurement of UI. In this review, we first use the theory to present a unified treatment of the welfare effects of UI benefit levels and durations and derive convenient expressions of the full disincentive effect of UI. We then discuss recent estimates of the effect of UI benefit levels and durations on labor supply based on newly available administrative data and quasi-experimental research designs. Although our review of the new estimates confirms the range of negative labor supply effects of the previous literature, we show, based on the model, that these estimates are imperfect proxies for the actual disincentive effects. We also discuss several active areas of research on UI. These include the effect of UI on aggregate labor market outcomes, its effect on job outcomes, its long-term effects, its effects under nonstandard behavioral assumptions, and its interactions with other programs. We isolate several additional areas in need of further research, including estimates of the social value of UI, as well as the effects of UI in less developed countries.</description><author>Schmieder, Johannes F.; von Wachter, Till</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armstrong, Mark
I examine the use of nonlinear pricing as a method of price discrimination, both with monopoly and oligopoly supply. Topics covered include an analysis of when it is profitable to offer quantity discounts and bundle discounts, connections between second- and third-degree price discrimination, the use of market demand functions to calculate nonlinear tariffs, the impact of consumers with bounded rationality, bundling arrangements between separate sellers, and the choice of prices for quality upgrades and add-on products.</description><author>Armstrong, Mark</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choice Complexity and Market Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spiegler, Ran
Consumers often find it hard to make correct value comparisons between market alternatives. Part of this choice complexity is the result of deliberate obfuscation by firms. This review synthesizes a theoretical literature that analyzes the role of choice complexity in otherwise competitive markets. I identify two general classes of market models in the literature: (a) The obfuscation strategy of firms is an independent framing device that affects the probability with which consumers make correct comparisons, and (b) market alternatives are multiattribute objects, and obfuscation is captured by lopsided location in attribute space, lowering the probability of being dominated by another market alternative. I address the following key questions: What determines the amount of choice complexity in market equilibrium? What is the relation between choice complexity and payoff-relevant aspects of the market outcome? What is the role of consumer protection measures? The models surveyed in this review suggest that equilibrium obfuscation and choice complexity increase in response to intensified competition, mitigating the positive effect of competition on consumer welfare. However, equilibrium effects can also attenuate the positive welfare effects of regulatory interventions.</description><author>Spiegler, Ran</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The China Shock: Learning from Labor-Market Adjustment to Large Changes in Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Autor, David H.; Dorn, David; Hanson, Gordon H.
China's emergence as a great economic power has induced an epochal shift in patterns of world trade. Simultaneously, it has challenged much of the received empirical wisdom about how labor markets adjust to trade shocks. Alongside the heralded consumer benefits of expanded trade are substantial adjustment costs and distributional consequences. These impacts are most visible in the local labor markets in which the industries exposed to foreign competition are concentrated. Adjustment in local labor markets is remarkably slow, with wages and labor-force participation rates remaining depressed and unemployment rates remaining elevated for at least a full decade after the China trade shock commences. Exposed workers experience greater job churning and reduced lifetime income. At the national level, employment has fallen in the US industries more exposed to import competition, as expected, but offsetting employment gains in other industries have yet to materialize. Better understanding when and where trade is costly, and how and why it may be beneficial, is a key item on the research agenda for trade and labor economists.</description><author>Autor, David H.; Dorn, David; Hanson, Gordon H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reputation and Feedback Systems in Online Platform Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tadelis, Steven
Online marketplaces have become ubiquitous, as sites such as eBay, Taobao, Uber, and Airbnb are frequented by billions of users. The success of these marketplaces is attributed to not only the ease in which buyers can find sellers, but also the trust that these marketplaces help facilitate through reputation and feedback systems. I begin by briefly describing the basic ideas surrounding the role of reputation in facilitating trust and trade, and offer an overview of how feedback and reputation systems work in online marketplaces. I then describe the literature that explores the effects of reputation and feedback systems on online marketplaces and highlight some of the problems of bias in feedback and reputation systems as they appear today. I discuss ways to address these problems to improve the practical design of online marketplaces and suggest some directions for future research.</description><author>Tadelis, Steven</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Evolution of Gender Gaps in Industrialized Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Olivetti, Claudia; Petrongolo, Barbara
Women in developed economies have made major advancements in labor markets throughout the past century, but remaining gender differences in pay and employment seem remarkably persistent. This article documents long-run trends in female employment, working hours, and relative wages for a wide cross section of developed economies. It reviews existing work on the factors driving gender convergence, and novel perspectives on remaining gender gaps. Finally, the article emphasizes the interplay between gender trends and the evolution of the industry structure. Based on a shift-share decomposition, it shows that the growth in the service share can explain at least half of the overall variation in female hours, both over time and across countries.</description><author>Olivetti, Claudia; Petrongolo, Barbara</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bunching</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kleven, Henrik Jacobsen
Recent years have seen a surge of applied work using bunching approaches, a development that is closely linked to the increased availability of administrative data. These approaches exploit the incentives for bunching created by discontinuities in the slope of choice sets (kinks) or in the level of choice sets (notches) to study the behavior of individuals and firms. Although the bunching approach was originally developed in the context of taxation, it is beginning to find applications in many other areas, such as social security, social insurance, welfare programs, education, regulation, private sector prices, and reference-dependent preferences. This review provides a guide to bunching estimation, discusses its strengths and weaknesses, surveys a range of applications across fields, and considers reasons for the ubiquity of kinks and notches.</description><author>Kleven, Henrik Jacobsen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer-to-Peer Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Einav, Liran; Farronato, Chiara; Levin, Jonathan
Peer-to-peer markets such as eBay, Uber, and Airbnb allow small suppliers to compete with traditional providers of goods or services. We view the primary function of these markets as making it easy for buyers to find sellers and engage in convenient, trustworthy transactions. We discuss elements of market design that make this possible, including search and matching algorithms, pricing, and reputation systems. We then develop a simple model of how these markets enable entry by small or flexible suppliers, and how they impact existing firms. Finally, we consider the regulation of peer-to-peer markets and the economic arguments for different approaches to licensing and certification, data, and employment regulation.</description><author>Einav, Liran; Farronato, Chiara; Levin, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active Labor Market Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crepon, Bruno; van den Berg, Gerard J.
Active labor market policies are massively used with the objective being to improve labor market outcomes of individuals out of work. Many observational evaluation studies have been published. In this review, we critically assess policy effectiveness. We emphasize insights from recent randomized controlled trials. In addition, we examine policy effects that have not been the primary object of most of the past evaluations, such as anticipatory effects of advance knowledge of future treatments and equilibrium effects, and we discuss the actual implementation of policies. We discuss the importance of heterogeneity of programs and effects and examine the extent to which potential participants are interested in enrollment. We also discuss the assessment of costs and benefits of programs.</description><author>Crepon, Bruno; van den Berg, Gerard J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Infrequent but Long-Lived Zero Lower Bound Episodes and the Optimal Rate of Inflation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dordal i Carreras, Marc; Coibion, Olivier; Gorodnichenko, Yuriy; Wieland, Johannes
Countries rarely hit the zero lower bound (ZLB) on interest rates, but when they do, these episodes tend to be very long-lived. These two features are difficult to incorporate jointly into macroeconomic models using typical representations of shock processes. We introduce a regime-switching representation of risk premium shocks into an otherwise standard New Keynesian model to generate a realistic distribution of ZLB durations. We discuss what different calibrations of this model imply for optimal inflation rates.</description><author>Dordal i Carreras, Marc; Coibion, Olivier; Gorodnichenko, Yuriy; Wieland, Johannes</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Has the Cyclicality of Productivity Changed? What Does It Mean?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernald, John G.; Wang, J. Christina
US labor and total factor productivity have historically been procyclical-rising in booms and falling in recessions. After the mid-1980s, however, total factor productivity became much less procyclical with respect to hours while labor productivity turned strongly countercyclical. We find that the key empirical "fact" driving these changes is reduced variation in factor utilization-conceptually, the workweek of capital and labor effort. We discuss a range of theories that seek to explain the changes in productivity's cyclicality. Increased flexibility, changes in the structure of the economy, and shifts in relative variances of technology and "demand" shocks all play key roles.</description><author>Fernald, John G.; Wang, J. Christina</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring and Modeling Attention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caplin, Andrew
This article presents a selective review of economic research on attentional choice, taking an observation of Block &amp; Marschak (1960) as its starting point. Because standard choice data conflate utilities and perception, they point out that it is inadequate for research in which attention is endogenous. The review focuses on their thesis that advances in our understanding of attention require modeling of novel choice-based data sets, and corresponding methods of measurement. By way of example, recent attentional research based on measuring and modeling state-dependent stochastic choice data is detailed. Next research steps in relation to strategic attention and the dynamics of learning are outlined. If the thesis of Block &amp; Marschak is valid, engineering of new data sets will become an increasingly essential professional activity as attentional research advances.</description><author>Caplin, Andrew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identification in Differentiated Products Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berry, Steven; Haile, Philip
Empirical models of differentiated products demand (and often supply) are widely used in industrial organization and other fields of economics. We review some recent work studying identification in a broad class of such models. This work shows that the parametric functional forms and distributional assumptions commonly used for estimation are not essential for identification. Rather, identification relies primarily on the standard requirement that instruments be available for the endogenous variables-here, typically, prices and quantities. We discuss the types of instruments that can suffice, as well as how instrumental variables requirements can be relaxed by the availability of individual-level data or through restrictions on preferences. We also review new results on discrimination between alternative models of oligopoly competition. Together, these results reveal a strong nonparametric foundation for a broad applied literature, provide practical guidance for applied work, and may suggest new approaches to estimation and testing.</description><author>Berry, Steven; Haile, Philip</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Econometric Analysis of Large Factor Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Jushan; Wang, Peng
Large factor models use a few latent factors to characterize the co-movement of economic variables in a high-dimensional data set. High dimensionality brings challenges as well as new insights into the advancement of econometric theory. Because of their ability to effectively summarize information in large data sets, factor models have been increasingly used in economics and finance. The factors, estimated from the high-dimensional data, can, for example, help improve forecasting, provide efficient instruments, control for nonlinear unobserved heterogeneity, and capture cross-sectional dependence. This article reviews the theory on estimation and statistical inference of large factor models. It also discusses important applications and highlights future directions.</description><author>Bai, Jushan; Wang, Peng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting in Economics and Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elliott, Graham; Timmermann, Allan
Practices used to address economic forecasting problems have undergone substantial changes over recent years. We review how such changes have influenced the ways in which a range of forecasting questions are being addressed. We also discuss the promises and challenges arising from access to big data. Finally, we review empirical evidence and experience accumulated from the use of forecasting methods to a range of economic and financial variables.</description><author>Elliott, Graham; Timmermann, Allan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Comparative Household Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Badarinza, Cristian; Campbell, John Y.; Ramadorai, Tarun
This article reviews the literature on international comparative household finance. It presents summary statistics on household balance sheets for 13 developed countries and uses these statistics to discuss common features and contrasts across countries. It then discusses retirement savings, investments in risky assets, unsecured debt, and mortgages.</description><author>Badarinza, Cristian; Campbell, John Y.; Ramadorai, Tarun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Paternalism and Energy Efficiency: An Overview</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allcott, Hunt
This article provides an overview of the application of behavioral public economics to energy efficiency. I document policy makers' arguments for "paternalistic" energy efficiency policies, formalize with a simple model of misoptimizing consumers, review and critique empirical evidence, and suggest future research directions. Although empirical results suggest that policies to address imperfect information and internalities may increase welfare in some cases, some existing policies may be mistargeted or miscalibrated.</description><author>Allcott, Hunt</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Savings After Retirement: A Survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Nardi, Mariacristina; French, Eric; Jones, John Bailey
The saving patterns of retired US households pose a challenge to the basic life-cycle model of saving. The observed patterns of out-of-pocket medical expenses, which rise quickly with age and income during retirement, and heterogeneous life span risk can explain a significant portion of US saving during retirement. However, more work is needed to distinguish these precautionary saving motives from other motives, such as the desire to leave bequests. Progress toward disentangling these motivations has been made by matching other features of the data, such as public and private insurance choices. An improved understanding of whether intended bequests left to children and spouses are due to altruism, risk sharing, exchange motivations, or a combination of these factors is an important direction for future research.</description><author>De Nardi, Mariacristina; French, Eric; Jones, John Bailey</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Patents and Innovation in Economic History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moser, Petra
A strong tradition in economic history, which relies primarily on qualitative evidence and statistical correlations, has emphasized the importance of patents as a primary driver of innovation. Recent improvements in empirical methodology-through the creation of new datasets and advances in identification-have produced research that challenges this traditional view. The findings of this literature provide a more nuanced view of the effects of intellectual property and suggest that when patent rights have been too broad or too strong, they have actually discouraged innovation. This review summarizes the major results from this research and presents open questions.</description><author>Moser, Petra</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Methods for Nonparametric and Semiparametric Regressions with Endogeneity: A Gentle Guide</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Xiaohong; Qiu, Yin Jia Jeff
This article reviews recent advances in estimation and inference for nonparametric and semiparametric models with endogeneity. It first describes methods of sieves and penalization for estimating unknown functions identified via conditional moment restrictions. Examples include nonparametric instrumental variables (NPIV) regression, nonparametric quantile IV regression, and many more semi/nonparametric structural models. Asymptotic properties of the sieve estimators and the sieve Wald, quasi-likelihood ratio hypothesis tests of functionals with nonparametric endogeneity are presented. For sieve NPIV estimation, the rate-adaptive data-driven choices of sieve regularization parameters and the sieve score bootstrap uniform confidence bands are described. Finally, simple sieve variance estimation and overidentification tests for the semiparametric two-step generalized method of moments are reviewed. Monte Carlo examples are also included.</description><author>Chen, Xiaohong; Qiu, Yin Jia Jeff</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Health Care Spending: Historical Trends and New Directions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Alice; Goldman, Dana
Over the past five decades, broad changes in the US health care system have dramatically influenced growth in health care expenditures. This review identifies the salient factors driving the growth of medical expenditures and how they influenced the trajectory of health economics research. We find that the research identified-and was strongly influenced by-four eras of expenditure growth: period 1, coverage expansion; period 2, experimentation with financial incentives; period 3, the managed care backlash; and period 4, a golden era of declining expenditure growth. We conclude by discussing some themes from this research suggesting optimism that, going forward, we can curb excess expenditure growth above GDP growth without harming population health.</description><author>Chen, Alice; Goldman, Dana</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Advances in the Measurement Error Literature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schennach, Susanne M.
This article reviews recent significant progress made in developing estimation and inference methods for nonlinear models in the presence of mis-measured data that may or may not conform to the classical assumption of independent zero-mean errors. The aim is to cover a broad range of methods having differing levels of complexity and strength of the required assumptions. Simple approaches that form the elementary building blocks of more advanced approaches are discussed first. Then, special attention is devoted to methods that rely on readily available auxiliary variables (e.g., repeated measurements, indicators, or instrumental variables). Results relaxing most of the commonly invoked simplifying assumptions are presented (linear measurement structure, independent errors, zero-mean errors, availability of auxiliary information). This article also provides an overview of important connections with related fields, such as latent variable models, nonlinear panel data, factor models, and set identification, and applications of the methods to other fields traditionally unrelated to measurement error models.</description><author>Schennach, Susanne M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Media and Politics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stromberg, David
This article provides a review of recent literature in economics on the effect of mass media on politics. The focus is on the welfare effects of mass media. I also discuss the likely implications of existing behavioral theories of media effects, developed outside of economics.</description><author>Stromberg, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy Implications of Dynamic Public Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golosov, Mikhail; Tsyvinski, Aleh
The dynamic public finance literature underwent significant changes over the past decade. This research agenda has now reached a stage at which it is able to analyze the design of social insurance programs and optimal taxation in rich environments that can be closely matched to microeconomic data. We provide an overview of the recent advances in this literature, discuss the key trade-offs, and explain how the prescriptions for the optimal policy depend on the specific parameters that can be estimated in the data. We also describe the relationship between the dynamic mechanism design approach to optimal taxation and the approach that considers sophisticated tax functions chosen within parametrically restricted classes.</description><author>Golosov, Mikhail; Tsyvinski, Aleh</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Roots of Gender Inequality in Developing Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jayachandran, Seema
Is the high degree of gender inequality in developing countries-in education, personal autonomy, and more-explained by underdevelopment itself? Or do the societies that are poor today hold certain cultural views that lead to gender inequality? This article discusses several mechanisms through which gender gaps narrow as countries grow. I argue that although much of the GDP/gender-inequality relationship can be explained by the process of development, society-specific factors are also at play: Many countries that are poor today have cultural norms that exacerbate favoritism toward males. Norms such as patrilocality and concern for women's "purity" help explain the male-skewed sex ratio in India and China and low female employment in India, the Middle East, and North Africa, for example. I also discuss why the sex ratio has become more male-skewed with development. Finally, I lay out some policy approaches to address gender inequality.</description><author>Jayachandran, Seema</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Ricardo: Assignment Models in International Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Costinot, Arnaud; Vogel, Jonathan
International trade has experienced a Ricardian revival. In this article, we offer a user guide to assignment models, which we refer to as Ricardo-Roy (R-R) models, that have contributed to this revival.</description><author>Costinot, Arnaud; Vogel, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Decentralization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mookherjee, Dilip
I provide a critical overview of the literature on political decentralization. After reviewing first- and second-generation theories of federalism, I describe recent empirical studies focusing mainly on determinants of capture and local government accountability emphasized by second-generation theories. The article concludes by describing emerging new issues that deserve more attention in future research: a wider range of political distortions beyond capture and corruption; effects of decentralization on intercommunity allocations, learning, and experimentation, and on democracy itself; a comparison of decentralization with other organizational alternatives; and issues pertaining to design and implementation raised by first-generation federalism theories, such as interjurisdictional spillovers, vertical fiscal relations, the range of devolution, and the political economy of implementation.</description><author>Mookherjee, Dilip</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Household Debt: Facts, Puzzles, Theories, and Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zinman, Jonathan
Borrowing decisions affect most households, with large stakes and implications for research subfields as varied as macroeconomics and industrial organization. I review theoretical and empirical work on household debt: its prevalence, level, growth, and composition, as well as various measures of consumer choice and market (in) efficiency, elasticities, and prices, including new evidence on how borrowing heterogeneity affects the distribution of the opportunity cost of consumption. I also discuss opportunities and challenges in policy evaluation. A key takeaway is that puzzles abound, and I highlight numerous avenues for further research.</description><author>Zinman, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making Progress on Foreign Aid</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Nancy
Foreign aid is one of the most important policy tools that rich countries use to help poor countries improve population well-being and facilitate economic and institutional development. The empirical evidence on its benefits is mixed and has generated much controversy. This article presents descriptive statistics that show that foreign aid to very poor countries accounts for very little of total global aid; reviews the evidence that foreign aid is often determined by the objectives of donor countries rather than the needs of recipient countries; argues that the evidence on the impact of aggregate foreign aid is hindered by problems of measurement and identification, which partly result from the heterogeneous nature of aid; and discusses recent studies using natural and randomized experiments to examine narrowed definitions of aid on more disaggregated outcomes.</description><author>Qian, Nancy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reconciling Micro and Macro Labor Supply Elasticities: A Structural Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keane, Michael; Rogerson, Richard
The response of aggregate labor supply to various changes in the economic environment is central to many economic issues, including the optimal design of tax policies. Whereas the earlier literature often concluded that aggregate labor supply elasticities were small, we argue that recent work using structural models and micro data credibly supports large aggregate elasticities. We focus on three issues. First, earlier analyses abstracted from several key features, including human capital accumulation, that severely negatively biased estimates of a key preference parameter. Second, failure to understand that aggregate labor supply adjustments can occur along both the hours per worker and employment margins has led economists to misinterpret the implications of preference parameters for aggregate labor supply. Third, structural estimation of models that feature choice along the extensive margin using micro data typically finds large responses.</description><author>Keane, Michael; Rogerson, Richard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Climate and Conflict</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burke, Marshall; Hsiang, Solomon M.; Miguel, Edward
We review the emerging literature on climate and conflict. We consider multiple types of human conflict, including both interpersonal conflict, such as assault and murder, and intergroup conflict, including riots and civil war. We discuss key methodological issues in estimating causal relationships and largely focus on natural experiments that exploit variation in climate over time. Using a hierarchical meta-analysis that allows us to both estimate the mean effect and quantify the degree of variability across 55 studies, we find that deviations from moderate temperatures and precipitation patterns systematically increase conflict risk. Contemporaneous temperature has the largest average impact, with each 1 sigma increase in temperature increasing interpersonal conflict by 2.4% and intergroup conflict by 11.3%. We conclude by highlighting research priorities, including a better understanding of the mechanisms linking climate to conflict, societies' ability to adapt to climatic changes, and the likely impacts of future global warming.</description><author>Burke, Marshall; Hsiang, Solomon M.; Miguel, Edward</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurship and Financial Frictions: A Macrodevelopment Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buera, Francisco J.; Kaboski, Joseph P.; Shin, Yongseok
We review both the theoretical and empirical literature on entrepreneurship and financial frictions, with an emphasis on the heterogeneous and dynamic microlevel implications of financial frictions for macrodevelopment.</description><author>Buera, Francisco J.; Kaboski, Joseph P.; Shin, Yongseok</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crime and Economic Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Draca, Mirko; Machin, Stephen
In economic models of crime, changing economic incentives alter the participation of individuals in criminal activities. We critically appraise the work in this area. After a brief overview of the workhorse economics of crime model for organizing our discussion on crime and economic incentives, we first document the significant rise of the economics of crime as a research field and then go on to review the evidence on the relationship between crime and economic incentives. We divide this discussion into incentives operating through legal wages in the formal labor market and the economic returns to illegal activities. Evidence that economic incentives matter for crime emerges from both.</description><author>Draca, Mirko; Machin, Stephen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting in Nonstationary Environments: What Works and What Doesn't in Reduced-Form and Structural Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giacomini, Raffaella; Rossi, Barbara
This review provides an overview of forecasting methods that can help researchers forecast in the presence of nonstationarities caused by instabilities. The emphasis of the review is both theoretical and applied, and we provide several examples of interest to economists. We show that modeling instabilities can help, but it depends on how they are modeled. We also demonstrate how to robustify a model against instabilities.</description><author>Giacomini, Raffaella; Rossi, Barbara</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Trade, Multinational Activity, and Corporate Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foley, C. Fritz; Manova, Kalina
An emerging new literature brings unique ideas from corporate finance to the study of international trade and investment. Insights about differences in the development of financial institutions across countries, the role of financial constraints, and the use of internal capital markets are proving central in understanding international economics. The ability to access financial capital to pay fixed and variable costs affects choices firms make regarding export entry and operations and, as a consequence, influences aggregate trade patterns. Financial frictions and the use of internal capital markets shape decisions that multinationals make regarding production locations, integration, and corporate governance. This article surveys this recent research with the goal of highlighting the main themes it explores, the key results it establishes, and the leading open questions it raises.</description><author>Foley, C. Fritz; Manova, Kalina</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Knowledge-Based Hierarchies: Using Organizations to Understand the Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garicano, Luis; Rossi-Hansberg, Esteban
Incorporating the decision of how to organize the acquisition, use, and communication of knowledge into economic models is essential to understand a wide variety of economic phenomena. We survey the literature that has used knowledge-based hierarchies to study issues such as the evolution of wage inequality, the growth and productivity of firms, economic development, and the gains from international trade, as well as offshoring and the formation of international production teams. Wealso review the nascent empirical literature that has, so far, confirmed the importance of organizational decisions and many of their more salient implications.</description><author>Garicano, Luis; Rossi-Hansberg, Esteban</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit, Financial Stability, and the Macroeconomy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Alan M.
Since the 2008 global financial crisis, and after decades of relative neglect, the importance of the financial system and its episodic crises as drivers of macroeconomic outcomes has attracted fresh scrutiny from academics, policy makers, and practitioners. Theoretical advances are following a lead set by a fast-growing empirical literature. Recent long-run historical work has uncovered a range of important stylized facts concerning financial instability and the role of credit in advanced economies, and this article provides an overview of the key findings.</description><author>Taylor, Alan M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supplemental Appendix for "Valid Post-Selection and Post-Regularization Inference: An Elementary, General Approach"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernozhukov, Victor; Hansen, Christian; Spindler, Martin
nan</description><author>Chernozhukov, Victor; Hansen, Christian; Spindler, Martin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valid Post-Selection and Post-Regularization Inference: An Elementary, General Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernozhukov, Victor; Hansen, Christian; Spindler, Martin
We present an expository, general analysis of valid post-selection or post-regularization inference about a low-dimensional target parameter in the presence of a very high-dimensional nuisance parameter that is estimated using selection or regularization methods. Our analysis provides a set of high-level conditions under which inference for the low-dimensional parameter based on testing or point estimation methods will be regular despite selection or regularization biases occurring in the estimation of the high-dimensional nuisance parameter. A key element is the use of so-called immunized or orthogonal estimating equations that are locally insensitive to small mistakes in the estimation of the high-dimensional nuisance parameter. As an illustration, we analyze affine-quadratic models and specialize these results to a linear instrumental variables model with many regressors and many instruments. We conclude with a review of other developments in post-selection inference and note that many can be viewed as special cases of the general encompassing framework of orthogonal estimating equations provided in this article.</description><author>Chernozhukov, Victor; Hansen, Christian; Spindler, Martin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Gains from Market Integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donaldson, Dave
How large are the gains from product market integration-or, equivalently, from a reduction in barriers to trade over space? This article surveys recent work on this question in the context of both international and intranational trade.</description><author>Donaldson, Dave</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Schumpeterian Growth Paradigm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aghion, Philippe; Akcigit, Ufuk; Howitt, Peter
In this review, we argue that the Schumpeterian growth paradigm, which models growth as resulting from innovations involving creative destruction, sheds light on several aspects of the growth process that cannot be properly addressed by alternative theories. We focus on three important aspects for which Schumpeterian growth theory delivers predictions that distinguish it from other growth models, namely, (a) the role of competition and market structure, (b) firm dynamics, and (c) the relationship between growth and development.</description><author>Aghion, Philippe; Akcigit, Ufuk; Howitt, Peter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is College a Worthwhile Investment?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barrow, Lisa; Malamud, Ofer
This article surveys the existing evidence on the return to a college education and offers new calculations based on recent data. We focus on an individual's decision and outline the standard conceptual framework used by economists to analyze investments in education. We then compare alternative estimates of the value of a college education in the literature and reconcile them with our own preferred estimates. We also conduct a selective review of the literature seeking to estimate the causal effects of college on pecuniary and nonpecuniary outcomes. Finally, we provide additional calculations showing the heterogeneity in returns to college across certain institutional and demographic characteristics, review the related academic literature, and discuss the risk associated with a college investment. We conclude that college is certainly a worthwhile investment on average and likely worthwhile for many subgroups, although not necessarily for everyone.</description><author>Barrow, Lisa; Malamud, Ofer</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Affirmative Action in Undergraduate Education</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arcidiacono, Peter; Lovenheim, Michael; Zhu, Maria
The use of race in college admissions is one of the most contentious issues in US higher education. We survey the literature on the impact of racial preferences in college admissions on both minority and majority students. With regard to minority students, particular attention is paid to the scope of preferences as well as how preferences affect graduation, choice of major, and labor market earnings. We also examine how schools respond to bans on racial preferences and the effects these responses have on racial diversity at elite schools. With regard to majority students, we examine the evidence on the returns to attending a more racially diverse school, as well as how racial preferences affect friendship formation. Finally, we supplement studies of affirmative action in the United States with evidence from India, which provides a much more straightforward environment in which to study affirmative action owing to the use of quotas and admissions rules based solely on exam scores.</description><author>Arcidiacono, Peter; Lovenheim, Michael; Zhu, Maria</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Methods of Identification in Social Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, Bryan S.
Social and economic networks are ubiquitous, serving as contexts for job search, technology diffusion, the accumulation of human capital, and even the formulation of norms and values. The systematic empirical study of network formation-the process by which agents form, maintain, and dissolve links-within economics is recent, is associated with extraordinarily challenging modeling and identification issues, and is an area of exciting new developments, with many open questions. This article reviews prominent research on the empirical analysis of network formation, with an emphasis on contributions made by economists.</description><author>Graham, Bryan S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The US Electricity Industry After 20 Years of Restructuring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borenstein, Severin; Bushnell, James
Electricity restructuring in the 1990s ended the era of vertically integrated monopolies in many states, allowing nonutility generators to sell electricity to utilities and, in fewer states, allowing retail service providers to buy electricity from generators and sell to end-use customers. We review the economic arguments for restructuring and the resulting effects in subsequent years. Weargue that the greatest political motivation for restructuring was rent shifting, not efficiency improvements. Although electricity restructuring has brought efficiency improvements, it has generally been viewed as a disappointment because the price-reduction promises made by some advocates were based on politically unsustainable rent transfers. In reality, electricity rate changes since restructuring have been driven more by exogenous factors, such as generation technology advances and natural gas price fluctuations, than by restructuring. We argue that a similar dynamic underpins the current political momentum behind distributed generation, primarily rooftop solar photovoltaic systems, which remains costly from a societal viewpoint, but privately economic owing to the rent transfers it enables.</description><author>Borenstein, Severin; Bushnell, James</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Evolution of Social Norms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Young, H. Peyton
Social norms are patterns of behavior that are self-enforcing within a group: Everyone conforms, everyone is expected to conform, and everyone wants to conform when they expect everyone else to conform. Social norms are often sustained by multiple mechanisms, including a desire to coordinate, fear of being sanctioned, signaling membership in a group, or simply following the lead of others. This article shows how stochastic evolutionary game theory can be used to study the resulting dynamics. I illustrate with a variety of examples drawn from economics, sociology, demography, and political science. These include bargaining norms, norms governing the terms of contracts, norms of retirement, dueling, foot binding, medical treatment, and the use of contraceptives. These cases highlight the challenges of applying the theory to empirical cases. They also show that the modern theory of norm dynamics yields insights and predictions that go beyond conventional equilibrium analysis.</description><author>Young, H. Peyton</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Job Creation, Job Destruction, and Productivity Growth: The Role of Young Businesses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haltiwanger, John
Recent improvements in the data infrastructure at US statistical agencies have dramatically enhanced the ability to measure and study job creation and job destruction. The longitudinal data now permit the tracking of all firms and establishments in the US private sector in a comprehensive and integrated manner. This allows researchers to distinguish between the contribution of new firms and that of new establishments. In addition, firm entry, growth, and survival dynamics can be tracked in terms of organic changes instead of changes associated with mergers and acquisitions or other forms of business ownership changes. These new developments have led to a burgeoning literature on US firm dynamics. The recent literature has especially focused on the role of young businesses for job and productivity growth. The findings from that literature are the focus of the current article. The recent developments are discussed in light of the large literature on firm dynamics (in terms of both theory and empirics) that has developed over the past few decades.</description><author>Haltiwanger, John</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Endowment Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ericson, Keith M. Marzilli; Fuster, Andreas
The endowment effect is among the best known findings in behavioral economics and has been used as evidence for theories of reference-dependent preferences and loss aversion. However, a recent literature has questioned the robustness of the effect in the laboratory, as well as its relevance in the field. In this review, we provide a summary of the evidence and describe recent theoretical developments that can potentially reconcile the different findings, with a focus on expectation-based reference points. We also survey recent work from psychology that provides either alternatives to or refinements of the usual loss-aversion explanation. We argue that loss aversion is still the leading paradigm for understanding the endowment effect, but given the rich psychology behind the effect, a version of the theory that encompasses multiple reference points may be required.</description><author>Ericson, Keith M. Marzilli; Fuster, Andreas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quality of Primary Care in Low-Income Countries: Facts and Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, Jishnu; Hammer, Jeffrey
New research on the quality of care in public and private primary care facilities has significantly enriched our understanding of how health care is delivered in low-and middle-income countries. First, this article summarizes recent advances in the measurement of quality, distinguishing between measurements of provider knowledge and provider effort. Second, it looks at the determinants of practice quality variation in low-income settings, highlighting the limited role of structural constraints such as infrastructure, the supply of materials including drugs, and provider training-the mainstay of much of global health policy today. In contrast, practice quality variation is clearly linked to provider effort, an aspect of provider behavior that can be altered through a variety of means. Third, it provides a broad economic framework to interpret the findings. We look for evidence of specific market failures in the provision of primary care and emphasize that the key difficulty is (and always was) the transaction-specific nature of medical advice. Providers can do too much or too little (or both), and the extent of either depends on the specific patient and the specific disease. We document specific ways in which it is difficult for both consumers and governments to monitor every transaction to detect potentially errant behavior.</description><author>Das, Jishnu; Hammer, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ill-Posed Inverse Problems in Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horowitz, Joel L.
A parameter of an econometric model is identified if there is a one-to-one or many-to-one mapping from the population distribution of the available data to the parameter. Often, this mapping is obtained by inverting a mapping from the parameter to the population distribution. If the inverse mapping is discontinuous, then estimation of the parameter usually presents an ill-posed inverse problem. Such problems arise in many settings in economics and other fields in which the parameter of interest is a function. This article explains how ill-posedness arises and why it causes problems for estimation. The need to modify or regularize the identifying mapping is explained, and methods for regularization and estimation are discussed. Methods for forming confidence intervals and testing hypotheses are summarized. It is shown that a hypothesis test can be more precise in a certain sense than an estimator. An empirical example illustrates estimation in an ill-posed setting in economics.</description><author>Horowitz, Joel L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Old Age Dependency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nishiyama, Shinichi; Smetters, Kent
Baby boomers are now retiring in large numbers, and most do not have enough assets of their own to finance retirement. Social insurance programs help baby boomers afford retirement, but these programs are substantially underfunded. Reforming these institutions earlier will produce fewer distortions than continued delays. Several options also exist for helping households prepare for their own retirement: improving financial literacy, more opt-out defaults, better guidance about the value of delaying retirement, better guidance about delaying the claiming of social security benefits, improved estimation of out-of-pocket medical costs, and understanding the incentives facing their financial advisors. Some of these options are likely to be more effective than others.</description><author>Nishiyama, Shinichi; Smetters, Kent</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Developments in Empirical Likelihood and Related Methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parente, Paulo M. D. C.; Smith, Richard J.
This article reviews a number of recent contributions to estimation and inference for models defined by moment condition restrictions. The particular emphasis is on the generalized empirical likelihood class of estimators as an alternative to the generalized method of moments. Estimation methods for parameters defined through moment restrictions and their properties are described with tests of overidentifying moment restrictions and parametric hypotheses. Computational issues are discussed together with some proposals for their amelioration. Higher-order and other properties are also addressed in some detail. Models specified by conditional moment restriction models are considered, and the adaptation of these methods to weakly dependent data is discussed.</description><author>Parente, Paulo M. D. C.; Smith, Richard J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Belief Elicitation in the Laboratory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schotter, Andrew; Trevino, Isabel
One constraint we face as economists is not being able to observe all the relevant variables required to test our theories or make policy prescriptions. Laboratory techniques allow us to convert many variables (such as beliefs) that are unobservable in the field into observables. This article presents a survey of the literature on belief elicitation in laboratory experimental economics. We discuss several techniques available to elicit beliefs in an incentive-compatible manner and the problems involved in their use. We then look at how successful these techniques have been when employed in laboratory studies. We find that despite some problems, beliefs elicited in the laboratory are meaningful (i.e., they are generally used as the basis for behavior), and the process of eliciting beliefs seems not to be too intrusive. One hope for the future is that by eliciting beliefs, we may be able to develop better theories of belief formation.</description><author>Schotter, Andrew; Trevino, Isabel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Precocious Albion: A New Interpretation of the British Industrial Revolution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, Morgan; Mokyr, Joel; Grada, Cormac O.
Many explanations have been offered for the British Industrial Revolution. This article points to the importance of human capital (broadly defined) and the quality of the British labor force on the eve of the Industrial Revolution. It shows that in terms of both physical quality and mechanical skills, British workers around 1750 were at a much higher level than their continental counterparts. As a result, new inventions-no matter where they originated-were adopted earlier, faster, and on a larger scale in Britain than elsewhere. The gap in labor quality is consistent with the higher wages paid in eighteenth-century Britain. The causes for the higher labor quality are explored and found to be associated with a higher level of nutrition and better institutions, especially England's Poor Law and the superior functioning of its apprenticeship system.</description><author>Kelly, Morgan; Mokyr, Joel; Grada, Cormac O.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Design of Funded Pension Schemes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bovenberg, Lans; Mehlkopf, Roel
This article reviews the literature on the optimal design and regulation of funded pension schemes. We first characterize optimal saving and investment over an individual's life cycle. Within a stylized modeling framework, we explore optimal individual saving and investing behavior. Subsequently, various extensions of the model are considered, such as additional financial risk factors, stochastic human capital, and more elaborate individual preferences. We then turn to the literature on intergenerational risk sharing, which suggests that a long-lived entity such as a pension fund or the government can yield ex ante welfare gains by allowing nonoverlapping generations to trade risk. The scope for this type of intergenerational risk sharing, however, is limited by the ability to commit generations to the contract. These commitment problems raise concerns with respect to sustainability and intergenerational fairness. We explore the role of solvency regulations to address these concerns about intergenerational fairness and discontinuity risk.</description><author>Bovenberg, Lans; Mehlkopf, Roel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Models of Caring, or Acting as if One Cared, About the Welfare of Others</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rotemberg, Julio J.
This article surveys the theoretical literature in which people are modeled as taking other people's payoffs into account either because this affects their utility directly or because they wish to impress others with their social-mindedness. Key experimental results that bear on the relevance of these theories are discussed as well. Five types of models are considered. In the first, an individual's utility function is increasing in the payoffs of other people. The more standard version of these preferences supposes that only consumption leads to payoffs and has trouble explaining prosocial actions such as voting and charitable contributions by poor individuals. If one lets other variables determine happiness as well, this model can explain a much wider set of observations. The second type of model surveyed involves people trying to demonstrate to others that they have prosocial (or altruistic) preferences. In these models, altruistic acts need not have a direct effect on utility. The third class of models includes those of reciprocity in which people's altruism depends on whether others act kindly or unkindly toward them. In the fourth type of model, inequality has a profound effect on altruism, with individuals being spiteful toward people whose resources exceed their own. Finally, I discuss the fifth type of model, in which specifications of altruism might have to be modified to take into account how people behave when they are able to transfer lotteries to others.</description><author>Rotemberg, Julio J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decentralization in Developing Economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gadenne, Lucie; Singhal, Monica
Standard models of fiscal federalism suggest many benefits of decentralization in developing economies, and there has been a recent push toward decentralization around the world. However, developing countries presently still have less decentralization, particularly on the revenue side, than both developed countries today and the United States and Europe historically. We consider how the trade-offs associated with fiscal federalism apply in developing countries and discuss reasons for their relatively low levels of decentralization. We also consider additional features relevant to federalism in developing economies, such as the prevalence of nongovernmental organizations and the role of social incentives in policy design.</description><author>Gadenne, Lucie; Singhal, Monica</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous Collateral Constraints and the Leverage Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fostel, Ana; Geanakoplos, John
We review the theory of leverage developed in collateral equilibrium models with incomplete markets. We explain how leverage tends to boost asset prices and create bubbles. We show how leverage can be endogenously determined in equilibrium and how it depends on volatility. We describe the dynamic feedback properties of leverage, volatility, and asset prices, in what we call the leverage cycle, and show how it differs from a credit cycle. We also describe some cross-sectional implications of multiple leverage cycles, including contagion, flight to collateral, and swings in the issuance volume of the highest-quality debt.</description><author>Fostel, Ana; Geanakoplos, John</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rethinking Reciprocity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malmendier, Ulrike; te Velde, Vera L.; Weber, Roberto A.
Reciprocal behavioral has been found to play a significant role in many economic domains, including labor supply, tax compliance, voting behavior, and fund-raising. What explains individuals' tendency to respond to the kindness of others? Existing theories posit internal preferences for the welfare of others, inequality aversion, or utility from repaying others' kindness. However, recent evidence on the determinants of (unilateral) sharing decisions suggests that external factors such as social pressure are equally important. So far, this second wave of social preference theories has had little spillover to two-sided reciprocity environments, in which one individual responds to the actions of another. We present a novel laboratory reciprocity experiment (the double-dictator game with sorting) and show that failure to account for external motives leads to a significant over-estimation of internal motives such as fairness and altruism. The experimental data illustrate the importance of combining reduced-form and structural analyses to disentangle internal and external determinants of prosocial behavior.</description><author>Malmendier, Ulrike; te Velde, Vera L.; Weber, Roberto A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probabilistic Expectations in Developing Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delavande, Adeline
Many decisions are made under uncertainty, and individuals are likely to form subjective expectations about the probabilities of events that are relevant to their decisions. I review here a recent and growing literature that uses probabilistic expectations elicited from survey respondents in developing countries. I first present an illustrativemodel of one particular decision under uncertainty-the choice of a college-to exemplify the importance of subjective expectations data for identification purposes. I then review existing evidence emphasizing that it is feasible to elicit probabilities from survey respondents in low-literacy settings and describe common patterns of answers. Finally, I describe existing applications, many of which seek to assess how expectations influence behavior, in various domains, including health, education, agricultural production, and migration.</description><author>Delavande, Adeline</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Copulas in Econometrics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, Yanqin; Patton, Andrew J.
Copulas are functions that describe the dependence between two or more random variables. This article provides a brief review of copula theory and two areas of economics in which copulas have played important roles: multivariate modeling and partial identification of parameters that depend on the joint distribution of two random variables with fixed or known marginal distributions. We focus on bivariate copulas but provide references on recent advances in constructing higher-dimensional copulas.</description><author>Fan, Yanqin; Patton, Andrew J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Performance in a Global Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Loecker, Jan; Goldberg, Pinelopi Koujianou
In this article, we introduce an empirical framework to analyze how firm performance is affected by increased globalization. Using this framework, we discuss recent work on measuring the impact of various shocks firms face in the global marketplace, such as reductions in trade costs (through lowering tariffs and abolishing quotas). Our analytical framework nests most empirical approaches to estimating the impact of trade and industrial policies on firms active in international markets. We identify outstanding issues surrounding the identification of the underlying mechanisms and conclude with suggestions for future research.</description><author>De Loecker, Jan; Goldberg, Pinelopi Koujianou</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Experimental and Quasi-Experimental Analysis of Peer Effects: Two Steps Forward?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sacerdote, Bruce
In the past 10 years, there has been an explosion of well-identified studies that measure peer effects across many settings and for many outcomes. The emphasis on natural experiments and randomization is a highly useful one; in more standard observational studies, the self-selection of people into peer groups can make the measurement of peer effects extremely difficult. In the absence of exogenous variation, knowing that people have similar outcomes as their friends, classmates, and coworkers may tell us little about peer effects. I examine the successes, failures, and findings of experimental analyses of peer effects. I draw three broad conclusions. First, even more than in other areas of social science, the size and nature of peer effects estimated are highly context specific; peer effects in student test scores and grades are prominent in some cases and absent in others. That said, there is a pattern across studies suggesting that social outcomes (e.g., crime, drinking behavior) and career choices show larger peer influences than do test scores. Second, researchers have shown that the linear-in-means model of peer effects is often not a good description of the world, although we do not yet have an agreed-upon model to replace it. Third, despite potential temptation, we have not reached the point at which we can reliably use knowledge of peer effects to implement policies that improve outcomes for students and other human subjects.</description><author>Sacerdote, Bruce</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Measurement of Household Consumption Expenditures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Browning, Martin; Crossley, Thomas F.; Winter, Joachim
Household-level data on consumer expenditures underpin a wide range of empirical research in modern economics, spanning micro-and macroeconomics. This research includes work on consumption and saving, on poverty and inequality, and on risk sharing and insurance. We review different ways in which such data can be collected or captured: traditional detailed budget surveys, less onerous survey procedures that might be included in more general surveys, and administrative or process data. We discuss the advantages and difficulties of each approach and suggest directions for future investigation.</description><author>Browning, Martin; Crossley, Thomas F.; Winter, Joachim</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Revealed Preference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crawford, Ian; De Rock, Bram
This article aims to provide an introduction to empirical revealed preference (RP) and an overview of the current state of the field. We hope to give a sense of how RP methods work and the types of questions they can address and to assess the strengths and drawbacks of the approach. After briefly recapping the basics of RP theory, we review and critically assess the literature in two main areas representing the principal fields in which recent research has made significant advances: broadening the scope of RP methods and dealing with empirical issues related to bringing RP to the data. We conclude with a discussion of some future directions.</description><author>Crawford, Ian; De Rock, Bram</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange Rate Stabilization and Welfare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engel, Charles
This article considers recent literature on optimal monetary policy in simple open-economy models. The presence of pricing to market, incomplete financial markets, and differences in preferences among households (in different countries) introduces some fundamental differences between closed-and open-economy New Keynesian models. In addition to the goals of stabilizing inflation and the output gap, policy makers may target currency misalignments and global imbalances. Optimal policies may involve targeting the exchange rate both directly, because of currency misalignments, and indirectly, because of the effects of exchange rates on imbalances, inflation, and output gaps.</description><author>Engel, Charles</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Applications of Random Set Theory in Econometrics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Molchanov, Ilya; Molinari, Francesca
In recent years, the econometrics literature has shown a growing interest in the study of partially identified models, in which the object of economic and statistical interest is a set rather than a point. The characterization of this set and the development of consistent estimators and inference procedures for it with desirable properties are the main goals of partial identification analysis. This review introduces the fundamental tools of the theory of random sets, which brings together elements of topology, convex geometry, and probability theory to develop a coherent mathematical framework to analyze random elements whose realizations are sets. It then elucidates how these tools have been fruitfully applied in econometrics to reach the goals of partial identification analysis.</description><author>Molchanov, Ilya; Molinari, Francesca</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coordination of Expectations: The Eductive Stability Viewpoint</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desgranges, Gabriel
The eductive approach consists of finding solutions consistent with common knowledge of individual rationality and the model. An equilibrium is stable whenever it is the unique outcome consistent with these assumptions. This is a strong stability criterion as it relies on noassumption of prior knowledge of others' expectations. This review presents various (in) stability results. It focuses on the following method: Rewrite the model as a temporary equilibrium map in which the current economic outcome is determined by expectations and characterize stability by contracting properties of this map. The main insight suggested by these results is due to Guesnerie (2002): Stability is obtained when the actual outcome is not very sensitive to expectations. Additional insights include that agents' heterogeneity is a source of instability; the ability of prices to transmit information is limited by the quality of private information; and coordination when agents are infinitely lived is difficult because of the large effect of long-run expectations.</description><author>Desgranges, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From Sudden Stops to Fisherian Deflation: Quantitative Theory and Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korinek, Anton; Mendoza, Enrique G.
In the 1990s, Sudden Stops in emerging markets were a harbinger of the 2008 global financial crisis. During these Sudden Stops, countries lost access to credit, which caused abrupt current account reversals, and suffered severe recessions. This article reviews a class of models that yield quantitative predictions consistent with these observations, based on an occasionally binding credit constraint that limits debt to a fraction of the market value of incomes or assets used as collateral. Sudden Stops are infrequent events nested within regular business cycles and occur in response to standard shocks after periods of expansion increase leverage ratios sufficiently. When this happens, the Fisherian debt-deflation mechanism is set in motion, as lower asset or goods prices tighten the constraint further, causing further deflation. This framework also embodies a pecuniary externality with important implications for macroprudential policy because agents do not internalize how current borrowing decisions affect collateral values during future financial crises.</description><author>Korinek, Anton; Mendoza, Enrique G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Human Development and Social Mobility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heckman, James J.; Mosso, Stefano
This article distills and extends recent research on the economics of human development and social mobility. It summarizes the evidence from diverse literatures on the importance of early life conditions in shaping multiple life skills and the evidence on critical and sensitive investment periods for shaping different skills. It presents economic models that rationalize the evidence and unify the treatment effect and family influence literatures. The evidence on the empirical and policy importance of credit constraints in forming skills is examined. There is little support for the claim that untargeted income transfer policies to poor families significantly boost child outcomes. Mentoring, parenting, and attachment are essential features of successful families and interventions that shape skills at all stages of childhood. The next wave of family studies will better capture the active role of the emerging autonomous child in learning and responding to the actions of parents, mentors, and teachers.</description><author>Heckman, James J.; Mosso, Stefano</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>China's Great Convergence and Beyond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Storesletten, Kjetil; Zilibotti, Fabrizio
A recent wave of economic research has studied the transformation of China from a poor country in the 1970s to a middle-income economy today. Based on this literature, we discuss the factors driving China's development process. We provide a historical account of China's rise, fall, and resurgence. We then discuss the stylized facts associated with China's growth process and review a comprehensive theory of its economic transition. Finally, we discuss China's future. In particular, we review some recent studies about technological and politico-economic factors that may foster or hinder its future economic performance.</description><author>Storesletten, Kjetil; Zilibotti, Fabrizio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disclosure: Psychology Changes Everything</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loewenstein, George; Sunstein, Cass R.; Golman, Russell
We review literature examining the effects of laws and regulations that require public disclosure of information. These requirements are most sensibly imposed in situations characterized by misaligned incentives and asymmetric information between, for example, a buyer and seller or an advisor and advisee. We review the economic literature relevant to such disclosure and then discuss how different psychological factors complicate, and in some cases radically change, the economic predictions. For example, limited attention, motivated attention, and biased assessments of probability on the part of information recipients can significantly diminish, or even reverse, the intended effects of disclosure requirements. In many cases, disclosure does not much affect the recipients of the information but does significantly affect the behavior of the providers, sometimes for the better and sometimes for the worse. We review research suggesting that simplified disclosure, standardized disclosure, vivid disclosure, and social comparison information can all be used to enhance the effectiveness of disclosure policies.</description><author>Loewenstein, George; Sunstein, Cass R.; Golman, Russell</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectations in Experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wagener, Florian
The rational expectations hypothesis is one of the cornerstones of current economic theorizing. This review discusses a number of experiments that focus on expectation formation by human subjects in a number of learning-to-forecast experiments and analyzes the implications for the rational expectations hypothesis. In these experiments, most agents are rational in an operational sense, and their expectations coordinate quickly, but not necessarily on the rational expectations value. In several situations, the homogeneous rational expectations hypothesis of Lucas and Prescott poorly describes the expectational dynamics and is outperformed by other hypotheses. But even in those situations in which the hypothesis gives a good description, it is more likely that coordination on rational values is brought about by the institutional structure of the market rather than the rationality of the agents.</description><author>Wagener, Florian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Labor Markets and the Evolution of Inequality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Black, Dan A.; Kolesnikova, Natalia; Taylor, Lowell J.
US labor markets have experienced rising inequality over the past 30 years-as evidenced by an increased gap in wages earned by high-skill workers (e.g., college graduates) and low-skill workers (e.g., high school graduates). Empirical evidence documenting this evolution of inequality comes from studies that assess wage-education gradients at the national level. But of course people work in local labor markets that differ in important ways. We provide a theoretical framework for evaluating inequality changes when individuals work in local labor markets, and we give an empirical reassessment of inequality changes in light of the insights that emerge from our framework.</description><author>Black, Dan A.; Kolesnikova, Natalia; Taylor, Lowell J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>People, Places, and Public Policy: Some Simple Welfare Economics of Local Economic Development Programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kline, Patrick; Moretti, Enrico
Most countries exhibit large and persistent geographical differences in wages, income, and unemployment rates. A growing class of place-based policies attempts to address these differences through public investments and subsidies that target disadvantaged neighborhoods, cities, or regions. Place-based policies have the potential to profoundly affect the location of economic activity, along with the wages, employment, and industry mix of communities. These programs are widespread in the United States and throughout the world but have only recently been studied closely by economists. We consider the following questions: Who benefits from place-based interventions? Do the national benefits outweigh the costs? What sorts of interventions are most likely to be effective? To study these questions, we develop a simple spatial equilibrium model designed to characterize the welfare effects of place-based policies on the local and the national economy. Using this model, we critically evaluate the economic rationales for place-based policies and assess the latest evidence on their effects. We conclude with some lessons for policy and directions for future research.</description><author>Kline, Patrick; Moretti, Enrico</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Applying Insights from Behavioral Economics to Policy Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madrian, Brigitte C.
The premise of this article is that an understanding of psychology and other social science disciplines can inform the effectiveness of the economic tools traditionally deployed in carrying out the functions of government, which include remedying market failures, redistributing income, and collecting tax revenue. An understanding of psychology can also lead to the development of different policy tools that better motivate desired behavior change or that are more cost-effective than traditional policy tools. The article outlines a framework for thinking about the psychology of behavior change in the context of market failures. It then describes the research on the effects of a variety of interventions rooted in an understanding of psychology that have policy-relevant applications. The article concludes by discussing how an understanding of psychology can also inform the use and design of traditional policy tools for behavior change, such as financial incentives.</description><author>Madrian, Brigitte C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firms, Misallocation, and Aggregate Productivity: A Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hopenhayn, Hugo A.
Firm heterogeneity and the allocation of resources across firms play a key role in determining aggregate productivity. Entry barriers and misallocation can substantially impact productivity, as evidenced in recent work. This article provides a unifying theoretical framework and a review of this literature.</description><author>Hopenhayn, Hugo A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Teacher Effects and Teacher-Related Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jackson, C. Kirabo; Rockoff, Jonah E.; Staiger, Douglas O.
The emergence of large longitudinal data sets linking students to teachers has led to rapid growth in the study of teacher effects on student outcomes by economists over the past decade. One large literature has documented wide variation in teacher effectiveness that is not well explained by observable student or teacher characteristics. A second literature has investigated how educational outcomes might be improved by leveraging teacher effectiveness through processes of recruitment, assignment, compensation, evaluation, promotion, and retention. These two lines of inquiry are closely tied; the first tells us about the importance of individual teachers, and the second tells us how this information can be used in policy and practice. We review the most recent findings in economics on the importance of teachers and on teacher-related policies aimed at improving educational production.</description><author>Jackson, C. Kirabo; Rockoff, Jonah E.; Staiger, Douglas O.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Learning in Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mobius, Markus; Rosenblat, Tanya
Social learning is a rapidly growing field for empirical and theoretical research in economics. We encounter social learning in many economically important phenomena, such as the adoption of new products and technologies or job search in labor markets. We review the existing empirical and theoretical literatures and argue that they have evolved largely independently of each other. This suggests several directions for future research that can help bridge the gap between both literatures. For example, the theory literature has come up with several models of social learning, ranging from naive DeGroot models to sophisticated Bayesian models whose assumptions and predictions need to be empirically tested. Alternatively, empiricists have often observed that social learning is more localized than existing theory models assume, and that information can decay along a transmission path. Incorporating these findings into our models might require theorists to look beyond asymptotic convergence in social learning.</description><author>Mobius, Markus; Rosenblat, Tanya</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutions, Human Capital, and Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acemoglu, Daron; Gallego, Francisco A.; Robinson, James A.
In this article, we revisit the relationship among institutions, human capital, and development. We argue that empirical models that treat institutions and human capital as exogenous are misspecified, both because of the usual omitted variable bias problems and because of differential measurement error in these variables, and that this misspecification is at the root of the very large returns of human capital, about four to five times greater than that implied by micro (Mincerian) estimates, found in the previous literature. Using cross-country and cross-regional regressions, we show that when we focus on historically determined differences in human capital and control for the effect of institutions, the impact of institutions on long-run development is robust, whereas the estimates of the effect of human capital are much diminished and become consistent with micro estimates. Using historical and cross-country regression evidence, we also show that there is no support for the view that differences in the human capital endowments of early European colonists have been a major factor in the subsequent institutional development of former colonies.</description><author>Acemoglu, Daron; Gallego, Francisco A.; Robinson, James A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth and the Smart State</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aghion, Philippe; Roulet, Alexandra
As countries develop, the main driver of economic growth shifts from imitation to innovation. These two sources of growth require different policies and institutions. In particular, in this article we argue that the transition from an imitation-based to an innovation-based economy calls the old welfare state model into question. It is not so much the size of the state that is at stake but rather its governance. What we need to foster economic growth in developed economies is not a reduced state but a strategic state, which acts as a catalyst using selective and properly governed support to the market-driven innovation process. This idea of a strategic state that targets its investments to maximize growth in the face of hard budget constraints departs both from the Keynesian view of a state sustaining growth through demand-driven policies and from the neoliberal view of a minimal state confined to its regalian functions.</description><author>Aghion, Philippe; Roulet, Alexandra</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Causes and Consequences of Development Clusters: State Capacity, Peace, and Income</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Besley, Timothy; Persson, Torsten
Three important aspects of development-per capita income, state capabilities, and (the absence of) political violence-are correlated with each other at the country level. This article discusses the causes of such development clusters and highlights two explanations: common economic, political, and social drivers and complementarities (two-way positive feedbacks). It also draws out preliminary policy implications of these patterns of development and proposes topics for further research.</description><author>Besley, Timothy; Persson, Torsten</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Under the Thumb of History? Political Institutions and the Scope for Action</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Abhijit V.; Duflo, Esther
This article discusses the two leading views of history and political institutions. For some scholars, institutions are mainly products of historical logic, whereas for others, accidents, leaders, and decisions have a significant impact. We argue that although there is clear evidence that history matters and has long-term effects, there are not enough data to help us distinguish between the two views. Faced with this uncertainty, what is a social scientist to do? We argue that given the possibility that policy decisions indeed make a difference, it makes sense to assume they do and to try to improve policy making.</description><author>Banerjee, Abhijit V.; Duflo, Esther</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Web Appendix for The Economics of Human Development and Social Mobility James Heckman and Stefano Mosso February 4, 2014</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heckman, James; Mosso, Stefano
nan</description><author>Heckman, James; Mosso, Stefano</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fetal Origins and Parental Responses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almond, Douglas; Mazumder, Bhashkar
How do parental investments respond to health endowments at birth? Recent studies have combined insights from an earlier theoretical literature on household resource allocation with improved identification strategies to capture causal effects of early life health shocks. We describe empirical challenges in identifying behavioral responses and how recent studies have sought to address these. We then discuss the emerging literature on dynamic complementarities in parental investments arising from the staged, developmental nature of capability production and how capabilities may have multiple dimensions. The bulk of the empirical evidence to date suggests that parental investments reinforce initial endowment differences.</description><author>Almond, Douglas; Mazumder, Bhashkar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantile Models with Endogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernozhukov, V.; Hansen, C.
In this article, we review quantile models with endogeneity. We focus on models that achieve identification through the use of instrumental variables and discuss conditions under which partial and point identification are obtained. We discuss key conditions, which include monotonicity and full-rank-type conditions, in detail. In providing this review, we update the identification results of Chernozhukov &amp; Hansen (2005). We illustrate the modeling assumptions through economically motivated examples. We also briefly review the literature on estimation and inference.</description><author>Chernozhukov, V.; Hansen, C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Rigidity: Microeconomic Evidence and Macroeconomic Implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nakamura, Emi; Steinsson, Jon
We review recent evidence on price rigidity from the macroeconomics literature and discuss how this evidence is used to inform macroeconomic modeling. Sluggish price adjustment is a leading explanation for the large effects of demand shocks on output and, in particular, the effects of monetary policy on output. A recent influx of data on individual prices has greatly deepened macroeconomists' understanding of individual price dynamics. However, the analysis of these new data raises a host of new empirical issues that have not traditionally been confronted by parsimonious macroeconomic models of price setting. Simple statistics such as the frequency of price change may be misleading guides to the flexibility of the aggregate price level in a setting in which temporary sales, product churning, cross-sectional heterogeneity, and large idiosyncratic price movements play an important role. We discuss empirical evidence on these and other important features of micro price adjustment and ask how they affect the sluggishness of aggregate price adjustment and the economy's response to demand shocks.</description><author>Nakamura, Emi; Steinsson, Jon</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Immigration and Production Technology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewis, Ethan
Research on the labor market impact of immigration typically relies on a single-good model of production with separable capital. This article discusses theory and evidence that suggest that this standard model is too simple to capture the long-run labor market impact of immigration. A level of capital-skill complementarity supported in studies both involving and not involving immigration alone reduces the relative wage impact of immigration by 40% compared to simulations with separable capital. Other models in which the production structure responds to skill-mix changes, including models with endogenous choice of technique, directed technical change, or human capital spill-overs, also imply that the long-run impact of immigration on wages is smaller than predicted by the standard model. This article discusses new research that tries to credibly evaluate such models using immigration-induced variation in the skill mix, an approach with further potential, and evidence that immigration impacts innovation and firm formation.</description><author>Lewis, Ethan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneity in the Dynamics of Labor Earnings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Browning, Martin; Ejrnaes, Mette
In this article, we survey the literature on individual earnings dynamics with a particular focus on allowing for pervasive heterogeneity across individuals. We structure the discussion around ARMA processes with nonlinear trends for each individual. We show that allowing for pervasive and codependent heterogeneity in individual parameters has a major impact on econometric modeling, estimation, and substantive conclusions. We describe an econometric method that is suitable for models with pervasive heterogeneity. We develop a long list of statistics that describe any earnings panel in great detail and provide a demanding set of features of the data for fitting. This list encompasses most moments used in the literature and provides novel statistics based on individual regressions. Finally, we present an empirical illustration using a long Danish panel. Based on this, we provide some conclusions concerning earnings dynamics but emphasize that details will vary according to the sample.</description><author>Browning, Martin; Ejrnaes, Mette</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Analysis Without the Rational Expectations Hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Woodford, Michael
The article presents a temporary equilibrium framework for macroeconomic analysis that allows for a wide range of possible specifications of expectations but reduces to a standard new Keynesian model in the limiting case of rational expectations. This common framework is then used to contrast the assumptions and implications of several different ways of relaxing the assumption of rational expectations. As an illustration of the method, the implications of alternative assumptions for the selection of a monetary policy rule are discussed. Other issues treated include the conditions required for Ricardian equivalence and for existence of a deflation trap.</description><author>Woodford, Michael</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Biological Measures of Economic History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Steckel, Richard H.
This review discusses the methodology and some findings underlying four types of biological measures used by economic historians: mortality rates, stature, body mass index, and skeletal remains. Economic historians examine a variety of sources to learn when, why, and where modern industrial societies became rich and healthy. Monetary measures, such as income and wages, are highly desirable but usually unavailable to cover the time periods and countries over which modern societies evolved. Donning interdisciplinary lenses, these historians search archives, libraries, and archaeological sources for scraps of information, often assembled for other purposes, to construct a story of the evolution of humanity's well-being. Biological measures have the advantage of comparability across time and culture; life expectancy, for example, means about the same today as in ancient Egypt, but the same cannot be said for the purchasing power of income, wages, or wealth.</description><author>Steckel, Richard H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonparametric Identification in Structural Economic Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Matzkin, Rosa L.
Structural economic models allow one to analyze counterfactuals when economic systems change and to evaluate the well-being of economic agents. A key element in such analysis is the ability to identify the primitive functions and distributions of the economic models that are employed to describe the economic phenomena under study. Recent developments have provided ways to achieve identification of these primitive functions and distributions without imposing parametric restrictions. In this article, I consider a small set of stylized models and provide insight into some of the approaches that have been taken to develop nonparametric identification results in those models.</description><author>Matzkin, Rosa L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Microcredit Under the Microscope: What Have We Learned in the Past Two Decades, and What Do We Need to Know?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Abhijit Vinayak
Research on microcredit is now two decades old. There has been enormous progress in understanding both what microcredit does and how. Yet a lot of what we have learned has raised new and often quite fundamental questions about its nature: Is microcredit primarily about investment, consumption, or savings? Why is it that the investments financed by microcredit do not always lead to income growth, and does this have to do with the structure of microlending? What are the roles of social capital, reputation, and group lending? This article attempts to take stock of this significant body of work and tries to identify the most important questions for future research.</description><author>Banerjee, Abhijit Vinayak</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust and Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Algan, Yann; Cahuc, Pierre
This article surveys recent research on the relationship between trust and growth. It documents the strong international and interregional heterogeneity of trust. The theoretical mechanisms that explain the influence of trust on economic performance and the empirical methods used to identify the causal impact of trust on economic performance are reviewed.</description><author>Algan, Yann; Cahuc, Pierre</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early-Life Health and Adult Circumstance in Developing Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Currie, Janet; Vogl, Tom
A growing literature documents the links between long-term outcomes and health in the fetal period, infancy, and early childhood. Much of this literature focuses on rich countries, but researchers are increasingly taking advantage of new sources of data and identification to study the long reach of childhood health in developing countries. Health in early life may be a more significant determinant of adult outcomes in these countries because health insults are more frequent, the capacity to remediate is more limited, and multiple shocks may interact. However, the underlying relationships may also be more difficult to measure, given significant mortality selection. We survey recent evidence on the adult correlates of early-life health and the long-term effects of shocks resulting from disease, famine, malnutrition, pollution, and war.</description><author>Currie, Janet; Vogl, Tom</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deterrence: A Review of the Evidence by a Criminologist for Economists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagin, Daniel S.
This article reviews the evidence on the deterrent effect of police, imprisonment, and capital punishment and additionally summarizes knowledge of sanction risk perceptions. Studies of changes in police presence, whether achieved by changes in police numbers or in their strategic deployment, consistently find evidence of deterrent effects. Studies of the deterrent effect of increases in already long prison sentences find at most a modest deterrent effect. Studies of the deterrent effect of capital punishment provide no useful information on the topic. Four high-priority areas for future research are identified: developing and testing an integrated model of the effects of the threat and experience of punishment, measuring perceptions of sanction regimes, developing and testing a theory of criminal opportunities, and estimating the deterrent effect of shorter prison sentences and identifying high-deterrence policies.</description><author>Nagin, Daniel S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Econometric Analysis of Games with Multiple Equilibria</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Paula, Aureo
This article reviews the recent literature on the econometric analysis of games in which multiple solutions are possible. Multiplicity does not necessarily preclude the estimation of a particular model (and, in certain cases, even improves its identification), but ignoring it can lead to misspecifications. The review starts with a general characterization of structural models that highlights how multiplicity affects the classical paradigm. Because the information structure is an important guide to identification and estimation strategies, I discuss games of complete and incomplete information separately. Although many of the techniques discussed here can be transported across different information environments, some are specific to particular models. Models of social interactions are also surveyed. I close with a brief discussion of post-estimation issues and research prospects.</description><author>de Paula, Aureo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Multinational Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yeaple, Stephen Ross
This article documents the recent advances in the international trade literature toward understanding the role of multinational firms in the conduct of international commerce. Over the past 10 years, we have developed a better understanding of the incentives firms face in their choice of production location, and we know more about the incentives that induce firms to vertically integrate. Furthermore, the theory literature has progressed from two-country models that cannot capture the richness of multinational firms' activities to multicountry models that do. The empirics have advanced as well but at a slower pace. Progress has been slowed by the lack of comprehensive data and the difficulties of distinguishing between the various mechanisms proposed by theory.</description><author>Yeaple, Stephen Ross</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Research on Sovereign Debt and Default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tomz, Michael; Wright, Mark L. J.
In this article, we review the empirical literature about sovereign debt and default. As we survey the work of economists, historians, and political scientists, we also emphasize parallel developments by theorists and recommend steps to improve the correspondence between theory and data.</description><author>Tomz, Michael; Wright, Mark L. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Inflation Expectations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armantier, Olivier; de Bruin, Waendi Bruine; Potter, Simon; Topa, Giorgio; van der Klaauw, Wilbert; Zafar, Basit
To conduct monetary policy, central banks around the world increasingly rely on measures of public inflation expectations. In this article, we review findings from an ongoing initiative at the Federal Reserve Bank of New York aimed at improving the measurement and our understanding of household inflation expectations through surveys. We discuss the importance of question wording and the usefulness of new questions to elicit an individual's distribution of inflation beliefs. We present evidence suggesting that consumers update their inflation expectations in response to new information and that information dissemination may lead to more informed and reliable reporting of inflation expectations. Finally, we report on a financially incentivized experiment suggesting that expectations surveys are informative and that respondents generally act on their stated beliefs in a way consistent with expected utility theory.</description><author>Armantier, Olivier; de Bruin, Waendi Bruine; Potter, Simon; Topa, Giorgio; van der Klaauw, Wilbert; Zafar, Basit</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Literacy, Financial Education, and Economic Outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hastings, Justine S.; Madrian, Brigitte C.; Skimmyhorn, William L.
In this article, we review the literature on financial literacy, financial education, and consumer financial outcomes. We consider how financial literacy is measured in the current literature and examine how well the existing literature addresses whether financial education improves financial literacy or personal financial outcomes. We discuss the extent to which a competitive market provides incentives for firms to educate consumers or to offer products that facilitate informed choice. We review the literature on alternative policies to improve financial outcomes and compare the evidence with that on the efficacy and cost of financial education. Finally, we discuss directions for future research.</description><author>Hastings, Justine S.; Madrian, Brigitte C.; Skimmyhorn, William L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Great Trade Collapse</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bems, Rudolfs; Johnson, Robert C.; Yi, Kei-Mu
We survey recent literature on the causes of the collapse in international trade during the 2008-2009 global recession. We argue that the evidence points to the collapse in aggregate expenditure, concentrated on trade-intensive durable goods, as the main driver of the trade collapse. Inventory adjustment likely amplified the impact of these expenditure changes on trade. In addition, shocks to credit supply constrained export supply, further exacerbating the decline in trade. Most evidence suggests that changes in trade policy did not play a large role. We conclude that one benefit of the trade collapse is that it has stimulated research in neglected areas at the intersection of trade and macroeconomics.</description><author>Bems, Rudolfs; Johnson, Robert C.; Yi, Kei-Mu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Goals, Methods, and Progress in Neuroeconomics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Camerer, Colin F.
Neuroeconomics shares the main goals of microeconomics: to understand what causes choices, and the welfare properties of choice. The novel goal is linking mathematical constructs and observable behavior to mechanistic details of neural circuitry. Several complementary methods are used. An initial insight from neuroscience is that distinct systems guide choice: Pavlovian and instrumental conditioning (learning) of state-value and response-value associations, overlearned habits, and model- (or goal-) directed value that requires deliberation. These systems can differ economically from rational choice-for example, habitual choices have low utility and price elasticities, whereas model-directed values are often constructed preferences. Neuroeconomics also provides evidence of situations in which utility maximization either works well (in simple binary choice) or benefits from the introduction of behavioral constructs. Neuroeconomics is well equipped to guide the theory of how choices depend on mental states, such as fear or cognitive load. Examples include extensive studies of risk and time preference, finance, and neural decoding of private information.</description><author>Camerer, Colin F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Theory of Clubs and Competitive Coalitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wooders, Myrna
This review discusses research demonstrating that club economies and coalition economies with many participants and relatively small effective groups (clubs, jurisdictions, or coalitions) are competitive. Small groups are effective if all or almost all gains to collective activities can be realized by cooperation restricted to them. At this point, there are many papers in the literature demonstrating the competitiveness of club and coalition economies in a variety of contexts. To facilitate the exposition, I treat economies with quasi-linear utilities and games with side payments. The main concepts and results for this framework are discussed. Additionally, relationships are established with regard to broader models of club and coalition economies, including very recent contributions to the literature.</description><author>Wooders, Myrna</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous Extreme Events and the Dual Role of Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danielsson, Jon; Shin, Hyun Song; Zigrand, Jean-Pierre
Extreme events in financial markets are often generated by shocks that come from within the system, rather than those that arrive from outside the system. The combination of risk-sensitive behavior rules and the coordinated actions implied by market-to-market accounting can result in outcome distributions with fat tails, even if the fundamental shocks are Gaussian. We illustrate such endogenous extreme events through the pricing density resulting from dynamic hedging of options and the flash crash of May 2010.</description><author>Danielsson, Jon; Shin, Hyun Song; Zigrand, Jean-Pierre</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Natural Resource Wealth: The Challenge of Managing a Windfall</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van der Ploeg, Frederick; Venables, Anthony J.
Many countries have failed to use natural resource wealth to promote growth and development. They have been damaged by the volatility of revenues and have failed to save a sufficiently high proportion of their resource revenues and failed to make high-return investments to support diversification of their economies. This review explores the reasons for these failures and discusses policies to improve performance.</description><author>van der Ploeg, Frederick; Venables, Anthony J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Perspectives on Statistical Decisions Under Ambiguity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoye, Joerg
This review summarizes and connects recent work on the foundations and applications of statistical decision theory. Minimax models of decisions making under ambiguity are identified as a thread running through several literatures. In axiomatic decision theory, these models motivated a large literature on modeling ambiguity aversion. Some findings of this literature are reported in a way that should be directly accessible to statisticians and econometricians. In statistical decision theory, the models inform a rich theory of estimation and treatment choice, which was recently extended to account for partial identification and thereby ambiguity that does not vanish with sample size. This literature is illustrated by discussing global, finite-sample admissible, and minimax decision rules for a number of stylized decision problems with point and partial identification.</description><author>Stoye, Joerg</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Constraints in Education</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lochner, Lance; Monge-Naranjo, Alexander
We review studies of the impact of credit constraints on the accumulation of human capital. Evidence suggests that credit constraints have recently become important for schooling and other aspects of households' behavior. We highlight the importance of early childhood investments, as their response largely determines the impact of credit constraints on the overall lifetime acquisition of human capital. We also review the intergenerational literature and examine the macroeconomic impacts of credit constraints on social mobility and the income distribution. A common limitation across all areas of the human capital literature is the imposition of ad hoc constraints on credit. We propose a more careful treatment of the structure of government student loan programs and the incentive problems underlying private credit. We show that endogenizing constraints on credit for human capital helps explain observed borrowing, schooling, and default patterns and offers new insights about the design of government policy.</description><author>Lochner, Lance; Monge-Naranjo, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneity in Human Capital Investments: High School Curriculum, College Major, and Careers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altonji, Joseph G.; Blom, Erica; Meghir, Costas
Motivated by the large differences in labor market outcomes across college majors, we survey the literature on the demand for and return to high school and postsecondary education by field of study. We combine elements from several papers to provide a dynamic model of education and occupation choice that stresses the roles of the specificity of human capital and uncertainty about preferences, ability, education outcomes, and labor market returns. The model implies an important distinction between the ex ante and ex post returns to education decisions. We also discuss some of the econometric difficulties in estimating the causal effects of field of study on wages in the context of a sequential choice model with learning. Finally, we review the empirical literature on the choice of curriculum and the effects of high school courses and college major on labor market outcomes.</description><author>Altonji, Joseph G.; Blom, Erica; Meghir, Costas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Modeling and Analysis of Educational Vouchers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Epple, Dennis; Romano, Richard
The analysis of educational vouchers has evolved from market-based analogies to models that incorporate distinctive features of the educational environment. These distinctive features include peer effects, scope for private school pricing and admissions based on student characteristics, the linkage of household residential and school choices in multidistrict settings, the potential for rent seeking in public and private schools, the role of school reputations, incentives for student effort, and the intergenerational dynamics of human capital accumulation. Research has also elucidated features of voucher design, including income and ability targeting, restrictions on private school pricing and admissions, and the potential for garnering political support. We review these research advances.</description><author>Epple, Dennis; Romano, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Distribution of Teacher Quality and Implications for Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanushek, Eric A.; Rivkin, Steven G.
It has become commonplace to measure teacher quality in terms of teacher value-added. Operationally, this means evaluating teachers according to the learning gains of students on various achievement tests. Existing research consistently shows large variations in teacher effectiveness, much of which is within schools as opposed to between schools. The policy implications of these variations are dramatic. But the underlying statistical modeling has become the subject of intense research, in part because of this direct use of value-added measures in policy discussions.</description><author>Hanushek, Eric A.; Rivkin, Steven G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rare Macroeconomic Disasters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barro, Robert J.; Ursua, Jose F.
The potential for rare macroeconomic disasters may explain an array of asset-pricing puzzles. Our empirical studies of these extreme events rely on long-term data now covering 28 countries for consumption and 40 for GDP. A baseline model calibrated with observed peak-to-trough disaster sizes accords with the average equity premium with a reasonable coefficient of relative risk aversion. High stock-price volatility can be explained by incorporating time-varying long-run growth rates and disaster probabilities. Business-cycle models with shocks to disaster probability have implications for the cyclical behavior of asset returns and corporate leverage, and international versions may explain the uncovered-interest-parity puzzle. Richer models of disaster dynamics allow for transitions between normalcy and disaster, bring in postcrisis recoveries, and use the full time series on consumption. Potential future research includes applications to long-term economic growth and environmental economics, and the use of stock-index options prices and other variables to gauge time-varying disaster probabilities.</description><author>Barro, Robert J.; Ursua, Jose F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Developments in the Economics of Time Use</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aguiar, Mark; Hurst, Erik; Karabarbounis, Loukas
The proliferation of new data sets and their harmonization with the older data sets have allowed researchers to make significant progress in our understanding of how individuals allocate their time away from market work. We highlight how these new data can be used to test theories of time use and we review recent developments in long-run trends in time use, life-cycle patterns of expenditures and labor supply, and the allocation of time over the business cycle.</description><author>Aguiar, Mark; Hurst, Erik; Karabarbounis, Loukas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Comparisons in Health Economics: Evidence from Aging Studies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banks, James; Smith, James P.
We provide an overview of the growing literature that uses microlevel data from multiple countries to investigate health outcomes, and their link to socioeconomic factors, at older ages. Because the data are at a comparatively young stage, much of the analysis is at an early stage and limited to a handful of countries, with analysis for the United States and England being the most common. What is immediately apparent as we get better measures is that, between countries, health differences amongst those at older ages are real and large. Countries are ranked differently according to whether one considers life expectancy, prevalence, or the incidence of a specific condition. Moreover, the magnitude of international disparities may vary according to whether measures utilize doctor-diagnosed conditions or biomarker-based indicators of disease and poor health. But one key finding emerges-the United States ranks poorly on all indicators, with the exception of self-reported subjective health status.</description><author>Banks, James; Smith, James P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Saving Money or Just Saving Lives? Improving the Productivity of US Health Care Spending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baicker, Katherine; Chandra, Amitabh; Skinner, Jonathan S.
There is growing concern over the rising share of the US economy devoted to health care spending. Fueled in part by demographic transitions, unchecked increases in entitlement spending will necessitate some combination of substantial tax increases, elimination of other public spending, or unsustainable public debt. This massive increase in health spending might be warranted if each dollar devoted to the health care sector yielded real health benefits, but this does not seem to be the case. Although we have seen remarkable gains in life expectancy and functioning over the past several decades, there is substantial variation in the health benefits associated with different types of spending. Some treatments, such as aspirin, beta blockers, and flu shots, produce a large health benefit per dollar spent. Other more expensive treatments, such as stents for cardiovascular disease, are high value for some patients but poor value for others. Finally, a large and expanding set of treatments, such as proton-beam therapy or robotic surgery, contributes to rapid increases in spending despite questionable health benefits. Moving resources toward more productive uses requires encouraging providers to deliver and patients to consume high-value care, a daunting task in the current political landscape. But widespread inefficiency also offers hope: Given the current distribution of resources in the US health care system, there is tremendous potential to improve the productivity of health care spending and the fiscal health of the United States.</description><author>Baicker, Katherine; Chandra, Amitabh; Skinner, Jonathan S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Paul Samuelson's Legacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dixit, Avinash
Paul Samuelson is probably the most important economist of the second half of the twentieth century. His research publications; his introductory textbook; his articles on topical questions of economic policy; and his interactions with numerous students, colleagues, policy makers, and the wider public have all contributed to fundamental changes in economics as a science and as a profession. This article attempts to give a brief overview of his career spanning eight decades and to recapitulate and celebrate his legacy.</description><author>Dixit, Avinash</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics and Politics of Women's Rights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doepke, Matthias; Tertilt, Michele; Voena, Alessandra
Women's rights and economic development are highly correlated. Today, the discrepancy between the legal rights of women and men is much larger in developing compared with developed countries. Historically, even in countries that are now rich, women had few rights before economic development took off. Is development the cause of expanding women's rights, or conversely, do women's rights facilitate development? We argue that there is truth to both hypotheses. The literature on the economic consequences of women's rights documents that more rights for women lead to more spending on health and children, which should benefit development. The political-economy literature on the evolution of women's rights finds that technological change increased the costs of patriarchy for men and thus contributed to the expansion of women's rights. Combining these perspectives, we discuss the theory of Doepke &amp; Tertilt (2009), who find that an increase in the return to human capital induces men to vote for women's rights, which in turn promotes growth in human capital and income per capita.</description><author>Doepke, Matthias; Tertilt, Michele; Voena, Alessandra</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Life-Cycle Wage Growth and Heterogeneous Human Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sanders, Carl; Taber, Christopher
Wages grow rapidly for young workers, and the human capital investment model is the classic framework to explain this growth. While estimation and the theory of human capital have traditionally focused on general human capital, both have evolved toward models of heterogeneous human capital. In this article, we review and evaluate the current state of this literature. We exposit the classic model of general human capital investment and extend it to show how a model of heterogeneous human capital can nest previous models. We then summarize the empirical literature on firm-specific human capital, industry-and occupation-specific human capital, and task-specific human capital and discuss how these concepts can explain a wide variety of labor market phenomena that traditional models cannot.</description><author>Sanders, Carl; Taber, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Research on the Economics of Patents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hall, Bronwyn H.; Harhoff, Dietmar
This review surveys recent research on the economics of patents. The topics covered include theoretical and empirical evidence on patents as incentives for innovation, the effectiveness of patents for invention disclosure, patent valuation, and the design of patent systems. We also look at some current policy areas, including software and business method patents, university patenting, and the growth in patent litigation.</description><author>Hall, Bronwyn H.; Harhoff, Dietmar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Relationship Between Economic Preferences and Psychological Personality Measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Anke; Deckers, Thomas; Dohmen, Thomas; Falk, Armin; Kosse, Fabian
Although both economists and psychologists seek to identify determinants of heterogeneity in behavior, they use different concepts to capture them. In this review, we first analyze the extent to which economic preferences and psychological concepts of personality, such as the Big Five and locus of control, are related. We analyze data from incentivized laboratory experiments and representative samples and find only low degrees of association between economic preferences and personality. We then regress life outcomes (such as labor market success, health status, and life satisfaction) simultaneously on preference and personality measures. The analysis reveals that the two concepts are rather complementary when it comes to explaining heterogeneity in important life outcomes and behavior.</description><author>Becker, Anke; Deckers, Thomas; Dohmen, Thomas; Falk, Armin; Kosse, Fabian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Empirics of Firm Heterogeneity and International Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernard, Andrew B.; Jensen, J. Bradford; Redding, Stephen J.; Schott, Peter K.
This article reviews the empirical evidence on firm heterogeneity in international trade. A first wave of empirical findings from microdata on plants and firms proposed challenges for existing models of international trade and inspired the development of new theories emphasizing firm heterogeneity. Subsequent empirical research has examined additional predictions of these theories and explored other dimensions of the data not originally captured by them. These other dimensions include multiproduct firms, offshoring, intrafirm trade and firm export market dynamics.</description><author>Bernard, Andrew B.; Jensen, J. Bradford; Redding, Stephen J.; Schott, Peter K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>