<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF0</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Competition and risk taking in banking: The charter value hypothesis revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arping, Stefan
Conventional wisdom suggests that greater competition in banking, by eroding bank charter values, exacerbates banks' incentives to take excessive risks. This paper presents a model in which, contrary to this view, competition can cause banks to act more prudently: As competition intensifies and profit margins decline, banks face more-binding threats of failure, to which they may respond by taking lower risks. Nonetheless, competition is unambiguously destabilizing in this model: The direct effect of lower margins on bank failure rates always outweighs the prudence effect. A key implication is that the effects of competition on bank risk taking and on failure risk can move in opposite directions. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arping, Stefan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A non-structural investigation of VIX risk neutral density</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barletta, Andrea; de Magistris, Paolo Santucci; Violante, Francesco
We propose a non-structural method to retrieve the risk-neutral density (RND) implied by options on the CBOE Volatility Index (VIX). The methodology is based on orthogonal polynomial expansions around a kernel density and yields the RND of the underlying asset without the need for a parametric specification. The classic family of Laguerre expansions is extended to include the GIG and the generalized Weibull kernels. We show that orthogonal polynomial expansions yield accurate approximations of the RND of VIX and they generally outperform commonly used non-parametric methods when controlling for accuracy. Based on a panel of observed VIX options, we retrieve the variance swap term structure, the time series of VVIX, the VIX risk-neutral moments and the Volatility-at-Risk, which reveal a number of stylized facts on the RND of VIX. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barletta, Andrea; de Magistris, Paolo Santucci; Violante, Francesco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collective bargaining and mergers and acquisitions activity around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahmad, Muhammad Farooq; Lambert, Thomas
This paper studies the relationship between collective bargaining and mergers and acquisitions activity in 46 countries from the early 1990s. We find that the frequency and volume of mergers and acquisitions within industries increase in countries with powerful labor unions and high coverage of bargaining coordination. Economically, collective bargaining mitigates the negative effect of tighter employment protection legislations on mergers and acquisitions documented in prior works. Further analyses suggest that collective bargaining encourages mergers and acquisitions by reducing employment uncertainty among target firm employees. Our results provide new insights into the real effects of collective bargaining in the context of mergers and acquisitions around the world. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahmad, Muhammad Farooq; Lambert, Thomas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jump activity analysis for affine jump-diffusion models: Evidence from the commodity market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da Fonseca, Jose; Ignatieva, Katja
This study performs a joint analysis of jump activity for commodities and their respective volatility indexes; it also compares the results thereof to those for equities. Exploiting a property of affine jump diffusion models (i.e., that a volatility index quoted on the market is an affine function of the instantaneous volatility state variable), we perform a test of common jumps for multidimensional processes to assess whether an asset and its volatility jump together. Applying this test to the crude oil pair USO/OVX, the gold pair GLD/GVZ, the S&amp;P500/VIX, and three stock/volatility index pairs, we find strong evidence that these assets and their respective volatility indexes do not jump together. However, a copula analysis shows that for the equity index and individual stocks, there is a dependency between the jump sizes in the asset and in the volatility index. In contrast, for the commodity market, this dependency occurs only after decomposing the jump sizes that affect the asset into positive and negative components. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Da Fonseca, Jose; Ignatieva, Katja</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Politicians' promotion incentives and bank risk exposure in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Li; Menkhoff, Lukas; Schroeder, Michael; Xu, Xian
This paper shows that politicians' pressure to climb the career ladder increases bank risk exposure in their region. Chinese local politicians are set growth targets in their region that are relative to each other. Growth is stimulated by debt-financed programs which are mainly financed via bank loans. The stronger the performance pressure the riskier the respective local bank exposure becomes. This effect holds for local banks which are under some control of local politicians, it has increased with the release of stimulus packages requiring local co-financing and it is stronger if politicians hold chairmen positions in bank boards. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Li; Menkhoff, Lukas; Schroeder, Michael; Xu, Xian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate pyramids, geographical distance, and investment efficiency of Chinese state-owned enterprises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Opie, Wei; Tian, Gary Gang; Zhang, Hong Feng
We investigate how the state's intervention in the investment decisions of Chinese local SOEs is affected by corporate control distance in the form of pyramidal layers and the geographical distance between the SOEs and their government controllers. Although both the corporate control distance and the geographical distance affect the state's costs of acquiring information about the SOEs, the former is created intentionally by the state to delegate decision rights, and the latter is largely exogenous. We find that local SOEs' investment efficiency is positively associated with the extensiveness of pyramids but negatively related to the geographical distance. The positive impact of pyramid-building on investment efficiency remains strong even when information costs captured by the geographical distance are low. However, the two distance measures lose their impact on investment efficiency when local governments reclaim control through a vertical interlock of chairman. Our results indicate that the credibility of the government's intention to delegate decision rights is vital to the SOEs' efficiency when government intervention is the norm in China. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Opie, Wei; Tian, Gary Gang; Zhang, Hong Feng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit constraints, firm investment and employment: Evidence from survey data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia-Posada Gomez, Miguel
This paper assesses the impact of credit constraints on investment, inventories and employment using a large sample of firms from 12 European countries for the period 2014-2017. The data come from the Survey on the Access to Finance of Enterprises (SAFE), which contains direct information on the financial constraints faced by non-financial companies. The key identification challenge is a potential omitted variable bias, as firms with poor investment and growth opportunities may have a higher probability of being credit constrained. This problem is addressed by using an instrumental variable that is based on the allocation rule of the ECB's Targeted Longer-Term Refinancing Operations (TLTROs). The main findings suggest that credit constraints have strong negative effects on investment in fixed assets, while they have no impact on employment or inventories. Unconventional monetary policy may spur investment by reducing the incidence of credit constraints, especially in the case of large and old firms. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garcia-Posada Gomez, Miguel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political influence and financial flexibility: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gu, Xian; Hasan, Iftekhar; Zhu, Yun
This paper investigates how political influence affects firms' financial flexibility and speed of adjustment toward target leverage ratios. We find that at the macro level, firms in environments with high political advantages, proxied by provincial affiliations with heads of state as well as political status and party rank of provincial leaders, adjust faster. At the micro level, firms that are state-owned, have CPC members as executives, or bear low exposure to changes in political uncertainty adjust faster. When interacted, the micro-level political factors have more significant impact. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gu, Xian; Hasan, Iftekhar; Zhu, Yun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ultra-fast activity and intraday market quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cartea, Alvaro; Payne, Richard; Penalva, Jose; Tapia, Mikel
This paper studies the intraday relationship between ultra-fast machine-driven activity (UFA) and market quality in automated equity markets. We find that higher UFA is associated with lower intraday market quality (greater quoted and effective spreads and lower depth). This effect is economically significant, and robust to different specifications, endogeneity tests, and alternative measures of UFA. Our results hold after controlling for volatility, periods of unusually high UFA (a proxy for quote stuffing), and periods where UFA is primarily driven by fleeting orders inside the spread (a proxy for spoofing and competition between liquidity providers). (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cartea, Alvaro; Payne, Richard; Penalva, Jose; Tapia, Mikel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio sales and signaling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bougheas, Spiros; Worrall, Tim
This paper extends the DeMarzo and Duffle (1999) signaling model from single sales to portfolio sales. It shows that the extended model can account for retention of low quality assets and help explain why retained assets may be of varying quality. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bougheas, Spiros; Worrall, Tim</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash versus card: Payment discontinuities and the burden of holding coins</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Heng; Huynh, Kim P.; Shy, Oz
This paper provides new insights on consumers payment choice by comparing cost of paying with cash to paying with cards. Our novel method accounts for how much change is received in the form of banknotes and metal coins, assuming that the weight and size of coins are inconvenient to carry. We use the regression discontinuity design approach to estimate the model using the 2013 Bank of Canada Method-of-Payments Survey and find a significant number of cash users who switch to paying with debit or credit cards at transaction values marginally above $5 and $10. We attribute this finding to the burden of receiving coins as change associated with the currency denomination structure. Our proposed methodology is general and can be applied to other countries and institutional details. Crown Copyright (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Heng; Huynh, Kim P.; Shy, Oz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk mitigation by institutional participants in the secondary market: Evidence from foreign Rule 144A debt market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Alan G.; Kalimipalli, Madhu; Nayak, Subhankar; Ramchand, Latha
We study secondary market trades of debt issues by foreign firms in the U.S. under SEC Rule 144A, a unique market where the counterparties are qualified institutional buyers (QIBs). We find that even though the secondary yield spreads of foreign 144A debt issues are larger than comparable public debt issues by foreign and domestic firms in the U.S., the incremental impact of common risks - namely, credit, illiquidity, governance, and familiarity risks - on spreads are lower for foreign 144A issues compared to various control samples. Our finding is consistent with the notion that institutional participants, namely QIBs, play a specialized role in mitigating risk exposures in the foreign 144A secondary market. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Alan G.; Kalimipalli, Madhu; Nayak, Subhankar; Ramchand, Latha</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do financial crises cleanse the banking industry? Evidence from US commercial bank exits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spokeviciute, Laima; Keasey, Kevin; Vallascas, Francesco
We examine the cleansing effect of financial crises via their contribution to the exit of inefficient US commercial banks from 1984 to 2013. We find a larger increase in the exit likelihood of less efficient banks as compared to more efficient banks in the years of the Savings and Loans Crisis but not during the Global Financial Crisis. We highlight how the magnitude of the shock of the Global Financial Crisis and the subsequent, broad government interventions might explain these different results. Furthermore, we highlight that both crisis periods have a disproportionate effect on young banks regardless of their efficiency levels and that they do not generate any positive spillover effects on surviving banks in the three years post-crises in spite of some reallocation benefits in favor of new entry banks. Our findings highlight that forms of prudential regulation designed to strengthen bank resilience in good times might contribute to mitigating the effects of crisis on the longer-term productivity of the banking industry. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Spokeviciute, Laima; Keasey, Kevin; Vallascas, Francesco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and credit procyclicality in European banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leroy, Aurelien; Lucotte, Yannick
This paper empirically assesses how competition in the banking sector affects credit procyclicality by estimating both an interacted panel VAR model using macroeconomic data and a single-equation model with bank-level data. These two empirical approaches show that a deviation of actual GDP from potential GDP leads to greater credit fluctuations in economies where bank competition is weak. This suggests that increased market power for banks increases the financial accelerator mechanism, which is consistent with recent macroeconomic models showing that monopolistic banking tends to increase macroeconomic volatility by making credit cheaper during booms and more expensive during recessions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leroy, Aurelien; Lucotte, Yannick</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing for cojumps in high-frequency financial data: An approach based on first-high-low-last prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liao, Yin; Anderson, Heather M.
This paper proposes a new test for simultaneous intraday jumps (cojumps) in a panel of high frequency financial data. We utilize intraday first-high-low-last values of asset prices to construct estimates for the cross-variation of returns in a large panel of high frequency financial data, which we then use to form a test statistic that can detect cojumps. Simulations show that a bias corrected version of the test performs well when microstructure noise is present. Applied to a panel of high frequency Chinese equity data, our test identifies cojumps that coincide with announcements relating to monetary policy and stock market regulations. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liao, Yin; Anderson, Heather M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does dialect similarity add value to banks? Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bian, Wenlong; Ji, Yang; Zhang, Hao
This study examines the value of language, as an important dimension of culture, to banks. Based on a unique hand-collected dataset of Chinese commercial banks and a county-level dialect dataset, we find that a higher degree of dialect similarity between the chairman and the CEO is associated with a higher return on assets, a higher return on equity, and a lower cost-to-income ratio, suggesting that dialect similarity plays a positive role in improving bank performance. Further analyses show that dialect similarity has no significant association with bank risk and bank expansion. In addition, it does not cause higher CEO pay or lower pay-performance sensitivity. These results indicate that dialect similarity does not lower the monitoring effectiveness. We also investigate the relation between dialect similarity and banks' agency costs and the results show that dialect similarity reduces agency costs significantly. Our findings are robust to alternative measures of dialect similarity, the separation of the "dialect level effect", and the potential endogeneity of dialect similarity. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bian, Wenlong; Ji, Yang; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic conditions, financial constraints, and firms' financing decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Xin; Chen, Yunling; Dasgupta, Sudipto
We examine how time-varying macroeconomic conditions affect firms' financing decisions. A principal components decomposition of several macroeconomic variables characterizes three phases of the business cycle relative to recessions: early recovery, robust recovery, and economic crest; a fourth represents "windows of opportunity" in capital markets that are unrelated to recessions. This characterization yields results that traditional approaches miss. Specifically, debt issuance exhibits a non-monotonic pattern during the upward phase of the business cycle: it declines in robust recovery relative to recessions but peaks at the economic crest. Financially constrained firms issue more equity during windows of high stock market valuation, whereas unconstrained firms time debt issuance in response to debt market spreads. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chang, Xin; Chen, Yunling; Dasgupta, Sudipto</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do long-term institutional investors promote corporate social responsibility activities?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Hyun-Dong; Kim, Taeyeon; Kim, Yura; Park, Kwangwoo
This paper examines how the investment horizons of a firm's institutional investors affect its corporate social responsibility (CSR) activities. Using data on U.S. firms' CSR ratings over the 1995-2012 period, we find that longer investment horizons are positively related to CSR. Further, active long-term institutions increase CSR whereas passive long-term institutions have no significant effect. Our results suggest that investors with long-term horizons have more incentives to monitor their firms which leads managers to engage in more vigorous CSR activities. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Hyun-Dong; Kim, Taeyeon; Kim, Yura; Park, Kwangwoo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A new measure of financial constraints applicable to private and public firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schauer, Catharina; Elsas, Ralf; Breitkopf, Nikolas
We study managers' self-assessment of their firm's financial constraint status to assess the validity of commonly used indicators of financial constraints. As categorizations based on common financial constraints measures lead to high misclassifications, we derive a new measure of financial constraints which performs well in-sample and out-of-sample for private firms. Applying our new measure to a large sample of private European firms, we find consistently lower investment-cash flow sensitivities and greater distortions in response to exogenous financing frictions for constrained firms across countries. Besides private firms, our new measure can also be applied to listed U.S. firms, as it reliably identifies constrained firms as measured by the occurrence of liquidity events and the incidence of an inelastic capital supply. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schauer, Catharina; Elsas, Ralf; Breitkopf, Nikolas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictors and portfolios over the life cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kraft, Holger; Munk, Claus; Weiss, Farina
In a calibrated consumption-portfolio model with stock, housing, and labor income predictability, we evaluate the welfare effects of predictability on life-cycle consumption-portfolio choice. We compare skilled investors who are able to take advantage of all sources of predictability with unskilled investors ignoring predictability. For an unskilled investor the certainty equivalent of wealth is 0.3-6.8% lower than for a skilled investor, depending on the market entry date. We also determine the effect of luck to enter the market at a favorable time. Across market entry dates, skilled but unlucky investors can lose up to 15.4% compared to unskilled but lucky investors. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kraft, Holger; Munk, Claus; Weiss, Farina</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictive blends: Fundamental Indexing meets Markowitz</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pysarenko, Sergiy; Alexeev, Vitali; Tapon, Francis
When constructing a portfolio of stocks, do you turn a blind eye to the firms' future outlooks based on careful consideration of companies' fundamentals, or do you ignore the stocks' correlation structures which ensure the best diversification? The Fundamental Indexing (FI) and Markowitz mean-variance optimization (MVO) approaches are complementary but, until now, have been considered separately in the portfolio choice literature. Using data on S&amp;P 500 constituents, we evaluate a novel portfolio construction technique that utilizes the benefits of both approaches. Relying on the idea of forecast averaging, we propose to blend the two previously mentioned techniques to provide investors with a clear binocular vision. The out-of-sample results of the blended portfolios attest to their superior performance when compared to common market benchmarks, and to portfolios constructed solely based on the FI or MVO methods. In pursuit of the optimal blend between the two distinct portfolio construction techniques, MVO and FI, we find that the ratio of market capitalization to GDP, being a leading indicator for an overpriced market, demonstrates remarkably advantageous properties. Our superior results cannot be explained by classic asset pricing models. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pysarenko, Sergiy; Alexeev, Vitali; Tapon, Francis</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Higher-order Omega: A performance index with a decision-theoretic foundation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bi, Hongwei; Huang, Rachel J.; Tzeng, Larry Y.; Zhu, Wei
This paper proposes a new performance index referred to as the Nth-order Omega that includes the well-known Omega as a special case. The index is established by adopting an approach that is free of a utility functional form or/and distributional assumptions. A decision-theoretic foundation for our index is further established through introducing a new distribution ranking criterion. The index is monotonic with respect to Nth-degree stochastic dominance and offers a complete ordering on gambles. An empirical example of deriving the optimal hedge ratio is demonstrated to show the applicability of the index. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bi, Hongwei; Huang, Rachel J.; Tzeng, Larry Y.; Zhu, Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does residual state ownership increase stock return volatility? Evidence from China's secondary privatization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xie, Feng; Anderson, Hamish D.; Chi, Jing; Liao, Jing
Using hand-collected data, we find residual state ownership is negatively related to stock return volatility, following China's secondary privatization initiated by the non-tradable share reform. Conservative corporate policies are channels through which residual state ownership reduces stock return volatility. Further, the volatility-mitigating effect is more prevalent in firms in which the government has greater influence on corporate decisions. However, the volatility-mitigating effect is temporary, lasting up to three years after state shares become fully tradable. The evidence suggests the government can send credible signals by retaining state ownership, which reduces investor uncertainty. However, investors must weigh the positive signaling effect of residual state ownership in reducing uncertainty, surrounding sudden policy changes, against the inefficiencies of state control. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xie, Feng; Anderson, Hamish D.; Chi, Jing; Liao, Jing</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political uncertainty exposure of individual companies: The case of the Brexit referendum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hill, Paula; Korczak, Adriana; Korczak, Piotr
This paper studies cross-sectional determinants of the exposure of U.K. firms to Brexit, an event which resulted in an unprecedented rise in political uncertainty. We find that internationalization has a moderating effect on Brexit exposure which goes beyond the pure currency translation effect and is consistent with international activities acting as a diversification mechanism for domestic risks. We also provide some indicative evidence that high-growth firms are more affected by Brexit. At the industry level, we show that Financials and firms in the consumer-facing sectors have the highest exposure to Brexit-related uncertainty. Knowledge of the variation in exposure of individual firms and sectors to political uncertainty associated with major political events can assist managers, investors and policymakers in taking remedial actions to limit its impact. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hill, Paula; Korczak, Adriana; Korczak, Piotr</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US monetary policy and the euro area</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanisch, Max
This study documents empirically that contractionary US monetary policy may generate short-term expansionary spillover effects. In individual Euro Area (EA) member countries, economic activity increases, mainly via the trade channel. Also, domestic credit and stock markets expand, highlighting the importance of the financial channel. However, the international repercussions are transitory and distributed unevenly within the EA. The effect diminishes as EA interest rates increase with a few quarters delay. While the effects are heterogenous and rather large before 1999, responses become more homogeneous and smaller in size after the implementation of the euro. Still, country-specific asymmetries remain. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanisch, Max</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does seller status matter in inter-corporate asset sales?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, Giang; Nguyen, Hai
This paper examines the returns of asset acquirers when sellers have different statuses. We find that private sellers create lower returns for acquirers and receive higher premiums than public sellers. Both private equity and private operating sellers generate lower returns for acquirers than public sellers, but their relative gain differences are not significantly different. In addition, the gain difference cannot be explained by acquirer characteristics, sample selection effects, or means of payments, but it increases with sellers' director ownership. We examine alternative theories to explain our results. While we do not find supportive evidence for the synergy creation and information symmetry hypothesis, we find ample evidence for the manager discretion hypothesis. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nguyen, Giang; Nguyen, Hai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging parameter risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claussen, Arndt; Roesch, Daniel; Schmelzle, Martin
The accurate measurement and effective control of financial risk are of crucial importance to risk managers and regulators. However, risk measures are potentially affected by errors in the estimation of model parameters from limited samples, leading to parameter risk. The key contribution of this paper is the formulation of a general framework to hedge this parameter risk. Applying the new framework to credit portfolio modeling, we highlight the importance of parameter risk, estimation methods, and diversification effects. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Claussen, Arndt; Roesch, Daniel; Schmelzle, Martin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy mandates and institutional architecture</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lazopoulos, Ioannis; Gabriel, Vasco
The model developed in this paper examines the interaction between monetary and macroprudential policies in promoting macroeconomic stability, highlighting the role of shocks and policy instruments. The paper shows that assigning the mandates of monetary and financial stability to independent authorities enhances macroeconomic stability only when some level of coordination exists between policymakers and it is the dominant institutional arrangement when monetary stability is socially important. Instead, when society values financial stability, internalising the policy spillovers by assigning the two mandates to a single policymaker could become the dominant configuration depending on the model's parameter values. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lazopoulos, Ioannis; Gabriel, Vasco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does corporate social responsibility reduce the costs of high leverage? Evidence from capital structure and product market interactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, Kee-Hong; El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.; Zheng, Ying
Research on capital structure and product market interactions shows that high leverage is associated with substantial losses in market share due to unfavorable actions by customers and competitors. We examine whether corporate social responsibility (CSR) affects firms' interactions with customers and competitors, and whether it can reduce the costs of high leverage. We find that CSR reduces losses in market share when firms are highly leveraged. By reducing adverse behavior by customers and competitors, CSR helps highly leveraged firms keep customers and guard against rivals' predation. Our results support the stakeholder value maximization view of CSR. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bae, Kee-Hong; El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.; Zheng, Ying</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The debt tax shield in general equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischer, Marcel; Jensen, Bjarne Astrup
We study the general-equilibrium effects of the corporate debt tax shield in an endowment economy with a redistributive tax system that taxes firm profits and household income and redistributes tax revenues in an attempt to harmonize households' lifetime consumption opportunities. In general equilibrium, the debt tax shield not only affects corporate capital structure and valuation but also causes poorer households to consume more and save less at a younger age. Without the debt tax shield, the same welfare improvements for poorer households are achievable with significantly lower tax rates. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fischer, Marcel; Jensen, Bjarne Astrup</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial risk incentives and a firm's financing policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karpavicius, Sigitas; Yu, Fan
This paper provides a theoretical explanation for how risk preferences of a firm's manager impact a firm's optimal financing policy and shareholder value. The developed model implies that firms in growing industries are more valuable if they are run by more risk-seeking managers. Similarly, firms operating in declining industries should be run by less risk-seeking managers. Given that a firm's optimal assets do not depend on the growth opportunities, and that debt is the difference between assets and equity, the model implies that there is a negative (positive) correlation between the riskiness of CEOs' compensation packages and firms' financial leverage ratios for firms in growing (declining) industries. This prediction is in stark contrast to economic intuition and prior literature in that less risk aversion normally should increase risk-taking. The empirical analysis generally supports all the model's implications except those related to firms operating in declining industries. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Karpavicius, Sigitas; Yu, Fan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation effects of overconfident CEOs on corporate diversification and refocusing decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andreou, Panayiotis C.; Doukas, John A.; Koursaros, Demetris; Louca, Christodoulos
This study presents a theoretical model that links chief executive officer (CEO) overconfidence to the value loss of corporate diversification. Consistent with the model's prediction, the findings show that diversified firms run by overconfident CEOs experience value loss compared to diversified firms run by their rational counterparts. Empirically, the value loss is economically significant and ranges between 12.5% and 14.1%. In addition, the model predicts heightened corporate refocusing activity by overconfident CEOs who pursued diversified investments in the past once realized returns fail to match initial expectations. The empirical odds of corporate refocusing decisions are 67% to 98% higher when past diversifications are undertaken by overconfident rather than rational CEOs. Another prediction of the model is that overconfident CEOs exhibit preference for diversified investments, especially in the presence of ample internal funds. This prediction is also strongly supported by the data. Overall, this study proposes CEO overconfidence as a unified and consistent explanation of why firms pursue value-destructive corporate diversification policies and later adopt refocusing policies aiming to restore value. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andreou, Panayiotis C.; Doukas, John A.; Koursaros, Demetris; Louca, Christodoulos</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateralization and distance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bellucci, Andrea; Borisov, Alexander; Giombini, Germana; Zazzaro, Alberto
This paper examines how collateralization in small business lending varies with bank-borrower proximity. Our analysis establishes a robust inverse relationship between distance and collateral: Borrowers located in the vicinity of the bank face higher collateral requirements. The estimated relationship is independent of the allocation of decision-making authority within the lending organization, competitive pressure in the local credit markets, or risk rating of the borrower. Our findings seem consistent with the notion that distance reflects transaction costs associated with the assessment, inspection, and possible repossession of collateral. (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bellucci, Andrea; Borisov, Alexander; Giombini, Germana; Zazzaro, Alberto</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local religious norms, corporate social responsibility, and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zolotoy, Leon; O'Sullivan, Don; Chen, Yangyang
We explore the impact of religious norms on the relationship between corporate social responsibility (CSR) and firm value. Employing a longitudinal sample of publicly listed U.S. firms, we document that strong local religious norms in the area surrounding firms' headquarters attenuate the positive effect of CSR on firm value. In cross-sectional analyses, we find that the attenuating effect of strong local religious norms is amplified for firms with heightened litigation risk. We also find that the positive effect of CSR on firm value is amplified for firms headquartered in areas where prevailing religious norms are more tolerant of risk-taking. Further, we find that strong religious norms attenuated the positive association between CSR and abnormal stock returns during the 2008-2009 financial crisis. Taken together, our findings cast local religious norms as an important contextual factor that influences the insurance value of CSR the protection that CSR affords against stakeholder reactions to negative events. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zolotoy, Leon; O'Sullivan, Don; Chen, Yangyang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New directions in entrepreneurial finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, Douglas; Deloof, Marc; Manigart, Sophie; Wright, Mike
Entrepreneurial finance is a distinctive aspect of corporate finance, notably with respect to informational asymmetries and investor involvement in portfolio companies. Entrepreneurial finance research has explored four levels of analysis: the entrepreneur or entrepreneurial firm, the organization providing finance to the entrepreneurs, the organizations providing funds to these organizations, and the region or country in which the entrepreneurial firms or investors are established. We discuss recent developments in forms of entrepreneurial finance. We summarize the contributions of the papers published in this issue on entrepreneurial finance at different points in the life cycle, including work on trade credit, debt finance, micro-cap IPOs, venture capital, and angel finance. Also, we highlight avenues for future research focusing on funding gaps, accelerators, crowdfunding, secondary buyouts, boards, and exits. (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cumming, Douglas; Deloof, Marc; Manigart, Sophie; Wright, Mike</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The financing dynamics of newly founded firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirsch, Julia; Walz, Uwe
We aim to extend the sparse knowledge on the financing dynamics of newly founded firms by investigating 2456 French manufacturing firms that were founded between 2004 and 2006. Our data comes from their legally required and reported financial statements. We observe significant heterogeneity in the financing decisions at foundation and analyze whether these differences widen or converge by using different convergence concepts. We consistently find beta-convergence that indicates the initial financing decisions have a negative effect on the accumulation of this source of financing. After investigating the development of variation in financing patterns across firms over time (sigma-convergence), we find mixed results. While differences in debt composition (e.g. role of trade credit, bank loans as well as relation between short and long-term debt) vanish over time the opposite is true for debt-equity mixes. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hirsch, Julia; Walz, Uwe</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial manipulation with staged financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yung, Chris
Finance is staged in entrepreneurial settings. It has been argued that staging has a drawback: entrepreneurs manipulate short-term appearances to keep funds flowing. In contrast, this paper finds that staging can lead to either more or less manipulation than non-staged finance. Finally, behavior in early rounds induces a kind of "manipulation persistence" so that total manipulation is path-dependent. The model makes predictions regarding crowdsourced finance, switching of VCs, and lifecycle issues in entrepreneurial finance. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Yung, Chris</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial innovation in microcap public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knyazeva, Anzhela
This paper examines external financing of small and growth firms using a regulatory experiment in the US microcap market. The paper focuses on a new financing method for entrepreneurial firms - small public offerings under Regulation A, which was significantly expanded by 2015 amendments. Regulation A offerings serve as a financing alternative for issuers that seek public capital but are unable to conduct a traditional registered public offering. Compared to small registered public offerings, Regulation A involves fewer requirements and draws smaller, younger companies, often raising capital without intermediaries or on a best efforts basis. Regulation A companies raise less capital on average after accounting for their historical financials. The use of Regulation A increased significantly following the 2015 shock, particularly in market segments that had more private placements and traditional public offerings. Different types of issuers are pursuing Regulation A and registered offerings, and Regulation A does not appear to draw issuers away from traditional public offerings. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Knyazeva, Anzhela</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A personality perspective on business angel syndication</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Block, Joern H.; Fisch, Christian O.; Obschonka, Martin; Sandner, Philipp G.
The decision to syndicate investments in entrepreneurial finance has been explained through financial, networking, and resource-based perspectives. We posit that a personality perspective exists next to these three perspectives and hypothesize that the personality of business angels influences syndication behavior. Using data from 3,234 syndication decisions of 1,348 business angels, we find evidence for some of our predictions. By measuring personality through a comprehensive language analysis based on digital footprints in Twitter statements of business angels, we show that extraversion makes syndication more likely, whereas conscientiousness reduces the likelihood of syndication. Several sensitivity analyses underline the robustness of our main results. Further exploratory analyses assess the relationship between personality and syndicate composition as well as that between personality and venture success. Our study contributes to the entrepreneurial finance literature by adding and validating a new perspective to explain syndication behavior. In addition, our study contributes to research on the personality of business angels. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Block, Joern H.; Fisch, Christian O.; Obschonka, Martin; Sandner, Philipp G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of angel-backed companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonini, Stefano; Capizzi, Vincenzo; Zocchi, Paola
We provide empirical evidence of the post-investment performance and survivorship profile of angel backed companies, filling a long-standing gap within the entrepreneurial finance literature. Using a unique database of 111 angel-backed companies that received angel investments between 2008 and 2012 and at least 3 years of post-investment financial data, we develop an innovative performance metric and show that the performance and the probability of survival of investee companies are positively affected by the presence of angel syndicates and the hands-on involvement of business angels, while they are negatively related to the intensity of angel monitoring and the time structure of equity provision. Our results are robust to several endogeneity tests and provide insights on the multifaceted contributions of angel investors to the performance and survival of new ventures. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bonini, Stefano; Capizzi, Vincenzo; Zocchi, Paola</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Made for each other: Perfect matching in venture capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fu, Hui; Yang, Jun; An, Yunbi
This paper studies bargaining power allocation and stable matching between venture capitalists and entrepreneurs with double-sided moral hazard in venture capital markets. We find that the optimal bargaining power allocation is determined by the output elasticities of effort by the two parties; the higher the output elasticity for one's effort, the greater her bargaining power. We show that efficient and stable matching follows the principle of positive assortative matching, suggesting that strong entrepreneurs/VCs match with strong partners, and weak ones match with weak counterparts. Using a large sample from the Chinese venture capital market, we empirically confirm that entrepreneurs and VCs with similar standing in their peer groups are more likely to match. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fu, Hui; Yang, Jun; An, Yunbi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beggars or choosers? Lead venture capitalists and the impact of reputation on syndicate partner selection in international settings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Plagmann, Carolin; Lutz, Eva
We investigate the importance of reputation for lead venture capitalists' choice of international and domestic syndicate partners for domestic deals. Our study is based on a novel dataset of global syndicated investments covering the period 2005 to 2014 and comprising 46,101 triads among lead investors, syndicate partners, and portfolio firms. We find reputation to be more relevant in selecting cross-border co-investors than local co-investors. The results are consistent for our international and domestic reputation scores as well as for single reputation components such as equity invested, number of investments, or number of IPO exits. In addition, we show that the reputation of the lead investor matters in international syndicate partner selection. Highly reputed venture capitalists seem to follow an intricate decision model in which they carefully choose cross-border partners over domestic ones. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Plagmann, Carolin; Lutz, Eva</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk and competition revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Silva-Buston, Consuelo
This paper revisits the mechanism behind the relation between bank competition and systemic risk. I decompose this risk into a component driven by banks' commonality with the market and a component arising from other sources of interbank commonality. I show that competition is negatively related to the latter. This relationship is stronger for more informationally opaque banks, financed with a larger share of uninsured sources and in countries with lower deposit insurance coverage. The findings are consistent with herding incentives at banks when competition is low. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Silva-Buston, Consuelo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Operational risk and reputation in financial institutions: Does media tone make a difference?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barakat, Ahmed; Ashby, Simon; Fenn, Paul; Bryce, Cormac
Operational risk announcements are unexpected adverse media news that potentially harm the reputation of financial institutions. This paper examines the equity-based and debt-based reputational effects of financial sentiment tones in operational risk announcements and shows how such reputational effects are moderated by alternative sources of public information. Our analysis reveals that the net negative tone and litigious tone have adverse reputational effects, and the uncertainty tone mitigates the adverse reputational impact. Additionally, alternative, simultaneous sources of information neutralize the reputational effects of textual tones. First, third-party information about the event (i.e. regulatory announcements and final settlements) dissolves the favorable (adverse) reputational impact of the uncertainty tone (litigious tone). Second, loss amount disclosure and firm recognition substitute the reputational effects of the net negative tone and uncertainty tone only in Anglo-Saxon countries and market-based economies. Overall, our findings indicate that the reputational effects of the media materialize most when there is lack of certain, quantifiable and regulated public information about the operational risk event. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barakat, Ahmed; Ashby, Simon; Fenn, Paul; Bryce, Cormac</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market development and the financing role of IPOs in acquisitionsn</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aktas, Nihat; Andries, Kathleen; Croci, Ettore; Ozdakak, Ali
We examine the role of IPOs as a source of financing by comparing firms from countries with different degrees of stock market development. Focusing on acquisition investments, our results suggest that firms operating in economies with a more developed stock market extract more benefits from the financing role of IPOs than firms from countries with a less developed stock market. Controlling for the importance of bank financing does not alter our main findings. IPO firms from market-focused countries also experience a relatively larger increase in size and in profitability in the post-IPO period. Our results indicate that the purpose of IPO financing varies with the financial system in general and with the degree of stock market development in particular. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aktas, Nihat; Andries, Kathleen; Croci, Ettore; Ozdakak, Ali</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of pro-environmental preferences on bond prices: Evidence from green bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zerbib, Olivier David
We use green bonds as an instrument to identify the effect of non-pecuniary motives, specifically pro environmental preferences, on bond market prices. We perform a matching method, followed by a two-step regression procedure, to estimate the yield differential between a green bond and a counterfactual conventional bond from July 2013 to December 2017. The results suggest a small negative premium: the yield of a green bond is lower than that of a conventional bond. On average, the premium is -2 basis points for the entire sample and for euro and USD bonds separately. We show that this negative premium is more pronounced for financial and low-rated bonds. The results emphasize the low impact of investors' pro-environmental preferences on bond prices, which does not represent, at this stage, a disincentive for investors to support the expansion of the green bond market. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zerbib, Olivier David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How persistent are the effects of experience sampling on investor behavior?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradbury, Meike A. S.; Hens, Thorsten; Zeisberger, Stefan
Investor behavior was shown to be considerably different when the risk-return tradeoff is presented by experience sampling as opposed to a descriptive communication. We analyze the persistency of this difference in a setting in which investors are faced with multiple decisions over time and are consequently able to adjust the risk level they initially chose. For this we use an experimental setting with repeated investment decisions over multiple trading days, and we also test a new form of risk simulation in which wealth paths over time are presented rather than just final outcomes. After investors' initial decisions, for which we confirm previous findings, we do not find persistent differences of simulation-based learning on investors' risk-taking behavior. With regards to trading volume, only a simulation in which investors see wealth paths and not only final outcomes leads to lower trading frequency soon after the initial asset allocation. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bradbury, Meike A. S.; Hens, Thorsten; Zeisberger, Stefan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-sectional seasonalities in international government bond returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zaremba, Adam
We are the first to document the cross-sectional return seasonality effect in international government bonds. Using a variety of tests, we examine fixed-income securities from 22 countries for the years 1980-2018. The bonds with high (low) returns in the same-calendar month in the past continue to overperform (underperform) in the future. The effect is robust to many considerations, including controlling for established predictors of bond returns. Our results support the behavioural story of the anomaly, demonstrating its highest profitability in the periods of elevated investor sentiment and in the market segments of strong limits to arbitrage. Nonetheless, investment application of bond seasonality might be challenging due to high trading costs and the required short holding periods. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zaremba, Adam</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do firms value debt capacity? Evidence from mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, James S.; Daher, Mai M.; Ismail, Ahmad K.
We examine how capital structure considerations affect acquisition pricing and valuation. We find that debt capacity improvement is value-enhancing for all acquirers when they gradually reveal their growth opportunities to the market. This is reflected in the long-run stock market returns, both 12- and 24-months after acquisition announcement. While both overlevered and underlevered acquirers benefit from an increase in debt capacity resulting from the merger, only overlevered acquirers pay higher premiums to increase debt capacity. Underlevered acquirers do not pay a premium for it; instead they consider market timing opportunities. Results are robust for alternative definitions of leverage and debt capacity improvement. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, James S.; Daher, Mai M.; Ismail, Ahmad K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset growth, style investing, and momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chou, Pin-Huang; Ko, Kuan-Cheng; Yang, Nien-Tzu
We establish a significant and robust connection between asset growth (AG) and style investing by showing that past style returns constructed based on AG and size jointly predict future stock returns significantly. Motivated by this notion, we propose a style momentum strategy based on AG and size and find that it dominates price momentum and size-BM style momentum in generating momentum profits. We examine two explanations for this predictability, including risk exposure to common risk factors and the limited-attention theory. Empirical evidence shows that the AG-size style momentum profit is induced because investors neglect the AG-size style performance, consistent with the limited-attention explanation, but not risk exposure to the investment factor. Further, we show that the profit of the AG-size style momentum is robust to different time periods partitioned by several time-series predictors. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chou, Pin-Huang; Ko, Kuan-Cheng; Yang, Nien-Tzu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The asymmetric effect of equity volatility on credit default swap spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Hwang Hee; Hyun, Jung-Soon
This study examines whether good and bad news have any asymmetric effect on credit default swap (CDS) spreads by decomposing equity volatility into continuous variation and signed jumps depending on the information. We find that negative jumps affect CDS spreads more significantly and economically than positive jumps even after controlling for other variables related to credit risk. This finding suggests that negative jumps in equity prices would be a credit risk factor of individual firms. Moreover, the effects of jumps on CDS spreads are more pronounced for firms with high leverage ratios and small sizes. Finally, we show that our findings remain intact even when considering the global financial crisis period and different CDS maturity terms. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Hwang Hee; Hyun, Jung-Soon</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A jump-diffusion model for pricing and hedging with margined options: An application to Brent crude oil contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hilliard, Jimmy E.; Hilliard, Jitka
We develop a jump-diffusion model for pricing and hedging with margined options on futures. Unlike a standard equity option, margined options require no up-front payment. An attractive feature of margined options is that there is no early exercise premiums under general assumptions. Model parameter estimates and out-of-sample pricing errors are calculated using data on Brent crude contracts. Using the same pricing technology, we also hedge equity style options with margined options. Hedging coefficients are derived by matching an extended set of Greeks. We find that a target equity option can be effectively hedged using a portfolio of two margined options and the underlying. As has been reported elsewhere, a delta hedge is inappropriate when the underlying is a jump-diffusion. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hilliard, Jimmy E.; Hilliard, Jitka</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign bond yield spreads and sustainability: An empirical analysis of OECD countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Capelle-Blancard, Gunther; Crifo, Patricia; Diaye, Marc-Arthur; Oueghlissi, Rim; Scholtens, Bert
We study whether and how a country's environmental, social, and governance (ESG) performance relates to its sovereign borrowing costs in international capital markets. We hypothesize that good ESG performance plays an economic role: It signals a country's commitment to sustainability and long-term orientation and is a buffer against negative shocks, leading to lower sovereign bond yield spreads. Using a sample of 20 OECD countries over the period 1996-2012, we show that countries with good ESG performance are associated with lower default risk and lower sovereign bond yield spreads. Moreover, we show that the social and governance dimensions have a significant negative association with sovereign bond yield spreads, whereas the environmental dimension does not. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Capelle-Blancard, Gunther; Crifo, Patricia; Diaye, Marc-Arthur; Oueghlissi, Rim; Scholtens, Bert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Senior debt and market discipline: Evidence from bank-to-bank loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Bill; Hasan, Iftekhar; Liu, LiuLing; Wang, Haizhi
We empirically investigate whether taking senior bank loans would enhance market discipline and control risk-taking among borrowing banks. Controlling for endogeneity concern arising from borrowing bank self-select into taking senior bank debt, we document that both the spreads and covenants in loan contracts are sensitive to bank risk variables. Our analysis also reveals that borrowing banks reduce their risk exposure after their first issuance of senior bank debt. We also find that lending banks significantly increase their collaboration with borrowing banks and increase their presence in the home markets of borrowing banks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Francis, Bill; Hasan, Iftekhar; Liu, LiuLing; Wang, Haizhi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do analysts really anchor? Evidence from credit risk and suppressed negative information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ashour, Samar; Hao
Recent findings indicate that stock analysts suffer from anchoring bias as they anchor their earnings per share forecasts on the industry median without making sufficient adjustments. Using a sample of firms rated by Standard and Poor's, we determine that this finding is concentrated in the worst rated firms, especially around credit rating downgrades. The driving force of the finding is that stock analysts suppress negative information for high credit risk stocks by dropping coverage instead of issuing low earnings per share forecasts, especially around credit rating downgrades. Our finding explains not only why stock analysts seem to suffer from anchoring bias, but also why analysts are overly optimistic for high credit risk stocks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ashour, Samar; Hao</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board interlock networks and informed short sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Shijun; Felix, Robert; Zhao, Yijiang
This study examines the association between informed short selling and a firm's position in the board interlock network formed by shared directors. We find that better-connected firms experience higher levels of informed short selling and that this association is driven by both eigenvector centrality (a measure that accounts for both the quantity and quality of firms' ties) and betweenness centrality (a measure of the extent to which firms serve as information intermediaries), not by degree centrality (a measure that only counts the quantity of their ties) in interlock networks. In addition, the positive association between interlock centrality and informed trading is more pronounced for firms whose directors have more opportunities to interact with directors of external firms in the network, consistent with director information leakage serving as a plausible underlying channel. Our further tests do not support an alternative interpretation based on short sellers' superior processing of public information. Our findings have policy implications for regulators and professional director associations. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cheng, Shijun; Felix, Robert; Zhao, Yijiang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Upside potential of hedge funds as a predictor of future performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Caglayan, Mustafa O.
This paper investigates the relationship between upside potential and future hedge fund returns. We measure upside potential based on the maximum monthly returns of hedge funds (MAX) over a fixed time interval, and show that MAX successfully predicts cross-sectional differences in future fund returns. Hedge funds with strong upside potential generate 0.70% per month higher average returns than funds with weak upside potential. After controlling for alternative risk and performance measures, funds' market-timing ability, and a large set of fund characteristics, the positive link between MAX and future returns remains highly significant. We conclude that MAX, as a simple proxy for realized noln-normalities in hedge funds, offers incremental information on future hedge fund returns above and beyond provided by standard risk, performance, and market-timing measures. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Caglayan, Mustafa O.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Activist investors and open market share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Autore, Don M.; Clarke, Nicholas; Liu, Baixiao
This study examines the role of activist investors in firms' decisions to conduct open market share repurchases. Compared with firms making ordinary share repurchases, firms making activist-involved repurchases have more cash holdings, are more undervalued, experience better subsequent stock performance and similar improvements in operating performance, and eventually repurchase more shares. Moreover, repurchasing firms in which an activist investor claims to take a passive role exhibit no undervaluation, and repurchasing firms that make multiple repurchases exhibit share undervaluation only in repurchases where an activist is involved. In all, our findings suggest that activist-involvement is associated with improved corporate repurchase decisions. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Autore, Don M.; Clarke, Nicholas; Liu, Baixiao</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual pension risk preference elicitation and collective asset allocation with heterogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alserda, Gosse A. G.; Dellaert, Benedict G. C.; Swinkels, Laurens; van der Lecq, Fieke S. G.
Collectively organized pension plans must increasingly demonstrate that the risk preferences of their members are adequately reflected in the plans' asset allocations. However, whether funds should elicit individual members' risk preferences to achieve this goal, or whether they can rely on other indicators, such as socio-demographics, remains unclear. To address this question, we apply a tailored augmented lottery choice method to elicit individual pension income risk preferences from 7894 members from five different pension plans. The results show that member risk preferences are strongly heterogeneous and can only partially be predicted from individual and plan characteristics. Differences in risk preference imply different optimal asset allocations. We find large welfare losses for heterogeneous members in pension plans with their current asset allocation because these allocations are safer than implied by members' preferences. We provide a framework for pension plans to gauge the need to elicit risk preferences among their members. (C) 2019 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Alserda, Gosse A. G.; Dellaert, Benedict G. C.; Swinkels, Laurens; van der Lecq, Fieke S. G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Family firms and access to credit. Is family ownership beneficial?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murro, Pierluigi; Peruzzi, Valentina
This paper investigates the impact of family ownership on credit rationing using a rich sample of Italian firms. Estimation results indicate that family owned firms are more likely to experience credit restrictions. The adverse impact of family ownership on credit rationing is particularly relevant for small-sized firms, whereas it is mitigated in firms with closer lending relationships. Finally, we find some evidence that family firms with high ownership concentration are more likely to be rationed by banks. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Murro, Pierluigi; Peruzzi, Valentina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Experimental evidence on bank runs with uncertain deposit coverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peia, Oana; Vranceanu, Radu
This paper studies depositor behavior in a bank run experiment with partial deposit insurance. In the experiment, depositors face two forms of uncertainty regarding their deposit coverage in the event of a bank run: (i) "intrinsic" uncertainty related to the size of the deposit insurance fund, and (ii) "strategic" uncertainty, as the actual coverage depends on the number of depositors who run on the bank. We consider three scenarios that differ in the way the deposit insurance scheme reimburses depositors. The results show that intrinsic uncertainty on its own has a negligible effect on the number of bank runs. However, when combined, the two forms of uncertainty exert a significant impact on the propensity to withdraw and result in a large number of bank runs. Moreover, runs are more frequent when leaving funds in the bank is an increasingly costly strategy. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Peia, Oana; Vranceanu, Radu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Director networks and initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, Yi; Song, Keke; Tian, Yisong S.
We investigate how director networks impact IPO characteristics and find that firms with better-connected directors have higher IPO market valuation, more positive offer price revisions, higher first-day returns, more pre-IPO media coverage, and superior post-IPO stock performance. Director networks are beneficial to the share offering because corporate directors help facilitate information exchange with prospective investors, attract their attention to the IPO, and maintain and grow their interest after the IPO. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Feng, Yi; Song, Keke; Tian, Yisong S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Passive mutual funds and ETFs: Performance and comparison</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; de Souza, Andre
Over 26% of investment company assets are held in passively managed vehicles. Thus, it is important to understand what affects the performance of passive vehicles and how to choose among the multiple passive options following any index. This paper examines the factors that are important in explaining differences across funds following the same index and demonstrates how to select a passive vehicle that has a high probability of having the best performance in the following years. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; de Souza, Andre</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Put-call parity violations and return predictability: Evidence from the 2008 short sale ban</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nishiotis, George P.; Rompolis, Leonidas S.
We investigate the link between stock and options markets during the 2008 U.S. short sale ban. First, we find definitive evidence that the ban indeed caused stock overvaluation. Second, we show that the short sale ban caused a significant increase in put-call parity violations only in the direction of the short sale constraints and it significantly enhanced the stock return predictability of put-call parity violations. Third, the overvaluation is really large. A portfolio formed on the trading signal that the put-call parity violation is in the top quintile underperforms the lowest quintile portfolio by a statistically and economically significant abnormal daily return of 5.6% during the short sale ban period. We employ a novel and rigorous method of using TAQ intraday data to ensure that our high-low violation arbitrage portfolio as well as the five Fama-French factors used to estimate the abnormal returns are implementable by a hypothetical investor exempt from the shorting ban. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nishiotis, George P.; Rompolis, Leonidas S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do small and medium enterprises (SMEs) demand property liability insurance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asai, Yoshihiro
Several empirical articles have attempted to clarify the insurance demands of listed firms, but few have sought to analyze small and medium enterprises' (SMEs) demands because of the unavailability of adequate data. In this study, I analyze SMEs' insurance demand by using a corporate survey and find the following. First, SMEs with relatively weak relationships with their main banks tend to demand more insurance. Second, SMEs with higher tax incentives tend to demand more insurance. Third, SMEs with a higher probability of bankruptcy tend to demand less insurance. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asai, Yoshihiro</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of government contracts on corporate valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Esqueda, Omar A.; Ngo, Thanh; Susnjara, Jurica
We document significantly lower valuations for government contractors in the United States. While contracting with government agencies reduces firms' cost of equity, it significantly lowers their sales growth. These findings are contingent on economic conditions; negative valuations dissipate as operating performance improves during economy- and industry-wide recessions. The overall negative valuation effect of government contracts holds only for government contractors in strategically unimportant industries, as strategically important contractors have higher valuations, driven by better operating performance regardless of economic conditions. This is the first study examining the relationship between government procurement and corporate valuation. It also adds to the growing body of literature on politically connected firms by analyzing government contractors as a related-but-separate channel of governmental influence on the corporate world. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Esqueda, Omar A.; Ngo, Thanh; Susnjara, Jurica</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives discretion in bank lending? Some evidence and a link to private information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ambrocio, Gene; Hasan, Iftekhar
We assess the extent to which discretion, unexplained variations in the terms of a loan contract, has varied across time and lending institutions and show that part of this discretion is due to private information that lenders have on their borrowers. We find that discretion is lower for secured loans and loans granted by a larger group of lenders, and is larger when the lenders are larger and more profitable. Over time, discretion is also lower around recessions although the private information content is higher. The results suggest that bank discretionary and private information acquisition behavior may be important features of the credit cycle. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ambrocio, Gene; Hasan, Iftekhar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt restructuring through equity issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Woojin; Ko, YoungKyung; Wang, Shu-Feng
This paper examines whether new equity may be issued to recapitalize existing assets in financially distressed firms. Using a sample of 3,184 follow-on primary common stock issues offered by Korean publicly traded firms from 2000-2013, we find that more than one-third of the equities are issued to creditors in direct exchange for debt. We also determine that equity issuers are in severe financial distress prior to the issue and are more likely to experience a subsequent change in control. The proceeds are used more to replace existing debt than to increase R&amp;D. These findings suggest that equity issues in emerging markets may be used primarily to recapitalize existing assets through debt restructuring or control transfers rather than to finance growth options. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Woojin; Ko, YoungKyung; Wang, Shu-Feng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>National culture and individual trading behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tan, Gary; Cheong, Chee Seng; Zurbruegg, Ralf
We study the role of national culture in influencing the trading behavior of individuals. We achieve this by analyzing the trading patterns of participants trading in a simulated asset market where decision outcomes are framed in terms of both gains and losses, and under different externally imposed constraints. By analyzing the trading history of participants from 21 countries and territories, we show that an individual's cultural background significantly impacts how often they trade, the size of their trades and how long they keep their positions open in the market. Our results are robust when controlling for personal and social characteristics of the traders and for how rewards are offered to traders. Overall, our research shows how culture relates to trading behavior and has implications for the liquidity and risk profiles of exchanges around the world. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tan, Gary; Cheong, Chee Seng; Zurbruegg, Ralf</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recovery rates: Uncertainty certainly matters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gambetti, Paolo; Gauthier, Genevieve; Vrins, Frederic
Previous studies identify default rate as the main systematic determinant of bond recovery rates. We revisit this paradigm by investigating the impact of another factor, economic uncertainty. Based on a wide sample of American default issues and relying on beta regression models, well-suited for the bounded, heteroskedastic and skewed sample of recovery rates, we analyze the determinants of recovery rate distributions. We find economic uncertainty to be of paramount importance, as it proves to be the most important systematic determinant of recovery rate distributions, significant for both their mean and dispersion. By contrast, default rate remains a key determinant of the dispersion of these distributions, but not for their means. Considering this evidence is critical to the sound implementation of stochastic recovery rate models used by financial institutions for the computation of regulatory capital. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gambetti, Paolo; Gauthier, Genevieve; Vrins, Frederic</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate capital structure actions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frank, Murray Z.; Shen, Tao
This paper is a study of the financing actions by firms to adjust leverage: debt reductions, stock sales, debt issues, and stock purchases. Each type of action is positively autocorrelated. The standard empirical models of corporate leverage produce leverage targets that do not correctly predict actual debt issues and stock sales. Firm-specific time-series regressions with the logarithm of firm assets and market-to-book as regressors, correctly predict these patterns. The estimates imply that on average firms adjust toward their target much faster than generally understood, closing about half of the leverage gap in a year. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frank, Murray Z.; Shen, Tao</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Drivers of solvency risk - Are microfinance institutions different?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schulte, Markus; Winkler, Adalbert
Based on a dataset covering 2938 banks and 1078 microfinance institutions (MFIs) operating in 106 countries this paper compares drivers of MFI and bank solvency risk. Measuring solvency risk by the nonperforming loans (NPL) ratio we find that several factors driving the bank NPL ratio play a more subdued role for MFIs. By contrast, MFI Z-scores, notably those of MFI banks, credit unions and other MFIs, are driven by largely the same factors as bank Z-scores. The difference in results can be linked to the special characteristics of credit technologies pursued by MFIs. Given that the Z-score is the broader risk measure we conclude from our results that larger and deposit taking MFIs should be subject to the same regulatory and supervisory regimes as banks. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schulte, Markus; Winkler, Adalbert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives interbank loans? Evidence from Canada</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bulusu, Narayan; Guerin, Pierre
We find that collateral reallocation costs are a significant driver of the dynamics of overnight interbank loans. The cost of negotiating and settling collateralized over-the-counter trades incentivizes the temporary use of unsecured loans to meet changes in short-term liquidity needs, as well as greater uptake of central bank overnight lending facilities. This friction also leads to repos adjusting gradually in response to persistent changes in liquidity demand. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bulusu, Narayan; Guerin, Pierre</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does efficiency help banks survive and thrive during financial crises?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Assaf, A. George; Berger, Allen N.; Roman, Raluca A.; Tsionas, Mike G.
We examine how bank efficiency during normal times affects survival, risk, and profitability during subsequent financial crises using data from five U.S. financial crises and preceding normal times. We find that cost efficiency during normal times helps reduce bank failure probabilities, decrease risk, and enhance profitability during subsequent financial crises, while profit efficiency has limited benefits. Results suggest that cost efficiency better measures management quality, while profit efficiency may partially reflect temporary high returns from risky investments during normal times. Findings have policy implications and imply that improving bank cost efficiency during normal times may promote better financial crisis performance. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Assaf, A. George; Berger, Allen N.; Roman, Raluca A.; Tsionas, Mike G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does scale matter in community bank performance? Evidence obtained by applying several new measures of performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hughes, Joseph P.; Jagtiani, Julapa; Mester, Loretta J.; Moon, Choon-Geol
We consider how size matters for banks in three size groups: small community banks with assets less than $1 billion, large community banks with assets between $1 billion and $10 billion, and midsize banks with assets between $10 billion and $50 billion. To illustrate the differences between these banks and larger banks whose business models are distinctly different, we examine large banks with assets between $50 billion and $250 billion and the largest banks with assets exceeding $250 billion. Community banks have potential advantages in relationship lending compared with large banks. However, increases in regulatory compliance and technological burdens may have disproportionately increased community banks' costs, raising concerns about small businesses' access to credit. Our evidence suggests several patterns: (1) while small community banks exhibit relatively more valuable investment opportunities, larger community banks, midsize banks, and larger banks exploit theirs more efficiently and achieve better financial performance; (2) average operating costs that include costs related to regulatory compliance and technology decrease with size; (3) unlike small community banks, large community banks have financial incentives to increase lending to small businesses; and (4) for business lending and commercial real estate lending, compared with small community banks, large community banks, midsize banks, and larger banks assume higher inherent credit risk and exhibit more efficient lending. Thus, concern that small business lending would be adversely affected if small community banks find it beneficial to increase their scale is not supported by our results. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hughes, Joseph P.; Jagtiani, Julapa; Mester, Loretta J.; Moon, Choon-Geol</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decomposing global yield curve co-movement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Byrne, Joseph P.; Cao, Shuo; Korobilis, Dimitris
This paper studies the co-movement of global yield curve dynamics using a Bayesian hierarchical factor model augmented with macroeconomic fundamentals. Our data-driven approach is able to pin down the drivers of yield curve dynamics and produce plausible term premium estimates. We reveal the relative importance of global shocks through two transmission channels: policy and risk channels. Global inflation is the most important core macro fundamental affecting international yields, operating through a policy channel. Two identified global yield factors significantly influence global yield co-movements through a risk channel. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Byrne, Joseph P.; Cao, Shuo; Korobilis, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does your neighbour know you better? The supportive role of local banks in the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barboni, Giorgia; Rossi, Carlotta
Relationship lending allows local banks to collect private information about their customers and to mitigate information asymmetries that often lead to credit rationing. In this paper, we argue that soft information collected through relationship lending favors lending decisions even when borrowers' quality is poor from a "hard-information" perspective. We compare the behaviour of local versus non-local banks using data immediately before and after the 2007-08 Financial Crisis. We exploit the heterogeneity in banks' reliance on soft information to study how their lending strategies changed when firms' hard-information indicators deteriorated after the outbreak of the financial crisis. Our paper shows that firms predominantly funded by local banks reported lower credit rationing immediately after the outbreak of the 2007-08 Financial Crisis. In the same period local banks were also less likely to terminate existing relationships with their customers, suggesting that they continued funding their clients even when borrowers' balance sheet variables worsened. We rule out alternative hypotheses explaining our results, such as demand effects, "zombie-lending" behaviour, or different impacts the financial crisis had on the credit supply of local versus local firms. This leads us to conclude that thanks to their greater reliance on soft information, local lenders supported their customers to a higher extent during bad times, at least in the period following immediately the outbreak of the financial crisis. (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Barboni, Giorgia; Rossi, Carlotta</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of forward moments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andreou, Panayiotis C.; Kagkadis, Anastasios; Philip, Dennis; Taamouti, Abderrahim
We estimate the term structures of risk-neutral forward variance and skewness, and examine their predictive power for equity market excess returns and variance. We use Partial Least Squares to extract a single predictive factor from each term structure that is motivated by the theoretical implications of affine no-arbitrage models. The empirical analysis shows that an increased forward variance factor, FVF (forward skewness factor, FSF) corresponds to a more negatively sloped forward variance (more U-shaped forward skewness) term structure, and significantly forecasts higher future market excess returns and variance. More importantly, FSF exhibits predictive power for market returns that is stronger than, and incremental to, that provided by FVF. However, it does not outperform FVF in terms of excess variance predictability. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andreou, Panayiotis C.; Kagkadis, Anastasios; Philip, Dennis; Taamouti, Abderrahim</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sentiment spillover effects for US and European companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Audrino, Francesco; Tetereva, Anastasija
The fast-growing literature on news analytics provides evidence that financial markets are partially driven by sentiments. In contrast with previous studies that have almost exclusively focused on the direct effects of the news related to single companies or sectors, we investigate the time-varying dynamics of news' cross-industry influences for a set of US and European stocks over a period of 10 years. The graphical Granger causality of the news sentiments-excess return networks is estimated by applying the adaptive lasso. We find significant spillover effects and show the importance of sentiments related to certain sectors for the whole cross-section of stocks. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Audrino, Francesco; Tetereva, Anastasija</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Characterizing the financial cycle: Evidence from a frequency domain analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Strohsal, Till; Proano, Christian R.; Wolters, Juergen
This paper introduces parametric spectrum estimation to the analysis of financial cycles. Our contribution is to formally test properties of financial cycles and to characterize their international interaction in the frequency domain. Existing work argues that the financial cycle is considerably longer in duration and larger in amplitude than the business cycle and that its distinguishing features became more pronounced over time. Also, a global cycle, being driven by US monetary policy, is said to be behind national financial cycles. We provide strong statistical evidence for the US and slightly weaker evidence for the UK validating the hypothesized features of the national financial cycle. In Germany, however, the financial cycle is much less visible. Similarly, a US-driven global financial cycle significantly affects national cycles in the UK but not in Germany. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Strohsal, Till; Proano, Christian R.; Wolters, Juergen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Practice makes progress: Evidence from divestitures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Powell, Ronan; Zhang, Emma Jincheng
This paper examines the role of firm-level experience in the context of divestitures. We find that divesting firms that have recent divestiture experience (hereafter, experienced divestors) are more likely to sell peripheral or underperforming units, and to divest during industry merger waves. Experienced divestors earn higher returns on divestiture announcement, have stronger operating performance post-divestiture, and tend to reinvest sale proceeds in expansion programs using acquisitions. Importantly, we show that divestiture experience at the firm level dominates other measures of experience, including divestiture experience of CEOs or boards, and experience in acquisitions. We take steps to mitigate concerns about econometric and sampling issues. These findings suggest that a strategy of restructuring through divestitures can improve firm value. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Powell, Ronan; Zhang, Emma Jincheng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset prices and "the devil(s) you know"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hollstein, Fabian; Nguyen, Duc Binh Benno; Prokopczuk, Marcel
In this paper, we study the asset pricing implications of persistence in the risk-neutral return distribution's central moments. We detect a both economically and statistically significant premium of stocks with low over stocks with high such persistence. Annual value-weighted excess (risk-adjusted) returns are 4.38% (3.06%). These results cannot be explained by factors and characteristics documented in the previous literature. Furthermore, it is not the persistence of only one of the individual distributional moments but rather the joint persistence in all central moments of the risk-neutral distribution that is priced. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hollstein, Fabian; Nguyen, Duc Binh Benno; Prokopczuk, Marcel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The daylight saving time anomaly in relation to firms targeted for mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siganos, Antonios
This paper finds evidence that daylight saving time changes influence the decision-making of investors when trading in firms targeted for mergers. We find that investors who face imbalances in their circadian cycle generate more positive abnormal stock returns upon the announcement of target firms. This result holds within a large number of robustness tests. Target firms also experience more pronounced stock return volatility in response to their merger announcements the first trading day after clock changes. Overall, these results seem to indicate that investors may overreact to available information when experiencing imbalances in their circadian cycle. Crown Copyright (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Siganos, Antonios</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option-Based performance participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zagst, Rudi; Kraus, Julia; Bertrand, Philippe
The purpose of this article is to introduce and analyze the option-based performance participation (OBPP) as performance participation method based on a portfolio consisting of two risky assets. By generalizing the provided guarantee to a participation in the performance of a second risky underlying, this new kind of strategies allows to cope with well-known problems associated with standard portfolio insurance methods, especially in times of low or even negative interest rates. However, the minimum guaranteed portfolio value at the end of the investment horizon is not deterministic anymore, but subject to systematic risk instead. Hence, we compare the newly introduced OBPP with the option-based portfolio insurance (OBPI) in various dimensions such as terminal payoffs, mean-variance efficiency and stochastic dominance. To do this, general analytical expressions for all moments of the payoff distributions of the two strategies are derived. Furthermore, we show how an OBBP can be designed so that it stochastically dominates a given OBPI (with a given probability) while retaining the potential for a participation in rising markets via a so-called reserve asset. Numerical case studies show how the proposed concept can be easily implemented for practical applications. (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Zagst, Rudi; Kraus, Julia; Bertrand, Philippe</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does bank efficiency influence the cost of credit?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shamshur, Anastasiya; Weill, Laurent
Using a large sample of firms from nine European countries, this study examines the relationship between bank efficiency and the cost of credit for borrowing firms. We hypothesize that bank efficiency - the ability of banks to operate at lower costs - is associated with lower loan rates and thus lower cost of credit. Combining firm-level and bank-level data, we find support for this prediction. The effect of bank efficiency on the cost of credit varies with firm and bank size. Bank efficiency reduces the cost of credit for SMEs, but does not exert a significant influence for either micro companies or large firms. Furthermore, the effect is driven by large banks, where improvements in bank efficiency tend to be strongly associated with lower cost of credit. We also find that lower bank competition facilitates the transmission of greater bank efficiency to lower cost of credit. Overall, our results indicate that measures that increase bank efficiency can foster access to credit. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shamshur, Anastasiya; Weill, Laurent</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model risk of expected shortfall</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lazar, Emese; Zhang, Ning
In this paper we propose to measure the model risk of Expected Shortfall as the optimal correction needed to pass several ES backtests, and investigate the properties of our proposed measures of model risk from a regulatory perspective. Our results show that for the DJIA index, the smallest corrections are required for the ES estimates built using GARCH models. Furthermore, the 2.5% ES requires smaller corrections for model risk than the 1% VaR, which advocates the replacement of VaR with ES as recommended by the Basel Committee. Also, if the model risk of VaR is taken into account, then the corrections made to the ES estimates reduce by 50% on average. Crown Copyright (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lazar, Emese; Zhang, Ning</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer debt non-payment and the borrowing constraint: Implications for consumer behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bechlioulis, Alexandros P.; Brissimis, Sophocles N.
This paper examines whether the consumption behavior of a borrowing-constrained household is affected by debt non-payment. From the household's intertemporal maximization problem, we derive a two-equation model consisting of augmented forms of the standard consumption Euler equation and the static labor supply equation. We estimate these equations by using nonlinear GMM and obtain estimates inter alia for the discount factor and the debt-payment-to-income ratio. The former is found to be much lower than the values often used in model calibrations in the literature, showing a high degree of impatience of households. The latter is close to the values reported in the consumer credit literature. Our results are found to be robust to a number of specification tests under different types of household preferences. These results are also subjected to a comparative analysis with the results derived from the consumption Euler equation under full debt repayment and no borrowing constraint. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bechlioulis, Alexandros P.; Brissimis, Sophocles N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Belief heterogeneity in the option markets and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borochin, Paul; Zhao, Yanhui
Standard deviations of the implied-historical volatility spread, of implied volatility innovations, and of the volatility term structure spread in equity options help explain the cross-section of one-month-ahead underlying stock returns. The explanatory power from standard deviations is robust to the levels of these three variables, volatility of volatility, firm characteristics, and common risk factor models. We find support for interpreting the standard deviations of these option-based measures as forward-looking proxies for heterogeneous beliefs. The negative relationship between our three measures and future underlying returns is consistent with the Miller (1977) overvaluation model which implies that divergence of investor opinions in the presence of short-sale constraints leads to lower expected returns. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Borochin, Paul; Zhao, Yanhui</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collectivism and the costs of high leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.; Zheng, Ying
Prior literature shows that high leverage is associated with losses in market share due to unfavorable actions by customers and competitors. Building on this literature, we investigate the effect of collectivism on the product market performance of highly leveraged firms. Using a sample of 46 countries over the 1989-2016 period, we find significantly lower costs of high leverage for countries with higher collectivism scores. Moreover, we find that the impact of collectivism on high leverage costs is more pronounced for firms with high product specialization and with financially healthy rivals. In additional analysis, we find that collectivism helps highly leveraged firms retain employees and obtain trade credit from suppliers. Our findings thus suggest that a country's culture affects corporate financial outcomes by influencing the actions of firm stakeholders. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.; Zheng, Ying</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tone at the top: CEOs' religious beliefs and earnings management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Ye; Kim, Yongtae; Li, Siqi; Pan, Carrie
Diverging from recent research that focuses on the effect of community religion on corporate outcomes, we study how top executives' personal religiosity affects corporate transparency. Using educational experience in church-affiliated colleges as a proxy for CEOs' religiosity, we show that firms with religious CEOs are associated with significantly less earnings management than firms with non-religious CEOs. Our results are robust to using matched samples and a difference-in-differences analysis based on voluntary CEO turnovers. The effect of CEO religiosity on earnings management is more pronounced when firms use more equity-based CEO compensation or when firms face higher operating cash flows volatility, and the effect is weaker in the post-SOX period. We also find evidence that firms with religious CEOs are less likely to engage in real earnings management. Taken together, our findings suggest an important role of CEOs' religious beliefs in shaping corporate policies. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cai, Ye; Kim, Yongtae; Li, Siqi; Pan, Carrie</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Household preferences for socially responsible investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rossi, Mariacristina; Sansone, Dario; van Soest, Arthur; Torricelli, Costanza
We analyze revealed and stated household preferences for socially responsible investments (SRI). Using a questionnaire specifically designed for this purpose and administered to a Dutch representative household panel, we investigate the actual and latent demand for SRI products. Respondents reported whether they owned SRI products, the reason behind this decision, but also answered stated choice questions on traditional investments and hypothetical SR products with an explicit return penalty and/or an in-kind compensation. Our results show that social investors are willing to pay a price to be socially responsible rather than needing a little nudge, such as a gift (a book or a voucher). Highly educated individuals have a substantial latent demand that is currently unexploited. Keeping education constant, individuals who consider themselves financially literate are less interested in SR products than others. Particularly at the intensive margin, the stated demand for SRI funds is sensitive to the return penalty. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rossi, Mariacristina; Sansone, Dario; van Soest, Arthur; Torricelli, Costanza</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory competition in capital standards: a 'race to the top' result</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haufler, Andreas; Maier, Ulf
Several countries have recently introduced national capital standards exceeding the internationally coordinated Basel III rules, which is inconsistent with the 'race to the bottom' in capital standards found in the literature. We study regulatory competition when banks are heterogeneous and give loans to firms that produce output in an integrated market. In this setting capital requirements change the pool quality of banks in each country and inflict negative externalities on neighboring jurisdictions by shifting risks to foreign taxpayers and by reducing total credit supply and output. Non-cooperatively set capital standards are higher than coordinated ones, and a 'race to the top' results, when governments care equally about bank profits, taxpayers, and consumers. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Haufler, Andreas; Maier, Ulf</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Founding family ownership, stock market returns, and agency problems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eugster, Nicolas; Isakov, Dusan
This paper explores the relationship between founding family ownership and stock market returns. Using the entire population of non-financial firms listed on the Swiss stock market for 2003-2013, we find that the stock returns of family firms are significantly higher than those of non-family firms after adjusting the returns for different firm characteristics and risk factors. Family firms generate an annual abnormal return of 2.8% to 7.1%. We also document that family firms potentially having more agency problems earn higher abnormal returns. Our evidence suggests that outside investors receive a premium for holding shares of these firms as they are exposed to the specific agency problems present in family firms. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eugster, Nicolas; Isakov, Dusan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did connected hedge funds benefit from bank bailouts during the financial crisis?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faff, Robert W.; Parwada, Jerry T.; Tan, Eric K. M.
We examine whether connected hedge funds (i.e. those that are prime-brokerage clients of bailout banks) benefited from bailout programs initiated in seven countries during the 2007-2009 financial crisis. We find that being connected to a bailout bank is generally beneficial for hedge funds in that it lowers the rate of fund failure. However, this benefit becomes smaller during the post bailout period, for example, due to the greater risk-taking and higher leverage of such funds subsequent to bailouts. As such, our findings provide support for the moral hazard hypothesis. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faff, Robert W.; Parwada, Jerry T.; Tan, Eric K. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Women on boards and bank earnings management: From zero to hero</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, Yaoyao; Jiang, Yuxiang; Zhang, Xuezhi; Zhou, Yue
We examine how women on boards influence bank earnings management. Using the likelihood of a board appointing women directors based on a Blau index of gender diversity in each director's total employment connections outside our sample banks for identification, we find an inverted U-shaped relation between women on boards and bank earnings management. Specifically, when there exists only a marginal number of women directors, banks are more likely to manipulate earnings. But, when the number of women directors reaches three or more, bank earnings management declines. This inverted U-shaped impact is intensified if women sit on audit or nomination committees, is moderated if women directors have higher education levels and more board experience, and is unchanged during the 2007-2009 financial crisis. Our results hold when we use alternative measures of bank earnings management, employ GMM estimations and test for alternative hypotheses for the inverted U-shaped relation. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fan, Yaoyao; Jiang, Yuxiang; Zhang, Xuezhi; Zhou, Yue</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO pricing deregulation and corporate governance: Theory and evidence from Chinese public firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Ping; Ma, Lin; Wang, Kun; Xiao, Xing
The disciplinary role of the financial market could interact with a firm's choice of internal corporate governance. We prove that when the efficiency of the initial public offering (IPO) pricing improves, entrepreneurs choose stronger corporate governance structures as way of committing to extract fewer private benefits in exchange for higher prices. Using a difference-in-difference method that exploits the asymmetric impacts of the IPO pricing deregulation on the Chinese mainland and Hong Kong markets, we find that improving the efficiency of IPO pricing has a positive impact on a firm's corporate governance quality. This impact is more pronounced for firms with lower tangibility, for firms with higher market-to-book ratios, and for state-owned enterprises. Our findings demonstrate that the development of the financial market can promote economic development through improving corporate governance. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Ping; Ma, Lin; Wang, Kun; Xiao, Xing</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial market development and firm investment in tax avoidance: Evidence from credit default swap market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Hyun A.; Lobo, Gerald J.; Ryou, Ji Woo
Lenders reduce their monitoring efforts after hedging their credit risk exposure through credit default swap (CDS) contracts, which are akin to insurance against borrowers' adverse credit events. In this study, we examine whether, upon observing the reduced lender monitoring following CDS trading, shareholders demand that borrowing firms invest in more aggressive tax planning strategies, which were previously constrained by risk-averse lenders. Using a difference-in-differences design that exploits the variation in timing of the inception of CDS trading, we document that borrowers exhibit greater tax avoidance after the inception of CDS trading. Consistent with shareholders stepping up their demands post-CDS, we find that the increase in tax avoidance is stronger for (i) firms with more powerful and influential shareholders, as measured by dedicated institutional investors, (ii) firms with stronger shareholder defenders, as measured by board independence and board size, and (iii) firms with more strategic default options. We also find that borrowers with higher levels of tax avoidance are less likely to file for bankruptcy in the future. Our findings are robust to a battery of sensitivity checks, including controlling for cost of debt and endogeneity, as well as using alternative measures of tax avoidance. (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hong, Hyun A.; Lobo, Gerald J.; Ryou, Ji Woo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An equilibrium model of risk management spillover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Shiyang; Jiang, Ying; Qiu, Zhigang; Ye, Zhiqiang
This paper investigates the effects of relative performance concerns on fund managers' behavior when managers are heterogeneous in their risk management practices. We find that relative performance concerns have distinct effects on different managers as follows: managers without risk management constraints conduct risk management, while those with risk management constraints do not change their trading. Our results suggest that a small number of fund managers with risk management requirements can have a significant impact on the market. Our theory can potentially reconcile the long-lasting debate regarding the impact of risk management on financial markets. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Shiyang; Jiang, Ying; Qiu, Zhigang; Ye, Zhiqiang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The decline in idiosyncratic values of US Treasury securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Livingston, Miles; Wu, Yanbin; Zhou, Lei
Unique features and market frictions can lead to idiosyncratic pricing for some US Treasury securities. This study uses a linear programming (LP) model to measure aggregate idiosyncratic pricing of T-notes and T-bonds from 1980 to 2016. We document an average idiosyncratic pricing of $0.11 per $100 par, as compared to an average bid-ask spread of $0.08. Further, idiosyncratic pricing declined dramatically from the early 1980s to the 2010s. Empirical evidence suggests that the 1986 Tax Reform Act, increasing issue sizes and improving market liquidity contribute to the decline. At the individual security level, we identify factors contributing to and mitigating idiosyncratic pricing. (C) 2019 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Livingston, Miles; Wu, Yanbin; Zhou, Lei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial sector debt bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luca, Oana; Tieman, Alexander F.
Most tax systems create a tax bias toward debt finance. Such debt bias increases firm leverage and may negatively affect financial stability. This paper presents novel evidence on debt bias in the "non-traditional" financial sector-i.e., investment banks and non-bank financial intermediaries such as finance and insurance companies. It also shows how debt bias in the financial sector has been affected by the global financial crisis. The paper finds debt bias to be pervasive, explaining as much as 10 percentage points of bank leverage. These effects are more pronounced before than after the global financial crisis, explained by the post-crisis focus on rebuilding buffers. Going forward, as buffers have largely been rebuilt, debt bias is once again gaining prominence as a key driver of leverage decisions of financial firms, underscoring the importance of policy reform at this juncture. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Luca, Oana; Tieman, Alexander F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Maturity mismatch and incentives: Evidence from bank issued wealth management products in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luo, Ronghua; Fang, Hongyan; Liu, Jinjin; Zhao, Senyang
Commercial banks in China issued a multitude of wealth management products (WMPs) from 2009 to 2016. These products are largely short-term, but a significant proportion of capital is allocated to long-term investments. In this paper, we first construct a measure of WMP maturity mismatch for each bank in each quarter using R(2)s from regressing expected yields of WMPs on expected yields of banks' generally claimed investment assets. The degree of maturity mismatch is positively related to banks' quarter-end non-performing loan ratio (NPLR), after accounting for time-varying bank characteristics, bank and time fixed effects. The result indicates that severer mismatch is associated with reduced NPLR. Cross-sectionally, the positive relation is stronger in big banks and when banks had a larger NPLR in the previous quarter. The results highlight the fact that regulated commercial banks use financial innovation and exploit maturity mismatch in their issued WMPs to evade regulator's credit risk monitoring. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Luo, Ronghua; Fang, Hongyan; Liu, Jinjin; Zhao, Senyang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank margins and profits in a world of negative rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Molyneux, Philip; Reghezza, Alessio; Xie, Ru
By investigating the influence of negative interest rate policy (NIRP) on bank margins and profitability, this paper identifies country- and bank- specific characteristics that amplify or weaken the effect of NIRP on bank performance. Using a dataset comprising 7,359 banks from 33 OECD member countries over 2012-16 and a difference-in-differences methodology, we find that bank margins and profits fell in NIRP-adopter countries compared to countries that did not adopt the policy. Moreover, this adverse NIRP effect depends on bank specific-characteristics such as size, funding structure, business models, assets repricing and product - line specialization. The effectiveness of the pass-through mechanism of NIRP can also be affected by the characteristics of a country's banking system, namely, the level of competition and the prevalence of fixed/floating lending rates. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Molyneux, Philip; Reghezza, Alessio; Xie, Ru</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Elite law firms in the IPO market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moran, Pablo; Pandes, J. Ari
IPOs with underwriters that retain an elite law firm exhibit a lower average first-day return. This empirical pattern remains after controlling for an extensive set of proxies associated with existing explanations of IPO initial returns. We rationalize this finding with a pre-IPO pricing model, in which underwriters convey their lack of conflicts of interest to the issuer by engaging an elite law firm. Consistent with this selection channel and our model's predictions, we find a lower incidence of elite law firm involvement and a larger difference in average first-day return associated with elite law firms during the dot-com period. We document similar findings with respect to the dispersion of IPO first-day returns and a pattern in the issuers' re-hiring decision of investment banks consistent with our theory. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moran, Pablo; Pandes, J. Ari</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives and culture in risk compliance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sheedy, Elizabeth; Zhang, Le; Tam, Kenny Chi Ho
In the finance industry, risk compliance has become an important issue after numerous policy violations resulting in significant costs for financial institutions and society as a whole. We run a lab-in-the-field experiment with 269 finance professionals, to investigate the effects of financial incentives and workplace culture on risk compliance. Relative to variable remuneration (linked to expected profits), fixed remuneration increases the proportion of people complying by as much as 25.1 percentage points. This is achieved with no diminution in productivity. Relative to a profit-focused workplace culture, a risk-focused workplace culture increases the proportion of people complying by 16.3 percentage points. (C) 2019 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Sheedy, Elizabeth; Zhang, Le; Tam, Kenny Chi Ho</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comparison of community bank failures and FDIC losses in the 1986-92 and 2007-13 banking crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balla, Eliana; Mazur, Laurel C.; Prescott, Edward Simpson; Walter, John R.
Failures and FDIC losses for community banks during the banking crises of the late 1980s and late 2000s are compared. Despite increases in risky commercial real estate (CRE) lending and more severe economic shocks in the recent crisis, failure rates were lower. We find that other changes in bank characteristics, like higher capital, made community banks more resilient to shocks. In contrast, FDIC losses on failed banks were higher. These are not explained by changes in CRE exposure or economic shocks. We find that an interest-receivable variable is predictive of failures and FDIC losses. Implications for prompt corrective action are discussed. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balla, Eliana; Mazur, Laurel C.; Prescott, Edward Simpson; Walter, John R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>To stay or go? Consumer bank switching behaviour after government interventions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diepstraten, Maaike; van der Cruijsen, Carin
We analyse whether and how individual savings and current account holders respond to government interventions, due to the financial crisis, at banks. We employ a difference-in-difference analysis and distinguish between a nationalisation and a capital injection. We show that current account holders of the nationalised bank are more likely to switch away shortly after the bail-out. Second, we find heterogeneity in consumer responses to government interventions, depending on the type of intervention and banking product. Consumers who trust the government are less likely to switch their current account from a nationalised bank. Furthermore, risk averse current account holders at a bank that received a capital injection are more likely to switch, which suggests the presence of a wake-up call effect. Finally, we report that financial literate current account holders are more likely to switch away after a nationalisation, and financial literate savings account holders are more likely to switch away from the recapitalised bank. The latter finding also indicates that risk awareness increased. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Diepstraten, Maaike; van der Cruijsen, Carin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Federal reserve private information and the stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lakdawala, Aeimit; Schaffer, Matthew
We study the response of stock prices to monetary policy, distinguishing effects of exogenous shocks from "Delphic" shocks that reveal the Federal Reserve's macroeconomic forecasts. To decompose monetary policy surprises into these separate components we construct a measure of Federal Reserve private information that exploits differences in central bank and market forecasts. Contractionary policy shocks of either type lower stock prices with exogenous shocks having a larger negative effect. There is some suggestive evidence of an asymmetry; when FOMC meetings are unscheduled or when the fed funds rate reverses direction, stock prices rise in response to a contractionary Delphic shock. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lakdawala, Aeimit; Schaffer, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price discrimination against retail Investors: Evidence from mini options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Yubin; Zhao, Chen; Zhong, Zhaodong
This paper studies the rise and fall of "Mini" options that are especially catered to retail investors for popular but high-priced securities. Using transaction-level data, we find that transaction costs of Mini options are much higher than those of standard options and the difference cannot be fully explained by cost-related determinants. Furthermore, we find evidence of price discrimination against retail investors from analyses of price elasticities of option traders, an event-study of changes in bid-ask spreads around earnings announcements, and comparisons of trade prices paid by Mini and standard option traders for the same security at approximately the same time. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Yubin; Zhao, Chen; Zhong, Zhaodong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A concave security market line</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Giorgi, Enrico G.; Post, Thierry; Yalcin, Atakan
We provide theoretical and empirical arguments in favor of a diminishing marginal premium for market risk. In capital market equilibrium with binding portfolio restrictions, investors with different risk aversion levels generally hold different sets of risky securities. Whereas the traditional linear relation breaks down, equilibrium can be described or approximated by a concave relation between expected return and market beta, and a concave relationship between market alpha and market beta. An empirical analysis of U.S. stock market data confirms the existence of a significant concave cross-sectional relation between average return and estimated market beta. We estimate that the market risk premium is at least four to six percent per annum, substantially above traditional estimates. A practical implication for active portfolio managers is that the alpha of "betting against beta" strategies seems dominated by the medium-minushigh-beta spread rather than the low-minus-medium-beta spread. The success of such strategies thus largely depends on underweighting or short selling high-beta stocks. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Giorgi, Enrico G.; Post, Thierry; Yalcin, Atakan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local versus non-local effects of Chinese media and post-earnings announcement drift</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Jeong-Bon; Li, Liuchuang; Yu, Zhongbo; Zhang, Hao
Taking advantage of the institutional difference in capture between local and non-local media in China, we examined the association between media capture and post-earnings announcement drift (PEAD). Using both portfolio and regression analyses, we found that, for the same firms, non-local media coverage is negatively associated with PEAD; however, there is no association between local media coverage and PEAD, except for non-state-owned firms. Given that in China, non-local media are less captured or more independent than local media, the negative association observed for non-local media coverage can be interpreted as an indication that media independence plays a role in reducing PEAD or improving informational efficiency in the stock market. (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kim, Jeong-Bon; Li, Liuchuang; Yu, Zhongbo; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining CDS prices with Merton's model before and after the Lehman default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gemmill, Gordon; Marra, Miriam
We examine whether CDS prices around the Credit Crisis can be explained with Merton's model. First we invert the model with market prices to reveal skewed volatility smiles over the whole 2005-2012 period. Then we calibrate the model to pre-Crisis data in two novel ways that allow for skewness, one based on equity-index options (MEIV) and the other on the sensitivity of CDS prices to equity volatility (MSKEW). In out-of-sample forecasts both calibrations match the in-Crisis peak of prices, but the second is better at capturing the systematic component of prices thereafter. Average CDS prices remain at twice their pre-Crisis level long after that event; the MSKEW calibration demonstrates that this is due to extra idiosyncratic risks, which are important for some firms but have negligible impact on others. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gemmill, Gordon; Marra, Miriam</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supervisory enforcement actions and bank deposits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos D.; Staikouras, Panagiotis K.; Tsoumas, Chris
We assess the effect of formal enforcement actions against banks for safety and soundness reasons on punished banks' deposits, and then examine whether this effect is caused by demand-side or supply-side forces. To this end, we use hand-collected data on enforcement actions, and bank-quarter data on deposits and other bank characteristics from 2000 through 2014. Our results show that total deposits at punished banks decrease by 8.5% in the post-enforcement year, with uninsured deposits declining by 14.5% and insured deposits falling by 7.4%. We also find that the deposit decline is predominantly caused by demand-side forces, that is, by punished banks' decision to curtail the asset side of their balance sheet. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Delis, Manthos D.; Staikouras, Panagiotis K.; Tsoumas, Chris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday liquidity facilities, late settlement fee and coordination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nellen, Thomas
This paper analyses the intraday liquidity management game played in large-value payment systems accounting for a variable and a fixed cost of liquidity. While the liquidity cost is a decisive factor for settlement behaviour, the availability of intraday liquidity until end-of-day matters too, as it mutes late settlement incentives originating from settlement risk. Whether liquidity is provided via overdraft or intraday credit hardly matters. A late settlement fee can both disincentivise settlement coordination or implement early settlement. Its calibration is usually non-trivial with the major exception of a fixed cost and end-of-day availability of intraday liquidity. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nellen, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry and credit rating: A quasi-natural experiment from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Xiaolu; Huang, Haozhi; Pan, Zheyao; Shi, Jing
We examine how the issuer paid incumbent credit rating agencies (CRAs) in China adjust their rating strategies in response to the 2010 entry of an independent credit rating agency, China Bond Rating (CBR) between 2006 and 2015. The business model that CBR employs is a combination of the public utility model and the investor-paid model. We find that the CBR's ratings coverage effectively reduced the information asymmetry in the Chinese corporate bond market. The evidence shows decreased ratings inflation and increased informativeness of rating change announcements by incumbent issuer-paid CRAs after CBR entered the market. The findings suggest that a firm's credibility is an important channel driving issuerpaid incumbent CRAs' strategic ratings. Our paper provides new information and insight into the debate of whether CRAs with alternative business models can alleviate the information asymmetry problem. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hu, Xiaolu; Huang, Haozhi; Pan, Zheyao; Shi, Jing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A new approach to optimal capital allocation for RORAC maximization in banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Woo-Young; Poshakwale, Sunil
We introduce a new model for optimal internal capital allocation, which would allow banks to maximize their Return on Risk-Adjusted Capital (RORAC) under regulatory and capital constraints. We extend the single period model of Buch et al., (2011) to a multi-period model and improve its forecasting accuracy by including the debt effect and Bayesian learning innovations. The empirical application shows that our model significantly improves the RORAC of a sample of banks listed in the S&amp;P 500 index. Crown Copyright (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kang, Woo-Young; Poshakwale, Sunil</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of interest rate ceilings on households' credit access: Evidence from a 2013 Chilean legislation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madeira, Carlos
This study analyzes the impact of a legislation introduced in Chile in 2013, which gradually reduced the maximum legal interest rate for consumer loans from 54% to 36%. Using a representative sample of households that matches survey data and banking loan records, I compare consumers with risk-adjusted interest rates slightly above and slightly below the legal interest rate ceiling, two groups of similar characteristics but who are differently affected by the law. After accounting for both macroeconomic shocks and unobserved household heterogeneity, the results show that being above the interest rate cap reduces the probability of credit access by 8.7% on average. A counterfactual exercise shows that the new legislation excluded 9.7% of the borrowers from banking consumer loans. The law's impact was strongest on the youngest, least educated and poorest families. Finally, I show that the new law affected all lenders of consumer loans in Chile, not just banks. (C) 2019 The Author. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Madeira, Carlos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio pumping and fund performance ranking: A performance-based compensation contract perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xiangwen; Wu, Wenfeng
We collect compensation policy data from 60 Chinese mutual fund companies, which cover 88% of the assets managed by all active stock and stock-oriented hybrid mutual funds in China. Using the collected data, we investigate portfolio pumping from a performance-based perspective. We find that portfolio pumping is stronger for funds ranking around critical points of performance distribution (i.e., the top one-tenth, one-fourth, one third, and half cutoffs). This finding is mainly driven by funds from companies that set these critical points to grade fund managers' bonus levels. Our findings provide evidence of portfolio pumping motivated by performance ranking instead of the flow-performance relationship documented in prior studies. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Xiangwen; Wu, Wenfeng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of intraday dynamics and collateral selection in centrally cleared and bilateral repos</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dufour, Alfonso; Marra, Miriam; Sangiorgi, Ivan
Using a novel dataset, we study intraday trades of overnight general collateral repurchase agreements (repos) on Italian government bonds. We focus both on repos cleared by central counterparties (CCPs) and traded bilaterally. Intraday bond supply, liquidity and duration significantly affect the spread of repo rates over the European Central Bank (ECB) deposit rate, but after the ECB quantitative easing interventions this impact is much reduced. During the European sovereign debt crisis, the increase in margins further deteriorates repo costs, creating a negative procyclical effect. Once we control for the impact of margin costs, CCP-based repos do not appear to be significantly cheaper than bilateral repos. We also show that bonds with lower liquidity and specialness, greater supply and longer duration are more likely to be selected as collateral. However, during the crisis, CCP-repo borrowers choose collateral bonds with higher liquidity and lower duration to reduce margin and repo trading costs. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dufour, Alfonso; Marra, Miriam; Sangiorgi, Ivan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A generic framework for monetary performance attribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blomvall, Jorgen; Hagenbjork, Johan
We propose a generic framework for performance attribution in monetary terms. Through a second-order Taylor approximation, the changes in portfolio value are attributed to a set of systematic risk factors. By considering two error terms arising from the Taylor approximation, combined with an exact definition of the carry term, we derive a residual-free performance attribution framework, where we exert control over the size of the error terms. The framework incorporates foreign exchange rates and transaction costs, which is illustrated by simulating a European investor acting on the U.S. fixed income market. For the out-of-sample period, we show that we can attribute almost all portfolio value differences and variance using six risk factors obtained from principal component analysis. The results show that our method, in combination with high-quality estimates of risk factors, outperforms other fixed-income attribution models from the literature. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blomvall, Jorgen; Hagenbjork, Johan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Marginal cost of risk-based capital and risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Tao; Goh, Jing Rong; Kamiya, Shinichi; Lou, Pingyi
We explore the impact of capital adequacy requirements on financial institutions' risk-taking behavior from a novel perspective. Specifically, we show that an important feature of the risk-based capital (RBC) system a built-in diversification benefit in aggregating risk categories induces moral hazard. We find that insurers that face lower marginal RBC costs of fixed-income (FI) investment tend to purchase riskier Fl securities. This relationship holds even when lower marginal RBC costs result from increased risk in other risk categories, which is an unintended consequence of the RBC's square root rule. Using Hurricanes Katrina and Sandy as exogenous shocks to the RBC cost, we find that insurers that suffered more in the two disasters undertook more risk in their Fl investments and witnessed an increase in their overall risk. We further show that insurers with a high RBC cost sell similar risky bonds during the financial crisis, presenting a source of systemic risk. These results provide an important regulatory implication for minimum capital calculation in capital regulation regimes. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Tao; Goh, Jing Rong; Kamiya, Shinichi; Lou, Pingyi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bulk volume classification and information detection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Panayides, Marios A.; Shohfi, Thomas D.; Smith, Jared D.
Using European stock data from two different venues and time periods for which we can identify each trade's aggressor, we test the performance of the bulk volume classification (Easley et al. (2016): BVC) algorithm. BVC is data efficient, but may identify trade aggressors less accurately than "bulk" versions of traditional trade-level algorithms. BVC-estimated trade flow is the only algorithm related to proxies of informed trading, however. This is because traditional algorithms are designed to find individual trade aggressors, but we find that trade aggressor no longer captures information. Finally, we find that after calibrating BVC to trading characteristics in out-of-sample data, it is better able to detect information and to identify trade aggressors. In the new era of fast trading, sophisticated investors, and smart order execution, BVC appears to be the most versatile algorithm. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Panayides, Marios A.; Shohfi, Thomas D.; Smith, Jared D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Grabit: Gradient tree-boosted Tobit models for default prediction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sigrist, Fabio; Hirnschall, Christoph
A frequent problem in binary classification is class imbalance between a minority and a majority class such as defaults and non-defaults in default prediction. In this article, we introduce a novel binary classification model, the Grabit model, which is obtained by applying gradient tree boosting to the Tobit model. We show how this model can leverage auxiliary data to obtain increased predictive accuracy for imbalanced data. We apply the Grabit model to predicting defaults on loans made to Swiss small and medium-sized enterprises (SME) and obtain a large and significant improvement in predictive performance compared to other state-of-the-art approaches. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sigrist, Fabio; Hirnschall, Christoph</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A BIT of investor protection: How Bilateral Investment Treaties impact the terms of syndicated loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fotak, Veljko; Lee, Haekwon; Megginson, William
We study the impact of government expropriation risk on the terms of cross-border syndicated loans. By comparing loans by foreign lenders from countries covered by Bilateral Investment Treaties (BITs) to loans from non-covered countries, we isolate and quantify the impact of strengthening property rights against government expropriation on loans. We find that stronger property rights lead to a lower cost of debt, larger loans, larger syndicates, less collateral, and fewer covenants. Results are stronger in countries with a history of government expropriations and robust to methodologies accounting for the endogenous nature of BITs and for the simultaneous determination of loan terms. Our findings persist after the inclusion of other metrics of institutional quality, such as legal origin identifiers and an index of creditor rights. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Fotak, Veljko; Lee, Haekwon; Megginson, William</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accounts payable and firm value: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nam, Hocheol; Uchida, Konari
We conduct a difference-in-differences (DID) analysis that uses the global financial crisis (GFC) in 2008 as an exogenous shock to examine the value effects of accounts payable. Analyses of 136,783 firm-year observations (21,765 companies) from 40 countries show that accounts payable significantly absorbed the reduction of Tobin's Q during the GFC. The value effect is pronounced for civil law, long-term-oriented, and high-uncertainty-avoidance countries, in which long-term relations are likely beneficial. These results are obtained after controlling for other country- and firm-level characteristics as well as with alternative definitions of the global financial crisis and accounts payable. We also find that trade credit in those countries prevents a significant reduction in inventory investments during the GFC. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nam, Hocheol; Uchida, Konari</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected shortfall and portfolio management in contagious markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buccioli, Alice; Kokholm, Thomas; Nicolosi, Marco
We study the impact of market contagion on portfolio management. To model possible recurrence in the arrival of extreme events, we equip classic Poisson jumps with long memory via past-weighted randomization of the likelihood of their occurrences (Hawkes processes). Within this framework, we tackle the problem of optimal portfolio selection in terms of Expected Shortfall (ES). We use the generalized method of moments to estimate the model on three US stock indexes, representing three major sectors of the US economy. The moment conditions of the model are computed efficiently in closed form applying a novel technique. Given parameter estimates we maximize (at a monthly frequency in the period 2001-2016) the expected return subject to a constraint on the ES of a portfolio consisting of the three US sector indexes. We find that the weights of the optimal portfolio are significantly adjusted when the level of contagion is high. Finally, we perform an extensive out-of-sample back-test of the model's ability to measure ES and find that the Hawkes jump-diffusion model outperforms two traditional models that are commonly implemented. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buccioli, Alice; Kokholm, Thomas; Nicolosi, Marco</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of TARP on loan loss provisions and bank transparency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Jinyong; Kim, Mingook; Lee, Jeong Hwan
We empirically investigate the effect of the Capital Purchase Program under the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) on the transparency of participating banks by examining changes in their loan loss provisions. We demonstrate that TARP banks reduced transparency to a greater extent than non-TARP banks did by recognizing smaller and less timely loan loss provisions for changes in nonperforming loans and increasing discretionary loan loss provisions more after receiving TARP funds. While the reduced timeliness was mainly observed in large TARP banks and banks with low tier 1 capital or high earnings, small TARP banks and banks with low earnings significantly increased their discretionary provisions. In addition, the decreased timeliness and increased discretionary provisions were mainly driven by TARP banks that did not repay their funds. TARP banks' reduced transparency, which inhibits the accurate assessment of bank risk by outsiders, is consistent with moral hazard in disclosing their financial reporting information. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Jinyong; Kim, Mingook; Lee, Jeong Hwan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing and extreme event risk: Common factors in ILS fund returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Braun, Alexander; Ben Ammar, Semir; Eling, Martin
Investment managers specializing in insurance-linked securities (ILS) generate returns that behave unlike those of any other asset class. We introduce four ILS-specific factor models, which explain their time series and cross-sectional variation. Despite a strong fit, we are left with positive-significant alphas for about one quarter of the funds in our sample, some of which can be attributed to industry loss warranty (ILW) exposures. In addition, they are related to fund size, age, and performance fees. Although we do not find evidence for market timing abilities, we can rule out luck as a cause of outperformance by controlling for false discoveries. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Braun, Alexander; Ben Ammar, Semir; Eling, Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oil price increases and the predictability of equity premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Yudong; Pan, Zhiyuan; Liu, Li; Wu, Chongfeng
We show that increases in oil prices, rather than changes in oil prices, can predict stock returns. The revealed stock return predictability is both statistically and economically significant. The forecasting performance of oil price increases is not affected by changes in the choice of subsample, a considerable advantage over other popular predictors. We obtain greater forecasting gains by adding oil price increases as an additional predictor to univariate macro models. This forecasting improvement is also present when using multivariate information methods. The success of oil-macro models in forecasting stock returns is robust to a large battery of robustness tests. Oil price increases predict stock returns by affecting future industrial production and discount rates. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Yudong; Pan, Zhiyuan; Liu, Li; Wu, Chongfeng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does financial development alter the impact of uncertainty?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karaman, K. Kivanc; Yildirim-Karaman, Secil
How does the impact of uncertainty on output vary with financial development levels? We investigate this question empirically, using a quarterly panel data set of 50 countries between 1971 and 2009 and an Instrumental Variables model. The results support the conjecture that financial development mitigates the negative impact of uncertainty on output. At the lower end of the distribution of the financial development levels, one standard deviation increase in uncertainty decreases output by more than two standard deviations. At the higher end of financial development, the impact on output is statistically insignificant. These results suggest that strengthening the financial system and increasing liquidity and credit availability improce the robustness of growth performance during periods of uncertainty. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Karaman, K. Kivanc; Yildirim-Karaman, Secil</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Environmental performance and the cost of debt: Evidence from commercial mortgages and REIT bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eichholtz, Piet; Holtermans, Rogier; Kok, Nils; Yonder, Erkan
The increasing societal focus on environmental issues leads to important questions about the relationship between corporate environmental (ESG) performance and firms' cost of capital, but research on this topic remains scant. The real estate sector offers an ideal testing ground to investigate the relationship in two distinct manners, while specifically addressing concerns about endogeneity. We first investigate the spreads on commercial mortgages collateralized by real assets, some of which are environmentally certified. We then study spreads on corporate debt of property companies (REITs), both at issuance and while trading in the secondary market. The results show that loans on environmentally certified buildings command lower spreads than conventional, but otherwise comparable buildings, varying between 24 and 29 basis points, depending on the specification. At the corporate level, REITs with a higher fraction of environmentally certified buildings have lower bond spreads in the secondary market. These results are robust to different estimation strategies, and signal that environmental risk is efficiently priced in the real estate debt market. Crown Copyright (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eichholtz, Piet; Holtermans, Rogier; Kok, Nils; Yonder, Erkan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>De-Leverage and illiquidity contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Conghui; Liu, Yu-Jane; Zhu, Ning
This paper investigates how variations in stock-level leverage lead to dynamic intraday trading behavior and illiquidity transmission across different stocks by utilizing a unique, precise, stock-level margin trading dataset. We document that leveraged investors' need to meet margin call requirements and liquidity demands due to prior market drops results in subsequent selloffs in otherwise stable stocks, particularly in trading sessions in which there is little new information. This effect exists both within and across different industries and is stronger for stocks with less information asymmetry, better liquidity, higher past stock performance, and even during trading suspension. We also find strong evidence on the volatility spillover induced by leverage. Taken together, such findings suggest that our results are driven by illiquidity contagion instead of information spillover. Our study contributes to the research on asset fire sales, margin trading, and funding liquidity during the intraday deleveraging process in financial market turmoil. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hu, Conghui; Liu, Yu-Jane; Zhu, Ning</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth in the shadow of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Jamus Jerome
This paper revisits the relationship between debt and growth from a vantage point that considers the totality of private and public debt. We exploit quarter-long timing lags inherent in the response of borrowing to innovations in output to identify the effects of debt on growth in a panel vector autoregressive model. We verify that debt accumulation is negatively related to output growth, with a one standard deviation innovation in the former leading to a 0.2 percentage-point contraction in the latter. This result is robust to the inclusion of exogenous variables in the system, alternative measures of the endogenous variables, and varying temporal treatments. We also find variations depending on the type of debt accumulated, the specific subset of countries considered, and the channels along which debt expansion operates. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lim, Jamus Jerome</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor horizons, long-term blockholders, and corporate social responsibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glossner, Simon
This paper investigates whether or not shareholders benefit from corporate social responsibility (CSR) by studying the effect of institutional investors on CSR. After all, arguing against CSR is hard when investors push for it. I find that longer investor horizons lead to significantly more CSR. This positive effect, however, is moderated by long-term investors who hold large ownership blocks. Long-term blockholders ensure, through monitoring, that managers do not blindly increase CSR, but rather that managers pursue a CSR strategy that reduces the risk of costly incidents. A battery of robustness tests indicates causality. Overall, these findings indicate that CSR is in the interests of long-term investors if CSR prevents incidents. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Glossner, Simon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Least impulse response estimator for stress test exercises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gourieroux, Christian; Lu, Yang
We introduce new semi-parametric models for the analysis of rates and proportions, such as proportions of default, (expected) loss-given-default and credit conversion factor encountered in credit risk analysis. These models are especially convenient for the stress test exercises demanded in the current prudential regulation. We show that the Least Impulse Response Estimator, which minimizes the estimated effect of a stress, leads to consistent parameter estimates. The new models with their associated estimation method are compared with the other approaches currently proposed in the literature such as the beta and logistic regressions. The approach is illustrated by both simulation experiments and the case study of a retail P2P lending portfolio. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gourieroux, Christian; Lu, Yang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does interest rate exposure explain the low-volatility anomaly?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Driessen, Joost; Kuiper, Ivo; Nazliben, Korhan; Beilo, Robbert
We show that part of the outperformance of low-volatility stocks can be explained by a premium for interest rate exposure. Low-volatility stock portfolios have negative exposure to interest rates, whereas the more volatile stocks have positive exposure. Incorporating an interest rate premium explains part of the anomaly. We also find that the interest rate risk premium in equity markets exhibits time variation similar to bond markets, but that the level of the interest rate premium, as estimated from the cross-section of stocks, is much higher than the premium observed in the bond market. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Driessen, Joost; Kuiper, Ivo; Nazliben, Korhan; Beilo, Robbert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan portfolio diversification, market structure and bank stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shim, Jeungbo
This paper examines whether the choice of bank loan diversification and market concentration are associated with a bank's financial stability. This study also investigates how the effect of loan diversification on bank stability varies depending on the level of the concentration or the competitiveness of the banking market. We find that increased loan diversification has a positive impact on the bank's financial strength. We show that market concentration is negatively associated with bank insolvency risk, consistent with the "concentration-stability" view. The results using interaction terms between loan portfolio diversification and market concentration indicate that diversifying banks operating in highly concentrated markets are more financially stable compared to those in less concentrated markets. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shim, Jeungbo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring indirect contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cont, Rama; Schaanning, Eric
We propose two indicators for quantifying the potential exposure of financial institutions to indirect contagion arising from deleveraging of assets in stress scenarios. The first indicator, the Endogenous Risk Index (ERI) captures spillovers across portfolios arising from deleveraging in stress scenarios. The second indicator, the Indirect Contagion Index (ICI) measures the systemic importance of a bank by quantifying the loss its distressed liquidation would inflict on other institutions. Both are computable from portfolio holdings of financial institutions and measures of market depth for the assets held in the portfolio. We discuss the micro-foundation of these indicators and apply them to the analysis of the vulnerability of the European banking system to indirect contagion. Using data on portfolio holdings of European banks, we show that our indicators correlate to the magnitude of fire-sales losses in simulated stress scenarios, thus providing a simple to compute proxy for the outcome of stress tests. We also show that the information provided by our indicators on the systemic importance of banks is different from indicators based on size, thereby providing a measure of interconnectedness complementary to those currently used by supervisors. (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cont, Rama; Schaanning, Eric</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking reform and industry structure: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ye, Jingjing; Zhang, Aoyang; Dong, Yan
The development of a country's financial sector plays an important role in shaping its industrial structure; however, evidence on the micro level channels through which this relationship appears remains relatively sparse, particularly for developing countries. We examine the banking sector's role in the industrial structure in China by exploiting a quasi-experimental shock from a banking sector reform in 2002 that entailed stricter capital and asset requirements. Based on longitudinal data on manufacturing firms and registered banks from 1998 to 2008, we find that banking reform reduced concentrations in the product market by encouraging the growth of smaller and younger firms. These effects were most pronounced in regions with lower levels of financial development prior to the reform. Our results are robust after considering alternative model specifications and measures of dependence on external financing. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ye, Jingjing; Zhang, Aoyang; Dong, Yan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of culture on CEO power: Evidence from executive turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Urban, Daniel
In this paper, I show that CEO power, which arises from differences in national culture, can weaken a firm's governance. Based on a hand-collected dataset with more than 5000 forced and voluntary CEO transitions across 37 countries, I find that CEOs are less likely to be dismissed for bad performance in more hierarchical countries. The results are robust to alternative measures of hierarchy, a large battery of control variables, subsample analysis, placebo tests, and different empirical methodologies. Stronger hierarchies also allow for idiosyncratic managerial styles around exogenous turnover events of CEOs. Overall, the results suggest that the power and importance of CEOs vary across countries. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Urban, Daniel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gross profitability and mutual fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kenchington, David; Wan, Chi; Yuksel, H. Zafer
We find that mutual funds holding a larger concentration of high gross profitability stocks generate better future performance. The outperformance of these funds is not driven by a profitability-related risk premium and is not a byproduct of fund managers' exploitation of other well-known investment strategies. We show that fund managers who trade on the gross profitability anomaly possess greater skill and create value by attracting future fund inflows and by growing fund assets under management. We contribute to both the mutual fund and market anomaly literatures by providing strong evidence that a sizable subset of mutual fund managers profit from an important market anomaly. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kenchington, David; Wan, Chi; Yuksel, H. Zafer</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demand curves for stocks do not slope down: Evidence using an exogenous supply shock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jain, Ankit; Tantri, Prasanna; Thirumalai, Ramabhadran S.
We analyze the price impact of an exogenous share sale of inside blockholders who were forced to sell a part of their shareholdings following a regulatory change in India. The affected firms experience a negative excess return of 4.3% during the issue week. Crucially, the price impact reverses within around 16 days of the event. Our results are consistent with the view that long-term demand curves for stocks are Flat; this view is echoed in classical finance theories. The short-term price reaction to a sale is probably due to temporary price pressure. (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jain, Ankit; Tantri, Prasanna; Thirumalai, Ramabhadran S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure and financial flexibility: Expectations of future shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrinoudakis, Costas; Skiadopoulos, George; Gkionis, Konstantinos
We test one of the main predictions of the financial flexibility paradigm, that expectations about future firm-specific investment shocks affect the firm's leverage. We extract the expectations of small and large future shocks from the market prices of equity options. We find that leverage decreases when expectations for any one of the two types of future shocks increase and the relation is statistically significant even when we control for standard determinants of leverage and the firm's probability of default. Expectations for future shocks explain a greater fraction of leverage variation than most standard determinants of leverage do and they affect more the small and financially constrained firms. Our results are not subject to an endogeneity bias and they confirm DeAngelo et al. (2011) model's predictions and the evidence that managers seek for financial flexibility. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lambrinoudakis, Costas; Skiadopoulos, George; Gkionis, Konstantinos</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comprehensive appraisal of style-integration methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandez-Perez, Adrian; Fuertes, Ana-Maria; Miffre, Joelle
The paper provides a comprehensive appraisal of style-integration methods in equity index, fixed income, currency, and commodity futures markets. We confront the naive equal-weight integration (EWI) method with a host of 'sophisticated' style-integrations that derive the style exposures using past data according to utility maximization, style rotation, volatility timing, cross-sectional pricing, style momentum or principal components criteria. The analysis, conducted separately per futures market and cross-markets, reveals that the EWI portfolio is unrivalled in terms of risk-adjusted performance while it sustains a relatively low turnover. The findings are robust to analyses that entertain variants of the sophisticated integrations, longer estimation windows, several asset scoring schemes, data snooping tests, sub-periods evaluation and equities in place of futures. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fernandez-Perez, Adrian; Fuertes, Ana-Maria; Miffre, Joelle</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings, risk-taking, and capital accumulation in small and large community banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balla, Eliana; Rose, Morgan J.
We examine the relationships between ownership structure and both earnings and risk-taking among community banks before, during, and after the US financial crisis. We find that publicly-held small community banks had lower earnings than privately-held ones before the recession, but had higher earnings during and after the recession. Publicly-held small community banks exhibited similar risk-taking to privately-held ones before and during the recession, but greater risk-taking after. We also find that publicly-held small community banks de-risked more slowly than privately-held ones following the recession. Large community banks, on the other hand, show no consistent relationship between ownership structure and earnings, and a strong cyclical relationship between ownership structure and risk-taking. These findings expand our understanding of how community bank performance and capital accumulation behaves through different cyclical periods, and how ownership structure affects that behavior. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balla, Eliana; Rose, Morgan J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO and director compensation, CEO turnover and institutional investors: Is there cronyism in the UK?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Jie; Goergen, Marc; Leung, Woon Sau; Song, Wei
This paper provides new evidence that correlated abnormal compensation of CEOs and directors is symptomatic of agency problems associated with cronyism. We find that director abnormal compensation has a negative impact on the likelihood of CEO turnover and reduces the sensitivity of CEO turnover to poor stock performance. However, for firms with greater institutional ownership the adverse effects of director abnormal compensation are mitigated, and the negative impact of abnormal compensation on firm performance is reduced. These findings suggest that correlated abnormal compensation of CEOs and directors is likely associated with agency problems. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Jie; Goergen, Marc; Leung, Woon Sau; Song, Wei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Country-level analyst recommendations and international stock market returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, Henk; Yang, Wanyi
This study defines the aggregate analyst recommendation for a country as the value-weighted average of all outstanding recommendations for shares of firms incorporated in that country. We show that country level analyst recommendations predict international stock market returns. A trading strategy based on country-level recommendations yields an abnormal return of around 1% per month. Aggregate recommendations also help to predict changes in gross domestic product and aggregate earnings surprises. Overall, we find that country-level analyst recommendations provide useful information to predict future aggregate cash flows and associated market returns across different countries. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berkman, Henk; Yang, Wanyi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prudential supervisors' independence and income smoothing in European banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia Osma, Beatriz; Mora, Araceli; Porcuna-Enguix, Luis
We investigate the role of prudential supervisors' independence in affecting income smoothing behavior in European banks. Powerful national supervisors are predicted to influence the accounting practices of their supervised entities, shaping the properties of the accounting numbers they prepare. In particular, we study whether greater independence of powerful supervisors from the government and from the industry is associated with lower income smoothing. We use the mandatory adoption of a single set of accounting standards in Europe as a shock to the influence of prudential supervisors over national banks' accounting practice. Our results confirm that political and industry independence of the supervisor are important determinants of income smoothing. This suggests that independence of prudential supervisors is a desirable governance characteristic, with positive impacts on financial transparency. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garcia Osma, Beatriz; Mora, Araceli; Porcuna-Enguix, Luis</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which private investors are willing to pay for sustainable investments? Empirical evidence from stated choice experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gutsche, Gunnar; Ziegler, Andreas
Based on data from a representative survey among German private financial decision makers that comprised two stated choice experiments for fixed-interest investment products and equity funds, this paper empirically examines whether and which investors are willing to pay for sustainable investments. In fact, our econometric analyses with mixed and latent class logit models reveal strong stated preferences and a considerable willingness to pay (WTP) for sustainable investment products. Furthermore, our mixed logit model analysis implies that the mean WTP for certified sustainable investment products is strongly higher than the mean WTP for the uncertified counterparts. In addition, our estimation results suggest that investors with high feelings of warm glow from sustainable investments, an affinity to left-wing parties, and a strong environmental awareness have a clearly higher mean willingness to sacrifice returns for sustainable investment products than their counterparts. While risk perceptions seem to be additionally relevant for certified sustainable equity funds, they obviously play a negligible role for less risky sustainable fixed-interest investment products. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gutsche, Gunnar; Ziegler, Andreas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting underestimates of risk in VaR models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thiele, Stephen
This paper explores avenues to improve VaR backtesting against violations of unconditional coverage, with emphasis on detecting underestimates of risk. I show that existing tests for unconditional coverage have an undesirable asymmetry in power, making them less (more) effective at detecting underestimates (overestimates) of risk. A set of Lagrange multiplier (LM) tests is proposed, leading to improved power against the more dangerous underestimates. Also, the use of one-sided coverage tests is revisited, with a one-sided version of the new LM test performing best. Results are supported by simulations, showing the effectiveness of the new tests in finite samples. The same issues of asymmetric power are shown to carry over to the case of conditional coverage, though it appears that finite sample issues affecting the independence component of the tests can adversely impact performance. A simple weighted test statistic is shown to help alleviate this problem, providing an avenue to exploit the advantages of the LM approach in a conditional coverage setting. Crown Copyright (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thiele, Stephen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Enforcement of banking regulation and the cost of borrowing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deli, Yota D.; Delis, Manthos D.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Liu, Liuling
We show that borrowing firms benefit substantially from important enforcement actions issued on U.S. banks for safety and soundness reasons. Using hand-collected data on such actions from the main three U.S. regulators and syndicated loan deals over the years 1997-2014, we find that enforcement actions decrease the total cost of borrowing by approximately 22 basis points (or $4.6 million interest for the average loan). We attribute our finding to a competition-reputation effect that works over and above the lower risk of punished banks post-enforcement and survives in a number of sensitivity tests. We also find that this effect persists for approximately four years post-enforcement. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Deli, Yota D.; Delis, Manthos D.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Liu, Liuling</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management and post-split drift</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Konan; Li, Fengfei; Lin, Tse-Chun
This paper explores whether firms manage their earnings after stock splits to meet the raised expectations from the market due to the positive signal sent by the splits. We first document that post-split drift mainly exists in the first three months and is positively associated with post-split standardized unexpected earnings (SUE). However, the higher post-split SUE of split firms is associated with higher discretionary accruals and abnormally lower R&amp;D expenses. This result is consistent with our hypothesis that split firms overstate their post-split earnings by manipulating accruals and reducing R&amp;D spending. Moreover, post-split abnormal returns increase with discretionary accruals and R&amp;D reduction for about six months and tend to reverse over longer horizons, especially for firms with negative pre-split SUE. Overall, our results indicate that the post-split drift is a short-term phenomenon and partly attributable to the earnings management after the splits. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Konan; Li, Fengfei; Lin, Tse-Chun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk managing tail-risk seekers: VaR and expected shortfall vs S-shaped utility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armstrong, John; Brigo, Damiano
We consider market players with tail-risk-seeking behaviour modelled by S-shaped utility, as introduced by Kahneman and Tversky. We argue that risk measures such as value at risk (VaR) and expected shortfall (ES) are ineffective in constraining such players, as such measures cannot reduce the traders expected Sshaped utilities. Indeed, when designing payoffs aiming to maximize utility under a VaR or ES risk limit, the players will attain the same supremum of expected utility with or without VaR or ES limits. By contrast, we show that risk management constraints based on a second more conventional concave utility function can reduce the maximum S-shaped utility that can be achieved by the investor. Indeed, product designs leading to progressively larger S-shaped utilities will lead to progressively lower expected constraining conventional utilities, violating the related risk limit. These results hold in a variety of market models, including the Black Scholes options model, and are particularly relevant for risk managers given the historical role of VaR and the endorsement of ES by the Basel committee in 2012-2013. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Armstrong, John; Brigo, Damiano</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making cents of tick sizes: The effect of the 2016 US SEC tick size pilot on limit order book liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffith, Todd G.; Roseman, Brian S.
We use the 2016 U.S. SEC tick size pilot to examine the effects of an increase in the minimum price variation on limit order book liquidity in NASDAQ-listed stocks on the NASDAQ exchange. For treatment stocks with an average pre-pilot quoted spread less than $0.05, the tick size increase is binding and leads to a significant decrease in liquidity in the limit order book. Specifically, the implied cost to trade at and away from the best bid and offer prices increases and the limit order book becomes less resilient-the amount of time required for a deviation in liquidity to return to its long-run mean. For treatment stocks with an average pre-pilot quoted spread of at least $0.05, the tick size increase is non-binding and leads to either a slight decrease, or no change in limit order book liquidity. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Griffith, Todd G.; Roseman, Brian S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A factor-model approach for correlation scenarios and correlation stress testing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Packham, N.; Woebbeking, C. F.
In 2012, JPMorgan accumulated a USD 6.2 billion loss on a credit derivatives portfolio, the so-called "London Whale", partly as a consequence of de-correlations of non-perfectly correlated positions that were supposed to hedge each other. Motivated by this case, we devise a factor model for correlations that allows for scenario-based stress testing of correlations. We derive a number of analytical results related to a portfolio of homogeneous assets. Using the concept of Mahalanobis distance, we show how to identify adverse scenarios of correlation risk. In addition, we demonstrate how correlation and volatility stress tests can be combined. As an example, we apply the factor-model approach to the "London Whale" portfolio and determine the value-at-risk impact from correlation changes. Since our findings are particularly relevant for large portfolios, where even small correlation changes can have a large impact, a further application would be to stress test portfolios of central counterparties, which are of systemically relevant size. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Packham, N.; Woebbeking, C. F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The short-selling skill of institutions and individuals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chague, Fernando; De-Losso, Rodrigo; Giovannetti, Bruno
Using market-wide data from the Brazilian stock lending market at the deal level, we find strong evidence of short-selling skill for institutions and individuals. Skilled short-sellers present out-of-sample performance persistence. Exploring the granularity of our dataset, we find that skilled short-sellers do not display the disposition effect, are more likely to pick value, liquid, high-volatility, and losing stocks, and to initiate a short position before earnings announcements and around sell recommendations. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chague, Fernando; De-Losso, Rodrigo; Giovannetti, Bruno</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why investors do not buy cheaper securities: Evidence from a natural experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Kalok; Wang, Baolian; Yang, Zhishu
We examine the trading behavior of Chinese domestic investors after they were given access to the B share market in 2001. Surprisingly, we find that only 2% of investors began buying B shares. Even among these 2%, investors were less likely to buy B shares if they had more experience in the A-share market, and vice-versa. Thus, prior market experience limits the extent to which investors respond to AFB-share premiums and liquidity and lowers their performance. Our findings cannot be explained by government intervention, investor heterogeneity, foreign currency constraint, AFB-share liquidity or speculation differentials, or information advantage. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Kalok; Wang, Baolian; Yang, Zhishu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of acquisitions by high default risk bidders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruyland, Evy; Lasfer, Meziane; De Maeseneire, Wouter; Song, Wei
We investigate the takeover strategies of high default risk acquirers and their value impact. We find that these bidders select bigger, less profitable and unrelated targets, pursue transactions during recessions, and pay with shares by offering target shareholders high premiums. Their long-term buy-and-hold returns are extremely negative, and reflect fundamentally their substantial drop in profitability combined with high leverage. We show that the well-established long-run underperformance of acquiring firms is largely driven by this sub-set of acquirers. The results are similar when we use alternative measures of default risk and performance, and a global sample of non-US bidders. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bruyland, Evy; Lasfer, Meziane; De Maeseneire, Wouter; Song, Wei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bailouts and systemic insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Ratnovski, Lev
We revisit the link between bailouts and bank risk taking. Bailout expectations create moral hazard - increase bank risk taking. However, when an individual bank's success depends on both its effort and the overall stability of the banking system, bailouts that shield banks from contagion may increase their incentives to invest prudently and so reduce bank risk taking. This systemic insurance effect is more important when bailout rents are low while contagion risk is high. The optimal policy is then to make bailouts not difficult, but "effective" : associated with lower rents. We further show that, besides better bank resolution, a powerful means to reduce bailout rents is higher ex ante bank capital, since it implies a larger bank equity cushion that can be expropriated in a resolution. This highlights an important complementarity between bank capital regulation and bailouts as tools to enhance financial stability. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Ratnovski, Lev</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fear, deposit insurance schemes, and deposit reallocation in the German banking system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fecht, Falko; Thum, Stefan; Weber, Patrick
Recent regulatory initiatives such as the European Deposit Insurance Scheme propose a change in the coverage and backing of deposit insurances. An assessment of these proposals requires a thorough understanding of what drives depositors' withdrawal decisions. We show that Google searches for 'deposit insurance' and related strings reflect depositors' fears and help to predict deposit shifts in the German banking sector from private banks to fully guaranteed public banks. After the introduction of blanket state guarantees for all deposits in the German banking system this fear-driven reallocation of deposits stopped. Our findings highlight that a heterogeneous insurance of deposits can lead to a sudden, fear induced reallocation of deposits endangering the stability of the banking sector even in absence of redenomination risks. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fecht, Falko; Thum, Stefan; Weber, Patrick</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The counterparty risk exposure of ETF investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hurlin, Christophe; Iseli, Gregoire; Perignon, Christophe; Yeung, Stanley
As most Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs) engage in securities lending or are based on total return swaps, they expose their investors to counterparty risk. In this paper, we estimate empirically such risk exposures for a sample of physical and swap-based funds. We find that counterparty risk exposure is higher for swap-based ETFs, but that investors are compensated for bearing this risk. Using a difference-indifferences specification, we uncover that ETF flows respond significantly to changes in counterparty risk. Finally, we show that switching to an optimal collateral portfolio leads to substantial reduction in counterparty risk exposure. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hurlin, Christophe; Iseli, Gregoire; Perignon, Christophe; Yeung, Stanley</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit ratings of Chinese firms by domestic and global agencies: Assessing the determinants and impact</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Xianfeng; Packer, Frank
The market for the credit ratings of Chinese firms is large and growing. We analyse Chinese firms that have ratings from both domestic and global agencies. Despite the similar symbols, the rating scales of the domestic and global agencies clearly differ - as any single company's global agency and domestic agency ratings differ by 6-7 notches on average. Focusing on the comparable rank ordering of domestic and global credit ratings, we test general hypotheses about the impact of the ratings industry structure on ratings outcomes. While potential ownership-related conflicts of interest and growth of the business are not consistently associated with higher ratings, ratings industry competition is related to inflated ratings. There is also weak evidence that the downgrade of the Chinese sovereign rating by foreign rating agencies has impacted the global ratings of corporations, particularly when they are state owned. While factors relating to rating industry structure do not significantly impact bond yields, both domestic and global ratings are significant factors in yield spread multivariate regressions, and thus appear to add value beyond financial variables. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Xianfeng; Packer, Frank</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do closed-end fund investors herd?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cui, Yueting; Gebka, Bartosz; Kallinterakis, Vasileios
We provide the first investigation of herding among closed-end fund investors, drawing on the US closed end fund market for the 1992-2016 period. Results suggest closed-end fund investors herd significantly, with their herding being mainly driven by non-fundamentals. Closed-end fund herding rises in economic/market uncertainty, with its significance being mainly concentrated in the post-2007 period. Herding among closed-end funds is strongly motivated by discounts, is more pronounced than that among their net asset values and tends to grow inversely with fund-size. The fact that closed-end fund herding is noise-driven and linked to their discounts raises the possibility that it is related to the noise trader risk attributed to closed-end funds by investor sentiment theory. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cui, Yueting; Gebka, Bartosz; Kallinterakis, Vasileios</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option-Implied variance asymmetry and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Tao; Li, Junye
We find a positive relationship between individual stocks' implied variance asymmetry, defined as the difference between upside and downside risk-neutral semivariances extracted from out-of-money options, and future stock returns. The high-minus-low hedge portfolio earns the excess return of 0.90% (0.67%) per month in equal-weighted (value-weighted) returns. We show that implied variance asymmetry provides a neat measure of risk-neutral skewness and outperforms the standard risk-neutral skewness in predicting the cross-section of future stock returns. Risk-based equilibrium asset pricing models can not explain such a positive relationship, which instead can be potentially explained by information asymmetry and informed trading. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Tao; Li, Junye</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate risk and efficiency of mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kucinskas, Simas
This paper studies the welfare properties of mutual funds in a Diamond-Dybvig economy with two sources of aggregate risk: (i) shocks to long-term investment returns; and (ii) shocks to aggregate liquidity demand. Mutual funds are inefficient when the long-term investment is risky. Mutual funds improve upon autarky by introducing a wedge between the market and technological rates of return. However, the wedge distorts the decisions of consumers not facing liquidity shocks, and the resulting equilibrium is inefficient. If only aggregate liquidity demand is subject to shocks, mutual funds can implement the social optimum (even when liquidity demand is not directly observable) by means of a price-contingent dividend policy. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kucinskas, Simas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity in securitization markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Alyssa Gray
During the financial crisis of 2008, origination and trading in asset-backed securities markets dropped dramatically. I present a model with ambiguity-averse investors to explain how such a market freeze could occur and to investigate how ambiguity affects origination and securitization decisions. The model shows how non-fundamental factors such as ambiguity can lead to market freezes and fire sales, as well as reductions in real economic activity. I consider the differing implications of a non-fundamental shock, such as ambiguity, and fundamental shocks, such as changes in risk or a deterioration of expected value. Market outcomes can change more abruptly under ambiguity than under either fundamental deterioration or risk alone. Additionally, ambiguity leads to different policy implications than fundamental shocks do. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anderson, Alyssa Gray</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why has the size effect disappeared?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, Dong-Hyun; Min, Byoung-Kyu; Yoon, Bohyun
This paper explores why the size effect vanished after the early 1980s. We show that the size effects are significantly positive primarily at the bottom of the business cycles. More importantly, this dependency of the size effect on the business cycles is preserved even after the 1980s. Therefore, our findings suggest that while unconditional size effect has perished, the size effect conditional on the business cycles is alive and well. The less frequent occurrences of troughs, due to prolonged business cycle length, are shown to be responsible for the dissolution of the size effect. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahn, Dong-Hyun; Min, Byoung-Kyu; Yoon, Bohyun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor control and product-market competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, Matthew T.; Esmer, Burcu; Yu, Miaomiao
We explore how rival firms respond when firms in their industry violate debt covenants. We find that rival firms increase advertising expense, and that this increase is proportional to the size of industry violators' pre-existing market share. Rival firm product-market share also increases in the industry market share of violators, and this relation is more pronounced when products are more substitutable. Rival firm operating performance also increases in proportion to the industry market share of violators. Overall, these findings suggest that the increased creditor control associated with covenant violations has a significant influence on rival firms and product-market competition. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Billett, Matthew T.; Esmer, Burcu; Yu, Miaomiao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>To what extent did the economic stimulus package influence bank lending and corporate investment decisions? Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Qigui; Pan, Xiaofei; Tian, Gary Gang
Using a panel of Chinese firms over the period 2003-2013, we show that, from the supply-side perspective, as a result of the implementation of the economic stimulus package in China, state-owned enterprises (SOEs) received more bank loans and invested more than non-SOEs. We further find that after the implementation of the economic stimulus package, bank lending became less responsive to firm profitability, and firm investments became less responsive to investment opportunities for SOEs, non-SOEs from favoured industries and regions, and non-SOEs with political connections. Overall, our findings support the view that the stimulus package and the associated increase in bank loan supply in China resulted in more resources being allocated to SOEs. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Liu, Qigui; Pan, Xiaofei; Tian, Gary Gang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring firm size in empirical corporate finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dang, Chongyu; Li, Zhichuan; Yang, Chen
In empirical corporate finance, firm size is commonly used as an important, fundamental firm characteristic. However, no research comprehensively assesses the sensitivity of empirical results in corporate finance to different measures of firm size. This paper fills this hole by providing empirical evidence for a "measurement effect" in the "size effect". In particular, we examine the influences of employing different proxies (total assets, total sales, and market capitalization) of firm size in 20 prominent areas in empirical corporate finance research. We highlight several empirical implications. First, in most areas of corporate finance the coefficients of firm size measures are robust in sign and statistical significance. Second, the coefficients on regressors other than firm size often change sign and significance when different size measures are used. Unfortunately, this suggests that some previous studies are not robust to different firm size proxies. Third, the goodness of fit measured by R-squared also varies with different size measures, suggesting that some measures are more relevant than others in different situations. Fourth, different proxies capture different aspects of "firm size", and thus have different implications. Therefore, the choice of size measures needs both theoretical and empirical justification. Finally, our empirical assessment provides guidance to empirical corporate finance researchers who must use firm size measures in their work. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dang, Chongyu; Li, Zhichuan; Yang, Chen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate derivatives use in banking: Market pricing implications of cash flow hedges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhigbe, Aigbe; Makar, Stephen; Wang, Li; Whyte, Ann Marie
We examine whether investors are able to fully anticipate the pricing implications of cash flow hedges in the banking industry. We show that mark-to-market adjustments on cash flow hedges are inversely related to future cash flows and that investors underestimate the extent of this inverse relation. Our evidence supports the notion that incomplete information on value relevant parameters makes it difficult for investors to accurately predict the effects of current cash flow hedge adjustments on future cash flows. Our results are also consistent with the evidence that investors have limited attention such that information, particularly information that is difficult to discern, is not fully reflected in stock prices. Thus, the additional disclosures mandated by regulatory agencies in the banking industry are not sufficient to overcome the challenges associated with incomplete information and investors' limited attention. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akhigbe, Aigbe; Makar, Stephen; Wang, Li; Whyte, Ann Marie</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Innovation externalities and the customer/supplier link</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Keming
This paper proposes a novel channel through which innovation externalities can affect firm performance. I find cross-sectional evidence that the positive innovation outputs of customer firms increase their supplier profitability as measured by firm ROE. This result is robust to the inclusion of industry fixed effect, a control for both supplier and customer characteristics, such as ROE, advertisement expenditure, capital expenditure, firm age, industry concentration, institutional ownership, dividend yield, and a control for industry spillover or geographical spillover. To identify the causal effect of customer innovation outputs on supplier performance, I study an exogenous shock-State Street Bank and Trust Company v. Signature Financial Group, Inc.-and find that an increase in granted customer patents causes an improvement in future supplier performance. This effect is mainly driven by the demand channel and the knowledge diffusion channel from customers to suppliers. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Keming</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate risk management and the mix of fixed and floating rate debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oberoi, Jaideep
We analyze the after-swap mix of fixed and floating rate debt in a sample of non-financial firms, using hand-collected data from a window of time when derivative positions were included in accounting disclosures. To motivate the analyses, we present a simple theoretical model that highlights the special features of interest rate risk. Consistent with the theory, we find that firms that issue more fixed rate debt have higher liquidity ratios and lower operating income ratios. We also document that individual firms actively vary the proportion of their fixed rate debt to a strikingly high extent. There is a debate as to whether such variation should be interpreted as hedging or speculation. We show that the firms more actively varying their debt mix respond to different hedging motives than those with low activity. We then empirically motivate an alternative indicator of speculative activity: co-variation between ex-post profitability of financial decisions and operating results. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oberoi, Jaideep</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capturing the value premium - global evidence from a fair value-based investment strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Woltering, Rene-Ojas; Weis, Christian; Schindler, Felix; Sebastian, Steffen
This paper examines the risk premium of value stocks within a global investment strategy framework. We test whether absolute or relative mispricing is better suited to capturing the global value premium by using fair value-based net asset values (NAVs) as our proxies for fundamental value. We find that investing in the most underpriced stocks relative to the average ratio of price to fundamental value in a country is the key to achieving superior risk-adjusted returns. The annualized excess return of the global value portfolio sorted according to relative mispricing is 10.0%, and remains significant after controlling for common risk factors. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Woltering, Rene-Ojas; Weis, Christian; Schindler, Felix; Sebastian, Steffen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>China's "Mercantilist" Government Subsidies, the Cost of Debt and Firm Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Chu Yeong; Wang, Jiwei; Zeng, Cheng
China has been adopting a "mercantilist" policy by lavishing massive government subsidies on Chinese firms. Using hand-collected subsidy data on Chinese listed companies, we find that firms receiving more subsidies tend to have a lower cost of debt. However, such firms fail to have superior financial performance. Instead, firms with more subsidies tend to be overstaffed, which demonstrates higher social performance. These results are mainly driven by non-tax-based subsidies rather than tax-based subsidies. Overall, our results suggest that the Chinese government uses non-tax-based subsidies to achieve its social policy objectives at the expense of firms' profitability. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lim, Chu Yeong; Wang, Jiwei; Zeng, Cheng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating VPIN as a trigger for single-stock circuit breakers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abad, David; Massot, Magdalena; Pascual, Roberto
We study if VPIN (Easley et al., 2012a) is an efficient advance indicator of toxicity-induced liquidity crises and related sharp price movements. We find that high VPIN readings rarely signal abnormal illiquidity, and very occasionally anticipate large intraday price changes leading to actual trading halts. We find significant differences in illiquidity and price impact between VPIN-identified toxic and non-toxic halts, but they tend to vanish when we control for ex ante realized volatility. We conclude that the capacity of VPIN to anticipate truly toxic events is limited. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abad, David; Massot, Magdalena; Pascual, Roberto</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of conventional and unconventional monetary policy on expectations and sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galariotis, Emilios; Makrichoriti, Panagiota; Spyrou, Spyros
This paper offers evidence on the effect of ECB's conventional and unconventional monetary policy on economic expectations in Euro-area countries during the US and EU crisis. We employ a range of research methodologies in a sample of nine Eurozone countries and combine expectations/sentiment indicators with a set of macroeconomic and financial variables. We find that ECB's conventional monetary policy (and Fed's monetary policy stance) has a positive and significant effect on economic expectations for Core Eurozone countries and a weak effect on Peripheral Eurozone countries. ECB's unconventional policy measures, however, have a negative short term effect on Core countries' economic expectations. This result is robust to different methodologies (PVAR, QVAR, FAVAR) and different datasets. Overall, our findings highlight the importance of monetary policy in the determination of economic expectations. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Galariotis, Emilios; Makrichoriti, Panagiota; Spyrou, Spyros</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In search for managerial skills beyond common performance measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Fan; Qian, Meifen; Sun, Ping-Wen; Yu, Bin
One caveat of current literature on the value of active management is the lack of treatment for the performance measures that can be gamed. We propose to use the performance measure that can't be manipulated with respect to the underlying distribution, time variation, nor estimation error, (the manipulation proof performance measure (MPPM, Goetzmann et al. (2007)), to rank all active U.S. domestic equity mutual funds from 1980 to 2013 on a quarterly basis to analyze managerial skills. We find fund managers in the higher ranked persistently outperform lower ranked managers by posting higher gross and net fund returns, higher holding-based returns, and generating positive return gap. Analyzing the holdings of the portfolios indicates higher ranked managers hold stocks with higher information asymmetry, especially the growth companies that are younger, smaller, and with lower liquidity. Our results show that the spread on gross and net fund returns between highest ranked and the lowest ranked fund managers is between 49 and 52 basis points per month. The holding returns are statistically significant for up to six months indicating the stock picking skills exist for those higher ranked managers. Even though MPPM identifies managerial skills, the positive alphas may not be warranted due to their operating expenses. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Fan; Qian, Meifen; Sun, Ping-Wen; Yu, Bin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bid-to-cover and yield changes around public debt auctions in the euro area</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beetsma, Roel; Giuliodori, Massimo; Hanson, Jesper; de Jong, Frank
Earlier research has shown that euro-area primary public debt markets affect secondary markets. We find that more successful auctions of euro area public debt, as captured by higher bid-to-cover ratios, lead to lower secondary-market yields following the auctions. This effect is stronger when market volatility is higher. We rationalize both findings using a simple theoretical model of primary dealer behavior, in which the primary dealers receive a signal about the value of the asset auctioned. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beetsma, Roel; Giuliodori, Massimo; Hanson, Jesper; de Jong, Frank</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alternative corporate governance: Domestic media coverage of mergers and acquisitions in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borochin, Paul; Cu, Wei Hua
A text analysis of domestic Chinese newspaper articles covering 797 proposed domestic mergers shows that the media in developing countries is susceptible to pressure: coverage is more favorable for deals consistent with government objectives and involving powerful local firms. However, we also find that coverage can affect the outcome of proposed M&amp;A deals in non-stateowned firms. We identify this effect using an exogenous shock to market-driven governance from the Split-Share Structure Reform of 2007. Negotiation coverage predicts long-term performance, consistent with information dissemination. Despite biased coverage, domestic media in developing countries can function as an alternative channel for corporate governance. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Borochin, Paul; Cu, Wei Hua</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hidden gems and borrowers with dirty little secrets: Investment in soft information, borrower self-selection and competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gropp, Reint; Guettler, Andre
This paper empirically examines the role of soft information in the competitive interaction between relationship and transaction banks. Soft information can be interpreted as a valuable signal about the quality of a firm that is observable to a relationship bank, but not to a transaction bank. We show that borrowers self-select to relationship banks depending on whether their observed soft information is positive or negative. Competition affects the investment in learning the soft information from firms by relationship banks and transaction banks asymmetrically. Relationship banks invest more; transaction banks invest less in soft information, exacerbating the selection effect. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gropp, Reint; Guettler, Andre</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring banks' market power in the presence of economies of scale: A scale-corrected Lerner index</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spierdijka, Laura; Zaourasa, Michalis
A positive Lerner index indicates a welfare loss for consumers due to deviations from marginal-cost pricing. Such a welfare loss may not always be due to market power, though. In particular, marginal-cost pricing would result in negative profit for the firm in the presence of economies of scale. In such a scenario, a positive Lerner index could simply reflect the firm's need to earn non-negative profits rather than market power. We propose a novel, scale-corrected price-cost margin for firms that produce in the economies of scale range. We show that this measure is more informative about market power than the Lerner index itself. As an empirical illustration, we analyze market power in the U.S. banking sector using both the corrected and uncorrected Lerner index. The corrected Lerner index reveals significant market power for U.S. commercial banks during the 2000 - 2014 period. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Spierdijka, Laura; Zaourasa, Michalis</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local corporate social responsibility, media coverage, and shareholder value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Byun, Seong K.; Oh, Jong-Min
Using news articles covering firm's corporate social responsibility (CSR) activities, we find that publicized CSR activities are positively associated with shareholder value and improved future operating performance. Furthermore, we find that media coverage on CSR engagements with local impact on companies' communities and employees, rather than those with broader social impact on the general public, is the main driver in explaining higher shareholder value and operating performance. We also implement a two-stage least-squares regression (2SLS) and propensity score matching to establish a causal link between publicized local CSR activities and shareholder value. Our evidence is consistent with the notion that shareholders put positive value on locally-oriented CSR when it is also complemented with high level of stakeholder awareness. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Byun, Seong K.; Oh, Jong-Min</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social capital and the cost of equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, Atul; Raman, Kartik; Shang, Chenguang
We find that a firm's cost of equity is inversely related to the level of social capital in the state where the firm is headquartered. Further, the cost of equity declines when firms move their headquarters from a low-social-capital state to a state with higher social capital. The negative relation between social capital and the cost of equity is statistically significant only for firms facing relatively low levels of product market competition and is not significant for firms with good firm-specific reputations. We interpret these findings as indicating that social capital serves as a societal monitoring mechanism, and can be value-enhancing for firms that are perceived as having greater agency problems and face weak product market monitoring. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gupta, Atul; Raman, Kartik; Shang, Chenguang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Q-theory, mispricing, and profitability premium: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Fuwei; Qi, Xinlin; Tang, Guohao
Using various empirical measures, we find that, in China, firms with high profitability generate substantially higher future stock returns than those with low profitability. This positive effect of profitability on expected returns is robust to controlling for other firm characteristics and risks. We show that the profitability premium is stronger among firms with low investment friction, which is consistent with the implications of investment-based q-theory asset pricing models. However, the premium is not stronger among firms with high limits to arbitrage, contradicting behavioral mispricing explanations. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Fuwei; Qi, Xinlin; Tang, Guohao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Export market exit and financial health in crises periods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goerg, Holger; Spaliara, Marina-Eliza
This paper uses rich firm-level data for the UK to investigate the link between firms' financial health and export exit, paying attention to the ERM currency crisis and the global financial crisis. Our results show that deterioration in the financial position of firms has increased the hazard of export exit during the 2007-09 crisis but has no significant effect on the early 1990s crisis. We also explore the extent to which firms in financially vulnerable industries face greater sensitivity of export exit to financial conditions. We conclude that firms in sectors with great reliance on external finance experience higher hazards of exiting the export market during the 2007-09 crisis. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goerg, Holger; Spaliara, Marina-Eliza</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank funding costs in a rising interest rate environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gerlach, Jeffrey R.; Mora, Nada; Uysal, Pinar
One key risk to the banking system is how funding costs will change as monetary policy is normalized and interest rates rise after almost a decade of near-zero rates. Our contribution is to develop a model that jointly estimates banks' balance sheets and retail interest rates to arrive at a consistent estimate of the change in bank funding costs as market rates change. Our estimates imply a 100 basis-point shock to the Federal Funds rate would increase overall deposit funding costs by about $40 billion, which is roughly equal to 25% of aggregate annual net income for commercial banks and savings institutions. We also find that deposit rate responses are largely symmetric, in contrast to some previous research showing deposit rates are less responsive to upward movements in reference rates. We introduce unique and confidential data on bank deposit betas to anchor our results. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gerlach, Jeffrey R.; Mora, Nada; Uysal, Pinar</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Chinese credit ratings relevant? A study of the Chinese bond market and credit rating industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Livingston, Miles; Poon, Winnie P. H.; Zhou, Lei
We investigate the nascent but fast-growing Chinese bond market and credit rating industry. We find Chinese bond ratings are informative and significantly correlated with bond offering yields. In addition, the Chinese bond investors distinguish ratings from different credit rating agencies (CRAs), demanding lower yields on bonds rated by global-partnered CRAs. However, the empirical results suggest that the rating scales used by Chinese CRAs are not comparable to those of international CRAs. Furthermore, Chinese CRAs have very broad rating scales and pool bonds with significantly different default risks into a single rating category, resulting in over 90% of bonds in only three rating categories. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Livingston, Miles; Poon, Winnie P. H.; Zhou, Lei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forex trading and the WMR Fix</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evans, Martin D. D.
I examine the behavior of forex prices around the setting of the 4:00 pm WMR Fix. Numerous banks have been fined by regulators for their trading activities around the Fix, but the overall impact of their actions is not known. I first examine trading patterns around the Fix in a microstructure model of competitive trading. I then compare the model with the empirical behavior of forex prices across 21 currencies over a decade. Contrary to the predictions of the model, forex price changes display extraordinary volatility and negative serial correlation around the Fix. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Evans, Martin D. D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dawn of an 'age of deposits' in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jaremski, Matthew; Rousseau, Peter L.
Individual deposits in the United States grew from 5% to 23% of GDP between 1863 and 1913. A comprehensive database shows bank entry underlying this trend while historical events, including the National Banking Acts, resumption in 1879, and the election of 1896, influenced deposits at the bank-level. The nation's embrace of deposits was thus driven by stability of the monetary system and confidence in the safety and utility of established and well-capitalized banks. Bank-level and county-level regressions confirm these patterns for national banks over the entire postbellum period and for a sample of Midwest state and national banks from 1888. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jaremski, Matthew; Rousseau, Peter L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regional banking instability and FOMC voting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eichler, Stefan; Laehner, Torn; Noth, Felix
This study analyzes if regionally affiliated Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) members take their districts' regional banking sector instability into account when they vote. Considering the period 1979-2010, we find that a deterioration in a district's bank health increases the probability that this district's representative in the FOMC votes to ease interest rates. According to member-specific characteristics, the effect of regional banking sector instability on FOMC voting behavior is most pronounced for Bank presidents (as opposed to Governors) and FOMC members who have career backgrounds in the financial industry or who represent a district with a large banking sector. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eichler, Stefan; Laehner, Torn; Noth, Felix</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Timing of banks' loan loss provisioning during the crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Haan, Leo; van Oordt, Maarten R. C.
We estimate a panel error correction model for loan loss provisions, using unique supervisory data on flow of funds into and out of the allowance for loan losses of 25 Dutch banks in the post-2008 crisis period. We find that these banks aim for an allowance of 49% of impaired loans. In the short run, however, the adjustment of the allowance is only 29% of the change in impaired loans. The deviation from the target is made up by (a) larger additions to allowances in subsequent quarters and (b) smaller reversals of allowances when loan losses do not materialize. After one quarter, the adjustment toward the target level is 32%, and after four quarters it is 79%. For individual banks, there are substantial differences in timing of provisioning for bad loan losses. Crown Copyright (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Haan, Leo; van Oordt, Maarten R. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender, risk tolerance, and false consensus in asset allocation recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Posavac, Steven
We study the impact of gender on asset allocation recommendations. Graduate business students and professional wealth managers are randomly assigned a male or female client. Participants recommend an allocation and choose an allocation for themselves. Male students choose a riskier allocation than female students, consistent with existing evidence of a gender difference in risk tolerance, and recommend a riskier allocation. In contrast, male and female wealth managers choose and recommend the same allocation, indicating that male and female finance professionals feature similar risk preferences. In both samples, a subject's allocation choice is the strongest predictor of the recommendation provided. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Posavac, Steven</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash flows and credit cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Figueroa, Nicolas; Leukhina, Oksana
Aggregate productivity falls in recessions and rises in expansions. Several empirical studies suggest that the systematic behavior of lending standards, with laxer (tighter) standards applied during expansions (recessions), is responsible for reverting trends in aggregate productivity. We build a dynamic model that rationalizes these findings. Adverse selection in credit markets emerges as a potential source of macroeconomic instability. The key idea modeled is that in order to effectively signal their type to financiers, productive entrepreneurs must suffer a cost. The effective cost of signaling rises with higher cash flow brought about by stronger economic fundamentals, because higher cash flow makes it easier for the unproductive type to mimic the productive type. Competition among the financiers then results in suboptimally lax lending standards. Low productivity entrepreneurs obtain financing, the producer composition effect inducing a recession. This, in turn, creates conditions - weak economic fundamentals and low cash flow - conducive to the emergence of tighter lending terms, the strong composition effect leading to an economic recovery. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Figueroa, Nicolas; Leukhina, Oksana</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Legal framework quality and success of (different types of) venture capital investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tykvova, Tereza
Drawing on an analysis of 8,270 companies from 41 countries, I explore the relationship between success of venture capital investments and legal frameworks in the investment countries. Legal framework quality is related to success, but the effect varies with the deal type. First, the significant and positive relationship between legal framework quality and success is more pronounced for domestic deals than for international deals. Further investigations suggest that international venture capitalists often exit their portfolio companies abroad, particularly when these companies are located in countries with in efficient legal frameworks. In addition, the results lend support to the view that international venture capitalists have a greater experience and reputation. Second, legal framework quality seems to be more important for success in syndicated than in standalone deals. This finding supports the view that a sound legal framework may improve the benefit-cost balance of syndication, while an inefficient legal framework may tend to increase costs in syndicated deals. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tykvova, Tereza</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting money market bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baldeaux, Jan; Ignatieva, Katja; Platen, Eckhard
The existence of a self-financing trading strategy that replicates the money market account at a fixed future date at a lower cost than the current value of this account constitutes a money market bubble (MMB). Understanding whether a market exhibits an MMB is crucial, in particular, for derivative pricing. An MMB precludes the existence of a risk-neutral probability measure. The benchmark approach allows to study MMBs and is formulated under the real world probability measure. It does not require the existence of a risk neutral probability measure. Using a range of well-known stochastic volatility models, we study the existence of an MMB in the US economy, and find that the US market exhibits an MMB for all models considered that allow it. This suggests that for derivative pricing and hedging care should be taken when making assumptions pertaining to the existence of a risk-neutral probability measure. Less expensive portfolios are likely to exist for a wide range of long-term derivatives, as typical for pensions. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baldeaux, Jan; Ignatieva, Katja; Platen, Eckhard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sex and credit: Do gender interactions matter for credit market outcomes?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Behr, Patrick; Madestam, Andreas
This paper studies the effects of gender interactions on the supply of and demand for credit using data from a large Albanian lender. We document that first-time borrowers assigned to officers of the opposite sex are less likely to return for a second loan. The effect is larger when officers have little prior exposure to borrowers of the other gender and when they have more discretion to act on their gender beliefs, as proxied by financial market competition and branch size. We also find that first-time borrowers matched with opposite-sex officers pay higher interest rates and receive smaller and shorter-maturity loans, but do not experience higher arrears. Our results are consistent with the existence of a gender bias and learning effects that lead to the disappearance of the bias. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Behr, Patrick; Madestam, Andreas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>All's well that ends well? On the importance of how returns are achieved</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grosshans, Daniel; Zeisberger, Stefan
We demonstrate that investor satisfaction and investment behavior are influenced substantially by the price path by which the final investor return is achieved. In a series of experiments, we analyze various different price paths. Investors are most satisfied if their assets first fall in value and then recover, and they are least satisfied with the opposite pattern, independent of whether the final return is positive or negative. Price paths systematically influence risk preferences, return beliefs, and ultimately trading decisions. Our results enable a much more holistic perspective on a wide range of topics in finance, such as the disposition effect, risk-taking behavior after previous gains and losses, and behavioral asset pricing. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grosshans, Daniel; Zeisberger, Stefan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-interest income and bank lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abedifar, Pejman; Molyneux, Philip; Tarazi, Amine
This paper examines the influence of non-interest activities on bank lending in terms of loan quality and interest spread. We also investigate the possible existence of profit complementarities between non interest activities and lending. Using quarterly data on 6921 U.S. commercial banks between 2007:Q3 to 2016:Q3 we find that non-interest activities have no adverse influence on bank credit risk. This is the case for banks of different asset size (including systemically important banks) as well as for distressed banks. There is evidence that banks with assets between $100 million and $1 billion that have a greater share of fiduciary income have lower credit risk. They also have lower interest rates on loans secured by real estate, and higher franchise values, particularly post-crisis. Moreover, banks in the aforementioned size range benefit from synergies in joint production of non-interest income and lending, whereas other banks, in particular smaller banks (below $100 million in assets) suffer from diseconomies of joint production. Larger banks exhibit cross-subsidization between several non-interest activities and lending business. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abedifar, Pejman; Molyneux, Philip; Tarazi, Amine</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of more frequent portfolio disclosure on mutual fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parida, Sitikantha; Teo, Terence
This paper analyzes the impact of more frequent portfolio disclosures on performance of mutual funds. Since 2004, SEC requires all U.S. mutual funds to disclose their portfolio holdings on a quarterly basis from semi-annual previously. This change in regulation provides a natural setting to study the impact of frequency of disclosure on performance of mutual funds. Prior to the policy change, we find that successful semi-annual funds outperform successful quarterly funds by 17-20 basis points a month. After 2004, their performance goes down and they no longer outperform successful quarterly funds. This reduction in performance is higher for semi-annual funds holding illiquid assets. These results support our hypothesis that the performance of funds with more frequent disclosure, particularly of those holding illiquid assets, suffer more from front running activities. We also find complementary evidence that the profitability of a hypothetical front running strategy based on public disclosures goes up with the frequency of portfolio disclosures. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Parida, Sitikantha; Teo, Terence</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fraud recovery and the quality of country governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Curti, Filippo; Mihov, Atanas
Using supervisory data from U.S. financial institutions on fraud-related losses in foreign markets, we find that losses in countries with poor governance have lower recovery rates. Our results are robust to accounting for potential endogeneity and reverse causality concerns, among numerous robustness checks. The association is driven by intuitive governance dimensions such as control of corruption, rule of law, regulatory quality and government effectiveness. In addition, country governance plays a particularly important role in fraud recovery for firms with poor risk management quality. Overall, this paper presents unique and novel evidence tying country governance quality to firm-level risk realizations. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Curti, Filippo; Mihov, Atanas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>