<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF1</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Monetary policy uncertainty and the market reaction to macroeconomic news</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kurov, Alexander; Stan, Raluca
We examine whether monetary policy uncertainty influences the reaction of the equity, Treasury security, foreign exchange and crude oil markets, as well as medium-term interest rates, to U.S. macroeconomic announcements. Using intraday futures data, we show that in the presence of higher policy uncertainty the response to macroeconomic news weakens in the stock and crude oil markets and strengthens in the Treasury, interest rate and foreign exchange markets. In times of elevated monetary policy uncertainty, macroeconomic announcements impact the financial and crude oil markets to a large extent through expectations of future monetary policy. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kurov, Alexander; Stan, Raluca</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The skewness of commodity futures returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandez-Perez, Adrian; Frijns, Bart; Fuertes, Ana-Maria; Miffre, Joelle
This article studies the relation between the skewness of commodity futures returns and expected returns. A trading strategy that takes long positions in commodity futures with the most negative skew and shorts those with the most positive skew generates significant excess returns that remain after controlling for exposure to well-known risk factors. A tradeable skewness factor explains the cross-section of commodity futures returns beyond exposures to standard risk premia. The impact that skewness has on future returns is explained by investors' preferences for skewness under cumulative prospect theory and selective hedging practices. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fernandez-Perez, Adrian; Frijns, Bart; Fuertes, Ana-Maria; Miffre, Joelle</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The mechanics of commercial banking liberalization and growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dal Colle, Alessandra
This paper formalizes the effects of liberalization across the border of deposit-taking and lending activities on the regime of competition in the banking market and on the rate of growth of the economy. We extend two economy based Deidda (2006)'s banking model in which originally each economy hosts at least one operating bank. We introduce two GATS-defined modes of commercial banking liberalization namely the Commercial Presence mode and the Cross-Border mode. Additionally, we introduce the possibility of strategic behavior by competing banks in equilibrium. The extended model provides a causal link between the cost structure of the banking industry, the regime of competition in the liberalized banking sector and the rate of growth of the economy under alternative modes of liberalization. In particular, we show a threshold effect in terms of economic development: above certain economic development the banking sector operates competitively and supports an accelerating rate of growth, generating a bidirectional, self-reinforcing link between commercial banking liberalization and growth. The pace of growth is further increased, with respect to a scenario where such behavior is not present, by the presence of strategic behavior by competing banks in equilibrium. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Dal Colle, Alessandra</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital markets' assessment of the economic impact of the Dodd-Frank Act on systemically important financial firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Yu; Liao, Scott; Wang, Xue
We examine stock and bond market reactions to the key events leading to the passage of the Dodd-Frank Act to assess the markets' expectations about the effectiveness of the Act on systemically important financial firms. Using small/medium sized domestic financial institutions as a control group, we find that large financial institutions overall had negative abnormal stock returns and positive abnormal bond returns, suggesting that the markets expect the Act to be effective in reducing these banks' risk-taking. We further investigate the market reactions for (1) larger and more interconnected financial institutions; and (2) the Big 6 banks to evaluate the markets' assessment about the effectiveness of the act in ending the too-big-to-fail policy. We document that larger and more interconnected financial institutions experienced more negative abnormal stock returns and more positive abnormal bond returns as compared to other banks in our sample, but these relations are not present during the final phase of the passage. Likewise, we find that both shareholders and bondholders of the Big 6 banks initially experienced significant negative returns, followed by insignificant returns during the final phase of the passage. These results appear to suggest the markets are doubtful about the effectiveness of the final version of the bill to end the too-big-to-fail status in particular for the Big 6 banks. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gao, Yu; Liao, Scott; Wang, Xue</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limits of arbitrage and idiosyncratic volatility: Evidence from China stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gu, Ming; Kang, Wenjin; Xu, Bu
This study examines how limits of arbitrage can affect the pricing of idiosyncratic volatility. Using both unique trading constraints in the Chinese stock market and other commonly-used limits-of-arbitrage measures, we construct a comprehensive limits-of-arbitrage index. Based on this index, we find that the negative idiosyncratic volatility return premium is much stronger and more persistent in stocks with high limits of arbitrage. Furthermore, the existing explanations about the idiosyncratic volatility return premium cannot fully explain what we find about the role of limits of arbitrage in the pricing of idiosyncratic volatility in the Chinese stock market. Our study suggests that the trading constraints introduced in the name of protecting individual investors can actually hurt them, since these additional limits of arbitrage will increase the inefficiency of the security market. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gu, Ming; Kang, Wenjin; Xu, Bu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do players perform for pay? An empirical examination via NFL players' compensation contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Seoyoung; Sarin, Atulya; Sarin, Saagar
How to properly compensate and incentivize players is an important question in the realm of professional sports, and more broadly, is a central question in contract design. With the increasing use of performance-based compensation packages and tax law favoring such compensation design, a natural question arises as to whether workers do indeed perform for pay. We examine this question in a setting that is not fraught with the typical measurement and identification problems found in many pay performance settings. Specifically, we examine changes in a NFL player's Win Probability Added (WPA) and Expected Points Added (EPA) in response to his compensation-contract design. Overall, our paper provides evidence that players do indeed perform for (properly designed) pay, and has important implications for future work on compensation and incentive-based contract design. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Seoyoung; Sarin, Atulya; Sarin, Saagar</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do the prices of UK inflation-linked securities say on inflation expectations, risk premia and liquidity risks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaminska, Iryna; Liu, Zhuoshi; Relleen, Jon; Vangelista, Elisabetta
The difference between yields on nominal and inflation-linked government bonds or inflation swap rates are important indicators of the outlook for inflation and are monitored regularly by central banks, including the United Kingdom's Monetary Policy Committee (MPC). However, in the United Kingdom, inflation linked instruments reference RPI inflation, whereas the MPC's target is CPI inflation of 2%. In this paper we extract market expectations for UK CPI inflation with the help of UK RPI-linked gilt prices, which is a novelty in the literature. To better extract useful information about expectations for CPI inflation, we develop a no-arbitrage term structure model and decompose the forward inflation curve into: measures of CPI inflation expectations; the expected wedge between RPI and CPI inflation; estimates of inflation risk premia and estimates of liquidity risk premia. We show that long-horizon expectations of CPI inflation fell in the 1990 s, after the introduction of inflation targeting and the creation of the MPC, and have since remained fairly stable at around 2%. (C) 2017 The Bank of England. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaminska, Iryna; Liu, Zhuoshi; Relleen, Jon; Vangelista, Elisabetta</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How much is too much? Large termination fees and target distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neyland, Jordan; Shekhar, Chander
We provide evidence that large termination fees mitigate contracting problems in acquisitions of targets with high information asymmetry. Large fees are more common if targets face financial constraints or distress. Deals with large termination fees are less likely to be consummated, consistent with large fees allowing acquirers to recover bidding costs when facing a high risk of bid failure. We correct for the endogenous selection of large termination fees and present evidence that managers negotiate large fees in exchange for higher premiums. This is in contrast with prior evidence that suggests large fees result from managerial self-interest and harm target shareholders. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Neyland, Jordan; Shekhar, Chander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>National elections and tail risk: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Qingyuan; Li, Si; Xu, Li
We investigate stock tail risk around national elections worldwide over the period of 1982-2012. We find that firm stock is less likely to crash during the election years, and is more likely to crash during the post-election period. This inter-temporal pattern is consistent with the suppression of negative information when there is heightened political uncertainty around elections and with the subsequent release of adverse news when the uncertainty is reduced. Further analysis shows that the impact of political uncertainty on tail risk is stronger in countries with poorer investor protection, fewer electoral checks and balances, more uncertain election outcomes and pro-business incumbent governments, in industries which are more politically sensitive, and in firms with larger information asymmetry. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Qingyuan; Li, Si; Xu, Li</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry networks and IPO waves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baxamusa, Mufaddal; Jalal, Abu
We offer a new perspective on why initial public offerings (IPOs) occur in waves and propose that the customer-supplier relationships among industries help propagate IPO waves. Our empirical tests provide evidence that demand shocks increase the number of IPOs in an industry. The shocks then spread upstream through customer relationships leading to an increase in the number of IPOs in more central and connected industries. These findings contribute to the IPO literature by demonstrating the channel through which IPO waves propagate. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baxamusa, Mufaddal; Jalal, Abu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Point process models for extreme returns: Harnessing implied volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herrera, R.; Clements, A. E.
Forecasting the risk of extreme losses is an important issue in the management of financial risk. There has been a great deal of research examining how option implied volatilities (IV) can be used to forecast asset return volatility. However, the role of IV in the context of predicting extreme risk has received relatively little attention. The potential benefit of IV in forecasting extreme risk is considered within a range of models beginning with the traditional GARCH based approach, along with a number of novel point process models. Univariate models where IV is included as an exogenous variable are considered along with a novel bivariate approach where extreme movements in IV are treated as another point process. It is found that in the context of forecasting Value-at-Risk, the bivariate models produce the most accurate forecasts across a wide range of scenarios. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Herrera, R.; Clements, A. E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monthly cyclicality in retail Investors' liquidity and lottery-type stocks at the turn of the month</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Meng, Yun; Pantzalis, Christos
The well-documented underperformance of lottery stocks masks a within-month cyclical pattern. Demand for lottery stocks increases at the turn of the month, especially in areas whose demographic profile resembles that of typical lottery-ticket buyers (i.e., gamblers), thus driving their prices higher. This effect is rooted in local retail investors' preference for lottery stocks and propelled by the within-month cyclicality of local investors' personal liquidity positions. A long-short investment strategy based on this cyclical pattern of lottery stocks' performance yields gross abnormal returns of about 12.6% per year. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Meng, Yun; Pantzalis, Christos</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How data breaches affect consumer credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mikhed, Vyacheslav; Vogan, Michael
We use the 2012 South Carolina Department of Revenue data breach as a natural experiment to study how data breaches and news coverage about them affect consumers' interactions with the credit market and their use of credit. We find that some consumers directly exposed to the breach protected themselves against potential losses from future fraudulent use of stolen information by monitoring their files and freezing access to their credit reports. However, these consumers continued their regular use of existing credit cards and did not switch lenders. The response of consumers exposed to the news about the breach only was negligible. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mikhed, Vyacheslav; Vogan, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial synergies and systemic risk in the organization of bank affiliates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luciano, Elisa; Wihlborg, Clas
We analyze theoretically banks' choice of organizational structures in branches, subsidiaries or stand-alone banks, in the presence of public bailouts and default costs. These structures are characterized by different arrangements for internal rescue of affiliates against default. The cost of debt and leverage are endogenous. For moderate bailout probabilities, subsidiary structures, wherein the two entities provide mutual internal rescue under limited liability, have the highest group value, but also the highest risk taking as measured by leverage and expected loss. We explore the effect of constraints on leverage and policy implications. The conflict of interests between regulators, who minimize systemic risk, and banks, who maximize their own value, is mitigated when capital requirements are effective. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Luciano, Elisa; Wihlborg, Clas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank monitoring and CEO risk-taking incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saunders, Anthony; Song, Keke
This paper investigates whether monitoring by bank lenders affects CEO incentives of borrowing firms. We find that an increase in bank monitoring incentives significantly reduce the sensitivity of CEO wealth to stock return volatility (Vega). The results are more profound when bank lenders are more powerful and reputable and have a prior lending relationship with the borrowing firms. Additionally, Vega decreases after financial covenant violations and increases when bank lenders have offsetting equity stakes in borrowing firms. The reduction in Vega due to bank monitoring has some real effects on borrowing firms' corporate policies. These results together suggest banks have a unique role in monitoring and shaping CEO incentives to mitigate the risk-shifting incentives of firm managers. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Saunders, Anthony; Song, Keke</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option-implied objective measures of market risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leiss, Matthias; Nax, Heinrich H.
Foster and Hart (2009) introduce an objective measure of the riskiness of an asset that implies a bound on how much of one's wealth is 'safe' to invest in the asset while (a.s.) guaranteeing no-bankruptcy. In this study, we translate the Foster-Hart measure from static and abstract gambles to dynamic and applied finance using nonparametric estimation of risk-neutral densities from S&amp;P 500 call and put option prices covering 2003-2013. The dynamics of the resulting 'option-implied Foster-Hart bound' are assessed in light of other well-known option-implied risk measures including value at risk, expected shortfall and risk-neutral volatility, as well as high moments of the densities and several industry measures. Rigorous variable selection reveals that the new measure is a significant predictor of (large) ahead-return downturns. Furthermore, it grasps more characteristics of the risk-neutral probability distributions in terms of moments than other measures and exhibits predictive consistency. The robustness of the risk-neutral density estimation is analyzed via Monte Carlo methods. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leiss, Matthias; Nax, Heinrich H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate tax incentives and capital structure: New evidence from UK firm-level tax returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Devereux, Michael P.; Maffini, Giorgia; Xing, Jing
We investigate how companies' capital structure is affected by corporate income taxes using confidential company-level tax returns for a large sample of UK firms. Exploiting variation in companies' marginal tax rates, we find a positive and substantial long-run tax effect on leverage. Leverage responds more to decreases in the marginal tax rate, and it responds to changes in the marginal rather than the average tax rate. Most importantly, we find that the marginal tax rate based on tax returns has greater explanatory power for companies' leverage than the marginal tax rate based on financial statements. Our study suggests that errors in the measurement for tax incentives using financial statements could lead to underestimation of the tax effects on capital structure. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Devereux, Michael P.; Maffini, Giorgia; Xing, Jing</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Female board directorship and firm performance: What really matters?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennouri, Moez; Chtioui, Tawhid; Nagati, Haithem; Nekhili, Mehdi
Using a sample of 394 French firms for the period of 2001 to 2010, we study the relationship between female directorship and firms' accounting (ROA and ROE) and market-based (Tobin's Q) performance. We find that female directorship significantly increases ROA and ROE, and significantly decreases Tobin's Q. We postulate that these relationships are affected by the attributes of female directors. To this end, we collect a set of nine different attributes of female directors capturing their monitoring capabilities and contribution to the board's human capital (demographic and board relational attributes). We find that the positive relationship between accounting performance and female directorship remains when we include these attributes, while the negative relationship between Tobin's Q and female directorship disappears. Interestingly, the different attributes of female directors do not uniformly affect accounting and market-based performance. We explain the different relationships between attributes and firm performance by the tradeoff between the benefits and costs of diversity on board effectiveness, particularly in a low investor protection environment. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bennouri, Moez; Chtioui, Tawhid; Nagati, Haithem; Nekhili, Mehdi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance of foreign banks in developing countries: Evidence from sub-Saharan African banking markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pelletier, Adeline
Do foreign banks perform better than domestic banks in host developing economies? Relying on financial statements and survey data I compare the performance of three different categories of foreign banks to the group of domestic banks in sub-Saharan Africa: global banks from developed countries, regional African banks and banks from non-African emerging economies. While emerging-market banks and global banks consistently outperform domestic banks, the difference is not significant for regional African banks. The higher performance of global banks and emerging-market banks is related to higher operational efficiency and lower cost of funding, while there is no strong evidence of segmentation by business segment in the loans market. Regional African banks, which started their foreign expansion more recently, are less able to generate interest income compared to domestic banks. These findings highlight the importance of taking into account foreign banks' heterogeneity when assessing the impact of financial FDI on the host economy. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pelletier, Adeline</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum and funding conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia-Feijoo, Luis; Jensen, Gerald R.; Jensen, Tyler K.
We find evidence linking return momentum with macroeconomic conditions, namely, the funding environment. We show that winners outperform losers by a significant amount in restrictive funding states, while in expansive states, winners and losers perform similarly. This pattern is consistent with changing investor preferences for winners and losers following signaled shifts in funding availability. One plausible channel for this relation is the interaction between stock-level illiquidity and funding conditions. We find that liquidity risk is significantly priced during restrictive states, especially in loser stocks. Furthermore, loser stocks become more illiquid during restrictive conditions. Both effects help explain the relative performance difference between losers and winners across funding environments. Moreover, the funding environment influences the relationship between momentum and firm characteristics, after controlling for the influence of sentiment, market states and return dispersion. Overall, transitions in funding states appear to encourage investors to revise their factor pricing decisions, which produces inter-temporal variation in momentum. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garcia-Feijoo, Luis; Jensen, Gerald R.; Jensen, Tyler K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the transactions costs of UK quantitative easing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breedon, Francis
Most quantitative easing programmes primarily involve central banks acquiring government liabilities in return for central bank reserves. In all cases this process is undertaken by purchasing these liabilities from private sector intermediaries rather than directly from the government. This paper estimates the cost of this round-trip transaction - government issuance of liabilities and central bank purchases of those liabilities in the secondary market - for the UK. I estimate that this cost amounts to about 0.5% of the total value of QE (over E1.8 billion in my sample). I also find some evidence that this figure is inflated by the unusual design of UK QE operations. Crown Copyright (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Breedon, Francis</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loss aversion around the world: Empirical evidence from pension funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xie, Yuxin; Hwang, Soosung; Pantelous, Athanasios A.
We propose a novel method to estimate loss aversion together with risk aversion and subjective probability weighting in a reference-dependent utility. Using multiple asset allocations in the 31 OECD pension funds, we find that our estimates of loss aversion and subjective probability weights are similar to those reported by Wang et al. (2017) and Rieger et al. (2011), respectively, despite the differences in the estimation methods. However, loss aversion increases with wealth and only Hofstede's Individualism is positively related to loss aversion. Countries with high individualism or masculinity prefer high risk and high return assets to bonds, whereas countries that dislike uncertainty prefer bonds to risky assets. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xie, Yuxin; Hwang, Soosung; Pantelous, Athanasios A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size does not matter: Diseconomies of scale in the mutual fund industry revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phillips, Blake; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Rau, P. Raghavendra
The academic literature has found mixed evidence that fund size is negatively related to performance. One reason for the lack of consensus may be that the fund size and performance relation is endogenous. In this paper, we identify a set of instrumental variables that influence fund size but are unrelated to expected fund performance. Using this specification, we show that fund size does not appear to affect fund performance. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Phillips, Blake; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Rau, P. Raghavendra</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subjectivity in sovereign credit ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Moor, Lieven; Luitel, Prabesh; Sercu, Piet; Vanpee, Rosanne
A sovereign creditrating is a function of hard and soft information that should reflect the creditworthiness and the probability of default of a country. We propose an alternative characterisation for the subjective component of a sovereign credit rating - the parts related to the ratee's lobbying effort or its familiarity from a United States point of view - and apply it to S&amp;P, Moody's and Fitch ratings, using both traditional ordered-logit panel models and machine learning techniques. This subjective component turns out to be large, especially for the low-rated countries. Countries that are rated as investment grade tend to be positively influenced by it, and vice versa. Subjective judgment in credit ratings does have predictive value: it helps in identifying chances of sovereign defaults in the short-term. Still, the impact of subjectivity in sovereign ratings on borrowing costs is very limited on average. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Moor, Lieven; Luitel, Prabesh; Sercu, Piet; Vanpee, Rosanne</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multinomial VaR backtests: A simple implicit approach to backtesting expected shortfall</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kratz, Marie; Lok, Yen H.; McNeil, Alexander J.
Under the Fundamental Review of the Trading Book, capital charges are based on the coherent Expected Shortfall (ES) risk measure, which is sensitive to tail risk. We argue that backtesting of the forecasting models used to derive ES can be based on a multinomial test of Value-at-Risk (VaR) exceptions at several levels. Using simulation experiments with heavy-tailed distributions and GARCH volatility models, we design a statistical procedure to show that at least four VaR levels are required to obtain tests for misspecified trading book models that are more powerful than single-level (or even two-level) binomial exception tests. A traffic-light system for model approval is proposed and illustrated with three real-data examples spanning the 2008 financial crisis. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kratz, Marie; Lok, Yen H.; McNeil, Alexander J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The strategic choice of payment method in corporate acquisitions: The role of collective bargaining against unionized workers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, I.-Ju; Chen, Yan-Shing; Chen, Sheng-Syan
Acquirers facing strong union power tend to acquire target firms with cash rather than equity or a mix of cash and equity. A one standard deviation increase in the union power faced by the acquirer increases the odds of choosing cash payment by a factor ranging from 1.26 to 1.57. The effect is stronger when: the acquiring firm is located in states without the right-to-work laws; the interests of managers are more aligned with shareholders in acquiring firms; and acquiring firms' asset specificity is high. When union power is strong, acquirers making cash payment are associated with a significantly positive announcement return. In addition, they are less likely to experience labor strikes or declines in operating performance, and more likely to obtain wage concessions in collective bargaining in the post-acquisition period than acquirers using other methods of payment. These findings suggest that cash payment allows acquirers to reduce excess liquidity and strengthen their bargaining power with unions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, I.-Ju; Chen, Yan-Shing; Chen, Sheng-Syan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital regulation with heterogeneous banks - Unintended consequences of a too strict leverage ratio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barth, Andreas; Seckinger, Christian
We provide an equilibrium analysis of potential consequences from the introduction of a binding leverage ratio, as proposed in Basel III. If banks differ in their monitoring skills and their ability to successfully complete a risky investment project, a tighter leverage ratio does not only mitigate moral hazard arising from limited liability, but also carries an unintended consequence: high-quality banks are not allowed to absorb the entire supply of debt if it is too costly to issue new equity. This increases the market share of low-skilled bankers and decreases the average ability of operating banks. We further show that rising heterogeneity in the banking sector increases this negative effect. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barth, Andreas; Seckinger, Christian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic activity and momentum profits: Further evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maio, Paulo; Philip, Dennis
We show that economic activity plays an important role in explaining momentum-based anomalies. A simple two-factor model containing the market and alternative indicators of economic activity as risk factors industrial production, capacity utilization rate, retail sales, and a broad economic index offers considerable explanatory power for the cross-section of price and industry momentum portfolios. Hence past winners enjoy higher average returns than past losers because they have larger macroeconomic risk. The model compares favorably with popular multifactor models used in the literature. Moreover, our model is consistent with Merton's Intertemporal CAPM framework, since the macro variables forecast stock market volatility and future economic activity. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maio, Paulo; Philip, Dennis</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jumps, cojumps, and efficiency in the spot foreign exchange market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piccotti, Louis R.
I identify intraday jumps and cojumps in exchange rates controlling for volatility patterns and relate these events to pre-scheduled macroeconomic news and market conditions. Event study results show that preceding jump and cojump events, exchange rate quote volume, illiquidity, signed order flow, and informed trades are at heightened levels revealing that jump events are consistent with rational dealer quoting behavior. Following jump and cojump events, quote volume and return variance remain at heightened levels while illiquidity, informed trade, and signed order flow remain at depressed levels providing evidence that order flow following jump events is largely uninformed liquidity provision. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Piccotti, Louis R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can lenders discern managerial ability from luck? Evidence from bank loan contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bui, Dien Giau; Chen, Yan-Shing; Hasan, Iftekhar; Lin, Chih-Yung
We investigate the effect of managerial ability versus luck on bank loan contracting. Borrowers showing a persistently superior managerial ability over previous years (more likely due to ability) enjoy a lower loan spread, while borrowers showing a temporary superior managerial ability (more likely due to luck) do not enjoy any spread reduction. This finding suggests that banks can discern ability from luck when pricing a loan. Firms with high-ability managers are more likely to continue their prior lower loan spread. The spread-reduction effect of managerial ability is stronger for firms with weak governance structures or poor stakeholder relationships, corroborating the notion that better managerial ability alleviates borrowers' agency and information risks. We also find that well governed banks are better able to price governance into their borrowers' loans, which helps explain why good governance enhances bank value. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bui, Dien Giau; Chen, Yan-Shing; Hasan, Iftekhar; Lin, Chih-Yung</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate litigation and debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arena, Matteo P.
This study examines the effect of litigation risk and litigation costs on firms' credit ratings and debt financing. The results show that litigation affects a firm's creditworthiness and debt costs in two stages. Before a lawsuit filing, firms at higher risk of litigation have lower credit ratings, are more likely to be rated speculative grade, pay higher yields on loans and bonds, and are less likely to rely on debt financing. At the time of the lawsuit resolution, settlement costs have an additional effect on firm credit quality. Companies facing larger settlement disbursements in relation to their available cash experience a decline in credit ratings and an increase in yield spread. The results are robust to endogeneity concerns and different proxies of litigation risk. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arena, Matteo P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An examination of the relation between strategic interaction among industry firms and firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bayar, Tumennasan; Cornett, Marcia Millon; Erhemjamts, Otgontsetseg; Leverty, Ty; Tehranian, Hassan
This paper examines the relation between the degree and type of strategic interaction among industry firms and firm performance. As a measure of firm performance, we use data envelopment analysis (DEA) to estimate the efficiency of a firm relative to the 'best practice' firms in its industry. We find that firms in industries with higher levels of strategic interaction are less efficient and the negative relation is more pronounced in industries where firms compete in strategic substitutes. This finding is consistent with the idea that there is significantly more cooperation (tacit collusion) under strategic complements than strategic substitutes. We also find that frontier efficiency methodology outperforms other measures of firm performance in explaining the relation between strategic interaction and firm performance. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bayar, Tumennasan; Cornett, Marcia Millon; Erhemjamts, Otgontsetseg; Leverty, Ty; Tehranian, Hassan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The peer performance ratios of hedge funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ardia, David; Boudt, Kris
We define the outperformance (resp. underperformance) of an investment fund as the percentage of funds in the peer universe for which the true performance of the focal fund is higher (resp. lower). We show that the p-values of the pairwise tests of equal performance can be used to obtain estimates of the out- and underperformance ratio that are robust to false discoveries - estimated alpha differentials for which the significance test has a low p-value while the true alpha is identical. When applied to hedge funds, we find that ranking funds on the outperformance ratio leads to a top quintile portfolio with a higher absolute and risk-adjusted performance than when the estimated alpha is used. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ardia, David; Boudt, Kris</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The state dependent impact of bank exposure on sovereign risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Podstawski, Maximilian; Velinov, Anton
The theoretical literature remains inconclusive on whether changes in bank exposure to the domestic sovereign have an adverse effect on the sovereign risk position through a diabolic loop in the sovereign bank nexus, or reduce perceived default risk by acting as a disciplinary device for the sovereign. In this paper we empirically analyze the impact of exogenous changes in bank exposure on the risk position of the sovereign within a Markov switching structural vector autoregressive in heteroscedasticity (MSH-SVAR) framework for a set of EMU countries. We add to the methodological literature by allowing for regime dependent shock transmissions according to the volatility state of the financial system. Finding support for both, a stabilizing and a destabilizing effect, we document a clear clustering among the country sample: rising bank exposure increased default risk for the EMU periphery, but decreased credit risk for the core EMU countries during times of financial stress. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Podstawski, Maximilian; Velinov, Anton</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are gold and silver cointegrated? New evidence from quantile cointegrating regressions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schweikert, Karsten
This paper revisits the study on the long-run relationship between gold and silver by Escribano and Granger (1998). We apply a quantile cointegration model to gold and silver prices and to prices of the corresponding futures contracts. Whereas cointegration models, assuming a constant cointegrating vector, fail to detect a cointegration relationship between gold and silver, we are able to show that a nonlinear long-run relationship exits. The cointegrating vector is modelled as state-dependent and time-varying in our framework and the quantile cointegration estimates reveal substantial asymmetry in the relationship. The results suggest that the pronounced role of precious metals as investment opportunities particularly in bubble-like episodes and times of financial turmoil leads to comovement of gold and silver in these periods. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schweikert, Karsten</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short selling around the expiration of IPO share lockups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gibbs, Michael; Hao
We are the first to examine daily short selling activity around the expiration of IPO share lockups. We find that short selling increases before the lockup expiration date and declines afterward, and the level of short selling is higher in stocks of venture capital (VC)- and private equity (PE)-backed IPOs than other IPOs. Unlike VC-backed IPO stocks, PE-backed IPO stocks do not experience a negative return or a trading volume jump on the lockup expiration date. PE investors do not reduce percentage ownership in the IPO firm as much as VC investors do after lockup expirations. Short selling in PE- and VC-backed IPO stocks prior to the lockup expiration date can predict PE and VC ownership reduction but not the stock returns after the lockup expires. In contrast, short selling in stocks of the IPO firms without a PE or VC investor can predict stock returns after the lockup expires. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gibbs, Michael; Hao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading efficiency of fund families: Impact on fund performance and investment behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cici, Gjergji; Dahm, Laura K.; Kempf, Alexander
This study examines how the efficiency of trading desks operated by mutual fund families affects portfolio performance and investment behavior of affiliated funds. We estimate the trading efficiency of a fund family's trading desk as the difference between the gross return of the family's index fund, which incorporates trading costs, and the return of the underlying index, which does not incorporate trading costs, around index adjustment dates. By operating more efficient trading desks that help reduce trading costs, fund families improve the performance of their funds significantly and also enable their funds to trade more and hold less liquid portfolios. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cici, Gjergji; Dahm, Laura K.; Kempf, Alexander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distance to compliance portfolios: An integrated shortfall measure for basel III</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmaltz, Christian; Heidorn, Thomas; Torchiani, Ingo
We propose measuring a bank's distance to compliance with Basel III using a portfolio that makes the bank compliant. This "Distance to Compliance" portfolio describes an implementable strategy and incorporates the interactions of all Basel III ratios. We derive the portfolio in a microeconomic banking model in which the board decides on the regulatory target levels and bears the responsibility in case the bank fails to meet the regulatory requirements in a stress situation. We apply our framework to two hypothetical banks and find that they achieve compliance by growth strategies without cutting lending. We corroborate that shareholders choose different compliance strategies than managers, emphasizing the importance of setting managers' incentives carefully. We compare our results to findings from impact studies that are not model-based and do not consider the interactions of the Basel III ratios. We observe that the synergies of LCR and NSFR are the most pronounced ones but of secondary order in absolute magnitude. This means that measuring "Distance to Compliance" on a ratio-by-ratio basis omitting synergies, as often done by regulators, does not introduce a major bias. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schmaltz, Christian; Heidorn, Thomas; Torchiani, Ingo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oil volatility risk and expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Pan, Xuhui
After the financialization of commodity futures markets in 2004-2005 oil volatility has become a strong predictor of returns and volatility of the overall stock market. Furthermore, stocks' exposure to oil volatility risk now drives the cross-section of expected returns. The difference in average return between the quintile of stocks with low exposure versus high exposure to oil volatility is significant at 0.66% per month, and oil volatility risk carries a significant risk premium of -0.60% per month. We also find that increases in oil price uncertainty predict tightening funding constraints of financial intermediaries suggesting a link between oil volatility risk and the stock market. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Pan, Xuhui</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of commodity benchmarks on derivatives markets: The case of the dated Brent assessment and Brent futures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frino, Alex; Ibikunle, Gbenga; Mollica, Vito; Steffen, Tom
We examine the response of ICE Brent Crude futures to the spot Dated Brent benchmark published by Platts. Trading activity in the futures market intensifies during the benchmark assessment. We also find trading in the direction of the published benchmark during the price assessment window. Aligned positions and a substantially increased arrival rate of informed traders suggest that sophisticated traders, taking advantage of a rise in uninformed trading activity, induce the price run-up in Brent futures, ahead of the Dated Brent assessment end. The general increase in the arrival rate of both informed and uninformed traders during the assessment window underlines the benchmark's relevance and its potential for attracting liquidity. Our results are robust to alternative specifications and underscore the significance of physical commodity benchmarks as critical elements of the financial market infrastructure. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frino, Alex; Ibikunle, Gbenga; Mollica, Vito; Steffen, Tom</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk factors and their associated risk premia: An empirical analysis of the crude oil market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hain, Martin; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese; Unger, Nils
This paper sheds new light on higher-order price risks in crude oil markets. A model-free analysis reveals that crude oil variance risk behaves fundamentally different from variance risk in equity markets. Most importantly, a skewness swap is no valid hedge for a variance swap and investors fear large price jumps in both directions. A model-based assessment confirms this and reveals that while stochastic volatility is important to capture the statistical properties such as volatility clusters and time-varying variance swap rates, only jump risk seems to be priced with a premium. Empirical evidence from a pricing and hedging exercise confirms these findings. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hain, Martin; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese; Unger, Nils</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculation, risk aversion, and risk premiums in the crude oil market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Bingxin
Speculative activity in commodity markets has increased dramatically since 2002. This paper investigates how aggregate risk aversion and risk premiums in the crude oil market covary with the level of speculation. Using crude oil futures and option data, we estimate aggregate risk aversion in the crude oil market and find that it is significantly lower between 2005 and 2008 when speculative activity increases dramatically. Risk premiums implied by the state-dependent risk aversion are also negatively correlated with speculative activity and are on average lower and more volatile during this period. These findings, together with the increased index fund and managed-money infusion in the commodity market, suggest that speculators who demand commodity futures for the purpose of portfolio diversification are willing to accept lower compensation for their positions. Decreasing speculation after 2009 amid increased producers' hedging demand has a reverse impact on the market risk aversion and risk premiums. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Bingxin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is food financialized? Yes, but only when liquidity is abundant</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ordu, Beyza Mina; Oran, Adil; Soytas, Ugur
In this paper, we investigate whether commodity index trader (CIT) positions help to explain the increase in the correlations between agricultural commodities and equities starting around 2008. Some argue institutional investors who invest both in stock and commodity markets demolish the borders between these two seemingly unrelated markets and increase correlations, a recent phenomenon known as financialization. Yet, some others argue recently correlations have decreased back to historical levels and the increase between 2008 and 2012 was merely due to a business cycle effect. Our results do not support one side at the expense of the other but rather shows that both factors are important in explaining the correlations between agricultural commodities and stocks. Furthermore, we find that CITs prefer to go back to their circle of competence under scarce liquidity and thus correlations decrease back to levels absent institutions. Hence, low liquidity is a significant obstacle inhibiting financialization to occur. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ordu, Beyza Mina; Oran, Adil; Soytas, Ugur</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium commodity prices with irreversible investment and non-linear technologies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casassus, Jaime; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Routledge, Bryan R.
We model oil price dynamics in a general equilibrium production economy with two goods: a consumption good and oil. Production of the consumption good requires drawing from oil reserves at a fixed rate. Investment necessary to replenish oil reserves is costly and irreversible. We solve for the optimal consumption, production and oil reserves policy for a representative agent. We analyze the equilibrium price of oil, as well as the term structure of oil futures prices. Because investment in oil reserves is irreversible and costly, the optimal investment in new oil reserves is periodic and lumpy. Investment occurs when the crude oil is relatively scarce in the economy. This generates an equilibrium oil price process that has distinct behavior across two regions (characterized by the abundance/scarcity of oil). We undertake three empirical tests suggested by our model. First, we estimate key parameters using SMM to match moments of oil price futures as well as other macroeconomic properties of the data. Second, we estimate an affine regime switching model of the oil price, which captures the main features of our equilibrium model and preserves the tractability of reduced-form models. Lastly, we compare the risk premium in short-maturity oil futures implied by our model to the data. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Casassus, Jaime; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Routledge, Bryan R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing of long-dated commodity derivatives: Do stochastic interest rates matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Benjamin; Nikitopoulos, Christina Sklibosios; Schlogl, Erik
Does modelling stochastic interest rates, beyond stochastic volatility, improve pricing performance on long-dated commodity derivatives? To answer this question, we consider futures price models for commodity derivatives that allow for stochastic volatility and stochastic interest rates and a correlation structure between the underlying variables. We examine the empirical pricing performance of these models on pricing long-dated crude oil derivatives. Estimating the model parameters from historical crude oil futures prices and option prices, we find that stochastic interest rate models improve pricing performance on long-dated crude oil derivatives, when the interest rate volatility is relatively high. Furthermore, increasing the model dimensionality does not tend to improve the pricing performance on long-dated crude oil option prices, but it matters for long-dated futures prices. We also find empirical evidence for a negative correlation between crude oil futures prices and interest rates that contributes to improving fit to long-dated crude oil option prices. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cheng, Benjamin; Nikitopoulos, Christina Sklibosios; Schlogl, Erik</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gas storage valuation under multifactor Levy processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cummins, Mark; Kiely, Greg; Murphy, Bernard
A practical problem for energy companies is instituting a consistent framework across its supply and trading activities to deliver on all-important P&amp;L and at-Risk reporting requirements. With a focus on storage assets and wider natural gas market exposures, we present a gas storage valuation methodology, which uniquely uses a flexible multifactor Levy process setting that allows for consistent valuation and risk management reporting across a general derivative book. Our approach is capable of replicating the complex covariance structure of the natural gas forward curve and capturing time spread volatility, a key driver of extrinsic storage value, while being simultaneously capable of accurately calibrating to market traded options. We begin by extending a single factor Mean Reverting Variance Gamma process to an arbitrary number of dimensions and, by way of specific examples, show how the traditional Principal Component Analysis based view of gas forward curve dynamics can be incorporated into a primarily market based valuation. We develop in the process an innovative implied moments based calibration technique, which allows for efficient calibration of general multifactor forward curve models to delivery period options common in energy and commodity markets. Furthermore, to accommodate the forward curve and traded options market consistency, we propose an appropriate joint market based calibration and historical estimation methodology. Through a formal model specification analysis, we provide evidence that the multifactor Levy models we propose provide a better joint fit to NBP natural gas options-forward market data, relative to comparative benchmark models. Finally, we develop a novel multidimensional fast Fourier transform based storage valuation algorithm and provide empirical evidence that the multifactor Levy model suite is better specified to more accurately capture extrinsic value. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cummins, Mark; Kiely, Greg; Murphy, Bernard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From the Samuelson volatility effect to a Samuelson correlation effect: An analysis of crude oil calendar spread options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schneider, Lorenz; Tavin, Bertrand
Our first aim in this paper is to introduce a futures-based model able of capturing the main features displayed by Crude Oil futures and options contracts, such as the Samuelson volatility effect and the volatility smile. We calculate the joint characteristic function of two futures contracts in the model in analytic form and use it to price calendar spread options. In an empirical application we show that the model, in contrast to simpler nested models, can be successfully calibrated to market prices of vanilla and calendar spread options. Our second aim is to use this model to analyze the dependence structure of Crude Oil futures contracts. To this end, we propose analytical expressions giving the copula and copula density directly in terms of the joint characteristic function. These tools allow us to perform an in-depth analysis for pairs of futures, and we observe a phenomenon we call the Samuelson correlation effect. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schneider, Lorenz; Tavin, Bertrand</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A space-time random field model for electricity forward prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benth, Fred Espen; Paraschiv, Florentina
Stochastic models for forward electricity prices are of great relevance nowadays, given the major structural changes in the market due to the increase of renewable energy in the production mix. In this study, we derive a spatio-temporal dynamical model based on the Heath-Jarrow-Morton (HJM) approach under the Musiela parametrization, which ensures an arbitrage-free model for electricity forward prices. The model is fitted to a unique data set of historical price forward curves. As a particular feature of the model, we disentangle the temporal from spatial (maturity) effects on the dynamics of forward prices, and shed light on the statistical properties of risk premia, of the noise volatility term structure and of the spatio-temporal noise correlation structures. We find that the short-term risk premia oscillates around zero, but becomes negative in the long run. We identify the Samuelson effect in the volatility term structure and volatility bumps, explained by market fundamentals. Furthermore we find evidence for coloured noise and correlated residuals, which we model by a Hilbert space-valued normal inverse Gaussian Levy process with a suitable covariance functional. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benth, Fred Espen; Paraschiv, Florentina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-optimized pooling of intermittent renewable energy sources</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gersema, Gerke; Wozabal, David
Many photovoltaic and wind generation capacity owners gain access to power markets by signing up with virtual power plants. Power generation from these renewable sources of electricity is inherently uncertain and, consequently, revenue is random, which induces a risk for the owner. In this study, we investigate to what extent pooling different technologies and locations in the portfolio of a virtual power plant can reduce aggregate risk. To this end, we develop stochastic models for factors driving the assets' underlying market and volume risks on which we base a model for risk-optimized pooling. Using the German market as an example, we demonstrate that optimal portfolios have a clearly better risk/return profile than the market portfolio. This finding holds in the case without subsidies as well as the case with feed-in tariffs. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gersema, Gerke; Wozabal, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-commodity news transmission and volatility spillovers in the German energy markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, Rikard; Larsson, Karl; Lunina, Veronika; Nilsson, Birger
This study investigates volatility spillovers to electric power from large exogenous shocks in the prices of gas, coal, and carbon emission allowances in the German energy market. Our sample ranges from 2008 to 2016 and covers periods of different market conditions. We use a general VAR-BEKK model and the volatility impulse response function methodology to analyze and evaluate the spillover effects. Special attention is paid to selecting an appropriate econometric volatility model. Our results show that the spillover effects often are of a significant magnitude and display considerable variation over time and across commodities. Coal and gas generate non-negligible spillovers during almost the entire sample period. Carbon has very little impact during the early and late parts of the sample, but generates significant, and highly variable, spillovers during the period from 2011 to the end of 2014. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Green, Rikard; Larsson, Karl; Lunina, Veronika; Nilsson, Birger</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Talking Numbers: Technical versus fundamental investment recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Kaplanski, Guy; Levy, Haim
Market efficiency is often evaluated through the ability of fundamental analysis or technical trading rules to exploit predictable patterns in asset prices. The evidence following decades of empirical research is mixed. This paper reexamines the evidence using a novel database from the TV show "Talking Numbers." We assess the performance of 1,599 investment recommendations, where each recommendation features a fundamental and a technical forecast. We show that technicians are able to predict individual stock returns to economically significant degrees up to a one-year horizon. Beyond that, the null hypothesis of market efficiency is not rejected for market-wide indices, equity sectors, bonds, or commodities. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Kaplanski, Guy; Levy, Haim</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A tale of two uncertainties</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Hae Mi
Consistent with Bayesian learning models, I find that two types of uncertainty market uncertainty and firm-signal uncertainty have opposite effects on investors' learning from new information. I provide novel evidence that investor learning increases with the level of prior market uncertainty and decreases with firm-signal uncertainty (i.e., signal precision). Specifically, I find that the stock price response to earnings announcements increases with market volatility and decreases with earnings volatility. The results indicate that investor learning increases linearly with market uncertainty and decreases nonlinearly with firm-signal uncertainty. The effect of market uncertainty is stronger for large firms, firms with more market information in their returns, and firms with more institutional ownership. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choi, Hae Mi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge fund vs. non-hedge fund institutional demand and the book-to-market effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caglayan, Mustafa Onur; Celiker, Umut; Sonaer, Gokhan
Recent studies have documented that institutional investors trade contrary to the predictions of the book to market anomaly. We examine whether a prominent sub-group of institutional investors, namely hedge funds, differ from other institutions in terms of their trading behavior with respect to the book-to-market effect. We find that hedge funds significantly alter their trading preferences with respect to growth and value stocks, after book-to-market values become public information. More importantly, we show that hedge funds are better able to identify overpriced growth stocks compared to other institutions. Our results contribute to the literature on institutional investors' trading with respect to stock return anomalies. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caglayan, Mustafa Onur; Celiker, Umut; Sonaer, Gokhan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Balance sheet strength and bank lending: Evidence from the global financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kapan, Tumer; Minoiu, Camelia
We use the 2007-2008 financial crisis as a lens to study the link between banks' financial health and the strength of transmission of financial sector shocks to the real economy. We find that banks with ex-ante stronger balance sheets, in particular higher levels of common equity, were better able to maintain credit supply when faced with liquidity shocks during the crisis. Bank recapitalizations mitigated the lending gap between high and low capital banks, but only in countries with strong sovereigns. These findings support the view that strong financial intermediary balance sheets are key for the recovery of credit and economic performance after large financial sector shocks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kapan, Tumer; Minoiu, Camelia</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It pays to partner with a firm that writes annual reports welll</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baxamusa, Mufaddal; Jalal, Abu; Jha, Anand
We use strategic alliances as a setting to examine whether the readability of a firm's partner's 10-K matters. We find that the increase in the cumulative abnormal return (CAR) around the announcement of an alliance is relatively lower when the firm's partner in a strategic alliance has a less readable 10-K report. Additional tests show that the impact of the readability of a partner's 10-K is much stronger when investors suspect insufficient due diligence before the alliance's formation, when the partner is from a different industry, and when the alliance occurs before the Sarbanes-Oxley Act. Overall, our results show that the readability of a partner's annual report matters it pays to partner with a firm that writes these reports well. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baxamusa, Mufaddal; Jalal, Abu; Jha, Anand</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>House price, loan-to-value ratio and credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bian, Xun; Lin, Zhenguo; Liu, Yingchun
Real estate transactions are often established through financing. We study the effect of financing on property prices. We show that properties can transact at prices well above their collateral values. Therefore, the commonly used loan-to-value (LTV) ratio suffers a bias that can significantly understate credit risk. This bias is exacerbated when mortgages are originated with longer terms, at higher LTV ratios, or when sellers possess stronger bargaining power. Furthermore, this bias is larger under aggressive lending products, e.g. interest-only loans and mortgages allowing negative amortization. Our simulation results suggest that many mortgages originated at the peak of the housing bubble are, in fact, "under water" at origination. In particular, the loan amount of a 30-year mortgage at a 95% LTV can be 15% greater than the collateral value of the property, suggesting the mortgage is already deep "under water" at origination. These findings call into questions underwriting and risk control practices in mortgages and other collateralized debts. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bian, Xun; Lin, Zhenguo; Liu, Yingchun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial market Volatility, macroeconomic fundamentals and investor Sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chin, Ching-wai; Harris, Richard D. F.; Stoja, Evarist; Chin, Michael
In this paper, we investigate the dynamic relationship between financial market volatility, macroeconomic fundamentals and investor sentiment, employing a two-factor model to decompose volatility into a persistent long run component and a transitory short run component. Using a structural VAR model with Bayesian sign restrictions, we show that adverse shocks to aggregate demand and supply cause an increase in the persistent component of both stock and bond market volatility, and that adverse shocks to the persistent component of either stock or bond market volatility cause a deterioration in macroeconomic fundamentals. We find no evidence of a relationship between the transitory component of volatility and macroeconomic fundamentals. Instead, we find that the transitory component is more closely associated with changes in investor sentiment. Our results are robust to a wide range of alternative specifications. Out-of-sample forecasting shows that the components of volatility can improve forecasts of macroeconomic fundamentals, and vice versa. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chin, Ching-wai; Harris, Richard D. F.; Stoja, Evarist; Chin, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Allergy onset and local investor distraction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pantzalis, Christos; Ucar, Erdem
We posit that investor distraction can be exogenously triggered by allergy onset's degrading effects on local investors' health and cognitive functioning. We document that allergy onset is related to lower trading activity. We use daily pollen counts to measure the severity of allergy onset at different locations and show that stocks of firms located in areas with severe allergy problems exhibit declines in trading volume and lower stock returns. Moreover, allergy onset is associated with both a decline in investor demand for firm information, as proxied by Google search volume, and stock underreaction to earnings news. Collectively our evidence supports the notion that the association of allergy onset and stock market outcomes may be emerging through a local investor distraction channel. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pantzalis, Christos; Ucar, Erdem</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political donations and political risk in the UK: Evidence from a closely-fought election</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acker, Daniella; Orujov, Ayan; Simpson, Helen
UK regulation discourages corporate political donations but is relatively benign in respect of individual donations. Few UK listed companies make political donations but many more company directors do. We use a unique, hand-collected dataset of political donations to examine whether UK corporate political connections are perceived as being created indirectly via directors' personal donations. Basing our tests on the sensitivity of company returns to opinion polls preceding the 2010 General Election we find that, on average, firms in industries which donate only to the Conservative Party exhibit higher sensitivity to the electoral success of the Conservatives. However, within industries, there is no consistent evidence that the firms which employ directors who make these donations exhibit higher sensitivity than firms which do not. We justify basing our inferences on return sensitivity to polls by confirming that UK domestic political risk, as proxied by opinion poll changes, is priced around General Elections. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acker, Daniella; Orujov, Ayan; Simpson, Helen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subjective financial literacy and retail investors' behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bellofatto, Anthony; D'Hondt, Catherine; De Winne, Rudy
This paper investigates the relationship between subjective financial literacy, i.e. self-reported by investors, and trading behavior. In particular, we use the level of financial knowledge and experience reported in the MiFID tests by retail investors. Such tests are implemented in the EU from the so-called Markets in Financial Instruments Directive since November 2007. We show that subjective financial literacy helps explain cross-sectional variations in retail investors' behavior. Investors who report higher levels of financial literacy seem to invest smarter, even after controlling for gender, age, portfolio value, trading experience and education. They trade more and are less prone to the disposition effect. They tend to concentrate their portfolios on a small set of stocks and achieve diversification through investment funds holding. Their trading behaviors allow them to display higher gross and net returns as well as higher excess Sharpe ratios. Our findings are relevant for both policy making and understanding retail investors' behavior. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bellofatto, Anthony; D'Hondt, Catherine; De Winne, Rudy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the effects of unconventional monetary policy and low interest rates on pension fund risk incentives (Reprinted of JOURNAL OF BANKING AND FINANCE vol 77, pg 35)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubaker, Sabri; Gounopoulos, Dimitrios; Nguyen, Duc Khuong; Paltalidis, Nikos
This study quantifies the effects of persistently low interest rates near to the zero lower bound and unconventional monetary policy on pension fund risk incentives in the United States. Using two structural vector autoregressive (VAR) models and a counterfactual scenario analysis, the results show that monetary policy shocks, as identified by changes in Treasury yields following changes in the central bank's target interest rates, lead to a substantial increase in pension funds' allocation to equity assets. Notably, the shift from bonds to equity securities is greater during the period where the US Federal Reserve launched unconventional monetary policy measures. Additional findings show a positive correlation between pension fund risk-taking, low interest rates and the decline in Treasury yields across both well-funded and underfunded public pension plans, which is thus consistent with a structural risk-shifting incentive. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubaker, Sabri; Gounopoulos, Dimitrios; Nguyen, Duc Khuong; Paltalidis, Nikos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>East or west, home is best: The birthplace bias of individual investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lindblom, Ted; Mavruk, Taylan; Sjogren, Stefan
We examine whether there is birthplace bias in addition to local bias in the portfolio choice of individual investors. We find that, on average, individual investors who live in their birthplace invest almost three times more of their portfolio capital in local firms than other locals. A bias toward birthplace firms persists for a long time after moving elsewhere and increases significantly for "homecomers." Our detailed analysis suggests that individual investors' proximity bias is largely an urban phenomenon, which is explained neither by the information hypothesis nor by the familiarity hypothesis. We find that more sophisticated investors, in terms of portfolio diversification, earn, on average, abnormal portfolio returns, but they do this regardless of their portfolio distortion. Thus, attention ought to be directed toward whether individual investors are financially sophisticated rather than whether they are proximity biased. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lindblom, Ted; Mavruk, Taylan; Sjogren, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Made poorer by choice: Worker outcomes in social security vs. private retirement accounts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahmed, Javed; Barber, Brad M.; Odean, Terrance
Can the freedom to choose how retirement funds are invested leave workers worse off? Via simulation, we document that choice in stock v. bond allocation and type of equity investments in private accounts leads to lower utility and greater risk of income shortfalls relative to private accounts without choice. We also compare private account outcomes to currently promised Social Security benefits to demonstrate that a representative worker (an average wage earner) benefits more from private-account alternatives with or without choice than do most workers. Thus, representative worker outcome should not be used to assess population-wide benefits of private account alternatives. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahmed, Javed; Barber, Brad M.; Odean, Terrance</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It takes two to Tango: Households' response to financial advice and the role of financial literacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stolper, Oscar
Using a unique dataset of over 6000 clients of a German advisory firm who have received rule-based financial advice on basic retirement provision and the insurance of major life risks, we investigate households' response to advice when the risk of product misselling is effectively minimized. Overall, we document a low degree of following standardized financial advice: two thirds of the households under review ignore the advice completely and if they choose to heed it, they tend to follow it only to a relatively little extent. Moreover, we find that standardized financial advice is not able to break up the negative effect of financial literacy on following advisors' recommendations. Instead, even in a setting where the potential for misselling is mitigated, the negative impact of advisees' financial knowledge on their propensity to implement financial advice remains statistically and economically significant for all advisees under review except for the affluent households. Our findings support the notion that an increase in financial literacy leads to a higher confidence in one's own judgment and prompts individuals to use financial advice as just another source of information they process when making their financial decisions. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stolper, Oscar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intergenerational risk sharing under loss averse preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boes, Mark-Jan; Siegmann, Arjen
Individual retirement savings schemes could benefit from risk-sharing mechanisms between generations that take behavioral aspects into account. We introduce a novel risk-sharing mechanism that incorporates nominal loss-aversion in two ways. First, the system avoids out-of-pocket wealth transfers by sharing only a fraction of positive returns over a high-water mark of pension assets. Secondly, payments from a generation insurance fund are targeted at nominal pension shortfalls below a reference point, which mitigates the loss experience at retirement. From a simulation of overlapping generations with stochastic asset returns and interest rates we find that the generation insurance scheme outperforms a pure individual retirement scheme by a significant margin: a similar risk of pension shortfall can be achieved with a contribution rate that is up to 20% lower. The efficiency gains vary with the extent of risk sharing over generations but remain large for sensible parameter values. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boes, Mark-Jan; Siegmann, Arjen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional and individual investors: Saving for old age</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ongena, Steven; Zalewska, Anna
This paper brings together the academic literature on individual and institutional investors in order to understand the nature of difficulties faced by them and set the background for the Special Issue. This introductory article and the papers in the Special Issue contribute to the debate on how to support individuals in their savings commitments and investment decision-making and whether and how institutional investors have fulfilled their role in supporting the development of the funded pension industry. There are three main conclusions: (i) individual investors are not ready for the role that has been assigned to them in the pension industry, (ii) institutional investors are a long way short of establishing healthy relational contracts and trustworthy relationships with their clients, and (iii) more effective regulation may be needed. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ongena, Steven; Zalewska, Anna</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The informational role of options markets: Evidence from FOMC announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Brian; Fung, Scott; Loveland, Robert
This paper examines the informational role of equity options trading around Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) announcements. We find that information contained in option trades prior to FOMC rate change announcements, measured as implied volatility spread, predicts bank stock returns to a greater degree than does volatility spread prior to non-meeting days. We examine U.S. banks due to their interest rate sensitivity; however, we also show that return predictability around rate changes is reliably stronger in all firms, across all industries that are more interest rate sensitive. We find that return predictability is primarily driven by surprise changes in interest rates that occur during meetings with high degrees of information asymmetry. Finally, we document that volatility spread impounds information about FOMC meetings before that information is reflected in stock prices; this effect is significantly greater during surprise events, suggesting that the options market is an important source of informed trading. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Du, Brian; Fung, Scott; Loveland, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry expert directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drobetz, Wolfgang; von Meyerinck, Felix; Oesch, David; Schmid, Markus
We analyze the valuation effect of board industry experience and channels through which industry experience of outside directors relates to firm value. Our analysis shows that firms with more experienced outside directors are valued at a premium compared to firms with less experienced outside directors. Additional analyses, including a quasi-experimental setting based on director deaths, mitigate endogeneity concerns. The association between having directors with more industry experience and higher firm value is more pronounced for firms with larger investment programs, larger cash reserves, and during crises. In contrast, it is weaker in more dynamic industries, i.e., industries that rank high in terms of sales growth, R&amp;D expenditures, merger activities, competitive threat, and product market changes, where the value of previously acquired experience is likely to be diminished. Overall, our findings are consistent with board industry experience being a valuable corporate governance mechanism. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Drobetz, Wolfgang; von Meyerinck, Felix; Oesch, David; Schmid, Markus</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Country transparency and the global transmission of financial shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandao-Marques, Luis; Gelos, Gaston; Melgar, Natalia
This paper considers the role of country-level opacity (the unavailability of information) in amplifying shocks emanating from financial centers. We provide a simple model where, in the presence of ambiguity about fundamentals (uncertainty about the probability distribution of returns), prices in periphery markets react more strongly to signals from the financial center, the more opaque the periphery market is. The second contribution is empirical evidence for more than 60 bond and equity markets in line with this prediction. Increasing the availability of information about public policies, improving accounting standards, and enhancing disclosure by governments and firms can reduce the response of peripheral asset markets to shocks from global financial centers. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brandao-Marques, Luis; Gelos, Gaston; Melgar, Natalia</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public guarantees to SME borrowing. A RDD evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Blasio, Guido; De Mitri, Stefania; D'Ignazio, Alessio; Russo, Paolo Finaldi; Stoppani, Lavinia
The paper evaluates the impact of the guarantees provided by the Italian scheme Fondo di Garanzia on the access to credit for small and medium enterprises. The study exploits the mechanism that assigns the guarantees, which is based on a scoring system to assess eligibility. By using regression discontinuity techniques, the paper finds that, at the threshold between eligible and non-eligible firms, the program has a positive impact on bank loans to firms; however, the scheme has no impact on the interest rate charged by the banks, while it affects positively the likelihood that a firm becomes unable to repay its loans. The guaranteed loans are mostly used to finance working capital. Finally, the paper provides inference for far-from-the-threshold firms. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Blasio, Guido; De Mitri, Stefania; D'Ignazio, Alessio; Russo, Paolo Finaldi; Stoppani, Lavinia</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Turnover threat and CEO risk-taking behavior in the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhongdong; Ebrahim, Alireza
We examine how the threat of turnover affects bank CEOs' risk-taking behavior. Using a sample of 212 U.S. banks from 1995 to 2010, in contrast with prior studies focusing on non-banking firms, we find a non-monotonic relationship between CEO turnover threat and CEO risk-taking behavior in the banking industry. Bank CEOs increase their risk-taking when the perceived turnover threat is moderate but reduce risk-taking when turnover threat is more imminent. This effect tends to concentrate on banks with a majority of independent directors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chen, Zhongdong; Ebrahim, Alireza</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dissecting bidder security returns on payment methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Yuanzhi
The choice of payment methods in M&amp;A deals can affect bidder stock and bond value through two channels simultaneously: signaling and wealth transfer. We propose a method to disentangle these two effects by combining observed bidder stock and bond abnormal returns around deal announcements. Our findings indicate that the negative average bidder stock return in stock deals is mostly caused by signaling, and the negative average bidder bond return in cash deals is mostly due to wealth transfer. We also hypothesize that signaling is related to bidder information uncertainty, while wealth transfer is related to deal significance and bidder default risk. Cross-sectional analysis supports our conjecture. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Yuanzhi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does carbon risk matter in firm dividend policy? Evidence from a quasi-natural experiment in an imputation environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balachandran, Balasingham; Nguyen, Justin Hung
We examine the role of carbon risk in dividend policy, and how its effect varies between imputation (paying franked dividends) and classical (paying unfranked dividends) tax environments in the unique experimental setting in Australia. We find that the probability of paying dividend and dividend payout ratio is lower for firms in the highest-emitting industries (polluters) relative to non-polluters, subsequent to ratification of the Kyoto Protocol. While the post-Kyoto reduction in the likelihood of paying dividend is not significantly different, the reduction in payout ratio is smaller in the imputation environment than classical tax system, highlighting the significance of imputation tax environment only on the impact of carbon risk on dividend payout rather than decision to pay. We further document that the post-Kyoto reduction in dividend payout of polluters is driven by their relative increase in earnings uncertainty. The evidence suggests a causal influence of carbon risk on firm dividend policy. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balachandran, Balasingham; Nguyen, Justin Hung</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposit insurance, bank exit, and spillover effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ji, Yang; Bian, Wenlong; Huang, Yiping
This study resolves a puzzle in the banking literature: why do an increasing number of countries adopt a deposit insurance scheme (DIS) while prior studies have shown that it increases the likelihood of banking crises? Using a dataset of 64 countries over the period 1970-2009, our study shows that the adoption of a DIS is associated with a 2.0-4.7 percentage points higher likelihood of banking crises (the "direct effect"), while it is associated with a 10.1-11.1 percentage points lower likelihood of non-banking financial crises (the "spillover effect"). Since the "spillover effect" is larger than the "direct effect", a DIS actually increases overall financial stability. Additionally, we analyze the mechanisms through which a DIS affects financial crises. First, we highlight the existence of the implicit guarantee and examine its interaction with an explicit DIS. Second, we investigate the substitution effect between banking crises and non-banking crises. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ji, Yang; Bian, Wenlong; Huang, Yiping</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate pass-through since the euro area crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holton, Sarah; d'Acri, Costanza Rodriguez
The financial crisis has been characterised by fragmentation in the transmission of monetary policy, as reflected in the high dispersion in interest rates on bank loans to euro area firms. Heterogeneity in interest rate pricing also emerged within countries, suggesting that macroeconomic differences were not the only driver of dispersion. Using individual bank data for twelve euro area countries covering almost a decade since the start of the crisis, we identify the balance sheet characteristics that contributed to this fragmentation and document the share of the deviation in interest rates from policy rates that is accounted for by each characteristic. Interest rate pass-through heterogeneity is estimated using an error correction framework that accounts for macroeconomic variation and market structure, and includes standard bank characteristics, such as size, capital and liquidity, as well as variables that capture banks' funding access, risk and asset quality. Results show incomplete pass-through of changes in money market rates targeted by the central bank to firms' lending rates. Sovereign bond yields are shown to affect the cost of finance for firms, particularly in stressed countries and market concentration is associated with smaller reductions in lending rates. With regard to bank characteristics, asset impairment leads to a significant decrease in pass-though. Bank size, as a proxy for market power, and reliance on central bank funding affect pass-through for smaller loans, while capital is more significant for larger loans. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Holton, Sarah; d'Acri, Costanza Rodriguez</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks' equity stakes and lending: Evidence from a tax reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Beschwitz, Bastian; Foos, Daniel
We study how a bank's equity stake in a borrowing firm affects lending to that firm. Similar to prior papers, we find a positive association between a bank's equity stake in a borrowing firm and lending to that firm. While such a positive cross-sectional correlation may be due to equity stakes benefiting lending, it may also be driven by endogeneity. To distinguish the two explanations, we study a German tax reform that permitted banks to sell their equity stakes tax-free. After the reform, many banks sold their equity stakes, but did not reduce lending to the firms. This observation is robust to several alternative model specifications, control groups, and time windows. Our findings suggest that banks' equity stakes may be less important for lending than previously thought. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>von Beschwitz, Bastian; Foos, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate social responsibility, investor protection, and cost of equity: A cross-country comparison</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Wolfgang; Mueller, Torbjoern; Rosenbach, David; Salzmann, Astrid
Based on a large international sample, we examine the effects of CSR on the cost of equity under different levels of investor protection. In countries where investor protection is strong (poor), our results show that the cost of equity falls (rises) when a firm invests in CSR. Our findings are robust to alternative variable definitions, sample selection, analyst forecast bias, and various methodological specifications. We also demonstrate that the investor base channel is able to explain different outcomes regarding the relation between CSR and the cost of equity, and we derive implications for both financial practice and public policy. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Breuer, Wolfgang; Mueller, Torbjoern; Rosenbach, David; Salzmann, Astrid</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ponzi schemes and the financial sector: DMG and DRFE in Colombia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hofstetter, Marc; Mejia, Daniel; Rosas, Jose Nicolas; Urrutia, Miguel
We use a novel dataset to estimate, for the first time in the literature, the effects of Ponzi schemes on the formal financial sector. DMG and DRFE, two Ponzi schemes that were shut down by the Colombian government in November 2008, had over half a million customers, who invested funds corresponding to 1.2% of Colombia's annual GDP. We find that pyramid costumers' obtained more loans from the financial sector and their credit standings were better than those in the respective control groups while the schemes were operating. Afterwards, their loan stocks started to decrease and their ratings with the banking sector deteriorated. Prior to November 2008, deposits in the financial sector fell more in the municipalities more affected by the schemes. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hofstetter, Marc; Mejia, Daniel; Rosas, Jose Nicolas; Urrutia, Miguel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A reinforced urn process modeling of recovery rates and recovery times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Dan; Cirillo, Pasquale
Answering a major demand in modern credit risk management, we propose a nonparametric survival approach for the modeling of the recovery rate and the recovery time of a defaulted counterparty, by introducing what we call the Recovery Reinforced Urn Process, a special type of combinatorial stochastic process. The new model allows for the elicitation and exploitation of prior knowledge and experts' judgements, and for the constant update of this information over time, as soon as new data become available. We show how to use it to perform Bayesian nonparametric prediction about the recovered amounts and the (total) recovery time of a series of defaulted exposures. An application to real data is provided using the Single Family Loan-Level Dataset by Freddie Mac. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cheng, Dan; Cirillo, Pasquale</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Curbing corporate debt bias: Do limitations to interest deductibility work?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hebous, Shafik; De Mooij, Ruud
Tax provisions favoring corporate debt over equity finance ("debt bias") are widely recognized as a risk to financial stability. This paper explores whether and how thin-capitalization rules, which restrict interest deductibility beyond a certain amount, affect corporate debt ratios and mitigate corporate default risk. We find that rules targeted at related party borrowing (the majority of today's rules) have no significant impact on debt bias, as they do not affect third-party borrowing. These rules also have no effect on broader indicators of firm corporate distress. Rules applying to all debt, in contrast, turn out to be effective: the presence of such a rule reduces the debt-asset ratio in an average company by 5 percentage points; and they reduce the probability of a firm being in financial distress by 5 percent. Debt ratios are found to be more responsive to thin capitalization rules in industries characterized by a high share of tangible assets. (C) 2018 International Monetary Fund. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hebous, Shafik; De Mooij, Ruud</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction-special issue on commodity and energy markets in the Journal of Banking and Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roncoroni, Andrea; Prokopczuk, Marcel; Ronn, Ehud I.
nan</description><author>Roncoroni, Andrea; Prokopczuk, Marcel; Ronn, Ehud I.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic corporate risk management: Motivations and real implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dionne, Georges; Gueyie, Jean-Pierre; Mnasri, Mohamed
We investigate the dynamics of corporate hedging programs used by US oil producers and examine the effects of hedging maturity choice on firm value. We find evidence of a concave relationship between hedging maturity and the likelihood of financial distress and oil spot prices. We further investigate the motivations of the early termination of outstanding hedging contracts. Using the essential heterogeneity approach, we evaluate the causal effects of hedging maturity on firm value. Marginal firm value increases with short-term hedging maturity. The causal effects vary across oil producers with different hidden attributes. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dionne, Georges; Gueyie, Jean-Pierre; Mnasri, Mohamed</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The balance sheet effects of oil market shocks: An industry level analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>ElFayoumi, Khalid
The paper estimates the dynamic impact of structural oil market shocks on the balance sheet of US firms, using industry level data covering manufacturing, trade and mining sectors. For manufacturing firms, findings indicate that an unexpected disruption in oil supply that raises oil prices by 1% lowers firm profits by 1.3% on impact. On the other hand, profits rise by 0.39% in response to the same increase in the price of oil, when it is driven by a positive movement in the global demand for oil, and by 0.79% after an unexpected surge in speculative oil demand. The positive balance sheet effect of speculative oil shocks on the manufacturing sector contrasts their negative effect on global economic activity. An explanation follows from the industry level analysis, which suggests that speculation in the oil market creates a ripple effect in downstream industries and raises inventory demand for petroleum and chemical products. In contrast to its secondary role in explaining historical variations in the price of oil and profits in trade and mining sectors, oil supply shocks are found to have been the dominant oil market innovations in driving fluctuations in manufacturing firms' profits. The analysis also finds a limited response of production costs to exogenous changes in the oil price, disputing the classic notion that the cost share of oil in an industry determines its level of exposure to oil market shocks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>ElFayoumi, Khalid</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal forward trading and battery control under renewable electricity generation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hinz, Juri; Yee, Jeremy
The increased market penetration of renewable energy sources and the rapid development of electric battery storage technologies yield a potential for reducing electricity price volatility while maintaining stability of the power grid. This work presents an algorithmic approach to control battery levels and forward positions to optimally manage power output fluctuations caused by intermittent renewable energy generation. This paper will also explore the effect of battery technology on the firm's optimal trading behaviour in the electricity spot market. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hinz, Juri; Yee, Jeremy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate transparency and reserve management: Evidence from US property-liability insurance companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Sangyong; Lai, Gene C.; Ho, Chia-Ling
Using a sample of US publicly traded property-liability insurers, we examine the effect of corporate transparency on earnings management. We find that a higher level of corporate transparency is associated with more conservative loss-reserves estimation. Our evidence shows that the positive effect of corporate transparency on insurers' reserves-estimate conservatism is more pronounced for insurers that are smaller and have more diversified lines of business and that certain board characteristics-such as being smaller, meeting more frequently, and having a higher percentage of independent directors-can restrain the inadequate reserves management of less transparent US publicly traded property-liability insurers. We also provide evidence that additional regulatory mandates to seek greater transparency in the Sarbanes-Oxley Act may be redundant, given the existing regulations in the property-liability insurance industry. Finally, we find insurers' conservative reserve estimates were more pronounced during the 2008-2009 financial crisis. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Han, Sangyong; Lai, Gene C.; Ho, Chia-Ling</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Twitter myth revisited: Intraday investor sentiment, Twitter activity and individual-level stock return volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Behrendt, Simon; Schmidt, Alexander
Taking an intraday perspective, we study the dynamics of individual-level stock return volatility, measured by absolute 5-minute returns, and Twitter sentiment and activity. After accounting for the intraday periodicity in absolute returns, we discover some statistically significant co-movements of intraday volatility and information from stock-related Tweets for all constituents of the Dow Jones Industrial Average. However, economically, the effects are of negligible magnitude and out-of-sample forecast performance is not improved when including Twitter sentiment and activity as exogenous variables. From a practical point of view, we find that high-frequency Twitter information is not particularly useful for highly active investors with access to such data for intraday volatility assessment and forecasting when considering individual-level stocks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Behrendt, Simon; Schmidt, Alexander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial development and the occurrence of banking crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mathonnat, Clement; Minea, Alexandru
We perform an in-depth analysis of the effect of different dimensions of financial development on the occurrence of banking crises. Horse-race estimations carried out on a large dataset of 113 banking crises in 112 countries reveal that the growth of M3/GDP and the level of banks' Credits/Deposits increase the occurrence of banking crises, while the growth and sometimes the volatility of the ratio of banks' assets to the sum of banks' and the Central Bank's assets decrease it. In addition, we do not find a significant effect of banks' Credits/GDP. Finally, we unveil heterogeneities related to nonlinearities in the effect of financial development, the time span for the pre-crisis dynamics of financial development, and the level of economic development. Our results suggest that only some dimensions of financial development are significantly associated with the occurrence of banking crises. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mathonnat, Clement; Minea, Alexandru</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price discovery in euro area sovereign credit markets and the ban on naked CDS</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gyntelberg, Jacob; Hordahl, Peter; Ters, Kristyna; Urban, Joerg
The sovereign debt crisis in the euro area saw credit spreads on sovereign bonds and credit default swaps (CDS) surge for a number of member states. The rise in sovereign yields was accompanied by a significant increase in sovereign CDS market activity. This pattern raised concerns that destabilising speculation via outright short-selling of CDS (so-called 'naked CDS') was behind the increase in bond yields. In response, policy-makers introduced a ban on naked CDS trading. We investigate the effect of the ban on the price discovery process of sovereign credit risk, contrasting results for the post-ban period with those obtained prior to the ban. We use intraday data on sovereign CDS and bonds across a number of euro area countries. Our first main finding is that the CDS market dominates the bond market in terms of price discovery. That is, CDS premia in most cases adjust quicker to reflect new information than bond spreads. This result holds also when taking into account transaction costs. Our second main finding is that the ban on short-selling did not alter price discovery dynamics or reduce the efficiency of the market. Finally, we find that prior to the ban, CDS spreads were persistently higher than bond credit spreads, even after controlling for transaction costs. This points to the presence of market frictions that limit the ability of arbitrage forces to fully close pricing gaps between the two markets. However, these pricing discrepancies were in many cases largely eliminated following the introduction of the ban. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gyntelberg, Jacob; Hordahl, Peter; Ters, Kristyna; Urban, Joerg</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A new risk factor based on equity duration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mohrschladt, Hannes; Nolte, Sven
We introduce a new risk factor linking a firms equity duration to investment opportunity risk. Low-duration firms generate short-run cash flows and face strong reinvestment risk. High-duration firms have long-run cash flows and their present value increases when discount rates decrease as a result of a deteriorating investment environment. Our empirical analysis reveals a significant return premium of low-duration stocks, confirming that investors charge a risk premium for stocks with returns that are positively related to the investment environment. Our newly introduced risk factor carries significant risk premiums in cross-sectional asset pricing tests. These premiums are robust to including further risk factors and a variety of different test specifications. Notably, our duration risk factor retains high explanatory power on the cross-section of stock returns in a model including direct measurement of the investment environment via state variable innovations. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mohrschladt, Hannes; Nolte, Sven</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond covenants and institutional blockholding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Xinde; Zhou, Simiao
We document a significant and positive relation between institutional block ownership and the number of bond covenants. This finding is robust to different measures of blockholding, alternative regression models, and endogeneity considerations. The positive association between blockholding and covenants is stronger for active as well as for short-term blockholders, suggesting that covenants are employed ex ante to mitigate incentive conflicts between shareholders and bondholders. While both covenants and blockholding are positively related to borrowing costs, their interaction implies that covenants attenuate the increase in borrowing costs resulting from more concentrated block ownership. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhang, Xinde; Zhou, Simiao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Covariance forecasting in equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Symitsi, Efthymia; Symeonidis, Lazaros; Kourtis, Apostolos; Markellos, Raphael
We compare the performance of popular covariance forecasting models in the context of a portfolio of major European equity indices. We find that models based on high-frequency data offer a clear advantage in terms of statistical accuracy. They also yield more theoretically consistent predictions from an empirical asset pricing perspective, and, lead to superior out-of-sample portfolio performance. Overall, a parsimonious Vector Heterogeneous Autoregressive (VHAR) model that involves lagged daily, weekly and monthly realised covariances achieves the best performance out of the competing models. A promising new simple hybrid covariance estimator is developed that exploits option-implied information and high-frequency data while adjusting for the volatility riskpremium. Relative model performance does not change during the global financial crisis, or, if a different forecast horizon, or, intraday sampling frequency is employed. Finally, our evidence remains robust when we consider an alternative sample of U.S. stocks. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Symitsi, Efthymia; Symeonidis, Lazaros; Kourtis, Apostolos; Markellos, Raphael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social stigma and executive compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Novak, Jiri; Bilinski, Pawel
We document that executives working at firms perceived negatively in light of social norms, such as tobacco, gambling and alcohol, earn a significant compensation premium. The premium compensates for personal costs executives bear due to their employer's negative public perception and include: (i) a reduced likelihood these CEOs will serve as directors on other firms' boards, which associates with lower executives' social status, and (ii) impaired job mobility as employers shun stigmatized executives. The compensation premium is not explained by higher managerial skill required in firms we investigate, higher employment contract risk, political capital, litigation risk, or differences in corporate governance quality, and robust to endogeneity concerns. Our results highlight the significant impact job-related social stigma has on executive compensation. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Novak, Jiri; Bilinski, Pawel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Smiling twice: The Heston plus plus model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pacati, Claudio; Pompa, Gabriele; Reno, Roberto
We recommend the addition of a deterministic displacement to multi-factor affine models to calibrate and hedge SPX and VIX derivatives jointly. The proposed model, labeled Heston++, calibrates both markets with an average relative error (on quoted implied volatilities over two years of data) of 2%, and a maximum relative error of 4%, without additional computational costs with respect to traditional affine benchmarks. Hedging performance on both markets is also drastically improved. The displacement can be interpreted as a volatility push-up reflecting expectations about a (risk-neutral) lower bound on forward VIX dynamics. Our empirical results document substantial correlation between the dynamics of the displacement and the variance risk premium, and still provide strong support for the presence of both price/volatility negatively correlated co-jumps and idiosyncratic jumps in the volatility dynamics, even when the displacement is added. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pacati, Claudio; Pompa, Gabriele; Reno, Roberto</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disciplinary directors: Evidence from the appointments of outside directors who have fired CEOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Jay; Nguyen, Tu
By examining board appointments of outside directors who have previously fired a CEO, we study how directors' willingness to take disciplinary actions is related to a firm's performance and risk-taking. Such directors ('disciplinary directors') appear to benefit firms with weak monitoring, but hurt firms in innovative industries. Firms appointing a disciplinary director subsequently exhibit lower idiosyncratic risk, leverage, and R&amp;D expense, make fewer acquisitions, and are more likely to replace poorly performing CEOs. Overall, disciplinary directors appear to influence managerial behavior and shareholder wealth. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cai, Jay; Nguyen, Tu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A clustering approach and a rule of thumb for risk aggregation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Di Lascio, F. Marta L.; Giammusso, Davide; Puccetti, Giovanni
The problem of establishing reliable estimates or bounds for the (T)VaR of a joint risk portfolio is a relevant subject in connection with the computation of total economic capital in the Basel regulatory framework for the finance sector as well as with the Solvency regulations for the insurance sector. In the computation of total economic capital, a financial institution faces a considerable amount of model uncertainty related to the estimation of the interdependence amongst the marginal risks. In this paper, we propose to apply a clustering procedure in order to partition a risk portfolio into independent subgroups of positively dependent risks. Based on available data, the portfolio partition so obtained can be statistically validated and allows for a reduction of capital and the corresponding model uncertainty. We illustrate the proposed methodology in a simulation study and two case studies considering an Operational and a Market Risk portfolio. A rule of thumb stems from the various examples proposed: in a mathematical model where the risk portfolio is split into independent subsets with comonotonic dependence within, the smallest VaR-based capital estimate (at the high regulatory probability levels typically used) is produced by assuming that the infinite-mean risks are comonotonic and the finite-mean risks are independent. The largest VaR estimate is instead generated by obtaining the maximum number of independent infinite-mean sums. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Di Lascio, F. Marta L.; Giammusso, Davide; Puccetti, Giovanni</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross-section of expected stock returns in the property liability insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben Ammar, Semir; Eling, Martin; Milidonis, Andreas
We conduct a comprehensive asset pricing analysis for the U.S. property/liability insurance industry using monthly data from 1988 to 2015. We find that state-of-the-art models such as the Fama and French (2015) five-factor model cannot explain the returns of property/liability insurance stocks in a satisfactory way. We adapt the model proposed by Adrian et al. (2015) for financial institutions and define an insurance-specific five-factor asset pricing model (INS5), which can explain the cross-section of property/liability insurance-stock returns better than competing models. The priced factors are the market return, the book-to-market ratio, return on equity, short-term reversal, and the spread between the property/liability insurance sector and the market return. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ben Ammar, Semir; Eling, Martin; Milidonis, Andreas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency problems in firms with an even number of directors: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Wen; Luo, Jin-hui
To avoid a tie in voting, most boards have an odd number of directors. We argue that boards with an even number of directors are more likely to be weak monitors because of inefficient decision making and being captured by controlling shareholders. Consistent with this argument, we find that in China boards with an even number of directors have fewer meetings and are more likely to have board members absent from board meetings. Firms with an even number of directors have more tunnelling through intercorporate loans and related party transactions, lower financial reporting quality and higher incidence of accounting irregularities. This evidence is stronger in firms with weaker external monitoring and for directors with weaker incentives to monitor. Finally, we show that firms with an even number of directors are associated with lower market valuation of equity. Our results suggest that corporate boards with an even number of directors in emerging markets are associated with more agency problems. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Wen; Luo, Jin-hui</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hidden effects of bank recapitalizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beccalli, Elena; Frantz, Pascal; Lenoci, Francesca
Given the importance of capital regulation in the banking industry, how and why a bank's behavior reacts to a recapitalization has profound consequences. To this end, we investigate the effects of 306 seasoned equity offerings (SEOs) conducted by listed European banks between 2002 and 2014. We use propensity score matching and find that SEOs lead to asset expansion as opposed to any deleveraging. Further, we find a decrease in lending in the short-term followed by a subsequent increase, a reduction in profitability, and an increase in systemic risk. Regulators might not have fully considered this last negative externality when they imposed the tougher Basel III capital requirements. The effects of SEOs strongly depend on the reasons behind the recapitalizations. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beccalli, Elena; Frantz, Pascal; Lenoci, Francesca</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial illiteracy and mortgage refinancing decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bajo, Emanuele; Barbi, Massimiliano
We analyze the effect of an exogenous shock to the Italian mortgage market, where a reform has abolished prepayment fees and simplified mortgage refinancing, making it a virtually cost-free decision for households. This law, along with the considerable drop in market interest rates, has generated important gains for fixed-rate borrowers, which we quantify at up to 15% of the principal balance. Nevertheless, only about 13% of borrowers have locked in this opportunity. We study the relationship between this sluggish behavior and their level of financial literacy. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bajo, Emanuele; Barbi, Massimiliano</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do firms respond to empty creditor holdout in distressed exchanges?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayanan, Rajesh; Uzmanoglu, Cihan
Empty creditors-bondholders hedged with Credit Default Swaps (CDSs)-face incentives to holdout from "Distressed Exchanges" (DEs) of debt because the CDS hedge alters their payoffs to favor bankruptcy. We show using detailed data on DEs that firms respond to this holdout problem by targeting junior bondholders who are more likely to tender than senior bondholders. Furthermore, we show that doing so allows them to successfully reduce debt through the DE and avoid bankruptcy. Our evidence underscores the importance of the firm's response to the holdout problem in understanding the role of empty creditors in distress resolution. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Narayanan, Rajesh; Uzmanoglu, Cihan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of interest rates with housing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vergara-Alert, Carles
This paper develops a general equilibrium model to study the link between the amount of capital invested in housing assets and the term structure of interest rates. In the model, the production of housing assets is irreversible and housing assets can be used as collateral for borrowing funds. Agents' decisions about consumption and investments in housing and non-housing assets generate a time-varying market price of risk that drives the dynamics of the term structure. The calibration to U.S. data using the simulated method of moments technique captures the dynamics of consumption, and the short- and long-term interest rates. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vergara-Alert, Carles</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysts' reinitiations of coverage and market underreaction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Philippot, Aurelien
I study the informativeness of reinitiations of coverage, which are defined as the resumption of coverage of a stock by a broker after more than six months of interruption. Reinitiations are associated with a significant short-term market response, in particular when the same analyst is assigned to the stock. However, I show that this market response is incomplete. Interestingly, the price patterns that follow the issuance of regular upgrades of recommendation and reinitiations differ significantly. Prices adjust quickly after a regular upgrade, while reinitiations are followed by a sustained price increase in the following six months, which does not revert during the following two years. I assess the economic magnitude of this initial underreaction by setting up a trading strategy. I show that reinitiations of coverage are the only type of recommendation that delivers significant positive abnormal returns after transaction costs with a three- and six-month investment horizon. I study and reject several candidate explanations in relation to momentum, and PEAD. Then, I investigate an information/superior ability hypothesis. I find that reinitiations are a more accurate signal than other recommendation types. Besides, the earnings conference call transcripts show that those analysts were able to maintain active relationships with the firms, even during the interruption of coverage. Their activity level is associated with more informative reinitiations of coverage. In particular, their participation rank in conference calls, which can be seen as a proxy for ability and proximity to the management appears to be a strong predictor of the drift after the reinitiation takes place. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Philippot, Aurelien</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund herding and stock price crashes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deng, Xin; Hung, Shengmin; Qiao, Zheng
We investigate the impact of mutual fund herding behaviours on stock price crashes. There are competing hypotheses with respect to how investors' herding behaviours are associated with information processing. Our empirical evidence shows that mutual fund herding is associated with a poor information environment and low disclosure quality. More importantly, mutual fund herding amplifies stock price crash risk afterwards. The main finding is concentrated on buy-herding rather than sell-herding. To mitigate the endogeneity concern, we use the 2004 SEC mutual fund disclosure regulation change as an exogenous shock and the results hold. We further use propensity score matching to alleviate the impact of information asymmetry. Finally, additional analysis reveals that our results are not driven by the price impact hypothesis. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Deng, Xin; Hung, Shengmin; Qiao, Zheng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impacts of asymmetric information and short sales on the illiquidity risk premium in the stock option market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Zih-Ying; Chang, Chuang-Chang; Wang, Yaw-Huei
The illiquidity risk premium hypothesis implies the existence of a positive relation between illiquidity in the option market and option returns. Based on numerous studies within the extant literature examining the roles of informed traders in the option markets, we explore how information asymmetry and short sales affect the illiquidity risk premium hypothesis. We find that the illiquidity risk premium is higher for both call and put options of those firms with higher information asymmetry, which is particularly driven by small firms. We also find that it is higher for put (call) options of those stocks with lower (higher) short-sale supply (demand). (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Zih-Ying; Chang, Chuang-Chang; Wang, Yaw-Huei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio selection with proportional transaction costs and predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mei, Xiaoling; Nogales, Francisco J.
We consider the portfolio selection problem for a multiperiod investor who seeks to maximize her utility of intermediate consumption facing multiple risky-assets and proportional transaction costs in the presence of return predictability. With the presence of transaction costs, this problem is very difficult to solve even numerically due to the curse of dimensionality. In this paper, we propose first several suboptimal rebalancing policies that are based on optimizing simple quadratic programs for a mean-variance investor who faces proportional transaction costs. Then, we propose some feasible rebalancing and consumption policies that can be easily computed even for many risky assets, for an investor with power utility, based on the proposed suboptimal policies. Finally, we show how to compute upper bounds and use them to study how the certainty equivalent losses of consumption, associated when using the approximate policies, depend on different problem parameters. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Mei, Xiaoling; Nogales, Francisco J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real estate as a common risk factor in bank stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carmichael, Benoit; Coen, Alain
This article investigates the potential role of real estate risk in the pricing of US bank stocks from February 1990 to December 2015. Generalized method of moments estimates of conditional multifactor models are provided. The real estate risk is proxied by the return of an investment strategy that is short on low-leverage real estate investment trust (REIT) assets and long on high-leverage REIT assets. We group banks into portfolios based on their market capitalization, real estate loans as a proportion of total assets, and book-to-market ratios. The results suggest that the real estate premium is a relevant risk factor in bank stocks returns. For instance, we find that a 100-basis-point increase to the real estate premium increases returns by 15.8 to 20.1 basis points for portfolios grouped by market capitalization. This conclusion remains when other oft-cited bank risk factors are considered, including small-minus-big, high-minus-low and the return on equity of the financial sector. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carmichael, Benoit; Coen, Alain</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inter-market competition and bank loan spreads: Evidence from the securities offering reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gustafson, Matthew T.
I provide evidence of a new mechanism by which access to public securities mitigates the bank hold-up problem and reduces loan spreads - it increases a borrower's bargaining power vis-a-vis a lender by offering a bank loan substitute. Difference-in-differences results indicate that loan spreads decline following legislation that makes public securities more attractive, but only when public securities represent a credible substitute for the bank loan (i.e., for term loans taken out by credit rated borrowers). Spreads on revolving lines of credit, which are more complementary with public securities, increase. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gustafson, Matthew T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A prudential stable funding requirement and monetary policy in a small open economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacob, Punnoose; Munro, Anella
The Basel Ill net stable funding requirement, introduced in January 2018, requires banks to use a minimum share of long-term wholesale funding and deposits to fund their assets. A similar regulation has been in place in New Zealand since 2010. We introduce the stable funding requirement (SFR) into an open-economy DSGE model featuring a banking sector with richly-specified liabilities, and estimate the model for New Zealand. We then evaluate the impact of the new prudential instrument on monetary policy trade-offs. A higher steady-state SFR level amplifies the effects of shocks to the spread on long-term bond financing in the banking sector, adding to macroeconomic volatility conditional on these shocks. However, the SFR plays a passive role in the transmission of all other shocks to the real economy. Hence in the overall picture, the monetary policy trade-off between inflation stabilisation and output stabilisation, is only slightly worsened by the SFR. We note that the trade-off can be improved when monetary policy responds systematically to credit growth. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacob, Punnoose; Munro, Anella</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer preferences for payment methods: Role of discounts and surcharges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stavins, Joanna
We use new data from the 2015 Diary of Consumer Payment Choice to analyze the role of consumer preferences for specific payment instruments, and how price discounts and surcharges based on payment method affect payment instrument choice. We test whether consumer demand for payment instruments is price elastic, namely whether consumers are likely to deviate from their preferred methods in order to get a discount or to avoid a surcharge. We find that the occurrence of price incentives is low, but that given cash discounts, the probability that a cash transaction is conducted by a consumer who prefers other payment methods increased by 19.2 percent, after controlling for merchant category and dollar value of the transaction. Payment method choice is affected very strongly by consumer individual preferences, but steering by merchants may be effective under some circumstances. Both merchants' reluctance to offer price discounts and consumers' limited response to them lead to the low observed occurrences of such incentives. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stavins, Joanna</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distilling liquidity costs from limit order books</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amaya, Diego; Filbien, Jean-Yves; Okou, Cedric; Roch, Alexandre F.
This paper proposes a method to compute ex-ante trading costs at the intraday level from limit order books. Using nearly 500 of the largest traded companies in the NYSE ArcaBook, we show that these costs have nontrivial intraday dynamics, are negatively related to volume and positively related to volatility. When ex-ante trading costs are incorporated into price impact specifications, the results show that this measure provides relevant information about price changes of the market at a high frequency level. Our evidence suggest that ex-ante trading costs constitute a new source of information for the study of intraday liquidity. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amaya, Diego; Filbien, Jean-Yves; Okou, Cedric; Roch, Alexandre F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>About the fear of reputational loss: Social trading and the disposition effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pelster, Matthias; Hofmann, Annette
This article studies the relationship between giving financial advice and the disposition effect in an online trading environment. Our empirical findings suggest that leader traders are more susceptible to the disposition effect than investors who are not being followed by any other trader. Using a differencein-differences approach, we show that becoming a first-time financial advisor increases the disposition effect. This finding holds for investors who engage in foreign exchange trading and for investors who trade stocks and stock market indices. The increased behavioral bias may be explained by leaders feeling responsible to their followers, by a fear of losing followers when admitting a poor investment decision, or by an attempt by newly appointed leaders to manage their social image and self-image. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pelster, Matthias; Hofmann, Annette</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do capital markets value corporate social responsibility? Evidence from seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, Zhi-Yuan; Chen, Carl R.; Tseng, Yen-Jung
We explore whether firms' corporate social responsibility (CSR) activities provide added value to capital market participants through seasoned equity offerings (SEOs). SEOs represent cleaner exogenous activity alleviating the reverse causality issue plaguing many prior studies examining the relation between firm performance and CSR. Using a large sample of U.S. SEOs, we find high-CSR issuers experience fewer negative market reactions to SEO announcements. We also show ethical issuers have incentive to provide extensive and informative disclosures, which mitigate the degree of information asymmetry, thereby decreasing SEO underpricing. Among CSR categories, we find issuers engaging in community and environmental CSR activities and improving the rights of women and minorities are more effective at reducing SEO negative announcement returns and underpricing. Our findings remain robust after controlling for possible self-selection bias and endogeneity problems. Overall, our findings support the stakeholder value maximization view of stakeholder theory and ethical theory. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Feng, Zhi-Yuan; Chen, Carl R.; Tseng, Yen-Jung</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor law and innovation revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Bill B.; Kim, Incheol; Wang, Bin; Zhang, Zhengyi
This paper examines the impact of changes in job security on corporate innovation in 20 non-U.S. OECD countries. Using a difference-in-differences approach, we provide firm-level evidence that the enhancement of labor protection has a negative impact on innovation. We then discuss possible channels and find that employee-friendly labor reforms induce inventor shirking and a distortion in labor flow. Further investigation reveals that the negative relation is more pronounced in (1) firms that heavily rely on external financing, (2) firms that have high R&amp;D intensity, (3) manufacturing industries, and (4) civil-law countries. Our micro-level evidence indicates that enhanced employment protection impedes corporate innovation. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Francis, Bill B.; Kim, Incheol; Wang, Bin; Zhang, Zhengyi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default probabilities of privately held firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duan, Jin-Chuan; Kim, Baeho; Kim, Woojin; Shin, Donghwa
We estimate the term structures of the default probabilities for private firms using data consisting of 1759 default events from 29,894 firms between 1999 and 2014. Each firm's default likelihood is characterized by a forward intensity model employing macro risk factors and firm-specific attributes. As private firms do not have traded stock prices, we devise a methodology to obtain a public-firm equivalent distance-to-default by projection that references the distance-to-defaults of public firms with comparable attributes. The fitted model provides accurate multi-period forecasts of defaults, leading to both economically and statistically significant benefits over benchmark models. The reported interest rates charged to private firms are reflective of the estimated default term structure. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duan, Jin-Chuan; Kim, Baeho; Kim, Woojin; Shin, Donghwa</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial distress, refinancing, and debt structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dudley, Evan; Yin, Qie Ellie
We examine changes in debt structure when firms experience financial distress. At these points in time, firms refinance and undergo substantial changes in priority structure. Specifically, we find that firms diversify their priority structure relative to its pre-distress composition. We show, using a simple model, that these changes are the firm's optimal response to its joint liquidity and investment needs. Additional predictions on the yield spreads of bonds issued to meet the firm's liquidity needs are also supported by the data. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dudley, Evan; Yin, Qie Ellie</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sector spillovers in credit markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collet, Jerome; Ielpo, Florian
Cross-sector volatility spillovers can both threaten the financial stability of credit markets and the diversification of a credit bond portfolio. In this article, we measure cross-sector volatility spillovers, casting light on their intensity in the US-denominated investment grade bond universe. We find that volatility spillovers are high in the US credit market and that the insurance, goods and energy sectors have been net contributors to these shocks over the 1996-2017 period. A structural analysis of the spillover history based on a three-regime multivariate VAR Markov Switching model is then proposed. It highlights that with different volatility regimes come different volatility spillover structures: the insurance and goods sectors are volatility spillover sources during crisis periods. However, according to our estimates a large portion of spillovers are non-recurring and therefore difficult to anticipate. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Collet, Jerome; Ielpo, Florian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differences in options investors' expectations and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andreou, Panayiotis C.; Kagkadis, Anastasios; Philip, Dennis; Tuneshev, Ruslan
We provide strong evidence that the dispersion of individual stock options trading volume across moneynesses (IDISP) contains valuable information about future stock returns. Stocks with high IDISP consistently underperform those with low IDISP by more than 1% per month. In line with the idea that IDISP reflects dispersion in investors' beliefs, we find that the negative IDISP-return relationship is particularly pronounced around earnings announcements, in high sentiment periods and among stocks that exhibit relatively high short-selling impediments. Moreover, the IDISP effect is highly persistent and robustly distinct from the effects of a large array of previously documented cross-sectional return predictors. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andreou, Panayiotis C.; Kagkadis, Anastasios; Philip, Dennis; Tuneshev, Ruslan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizational form, business strategies and the demise of demutualized building societies in the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shiwakoti, Radha K.; Iqbal, Abdullah; Funnell, Warwick
This paper examines and compares the performance and operating behavior of demutualized building societies (DBS) over the period of 1987-2007 relative to mutual building societies and major retail banks in the UK. We find significant differences in their operating behavior over this period and show that the operating behavior varies with the form of ownership. We also investigate the potential causes of the failure of all DBS in the UK. Our findings show significant changes in the funding and lending strategies of DBS which expose them to higher risk. We also find a strained capital formation and deteriorating capital base of DBS in the post-conversion period. Our results suggest that changes in the business model, diminished capital base and, in part, failing to get all the necessary funding from the wholesale market at the time of the financial crisis of 2007-08 contributed to the demise of a once a successful financial institution in the UK. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shiwakoti, Radha K.; Iqbal, Abdullah; Funnell, Warwick</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and performance of bonds sponsored by private equity firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Xiaping; Chan, Konan; Kahle, Kathleen
The bond market is an important source of financing for Private Equity (PE) sponsored transactions. Using the methodology suggested by Bessembinder et al. (2009), we find that PE-sponsored bonds under perform comparable benchmarks. This is especially true for bonds with credit ratings below investment grade and those issued in hot bond markets. Furthermore, bonds sponsored by more experienced PE groups (PEGs) underperform bonds associated with less experienced PE groups, while bonds backed by investment bank-affiliated PEGs underperform bonds sponsored by other PEGs. These findings highlight the risk and return relationship in the high-yield bond market related to leveraged buyouts (LBOs) and PEGs. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cao, Xiaping; Chan, Konan; Kahle, Kathleen</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund performance, management teams, and boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, John C.; Nishikawa, Takeshi; Rao, Ramesh P.
The recent surge in the use of team-managed funds in the mutual fund industry suggests that the benefits of team management might outweigh its costs. However, extant empirical evidence is not consistent with the view that team-managed funds generate superior returns relative to individual-managed funds. We argue that the benefits of team management are likely to be manifested in the presence of strong board monitoring because the potential free-rider problems within team-managed funds are alleviated. Our findings, that smaller boards and boards with a higher proportion of independent directors are positively associated with performance in team but not individual-managed funds, are consistent with this view. Our results suggest that in team-managed fund structures, where the potential free-riding problems exist, the presence of strong board monitoring improves fund performance. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, John C.; Nishikawa, Takeshi; Rao, Ramesh P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Control thyself: Self-control failure and household wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biljanovska, Nina; Palligkinis, Spyros
We examine the relationship between self-control and household wealth. Building on literature in psychology, we take a more comprehensive approach to the concept of self-control and posit that it consists of three ingredients: planning, monitoring, and commitment to pre-set goals. We build a measure which combines those three components and can be computed using a standard representative survey. We find that self-control failure is strongly associated with different household net wealth measures and with self-assessed financial distress. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Biljanovska, Nina; Palligkinis, Spyros</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing convertible bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Batten, Jonathan A.; Khaw, Karren Lee-Hwei; Young, Martin R.
Convertible bonds are an important segment of the corporate bond market although their pricing is compromised by the presence of complex option features and difficulty in measuring the risk factors needed as inputs to standard valuation models. Using a unique sample of pure U.S. convertible bonds, devoid of other optionality, we show that underpricing is affected mainly by the degree of underlying asset volatility and liquidity. Convertible bonds with a greater debt component (more credit sensitive), longer time to maturity and lower quality credit ratings are also found to be more underpriced. The global financial crisis (GFC) is an episode with high-underlying asset volatility and one subject to short-selling constraints. During this period there was deep convertible bond discounting, which highlights the importance of market conditions and the temporal, rather than systematic, nature of the pricing errors. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Batten, Jonathan A.; Khaw, Karren Lee-Hwei; Young, Martin R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employment protection and corporate cash holdings: Evidence from China's labor contract law</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cui, Chenyu; John, Kose; Pang, Jiaren; Wu, Haibin
Employment protection increases labor adjustment costs and hence the expected costs of financial distress for labor-intensive firms. It follows that these firms are likely to increase their cash holdings to reduce the risk of financial distress when employment protection is strengthened. Consistent with this prediction, we find that labor-intensive firms in China significantly increase their cash holdings following the enactment of China's Labor Contract Law; other contemporaneous shocks do not seem to drive the finding. We also find that two events prior to the enactment that increase the likelihood of enacting the law have a similar effect. Further analysis shows that the impact of the law is concentrated on areas with strict law enforcement, state-owned enterprises, and industries that employ large numbers of migrant workers. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cui, Chenyu; John, Kose; Pang, Jiaren; Wu, Haibin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticorruption regulation and firm value: Evidence from a shock of mandated resignation of directors in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Yongxin
China's broad anti-corruption campaign includes a regulation that requires bureaucrats to resign from director positions in listed companies. Using this particular event to test the effect of the anticorruption regulation, we find that this regulation costs firms with banned directors on average 4%. This cost cannot be explained by the typical cost of losing a director or by damage from a political vendetta conducted by the leadership. We further show that the anticorruption regulation impedes firm value not only through political connections but also through the anticorruption disincentive, the incentive to act passively for fear of being accused of corruption. Finally, affected firms reduce their investments, hire more employees and have poor performance afterwards. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xu, Yongxin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public health insurance and household portfolio Choices: Unravelling financial "Side Effects" of Medicare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angrisani, Marco; Atella, Vincenzo; Brunetti, Marianna
Large, unpredictable and not fully insurable health-care costs represent a source of background risk that might deter households' financial risk taking. Using panel data from the Health and Retirement Study, we test whether universal health insurance, like Medicare for over-65 Americans, shields against this risk promoting stockholding. We adopt a fixed-effects estimation strategy, thereby taking into account household-level heterogeneity in health status and private insurance coverage. We find that, before Medicare eligibility, households in poor health, who face a higher risk of medical expenses, are less likely to hold stocks than their healthier counterparts. Yet, this gap is mostly eliminated by Medicare. Notably, the offsetting is primarily experienced by households in poor health and without private health insurance over the observation period. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Angrisani, Marco; Atella, Vincenzo; Brunetti, Marianna</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign credit spreads under good/bad governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jeanneret, Alexandre
This paper explores how sovereign credit spreads vary with the level of governance. An analysis of 74 countries over the 2001-2016 period shows that sovereign credit default swap (CDS) spreads decrease with government effectiveness, particularly in countries exhibiting severe default risk, high indebtedness, and poor economic conditions. We formulate a theoretical explanation for these findings using a structural model in which governments adjust default and debt policies based on their abilities to collect and use fiscal revenues. The theory posits that more effective governments have less incentive to default and thus benefit from narrower credit spreads, although they may choose higher indebtedness levels. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jeanneret, Alexandre</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit risk in European banks: The bright side of the internal ratings based approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cucinelli, Doriana; Di Battista, Maria Luisa; Marchese, Malvina; Nieri, Laura
This paper investigates the accuracy of internal rating based (IRB) models in measuring credit risk. We contribute to the growing debate on the current prudential regulatory framework by investigating the use of validated IRB models in promoting efficient risk management practices. Our empirical analysis is based on a novel panel data set of 177 Western European banks observed from 2008 to 2015, in the aftermath of the financial and economic crisis. We find that IRB banks were able to curb the increase in credit risk driven by the macroeconomic slowdown better than banks under the standardized approach. This suggests that the introduction of the internal ratings based approach by Basel II has promoted the adoption of stronger risk management practices among banks, as meant by the regulators. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cucinelli, Doriana; Di Battista, Maria Luisa; Marchese, Malvina; Nieri, Laura</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating risk-return relations with analysts price targets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Liuren
Asset pricing tests often replace ex ante return expectation with ex post realization. The large deviation between the two drastically weakens the power of these tests. This paper proposes to use analysts consensus price target for a stock as the market expectation of the stock's future price to directly construct the stock's expected excess return. Analyzing the expected excess return behavior both over time and across different stocks shows that classic asset pricing theory works much better on ex ante return expectations than on ex post realizations. The analysis also provides new insights on the pricing of common equity risk factors. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm size effects in trade credit supply and demand</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lawrenz, Jochen; Oberndorfer, Julia
By investigating trade credit usage among SMEs and large companies following the macroeconomic shock of the financial crisis of 2007/08, we identify a firm size effect, which is genuine in the sense that it cannot be entirely explained by financial constraints, external finance dependence or creditworthiness. We find that (i) SMEs, in contrast to large firms, do not display evidence for the inter-firm liquidity redistribution hypothesis. Especially large vulnerable firms did cut down trade credit provision to the detriment of small vulnerable firms. (ii) We document a general substitution effect between bank and trade credit and show that it has strengthened during the crisis among large firms, but not among SMEs. (iii) We provide evidence that the shift in trade credit financing had adverse real effects on investment behaviour of SMEs. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lawrenz, Jochen; Oberndorfer, Julia</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous scope economies in microfinance institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malikov, Emir; Hartarska, Valentina
Scope economies resulting from the joint offering of loans and savings accounts (as opposed to loans only) are customarily invoked to promote the transformation of credit-only microfinance institutions (MFIs) into integrated loans-and-savings entities. To ensure robust inference, we estimate scope economies for the microfinance industry using a novel approach which, among its other advantages, accommodates inherent heterogeneity across loans-only and loans-and-savings MFIs as well as controls for endogenous self-selection of institutions into the either type. For analysis, we use a large 2004-2014 Mixmarket dataset. Unlike earlier studies, we do not find prevalent scope economies in the microfinance industry. We find that the median degree of scope economies is statistically indistinguishable from zero and that scope economies are significantly positive for less than a half of loans-and-savings MFIs. For a non-trivial 14% of institutions, the empirical evidence suggests the existence of significantly negative diseconomies of scope indicating that the separate production of loans and savings accounts actually has the potential to reduce an MFI's costs. We also find that the failure to account for endogenous selectivity dramatically overestimates the degree of scope economies resulting in the failure to detect scope diseconomies among MFIs. Thus, our findings call for caution when invoking scope economies as a blanket justification for universal expansion of the scope of financial operations by MFIs. Instead, promoting integrated loans-and-savings MFIs may be justifiable as a means to meeting the needs of the poor rather than as a way for the industry to save costs. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malikov, Emir; Hartarska, Valentina</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The competitive effect of a bank megamerger on credit supply</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fraisse, Henri; Hombert, Johan; Le, Mathias
We study the effect of a merger between two large banks on credit market competition. We identify the competitive effect of the merger using matched loan-level and firm-level data and exploiting variation in the merging banks' market overlap across local lending markets. On the credit market side, we find a reduction in lending, in particular through termination of relationships. In the average market, bank credit decreases by 2.7%. On the real side, firm exit increases by 4%, whereas firms that do not exit and firms that start up experience no adverse real effect on investment and employment. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fraisse, Henri; Hombert, Johan; Le, Mathias</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank size and market value: The role of direct monitoring and delegation costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramidis, Panagiotis; Cabolis, Christos; Serfes, Konstantinos
Recent studies have presented evidence of scale economies for large banks, providing a rationale for some very large banks seen worldwide. In this study, we focus on the negative side of bank size which relates to monitoring costs. In particular, we show that the relationship between size and bank's market to book value of assets is contained by the cost of the manager to directly monitor the borrowers and by the (delegation) cost of the owner to monitor the bank manager. Using a sample of US bank holding companies from 2001 to 2015, we provide evidence that the relationship between size and bank's market to book value of assets is inverse U-shaped and that monitoring costs offset the benefits from economies of scale. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avramidis, Panagiotis; Cabolis, Christos; Serfes, Konstantinos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does CEO bias escalate repurchase activity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Suman; Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Nanda, Vikram
We propose and test the hypothesis that overconfident-CEOs, with upwardly-biased estimates of own firm-value, are more predisposed to repurchasing stock. An implication is that the stock-market, recognizing overconfident-CEO behavior, will react less positively to repurchase announcements. The hypothesis is strongly supported: Overconfident managers repurchase stock at lower levels of cash holdings, and respond more to stock-price declines. Entrenchment exacerbates this behavior. Interestingly, institutional investors appear to encourage repurchases, perhaps to curb excessive investment. Overconfident-CEOs are also more likely to substitute repurchases for dividends or capital expenditure. Consistent with our hypothesis, the stock-market reaction to these share repurchase announcements is less positive. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Banerjee, Suman; Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Nanda, Vikram</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value at risk and expected shortfall based on Gram-Charlier-like expansions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zoia, Maria Grazia; Biffi, Paola; Nicolussi, Federica
This paper offers a new approach to modeling the distribution of a portfolio composed of either asset returns or insurance losses. To capture the leptokurtosis, which is inherent in most financial series, data are modeled by using Gram-Charlier (GC) expansions. Since we are interested in operating with several series simultaneously, the distribution of the sum of GC random variables is derived. This latter turns out to be a tail-sensitive density, suitable for modeling the distribution of a portfolio return-losses and, accordingly, can be conveniently adopted for computing risk measures such as the value at risk and the expected shortfall as well as some performance measures based on its partial moments. The closed form expressions of these risk measures are derived for cases when the density of a portfolio is the sum of GC expansions, either with the same or different kurtosis. An empirical application of this approach to a portfolio of financial asset indexes provides evidence of the comparative effectiveness of this technique in computing risk measures, both in and out of the sample period. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zoia, Maria Grazia; Biffi, Paola; Nicolussi, Federica</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The risk-taking channel of monetary policy transmission in the euro area</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neuenkirch, Matthias; Nockel, Matthias
In this paper, we provide evidence for a risk-taking channel of monetary policy transmission in the euro area that works through the relaxation of lending standards for borrowers. Our dataset covers the period 2003Q1-2016Q2 and includes, in addition to the standard variables for real GDP growth, inflation, and the monetary policy stance, indicators of bank lending standards and bank lending margins. Based on vector autoregressive models with (i) recursive identification and (ii) sign restrictions, we show that banks react aggressively to an expansionary monetary policy shock by lowering their lending standards. The banks' efforts to keep their lending margin stable, however, are not successful as we detect a significant compression. We document these findings for the euro area as a whole and for its individual member states. In particular, banks in the Netherlands, Portugal, Spain, and Ireland lowered their lending standards after expansionary monetary policy shocks. The compression of the lending margin is most pronounced in the five crisis countries (Greece, Ireland, Italy, Portugal, and Spain) (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Neuenkirch, Matthias; Nockel, Matthias</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of government bailouts on mortgage modification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Zhang, Yunqi
This paper shows how liquidity infusions affect loan modification in the mortgage market. The design of pooling and servicing agreements leads mortgage servicers to prefer foreclosure over modification when they are liquidity constrained. Therefore, a positive liquidity shock is expected to boost modification rates. Using a residential mortgage dataset that includes loan-level information, we find that the Troubled Asset Relief Program significantly increased the modification rate. Our findings help us better understand the economic consequences of government intervention and have important policy implications for the renegotiation of distressed mortgages. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Zhang, Yunqi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does your hedge fund manager smooth returns intentionally or inadvertently?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Tae Yoon; Lee, Hee Soo
We propose an econometrically logical approach that distinguishes intentional from inadvertent smoothing of hedge fund return. Other than the hedge fund return (Y) we introduce an explanatory variable: a market portfolio of hedge fund returns (X). By connecting X and Y, some critical parameters are found to be effectively related to testing the two types of return smoothing. Using those parameters, we develop distinct desmoothing algorithms against intentional and inadvertent smoothing. Our empirical results show that although intentional smoothing is partly responsible for hedge fund smoothing and is done more consistently than inadvertent smoothing, return smoothing is mainly caused by the nature of underlying assets. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Tae Yoon; Lee, Hee Soo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downside risk and stock returns in the G7 countries: An empirical analysis of their long-run and short-run dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Cathy Yi-Hsuan; Chiang, Thomas C.; Haerdle, Wolfgang Karl
Any risk-return tradeoff analysis in aggregate equity markets relies on appropriate measures of risk, in most studies based on (co-)variance relations. Consequently, in integrated global markets, country-specific expected return is priced with a world price of covariance risk. This study relates domestic excess stock returns to the world downside risk. Evidence shows that downside tail risk (as a multiplier of volatility) has long memory cointegration properties; hence, the underlying risk aversion behavior in an integrated market is associated with the conditional quantile ratio, the correlation of stock returns, and the cointegrating coefficient of downside risk. Our empirical results based on G7 countries indicate that investors are averse to downside risk, which via Cornish-Fisher expansions is related to higher moment risk and interpretable in a utility-based decision framework. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Cathy Yi-Hsuan; Chiang, Thomas C.; Haerdle, Wolfgang Karl</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting abnormal changes in credit default swap spreads using matching-portfolio models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertoni, Fabio; Lugo, Stefano
We evaluate the size and power of different statistical tests and adjustment methods for matching portfolio models to detect abnormal changes in credit default swap (CDS) spreads. The sign-test generally dominates the signed-rank test in terms of size, and dominates both the t-test and the signed-rank test in terms of power. Traditional adjustment methods often lead to a misspecified sign-test. We propose a new and parsimonious method (the spread-matched method), which leads to a well-specified and more powerful sign-test. The superiority of the spread-matched method is particularly evident for observations characterized by extreme levels of CDS spread. Analyses of CDS samples differing by contract maturity, data source, and time period confirm these results. We perform an event study on rating downgrades to illustrate how the choice of tests and adjustment methods can affect inference. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bertoni, Fabio; Lugo, Stefano</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal capital market practices of multinational banks evidence from south africa</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pelletier, Adeline
This paper examines how internal capital flows inside multinational banks create global financial interconnections, relying on a novel database on foreign banks operating in South Africa. Using the event of the East Asian crisis, I find that foreign affiliates' balance sheet face "reversal of fortune" when other members of their banking group need large amounts of internal capital to cushion capital losses, leading to an abrupt reallocation of internal capital across countries. At the same time, an increase of the volume of internal funding received is shown to cause an expansion of credit to the local private sector. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pelletier, Adeline</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust trading for ambiguity-averse insiders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vitale, Paolo
In an asset market with explicit trading rules we characterize the trading activity of an ambiguity-averse insider who faces Knightian uncertain over other market participants' beliefs and implements a robust trading strategy. Such insider employs a max-min choice mechanism, so that in any round of trading she selects as her market order that which maximizes her expected profits against those market beliefs which penalize her most. Her trading strategy is equivalent to that of a risk-averse insider who does not face any Knightian uncertain and possesses risk-sensitive recursive preferences. As she finds it optimal to trade more aggressively and reveal her private information at a faster pace than her risk-neutral (expected-profit maximizer) counterpart, we find that ambiguity-aversion is beneficial to the efficiency of the market. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vitale, Paolo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dealing with dealers: Sovereign CDS comovements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anton, Miguel; Mayordomo, Sergio; Rodriguez-Moreno, Maria
We show that sovereign CDS that have common dealers tend to be more correlated, especially when the dealers display similar quoting activity in those contracts over time. This commonality in dealers' activity is a powerful driver of CDS return comovements, over and above fundamental similarities between countries, including default, liquidity, and macro factors. We posit that the mechanism causing the excess correlation is the buying pressure faced by CDS dealers for credit enhancements and regulatory capital reliefs. An instrumental variable analysis helps alleviate the endogeneity concerns in our analysis. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anton, Miguel; Mayordomo, Sergio; Rodriguez-Moreno, Maria</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer effects, personal characteristics and asset allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Annie C.; Fang, Jiali; Jacobsen, Ben; Marshall, Ben R.
We study the relative importance of social factors (including household, workplace, and neighborhood peer effects) and personal characteristics (including age, gender, tax rates, and funds under management) for asset allocation decisions. The most important factors (in order) are household peer effects, personal characteristics and workplace peer effects. Neighborhood peer effects and financial advice play a less important role. We use instrumental variables for both household and workplace peer effects and find results that are consistent with causal peer effects. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhang, Annie C.; Fang, Jiali; Jacobsen, Ben; Marshall, Ben R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank liquidity creation and recessions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chatterjee, Ujjal K.
We investigate the relationship between bank liquidity creation and recessions in the U.S. For the 1984-2010 sample, we find that (i) lower bank on-balance sheet liquidity creation signals recessions four quarters into the future; (ii) off-balance sheet liquidity creation is not a robust predictor of recessions at longer forecast horizons; (iii) off-balance sheet liquidity creation falls in tandem with on-balance sheet liquidity creation one quarter prior to recessions, and aggregate, on- and off-balance sheet bank liquidity creation continue to decline during and up to five quarters after recessions; and (iv) liquidity creation of larger banks contains more information about future recessions than that of smaller ones. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chatterjee, Ujjal K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance effects of gender diversity on bank boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Owen, Ann L.; Temesvary, Judit
Previous literature has shown mixed results on the role of female participation on bank boards and bank performance: some papers find that more women on boards enhance financial performance, while others find negative or no effects. Applying instrumental variables methods to data on approximately 90 U.S. bank holding companies over the 1999-2015 period, we argue that these inconclusive results are due to the fact that there is a non-linear, U-shaped relationship between gender diversity on boards and various measures of bank performance: female participation has a positive effect once a threshold level of gender diversity is achieved. Furthermore, this positive effect is only observed in better capitalized banks. Our results suggest that continuing the voluntary expansion of gender diversity on bank boards will be value enhancing, provided that they are well capitalized. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Owen, Ann L.; Temesvary, Judit</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The time horizon of price responses to quantitative easing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mamaysky, Harry
Studies of how quantitative easing (QE) impacts asset prices typically look for effects in one- or two-day windows around QE announcements. This methodology underestimates the impact of QE on asset classes whose responses happen outside of this short time frame. We document that QE announcements by the Fed, ECB, and the Bank of England are associated with: quick price reactions of medium-and long-term government bonds; but with reactions in equity and equity implied volatility that occur over several weeks. Robustness checks using past monetary policy episodes and the cross-section of US industry returns confirm these results. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mamaysky, Harry</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why European banks are less profitable than US banks: A decomposition approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, Guohua; Wang, Chuan
The low profitability of European banks relative to their U.S. counterparts has recently raised concerns among policy makers and researchers. This paper attempts to shed light on this issue by using the O'Donnell (2012)decomposition approach. This approach enables us to decompose the relative profitability of European banks into an output-input price index and a total factor productivity index, with the former further decomposed into two price indexes and the latter further into four productivity and efficiency measures. Our results show that European banks' profitability was not only weak, but also deteriorated over time. Our further analysis shows that the decline in the output-input price index was due to declines in relative lending rate and relative return on securities and an increase in funding costs, while the decline in the productivity index was driven by declines in technical efficiency, scale efficiency, and residual mix efficiency. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Feng, Guohua; Wang, Chuan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary stimulation, bank relationship and innovation: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zheng, Gaoping; Wang, Shuxun; Xu, Yongxin
Using China's four trillion yuan stimulus package of 2008 (4 Trillion Plan) as an exogenous shock, we find that monetary stimulation could benefit the real economy to some extent. Specifically, compared with propensity-score-matched control firms, firms more likely affected by the stimulus plan (e.g., bank-connected firms) are granted with 18% to 24% more patents afterwards. Further evidence shows that the effect of monetary stimulation is more pronounced in firms with financial constraints, in firms located in regions with lower house price growth, and in firms with better corporate governance. Finally, monetary stimulation also increases R&amp;D expenditure, leaving innovation efficiency unaffected. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zheng, Gaoping; Wang, Shuxun; Xu, Yongxin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Operating performance and aggressive trade credit policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Box, Travis; Davis, Ryan; Hill, Matthew; Lawrey, Chris
We examine the operating performance improvements associated with the extension of trade credit. Our results suggest a positive and significant relation between future profitability and contemporaneous trade credit provision. Further findings indicate significantly higher margins, revenues and market shares for firms that extend more trade credit than industry competitors with similar characteristics, operational necessities and financial distress levels. These inferences are robust to several econometric concerns such as the joint determination of trade credit extension and firm performance. Overall, our results imply that aggressive trade credit policies can provide firm management with a unique channel to improve product market performance. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Box, Travis; Davis, Ryan; Hill, Matthew; Lawrey, Chris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer performance and earnings management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Qianqian; Shen, Rui
This paper studies how peer performance affects firms' earnings management decisions. Using peer firms' idiosyncratic returns as an exogenous peer performance measure and the instrumental variable approach, we find that higher peer performance leads to higher discretionary accruals. This effect is salient for both industry leaders and followers and is robust to alternative discretionary accrual measures and alternative peer definitions. We examine two mechanisms through which peer performance affects firms' earnings management. We find that analysts revise their earnings forecasts according to peer performance and that when peer performance is higher, firms are less likely to meet or beat analyst consensus without managing earnings. This evidence suggests a capital market pressure mechanism. In addition, the effect of peer performance is more pronounced in firms using relative performance evaluation, suggesting a compensation pressure mechanism. In sum, our evidence suggests that managers report opportunistically to match peer performance. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Du, Qianqian; Shen, Rui</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The objective function of government-controlled banks in a financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ogura, Yoshiaki
We present evidence that government-controlled banks (GCBs) significantly increased their lending to small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) whose main bank was a large bank in the 2008-09 financial crisis. Further analyses show that the weak relationship between large banks and SMEs is a major cause for this phenomenon. The mixed Cournot oligopoly model with relationship banking, where profit maximizing private banks and a welfare-maximizing GCB coexist, shows that this finding is consistent with the welfare maximization by a GCB rather than its own profit maximization. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ogura, Yoshiaki</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of share pledging regulations on stock trading and firm valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Yu-Chun; Chou, Robin K.
Previous research suggests that insiders' shareholding pledges are associated with agency problems. However, the ways investors evaluate and react to such behaviors are less clear. By investigating stock market reactions to three regulatory changes related to share pledging in Taiwan, this study shows that firms whose directors make share pledges experience significantly higher stock returns around these events, compared with those without such directors. Institutional investors increase their shareholdings of pledging (i.e., less compliant) firms after the passage of the 2011 amendment to the Company Act, indicating that reduced agency problems increase institutions' willingness to hold shares of less compliant firms. The results for stock trading and firm valuation also are more significant for firms with controlling shareholders, which are more likely to be expropriated. These results are consistent with the alignment hypothesis, in which firms that are less compliant with the rules benefit more from legislative changes. They also offer important implications, by showing how adjusting legal regulations can help improve investor protections. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Yu-Chun; Chou, Robin K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information shares Investor sentiment Lead-lag relation Limits to arbitrage Price discoveryInvestor sentiment and price discovery: Evidence from the pricing dynamics between the futures and spot markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chu-Bin; Chou, Robin K.; Wang, George H. K.
This study examines the role of investor sentiment in the pricing dynamics between the spot and futures markets. The empirical evidence suggests that investor sentiment has a positive impact on price volatility and the bid-ask spread on both the spot and futures markets, which induces higher arbitrage risk and trading costs during high sentiment periods. Consequently, during high sentiment periods, informed traders become less willing to leverage their information advantages on the futures market, which diminishes the futures markets' leading informational role and contributions to price discovery. Our findings provide support for the theory of limits to arbitrage. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Chu-Bin; Chou, Robin K.; Wang, George H. K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of ownership change on bank performance and risk exposure: Evidence from Indonesia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shaban, Mohamed; James, Gregory A.
This study investigates the effects of ownership change on the performance and exposure to risk of 60 Indonesian commercial banks over the period 2005-2012. We find that state-owned banks tend to be less profitable and more exposed to risk than private and foreign banks. Domestic investors tend to select the best performers for acquisition. Domestic acquisition is generally associated with a decrease in the efficiency of the acquired banks. Non-regional foreign acquisition is associated with a reduction in risk exposure. Acquisition by regional foreign investors is associated with performance gains. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shaban, Mohamed; James, Gregory A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition or manipulation? An empirical evidence of determinants of the earnings persistence of the US banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hung, Chi-Hsiou D.; Jiang, Yuxiang; Liu, Frank Hong; Tu, Hong
We examine the impact of competition on bank earnings persistence by exploiting a natural experiment following interstate banking deregulation that increased bank competition. We find that bank earnings adjustment speed increases after their states implement the deregulation. This relationship is weakened, however, with the increase of bank's abilities to sustain earnings, as reflected in size, diversification, managerial efficiency and safety. We further find that the impact of compeititon on bank earnings adjustment speed is direct but not indirectly through the channel of earnings management. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hung, Chi-Hsiou D.; Jiang, Yuxiang; Liu, Frank Hong; Tu, Hong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of corporate philanthropy in family firm succession: A social outreach perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Yue; Weng, Ruoyu; Xu, Nianhang; Chan, Kam C.
We propose and test a social outreach hypothesis of family firm succession. We argue that family firms proactively engage in social outreach activities as a strategy to ensure smooth succession. We focus on corporate philanthropy (CP), a social outreach activity, in a family firm succession to test our hypothesis. The results show that family firms engage in a strategy of using more CP in connection to family firm succession, especially when the successor is from the second generation. The findings are robust to alternative specifications of CP activities, various sub-sample analyses, using a difference-in-differences analysis, a two-stage least square approach, strategic choice on timing of succession, and accounting for the successor's education and experience of working for the family firm before succession. We document that despite generally poorer performance after succession, a family firm with a second-generation CEO that engages in CP exhibits better market and accounting performance relative to other types of transitions, suggesting a strategy in which CP reduces the magnitude of poor performance after succession. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pan, Yue; Weng, Ruoyu; Xu, Nianhang; Chan, Kam C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sentiment hedging: How hedge funds adjust their exposure to market sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zheng, Yao; Osmer, Eric; Zhang, Ruiyi
We investigate a new facet of hedging ability among hedge fund managers. Using a sentiment exposure model, we find evidence that fund managers adjust the market exposure of their portfolios to changes in market sentiment. Out-of-sample evidence indicates that hedge funds having the highest negative sentiment exposure outperform funds having the highest positive sentiment exposure by 1.7%-2.4% per year. The results remain persistent for both the sub-period analysis and the analysis excluding crisis periods. We also find that a hedge fund's willingness to take on sentiment exposure decreases with fund age and fund size and increases with incentive fees. Our findings remain robust even after controlling for hedge fund data biases, as well as using alternative sentiment measures. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zheng, Yao; Osmer, Eric; Zhang, Ruiyi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial literacy and participation in the derivatives markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsiao, Yu-Jen; Tsai, Wei-Che
We set out in this study to determine whether individuals with higher levels of financial literacy are more likely to be active participants in the derivatives markets. Our empirical results, based upon an official National Survey undertaken by the Financial Supervisory Commission of Taiwan, reveal that even after controlling for stock market participation rates, financial literacy represents a significant benefit to individuals since it helps them to lower the entry barriers to purchasing complex derivatives products. We also find that household wealth, gender, residential location and diverse sources of information have significant effects on participation rates in the derivatives markets. Furthermore, when taking into consideration issues of accessibility or measurement error, the positive effects of financial literacy on derivatives market participation are found to remain largely unchanged. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hsiao, Yu-Jen; Tsai, Wei-Che</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organization capital, labor market flexibility, and stock returns around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leung, Woon Sau; Mazouz, Khelifa; Chen, Jie; Wood, Geoffrey
Using data from 20 OECD countries, we find that firms with greater organization capital have significantly higher stock returns and that this represents an international phenomenon. We also find new evidence that the positive association between organization capital and stock returns increases with labor market flexibility. This finding is consistent with greater labor mobility and competition in flexible labor markets rendering organization capital investment riskier from the shareholders' perspective. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leung, Woon Sau; Mazouz, Khelifa; Chen, Jie; Wood, Geoffrey</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected Shortfall, spectral risk measures, and the aggravating effect of background risk, or: risk vulnerability and the problem of subadditivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandtner, Mario
We analyze spectral risk measures (SRMs) including its most popular representative, Expected Shortfall (ES), with respect to Gollier and Pratt (1996)'s concept of risk vulnerability. We find that SRMs and risk vulnerability are mutually exclusive, owing to the property of subadditivity: while subadditivity is commonly regarded as the axiomatic cornerstone of SRMs, risk vulnerability, by contrast, prevails if and only if superadditivity holds. The lack of risk vulnerability yields questionable predictions in portfolio problems: SRM-decision makers who split their wealth between a risk free and a risky asset do constantly opt for an increase in the risky investment when their deterministic background wealth is complemented by some additional background risk. The more general setting where background wealth is already random and then becomes more risky is not as clear-cut: Any SRM-decision maker may both increase or decrease the risky investment, depending on the concrete instance of the portfolio problem. However, when random background wealth and the risky asset are jointly normally distributed, SRM-decision makers will again unambiguously increase their risky investment. We further conduct a data analysis and discuss possible implications of the findings for regulatory risk management. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brandtner, Mario</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The invisible hand of internal markets in mutual fund families</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goncalves-Pinto, Luis; Sotes-Paladino, Juan; Xu, Jing
internal markets of fund families can encourage member funds to deviate excessively from their investment mandates. Theoretically, we show that fund managers following sufficiently different style benchmarks can engage in risk-shifting by trading with one another at low cost inside their family. This benefits the managers and the family even in the absence of a family-level strategy. However, the excessive risks taken by the managers can be costly to fund investors. Empirically, we find support for the positive effect of intra-family style diversity on offsetting trades across funds and on deviations of funds' portfolios from their benchmarks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goncalves-Pinto, Luis; Sotes-Paladino, Juan; Xu, Jing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank's interest rate risk and profitability in a prolonged environment of low interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaudron, Raymond F. D. D.
This paper investigates the size and development of banking book interest rate risk positions of Dutch banks during 2008 to 2015. Due to hedging, interest rate risk is small and the income from maturity transformation is only a small share of the net interest margin and the return on assets. However, interest rate risk positions do vary significantly between banks and over time. My results suggest that banks lower their interest rate risk significantly when the yield curve flattens. Interest rate risk is negatively related to on-balance sheet leverage and has a U-shaped relation with solvability for banks that do not use derivatives. Banks that received government assistance during the financial crisis have higher interest rate risk than banks that did not receive assistance. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chaudron, Raymond F. D. D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional trading and asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frijns, Bart; Huynh, Thanh D.; Tourani-Rad, Alireza; Westerholm, P. Joakim
This paper examines whether the trading activity of different investor types, institutional versus retail, can affect the relation between beta and average returns. We find that the beta-return relation is strong and positive on days with high institutional trading activity, and negative and significant on low institutional trading days. Our findings are robust and not driven by recently documented effects such as macroeconomic news and leverage constraints, among others. The evidence is consistent with the hypothesis that the preferences and characteristics of various investor types, which are revealed through their trading activity, cause the slope of the Security Market Line to change. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frijns, Bart; Huynh, Thanh D.; Tourani-Rad, Alireza; Westerholm, P. Joakim</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buyouts under the threat of preemption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tarsalewska, Monika
This paper analyses the effects of preemption fears on the buyout efficiency when firms combine non synergistic operational activities and have asymmetric access to financing. Bidders with preemption fears are more likely to acquire target firms at an earlier development stage. However, if uncertainty is high, an acquirer may opt to wait and buy the target firm at a later stage as assets in place. The fear of preemption affects the efficient exercise of each offer differently. While the timing of a hostile takeover under threat of preemption converges to an efficient global optimiser threshold, negotiated mergers are exercised inefficiently too early. Premiums to the target firm are higher when the firm is acquired at an earlier stage, and when the bidder fears being preempted. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tarsalewska, Monika</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluation of academic finance conferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kerl, Alexander; Miersch, Enrico; Walter, Andreas
We develop a novel framework to evaluate the quality of academic finance conferences. In particular, we analyze the publication and citation outcomes of 18,535 conference papers presented at 15 academic finance conferences between 2007 and 2012. In addition, we provide evidence of the perceived quality of these academic finance conferences by surveying a large number of participants of the 15 conferences. The use of three different quality proxies enables us to contrast levels of conference quality based on the quality of presented papers to levels of conference quality perceived by conference participants. Our results reveal two quality clusters of academic finance conferences and show that the use of the three quality dimensions, while generally robust, is associated with a number of peculiarities. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kerl, Alexander; Miersch, Enrico; Walter, Andreas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic variable selection for creditor recovery rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nazemi, Abdolreza; Fabozzi, Frank J.
We study the relationship between U.S. corporate bond recovery rates and macroeconomic variables used in the credit risk literature. The least absolute shrinkage and selection operator (LASSO) is used in selecting macroeconomic variables. The LASSO-selected macroeconomic variables are considered to be explanatory variables in ordinary least squares regressions, bootstrap aggregating (bagging), regression trees, boosting, LASSO, ridge regression and support vector regression techniques. We compare the out-of P-sample predictive power of two types of models (LASSO-selected models with models that add principal components derived from 179 macroeconomic variables as explanatory variables). We find the recovery models with LASSO-selected macroeconomic variables outperform suggested models in the literature. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nazemi, Abdolreza; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning about noise</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marmora, Paul; Rytchkov, Oleg
This paper studies how acquisition of non-fundamental information (learning about noise) affects financial markets. We develop a rational expectations model with investors who are endowed with fundamental and non-fundamental information of heterogeneous quality and who optimally allocate learning capacity between fundamentals and noise. We demonstrate that learning about noise increases price informativeness, and the price can be the most informative when the majority of investors acquire non fundamental information. We also find that i) investors whose prior fundamental information is relatively precise (imprecise) compared to their prior non-fundamental information learn only about fundamentals (noise) and ii) learning about fundamentals (noise) increases (decreases) the heterogeneity in the fundamental information quality across investors. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marmora, Paul; Rytchkov, Oleg</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State history, legal adaptability and financial development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, James B.; Fredriksson, Per G.
A country's cumulative experience with statehood influences its ability to consolidate power and create a capable bureaucracy. Longer statehood experience gives countries more time to adapt their laws to local needs, provided the legal system is adaptable. We find that, relative to British common law countries with the most flexible laws, German and Scandinavian civil law countries initially exhibit lower financial development. However, as their history of statehood grows longer, financial development improves in countries with adaptable laws such as the German and Scandinavian civil law countries. This is not the case in French civil law countries with more rigid legal systems. Our results mainly show no or at most a weakly negative effect of French civil law legal origin on financial development. We also explore how changes in stock market development over time, financial integration, and financial crises are impacted by statehood experience, legal origins and their interaction. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, James B.; Fredriksson, Per G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial market illiquidity shocks and macroeconomic dynamics: Evidence from the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellington, Michael
We examine the link between financial market illiquidity and macroeconomic dynamics by fitting a Bayesian time-varying parameter VAR with stochastic volatility to UK data from 1988Q1 to 2016Q4. We capture liquidity conditions in the stock market using a battery of illiquidity proxies. This paper departs from previous studies examining macro-financial linkages by using theoretically grounded sign restrictions, and conducting structural inference in a non-linear framework. We document both statistically significant differences in the transmission of these shocks, and substantial increases in the economic importance of these shocks during the 2008 recession. (C) 2018 The Author. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Ellington, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market states, sentiment, and momentum in the corporate bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Lifang; Galvani, Valentina
We show that momentum profits for corporate bonds depend on the state of the market (UP/DOWN), as already documented for equities. Momentum gains exclusively follow UP periods. In contrast, DOWN markets herald momentum losses. Importantly, this study links momentum gains to underpricing, as measured by low sentiment. In particular, the UP-market momentum gains are generated exclusively by momentum portfolios formed in periods of low sentiment. The DOWN-market reversal returns in low sentiment are even larger than the UP-market momentum gains. We also introduce a novel top-volume bond momentum strategy and show that it yields large and persistent unconditional profits. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Lifang; Galvani, Valentina</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accounting quality in banking: The role of regulatory interventions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos D.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Iosifidi, Maria; Li, Lingxiang
Using the full sample of U.S. banks and hand-collected data on enforcement actions over 2000-2014, we analyze the role of these interventions in promoting several aspects of accounting quality. We find that enforcement actions issued for both risk-related and accounting-related reasons lead to significant improvements in accounting quality. This improvement is consistently found for earnings smoothing, big bath accounting, timely recognition of future loan losses, the association of loan loss provisions with future loan charge offs, loss avoidance, and cash flow predictability and earnings persistence. Most of the effects are somewhat more potent in the crisis period and survive in several sensitivity tests. Our findings highlight the imperative role of regulatory interventions in promoting bank accounting quality. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Delis, Manthos D.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Iosifidi, Maria; Li, Lingxiang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What makes individual investors exercise early? Empirical evidence from non-tradable fixed-income products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eickholt, Mathias; Entrop, Oliver; Wilkens, Marco
This paper studies the early exercise behavior of individual investors in non-tradable German governmental putable bonds. Analyzing holding and exercise decisions of more than 220,000 individual investors at a single-account level over 13 years, our major findings are: (i) Individual investors use their early exercise right predominantly at times that are not optimal according to standard option pricing theory. (ii) Only very few attractive exercise opportunities are exploited over time. (iii) Both exercises and failure to exercise differ significantly among investor groups, are related to their personal characteristics as well as product characteristics and environmental circumstances, and are subject to cognitive biases. They tend to be persistent over time on the investor level. (iv) The demand by investors for liquidity and financial flexibility is a more important motive for investment and exercise than performance seeking. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eickholt, Mathias; Entrop, Oliver; Wilkens, Marco</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Zero leverage and the value in waiting to have debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lotfaliei, Babak
This paper documents that the real option to have debt motivates some firms to remain debt-free, even when standard trade-off theory predicts that these firms should have leverage. The real option has a first-order effect similar to the effect of bankruptcy costs in addressing the zero-leverage puzzle: the observation that many firms seemingly forgo sizable debt benefits by remaining debt-free. The debt-free firms' value includes the option whose value is derived from future debt benefits and hedging bankruptcy costs. This paper proposes an optimal timing model for having debt and finds support for the model's predictions through calibrations and simulations. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lotfaliei, Babak</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-series momentum in nearly 100 years of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Bryan Y.; Wang, Jiaguo; Yao, Yaqiong
We document strong time-series momentum effects in individual stocks in the US markets from 1927 to 2017. Time-series momentum is not specific to sub-periods, firm sizes, formation- and holding-period lengths, or geographic markets. The effects persist after controlling for standard risk factors. Time-series momentum effects are conditional on the market state, the information discreteness of the constituent stocks and investor sentiment. We propose two alternative implementations, revised time-series momentum and dual momentum, which generate even higher profits than standard time-series momentum. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lim, Bryan Y.; Wang, Jiaguo; Yao, Yaqiong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset market responses to conventional and unconventional monetary policy shocks in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claus, Edda; Claus, Iris; Krippner, Leo
We quantify the responses of a wide range of United States financial market variables to domestic monetary policy shocks over conventional and unconventional monetary policy environments. Our results show that responses to policy shocks are in the same direction but generally larger and more significant in the unconventional period. The larger responses are mostly due to larger shocks in the unconventional period, but some variables show evidence of a larger transmission of shocks. We separately use our framework to test shadow short rate estimates as a proxy for short-maturity interest rates across conventional and unconventional periods. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Claus, Edda; Claus, Iris; Krippner, Leo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset allocation strategies, data snooping, and the 1/N rule</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Han, Qiheng; Wu, Wensheng; Cao, Zhiguang
Using a series of advanced tests from White's (2000) "Reality Check" to correct for data-snooping bias, we assess the out-of-sample performance of various portfolio strategies relative to the naive 1/N rule. When we analyze 16 basic portfolio strategies, 126 learning strategies, and nearly 2,000 extended strategies, we find that some strategies outperform the 1/N rule in conventional tests that do not account for data-snooping bias. However, after we use the new tests that control for such bias, we find that none or very few of these strategies outperform the 1/N rule. Thus, our finding underscores the necessity to control for data-snooping bias when making asset allocation decisions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Han, Qiheng; Wu, Wensheng; Cao, Zhiguang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the traditional banking model a survivor?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiorazzo, Vincenzo; D'Apice, Vincenzo; DeYoung, Robert; Morelli, Pierluigi
We test whether small US commercial banks that use a traditional business model are more likely to survive than nontraditional banks during both good and bad economic climates. Our concept of bank survival is derived from Stigler (1958) and includes any bank that does not fail or is not acquired. We define traditional banking by four hallmark characteristics: relationship loans, core deposit funding, revenue streams from traditional banking services, and physical bank branches. Banks that adhered more closely to this business strategy were an estimated 8 to 13 percentage points more likely to survive from 1997 to 2012 compared to other small banks using less traditional business strategies. This survival advantage approximately doubled during the financial crisis period. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiorazzo, Vincenzo; D'Apice, Vincenzo; DeYoung, Robert; Morelli, Pierluigi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of the Solvency II regulatory framework's Smith-Wilson model for the term structure of risk-free interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jorgensen, Peter Lochte
In the European Union financial regulation requires that life and pension (L&amp;P) companies use the Smith and Wilson (2000) model for the term structure of risk-free interest rates when valuing their liabilities and long term guarantees. Some key features of this model are that it allows for a perfect fit to market observed bond prices, and that its extrapolated long rates converge towards a constant level, the Ultimate Forward Rate (UFR). Both this level and the rate at which convergence towards it takes place are directly specified via parameters of the model. Since the Smith-Wilson model is not one of finance theory's standard term structure models, we introduce the model and summarize its most important mathematical properties. We also describe how the European Solvency II regulation came to embrace this particular model. The paper moves on to document how the regulation also imposes quite detailed and tight restrictions on how the Smith-Wilson model should be parameterized and applied. We argue that many of these implementation instructions - one of which is the regulator's specification of a very high UFR - seem biased in the same direction and that this could indicate a systematic attempt to "lift" the term structure curve up and away from its true location whereby artificially high discount rates are induced. The result of the bias is not only significant undervaluation of L&amp;P liabilities but also a peculiar contradiction of the Solvency II overall objective of enhancing financial stability and of protecting policyholders via the promotion of economic valuation in accordance with market consistent principles. The paper's analysis is accompanied by valuation illustrations based on data on the liability composition of an actual medium-sized Danish pension fund. The results suggest that the undervaluation of liabilities resulting from use of the regulation compliant Smith-Wilson model can be massive compared to results obtained from some alternative and more freely calibrated models. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jorgensen, Peter Lochte</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The joint dynamics of sovereign ratings and government bond yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>El-Shagi, Makram; von Schweinitz, Gregor
Can a negative shock to sovereign ratings invoke a vicious cycle of increasing government bond yields and further downgrades, ultimately pushing a country toward default? The narratives of public and political discussions, as well as of some widely cited papers, suggest this possibility. In this paper, we will investigate the possible existence of such a vicious cycle. We find no evidence of a bad long-run equilibrium and cannot confirm a feedback loop leading into default as a transitory state for all but the very worst ratings. We use a bivariate semiparametric dynamic panel model to reproduce the joint dynamics of sovereign ratings and government bond yields. The individual equations resemble Pesaran-type cointegration models, which allow for valid interference regardless of whether the employed variables display unit-root behavior. To incorporate most of the empirical features previously documented (separately) in the literature, we allow for different long-run relationships in both equations, nonlinearities in the level effects of ratings, and asymmetric effects in changes of ratings and yields. Our finding of a single good equilibrium implies the slow convergence of ratings and yields toward this equilibrium. However, the persistence of ratings is sufficiently high that a rating shock can have substantial costs if it occurs at a highly speculative rating or lower. Rating shocks that drive the rating below this threshold can increase the interest rate sharply, and for a long time. Yet, simulation studies based on our estimations show that it is highly improbable that rating agencies can be made responsible for the most dramatic spikes in interest rates. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>El-Shagi, Makram; von Schweinitz, Gregor</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of information: When is Directors' and Officers' insurance value-added?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Shih-Chung; Ren, Yayuan; Yeh, Jason
The paper presents a model of shareholders' decisions to purchase Directors' and Officers' liability insurance (D&amp;O insurance) for their directors. We consider the tradeoff between the governance enhancing effect and the moral hazard effect of D&amp;O insurance and focus on the role of information in determining the optimal level of D&amp;O insurance purchase. The model shows that when directors are well informed, the governance enhancing effect of D&amp;O insurance dominates the moral hazard effect, and thus, D&amp;O insurance adds value to the firm. When directors are under-informed, the best strategy for shareholders is not to provide D&amp;O insurance for directors. The model further shows that the optimal level of D&amp;O insurance, when it exists, increases in the quality of the information received by directors. These results imply cross-firm variations in D&amp;O insurance purchase. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chang, Shih-Chung; Ren, Yayuan; Yeh, Jason</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International policy coordination for financial regime stability under cross-border externalities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Sungmin; Kim, Young-Han
This paper examines the conditions for effective coordination in financial regulatory policy when banks are politically influential, considering cross-border externalities arising from multinational banking operation. We demonstrate that when banks are inefficient with high loan monitoring costs, regulatory effort is a strategic substitute so that each country's regulator tends to exert lower effort free-riding that of the other countries' regulator. On the other hand, when banks are efficient with lower monitoring costs, regulatory effort is a strategic complement and regulators have lower incentives to free-ride. However, regulators face multiple equilibria and thus financial instability if each of them responds in an overly sensitive manner to another's strategy. In this case, introducing informational barriers can refine multiple equilibria into a unique equilibrium. The results suggest that cooperative financial policy coordination mechanism is more likely to be sustained among countries whose banking sectors' political influence on regulators is smaller and more homogeneous. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Park, Sungmin; Kim, Young-Han</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank opacity and financial crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jungherr, Joachim
This paper studies a model of endogenous bank opacity. Why do banks choose to hide their risk exposure from the public? And should policy makers force banks to be more transparent? In the model, bank opacity is costly because it encourages banks to take on too much risk. But opacity also reduces the incidence of bank runs (for a given level of risk taking). Banks choose to be inefficiently opaque if the composition of their asset holdings is proprietary information. In this case, policy makers can improve upon the market outcome by imposing public disclosure requirements (such as Pillar Three of Basel II). However, full transparency maximizes neither efficiency nor stability. The model can explain why empirically a higher degree of bank competition leads to increased transparency. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jungherr, Joachim</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Total attention: The effect of macroeconomic news on market reaction to earnings news</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Linda H.; Jiang, George J.; Zhu, Kevin X.
We show evidence that consistent with category-learning behavior, investors allocate more attention to macroeconomic news than to firm-specific news, such as earnings announcements. Despite the distracting effect of macroeconomic news on investor attention, we find that earnings announcements with concurrent macroeconomic news announcements actually have significantly stronger immediate market response and weaker post-earnings announcement drift. We hypothesize that the combined total attention to macroeconomic news and earnings announcements helps investors understand both the systematic and firm-specific components of earnings surprises. Consistent with the hypothesis, our results show that the macroeconomic news effect is mainly driven by firms with high exposure to macroeconomic news. Moreover, we show that the effect is stronger when macroeconomic news contains more information and for firms with greater information uncertainty. Finally, we provide evidence that macroeconomic news helps reduce stock return uncertainty and enhance stock price efficiency. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Linda H.; Jiang, George J.; Zhu, Kevin X.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macro-financial linkages and heterogeneous non-performing loans projections: An application to Ecuador</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grigoli, Francesco; Mansilla, Mario; Saldias, Martin
Economic contractions are generally associated with increases in NPL ratios. However, despite the common assumption used in the empirical literature of homogenous impact across banks, the strength of this relationship is often bank-specific, and imposing homogeneity may lead to over- or underestimating the resilience of the financial system to macroeconomic woes. We introduce a three-stage approach to generate forecasts of macro-financial variables and project non-performing loans (NPLs) in a way that accounts for banks' heterogeneous reactions to macro-financial shocks in a dynamic context and for potential cross-sectional dependence across banks caused by common shocks. An application to Ecuador suggests that both substantial heterogeneity and cross-sectional dependence are present and that should be taken into account when trying to anticipate inflections in the quality of the portfolio. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grigoli, Francesco; Mansilla, Mario; Saldias, Martin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonconsolidated affiliates, bank capitalization, and risk taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gong, Di; Huizinga, Harry; Laeven, Luc
This paper is the first to show that financial institutions may be effectively undercapitalized as a result of incomplete consolidation of minority ownership. Using two approaches - consolidating the minority owned affiliates with the parent or deducting equity investments in minority ownership from the parent's capital - we find that the effective capitalization ratios of small US bank holding companies (BHCs) are substantially lower than the reported ratios. Empirical evidence suggests that the effectively lower capitalization ratios are associated with higher riskiness at the BHC level. Capital adjustments following pro forma consolidation better capture the additional risks than capital adjustments in the form of equity deductions for investments in minority-owned affiliates. These findings have important implications for the regulation of bank capital. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gong, Di; Huizinga, Harry; Laeven, Luc</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rivals' competitive activities, capital constraints, and firm growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergbrant, Mikael C.; Hunter, Delroy M.; Kelly, Patrick J.
We examine the impact of rivals' competitive activities on firms' quantity-of-capital constraints in 60 countries. Prior work shows that competition increases the costs of debt and equity, which reduce the economic profit from investment. Capital constraints, however, may prevent firms from exploiting all positive NPV projects. Using unique survey data and several econometric techniques, we address endogeneity problems that affect both capital constraints and rivals' competitive activities. We find that rivals' competitive activities are positively associated with firms' capital constraints and are more strongly correlated with capital constraints than banking sector competition. We also show that quantity-of-capital constraints are negatively related to firm growth, incremental to the cost of capital. Crown Copyright (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bergbrant, Mikael C.; Hunter, Delroy M.; Kelly, Patrick J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity SRI funds vacillate between ethics and money: An analysis of the funds' stock holding decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joliet, Robert; Titova, Yulia
We provide a detailed holdings-based analysis of investment decisions made by U.S. equity SRI funds. Besides incorporating conventional fundamental factors, such as earnings growth, leverage, dividend yield, stock return and volatility, SRI funds adjust portfolio weights by considering companies' relative ESG performance. This holds for all categories of passively and actively managed funds, while for active funds ESG scores have a higher economic impact for value rather than growth funds. The timing of inclusion of companies in active SRI funds or their exclusion is driven primarily by fundamentals rather than by ESG performance. We find that both active SRI and matched conventional funds integrate ESG information as well as financial criteria in their investment decisions, but SRI portfolios exhibit higher average sustain ability scores. Finally, we posit that SRI screening criteria effectively guide investment decisions, positive screening resulting in higher active portfolio weights of best performers in a corresponding ESG pillar. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Joliet, Robert; Titova, Yulia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unobservable systematic risk, economic activity and stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Santis, Roberto A.
I extract a latent systematic risk factor, which is orthogonal to idiosyncratic risk and observable systematic risk, from credit spreads for 1764 Eurobonds across euro area non-financial firms over the 1999-2015 period. The extracted common latent factor negatively predicts stock market excess returns, the growth rate in real economic activity and economic sentiment. It predicts the financial crisis and the two economic recessions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Santis, Roberto A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interorganizational trust and agency costs in credit relationships between savings banks and SMEs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirsch, Bernhard; Nitzl, Christian; Schoen, Matthias
We analyze the impact of trust on agency costs in relationships between savings banks and SMEs as well as the mediating effects of hard information on interorganizational trust between these two actors. We tested six hypotheses using a structural equation model based on partial least squares. Study data were obtained from two German savings banks and dyadic questionnaires of relationship managers and credit risk officers. Our results provide evidence that interorganizational trust reduces agency costs by directly and indirectly increasing the quality of credit negotiations by lowering the bank's monitoring intensity via habitualization. Surprisingly, institutionalized trust increases the banks' monitoring intensity. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hirsch, Bernhard; Nitzl, Christian; Schoen, Matthias</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying relationship lending in the interbank market: A network approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kobayashi, Teruyoshi; Takaguchi, Taro
Relationship lending is broadly interpreted as a strong partnership between a lender and a borrower. Nevertheless, we still lack consensus regarding how to quantify the strength of a lending relationship, while simple statistics such as the frequency and volume of loans have been used as proxies in previous studies. Here, we propose statistical tests to identify relationship lending as a significant tie between banks. Application of the proposed method to the Italian interbank networks reveals that the fraction of relationship lending among all bilateral trades has been quite stable and that the relationship lenders tend to impose high interest rates at the time of financial distress. (C) 2018 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kobayashi, Teruyoshi; Takaguchi, Taro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing renewable energy production risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hain, Martin; Schermeyer, Hans; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese; Fichtner, Wolf
The growing share of renewables paired with their intermittent nature introduces significant new challenges for market participants along the value-chain in power markets. Taking the view of an owner of such a physical renewable asset we showcase the management of the associated stochastic production risks in Germany, one of the most dynamic electricity markets and the largest producer of renewable energy in the EU-28. We find that unhedged renewable portfolios are very risky and existing vanilla derivatives are poor hedges. New exotic quantity-related weather contracts proposed by major energy exchanges (EEX) show a lot of potential but are still very illiquid. Their hedging performance is heavily driven by the market wide renewable generation portfolio which, in its current state, favors specific regions. In the long-run price-related derivatives will transform into more useful hedging instruments due to the growing importance of renewables in the formation of wholesale market prices. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hain, Martin; Schermeyer, Hans; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese; Fichtner, Wolf</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skill or effort? Institutional ownership and managerial efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baghdadi, Ghasan A.; Bhatti, Ishaq M.; Nguyen, Lily H. G.; Podolski, Edward J.
Using a sample of U.S. firms during the 1989-2015 period, we study whether the efficiency with which managers generate revenue is sensitive to monitoring by institutional shareholders. We find that institutional ownership is positively related to managerial efficiency. Our identification relies on a discontinuity in ownership around the Russell 1000/2000 Index threshold and suggests that the positive effect of institutional ownership on managerial efficiency is causal. Furthermore, we document that monitoring by institutions helps improve managerial efficiency, and that an exogenous increase in institutional ownership leads to higher pay-for-performance sensitivity. Finally, we find consistent results after excluding from our sample forced CEO turnovers, suggesting that institutional shareholders force incumbent managers to exert greater effort rather than influence the replacement of less efficient CEOs. Taken together, our findings highlight the important role played by institutional shareholders in getting the most out of corporate executives. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baghdadi, Ghasan A.; Bhatti, Ishaq M.; Nguyen, Lily H. G.; Podolski, Edward J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Qualitative similarity and stock price comovement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Box, Travis
I introduce a method for gauging the qualitative similarity of firm-specific information based on linguistic commonality in newswire text. I show that this new qualitative similarity measure predicts future cross-firm return correlation even after accounting for the pair's contemporaneous price comovement, common exposures to systematic risk, firm liquidity, price, index membership, text volume, headquarters location, product similarity, shared mutual fund or institutional ownership, common analyst following and newswire co-mentions. I also demonstrate that content produced solely by journalists cannot predict an economically meaningful portion of future comovement. Out-of-sample tests confirm that knowledge of qualitative similarity can also reduce portfolio risk. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Box, Travis</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Awareness, determinants and value of reputation risk management: Empirical evidence from the banking and insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heidinger, Dinah; Gatzert, Nadine
The aim of this paper is to empirically study reputation risk management in the US and European banking and insurance industry, which has become increasingly important in recent years. We first use a text mining approach and find that the awareness of reputation risk (management) as reflected in annual reports has increased during the last ten years and that it has gained in importance relative to other risks. Furthermore, we provide the first empirical study of the determinants and value of reputation risk management. Our results show that larger firms, as well as firms that are located in Europe and have a higher awareness of their reputation, are significantly more likely to implement a reputation risk management program. Finally, we obtain initial indications of the value-relevance of reputation risk management. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heidinger, Dinah; Gatzert, Nadine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A network approach to unravel asset price comovement using minimal dependence structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campos de Carvalho, Pablo Jose; Gupta, Aparna
We develop a network representation-based methodology to aid an exploratory analysis of temporally evolving comovement in asset prices. This parsimonious order-n representation of the most significant comovement in asset prices, filtered by common factors, allows tackling a large number of assets and unraveling their complex comovement structure. Flexibility in choosing explanatory factors to suit the specific objectives of a study makes this methodology useful for portfolio analysis, risk parity approaches, and risk management decisions. We illustrate the features of the methodology for a set of major industry equity indices and to blue chip stocks, where we analyze the dynamic relevance of Fama-French factors. Investigating the network for more than 20 years, including the dot-corn bust, global financial crisis, and European debt crisis, helps draw many insights. For instance, unexpected industries are seen to connect idiosyncratically through the dot-corn bust. We demonstrate that a network factor model based portfolio allocation performs better than a regular factor model based allocation. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campos de Carvalho, Pablo Jose; Gupta, Aparna</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loss given default adjusted workout processes for leases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miller, Patrick; Toews, Eugen
Employing defaulted leases, this study divides the loss given default (LCD) into two parts. So far, LGD has been regarded as a holistic measure of risk. However, considering the specifics of leases, we distinguish between asset-related and miscellaneous revenues of the workout process in order to calculate component LGDs. We introduce a multi-step approach to estimate the overall LGD of leases, based on its economic composition, The performance is assessed out-of-sample and out-of-time. We find that our approach generates stable and accurate estimations. Moreover, using the estimated component LGDs, we obtain valuable information regarding the debt collection procedure that lead to monetary advantages for the lessor. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Miller, Patrick; Toews, Eugen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exposure at default modeling - A theoretical and empirical assessment of estimation approaches and parameter choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guertler, Marc; Hibbeln, Martin Thomas; Usselmann, Piet
Estimating the credit risk parameter exposure at default is important for banks from an internal risk management and a regulatory perspective. Several approaches are common in the literature and in practice. We theoretically and empirically analyze how the exposure at default should be modeled to obtain accurate estimates of the expected loss. Our empirical analysis is based on a large and unique dataset from a retail portfolio of a European bank. We demonstrate that some approaches can lead to substantially biased estimates of the expected loss and show that the generalized cohort approach is advantageous. Moreover, using in- and out-of-sample analyses, we empirically demonstrate that using the credit conversion factor is preferable to the loan equivalent factor, exposure at default factor, and direct exposure at default estimation to achieve high estimation accuracy. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guertler, Marc; Hibbeln, Martin Thomas; Usselmann, Piet</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit risk modelling under recessionary and financially distressed conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dendramis, Y.; Tzavalis, E.; Adraktas, G.
This paper provides clear cut evidence that economic recession and distressed financial conditions, as well as political instability constitute the key factors for mortgage default. Banning foreclosure procedures, often adopted by governments to mitigate the effects of the above conditions on loan defaulting, are found to positively influence the loan default probability, and thus they make efforts of banks to restructure (or refinance) mortgage loans a difficult task. Our results add support to the view that foreclosure moratorium may raise moral hazard incentives that borrowers will not maintain their payments in long run. The empirical analysis of the paper is based on an extension of the discrete-time survival analysis model which allows for a structural break in its baseline hazard function and a unique set of individual loan accounts. We also consider alternative specifications of the binary link function between default events and covariates. Asymmetric link functions are found to be more appropriate under financial distressed conditions. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dendramis, Y.; Tzavalis, E.; Adraktas, G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The spillover effect of enforcement actions on bank risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caiazza, Stefano; Cotugno, Matteo; Fiordelisi, Franco; Stefanelli, Valeria
Enforcement actions (sanctions) aim to penalize guilty companies and provide examples to other companies that bad behavior will be penalized. A handful of papers analyze the consequences of sanctions in banking for sanctioned companies, while no papers have investigated the spillover effects on non sanctioned banks. Focusing on credit-related sanctions, we show the existence of a spillover effect: non sanctioned banks behave similar to sanctioned banks, depending on their degree of similarity, offloading problematic loans and reducing their lending activity. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caiazza, Stefano; Cotugno, Matteo; Fiordelisi, Franco; Stefanelli, Valeria</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unbiased estimation of risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pitera, Marcin; Schmidt, Thorsten
The estimation of risk measures recently gained a lot of attention, partly because of the backtesting issues of expected shortfall related to elicitability. In this work we shed a new and fundamental light on optimal estimation procedures of risk measures in terms of bias. We show that once the parameters of a model need to be estimated, one has to take additional care when estimating risks. The typical plug-in approach, for example, introduces a bias which leads to a systematic underestimation of risk. In this regard, we introduce a novel notion of unbiasedness to the estimation of risk which is motivated by economic principles. In general, the proposed concept does not coincide with the well-known statistical notion of unbiasedness. We show that an appropriate bias correction is available for many well-known estimators. In particular, we consider value-at-risk and expected shortfall (tail value-at-risk). In the special case of normal distributions, closed-formed solutions for unbiased estimators can be obtained. We present a number of motivating examples which show the outperformance of unbiased estimators in many circumstances. The unbiasedness has a direct impact on backtesting and therefore adds a further viewpoint to established statistical properties. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pitera, Marcin; Schmidt, Thorsten</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>