<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF12</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Understanding partial mergers in Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ushijima, Tatsuo
Since the late 1990s, Japan has witnessed a substantial increase of partial mergers where two or more firms spin off whole operations in the same business and combine them into a joint venture (JV). This paper provides the first academic evidence on this phenomenon. I find that partial mergers normally occur as a response to negative economic shocks by firms that are larger and more diversified than firms in total mergers. An event study identifies positive and significant returns to partial merger announcements. Unlike total mergers whose value accrues mostly to the shareholders of small (acquired) firms, large and small firms in partial mergers receive comparable returns, which are particularly large to firms forming an equally owned JV. This study also finds that partial mergers are often ex post transformed, with equity sale between partners being the main source of change. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ushijima, Tatsuo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan growth and riskiness of banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foos, Daniel; Norden, Lars; Weber, Martin
We investigate whether loan growth affects the riskiness of individual banks in 16 major countries. Using Bankscope data from more than 16,000 individual banks during 1997-2007, we test three hypotheses on the relation between abnormal loan growth and asset risk, bank profitability, and bank solvency. We find that loan growth leads to an increase in loan loss provisions during the subsequent three years, to a decrease in relative interest income, and to lower capital ratios. Further analyses show that loan growth also has a negative impact on the risk-adjusted interest income. These results suggest that loan growth represents an important driver of the riskiness of banks. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Foos, Daniel; Norden, Lars; Weber, Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International financial integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucey, Brian M.
nan</description><author>Lucey, Brian M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integrated models of capital adequacy - Why banks are undercapitalised</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kretzschmar, Gavin; McNeil, Alexander J.; Kirchner, Axel
With the majority of large UK and many US banks collapsing or being forced to raise capital over the 2007-9 period, blaming bankers may be satisfying but is patently insufficient; Basel II and Federal oversight frameworks also deserve criticism. We propose that the current methodological void at the heart of Basel II, Pillar 2 is filled with the recommendation that banks develop fully-integrated models for economic capital that relate asset values to fundamental drivers of risk in the economy to capture systematic effects and inter-asset dependencies in a way that crude correlation assumptions do not. We implement a fully-integrated risk analysis based on the balance sheet of a composite European bank using an economic-scenario generation model calibrated to conditions at the end of 2007. Our results suggest that the more modular, correlation-based approaches to economic capital that currently dominate practice could have led to an undercapitalisation of banks, a result that is clearly of interest given subsequent events. The introduction of integrated economic-scenario-based models in future can improve capital adequacy, enhance Pillar 2's application and rejuvenate the relevance of the Basel regulatory framework. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kretzschmar, Gavin; McNeil, Alexander J.; Kirchner, Axel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>EMU and European government bond market integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abad, Pilar; Chulia, Helena; Gomez-Puig, Marta
In this study we adopt the CAPM-based model of Bekaert and Harvey (1995) to compare the differences in the relative importance of two sources of systemic risk (world and Eurozone) on Government bond returns, in two groups of countries in EU-15. Results show that euro markets are less vulnerable to the influence of world risk factors, and more vulnerable to EMU risk factors. However, they are only partially integrated. For their part, the markets of the countries that decided to stay out of the Monetary Union present a higher vulnerability to external risk factors. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abad, Pilar; Chulia, Helena; Gomez-Puig, Marta</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The reaction of emerging market credit default swap spreads to sovereign credit rating changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ismailescu, Iuliana; Kazemi, Hossein
This paper examines the effect of sovereign credit rating change announcements on the CDS spreads of the event countries, and their spillover effects on other emerging economies' CDS premiums. We find that positive events have a greater impact on CDS markets in the two-day period surrounding the event, and are more likely to spill over to other emerging countries. Alternatively, CDS markets anticipate negative events, and previous changes in CDS premiums can be used to estimate the probability of a negative credit event. The transmission mechanisms for positive events are the common creditor and competition in trade markets. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ismailescu, Iuliana; Kazemi, Hossein</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing financial market integration in Asia - Equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Ip-Wing; Fung, Kang-Por; Tam, Chi-Sang
Financial integration has strong implications for financial stability. On the one hand, financial integration among economies helps to improve their capacity to absorb shocks and foster development. On the other hand, intensified financial linkages in a world of increasing capital mobility may also harbour the risk of cross-border financial contagion. This paper provides a survey of high-frequency indicators to monitor the development of equity market integration in Asia. The results show that after slowing down between 2002 and 2006, the equity market integration process picked up again in 2007-08. Nevertheless, the process is not complete and the degrees of integration between mature and emerging equity markets are different. The divergence may be attributed to the difference in the political, economic and institutional aspects across jurisdictions in Asia. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yu, Ip-Wing; Fung, Kang-Por; Tam, Chi-Sang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the difference in valuation between domestic and foreign investors help explain their distinct holdings of domestic stocks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Hyung Cheol; Lee, Dong Wook; Park, Kyung Sub
This paper proposes an investor heterogeneity approach to the different domestic stock holdings between domestic and foreign investors. Specifically, we hypothesize that domestic and foreign investors evaluate domestic stocks via different models and thus arrive at different valuations for them; consequently, the two investor groups are attracted to different sets of domestic stocks. Using panel data from Korea, we find strong support for our hypothesis. More precisely, we find that the foreign ownership of a stock increases with foreigners' valuation for the stock in excess of that of domestic investors. As we control for various firm characteristics known to be correlated with foreign ownership, our results indicate that the valuation difference between domestic and foreign investors can help explain the allocation of domestic stocks between the two groups over and above the existing explanations. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kang, Hyung Cheol; Lee, Dong Wook; Park, Kyung Sub</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading activity and bid-ask spreads of individual equity options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wei, Jason; Zheng, Jinguo
We empirically examine the impact of trading activities on the liquidity of individual equity options measured by the proportional bid-ask spread. There are three main findings. First, the option return volatility, defined as the option price elasticity times the stock return volatility, has a much higher power in explaining the spread variations than the commonly considered liquidity determinants such as the stock return volatility and option trading volume. Second, after controlling for all the liquidity determinants, we find a maturity-substitution effect due to expiration cycles. When medium-term options (60-90 days maturity) are not available, traders use short-term options as substitutes whose higher volume leads to a smaller bid-ask spread or better liquidity. Third, we also find a moneyness-substitution effect induced by the stock return volatility. When the stock return volatility goes up, trading shifts from in-the-money options to out-of-the-money options, causing the latter's spread to narrow. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wei, Jason; Zheng, Jinguo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Timing exchange rates using order flow: The case of the Loonie</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>King, Michael; Sarno, Lucio; Sojli, Elvira
This paper examines the relation between the Canadian dollar/US dollar (CAD) exchange rate and foreign exchange order flow employing a novel data set on CAD order flow over the period 1994-2005. We investigate empirically the predictive information content and the determinants of order flow. The results suggest that order flow has strong out-of-sample predictive power for CAD returns, yielding significant market timing ability and tangible economic gains in a stylized dynamic asset allocation context. In terms of its determinants, order flow appears to reflect not only the menu of macroeconomic variables typically suggested in the literature but is also closely related to commodity price fluctuations, as expected from a 'commodity currency'. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>King, Michael; Sarno, Lucio; Sojli, Elvira</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An open-economy macro-finance model of international interdependence: The OECD, US and the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spencer, Peter; Liu, Zhuoshi
This paper develops a multi-country macro-finance model to study international economic and financial linkages. This approach models the economy and financial markets jointly using both types of data to throw light on such issues. The world economy is modelled using data for the US and aggregate OECD economies as well as the US Treasury bond market using latent variables to represent a common inflation trend and a US real interest rate factor. We find strong evidence of global effects on both the US and UK, calling into question the standard closed economy macro-finance specification. These economic linkages also help to explain the co-movement of yields in the US and UK Treasury bond markets. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Spencer, Peter; Liu, Zhuoshi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>De facto exchange rate regimes and currency crises: Are pegged regimes with capital account liberalization really more prone to speculative attacks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Esaka, Taro
This paper empirically examines whether de facto exchange rate regimes affect the occurrence of currency crises in 84 countries over the 1980-2001 period by using the probit model. We employ the de facto classification of Reinhart and Rogoff (2004) that allows us to estimate the impact of relatively long-lived exchange rate regimes on currency crises with much greater precision. We find that pegged regimes significantly decrease the likelihood of currency crises compared with floating regimes. By using the combined data of exchange rate regimes and the existence of capital controls, we also find interesting evidence that pegged regimes with capital account liberalization significantly lower the likelihood of currency crises compared with other regimes. These results are robust to a wide variety of samples and models. From the standpoint of the macroeconomic policy trilemma, we can conjecture that pegged regimes with capital account liberalization are substantially less prone to speculative attacks because they can enhance greater credibility in their currencies by abandoning monetary policy autonomy. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Esaka, Taro</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrenchment, governance, and the stock price reaction to sudden executive deaths</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Salas, Jesus M.
To study managerial entrenchment, I use the stock price reaction to unexpected senior executive deaths. If a highly effective manager dies unexpectedly, the stock price reaction should be negative. If, however, death removes an entrenched manager when the board would or could not, the stock price reaction should be positive. While, individually, age and tenure only weakly correlate with the stock price reaction to a sudden death, the reaction is strongly positive (6.8%) if: (1) the executive's tenure exceeds 10 years, and (2) abnormal stock returns over the last three years are negative. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Salas, Jesus M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short sales and speed of price adjustment: Evidence from the Hong Kong stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Crystal Xiaobei; Rhee, S. Ghon
We present empirical evidence that short sales contribute to market efficiency by increasing the speed of price adjustment to not only private/public firm-specific information but also market-wide information. Shortable stocks are characterized by weaker trade continuity and stronger quote reversals. They adjust faster to new information than non-shortable counterparts. These findings remain robust even in an "up" market condition in which short sales are not binding. The amount of information incorporated in each trade is also significantly higher for shortable than non-shortable stocks in both "up" and "down" market conditions. After controlling for firm size, trading volume, liquidity, price and option trading, short sales stand Out as one of the significant factors that speed up the price adjustment. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Crystal Xiaobei; Rhee, S. Ghon</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-sectional tests of the CAPM and Fama-French three-factor model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grauer, Robert R.; Janmaat, Johannus A.
Grouping does not produce a wide range of betas. Consequently, cross-sectional tests of the CAPM are bound to lack power. This paper provides a simple way to alleviate the problem by repackaging the data with zero-weight portfolios. When the CAPM is true and the data are repackaged, simulation shows that the average values of the intercept and slope converge to their true values more rapidly and there are striking increases in R 2 and the power of the tests. Empirical results are dramatically different in datasets with and without the zero-weight portfolios. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grauer, Robert R.; Janmaat, Johannus A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Illegal buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, Douglas; Zambelli, Simona
This study empirically examines the effects of a regulation change on the structure and governance of leveraged buyouts (LBOs) within the Italian private equity market, whose transactions were only recently legalized. With a new data set covering approximately 85% of the buyout funds active in Italy during the period of 1999-2006, we find that a regulation that prohibits LBOs can reduce their frequency, but does not exclude them altogether. Rather, it inhibits efficient governance and distorts decision making. Overall, the data are consistent with the view that laws prohibiting LBOs result in less efficient LBO arrangements. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cumming, Douglas; Zambelli, Simona</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate life cycle and M&amp;A activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Owen, Sian; Yawson, Alfred
We investigate the impact of corporate life cycle on takeover activity from the perspective of acquiring firms. Using the earned/contributed capital mix as the proxy for firm life cycle, we find a highly significant and positive relation between firm life cycle and the likelihood of becoming a bidder. This finding is, however, driven by the mature rather than the old acquirers in the sample. Further we find that, whilst firm life cycle has a positive effect on the probability that a deal will be negotiated, it is negatively related to tender offers. In addition, the likelihood of making both cash and mixed deals are positively related to the corporate life cycle. Finally, we find that life cycle has a negative impact on the abnormal returns generated on the announcement of a deal although it is unable to distinguish between the returns received by firms at different stages in their life cycle. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Owen, Sian; Yawson, Alfred</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trend-following trading strategies in commodity futures: A re-examination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szakmary, Andrew C.; Shen, Qian; Sharma, Subhash C.
This paper examines the performance of trend-following trading strategies in commodity futures markets using a monthly dataset spanning 48 years and 28 markets. We find that all parameterizations of the dual moving average crossover and channel strategies that we implement yield positive mean excess returns net of transactions costs in at least 22 of the 28 markets. When we pool our results across markets, we show that all of the trading rules earn hugely significant positive returns that prevail over most subperiods of the data as well. These results are robust with respect to the set of commodities the trading rules are implemented with, distributional assumptions, data-mining adjustments and transactions costs, and help resolve divergent evidence in the extant literature regarding the performance of momentum and pure trend-following strategies that is otherwise difficult to explain. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Szakmary, Andrew C.; Shen, Qian; Sharma, Subhash C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of bank ownership concentration on impaired loans and capital adequacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shehzad, Choudhry Tanveer; de Haan, Jakob; Scholtens, Bert
This paper examines the impact of bank ownership concentration on two indicators of bank riskiness, namely banks' non-performing loans and capital adequacy. Using balance sheet information for around 500 commercial banks from more than 50 countries averaged over 2005-2007, we find that concentrated ownership (proxied by different levels of shareholding) significantly reduces a bank's non-performing loans ratio, conditional on supervisory control and shareholders protection rights. Furthermore, ownership concentration affects the capital adequacy ratio positively conditional on shareholder protection. At low levels of shareholder protection rights and supervisory control, ownership concentration reduces bank riskiness. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shehzad, Choudhry Tanveer; de Haan, Jakob; Scholtens, Bert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What determines the composition of banks' loan portfolios? Evidence from transition countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Haas, Ralph; Ferreira, Daniel; Taci, Anita
This paper explores how bank characteristics and the institutional environment influence the composition of banks' loan portfolios. We use a new and unique data set based on the EBRD Banking Environment and Performance Survey (BEPS), which was conducted for 220 banks in 20 transition countries. We show that bank ownership, bank size, and legal creditor protection are important determinants of the composition of banks' loan portfolios. In particular, we find that foreign banks play an active role in mortgage lending. Moreover, banks that perceive pledge and mortgage laws to be of high quality choose to focus more on mortgage lending. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Haas, Ralph; Ferreira, Daniel; Taci, Anita</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund trades and the value of contradictory private information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cullen, Grant; Gasbarro, Dominic; Monroe, Gary S.
We investigate the performance of mutual funds that trade using private information. These funds are uniquely identified from a set of 2730 funds with 44,315 fund-periods between 1994 and 2005. We compare the alignment of fund trades with brokers' recommendations, which we regard as "public information" in the universe of informed and uninformed mutual funds. Funds that systematically trade counter to the public information form a homogenous subset of the privately informed funds. By using private information that contradicts the public information, these funds exhibit a superior average performance. After we control for serial correlation in fund returns, we assess this advantage as being an economically significant 1.7% per annum. We also show empirically that smaller funds are better able to capture the benefit of private information. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cullen, Grant; Gasbarro, Dominic; Monroe, Gary S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The level and quality of Value-at-Risk disclosure by commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perignon, Christophe; Smith, Daniel R.
In this paper we study both the level of Value-at-Risk (VaR) disclosure and the accuracy of the disclosed VaR figures for a sample of US and international commercial banks. To measure the level of VaR disclosures, we develop a VaR Disclosure Index that captures many different facets of market risk disclosure. Using panel data over the period 1996-2005, we find an overall upward trend in the quantity of information released to the public. We also find that Historical Simulation is by far the most popular VaR method. We assess the accuracy of VaR figures by studying the number of VaR exceedances and whether actual daily VaRs contain information about the volatility of subsequent trading revenues. Unlike the level of VaR disclosure, the quality of VaR disclosure shows no sign of improvement over time. We find that VaR computed using Historical Simulation contains very little information about future volatility. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Perignon, Christophe; Smith, Daniel R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The conditional nature of the value of corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chi, Jianxin Daniel; Lee, D. Scott
Agency theory suggests that governance matters more among firms with greater potential agency costs. Rational investors are unlikely to value safeguards against unlikely events. Yet, few studies of the relation between governance and firm value control for investor perceptions of the likelihood of agency conflicts. Shleifer and Vishny [Shleifer, A., Vishny, R-W., 1997. A survey of corporate governance. journal of Finance 52, 737-783] identify investment-related agency conflicts as the more severe type of agency conflicts in the US. We measure the perceived likelihood of this type of agency conflict using free cash flow (Jensen, M.C., 1986. Agency costs of free cash flow, corporate finance, and takeovers. American Economic Review 76, 323-329). We find that firm value is an increasing function of improved governance quality among firms with high free cash flow. In contrast, governance benefits are lower or insignificant among firms with low free cash flow. We show that not controlling for this conditional relation between governance and firm value could lead to erroneous conclusions that governance and firm value are unrelated. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chi, Jianxin Daniel; Lee, D. Scott</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk factor contributions in portfolio credit risk models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosen, Dan; Saunders, David
Determining contributions to overall portfolio risk is an important topic in risk management. For positions (instruments and sub-portfolios), this problem has been well studied, and a significant theory built, around the calculation of marginal contributions. We consider the problem of determining the contributions to portfolio risk of risk factors. This cannot be addressed through an immediate extension of techniques for position contributions, since the portfolio loss is a nonlinear function of the risk factors. We employ the Hoeffding decomposition of the portfolio loss into a sum of terms depending on the factors. This decomposition restores linearity, but includes terms arising from joint effects of groups of factors. These cross-factor terms provide information to risk managers, since they can be viewed as best hedges of the portfolio loss involving instruments of increasing complexity. We illustrate the technique on multi-factor portfolio credit risk models, where systematic factors represent industries, geographical sectors, etc. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rosen, Dan; Saunders, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks' intraday liquidity management during operational outages: Theory and evidence from the UK payment system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Merrouche, Ouarda; Schanz, Jochen
We investigate how settlement banks in the United Kingdom's large-value payment system deal with intraday liquidity and operational risk. In particular, we are interested in payments behaviour towards a bank that is, for operational reasons, unable to make but able to receive payments. If other banks did not sufficiently monitor their outgoing payments, these operational shocks could impact the entire payment system because the affected bank could absorb liquidity from the system. Our game-theoretic model predicts that only early in the day, when they are uncertain about the payment instructions they might have to execute, banks stop sending payments to a counterparty which is unable to make payments. Using a non-parametric method, we find that this prediction is supported by the data, implying that banks effectively contain the disruption caused by the operational outage: payment flows between healthy banks remain unaffected. (C) 2009 The Bank of England. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Merrouche, Ouarda; Schanz, Jochen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-term debt and overinvestment agency problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Mello, Ranjan; Miranda, Mercedes
We investigate the role of long-term debt in influencing overinvestments by analyzing the pattern of abnormal investments around a new debt offering by unlevered firms. Before being levered when the disciplining role of debt is missing, firms retain excessive amounts of cash. The introduction of debt leads to a dramatic decline in cash ratios and the relation is stronger for firms classified as having poor investment opportunities. For the sub-sample of firms that overinvest in real assets, issuing debt leads to a reduction in abnormal capital expenditures. The decline in overinvestments is explained by debt service obligations that reduce discretionary funds under managerial control. Further, the reduction in overinvestments has a positive impact on equity value. These conclusions hold in other settings where there is a dramatic change in firms' capital structures providing strong support for the hypothesis that debt reduces overinvestments. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>D'Mello, Ranjan; Miranda, Mercedes</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed arbitrage with speculative noise trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, F. Albert
We consider speculative noise trading when some naive speculators trade on noise as if it were information [Black, F., 1986. Noise. journal of Finance 41, 529-543]. We examine the optimal trading strategy of an informed investor who faces such naive speculators in the market. We find that the informed investor trades aggressively on her information and takes large, opposite positions against the naive speculators. The trading volume is thereby drastically magnified. While such speculative noise trading enhances liquidity. it makes prices less efficient. The overall dynamic patterns that emerge from our model are most consistent with the evidence for interday variations in volume, volatility, and transaction costs. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, F. Albert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing catastrophe options with stochastic arrival intensity in claim time (vol 34, pg 24, 2010)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Carolyn W.; Chang, Jack S. K.; Lu, WeiLi
nan</description><author>Chang, Carolyn W.; Chang, Jack S. K.; Lu, WeiLi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the performance of alternative investments using non-parametric efficiency measurement approaches: Is it convincing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glawischnig, Markus; Sommersguter-Reichmann, Margit
DEA-based performance assessment in the alternative investment fund industry is often motivated by the fact that DEA is capable of simultaneously handling multiple input (risk) and multiple output (return) measures, thereby still offering a single real number as a performance index without utilizing subjective weights to aggregate these inputs and outputs. This paper aims at investigating whether DEA-based performance indexes previously used to assess alternative investment fund performance are actually able to satisfy these properties, and to contrast the findings using a DEA-based performance index with those using a traditional financial performance index. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Glawischnig, Markus; Sommersguter-Reichmann, Margit</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extracting inflation expectations and inflation risk premia from the term structure: A joint model of the UK nominal and real yield curves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joyce, Michael A. S.; Lildholdt, Peter; Sorensen, Steffen
This paper analyses the UK interest rate term structure over the period since October 1992, when the United Kingdom adopted an explicit inflation target, using an affine term structure model estimated using both government bond yields and survey data. The model imposes no-arbitrage restrictions across nominal and real yields, which enables interest rates to be decomposed into expected real policy rates, expected inflation, real term premia and inflation risk premia. The model is used to shed light on major developments over the period, including the impact of Bank of England independence and the low real bond yield 'conundrum'. (C) 2009 The Bank of England. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Joyce, Michael A. S.; Lildholdt, Peter; Sorensen, Steffen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real estate prices and bank stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koetter, Michael; Poghosyan, Tigran
Real estate prices can deviate from their fundamental value due to rigid supply, heterogeneity in quality, and various market imperfections, which have two contrasting effects on bank stability. Higher prices increase the value of collateral and net wealth of borrowers and thus reduce the likelihood of credit defaults. In contrast, persistent deviations from fundamentals may foster the adverse selection of increasingly risky creditors by banks seeking to expand their loan portfolios, which increases bank distress probabilities. We test these hypotheses using unique data on real estate markets and banks in Germany. House price deviations contribute to bank instability, but nominal house price developments do not. This finding corroborates the importance of deviations from the fundamental value of real estate, rather than just price levels or changes alone, when assessing bank stability. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koetter, Michael; Poghosyan, Tigran</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model risk and capital reserves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kerkhof, Jeroen; Melenberg, Bertrand; Schumacher, Hans
We propose a procedure to take model risk into account in the computation of capital reserves. This addresses the need to make the allocation of capital reserves to positions in given markets dependent on the extent to which reliable models are available. The proposed procedure can be used in combination with any of the standard risk measures, such as Value-at-Risk and expected shortfall. We assume that models are obtained by usual econometric methods, which allows us to distinguish between estimation risk and misspecification risk. We discuss an additional source of risk which we refer to as identification risk. By way of illustration, we carry out calculations for equity and FX data sets. In both markets, estimation risk and misspecification risk together explain about half of the Multiplication factors employed by the Bank for International Settlements (BIS). (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kerkhof, Jeroen; Melenberg, Bertrand; Schumacher, Hans</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial rights, use of investment banks, and the wealth effects for acquiring firms' shareholders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Weishen; Whyte, Ann Marie
We examine the relation between managerial rights in acquiring firms and the decision to use an investment bank in merger and acquisition deals, and explore whether this relation impacts the wealth effects for acquiring firms' shareholders. We find that acquiring firms whose managers have relatively strong rights are more likely to use investment banks to facilitate deals and are more likely to use reputable banks. The wealth effects to acquiring firms are inversely related to the use of investment banks when managerial rights are relatively strong. However, the wealth loss is mitigated when acquiring firms use reputable investment banks. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Weishen; Whyte, Ann Marie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing catastrophe options with stochastic claim arrival intensity in claim time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Carolyn W.; Chang, Jack S. K.; Lu, WeLi
We model claim arrival and loss uncertainties jointly in a doubly-binomial framework to price an Asian-style catastrophe (CAT) option with a non-traded underlying loss index using the no-arbitrage martingale pricing methodology. We span these uncertainties by benchmarking to the shadow price of a one-claim bond and the premium of a reinsurance contract. We implement a stochastic time change from calendar time to claim time to more efficiently price the CAT option as a random sum - a binomial sum of claim time binomial Asian option prices. This choice of the operational time dimension allows us to incorporate different patterns of catastrophe arrivals by adjusting the claim arrival probability. We demonstrate this versatility by incorporating a mean-reverting Ornstein-Uhlenbeck intensity arrival process. Simulation results verify our model predictions and demonstrate how the claim arrival probability varies with the expected claim arrival intensity. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Carolyn W.; Chang, Jack S. K.; Lu, WeLi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity issues and temporal variation in information asymmetry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Autore, Don M.; Kovacs, Tunde
We investigate the intertemporal relation between information asymmetry and equity issues, and particularly focus on which firms drive this relation. We find that when information asymmetry for a particular firm is low compared to the recent past, the firm is more likely to issue equity as opposed to debt. Importantly, this intertemporal association is driven by firms with high levels of information asymmetry. These firms are more prone to adverse selection costs and thus have more to gain by issuing equity after a narrowing of the information gap between managers and investors. Our findings are robust to various firm-specific proxies for information asymmetry. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Autore, Don M.; Kovacs, Tunde</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The predictive power of the implied volatility of options traded OTC and on exchanges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Wayne W.; Liu, Evans C. K.; Wang, Jacqueline W.
This paper investigates the efficiency of stock index options traded over-the-counter (OTC) and on the exchanges in Hong Kong and Japan. Our findings suggest that implied volatility is superior to either historical volatility or a GARCH-type volatility forecast in predicting future volatility in both the OTC and exchange markets. This paper is also one of the first to compare the predictive power of the implied volatility of stock index options traded OTC to that of exchange-traded stock index options. Our evidence suggests that the OTC market is more efficient than the exchanges in Japan, but that the opposite is true in Hong Kong. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yu, Wayne W.; Liu, Evans C. K.; Wang, Jacqueline W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The index fund rationality paradox</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boldin, Michael; Cici, Gjergji
Mutual funds that track the S&amp;P 500 are popular because they have significantly lower costs than the average, actively managed equity fund. However, a measurable number of investors select index funds with excessive fees and uncompetitive returns. We call this observation the Index Fund Rationality Paradox because it conflicts with the belief that index fund investors are making a rational, low-cost choice in their 'type of fund' decision. In our analysis of this paradox, we find that both retail and institutional index investors tended to make better choices in recent years, but the cost of poor choices among both groups continues to be significant. In fact, we are able to identify an arguably naive group of retail investors that seem to be unduly influenced by brokers and financial advisors. These investors are largely responsible for the remaining paradox. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boldin, Michael; Cici, Gjergji</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification and Value-at-Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perignon, Christophe; Smith, Daniel R.
A pervasive and puzzling feature of banks' Value-at-Risk (VaR) is its abnormally high level, which leads to excessive regulatory capital. A possible explanation for the tendency of commercial banks to overstate their VaR is that they incompletely account for the diversification effect among broad risk categories (e.g., equity, interest rate, commodity, credit spread, and foreign exchange). By underestimating the diversification effect, bank's proprietary VaR models produce overly prudent market risk assessments. In this paper, we examine empirically the validity of this hypothesis using actual VaR data from major US commercial banks. In contrast to the VaR diversification hypothesis, we find that US banks show no sign of systematic underestimation of the diversification effect. In particular, diversification effects used by banks is very close to (and quite often larger than) our empirical diversification estimates. A direct implication of this finding is that individual VaRs for each broad risk category, just like aggregate VaRs, are biased risk assessments. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Perignon, Christophe; Smith, Daniel R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The strategic specialist and imperfect competition in a limit order market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dumitrescu, Ariadna
The empirical literature suggests that the limit order book contains information that might be used by the specialist to his own advantage. I develop a model where there is a strategic specialist who competes against a limit order book and has information about supply. The presence of a strategic specialist in an imperfectly competitive limit order book market induces non-monotonicity of market indicators with respect to the variance of liquidation value. Moreover, the existence of private information about supply significantly affects market performance as it induces, among other effects, lower market liquidity. Finally, this model suggests another link between Kyle's (1985,1989) [Kyle, A., 1985. Continuous auctions and insider trading. Econometrica 53, 1315-1336, Kyle, A., 1989. Informed speculators with imperfect competition. Review of Economic Studies 56, 317-356] and Glosten and Milgrom's (1985) [Glosten, L., Milgrom, P., 1985. Bid, ask and transaction prices in a specialist market with heterogeneously informed markets. Journal of Financial Economics 14, 71-100] models by allowing for strategic behaviour of the specialist. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dumitrescu, Ariadna</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Irish credit unions: Investigating performance determinants and the opportunity cost of regulatory compliance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glass, J. Colin; McKillop, Donal G.; Rasaratnam, Syamarlah
The study investigates how producer-specific environmental factors influence the performance of Irish credit unions. The empirical analysis uses a two-stage approach. The first stage measures efficiency by a data envelopment analysis (DEA) estimator, which explicitly incorporates the production of undesirable outputs such as bad loans in the modelling, and the second stage uses truncated regression to infer how various factors influence the (bias-corrected) estimated efficiency. A key finding of the analysis is that 68% of Irish credit unions do not incur an extra opportunity cost in meeting regulatory guidance on bad debt. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Glass, J. Colin; McKillop, Donal G.; Rasaratnam, Syamarlah</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of regulatory reforms on cost structure, ownership and competition in Indian banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhao, Tianshu; Casu, Barbara; Ferrari, Alessandra
This paper evaluates the impact of financial sector reforms on the cost structure characteristics and on the ownership-cost efficiency relationship in Indian banking. It also examines the impact of reforms on the dynamics of competition in the lending market. We find evidence that deregulation improves banks performance and fosters competition in the lending market. Results suggest technological progress, once Indian commercial banks have adjusted to the new regulatory environment. This, however, does not translate in efficiency gains. There is also evidence of an ownership effect on the level and pattern of efficiency change. Finally, competition keeps building pace even in the re-regulation period and technological improvements are not hampered by the tightening of prudential norms. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhao, Tianshu; Casu, Barbara; Ferrari, Alessandra</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International diversification strategies: Revisited from the risk perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Ye; Green, Christopher J.
Following Roll [Roll, R., 1992. Industrial structure and comparative behaviour of international stock market indices. journal of Finance 47, 3-42] and Heston and Rouwenhorst [Heston, S.L., Rouwenhorst, G.K., 1994. Does industrial structure explain the benefits of international diversification. journal of Financial Economics 36, 3-27], researchers have decomposed stock returns into country and industry components. Evidence suggests that industry components have become more important in recent years, but the reasons for this are unclear. Existing research concentrated mainly on stock returns in industrial countries. In this paper we consider instead the decomposition of stock risks within emerging equity markets. We provide a rationale for this procedure and its relationship to return decompositions. The results provide new firm-specific evidence on the debate over country and industry components, their stability over time, and the implications for portfolio diversification. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bai, Ye; Green, Christopher J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Operational risk and reputation in the financial industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gillet, Roland; Hubner, Georges; Plunus, Severine
By examining stock market reactions to the announcement of operational losses by financial companies, this paper attempts to disentangle operational losses from reputational damage. Our analysis deals with 154 events coming from the FIRST database of OpVantage. Events occurred between 1990 and 2004 in companies belonging to the financial sector and that are listed on the major European and US Stock Exchanges. Results show significant, negative abnormal returns at the announcement date of the loss, along with an increase in the volumes of trade. In cases of internal fraud, the loss in market value is greater that the operational loss amount announced, which is interpreted as a sign of reputational damage. Negative impact is proportionally greater when the loss amount represents a larger share in the company's net profit. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gillet, Roland; Hubner, Georges; Plunus, Severine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does cross-listing facilitate changes in corporate ownership and control?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayyagari, Meghana; Doidge, Craig
This paper examines whether controlling shareholders of foreign firms use a US cross-listing to facilitate changes in ownership and control. Prior to listing, about three quarters of the firms in our sample have a controlling shareholder. After listing, about half of the controlling shareholders' voting rights decrease, with an average decrease of 24% points that differs significantly from that of the controlling shareholders of benchmark firms that do not cross-list. Large decreases in voting rights are associated with controlling shareholder characteristics, domestic market constraints, and better stock market performance and liquidity. In addition, there is control change in 22% of the firms. Controlling shareholders are more likely to sell control, and are more likely to do so to a foreign buyer, than controlling shareholders of benchmark firms. The results suggest that controlling shareholders who want to sell shares or their control stake can use a US cross-listing to decrease the cost of transferring ownership. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ayyagari, Meghana; Doidge, Craig</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reputation stretching in mutual fund starts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hsuan-Chi; Lai, Christine W.
This study examines the role of reputation stretching in the context of mutual funds. We show that the reputation stretching strategy increases net fund inflows to new funds run by well-performing fund managers and yields a net increase of fund inflows to fund families. Reputable fund managers exhibit one-year performance persistence for managing new funds, which can help investors assess managers when selecting funds. We also find that the decrease in information asymmetry associated with managerial reputation benefits investors by leading to an increase in new fund returns in the short run, compared to those of new funds run by managers without track records. Overall, the reputation stretching strategy benefits both investors, by reducing information asymmetry and improving investment returns, and fund families, by increasing net fund inflows to new equity funds. (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chen, Hsuan-Chi; Lai, Christine W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dark side of global integration: Increasing tail dependence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beine, Michel; Cosma, Antonio; Vermeulen, Robert
We measure stock market coexceedances using the methodology of Cappiello, Gerard and Manganelli (2005, ECB Working Paper 501). This method enables us to measure comovement at each point of the return distribution. First, we construct annual coexceedance probabilities for both lower and upper tail return quantiles using daily data from 1974-2006. Next, we explain these probabilities in a panel gravity model framework. Results show that macroeconomic variables asymmetrically impact stock market comovement across the return distribution. Financial liberalization significantly increases left tail comovement, whereas trade integration significantly increases comovement across all quantiles. Decreasing exchange rate volatility results in increasing lower tail comovement. The introduction of the euro increases comovement across the entire return distribution, thereby significantly reducing the benefits of portfolio diversification within the euro area. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beine, Michel; Cosma, Antonio; Vermeulen, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information content of options trading volume for future volatility: Evidence from the Taiwan options market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Chuang-Chang; Hsieh, Pei-Fang; Wang, Yaw-Huei
This study follows the approach of Ni et al. [Ni, S.X., Pan, J., Poteshman, A.M., 2008. Volatility information trading in the option market. journal of Finance 63, 1059-1091] - based upon the vega-weighted net demand for volatility - to determine whether volatility information exists within the Taiwan options market. Our empirical results show that foreign institutional investors possess the strongest and most direct volatility information, which is realized by the delta-neutral options/futures trades. In addition, a few individual investors (less than 1% of individuals' trades) might be informed and realize their volatility information using the strangle strategy. Surprisingly, we find no evidence to support the predictive ability of the volatility demand from straddle trades, despite the widespread acknowledgement that such trades are sensitive to volatility. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Chuang-Chang; Hsieh, Pei-Fang; Wang, Yaw-Huei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is international diversification really beneficial?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>You, Leyuan; Daigler, Robert T.
Previous research claims that low constant correlations among international stock indices create substantial risk-reduction from diversification. We contend that only using constant correlations is too simplistic an approach. We examine international diversification by: (1) using conditional correlations, (2) evaluating tail risk, including the effect of skewness and kurtosis, and (3) examining the possible tradeoffs of standard deviation with correlation, skewness, and kurtosis. We show that conclusions concerning diversification based solely on constant correlations across markets can be misleading, since the diversification benefits are time-varying, are affected by non-normality, and depend on the benchmark (country) employed. Finally, tradeoffs do exist between standard deviation and the other risk factors. (C) Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>You, Leyuan; Daigler, Robert T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial development and asset valuation: The special case of real estate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ebrahim, M. Shahid; Hussain, Sikandar
This paper studies the impact of financial development on asset valuation. We model the agency theoretic perspective of risk-averse investors and financiers in a general equilibrium setting under the framework of rational expectations (i.e., symmetric information). We focus on real estate, as it constitutes a special case of complete market contracting where adverse selection and moral hazard are easily mitigated. Our results illustrate an increase in pareto-efficiency, as financial architecture advances from: (i) banks to capital markets; and (ii) plain vanilla debt to an innovative one with participation clauses. This is attributed to the reduction in agency costs and cross-sectional risk-sharing, leading to an increase in the value of property. Our results predict that an optimal financial system will orient itself towards efficient financial contracts, irrespective of its source of origination. We also rationalize the co-existence of banks and capital markets, and generalize our results under a set of restrictive conditions. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ebrahim, M. Shahid; Hussain, Sikandar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sentiment and the stock market's reaction to monetary policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kurov, Alexander
This paper shows that monetary policy decisions have a significant effect on investor sentiment. The effect of monetary news on sentiment depends on market conditions (bull versus bear market). We also find that monetary policy actions in bear market periods have a larger effect on stocks that are more sensitive to changes in investor sentiment and credit market conditions. Overall, the results show that investor sentiment plays a significant role in the effect of monetary policy on the stock market. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kurov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency, technical change, and returns to scale in large US banks: Panel data evidence from an output distance function satisfying theoretical regularity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, Guohua; Serletis, Apostolos
This paper provides parametric estimates of technical change, efficiency change, economies of scale, and total factor productivity growth for large banks (those with assets in excess of $1 billion) in the United States, over the period from 2000 to 2005. This is done by estimating an output distance function subject to theoretical regularity within a Bayesian framework. We find that failure to incorporate theoretical regularity conditions results in mismeasured shadow revenue and/or cost shares, which in turn leads to perverse conclusions regarding productivity growth. Our results from the regularity-constrained model show that total factor productivity of the large US banks grew at an average rate of 1.98% over the sample period. However, Our estimates also show a clear downward trend in the growth rate of total factor productivity and our decomposition of the primal Divisia total factor productivity growth index into its three components - technical change, efficiency change, and economies of scale - indicates that technical change is the driving force behind this decline. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Feng, Guohua; Serletis, Apostolos</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The S&amp;P500 index effect reconsidered: Evidence from overnight and intraday stock price performance and volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kappou, Konstantina; Brooks, Chris; Ward, Charles
This study focuses on S&amp;P500 inclusions and deletions, examining the impact of potential overnight price adjustment after the announcement of an S&amp;P500 index change. We find evidence of a significant overnight price change that diminishes the returns available to speculators although there are still profits available from the first day after announcement until a few days after the actual event. More importantly, observing the tick-by-tick stock price performance and volume effects on the key days during the event window for the first time, we find evidence of consistent trading patterns during trading hours. A separate analysis of NASDAQ and NYSE listed stocks allows for a detailed examination of the price and volume effect at an intra-day level. We find that index funds appear to cluster their rebalancing activities near to and after the close on the event date, suggesting that they are more concerned with tracking error than profit. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kappou, Konstantina; Brooks, Chris; Ward, Charles</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conglomerate investment under various capital market conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yan, An; Yang, Zaihui; Jiao, Jie
This paper studies the investment of diversified and focused firms under various capital market conditions. When external capital becomes more costly at the aggregate level, investment declines in focused firms but remains unchanged in diversified firms. This investment advantage enjoyed by diversified firms could attribute to both their easy access to external capital and their ability to substitute internal capital markets for costly external markets. Consistent with the internal capital market argument, our findings show that the investment advantage exists for diversified firms even after we control for their easy access to external markets. We also find that the role of internal markets in financing investment is more important for diversified firms that are more financially constrained in external markets. Finally, we find that the segment-level investment becomes more efficient in conglomerates' internal capital markets under depressed external capital market conditions. Overall, our findings suggest that internal capital allocation functions as a valuable and efficient substitute for diversified firms in a tightened external capital market. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yan, An; Yang, Zaihui; Jiao, Jie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity fund ownership and the cross-regional diversification of household risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Sascha O.; Hoffmann, Mathias
We explore the link between portfolio home bias and consumption risk sharing among Italian regions using household-level information on consumption, income and portfolio holdings. Since equity funds are typically diversified at the national or international level, we use data on equity fund ownership to proxy for regional home bias. Cross-regional patterns of equity fund ownership are qualitatively consistent with simple portfolio theory: regions with more asymmetric business cycles are more diversified because they have higher fund participation rates (the extensive margin of diversification) and higher average holdings of equity funds (diversification's intensive margin). Also, fund holdings increase with the exposure of non-tradable income components (such as labor or entrepreneurial income) to regional shocks. Finally, interregional consumption risk sharing increases with fund holdings and this effect seems strongest when participation is widespread. Increased equity market participation could substantially improve interregional risk sharing. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Becker, Sascha O.; Hoffmann, Mathias</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tight bounds on American option prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, San-Lin; Hung, Mao-Wei; Wang, Jr-Yan
In contrast to the constant exercise boundary assumed by Broadie and Detemple (1996) [Broadie, M., Detemple, J., 1996. American option valuation: New bounds, approximations, and comparison of existing methods. Review of Financial Studies 9, 1211-1250], we use an exponential function to approximate the early exercise boundary. Then, we obtain lower bounds for American option prices and the optimal exercise boundary which improve the bounds of Broadie and Detemple (1996). With the tight lower bound for the optimal exercise boundary, we further derive a tight upper bound for the American option price using the early exercise premium integral of Kim (1990) [Kim, I.j., 1990. The analytic valuation of American options. Review of Financial Studies 3, 547-572]. The numerical results show that our lower and upper bounds are very tight and can improve the pricing errors of the lower bound and upper bound of Broadie and Detemple (1996) by 83.0% and 87.5%, respectively. The tightness of our upper bounds is comparable to some best accurate/efficient methods in the literature for pricing American options. Moreover, the results also indicate that the hedge ratios (deltas and gammas) of our bounds are close to the accurate values of American options. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, San-Lin; Hung, Mao-Wei; Wang, Jr-Yan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate insider trading: Contrarian beliefs or superior information?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Xiaoquan; Zaman, Mir A.
We decompose realized market returns into expected return, unexpected cash-flow news and unexpected discount rate news to test the relation between aggregate market returns and aggregate insider trading. We find that (1) the predictive ability of aggregate insider trading is much stronger than what was reported in earlier studies, (2) aggregate insider trading is strongly related to unexpected cash-flow news, (3) market expectations do not cause insider trading contrary to what others have documented, and (4) aggregate insider trading in firms with high information uncertainty is more likely to be associated with contrarian investment strategy. These results strongly suggest that the predictive ability of aggregate insider trading is because of insider's ability to predict future cash-flow news rather than from adopting a contrarian investment strategy. These results hold even after we control for non-informative trades and information uncertainty. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Xiaoquan; Zaman, Mir A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pension regulation and the market value of pension liabilities: A contingent claims analysis using Parisian options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Broeders, Dirk; Chen, An
We analyze the market-consistent valuation of pension liabilities in a contingent claim framework whereby a knock-out barrier feature is applied to capture early regulatory closure of a pension plan. We investigate two cases which we call "immediate closure procedure" and "delayed closure procedure". In an immediate closure procedure, when the assets value hits the regulatory boundary, the pension plan is terminated immediately. Whereas in a delayed closure procedure, a grace period is given to the pension fund for reorganization and recovery before premature closure is executed. The framework is then used to construct fair pension deals. Furthermore, we provide rules for deriving the optimal recovery period in pension regulation using utility analysis and interconnect the recovery period to the regulatory liquidation probability. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Broeders, Dirk; Chen, An</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of shareholder value in European banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fiordelisi, Franco; Molyneux, Phil
This paper examines the determinants of shareholder value creation for a large sample of European banks between 1998 and 2005. As the recent turmoil in global banking systems has illustrated, bank performance can have a substantial influence on efficient capital allocation, company growth and economic development. We use a dynamic panel data model where the bank's shareholder value is a linear function of various bank-specific, industry-specific and macroeconomic variables. We show that shareholder value has a positive relationship with cost efficiency changes, while economic profits are linked to revenue efficiency changes. Credit losses, market and liquidity risk and leverage are also found to substantially influence bank performance. These results are robust to a variety of different model specifications. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fiordelisi, Franco; Molyneux, Phil</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictable dynamics in implied volatility surfaces from OTC currency options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chalamandaris, Georgios; Tsekrekos, Andrianos E.
Recent empirical studies report predictable dynamics in the volatility surfaces that are implied by observed index option prices, such as those prescribed by general equilibrium models. Using an extensive data set from the over-the-counter options market, we document similar predictability in the factors that capture the daily variation of surfaces implied by options on 25 different foreign exchange rates. We proceed to demonstrate that simple vector autoregressive specifications for the factors can help produce accurate out-of-sample forecasts of the systematic component of the surface at short horizons. Profitable delta-hedged positions can be set up based on these forecasts; however, profits disappear when typical transaction costs are taken into account and when trading rules on wide segments of the surface are sought. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chalamandaris, Georgios; Tsekrekos, Andrianos E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CAPM and APT-like models with risk measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balbas, Alejandro; Balbas, Beatriz; Balbas, Raquel
The paper deals with optimal portfolio choice problems when risk levels are given by coherent risk measures, expectation bounded risk measures or general deviations. Both static and dynamic pricing models may be involved. Unbounded problems are characterized by new notions such as (strong) compatibility between prices and risks. Surprisingly, the lack of bounded optimal risk and/or return levels arises for important pricing models (Black and Scholes) and risk measures (VaR, CVaR, absolute deviation, etc.). Bounded problems present a Market Price of Risk and generate a pair of benchmarks. From these benchmarks we introduce APT and CAPM-like analyses, in the sense that the level of correlation between every available security and some economic factors explains the security expected return. The risk level non correlated with these factors has no influence on any return, despite the fact that we are dealing with risk functions beyond the standard deviation. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balbas, Alejandro; Balbas, Beatriz; Balbas, Raquel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>World market risk, country-specific risk and expected returns in international stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret
This paper determines whether the world market risk, country-specific total risk, and country-specific idiosyncratic risk are priced in an international capital asset pricing model (ICAPM). Portfolio-level analyses, country-level cross-sectional regressions, stacked time-series, and pooled panel regressions indicate that the world market risk is not, but country-specific total and idiosyncratic risks are significantly priced in an ICAPM framework with partial integration. This result is robust to different methods for estimating risk measures, different investment horizons, and after controlling for the countries' aggregate dividend yield, earnings-to-price ratios, inflation risk, exchange rate uncertainties, aggregate volatility risk, and past return characteristics. The main findings turn out to be insensitive to the choice of one-factor vs. multifactor models used to estimate systematic and idiosyncratic risk measures. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Domestic liquidity and cross-listing in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, Henk; Nguyen, Nhut H.
This study examines changes in domestic liquidity after cross-listing in the United States. Our liquidity measures are based on intraday data from domestic markets for a large sample of firms that cross-list in the United States and for a matched sample of firms that do not cross-list. We find that unadjusted liquidity significantly improves after cross-listing. However, after controlling for contemporaneous changes in liquidity for a matched sample of firms that do not cross-list, there is no evidence of improvements in domestic liquidity due to cross-listing. Our results offer no support for the bonding hypothesis, or for the hypothesis that cross-listing improves domestic liquidity because of increased intermarket competition and additional order flow. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berkman, Henk; Nguyen, Nhut H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity financing and innovation: Is Europe different from the United States?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martinsson, Gustav
During the mid and late 1990s young, high-tech firms in the US experienced a supply shift in both internal and external equity fueling a finance-driven boom in corporate R&amp;D. This paper examines whether R&amp;D spending in Europe in a similar way was sensitive to fluctuations in the supply of internal and external equity during the late 1990s and early 2000s. I conjecture that UK and Continental Europe, due to their different financial systems, differ in terms of equity supply. I estimate dynamic R&amp;D regression models for UK and Continental European high-tech firms separately and find significant joint cash-flow effects for newly listed firms in both samples. However, only new firms in the UK experienced a joint external equity effect as well. The findings of this paper suggest a channel through which market-based financial systems outperform the bank-based economies of Continental Europe. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Martinsson, Gustav</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A stochastic dominance analysis of yen carry trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fong, Wai Mun
Yen carry trades have made headline news for over a decade. We examine the profitability of such trades for the period 2001-2009. Yen carry trades generated high mean returns and Sharpe ratios prior to the recent financial crisis. They continued to outperform major stock markets for the full sample period. Given the non-normality of carry trade returns, we apply non-parametric tests based on stochastic dominance (SD) to evaluate whether the high returns of yen carry trades are compatible with risk as reflected in returns on US and global stock market indices. We apply a general test for SD developed recently by Linton, Maasoumi and Whang (2005) to six currencies as well as portfolios of these currencies. For a large class of risk-averse investors, profits from yen carry trades cannot be attributed to risks. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fong, Wai Mun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of household and business credit in banking crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buyukkarabacak, Berrak; Valev, Neven T.
Private credit expansions are an important predictor of subsequent banking crises. We revisit that result with a new dataset from developed and developing countries that decomposes private credit into household credit and enterprise credit. We argue that household credit growth raises debt levels without much effect on long-term income. Rapid household credit expansions generate vulnerabilities that can precipitate a banking crisis. Enterprise credit expansions can have the same effects but it is tempered by the associated increase in income. Our estimates show that household credit expansions have been a statistically and economically significant predictor of banking crises. Enterprise credit expansions are also associated with banking crises but their effect is weaker and less robust. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buyukkarabacak, Berrak; Valev, Neven T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stated and revealed investment decisions concerning retail structured products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doebeli, Barbara; Vanini, Paolo
We analyze the investment behavior of private clients with regard to retail structured products. To ascertain their stated and revealed preferences, we use a questionnaire and a field experiment. The real product issued in the field experiment is comparable to the hypothetical product in the questionnaire in terms of both payoff and communication. We find that a product described in simple words strongly motivates people to invest in structured products for the first time, and also eliminates gender differences. However, the real product attracts far fewer first-time buyers than we expected from the questionnaire results. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doebeli, Barbara; Vanini, Paolo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic risks and characteristic-based factor models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aretz, Kevin; Bartram, Soehnke M.; Pope, Peter F.
We show that book-to-market, size, and momentum capture cross-sectional variation in exposures to a broad set of macroeconomic factors identified in the prior literature as potentially important for pricing equities. The factors considered include innovations in economic growth expectations, inflation, the aggregate survival probability, the term structure of interest rates, and the exchange rate. Factor mimicking portfolios constructed on the basis of book-to-market, size, and momentum therefore, serve as proxy composite macroeconomic risk factors. Conditional and unconditional cross-sectional asset pricing tests indicate that most of the macroeconomic factors considered are priced. The performance of an asset pricing model based on the macroeconomic factors is comparable to the performance of the Fama and French (1993) model. However, the momentum factor is found to contain incremental information for asset pricing. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aretz, Kevin; Bartram, Soehnke M.; Pope, Peter F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling of CPDOs - Identifying optimal and implied leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dorn, Jochen
When the subprime crisis started to emerge, collateralized products based on credit default swap (CDS) exposures combined with security features seemed to be a more rational alternative to classic asset backed securities. Constant Proportion Collateralized Debt Obligations (CPDOs) are a mixture of Collateralized Debt Obligations (CDOs) and CPPIs with inverse mechanism. This new asset aims at meeting the investors' demand for credit derivatives with security enhancements, but to our knowledge quantitative approaches for pricing other than simulation algorithms do not exist yet. CPDOs became famous notably by Standard &amp; Poor's rating model error which illustrated that closed-form analytical pricing is necessary in order to evaluate and understand complex derivatives. This article aims to shed a light on CPDOs' specific structural enhancements and mechanisms. We quantify inherent risks and provide a dynamic closed-form pricing formula. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dorn, Jochen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pricing of temperature futures at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dorfleitner, Gregor; Wimmer, Maximilian
This paper analyzes observed prices of US temperature futures at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME). Results show that an index modeling approach without detrending captures the prices exceptionally well. Moreover, weather forecasts significantly influence prices up to 11 days ahead. It is shown that valuations of temperature futures relying on a model without detrending yield biased valuations by over-pricing winter contracts and underpricing summer contracts. Several trading strategies are devised to exploit the mispricing observed at the CME and to demonstrate that speculating on temperature futures can not only generate high overall returns, but also perform well on a risk-adjusted basis. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dorfleitner, Gregor; Wimmer, Maximilian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's in a name? What leads a firm to change its name and what the new name foreshadows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, YiLin
This paper examines corporate name changes. This paper connects different types of corporate name changes to the reputational concerns that precede them and to the important corporate events and performance changes that follow them. The empirical results suggest that a firm adopts a radically different name to disassociate from a poor reputation, the name of one of its well-recognized brands to associate with a good reputation, or a minor change in its name by adding or deleting a part of its name that identifies it with a particular product to accompany a narrower business focus or a broader business focus. The empirical results also suggest that, except for radical name changes, significant organizational upheaval follows most corporate name changes. The strength of the firm's subsequent economic performance is tied to changes in the business direction that the type of name change foreshadows. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, YiLin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variations in sovereign credit quality assessments across rating agencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hill, Paula; Brooks, Robert; Faff, Robert
We investigate agency variation in credit quality assessment (Standard and Poor's vs. Moody's vs. Fitch) employing sovereign ratings data for 129 countries, spanning the period 1990-2006. While we find that the credit rating agencies often disagree about credit quality, it is usually confined to one or two notches on the finer scale. We find that several variables have varying importance in explaining ratings across agencies which leads us to conclude that material heterogeneity exists between them. Also, while watch and outlook procedures are generally strong predictors of rating changes relative to other public data, additional significant variables suggest that it might be possible to augment these agency data to provide better forecasts of future rating changes. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hill, Paula; Brooks, Robert; Faff, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sentiment and stock returns: The SAD anomaly revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, Patrick J.; Meschke, Felix
Widely-cited research by Kamstra et al. (2003) argues that changes in mood resulting from Seasonal Affective Disorder (SAD) drive changes in investor risk aversion and cause seasonal patterns in aggregate stock returns around the world. In this paper we reexamine the so-called SAD effect by replicating and extending Kamstra et al. (2003). We study the psychological underpinnings of the SAD hypothesis and show that the time-series predictions of the SAD model do not correspond to the seasonal patterns in depression found in the general population. We also investigate the cross-sectional prediction that SAD has a greater effect on stock markets in countries where SAD is more prevalent and find no relation between the prevalence of SAD and stock returns. Finally, we document that the SAD effect is mechanically driven by an overlapping dummy-variable specification and higher returns around the turn of the year. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kelly, Patrick J.; Meschke, Felix</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate deregulation: Monetary policy efficacy and rate rigidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chong, Beng Soon
This paper examines the effects of interest rate regulation, and subsequent deregulation, on the efficacy of monetary policy and rigidity of retail bank deposit rates in Hong Kong. Using an error-correction model, we find that interest rate deregulation increases the efficacy of monetary policy by improving the correlation between retail bank deposit rates and market interest rates and increasing the degree of long-term pass-through for retail bank deposit rates. Our study also shows that the adjustments in retail bank deposit rates are asymmetric and rigid upwards during the regulated period, but tend to be rigid downwards during the deregulated period. The spreads between retail bank deposit rates and market rates have also tightened sharply after the removal of interest rate controls. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chong, Beng Soon</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading strategies with partial access to the derivatives market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Muck, Matthias
This research analyzes trading strategies with derivatives when there are several assets and risk factors. We investigate portfolio improvement if investors have full and partial access to the derivatives markets, i.e. situations in which derivatives are written on some but not all stocks or risk factors traded on the market. The focus is on markets with jump risk. In these markets the choice of optimal exposures to jump and diffusion risk is linked. In a numerical application we study the potential benefit from adding derivatives to the market. It turns out that e.g. diffusion correlation and volatility or jump sizes may have a significant impact on the benefit of a new derivative product even if market prices of risk remain unchanged. Given the structure of risk investors may have different preferences for making risk factors tradable. Utility gains provided by new derivatives may be both increasing or decreasing depending on the type of contract added. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Muck, Matthias</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The anatomy of bank diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elsas, Ralf; Hackethal, Andreas; Holzhaeuser, Markus
We use panel data from nine countries over the period 1996-2008 to test how revenue diversification affects bank value. Relying on a comprehensive framework for bank performance measurement, we find robust evidence against a conglomerate discount, unlike studies concerned with industrial firms. Rather, diversification increases bank profitability and, as a consequence also market valuations. This indirect performance effect does not depend on whether diversification was achieved through organic growth or through M&amp;A activity. We further demonstrate that previous results in the literature on the impact of diversification on bank value presumably differ due to the way diversification is measured, and the negligence of the indirect value effect via bank profitability. Our evidence against a conglomerate discount in banking remains robust also during the sub-prime crisis. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elsas, Ralf; Hackethal, Andreas; Holzhaeuser, Markus</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock returns and inflation revisited: An evaluation of the inflation illusion hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Bong Soo
Several hypotheses have been proposed to explain the stock return-inflation relation. The Modigliani and Cohn's inflation illusion hypothesis has received renewed attention. Another hypothesis is the two-regime hypothesis. We reexamine these hypotheses using long sample data of the US and international data. We find that the inflation illusion hypothesis can explain the post-war negative stock return-inflation relation, but it is not compatible with the pre-war positive relation. Using a structural VAR identification method, we show that there are two regimes with positive and negative stock return-inflation relations not only in each period of the US but also in every developed country we consider. This seems inconsistent with the inflation illusion hypothesis that predicts only a negative relation. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Bong Soo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of implied volatilities and model-free volatility expectations: Evidence from options written on individual stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Stephen J.; Yadav, Pradeep K.; Zhang, Yuanyuan
We measure the volatility information content of stock options for individual firms using option prices for 149 US firms and the S&amp;P 100 index. We use ARCH and regression models to compare volatility forecasts defined by historical stock returns, at-the-money implied volatilities and model-free volatility expectations for every firm. For 1-day-ahead estimation, a historical ARCH model outperforms both of the volatility estimates extracted from option prices for 36% of the firms, but the option forecasts are nearly always more informative for those firms that have the more actively traded options. When the prediction horizon extends until the expiry date of the options, the option forecasts are more informative than the historical volatility for 85% of the firms. However, at-the-money implied volatilities generally outperform the model-free volatility expectations. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Taylor, Stephen J.; Yadav, Pradeep K.; Zhang, Yuanyuan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation risk and international asset returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moerman, Gerard A.; van Dijk, Mathijs A.
We show that inflation risk is priced in international asset returns. We analyze inflation risk in a framework that encompasses the International Capital Asset Pricing Model (ICAPM) of Adler and Dumas (1983). In contrast to the extant empirical literature on the ICAPM, we relax the assumption that inflation rates are constant. We estimate and test a conditional version of the model for the G5 countries (France, Germany, Japan. the UK, and the US) over the period 1975-1998 and find evidence of statistically and economically significant prices of inflation risk (in addition to priced nominal exchange rate risk). Our results imply a rejection of the restrictions imposed by the ICAPM. In an extension of our analysis to 2003, we show that even after the termination of nominal exchange rate fluctuations in the euro area in 1999, differences in inflation rates across countries entail non-trivial real exchange rate risk premia. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moerman, Gerard A.; van Dijk, Mathijs A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric effects of federal funds target rate changes on S&amp;P100 stock returns, volatilities and correlations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chulia, Helena; Martens, Martin; van Dijk, Dick
We study the effects of FOMC announcements of federal funds target rate decisions on individual stock returns, volatilities and correlations at the intraday level. For all three characteristics we find that the stock market responds differently to positive and negative target rate surprises. First, the average response to positive surprises (that is, bad news for stocks) is larger. Second, in case of bad news the mere occurrence of a surprise matters most, whereas for good news its magnitude is more important. These new insights are possible due to the use of high-frequency intraday data. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chulia, Helena; Martens, Martin; van Dijk, Dick</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discount window borrowing after 2003: The explicit reduction in implicit costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Artuc, Erhan; Demiralp, Selva
In 2003, the Federal Reserve introduced primary credit as its main discount window lending program. This program replaced the adjustment credit program, which, subject to a number of restrictions, had generated a stigma associated with borrowing from the Federal Reserve. Lessening the stigma of borrowing was viewed as essential for reducing the reluctance to borrow from the Federal Reserve. We develop a structural model of daily borrowing. Using this model, we estimate the implicit cost associated with borrowing. Our results suggest that the stigma of borrowing is significantly reduced. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Artuc, Erhan; Demiralp, Selva</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Antitakeover provisions in corporate spin-offs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Jordan, Bradford D.; Liu, Mark H.; Wu, Qun
We analyze the relation between antitakeover provisions (ATPs) and the performance of spin-off firms. We find that firms protected by more ATPs before spin-offs have higher abnormal announcement returns and greater improvements in post-spin-off operating performance than firms with fewer ATPs. Further, firms that reduce the number of ATPs after spin-offs have greater improvements in operating performance than firms that do not reduce the number of ATPs. Finally, CEOs of pre-spin-off firms tend to retain more ATPs in parent firms and assign fewer ATPs to the spun-off units if they remain as the CEOs of the parents but not the spun-off units. Overall, our results indicate a positive relation between ATPs and the value gains to spin-offs. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Jordan, Bradford D.; Liu, Mark H.; Wu, Qun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund portfolio trading and investor flow</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dubofsky, David A.
I estimate the extent to which mutual fund portfolio trading of securities is triggered by investor flows into and out of the funds, and find that this liquidity-induced portfolio trading activity is smaller than previously estimated by Edelen (1999). I obtain estimates from a much larger and broader sample of funds than Edelen's (1999) sample. Portfolio managers of international funds trade a smaller fraction of investor flow than do those of domestic funds. Index funds invest a larger fraction. A funds' usage of futures contracts does not have a statistically significant effect on how it trades in response to investor flows, but the unpredictability of investor flow weakly affects the trading response to flow. (C) 2009 Elsevier Boy. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dubofsky, David A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing multiasset equity options: How relevant is the dependence function?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bedendo, Mascia; Campolongo, Francesca; Joossens, Elisabeth; Saita, Francesco
In this paper we test how different choices for the dependence function can affect the prices of a set of multiasset equity options. We conduct the analysis for various 5-dimensional baskets of UK shares, and a wide range of payoffs for the multiasset options, consistent with the instruments traded on the market. We also test the relevance of the dependence specification over both volatile and quiet market scenarios. Interestingly, we find that, in most circumstances, the choice of a dependence structure richer than the standard linear correlation does not seem to affect option prices substantially. However, the dependence function becomes more relevant in particularly volatile market conditions. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bedendo, Mascia; Campolongo, Francesca; Joossens, Elisabeth; Saita, Francesco</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of sell-side analyst research coverage on an affiliated broker's market share of trading volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niehaus, Greg; Zhang, Donghang
Using NASDAQ reported individual stock level trading volume, we find that analyst research coverage on a stock increases the level of an affiliated broker's market share of trading volume in that stock by 0.8%, on average, which corresponds to an additional annual volume of about one million shares in an average stock. Optimistic recommendations increase the level of market share by an additional 0.3%, on average, which is consistent with the notion that analysts have an incentive to issue optimistic recommendations. Also, a broker's market share of volume increases on average when an affiliated analyst changes his/her recommendation, and decreases with the length of time during which an analyst maintains the same recommendation on a stock. The latter findings suggest that sell-side institutions are rewarded for providing new information to the market and for on-going research services. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Niehaus, Greg; Zhang, Donghang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the implications of market power in banking: Evidence from developing countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ariss, Rima Turk
This paper investigates how different degrees of market power affect bank efficiency and stability in the context of developing economies. It sheds light on the competition-stability nexus by documenting and analyzing the complex interactions between a tripod of variables that are central for regulators: the degree of market power, bank cost and profit efficiency, and overall firm stability. The results show that an increase in the degree of market power leads to greater bank stability and enhanced profit efficiency, despite significant cost efficiency losses. The findings lend empirical justification to the traditional view that increased competition may undermine bank stability, and may bear significant implications for stressed banking systems in developing economies. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ariss, Rima Turk</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recovery rates, default probabilities, and the credit cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruche, Max; Gonzalez-Aguado, Carlos
In recessions, the number of defaulting firms rises. On top of this, the average amount recovered on the bonds of defaulting firms tends to decrease. This paper proposes an econometric model in which this joint time-variation in default rates and recovery rate distributions is driven by an unobserved Markov chain, which we interpret as the "credit cycle". This model is shown to fit better than models in which this joint time-variation is driven by observed macroeconomic variables. We use the model to quantitatively assess the importance of allowing for systematic time-variation in recovery rates, which is often ignored in risk management and pricing models. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bruche, Max; Gonzalez-Aguado, Carlos</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market conditions, default risk and credit spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tang, Dragon Yongjun; Yan, Hong
This study empirically examines the impact of the interaction between market and default risk on corporate credit spreads. Using credit default swap (CDS) spreads, we find that average credit spreads decrease in GDP growth rate, but increase in GDP growth volatility and jump risk in the equity market. At the market level, investor sentiment is the most important determinant of credit spreads. At the firm level, credit spreads generally rise with cash flow volatility and beta, with the effect of cash flow beta varying with market conditions. We identify implied volatility as the most significant determinant of default risk among firm-level characteristics. Overall, a major portion of individual credit spreads is accounted for by firm-level determinants of default risk, while macroeconomic variables are directly responsible for a lesser portion. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tang, Dragon Yongjun; Yan, Hong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An economic capital model integrating credit and interest rate risk in the banking book</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alessandri, Piergiorgio; Drehmann, Mathias
Banks often measure credit and interest rate risk in the banking book separately and then add the risk measures to determine economic capital. This approach misses complex interactions between the two risk types. We develop a framework where these risks are analysed jointly. Since banking book positions are generally not marked to market, our model is based on book value accounting. Our simulations show that interactions matter, and that ignoring them leads to risk overstatement. The magnitude of the errors depends on the structure of the balance sheet and on the repricing characteristics of assets and liabilities. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alessandri, Piergiorgio; Drehmann, Mathias</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The integrated impact of credit and interest rate risk on banks: A dynamic framework and stress testing application</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drehmann, Mathias; Sorensen, Steffen; Stringa, Marco
Credit and interest rate risk are the two most important risks faced by commercial banks in their banking book. In this paper we derive a consistent and comprehensive framework to measure the integrated impact of both risks. By taking account of the repricing characteristics of assets, liabilities and off balance sheet items, we assess the integrated impact of credit and interest rate risk on banks' economic value and capital adequacy. We then stress test a hypothetical but realistic bank using our framework and show that it is fundamental to measure the impact of credit and interest rate risk jointly. Crown Copyright (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Drehmann, Mathias; Sorensen, Steffen; Stringa, Marco</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does adding up of economic capital for market- and credit risk amount to conservative risk assessment?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Thomas; Jandacka, Martin; Rheinberger, Klaus; Summer, Martin
There is a tradition in the banking industry of dividing risk into market risk and credit risk. Both categories are treated independently in the calculation of risk capital. But many financial positions depend simultaneously on both market risk and credit risk factors. In this case, an approximation of the portfolio value function separating value changes into a pure market risk plus pure credit risk component can result not only in an overestimation, but also in an underestimation of risk. We discuss this compounding effect in the context of foreign currency loans and argue that a separate calculation of economic capital for market risk and for credit risk may significantly underestimate true risk. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Breuer, Thomas; Jandacka, Martin; Rheinberger, Klaus; Summer, Martin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interaction of market and credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartmann, Philipp
Experience during the financial crisis illustrates that the integrated measurement and management of different forms of risk remains a challenge for industry practitioners, researchers and financial supervisors alike. In the context of related literature, this article summarizes new research on the interaction of market and credit risk and implications for risk management that is presented in this special issue. The research covered highlights in particular the errors that can occur in the aggregation of the two types of risk and the strong relationships between them that suggest caution in the use of pragmatic distinctions between them. The article also touches on some research-based lessons for supervisory policies and suggests some directions for future research. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hartmann, Philipp</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mean-variance convergence around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eun, Cheol S.; Lee, Jinsoo
In this paper, we show (i) that the risk-return characteristics of our sample of 17 developed stock markets of the world have converged significantly toward each other during our study period 1974-2007, and (ii) that this international convergence in risk-return characteristics is driven mainly by the declining 'country effect', rather than the rising 'industry effect', suggesting that the convergence is associated with international market integration. Specifically, we first compute the risk-return distance among international stock markets based on the Euclidean distance and find that the distance thus computed has been decreasing significantly over time, implying a mean-variance convergence. In particular, the average risk-return distance has decreased by about 50% over our sample period. We also document that the risk-return characteristics of our sample of 14 emerging markets have been converging rapidly toward those of developed markets in recent years. This development notwithstanding, emerging markets still remain as a distinct asset class. Lastly, we show that the convergence in risk-return characteristics has exerted a negative impact on the efficiency of international investment during our sample period. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eun, Cheol S.; Lee, Jinsoo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign exchange, fractional cointegration and the implied-realized volatility relation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kellard, Neil; Dunis, Christian; Sarantis, Nicholas
Almost all relevant literature has characterized implied volatility as a biased predictor of realized volatility. In this paper we provide new time series techniques to investigate the validity of this finding in several foreign exchange options markets, including the Euro market. First, we develop a new fractional cointegration test that is shown to be robust to both stationary and non-stationary regions. Second, we employ both intra-day and daily data to measure realized volatility in order to assess the relevance of data frequency in resolving the bias. Third, we use data on implied volatility traded on the market. In contrast to previous studies, we show that the frequency of data used for measuring realized volatility within a fractionally cointegrating framework is important for the results of unbiasedness tests. Significantly, for many popular exchange rates, the use of intra-day rather than daily data affects the emergence of a different bias, as the possibility of a fractionally integrated risk premium admits itself! (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kellard, Neil; Dunis, Christian; Sarantis, Nicholas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How bank capital buffers vary across countries: The influence of cost of deposits, market power and bank regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosa Fonseca, Ana; Gonzalez, Francisco
This paper analyzes the bank and country determinants of capital buffers using a panel data of 1337 banks in 70 countries between 1992 and 2002. After controlling for adjustment costs and the endogeneity of explanatory variables, the results show that capital buffers are positively related to the cost of deposits and bank market power, although the relations vary across countries depending on regulation, supervision, and institutions. Their impact is the result of two generally opposing effects: restrictions on bank activities and official supervision reduce the incentives to hold capital buffers by weakening market discipline, but at the same time they promote higher capital buffers by increasing market power. Institutional quality has the two opposite effects. Better accounting disclosure and less generous deposit insurance, however, have a clear positive effect on capital buffers by both strengthening market discipline and making charter value better able to reduce risk-taking incentives. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rosa Fonseca, Ana; Gonzalez, Francisco</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Random walk theory and the weak-form efficiency of the US art auction prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erdos, Peter; Ormos, Mihaly
We perform variance ratio tests based on non-parametric methods to detect the size of the random walk component of the US art auction prices. The past 134 years of the US art prices exhibit large transitory component (72%) and based on this, the random walk hypothesis does not hold. However, possibly due to sparse data before 1935 or due to institutional changes of the art market after World War II, we detect structural breakpoints and find that the random walk hypothesis and the weak-form efficiency of the US art market cannot be rejected at least for the past 64 years. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Erdos, Peter; Ormos, Mihaly</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment horizon and the attractiveness of investment strategies: A behavioral approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dierkes, Maik; Erner, Carsten; Zeisberger, Stefan
We analyze the attractiveness of investment strategies over a variety of investment horizons from the viewpoint of an investor with preferences described by Cumulative Prospect Theory (CPT), currently the most prominent descriptive theory for decision making under uncertainty. A bootstrap technique is applied using historical return data of 1926-2008. To allow for variety in investors' preferences, we conduct several sensitivity analyses and further provide robustness checks for the results. In addition, we analyze the attractiveness of the investment strategies based on a set of experimentally elicited preference parameters. Our study reveals that strategy attractiveness substantially depends on the investment horizon. While for almost every preference parameter combination a bond strategy is preferred for the short run, stocks show an outperformance for longer horizons. Portfolio insurance turns out to be attractive for almost every investment horizon. Interestingly, we find probability weighting to be a driving factor for insurance strategies' attractiveness. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dierkes, Maik; Erner, Carsten; Zeisberger, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>World War II events and the Dow Jones industrial index</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choudhry, Taufiq
This paper investigates which events of World War II (WWII) the US investors (at that time) considered as turning points (structural breaks) of the war. The empirical study employs daily Dow Jones industrial average stock index and volatility from January 1939 to December 1945 and applies structural shift oriented test to determine endogenously the structural breaks during the WWII period. Results show that the majority of the wartime events (on and off the battlefield) labelled important by historians did result in structural breaks in both price movement and stock returns volatility (risk). These results have major implications for investors of the present and future. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choudhry, Taufiq</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unobservable shocks as carriers of contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dungey, Mardi; Milunovich, George; Thorp, Susan
We propose an identified structural GARCH model to disentangle the dynamics of financial market crises. We distinguish between the hypersensitivity of a domestic market in crisis to news from foreign non-crisis markets, and the contagion imported to a tranquil domestic market from foreign crises. The model also enables us to connect unobserved structural shocks with their source markets using variance decompositions and to compare the size and dynamics of impulses during crises periods with tranquil period impulses. To illustrate, we apply the method to data from the 1997-1998 Asian financial crisis which consists of a complicated set of interacting crises. We find significant hypersensitivity and contagion between these markets but also show that links may strengthen or weaken. Impulse response functions for an equally-weighted equity portfolio show the increasing dominance of Korean and Hong Kong shocks during the crises and covariance responses demonstrate multiple layers of contagion effects. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dungey, Mardi; Milunovich, George; Thorp, Susan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>China's official rates and bond yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, Longzhen; Johansson, Anders C.
Recent research shows that bond yields are influenced by monetary policy decisions. To learn how this works in a bond market that differs significantly from those in the US and Europe, we model Chinese bond yields using the one-year deposit interest rate as a state variable. We also include the spread between the one-year market interest rate and the one-year deposit interest rate as another factor. The model is developed in an affine framework and closed-form solutions are obtained. We then test the model empirically with a Markov Chain Monte Carlo simulation procedure. The results show that the new model that incorporates the official rate in China characterizes the changing shape of the yield curve well. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fan, Longzhen; Johansson, Anders C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do the equity holding and soundness of bank underwriters affect issue costs of SEOs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Suzuki, Katsushi
This paper examines the effects of characteristics of bank underwriters on issue costs in seasoned equity offerings in Japan following deregulation in 1999. I find that banks' holding loans have a negative effect on price discounts and no effect on underwriting fees. However, banks' equity holdings have no effect on discount rates and a positive effect on underwriting fees. Furthermore, issuers with unhealthy banks pay higher discount rates, are more likely to be weak in their ex-post operating performance, and are less willing to switch underwriters. I conclude that the characteristics of banks have different effects on issue costs. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Suzuki, Katsushi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility risk and the value premium: Evidence from the French stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arisoy, Yakup Eser
This paper documents that systematic volatility risk is an important factor that drives the value premium observed in the French stock market. Using returns on at-the-money straddles written on the CAC 40 index as a proxy for systematic volatility risk, I document significant differences between volatility factor loadings of value and growth stocks. Furthermore, when markets are classified into expected booms and recessions, volatility factor loadings are also time-varying. When expected market risk premium is above its average, i.e. during expected recessions, value stocks are seen riskier than their growth counterparts. This implies in bad times, investors shift their preferences away from value firms. Instead they use growth stocks as hedges against deteriorations in their wealth during those times. The findings are in line with the predictions of rational asset pricing theory and support a "flight-to-quality" explanation. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arisoy, Yakup Eser</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and the January effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Qian; Tong, Wilson H. S.
We use a time-series GARCH framework with the conditional variance/covariance as proxies for systematic risk to reexamine the proposition by Rozeff and Kinney (1976) and Rogalski and Tinic (1986) that the January effect may be a phenomenon of risk compensation in the month. We find no clear evidence that either conditional volatility or unconditional volatility in January is predominantly higher across the sampling years. Hence, against the proposition, the January effect is not due to risk per se. Rather, we find strong evidence that the January effect is due to higher compensation for risk in the month. This may be possible if investors have an increasing RRA utility function. Although many studies find that volatility tends to be higher in January, we find it to be period-specific and mostly in value-weighted return series, but not in equal-weighted return series. This is true both for the unconditional and conditional return volatility. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Qian; Tong, Wilson H. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee well-being, firm leverage, and bankruptcy risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Verwijmeren, Patrick; Derwall, Jeroen
Employees of liquidating firms are likely to lose income and non-pecuniary benefits of working for the firm, which makes bankruptcy costly for employees. This paper examines whether firms take these costs into account when deciding on the optimal amount of leverage. We find that firms with leading track records in employee well-being significantly reduce the probability of bankruptcy by operating with lower debt ratios. Moreover, we observe that firms with better employee track records have better credit ratings, even when we control for differences in firm leverage. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Verwijmeren, Patrick; Derwall, Jeroen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic value in tranching of syndicated loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maskara, Pankaj Kumar
This paper presents a theory to explain the economic value of tranching and provides empirical evidence to support the theoretical implications. I show that riskier firms are more likely to take loans with multiple tranches. Therefore, the average credit spread on a syndicated loan with multiple tranches is higher than that on a non-tranched loan. However, after accounting for the risk characteristics of a tranched loan, I show that borrowings that are a part of tranched loans have lower credit spreads than otherwise identical non-tranched loans. I also show that the benefits of tranching accrue primarily to riskier borrowers. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maskara, Pankaj Kumar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Settlement delays in the money market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartolini, Leonardo; Hilton, Spence; McAndrews, James J.
We track 38,000 money market trades from execution to delivery and return, and provide a first empirical analysis of settlement delays in financial markets. In accord with the predictions of recent models of strategic settlement of financial claims, we document a tendency by lenders to delay delivery of loaned funds until the afternoon hours. We find banks to follow a simple strategy to manage the risk of account overdrafts, by delaying settlement of large payments relative to that of small payments. More sophisticated strategies such as increasing delays when own liquid balances are low and when dealing with small trading partners play a marginal role. We find evidence of strategic delay also when returning borrowed funds, although we can explain a smaller fraction of the dispersion in delays in the return than in delivery leg of money market lending. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved,</description><author>Bartolini, Leonardo; Hilton, Spence; McAndrews, James J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Excess liquidity, bank pricing rules, and monetary policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agenor, Pierre-Richard; El Aynaoui, Karim
This paper studies the implications of excess bank liquidity for the effectiveness of monetary policy in a simple model with credit market imperfections. The demand for excess reserves is determined by precautionary factors and the opportunity cost of holding cash. It is argued that excess liquidity may impart greater stickiness to the deposit rate in response to a monetary contraction and induce an easing of collateral requirements on borrowers - which in turn may translate into a lower risk premium and lower lending rates. As a result, asymmetric bank pricing behavior under excess liquidity may hamper the ability of a contractionary monetary policy to lower inflation. (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Agenor, Pierre-Richard; El Aynaoui, Karim</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of holdings data frequency on conclusions about mutual fund behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Blake, Christopher R.; Krasny, Yoel; Ozelge, Sadi O.
A number of articles in financial economics have used quarterly or semi-annual mutual fund holdings data to test hypotheses about investment manager behavior. This article reexamines four well-known hypotheses in finance to determine whether the results of prior tests of these hypotheses remain valid when higher frequency (monthly) holdings data are employed. The areas examined are: momentum trading, tax-motivated trading, window dressing, and tournament behavior. We find that the use of monthly holdings data rather than quarterly holdings data or, in the case of tournament behavior, holdings data rather than monthly return data, change, and in some cases reverse, previous results. This occurs because monthly holdings data capture a large number of trades missed by quarterly data (18.5% of the trades) and permit a more precise estimation of the timing of trades. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Blake, Christopher R.; Krasny, Yoel; Ozelge, Sadi O.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank loan recovery rates: Measuring and nonparametric density estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calabrese, Raffaella; Zenga, Michele
In this paper we analyse a comprehensive database of 149,378 recovery rates on Italian bank loans. We investigate a new methodology to compute the recovery percentage that we suggest to consider as a mixed random variable. To estimate the probability density function of such a mixture, we propose the mixture of beta kernels estimator and we analyse its performance by Monte Carlo simulations. The application of these proposals to the Bank of Italy's data shows that, even if we remove the endpoints from the support of the recovery rate, the density function estimate is far from being a beta function. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calabrese, Raffaella; Zenga, Michele</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling the dynamics of Chinese spot interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Yongmiao; Lin, Hai; Wang, Shouyang
Using the daily data of Chinese 7-day repo rates from January 1, 1997 to December 31, 2008, this paper tests a variety of popular spot rate models, including single-factor diffusion, GARCH, Markov regime-switching and jump-diffusion models. We document that Chinese spot rates are subject to both market forces and administrative forces. GARCH, regime-switching and jump-diffusion models capture some important features of the dynamics of Chinese spot rates, but all models under study are overwhelmingly rejected. We further explore possible sources of model misspecification using diagnostic tests. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Yongmiao; Lin, Hai; Wang, Shouyang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public entrants, public equity finance and creative destruction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, James R.; Petersen, Bruce C.
We explore the importance of new public firms and public equity finance for R&amp;D and creative destruction in the US high-tech sector. Over 1900 new public firms enter high-tech manufacturing between 1970 and 2004; they are increasingly R&amp;D intensive and rely extensively on public equity finance in the 1980s and 1990s. We estimate dynamic R&amp;D models and find a strong link between public equity finance and R&amp;D for new entrants, but not established entrants or incumbents. Further, recent cohorts of public entrants have a substantial economic impact: by 2000, recent public entrants account for almost half of high-tech sales and more than half of R&amp;D. Variation in the availability of public equity finance has a marked impact on entrant R&amp;D and the rate at which entrants take market share from incumbents. Our findings identify a key channel through which public equity markets facilitate the process of creative destruction. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, James R.; Petersen, Bruce C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax clientele effects of dividends under intertemporal consumption choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mori, Naoya
Corporate investors putatively seek high dividends because marginal tax rates on dividends are lower than those on capital gains. However, a lower tax "rate" does not necessarily mean that a higher dividend is desirable. Taking the intertemporal consumption choices given, corporate investors are expected to prefer "time-preference-fitted dividends" if tax rates remain constant over time; otherwise they confront a larger "amount" of tax obligation. If dividend shortfalls exist, they must realize capital gains and thereby suffer unfavorable tax treatment, whereas excessive payments cause intertemporal double taxation on reinvested dividends. Tax-saving problems should be linked with intertemporal consumption choices. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mori, Naoya</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Covered interest arbitrage profits: The role of liquidity and credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fong, Wai-Ming; Valente, Giorgio; Fung, Joseph K. W.
We study the profitability of Covered Interest Parity (CIP) arbitrage violations and their relationship with market liquidity and credit risk using a novel and unique dataset of tick-by-tick firm quotes for all financial instruments involved in the arbitrage strategy. The empirical analysis shows that positive CIP arbitrage deviations include a compensation for liquidity and credit risk. Once these risk premia are taken into account, small arbitrage profits only accrue to traders who are able to negotiate low trading costs. The results are robust to stale pricing and the nonsynchronous trading occurring in the markets involved in the arbitrage strategy. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fong, Wai-Ming; Valente, Giorgio; Fung, Joseph K. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minority shareholders' wealth effects and stock market development: Evidence from increase-in-ownership M&amp;As</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Croci, Ettore; Petmezas, Dimitris
This paper examines, using a global M&amp;A data set, the relationship between the target firm's minority shareholders' returns and a country's stock market development in deals in which large shareholders increase their ownership stakes. For the purpose of this study, we use two measures of stock market development: (1) turnover over GDP. and (2) turnover over market capitalization. We provide evidence supporting the view that minority shareholders in target firms gain significantly more in countries with high stock market development than their counterparts in less-developed markets. Our results are robust to several firm and deal characteristics and provide evidence to policy makers that the degree of stock market development is a key determinant in improving minority shareholders' welfare. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Croci, Ettore; Petmezas, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Concentrated control, institutions, and banking sector: An international study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haw, In-Mu; Ho, Simon S. M.; Hu, Bingbing; Wu, Donghui
Using a broad sample of listed commercial banks in East Asia and Western Europe, this paper investigates the relations among concentrated control, a set of bank operating characteristics, and legal and regulatory regimes. We find that banks with concentrated control exhibit poorer performance, lower cost efficiency, greater return volatility, and higher insolvency risk, relative to widely held ones. We also document that legal institutions and private monitoring effectively reduce the detrimental effects of concentrated control and that official disciplinary power plays a weak governance role, whereas government intervention exacerbates the adverse effects. Further evidence shows that the relations between control concentration and bank operating characteristics are curvilinear and vary according to the types of controlling owners. Overall, our findings support the contention that country-level institutions play important roles in constraining insider expropriation, and that private monitoring mechanisms are more effective than are public rules and supervision in governing banks. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Haw, In-Mu; Ho, Simon S. M.; Hu, Bingbing; Wu, Donghui</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The degree of financial liberalization and aggregated stock-return volatility in emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Umutlu, Mehmet; Akdeniz, Levent; Altay-Salih, Aslihan
In this study, we address whether the degree of financial liberalization affects the aggregated total volatility of stock returns by considering the time-varying nature of financial liberalization. We also explore channels through which the degree of financial liberalization impacts aggregated total volatility. We document a negative relation to the degree of financial liberalization after controlling for size, liquidity, country. and crisis effects, especially for small and medium-sized markets. Moreover, the degree of financial liberalization transmits its negative impact on aggregated total volatility through aggregated idiosyncratic and local volatilities. Overall, our results provide evidence in favor of the view that the broadening of the investor base due to the increasing degree of financial liberalization causes a reduction in the total volatility of stock returns. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Umutlu, Mehmet; Akdeniz, Levent; Altay-Salih, Aslihan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory competition and forbearance: Evidence from the life insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McShane, Michael K.; Cox, Larry A.; Butler, Richard J.
Regulatory separation theory indicates that a system with multiple regulators leads to less forbearance and limits producer gains while a model of banking regulation developed by Dell'Ariccia and Marquez (2006) predicts the opposite. Fragmented regulation of the US life insurance industry provides an especially rich environment for testing the effects of regulatory competition. We find positive relations between regulatory competition and profitability measures for this industry, which is consistent with the Dell'Ariccia and Marquez model. Our results have practical implications for the debate over federal versus state regulation of insurance and financial services in the US. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McShane, Michael K.; Cox, Larry A.; Butler, Richard J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International house prices and macroeconomic fluctuations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beltratti, Andrea; Morana, Claudio
The paper investigates linkages between general macroeconomic conditions and the housing market for the G-7 area. Among the key results of the paper, we find that the US are all important source of global fluctuations not only for real activity, nominal variables and stock prices, but also for real housing prices. Secondly, albeit distinct driving forces for real activity and financial factors can be pointed out, sizeable global interactions are also evident. In particular, global supply-side shocks are an important determinant of G-7 house prices fluctuations. The linkage between real housing prices and macroeconomic developments is however bidirectional, with investment showing in general a stronger reaction than consumption and output to housing price shocks. Implications for the real effects of the sub-prime crisis are also explored. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beltratti, Andrea; Morana, Claudio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Restricting consumer credit access: Household survey evidence on effects around the Oregon rate cap</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zinman, Jonathan
Many policymakers and some theories hold that restricting access to expensive credit helps consumers by preventing overborrowing. I examine some effects of restricting access, using household panel survey data on payday loan users collected around the introduction of binding restrictions on payday loan terms in Oregon. Borrowing fell in Oregon relative to Washington, with former payday borrowers shifting partially into plausibly inferior substitutes: bank overdrafts and late bill payment. Additional evidence suggests that restricting access caused deterioration in the overall financial condition of Oregon households. Overall the results are consistent with restricted access harming, not helping, consumers on average. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zinman, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous housing market cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sommervoll, Dag Einar; Borgersen, Trond-Arne; Wennemo, Tom
Housing markets tend to display positive serial correlation as well as considerable volatility over time. We present a heterogeneous agent model illustrating the connection between adaptive expectations and housing market fluctuations. A dwelling serves as a shelter, as a vehicle for investment and as mortgage collateral. interesting dynamics arise as the valuation of these three properties changes over time through the interaction of buyers, sellers and mortgagees. In the absence Of Credit constraints imposed by mortgagees, house prices oscillate mildly around the equilibrium price. However, credit constraints imposed by mortgagees can affect market dynamics quite dramatically with periods of mild oscillations interrupted by violent collapses. This chaotic behavior arises even though buyers, sellers and mortgagees agree on market forecasts. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sommervoll, Dag Einar; Borgersen, Trond-Arne; Wennemo, Tom</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture capital funds: Flow-performance relationship and performance persistence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phalippou, Ludovic
This paper finds that venture capital funds that are expected to be backed by more skilled investors show no performance persistence but a significant flow-performance relationship. In contrast, funds that are expected to be backed by less skilled investors show performance predictability and have a non-significant flow-performance relationship. These results suggest that only skilled investors use all available information to adjust their capital allocation and, as a result, eliminate performance predictability as argued theoretically by Berk and Green (2004). Results also show that Kaplan and Schoar (2005) overstate the persistence in fund performance by not using an ex ante measure of the performance of earlier funds. Whether or not an ex ante measure is used, however, the persistence is largely due to unsophisticated investors. When investors are sophisticated, the performance of earlier funds, sequence and fund size do not help predict the performance of the focal fund. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Phalippou, Ludovic</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditionally fitted Sharpe performance with an application to hedge fund rating</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Darolles, Serge; Gourieroux, Christian
We define a battery of Sharpe performance measures, which differ by the information taken into account in their computation, but also by the potential use of the fund by the investor. Four advantages of Sharpe performance based rating are especially important for the investor. First, the performance measures correspond to the standard measures used for mutual funds and known by retail investors. Second, we can compare the numerical results, even if they are obtained with different assumptions. Third, the rankings are based on regression analysis and easy to compute. Fourth, we can easily use these performance measures in the design of an optimal basket of hedge funds. Finally, we can use the performance measures to partition the set of funds into homogenous segments. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Darolles, Serge; Gourieroux, Christian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speed of convergence to market efficiency for NYSE-listed foreign stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat; Yang, Ting
This paper contributes to the cross-listing literature by documenting the speed of convergence to market efficiency for foreign stocks listed on the NYSE. We find that, on average, it takes 30-60 minutes for a foreign stock to achieve market efficiency. For a comparable US stock, it takes only 10-15 minutes. The significant difference between foreign and US stocks remains robust when the speed is measured by the number of transactions rather than in calendar time. After relevant firm characteristics are controlled for, the time that it takes for foreign stocks to reach efficiency is significantly negatively related to the quality of their home country institutions. We find that one possible channel through which institutions affect the speed is through their impact on information asymmetry. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat; Yang, Ting</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distribution of institutional ownership and corporate firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elyasiani, Elyas; Jia, Jingyi
We investigate the association between corporate firm performance and the level and stability of institutional ownership within a simultaneous equation model. Our main ownership stability measures include ownership persistence and the time-lengths over which investors hold non-zero shares or maintain their shareholding. We find that there is a positive relationship between firm performance and institutional ownership stability, accounting for the shareholding proportion. This relationship is robust to the employment of ownership turnover measures used in the literature and consistent with the view that stable institutional investors play an effective role in monitoring. When we disaggregate institutional investors into pressure-insensitive and pressure-sensitive categories, we find that stable shareholding of each group has a positive impact on performance, with the first group exerting a larger effect. The channels of the effect include, but are not limited to, decreased information asymmetry and increased incentive-based compensation. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved</description><author>Elyasiani, Elyas; Jia, Jingyi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure, equity ownership and firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Margaritis, Dimitris; Psillaki, Maria
This paper investigates the relationship between capital structure, ownership structure and firm performance using a sample of French manufacturing firms. We employ non-parametric data envelopment analysis (DEA) methods to empirically construct the industry's 'best practice' frontier and measure firm efficiency as the distance from that frontier. Using these performance measures we examine if more efficient firms choose more or less debt in their capital structure. We summarize the contrasting effects of efficiency on capital structure in terms of two competing hypotheses: the efficiency-risk and franchise-value hypotheses. Using quantile regressions we test the effect of efficiency on leverage and thus the empirical validity of the two competing hypotheses across different capital structure choices. We also test the direct relationship from leverage to efficiency stipulated by the Jensen and Meckling (1976) agency cost model. Throughout this analysis we consider the role of ownership Structure and type on capital structure and firm performance. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Margaritis, Dimitris; Psillaki, Maria</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalized parameter functions for option pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andreou, Panayiotis C.; Charalambous, Chris; Martzoukos, Spiros H.
We extend the benchmark nonlinear deterministic volatility regression functions of Dumas et al. (1998) to provide a semi-parametric method where an enhancement of the implied parameter values is used in the parametric option pricing models. Besides volatility, skewness and kurtosis of the asset return distribution can also be enhanced. Empirical results, using closing prices of the S&amp;P 500 index call options (in one day ahead out-of-sample pricing tests), strongly support our method that compares favorably with a model that admits stochastic volatility and random jumps. Moreover, it is found to be Superior in various robustness tests. Our semi-parametric approach is an effective remedy to the curse of dimensionality presented in nonparametric estimation and its main advantage is that it delivers theoretically consistent option prices and hedging parameters. The economic significance of the approach is tested in terms of hedging, where the evaluation and estimation loss functions are aligned. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andreou, Panayiotis C.; Charalambous, Chris; Martzoukos, Spiros H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lost in translation: Delayed ex-dividend price adjustments of Hong Kong ADRs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kadapakkam, Palani-Rajan; Meisami, Alex; Shi, Yilun
Previous research documents that Hong Kong stocks have a full ex-dividend price adjustment consistent with dividends and capital gains being tax free. We examine ex-dividend price behavior of Hong Kong ADRs to assess the impact of differing tax environments in US and Hong Kong. These ADRs typically go ex-dividend before their underlying stock. They experience significant abnormal returns of 1.16% on their ex-day: the average ex-day price drop is only 30% of the dividend. However, ADR prices drop when the underlying stock goes ex-dividend subsequently. The cumulative ADR price drop is equal to the dividend. Thus, the ADR ex-dividend adjustment resembles that of the underlying stock, consistent with home country tax laws governing ADR price behavior. Neither liquidity nor transaction costs can explain the anomalous delayed ex-dividend adjustment of ADRs. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kadapakkam, Palani-Rajan; Meisami, Alex; Shi, Yilun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of price discovery for cross-listed shares: Evidence from Australia and New Zealand</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frijns, Bart; Gilbert, Aaron; Tourani-Rad, Alireza
This paper studies the dynamics of price discovery for markets with bilateral cross-listings. Using a sample of four Australian stocks cross-listed in New Zealand and five New Zealand stocks cross-listed in Australia for the period January 2002 to December 2007, we assess Hasbrouck (1995) information shares and Grammig et al. (2005) conditional information shares over time. We observe that in both cases the home market is dominant in terms of price discovery. However, when studying price discovery over time, we find that the importance of the Australian market (the larger of the two markets) is increasing for both Australian and New Zealand domiciled firms. Finally, using panel regression analysis, we find that the growth in the importance of the Australian market is positively related to the growth in the size of the firm and negatively related to the size of the percentage spread in the Australian market, implying that as firms grow larger and their cost of trading in Australia declines, the Australian market becomes more informative. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frijns, Bart; Gilbert, Aaron; Tourani-Rad, Alireza</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>American GARCH employee stock option valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leon, Angel; Vaello-Sebastia, Antoni
We implement a flexible simulation-based approach for the fair value of employee stock option (ESO) that accounts for the vesting period, departure risk and voluntary suboptimal early exercise. We introduce GARCH effects on the underlying asset and we analyze,the price bias with respect to the constant volatility case. We also perform a sensitivity analysis with respect to changes in several ESO characteristics. We compare this Valuation with FAS 123 method revealing a FAS overvaluation. Finally, we value a real ESO plan providing the confidence intervals for the estimated ESO prices. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leon, Angel; Vaello-Sebastia, Antoni</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political regimes, business cycles, seasonalities, and returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Powell, John G.; Shi, Jing; Smith, Tom; Whaley, Robert E.
This paper provides a method for testing for regime differences when regimes are long-lasting. Standard testing procedures are generally inappropriate because regime persistence causes a spurious regression problem - a problem that has led to incorrect inference in a broad range of studies involving regimes representing political, business, and seasonal cycles. The paper outlines analytically how standard estimators can be adjusted for regime dummy variable persistence. While the adjustments are helpful asymptotically, spurious regression remains a problem in small samples and must be addressed using simulation or bootstrap procedures. We provide a simulation procedure for testing hypotheses in situations where an independent variable in a time-series regression is a persistent regime dummy variable. We also develop a procedure for testing hypotheses in situations where the dependent variable has similar properties. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Powell, John G.; Shi, Jing; Smith, Tom; Whaley, Robert E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extending the Basel II approach to estimate capital requirements for equity investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnston, Mark
Under the Basel II banking regulatory capital regime the capital requirements for credit exposures are calculated using the Asymptotic Single Risk Factor (ASRF) approach. The capital requirement is taken to be the contribution of an exposure to the unexpected loss on the bank's diversified portfolio. Here we extend this approach to calculate capital requirements for equity investments. We show that in the case when asset values have a normal distribution an analytical formula for the unexpected loss contribution may be developed. We show that the capital requirements for equity investments are quite different to those of credit exposures, since equity investments can suffer substantial loss of value even when the underlying company has not defaulted. Unexpected loss is commonly used as a measure of capital requirements, but it ignores the ability of earnings to absorb loss. We propose a definition of capital requirement that recognises the expected earnings on assets, and show how to combine the ASRF model and the Capital Asset Pricing Model to compute this quantity for credit and equity exposures. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Johnston, Mark</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New strategies and a new paradigm for Shariah-compliant portfolio optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Derigs, Ulrich; Marzban, Shehab
In this paper we analyze the effects of different strategies to construct Shariah compatible financial portfolios. The difference between conventional and current Shariah portfolio management is the application of sector screens and financial screens by which the asset universe is reduced. Yet, here different schools of scholars define different screening rules leading to significant differences with respect to compliance, but also with respect to performance. After analyzing this discrepancy we propose several new strategies to apply the inconsistent rule systems and a new paradigm for defining Shariah-compliance. Under this new paradigm compliance is attributed to the portfolio and not to the individual assets of the universe. We report results of an empirical study analyzing the potentials of these strategies and of the paradigm. We can show that under the proposed concepts Shariah-compliant portfolios can be realized which have return and risk profiles comparable to the conventional non-constrained portfolios. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Derigs, Ulrich; Marzban, Shehab</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of the volatility skew: A Kalman filter approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bedendo, Mascia; Hodges, Stewart D.
Much attention has been devoted to understanding and modeling the dynamics of implied volatility curves and surfaces. This is crucial for both trading, pricing and risk management of option positions. We suggest a simple, yet flexible, model, based on a discrete and linear Kalman filter updating of the volatility skew. From a risk management perspective, we assess whether this model is capable of producing good density forecasts of daily returns on a number of option portfolios. We also compare our model to the sticky-delta and the vega-gamma alternatives. We find that it clearly outperforms both alternatives, given its ability to easily account for movements of different nature in the volatility curve. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bedendo, Mascia; Hodges, Stewart D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inside the black box: Bank credit allocation in China's private sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Firth, Michael; Lin, Chen; Liu, Ping; Wong, Sonia M. L.
This study examines how the Chinese state-owned banks allocate loans to private firms. We find that the banks extend loans to financially healthier and better-governed firms, which implies that the banks use commercial judgments in this segment of the market. We also find that having the state as a minority owner helps firms obtain bank loans and this suggests that political connections play a role in gaining access to bank finance. In addition, we find that commercial judgments are important determinants of the lending decisions for manufacturing firms, large firms, and firms located in regions with a more developed banking sector: political connections are important for firms in service industries, large firms, and firms located in areas with a less developed banking sector. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Firth, Michael; Lin, Chen; Liu, Ping; Wong, Sonia M. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price trends and patterns in technical analysis: A theoretical and empirical examination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friesen, Geoffrey C.; Weller, Paul A.; Dunham, Lee M.
While many technical trading rules are based upon patterns in asset prices, we lack convincing explanations of how and why these patterns arise, and why trading rules based on technical analysis are profitable. This paper provides a model that explains the success of certain trading rules that are based on patterns in past prices. We point to the importance of confirmation bias, which has been shown to play a key role in other types of decision making. Traders who acquire information and trade on the basis of that information tend to bias their interpretation of subsequent information in the direction of their original view. This produces autocorrelations and patterns of price movement that can predict future prices, such as the "head-and-shoulders" and "double-top" patterns. The model also predicts that sequential price jumps for a particular stock will be positively autocorrelated. We test this prediction and find that jumps exhibit statistically and economically significant positive autocorrelations. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Friesen, Geoffrey C.; Weller, Paul A.; Dunham, Lee M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time diversification: Definitions and some closed-form solutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Kee H.; Smith, William T.; Wu, Tao L.
We establish general conditions under which younger investors should invest a larger proportion of their wealth in risky assets than older ones. In the finite horizon dynamic setting, we show that such phenomenon. known as "time diversification," can occur in the presence of human wealth, guaranteed consumption, or mean-reverting stock returns. We formalize two alternative notions of time diversification commonly confounded in the literature. Analytic solutions are provided for both time-series and cross-sectional forms of time diversification. To our best knowledge. this paper is the first to solve in closed-form the hedging demand for a CARA investor with inter-temporal consumption and a finite horizon, facing mean-reverting expected returns. Cur results indicate that horizon can have a significant effect on the portfolio demand of a CARA investor due to inter-temporal hedging. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, Kee H.; Smith, William T.; Wu, Tao L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Health status and portfolio choice: Causality or heterogeneity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, Elliott; Zhao, Ruoyun
This paper explores the role of unobserved individual characteristics in the health-assets and health-portfolio correlations. We apply various econometrics models to a unique longitudinal dataset with rich information that allows for the exploitation of four different health indices. Our findings show strong cross-sectional correlations between health and both financial and non-financial assets, but these correlations seem to be mainly driven by heterogeneity as the correlations largely disappear in the fixed-effects model. Adverse health shocks, however, are found to motivate a safer portfolio choice even after individual fixed-effects are controlled for - a result consistent with the prediction made by the background risk theory. Our findings suggest that health shocks shift investment from risky assets toward other financial assets, but keep the total financial assets unchanged. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fan, Elliott; Zhao, Ruoyun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary policy implementation and the federal funds rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nautz, Dieter; Schmidt, Sandra
This paper investigates how the implementation of monetary policy affects the dynamics and the volatility of the federal funds rate. Since the early 1980s, the most important changes in the Fed's conduct of monetary policy refer to the role of the federal funds rate target and the reserve requirement system. We show that the improved communication and transparency regarding the federal funds rate target has significantly increased the Fed's influence on the federal funds rate since 1994. By contrast, the declining role of required reserves in the US has contributed to higher federal funds rate volatility. Our results suggest that the introduction of remunerated required reserves will further enhance the controllability of the federal funds rate. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nautz, Dieter; Schmidt, Sandra</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private equity and regulatory capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bongaerts, Dion; Charlier, Erwin
Regulatory capital requirements for European banks have been put forward in the Base] 11 Capital Framework and Subsequently in the capital requirements directive (CRD) of the EU. We provide a detailed discussion of the capital requirements for private equity investments under different approaches. For the internal model approach we present a structural model that we calibrate to a proprietary dataset. We modify the standard Merton structural model to make it applicable in practice and to capture stylized facts of private equity investments. We also implement the early default feature with a fast simulation algorithm. Our results support capital requirements lower than in Basel 11, but not as low as in CRD, thereby giving adverse incentives to banks for using advanced risk models. A sensitivity analysis shows that this finding is robust to parameter uncertainty and stress scenarios. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bongaerts, Dion; Charlier, Erwin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decision-making under uncertainty - A field study of cumulative prospect theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gurevich, Gregory; Kliger, Doron; Levy, Ori
The presented research tests cumulative prospect theory (CPT, [Kahneman, D., Tversky, A., 1979. Prospect theory: An analysis of decision under risk. Econometrica 47, 263-291; Tversky, A., Kahneman, D., 1981. The framing of decisions and the psychology of choice. Science 211, 453-480]) in the financial market, using US stock option data. Option prices possess information about actual investors' preferences in such a way that an exploitation of conventional option analysis, along with theoretical relationships, makes it possible to elicit investor preferences. The option data in this study serve for estimating the two essential elements of the CPT, namely, the value function and the probability weighting function. The main part of the work focuses on the functions' simultaneous estimation under CPT original parametric specification. The shape of the estimated functions is found to be in line with theory. Comparing to results of laboratory experiments, the estimated functions are closer to linearity and loss aversion is less pronounced. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gurevich, Gregory; Kliger, Doron; Levy, Ori</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling CO2 emission allowance prices and derivatives: Evidence from the European trading scheme</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daskalakis, George; Psychoyios, Dimitris; Markellos, Raphael N.
This paper studies the three main markets for emission allowances within the European Union Emissions Trading Scheme (EU ETS): Powernext, Nord Pool and European Climate Exchange (ECX). The analysis suggests that the prohibition of banking of emission allowances between distinct phases of the EU ETS has significant implications in terms of futures pricing. Motivated by these findings, we develop an empirically and theoretically valid framework for the pricing and hedging of intra-phase and inter-phase futures and options on futures, respectively. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Daskalakis, George; Psychoyios, Dimitris; Markellos, Raphael N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio performance evaluation with generalized Sharpe ratios: Beyond the mean and variance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zakamouline, Valeri; Koekebakker, Steen
This paper presents a theoretically sound portfolio performance measure that takes into account higher moments of distribution. This measure is motivated by a study of the investor's preferences to higher moments of distribution within Expected Utility Theory and an approximation analysis of the optimal capital allocation problem. We show that this performance measure justifies the notion of the Generalized Sharpe Ratio (GSR) introduced by Hodges (1998). We present two methods of practical estimation of the GSR: nonparametric and parametric. For the implementation of the parametric method we derive a closed-form solution for the GSR where the higher moments are calibrated to the normal inverse Gaussian distribution. We illustrate how the GSR can mitigate the shortcomings of the Sharpe ratio in resolution of Sharpe ratio paradoxes and reveal the real performance of portfolios with manipulated Sharpe ratios. We also demonstrate the use of this measure in the performance evaluation of hedge funds. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zakamouline, Valeri; Koekebakker, Steen</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the market dole out collective punishment? An empirical analysis of industry, geography, and Arthur Andersen's reputation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Roger D.; Li, Hang
Arthur Andersen's reputation was tarnished following news that its Houston office had shredded documents related to the auditing of energy giant Enron. Earlier studies documented widespread spillover of the reputation effect, suggesting a strong commonality in Big 5 audit practices. We examine whether the market is more discriminating in its assessments. We focus on the roles industry specialization of auditors and the geography of clients' audit offices play in accounting for the contagion. Our results are supportive of investors who differentiate audit practices by industry and who account for the location of the specific office where the audit work is done. We find that losses suffered by energy firms or firms located close to Houston are equivalent to approximately 90% of the aggregate abnormal losses suffered by Big 5 clients. Our evidence suggests the possibility of more localized impact of accounting scandals and supports accounting regulations targeted at individual industries. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Roger D.; Li, Hang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulation of credit rating agencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stolper, Anno
Financial regulators recognize certain credit rating agencies for regulatory purposes. However, it is often argued that credit rating agencies have an incentive to assign inflated ratings. This paper studies a repeated principal-agent problem in which a regulator approves credit rating agencies. Credit rating agencies may collude to assign inflated ratings. Yet we show that there exists an approval scheme which induces credit rating agencies to assign correct ratings. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stolper, Anno</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overreaction in the thrift IPO aftermarket</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friesen, Geoffrey C.; Swift, Christopher
We study the initial returns and long-run performance of a unique sample of thrifts that have recently converted from mutual to stock form. In addition to a full claim on all IPO proceeds, new investors in a converted thrift also receive a claim on all pre-conversion market value at no cost. Thus, the average firm in our sample has a degree of underpricing automatically built into its offer price. We find that after removing the large initial returns, cumulative excess returns for the firms in our sample are positive for 12 months after the IPO. Beginning in the second year after the IPO, the average firm in our sample undergoes a significant price correction that lasts approximately 18 months and which produces negative cumulative abnormal returns for up to 5 years post-issue. Differences in risk-adjusted returns also indicate negative long-run returns, with poor performance concentrated in the second and third years following the IPO. The return differences are most pronounced among the small thrifts in our sample, and are broadly consistent with investor overreaction at the time of the IPO that continues for 6-12 months before prices begin reverting back to fundamental value. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Friesen, Geoffrey C.; Swift, Christopher</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The slicing approach to valuing tax shields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Yuan-Chi
The literature develops the theoretical rationale for the Value of Tax Shields (VTS) on the following misguided basis: it uses required rate of return on assets (or WACC) as the discount rate for capitalization, it uses expected rate of return on assets (ROA or ROI) as a proxy for WACC, and it is not aware of (I) the influence of the difference between "expected rate of return on equity" and "Required rate of Return On Equity (RROE)" on VTS, (2) the fact that RROE is equity normal profit which is not measurable, (3) the economic content of the weight attached to the VTS capacity, and (4) the co-definition of "tax shield and leverage return." This paper takes tax shields and leverage return as a system and provides a knife, "interest rate/ROI = Cost/Price", to slice the VTS capacity into "earned VTS" and "unearned VTS." Earned VTS is VTS. Unearned VTS is the value of leverage return, because leverage return is tax payable. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All Rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Yuan-Chi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consolidation in banking and financial stability in Europe: Empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uhde, Andre; Heimeshoff, Ulrich
Using aggregate balance sheet data from banks across the EU-25 over the period from 1997 to 2005 we provide empirical evidence that national banking market concentration has a negative impact on European banks' financial soundness as measured by the Z-score technique while controlling for macroeconomic, bank-specific, regulatory, and institutional factors. Furthermore, our analysis reveals that Eastern European banking markets exhibiting a lower level of competitive pressure, fewer diversification opportunities and a higher fraction of government-owned banks are more prone to financial fragility whereas capital regulations have supported financial stability across the entire European Union. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Uhde, Andre; Heimeshoff, Ulrich</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign institutional ownership and stock market liquidity: Evidence from Indonesia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rhee, S. Ghon; Wang, Jianxin
From January 2002 to August 2007, foreign institutions held almost 70% of the free-float value of the Indonesian equity market, or 41% of the total market capitalization. Over the same period, liquidity on the Jakarta Stock Exchange improved substantially with the average bid-ask spread more than halved and the average depth more than doubled. In this study we examine the Granger causality between foreign institutional ownership and liquidity, while controlling for persistence in foreign ownership and liquidity measures. We find that foreign holdings have a negative impact on future liquidity: a 10% increase in foreign institutional ownership in the current month is associated with approximately 2% increase in the bid-ask spread, 3% decrease in depth, and 4% rise in price sensitivity in the next month, challenging the view that foreign institutions enhance liquidity in small emerging markets. Our findings are consistent with the negative liquidity impact of institutional investor ownership in developed markets. Crown Copyright (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rhee, S. Ghon; Wang, Jianxin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial reforms and time-varying microstructures in emerging equity markets (vol 22, pg 1325, 2009)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lagoarde-Segot, Thomas
nan</description><author>Lagoarde-Segot, Thomas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market microstructure of the Pink Sheets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Christie, William G.
We study the microstructure of the Pink Sheets and assess the ability of existing theory to capture salient features of this relatively unstructured and unregulated market. Clustering patterns in quotes, quoted spreads, and trade prices indicate that market participants have selected price-dependent tick sizes for different stocks. Clustering intensity varies across stocks as a function of proxies for information availability. Similarly, the bid-ask spread varies as a function of volatility and liquidity. These results suggest (1) microstructure research has established robust predictions of market attributes and (2) unstructured markets are able to develop at least some effective behavioral norms endogenously. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Christie, William G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strong boards, CEO power and bank risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pathan, Shams
This study examines the relevance of bank board structure on bank risk-taking. Using a sample of 212 large US bank holding companies over 1997-2004 (1534 observations). this study finds that strong bank boards (boards reflecting more of bank shareholders interest) particularly small and less restrictive boards positively affect bank risk-taking. In contrast, CEO power (CEO's ability to control board decision) negatively affects bank risk-taking. These results are consistent with the bank contracting environment and robust to several proxies for bank risk-takings and different estimation techniques. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pathan, Shams</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Causality in quantiles and dynamic stock return-volume relations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chuang, Chia-Chang; Kuan, Chung-Ming; Lin, Hsin-Yi
This paper investigates the causal relations between stock return and volume based on quantile regressions. We first define Granger non-causality in all quantiles and propose testing non-causality by a sup-Wald test. Such a test is consistent against any deviation from non-causality in distribution, as opposed to the existing tests that check only non-causality in certain moment. This test is readily extended to test non-causality in different quantile ranges. In the empirical studies of three major stock market indices, we find that the causal effects of volume on return are usually heterogeneous across quantiles and those of return on volume are more stable. In particular, the quantile causal effects of volume on return exhibit a spectrum of (symmetric) V-shape relations so that the dispersion of return distribution increases with lagged volume. This is an alternative evidence that volume has a positive effect on return volatility. Moreover, the inclusion of the squares of lagged returns in the model may weaken the quantile causal effects of volume on return but does not affect the causality per se. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chuang, Chia-Chang; Kuan, Chung-Ming; Lin, Hsin-Yi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market power in local banking monopolies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coccorese, Paolo
By means of two NEIO techniques, this paper analyzes the conduct of a group of Italian single-branch banks operating as monopolists in small local areas (municipalities) in the years 1988-2005, in order to assess pricing behavior in highly concentrated banking markets. Both tests strongly reject the hypothesis of pure monopoly pricing: regardless the advantageous condition, these banks are able to exploit only partially their market power, principally by reason of the nearby competition, the latest banking consolidation trend and the local presence of big banks. Employing another sample, we also show that in duopolistic markets the conduct of single-branch banks is virtually competitive. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coccorese, Paolo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of FX central bank intervention in a noise trading framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beine, Michel; De Grauwe, Paul; Grimaldi, Marianna
in this paper, we analyse the effectiveness of the direct central bank interventions using a new effectiveness criterion. To this aim, we investigate the effects of central bank interventions (CBI) in a noise trading model with chartists and fundamentalists. We first estimate a model in which chartists extrapolate past returns and fundamentalists forecast a mean reverting dynamics of the exchange rate towards a fundamental value. Then, we investigate the role of central bank interventions for explaining the switching properties between the two types of agents. We find evidence that in the medium run, interventions increase the proportion of fundamentalists and therefore exert some stabilizing influence on the exchange rate. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beine, Michel; De Grauwe, Paul; Grimaldi, Marianna</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposit guarantee evaluation and incentives analysis in a mutual guarantee system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Giuli, Maria Elena; Maggi, Mario Alessandro; Paris, Francesco Maria
This paper analyzes how the deposit guarantee value affects the risk incentives in a mutual guarantee system. We liken the guarantee's value to that of a European-style contingent claims portfolio. The main feature emerging from our model is that a mutual guarantee system would give banks an adverse incentive to increase riskiness. To mitigate this incentive, we introduce a regulatory provision modelled using a path-dependent contingent claim. By comparing the mutual guarantee system with a non-mutual one, we show that the former is less expensive, but implies higher adverse incentives for the banks, especially for undercapitalized institutions. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Giuli, Maria Elena; Maggi, Mario Alessandro; Paris, Francesco Maria</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme coexceedances in new EU member states' stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christiansen, Charlotte; Ranaldo, Angelo
We analyze the financial integration of the new European Union (EU) member states' stock markets using the negative (positive) coexceedance variable that counts the number of large negative (large positive) returns on a given day across the countries. A similar analysis is performed for the old EU countries. We use a multinomial logit model to investigate how persistence, asset classes, and volatility are related to the coexceedance variables. We find that the effects differ (a) between negative and positive coexceedance variables (b) between old and new EU member states, and (c) before and after the EU enlargement in 2004, suggesting a closer connection of new EU stock markets to those in Western Europe. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christiansen, Charlotte; Ranaldo, Angelo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the market valuation of banks' loan loss provision conditional on auditor reputation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Krishnan, Gopal V.; Lobo, Gerald J.
We examine how auditor reputation conditions the market valuation of banks' loan loss provision (LLP). The inherent uncertainty associated with and discretion permitted in estimating the LLP contributes to information asymmetry. The auditor's certification and monitoring roles influence firm value by mitigating this information asymmetry. We examine two aspects of auditor reputation, auditor type (Big 5 vs. non-Big 5) and auditor expertise, in the banking industry. We find a significant, positive association between the discretionary component of LLP and stock return for banks audited by the Big 5 auditors. Further analysis indicates that auditor expertise within banking and not auditor type drives this significant, positive association. Overall, our results are consistent with auditor expertise in the banking industry mitigating information asymmetry between bank managers and investors and enhancing the information conveyed by discretionary loan loss provision. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Krishnan, Gopal V.; Lobo, Gerald J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The jump component of S&amp;P 500 volatility and the VIX index</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Ralf; Clements, Adam E.; McClelland, Andrew
Much research has investigated the differences between option implied volatilities and econometric model-based forecasts. Implied volatility is a market determined forecast, in contrast to model-based forecasts that employ some degree of smoothing of past volatility to generate forecasts. Implied volatility has the potential to reflect information that a model-based forecast could not. This paper considers two issues relating to the informational content of the S&amp;P 500 VIX implied volatility index. First, whether it subsumes information on how historical jump activity contributed to the price volatility, followed by whether the VIX reflects any incremental information pertaining to future jump activity relative to model-based forecasts. It is found that the VIX index both subsumes information relating to past jump contributions to total volatility and reflects incremental information pertaining to future jump activity. This issue has not been examined previously and expands our understanding of how option markets form their volatility forecasts. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Becker, Ralf; Clements, Adam E.; McClelland, Andrew</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of domestic and cross-border bank acquisitions in the European Union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hernando, Ignacio; Nieto, Maria J.; Wall, Larry D.
This paper analyzes the determinants of bank acquisitions both within and across countries in the EU-25 over the period 1997-2004. Our results suggest poorly managed banks (high cost to income) and larger banks are more likely to be acquired by other banks in the same country. The probability of being a target in a cross-border deal is larger for banks that are quoted in the stock market. Finally, banks operating in more concentrated markets are less likely to be acquired by other banks in the same country but are more likely to be acquired by banks in other EU-25 countries. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hernando, Ignacio; Nieto, Maria J.; Wall, Larry D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-varying market integration and stock and bond return concordance in emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Panchenko, Valentyn; Wu, Eliza
We investigate the extent to which emerging stock market integration affects the joint behavior of stock and bond returns using a two-stage semi-parametric approach. Using a sample of 18 emerging markets, we find an unambiguous and robust link between emerging stock market integration and stock-bond return decoupling. We explain this with a decline in the segmentation risk premia in equities modeled by De Jong and De Roon [De Jong, F., De Roon, F.A., 2005. Time-varying market integration and expected returns in emerging markets. journal of Financial Economics 78, 583-613] that leads to increased demand for stocks and reduced or unchanged demand for bonds. Our findings deliver new insights into the financial liberalization and stock-bond comovement literatures. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Panchenko, Valentyn; Wu, Eliza</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From boom 'til bust: How loss aversion affects asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkelaar, Arjan; Kouwenberg, Roy
This article studies the impact of heterogeneous loss averse investors on asset prices. In very good states loss averse investors become gradually less risk averse as wealth rises above their reference point, pushing up equity prices. When wealth drops below the reference point the investors become risk seeking and demand for stocks increases drastically, eventually leading to a forced sell-off and stock market bust in bad states. Heterogeneity in reference points and initial wealth of the loss averse investors does not change the salient features of the equilibrium price process, such as a relatively high equity premium, high volatility and counter-cyclical changes in the equity premium. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berkelaar, Arjan; Kouwenberg, Roy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News and the cross-section of expected corporate bond returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abhyankar, Abhay; Gonzalez, Angelica
We study the cross-section of expected corporate bond returns using an inter-temporal CAPM (ICAPM) with three-factors: innovations in future excess bond returns, future real interest rates and future expected inflation. Our test assets are a broad range of corporate bond market index portfolios. We find that two factors - innovations about future inflation and innovations about future real interest rates explain the cross-section of expected corporate bond returns in our sample. Our model provides an alternative to the ad hoc risk factor models used, for example, in evaluating the performance of bond mutual funds. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abhyankar, Abhay; Gonzalez, Angelica</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection and convertible debt design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Cheng-Few; Lee, Kin-Wai; Yeo, Gillian Hian-Heng
An important issue that firms consider when designing convertible debt is to specify security features such as conversion ratio, maturity date and call period. Following Lewis et al. [Lewis, M., Rogalski. R., Seward, J., 2003. Industry conditions, growth opportunities and market reactions to convertible debt financing decisions. journal of Banking and Finance 27, 153-181], we employ a single measure that simultaneously considers all of these features: the expected probability (measured at issue date) that the convertible will be converted to equity at maturity. We find that firms in countries with stronger shareholder rights issue convertible debt with a higher expected probability of converting to equity. The positive association between the expected probability of conversion and shareholder rights is less pronounced in firms for which ownership structures create potentially high managerial agency costs. Specifically, in Countries with stronger shareholder rights, firms with higher separation of control rights and cash flow rights tend to issue convertibles with lower probability of conversion. Furthermore, we find that large non-management block ownership strengthens the likelihood of issuing convertible debt with higher probability of conversion in countries with stronger shareholder rights. In contrast, firms in countries with stronger creditor rights issue convertibles with lower probability of conversion. We also document that the negative association between creditor rights and probability of conversion is more pronounced in firms with higher separation of control rights and cash flow rights. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Lee, Cheng-Few; Lee, Kin-Wai; Yeo, Gillian Hian-Heng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managers and efficiency in banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kauko, Karlo
This paper presents evidence on the impact of managers on cost efficiency in banking. Stochastic frontier analysis is applied to a unique Finnish data set. Manager age and education have strong yet complicated effects on efficiency. The impact of age on efficiency depends on education. A university degree is useful mainly in the largest banks of the sample. Educational background seems to be less important for young managers than for mature ones. Managing director changes are systematically followed by efficiency changes. Retirement typically causes an efficiency improvement whereas other manager changes can either improve or weaken efficiency. However, in many cases mature managers outperform their young colleagues. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kauko, Karlo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is it the weather? Response</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobsen, Ben; Marquering, Wessel
Kamstra, Kramer and Levi (KKL) in their comment seem to miss the main point Of Our paper. Many things are correlated with the seasons so it is difficult to distinguish between them when we try to explain the well-known summer winter pattern in stock returns. Finding an isolated seasonal affective disorder (SAD) effect without proper control variables does not disprove our point but strengthens it. To sidestep all of the issues they raise and take our point to the extreme, we show using plain vanilla regressions that the seasonal stock market pattern they attribute to SAD can also be "explained" by variables like ice cream consumption or airline travel. The new variations of SAD variables ("onset" and "incidence") KKL propose in their recent work for North America are even more problematic than the original SAD variables. We find that these new SAD proxies are not significant in countries where according to KKL they should be: Canada and the United States. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacobsen, Ben; Marquering, Wessel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is it the weather? Comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamstra, Mark J.; Kramer, Lisa A.; Levi, Maurice D.
This comment discusses some errors in a recent paper by Jacobsen and Marquering [Jacobsen, B., Marquering, W., 2008. Is it the weather? journal of Banking and Finance 32 (4), 526-540], in which the authors challenge our previous finding that stock market returns exhibit seasonal patterns consistent with the influence of seasonal affective disorder on investor risk aversion. We find that we cannot replicate the authors' findings, even after corresponding with them. Furthermore, we document several problems with their methodology, including misspecification of their economic model, misspecification of their econometric model, and use of inappropriate data. While we agree that seasonal affective disorder is not an explanation for all variation in equity markets, we do maintain that careful analysis leads to economically and statistically significant evidence of the effect we originally documented. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kamstra, Mark J.; Kramer, Lisa A.; Levi, Maurice D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on capital asset pricing and heterogeneous taxes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eikseth, Hans Marius; Lindset, Snorre
In this paper, we present a stylized model where we show how asset prices, i.e., required expected rates of returns, may be characterized in a world with heterogeneous asset taxes. Within a simple CAPM-like framework, we derive an after-tax beta equal to the pre-tax beta multiplied by a (non-obvious) asset specific tax adjustment. We further show in what sense the Security Market Line here can be replaced by a Security Market Fan. Well-known CAPM relations are obtained as special cases, and policy implications are analyzed. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eikseth, Hans Marius; Lindset, Snorre</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-concavity problems in the dynamic macroeconomic models: A note</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hiraguchi, Ryoji
This note provides a method to convert the dynamic models in Cysne [Cysne, Rubens P., 2006. A note on the non-convexity problem in some shopping-time and human-capital models. journal of Banking and Finance 30 (10), 2737-2745] and in Cysne [Cysne, Rubens P., 2008. A note on "inflation and welfare". journal of Banking and Finance 32 (9), 1984-1987] to concave optimization problems. We do this by introducing new control and state variables in the models. Cysne (2006, 2008) restrict attention to continuous time models and derive parametric conditions to use Arrow's sufficiency theorem. When the sufficient conditions presented in Cysne (2006) are satisfied (but not under the sharper sufficient conditions presented in Cysne (2008)) we can rewrite these models as concave optimization problems even if time is discrete. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hiraguchi, Ryoji</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency and productivity growth in the banking industry of Central and Eastern Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koutsomanoli-Filippaki, Anastasia; Margaritis, Dimitris; Staikouras, Christos
We employ the directional technology distance function and provide estimates of bank efficiency and productivity change across Central and Eastern European (CEE) countries and across banks with different ownership status for the period 1998-2003. Our results demonstrate the strong links of competition and concentration with bank efficiency. They also show that productivity for the whole region initially declined but has improved more recently with further progress on institutional and structural reforms. Input-biased technical change has been consistently positive throughout the entire period suggesting that the reforms have induced favorable changes in relative input prices and input mix. However we find evidence of diverging trends in productivity growth patterns across banking industries and that foreign banks outperform domestic private and state-owned banks both in terms of efficiency and productivity gains. Overall, we find that productivity Change in CEE is driven by technological change rather than efficiency change. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koutsomanoli-Filippaki, Anastasia; Margaritis, Dimitris; Staikouras, Christos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of the true notional bond system applied to the CBOT T-bond futures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-Abdallah, Ramzi; Ben-Ameur, Hatem; Breton, Michele
The conversion factor system (CFS) is used in the determination of the invoice price of the Chicago Board of Trade Treasury-bond futures. As an alternative to the CFS, Oviedo [Oviedo, R.A., 2006. Improving the design of Treasury-Bond futures contracts. The journal of Business 79, 1293-1315] proposed the True Notional Bond System (TNBS), and showed that it outperforms the CFS when interest rates are deterministic. The main purpose of this paper is to compare the effectiveness of the two systems in a stochastic environment. In order to do so, we price the CBOT T-bond futures as well as all its embedded delivery options under both the CFS and the TNBS. Our pricing procedure is an adaptation of the Dynamic Programming algorithm described in Ben-Abdallah er al. [Ben-Abdallah, R., Ben-Ameur, H., Breton, M., 2007. Pricing CBOT Treasury Bond futures. Les Cahiers du GERAD G-2006-77]. Numerical illustrations show that, in a stochastic framework, TNBS does not always outperform the CFS. However, as the long-term mean moves away from the level of the notional rate, the TNBS performs increasingly better than the CFS. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ben-Abdallah, Ramzi; Ben-Ameur, Hatem; Breton, Michele</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO turnover and bondholder wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, John C.; Mansi, Sattar A.
We examine the impact of CEO turnover announcements on bondholder wealth, stockholder wealth, and overall firm value. Using publicly traded data for the period from 1973 to 2000, we find evidence consistent with both the wealth transfer and signaling hypotheses. Specifically, we find that CEO turnover events are associated with lower bondholder values, higher stockholder values, and that net changes in firm value are a function of turnover type (forced vs Voluntary and outside vs inside firm replacements) and the riskiness of the firm's debt (investment vs non-investment grade). Overall, the results contribute to the understanding of the effects of corporate governance mechanisms, of which CEO turnover is an extreme form, on bondholders. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, John C.; Mansi, Sattar A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does collateral fuel moral hazard in banking?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niinimaki, J.-P.
This paper presents two models in which the fluctuating value of loan collateral (real estate) generates the problem of moral hazard between a bank and a deposit insurance agent. The bank finances risky projects against collateral and relies on the rising collateral value. If the collateral value later appreciates, the bank enjoys handsome profits: otherwise, the bank fails, The findings are rather consistent with the characteristics of the topical subprime mortgage crisis. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Niinimaki, J.-P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recovery rates of commercial lending: Empirical evidence for German companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grunert, Jens; Weber, Martin
There are very few studies concerning the recovery rate of bank loans. Prediction models of recovery rates are increasing in importance because of the Basel II-framework, the impact on credit risk management, and the calculation of loan rates. In this study, we focus the analyses on the distribution of recovery rates and the impact of the quota of collateral, the creditworthiness of the borrower, the size of the company and the intensity of the client relationship on the recovery rate. All Our hypotheses can be confirmed. A higher quota of collateral leads to a higher recovery rate, whereas the risk premium of the borrower and the size of the company is negatively related to the recovery rate. Borrowers with an intense client relationship with the bank exhibit a higher recovery rate. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grunert, Jens; Weber, Martin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive compensation and competition in the banking and financial sectors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cunat, Vicente; Guadalupe, Maria
This paper studies the effect of product market competition on the compensation packages that firms offer to their executives. We use a panel of US executives in the 1990s and exploit two deregulation episodes in the banking and financial sectors as quasi-natural experiments. We provide difference-in-differences estimates of their effect on (1) total pay, (2) estimated fixed pay and performance-pay sensitivities, and (3) the sensitivity of stock option grants. Our results indicate that the deregulations Substantially changed the level and structure of compensation: the variable components of pay increased along with performance-pay sensitivities and, at the same time, the fixed component of pay fell. The overall effect on total pay was small. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cunat, Vicente; Guadalupe, Maria</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividends and price momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asem, Ebenezer
Stock market evidence shows that momentum profits are lower among dividend-paying firms than their non-paying counterparts due to differences in losers' returns. Additionally, dividend maintenance is associated with higher returns for losers but not for winners. Finally, buying winners that increased their dividends and shorting losers that decreased their dividends enhances momentum profits. Consistent with the evidence, the behavioral models suggest that investors underreact to the losers' positive dividend-maintaining news, reducing their return momentum and shrinking the payers' momentum profit. Also, underreaction to positive news from winners' dividend-increasing announcements as well as to negative news from losers' dividend-decreasing announcements explains the higher momentum profits for strategies based on these stocks. The results do not appear consistent with risk-based explanations. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asem, Ebenezer</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Linear-quadratic term structure models - Toward the understanding of jumps in interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, George; Yan, Shu
We study linear-quadratic term structure models with random jumps in the short rate process where the jump arrival rate follows a stochastic process. Empirical results based oil the US data show that incorporating stochastic jump intensity significantly improves model fit to the dynamics of both interest rate and volatility term structure. Our results also show that jump intensity is negatively correlated with interest rate changes and the average size is larger on the downside than upside. Examining the relation between jump intensity and macroeconomic shocks, we find that at monthly frequency, jumps are neither triggered by nor predictive of changes in macroeconomic variables. At daily frequency, however, we document interesting patterns for jumps associated with information shocks. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, George; Yan, Shu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common risk factors in bank stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Viale, Ariel M.; Kolari, James W.; Fraser, Donald R.
This paper provides evidence on the risk factors that are priced in bank equities. Alternative empirical models with precedent in the nonfinancial asset pricing literature are tested, including the single-factor CAPM, three-factor Fama-French model, and ICAPM. Our empirical results indicate that an unconditional two-factor ICAPM model that includes the stock market excess return and shocks to the slope of the yield curve is useful in explaining the cross-section of bank stock returns. However, we find no evidence that firm specific factors such as size and book-to-market ratios are priced in bank stock returns. These results have a number of important implications for the estimation of the banks' cost of capital as well as regulatory initiatives to utilize market discipline to evaluate bank risk under Basel II. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Viale, Ariel M.; Kolari, James W.; Fraser, Donald R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Two counters of jumps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Camara, Antonio
This paper introduces a class of two counters of jumps option pricing models. The stock price follows a jump-diffusion process with price jumps up and price jumps down, where each type of jumps can have different means and standard deviations. Price jumps can be negatively autocorrelated as it has been observed in practice. We investigate the volatility surfaces generated by this class of two counters of jumps option pricing models. Our formulae, like the jump-diffusion models with a single counter of jumps, are able to generate smiles, and skews with similar shapes to those observed in the options markets. More importantly, unlike the jump-diffusion models with a single counter of jumps, our formulae are able to generate term structures of implied volatilities of at-the-money options with boolean AND-shaped patterns similar to those observed in the marketplace. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Camara, Antonio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital management in mutual financial institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Christine; Davis, Kevin
Capital management by mutual financial institutions (such as credit unions) provides a valuable testing ground for assessing the impact of capital regulation and theories of managerial behaviour in financial institutions. Limited access to external equity capital means that capital accumulation Must be met primarily by reliance oil retained earnings. To deal with shocks to the capital position and avoid breaching regulatory requirements, managers will aim to have a buffer of capital in excess of the regulatory minimum. Moreover, mutual governance arrangements and ail absence of capital market discipline mean that managers have discretion to set target capital ratios which differ significantly from industry averages. This paper develops a formal model of capital management and risk management in mutual financial institutions such as credit unions which reflects these industry characteristics. The model is tested using data from larger credit unions in Australia, which have been subject to the Basel Accord Risk Weighted Capital Requirements since 1993. The data supports the hypothesis that credit unions manage their capital position by setting a short term target profit rate (return oil assets) which is positively related to asset growth and which is aimed at gradually removing discrepancies between the actual and desired capital ratio. Desired capital ratios vary significantly across credit unions. There is little evidence of short run adjustments to the risk of the asset portfolio to achieve a desired capital position. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Christine; Davis, Kevin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing the expectations hypothesis when interest rates are near integrated</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beechey, Meredith; Hjalmarsson, Erik; Osterholm, Par
Nominal interest rates are unlikely to be generated by unit-root processes. Using data on short and long interest rates from eight developed and six emerging economies, we test the expectations hypothesis using cointegration methods under the assumption that interest rates are near integrated. If the null hypothesis of no cointegration is rejected, we then test whether the estimated cointegrating vector is consistent with that suggested by the expectations hypothesis. The results show support for cointegration in 10 of the 14 countries we consider, and the cointegrating vector is similar across countries. However, the parameters differ from those suggested by theory. We relate our findings to existing literature on the failure of the expectations hypothesis and to the role of term premia. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Beechey, Meredith; Hjalmarsson, Erik; Osterholm, Par</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leveraged carry trade portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Darvas, Zsolt
Studying all possible pairs of 11 major currencies and 11 portfolios in 1976-2008 we show that, when there is no leverage, carry trade is significantly profitable for most currency pairs and portfolios. Positive returns do not diminish in time providing a strong case against the hypothesis of uncovered interest rate parity. We explain these findings with the leveraged nature of carry trade: leverage may increase profitability but it materially increases downside risk. We argue that market inefficiency is related to the level of leverage. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Darvas, Zsolt</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic linkages across commodity futures: Hedging and trading implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chng, Michael T.
We investigate cross-market trading dynamics in futures contracts written on seemingly unrelated commodities that are consumed by a common industry. On the Tokyo Commodity Exchange, we find such evidence in natural rubber (NR), palladium (PA) and gasoline (GA) futures markets. The automobile industry is responsible for more than 50% of global demand for each of these commodities. VAR estimation reveals short-run cross-market interaction between NR and GA, and from NR to PA. Cross-market influence exerted by PA is felt in longer dynamics, with PA volatility (volume) affecting NR (GA) volume (volatility). Our findings are robust to lag-specification, volatility measure, and consistent with full BEKK-GARCH estimation results. Further analysis, which benchmarks against silver futures market, TOCOM index and TOPIX transportation index, confirms that our results are driven by a common industry exposure, and not a commodity market factor. A simple trading rule that incorporates short-run GA and long-run PA dynamics to predict NR return yields positive economic profit. Our study offers new insights into how commodity and equity markets relate at an industry level, and implications for multi-commodity hedging. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chng, Michael T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why has the investment-cash flow sensitivity declined so sharply? Rising R&amp;D and equity market developments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, James R.; Petersen, Bruce C.
The study of the investment-cash flow (ICF) sensitivity constitutes one of the largest literatures in corporate finance, yet little is known about changes in the ICF relationship over time, and the literature has largely ignored how rising R&amp;D investment and developments in equity markets have impacted ICF sensitivity estimates. We show that for the time period 1970-2006, the ICF sensitivity: (i) largely disappears for physical investment, (ii) remains comparatively strong for R&amp;D, and (iii) declines, but does not disappear, for total investment. We argue that these findings can largely be explained by the changing composition of investment and the rising importance of public equity as a source of funds, particularly for firms with persistent negative cash flows. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, James R.; Petersen, Bruce C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivative use, fund flows and investment manager performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frino, Alex; Lepone, Andrew; Wong, Brad
Prior literature which examines the use of derivatives by investment managers does not discern between different types of derivative trading strategies. This study is the first to examine and gather data on a particular type of derivative trading strategy undertaken by investment managers. We examine the extent to which equity fund managers use index futures to manage fund flows and the effect this has on their alpha and market timing measures of performance. Our results show that funds that do not use derivatives exhibit lower returns and negative market timing skills when they experience fund flow. The performance of funds that use derivatives, however, is independent of investor's liquidity demands. In fact, the unconditional performance of the average user fund is statistically equivalent to the performance of the average non-user fund conditional on zero fund flow. Our results provide evidence that derivatives can be beneficial for mutual fund holders under certain conditions. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frino, Alex; Lepone, Andrew; Wong, Brad</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buy high, sell low: How listed firms price asset transfers in related party transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheung, Yan-Leung; Qi, Yuehua; Rau, P. Raghavendra; Stouraitis, Aris
We examine a sample of 254 related party and arms' length acquisitions and sales of assets in Hong Kong during 1998-2000. Our analysis shows that publicly listed firms enter deals with related parties at unfavourable prices compared to similar arms' length deals. Firms acquire assets from related parties by paying a higher price compared to similar arms' length deals. In contrast, when they sell assets to related parties, they receive a lower price than in similar arms' length deals. With the exception of audit committees, Corporate governance characteristics have limited impact on transaction prices. Firms with audit committees on their boards pay lower prices to related parties for acquisitions and receive higher prices from related parties from divestments. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cheung, Yan-Leung; Qi, Yuehua; Rau, P. Raghavendra; Stouraitis, Aris</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intervention policy of the BoJ: A unified approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beine, Michel; Bernal, Oscar; Gnabo, Jean-Yves; Lecourt, Christelle
intervening in the FX market implies a complex decision process for central banks. Monetary authorities have to decide whether to intervene or not, and if so, when and how. Since the successive steps of this procedure are likely to be highly interdependent, we adopt a nested logit approach to capture their relationships and to characterize the prominent features of the various steps of the intervention decision process. Our estimations based on Japanese data from 1991 to 2004 indicate that the Bank of Japan: (i) mainly reacted to deviations of the exchange rate with respect to fundamentals and (ii) tended to favour secrecy when its credibility was low. We also provide new insights on the so-called secrecy puzzle by modeling explicitly the risk for a secret intervention to be detected. Our results have important implications in terms of exchange rate policy, such as the emergence of a trade-off between intervention size, communication policy and secrecy. Our results tend to provide some explanation for the observed persistence of ineffective intervention policy during some sub-periods. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beine, Michel; Bernal, Oscar; Gnabo, Jean-Yves; Lecourt, Christelle</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sentiment as conditioning information in asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ho, Chienwei; Hung, Chi-Hsiou
This paper assesses whether incorporating investor sentiment as conditioning information in asset-pricing models helps capture the impacts of the size, value, liquidity and momentum effects on risk-adjusted returns of individual stocks. We use survey sentiment measures and a composite index as proxies for investor sentiment. In our conditional framework, the size effect becomes less important in the conditional CAPM and is no longer significant in all the other models examined. Furthermore, the conditional models often capture the value, liquidity and momentum effects. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ho, Chienwei; Hung, Chi-Hsiou</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity shocks, size and the relative performance of hedge fund strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ding, Bill; Shawky, Hany A.; Tian, Jianbo
We examine whether the increase in the flow of capital to hedge funds over the period 1994-2005 had a negative impact on performance. More specifically, we study the relative performance of small versus large funds for each of the hedge fund strategies. Our results indicate that on an absolute return basis, small funds outperform large funds. On a risk-adjusted return basis, however, we find that large funds outperform small funds, and that large funds are also shown to hold less liquid assets and take on less systematic and idiosyncratic risk than small funds. Further, funds that experience positive liquidity shocks generally outperform those that experience negative liquidity shocks. We also find evidence that hedge fund managers that are aggressive in dealing with liquidity shocks perform better than hedge fund managers that are conservative in dealing with liquidity shocks. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ding, Bill; Shawky, Hany A.; Tian, Jianbo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price-setting behavior of banks: An analysis of open-end leverage certificates on the German market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Entrop, Oliver; Scholz, Hendrik; Wilkens, Marco
This paper presents the first analysis of open-end leverage certificates on the German market. The major innovations of these certificates are twofold. First, issuers announce a price-setting formula according to which they are willing to buy and sell the certificates over time. Second, the product's lifetime is potentially endless. Our main findings are that the price-setting formula is (i) designed to strongly favor the issuer and (ii) is consistent with the main outcome of the 'life cycle hypothesis' for structured financial products [Stoimenov, P.A., Wilkens, S., 2005. Are structured products 'fairly' priced? An analysis of the German market for equity-linked instruments. journal of Banking and Finance 29, 2971-2993] (iii) This holds for different product features and also in the presence of issuers' credit risk and jump risk in the underlying. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Entrop, Oliver; Scholz, Hendrik; Wilkens, Marco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What makes a bank risky? Insights from the optimal capital structure of banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koziol, Christian; Lawrenz, Jochen
Assessing the risk of bank failures is the paramount concern of bank regulation. This paper argues that in order to assess the default risk of a bank, it is important to consider its financing decisions as an endogenous dynamic process. We provide a continuous-time model, where banks choose the deposit volume in order to trade off the benefits of earning deposit premiums against the costs that occur at future capital structure adjustments. The bank's asset value may suffer from shocks and follows a jump-diffusion process. Our main finding is that the dynamic endogenous financing decision introduces an important self-regulation mechanism, where it is crucial to distinguish between the diffusion risk and the jump risk component. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koziol, Christian; Lawrenz, Jochen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of household risky asset holdings: Australian evidence on background risk and other factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cardak, Buly A.; Wilkins, Roger
We study the portfolio allocation decisions of Australian households using the relatively new Household, Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia (HILDA) Survey. We focus on household allocations to risky financial assets. Our empirical analysis considers a range of hypothesised determinants of these allocations. We find background risk factors posed by labor income uncertainty and health risk are important. Credit constraints and observed risk preferences play the expected role. A positive age gradient is identified for risky asset holdings and home-ownership is associated with greater risky asset holdings. A unifying theme for many of our empirical findings is the important role played by financial awareness and knowledge in determining risky asset holdings. Many non-stockholding households appear to lack the experience and financial literacy that might enable them to benefit from direct investment in stocks. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cardak, Buly A.; Wilkins, Roger</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A study on long-run inefficiency levels of a panel dynamic cost frontier under the framework of forward-looking rational expectations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Tai-Hsin; Chen, Ying-Hsiu
This paper aims to provide a theoretical underpinning of the dynamic efficiency model pioneered by [Ahn, S.C., Good, D.H., Sickles, R.C., 2000. Estimation of long-run inefficiency levels: A dynamic frontier approach. Econometric Reviews 19, 461-492]. In the context of a quadratic loss function this paper formulates a multi-period forward-looking rational expectations model on the evolution of the technical inefficiency level, which correctly produces a dynamic panel data model. The model is illustrated using panel data of 112 French banks. Encouraging evidence of superiority in favor of the model is reached. Substantial cost inefficiency prevails in this industry, where the constituent banks are characterized as having volatile adjustment speeds toward their long-run steady states. The sample banks exhibit increasing returns to scale and product-mix economies. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Tai-Hsin; Chen, Ying-Hsiu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Family control and dilution in mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basu, Nilanjan; Dimitrova, Lora; Paeglis, Imants
We analyze the influence of the level as well as the change in family ownership on value creation in mergers involving newly public firms. Our findings suggest that acquirers with low levels of family ownership earn lower abnormal returns than do those with high levels of ownership. In addition, families with low ownership in their firm are more likely to use cash as the medium of exchange, thus avoiding dilution and maintaining their control. Further, acquisitions of targets with low levels of family ownership are associated with greater value creation. Our results are consistent with the entrenchment of families at low levels of ownership and a better alignment of their interests with those of minority shareholders at high levels of ownership. Finally, we find that dilution of the family's ownership, due to the use of stock as the medium of exchange, alters the family's incentives and thus influences firm value. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Basu, Nilanjan; Dimitrova, Lora; Paeglis, Imants</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ineffective corporate governance: Director busyness and board committee memberships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiraporn, Pornsit; Singh, Manohar; Lee, Chun I.
Our paper examines whether holding multiple outside board seats compromises a director's ability to effectively perform monitoring duties. Analyzing over 1400 firms, we report that individuals who hold more Outside directorships serve on fewer board committees. The relation, however, appears non-linear, U-shaped, and in Support for both the busyness and the reputation hypotheses. In addition, we find that holding more outside board seats decreases the likelihood of membership on compensation and audit committees. The findings substantiate evidence [Akhigbe, A., Martin, A.D., 2006. Valuation impact of Sarbanes-Oxley: Evidence from disclosure and governance within the financial services industry. journal of Banking and Finance 30 (3), 989-1006] of value relevance of board committee structures. Additional analysis of committee memberships suggests that women and ethnic minorities are placed on more board committees. Also, directors on smaller and independent boards serve on more committees. Finally, it appears that the Sarbanes-Oxley act had a material impact on the association between the number of multiple board seats and committee memberships. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiraporn, Pornsit; Singh, Manohar; Lee, Chun I.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial markets, financial dependence, and the allocation of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pang, Jiaren; Wu, Haibin
We explore one specific channel through which finance promotes growth: the allocation of capital. Using international industrial data, we find that countries with developed financial markets invest more in growing industries, and pull out more funds of declining ones. Most interestingly, this pattern is more eminent for those industries more dependent on external financing. Various robustness checks show that the results are not driven by reverse causality, omitted variables, specific countries or industries. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pang, Jiaren; Wu, Haibin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competitive inventory management in Treasury markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chatrath, Arjun; Christie-David, Rohan A.; Lee, Kiseop; Moore, William T.
We decompose US Treasury bid-ask spreads into inventory, adverse selection and order processing costs by using the fact that inventory trades have different effects on spreads than do proprietary trades. We exploit this asymmetry and develop a technique to identify the three components of the spread in order to test three hypotheses: dealers make larger changes to inventory (1) following macroeconomic announcements (2) at the start and toward the end of the New York trading hours, and (3) when transaction sizes are relatively large. We test these predictions using GovPX data for on-the-run 2-year and 10-year Treasury Notes. All three predictions are supported. We also assess how primary dealers react to the Federal Reserve's open market operations (OMOs). Our findings reveal interesting intraday patterns in the inventory component for both securities. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chatrath, Arjun; Christie-David, Rohan A.; Lee, Kiseop; Moore, William T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loss given default of high loan-to-value residential mortgages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qi, Min; Yang, Xiaolong
This paper studies loss given default using a large set of historical loan-level default and recovery data of high loan-to-value residential mortgages from several private mortgage insurance companies. We show that loss given default can largely be explained by various characteristics associated with the loan, the underlying property, and the default, foreclosure, and settlement process. We find that the current loan-to-value ratio is the single most important determinant. More importantly, mortgage loss severity in distressed housing markets is significantly higher than under normal housing market conditions. These findings have important policy implications for several key issues in Basel II implementation. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Qi, Min; Yang, Xiaolong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the power of cross-sectional and multivariate tests of the CAPM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grauer, Robert R.; Janmaat, Johannus A.
This paper examines the power of the cross-sectional and multivariate tests of the CAPM under ideal conditions. When the CAPM is true the positively weighted market portfolio is W-efficient and securities plot on the security market line. When the CAPM is false an alternative asset pricing model determines prices. An examination of the population intercepts, slopes and R(2) from cross-sectional regressions of expected returns on betas indicates that all three are unreliable indicators of whether the CAPM holds. Simulation analysis of the power of the cross-sectional tests expands on and reinforces the analysis based on the population values. The Gibbons et al. (1989) multivariate test fares much better. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grauer, Robert R.; Janmaat, Johannus A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The stock-bond correlation and macroeconomic conditions: One and a half centuries of evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Jian; Zhou, Yinggang; Wang, Zijun
Using monthly stock and bond return data in the past 150 years (1855-2001) for both the US and the UK, this study documents time-varying stock-bond correlation over macroeconomic conditions (the business cycle, the inflation environment and monetary policy stance). There are different patterns of time variation in stock-bond correlations over the business cycle between US and UK, which implies that bonds may be a better hedge against stock market risk and offer more diversification benefits to stock investors in the US than in the UK. Further, there is a general pattern across both the US and the UK during the post-1923 subperiod and during the whole sample period: higher stock-bond correlations tend to follow higher short rates and (to a lesser extent) higher inflation rates. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yang, Jian; Zhou, Yinggang; Wang, Zijun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of venture capital backing on the corporate governance of Australian initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Suchard, Jo-Ann
This study explores the role of venture capitalists oil investee boards at the time of listing for 552 initial public offerings. Australian board structures and mechanisms are more similar to those in the US and the United Kingdom, but market activity characteristics are more similar to Japanese and German systems. Further, the Australian private equity market is relatively young compared to US and European markets. IPOs backed by venture capital have more independent boards, similar to US IPOs. Venture capitalists improve governance by using their networks to recruit specialist independent directors with industry experience. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Suchard, Jo-Ann</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do informed option investors predict stock returns? Evidence from the Taiwan stock exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Chuang-Chang; Hsieh, Pei-Fang; Lai, Hung-Neng
In this paper, we set out to investigate the information content of options trading using a unique dataset to examine the predictive power of the put and call positions of different types of traders in the TAIEX option market. We find that options volume, as a whole, carries no information on TAIEX spot index changes. On the other hand, however. although foreign institutional investors do not engage in much trading, there is strong evidence to show that the trading in which they do engage has significant predictive power on the underlying asset returns. We also find that foreign institutional investors have greater predictive power with regard to in near-the-money and middle-horizon options. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Chuang-Chang; Hsieh, Pei-Fang; Lai, Hung-Neng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>