<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF15</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Does implied volatility provide any information beyond that captured in model-based volatility forecasts?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Ralf; Clements, Adam E.; White, Scott I.
This paper contributes to our understanding of the informational content of implied volatility. Here we examine whether the S&amp;P 500 implied volatility index (VIX) contains any information relevant to future volatility beyond that available from model based volatility forecasts. It is argued that this approach differs from the traditional forecast encompassing approach used in earlier studies. The findings indicate that the VIX index does not contain any such additional information relevant for forecasting volatility. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Becker, Ralf; Clements, Adam E.; White, Scott I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coherent measures of risk from a general equilibrium perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Csoka, Peter; Herings, P. Jean-Jacques; Koczy, Laszlo A.
Coherent measures of risk defined by the axioms of monotonicity, subadditivity, positive homogeneity, and translation invariance are recent tools in risk management to assess the amount of risk agents are exposed to. If they also satisfy law invariance and comonotonic additivity, then we get a subclass of them: spectral measures of risk. Expected shortfall is a well-known spectral measure of risk. We investigate the above mentioned six axioms using tools from general equilibrium (GE) theory. Coherent and spectral measures of risk are compared to the natural measure of risk derived from an exchange economy model, which we call the GE measure of risk. We prove that GE measures of risk are coherent measures of risk. We also show that spectral measures of risk are GE measures of risk only under stringent conditions, since spectral measures of risk do not take the regulated entity's relation to the market portfolio into account. To give more insights, we characterize the set of GE measures of risk via the pricing kernel property. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Csoka, Peter; Herings, P. Jean-Jacques; Koczy, Laszlo A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are bank shareholders enemies of regulators or a potential source of market discipline?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Sangkyun; Peristiani, Stavros
in moral hazard models, bank shareholders have incentives to transfer wealth from the deposit insurer-that is, maximize put option value - by pursuing riskier strategies. For safe banks with large charter value, however, the risk-taking incentive is outweighed by the possibility of losing charter value. Focusing on the relationship between Tobin's q and an ex ante measure of the failure probability, this paper develops a semi-parametric model for estimating the critical level of bank risk at which put option value starts outweighing charter value. From these estimates, we infer the prevalence of moral hazard. Examining publicly held bank holding companies (BHC) during the tumultuous 1986-1992 period, we find that shareholders' risk-taking incentives were confined to a small fraction of highly risky institutions. Furthermore, our analysis shows that the inflection point at which banks begin to tilt in favor of moral hazard increased substantially in 1993-2005. These findings are encouraging to bank regulators and legislators because they indicate that tighter capital rules and more rigorous supervision introduced by several legislative initiatives in the 1990s have helped squeeze a lot of the moral hazard incentives out of the banking system. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Park, Sangkyun; Peristiani, Stavros</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A simple model of credit contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Egloff, Daniel; Leippold, Markus; Vanini, Paolo
We propose a simple model of credit contagion in which we include macro- and microstructural interdependencies among the debtors within a credit portfolio. The microstructure captures interdependencies between debtors that go beyond their exposure to common factors, e.g., business or legal interdependencies. We show that even for diversified portfolios, moderate microstructural interdependencies have a significant impact on the tails of the loss distribution. This impact increases dramatically for less diversified microstructures. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Egloff, Daniel; Leippold, Markus; Vanini, Paolo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification and the cost of debt of bank holding companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deng, Saiying; Elyasiani, Elyas; Mao, Connie X.
In this study, we investigate the relationship between various dimensions of diversification and the cost of debt for publicly traded bank holding companies (BHCs). We find that both domestic geographic diversification of deposits and diversification of assets lead to a lower bond yield-spread. Diversification of non-traditional banking activities leads to a lower cost of debt only when yield-spread and diversification are estimated simultaneously. In addition, we find that medium-sized BHCs experience a greater reduction in bond yield-spread than small-sized and large-sized BHCs. This is consistent with the too-big-to-fail (TBTF) effects in the banking industry. Furthermore, we document that the association between diversification and yield-spread is bidirectional with higher yield-spreads being associated with greater asset and activity diversification and lower geographic deposit dispersion. The effect of diversification on bond yield-spread is robust after accounting for cross-sectional and serial correlation, and the endogeneity of diversification. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Deng, Saiying; Elyasiani, Elyas; Mao, Connie X.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric information and liquidity constraints: A new test</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holod, Dmytro; Peek, Joe
Using a novel measure of the degree of information asymmetry across firms, this study shows that information-related financial market imperfections do matter for a firm's access to external finance. Prior studies of the importance of liquidity constraints faced by nonfinancial firms have suffered from a glaring weakness. They have been based on a sample of publicly traded firms, omitting precisely those firms most likely to be liquidity constrained. Furthermore, they have tended to rely on indirect measures of the degree of information asymmetry, such as firm size. We overcome these limitations by focusing on the banking sector. Unlike the nonfinancial sector, the banking sector has balance sheet and income data available for all firms, whether or not they are publicly traded. This allows the use of a superior measure of the degree of information asymmetry across firms by distinguishing between publicly traded and non-publicly traded banks. We focus on changes in monetary policy that represent exogenous (to the banks) changes in the financing constraints they face. We find that publicly traded banks, which exhibit a lower degree of information asymmetry, are better able to overcome information-based financial market frictions, compared to the relatively opaque non-publicly traded banks, when monetary policy is tightened. Lending by the more transparent publicly traded banks is less affected by a monetary policy tightening in large part due to their relative advantage in raising external funds by issuing uninsured large time deposits. These results are obtained controlling for bank (and bank holding company) size, a dimension commonly used in the literature as the measure of the degree of firm access to external finance. Moreover, we show that the distinction between publicly traded and non-publicly traded banks dominates bank size as an indicator of the degree of access to external funds. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Holod, Dmytro; Peek, Joe</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selecting copulas for risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kole, Erik; Koedijk, Kees; Verbeek, Marno
Copulas offer financial risk managers a powerful tool to model the dependence between the different elements of a portfolio and are preferable to the traditional, correlation-based approach. In this paper, we show the importance of selecting an accurate copula for risk management. We extend standard goodness-of-fit tests to copulas. Contrary to existing, indirect tests, these tests can be applied to any copula of any dimension and are based on a direct comparison of a given copula with observed data. For a portfolio consisting of stocks, bonds and real estate, these tests provide clear evidence in favor of the Student's t copula, and reject both the correlation-based Gaussian copula and the extreme value-based Gumbel copula. In comparison with the Student's t copula, we find that the Gaussian copula underestimates the probability of joint extreme downward movements, while the Gumbel copula overestimates this risk. Similarly we establish that the Gaussian copula is too optimistic on diversification benefits, while the Gumbel copula is too pessimistic. Moreover, these differences are significant. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kole, Erik; Koedijk, Kees; Verbeek, Marno</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Theory and evidence on the dynamic interactions between sovereign credit default swaps and currency options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren
Using sovereign CDS spreads and currency option data for Mexico and Brazil, we document that CDS spreads covary with both the currency option implied volatility and the slope of the implied volatility curve in moneyness. We propose a joint valuation framework, in which currency return variance and sovereign default intensity follow a bivariate diffusion with contemporaneous correlation. Estimation shows that default intensity is much more persistent than currency return variance. The market price estimates on the two risk factors also explain the well-documented evidence that historical average default probabilities are lower than those implied from credit spreads. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing joint ventures as corporate control activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Slovin, Myron B.; Sushka, Marie E.; Mantecon, Tomas P.
We analyze joint ventures initiated by two publicly traded firms, and compare the results to asset sales and mergers. Combined returns are significantly greater for joint ventures than asset sales, and smaller than mergers. Gains are shared between joint venture parties, unlike asset sales and mergers where all gains accrue to sellers/targets. Ownership structure has no effect on joint venture returns. Combined gains from quasi-asset-sale joint ventures are significantly greater than for asset sales, and similar to mergers. Horizontal joint ventures generate greater gains than vertical or cross-industry ventures, and there is evidence that horizontal ventures capitalize expected monopoly rents. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Slovin, Myron B.; Sushka, Marie E.; Mantecon, Tomas P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Potential cost synergies from banks acquiring real estate brokerage services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewis, Danielle; Webb, James R.
National banks and Financial Holding Companies (FHC) solicited permission from the Federal Reserve Board and the Treasury Department to add real estate brokerage and management services to list of permissible business activities under the 1999 Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLB). To date, permission has been denied due to the Community Choice in Real Estate Act, HR 111 and S 98. This study offers a method of combining the financial data of two independent industries. Additionally, this study identifies the scale returns and cost complementarities that may occur if banks offered real estate brokerage services under a single organization. Considerable evidence suggests that joining bank and real estate activities under a single organization would continue to generate increasing returns to scale for banks even when large levels of real estate brokerage services are offered by the joint institution. In addition, the results indicate evidence that bank acquisitions of real estate brokerages do create some cost saving synergies from cost complementarities between product lines. Finally, complementarities exist between traditional bank services and real estate services most at low levels of real estate outputs. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lewis, Danielle; Webb, James R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum strategies based on reward-risk stock selection criteria</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rachev, Svetlozar; Jasic, Teo; Stoyanov, Stoyan; Fabozzi, Frank J.
In this paper, we analyze momentum strategies that are based on reward-risk stock selection criteria in contrast to ordinary momentum strategies based on a cumulative return criterion. Reward-risk stock selection criteria include the standard Sharpe ratio with variance as a risk measure, and alternative reward-risk ratios with the expected shortfall as a risk measure. We investigate momentum strategies using 517 stocks in the S&amp;P 500 universe in the period 1996-2003. Although the cumulative return criterion provides the highest average monthly momentum profits of 1.3% compared to the monthly profit of 0.86% for the best alternative criterion, the alternative ratios provide better risk-adjusted returns measured on an independent risk-adjusted performance measure. We also provide evidence on unique distributional properties of extreme momentum portfolios analyzed within the framework of general non-normal stable Paretian distributions. Specifically, for every stock selection criterion, loser portfolios have the lowest tail index and tail index of winner portfolios is lower than that of middle deciles. The lower tail index is associated with a lower mean strategy. The lowest tail index is obtained for the cumulative return strategy. Given our data-set, these findings indicate that the cumulative return strategy obtains higher profits with the acceptance of higher tail risk, while strategies based on reward-risk criteria obtain better risk-adjusted performance with the acceptance of the lower tail risk. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rachev, Svetlozar; Jasic, Teo; Stoyanov, Stoyan; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the stock market value bank diversification?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baele, Lieven; De Jonghe, Olivier; Vennet, Rudi Vander
This paper investigates whether or not functionally diversified banks have a comparative advantage in terms of long-term performance/risk profile compared to their specialized competitors. To that end, this study uses market-based measures of return potential and bank risk. We calculate the franchise value over time of European banks as a measure of their long-run performance potential. In addition, we measure risk as both the systematic and the idiosyncratic risk components derived from a bank stock return model. Finally, we analyze the return/risk trade-off implied in different functional diversification strategies using a panel data analysis over the period 1989-2004. A higher share of non-interest income in total income affects banks' franchise values positively. Diversification of revenue streams from distinct financial activities increases the systematic risk of banks while the effect on the idiosyncratic risk component is non-linear and predominantly downward-sloping. These findings have conflicting implications for different stakeholders, such as investors, bank shareholders, bank managers and bank supervisors. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baele, Lieven; De Jonghe, Olivier; Vennet, Rudi Vander</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Small European banks: Benefits from diversification?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mercieca, Steve; Schaeck, Klaus; Wolfe, Simon
Motivated by the liberalisation and harmonisation of financial systems in Europe, we investigate whether the observed shift into non-interest income activities improves performance of small European credit institutions. Using a sample of 755 small banks for the period 1997-2003, we find no direct diversification benefits within and across business lines and an inverse association between non-interest income and bank performance. Our findings are robust to a set of sensitivity analyses using alternative samples and controlling for the regulatory environment. Furthermore, the results provide circumstantial evidence for the presence of economies of scale. The absence of benefits of diversification confirms findings for other banking markets and suggests small European banks enter lines of business where they currently lack expertise and experience. These results have implications for bank supervisors, regulators and bank managers. Crown Copyright (c) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mercieca, Steve; Schaeck, Klaus; Wolfe, Simon</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Obstacles to a global banking system: "Old Europe" versus "New Europe"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.
"Old Europe" - the developed nations of continental Europe - averages only about 15% foreign bank ownership, whereas "New Europe" - the transition nations of Eastern Europe - averages about 70%. Similar findings hold elsewhere in the world - developed nations tend to have much lower foreign bank ownership shares than developing nations. We examine the causes of the differences within Europe with an eye toward more general conclusions. Our findings suggest that the low foreign bank shares in "Old Europe" - and perhaps developed nations more generally - may primarily result from net comparative disadvantages for foreign banks and relatively high implicit government entry barriers. The high foreign penetration in "New Europe" - and perhaps developing nations more generally - may be due to net comparative advantages for foreign banks and low government entry barriers, particularly in nations that reduced their state bank ownership. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and growth in the EU: New evidence from the harmonisation of the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Romero-Avila, Diego
This paper presents an investigation of the finance-growth nexus by analysing the growth effect of the harmonisation of banking laws in the EU-15 over the period 1960-2001. The main findings point to the existence of a positive growth impact from banking harmonisation. These results are robust to controlling for other growth determinants, unobserved heterogeneity, potential simultaneity bias and business-cycle effects. The analysis of the transmission channels indicates that the harmonisation process influences economic growth mainly through the increase in the efficiency of financial intermediation. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Romero-Avila, Diego</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>European banking: An overview</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goddard, John; Molyneux, Philip; Wilson, John O. S.; Tavakoli, Manouche
Against a background of far-reaching structural change in the banking sector, this article reviews the recent academic literature on developments in European banking. European banking markets have become increasingly integrated in recent years, but barriers to full integration, especially in retail banking, still remain. European integration has possible implications for systemic risk, and poses various challenges for the current supervisory framework. The banks' responses to the changing competitive environment include the pursuit of strategies of diversification, vertical product differentiation and consolidation. European integration has implications for competition in banking markets, for the nature of long-term borrower-lender relationships, and for the relationships between ownership structure, technological change and bank efficiency. The article concludes by reviewing recent literature on the credit channel in the monetary transmission mechanism, and interest rate pass-through. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goddard, John; Molyneux, Philip; Wilson, John O. S.; Tavakoli, Manouche</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Developments in European banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Molyneux, Phil; Wilson, John O. S.
nan</description><author>Molyneux, Phil; Wilson, John O. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Euro and European financial market dependence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Sohnke M.; Taylor, Stephen J.; Wang, Yaw-Huei
A time-varying copula model is used to investigate the impact of the introduction of the Euro on the dependence between 17 European stock markets during the period 1994-2003. The model is implemented with a GJR-GARCH-MA-t model for the marginal distributions and the Gaussian copula for the joint distribution, which allows capturing time-varying, non-linear relationships. The results show that, within the Euro area, market dependence increased after the introduction of the common currency only for large equity markets, such as in France, Germany, Italy, the Netherlands and Spain. Structural break tests indicate that the increase in financial market dependence started around the beginning of 1998 when Euro membership was determined and the relevant information was announced. The UK and Sweden, but not other European countries outside the Euro area, are found to exhibit an increase in equity market co-movement, which is consistent with the interpretation that these countries may be expected to join the Euro in the future. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bartram, Sohnke M.; Taylor, Stephen J.; Wang, Yaw-Huei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bricks versus Clicks: The changing nature of banking in the 21st century - Special issue in memory of Lawrence Goldberg</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Linda; Rai, Anoop
nan</description><author>Allen, Linda; Rai, Anoop</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical evaluation of the overconfidence hypothesis (vol 30, pg 2489, 2006)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chuang, Wen-I.; Lee, Bong-Soo
nan</description><author>Chuang, Wen-I.; Lee, Bong-Soo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Noise sensitivity of portfolio selection under various risk measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kondor, Ime; Pafka, Szilard; Nagy, Gabor
We study the sensitivity to estimation error of portfolios optimized under various risk measures, including variance, absolute deviation, expected shortfall and maximal loss. We introduce a measure of portfolio sensitivity and test the various risk measures by considering simulated portfolios of varying sizes N and for different lengths T of the time series. We find that the effect of noise is very strong in all the investigated cases, asymptotically it only depends on the ratio NIT, and diverges (goes to infinity) at a critical value of NIT, that depends on the risk measure in question. This divergence is the manifestation of a phase transition, analogous to the algorithmic phase transitions recently discovered in a number of hard computational problems. The transition is accompanied by a number of critical phenomena, including the divergent sample to sample fluctuations of portfolio weights. While the optimization under variance and mean absolute deviation is always feasible below the critical value of NIT, expected shortfall and maximal loss display a probabilistic feasibility problem, in that they can become unbounded from below already for small values of the ratio NIT, and then no solution exists to the optimization problem under these risk measures. Although powerful filtering techniques exist for the mitigation of the above instability in the case of variance, our findings point to the necessity of developing similar filtering procedures adapted to the other risk measures where they are much less developed or non-existent. Another important message of this study is that the requirement of robustness (noise-tolerance) should be given special attention when considering the theoretical and practical criteria to be imposed on a risk measure. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kondor, Ime; Pafka, Szilard; Nagy, Gabor</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bidding behavior in the longer term refinancing operations of the European Central Bank: Evidence from a panel sample selection model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linzert, Tobias; Nautz, Dieter; Bindseil, Ulrich
This paper analyzes individual bidding data of the longer term refinancing operations (LTROs) of the European Central Bank. We investigate how banks' bidding behavior is related to a series of exogenous variables including collateral costs, interest rate expectations, market volatility and to individual bank characteristics like country of origin, size, and experience. A specific feature of these auctions is that the number and composition of bidders varies over time. Therefore, we estimate panel sample selection models to control for a bank's endogenous participation decision. We find that bidding strategies depend on the banks' attributes. Yet, different bidding behavior generally does not translate into differences concerning bidder success. There is evidence for the winner's curse effect in LTROs indicating a common value component in banks' demand for longer term refinancing. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Linzert, Tobias; Nautz, Dieter; Bindseil, Ulrich</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Closed-form transformations from risk-neutral to real-world distributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Xiaoquan; Shackleton, Mark B.; Taylor, Stephen J.; Xu, Xinzhong
Risk-neutral and real-world densities are derived from option prices and risk assumptions, and are compared with historical densities obtained from time series. Two parametric risk-transformations are used to convert risk-neutral densities into real-world densities. Both transformations are estimated by maximizing the likelihood of observed index levels, for two parametric density families. Results for the FTSE-100 index show that parametric densities derived from option prices have more explanatory power than historical densities and higher likelihoods than densities estimated by spline methods. A combination of parametric real-world and historical densities provides the preferred predictive densities. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Xiaoquan; Shackleton, Mark B.; Taylor, Stephen J.; Xu, Xinzhong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-listing and legal bonding: Evidence from mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burns, Natasha; Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar
Using a sample of foreign acquisitions of US targets, this study examines the extent to which cross-listing in the US leads to legal and regulatory bonding, and/or whether reputational bonding proxied by financial intermediaries monitoring, an often ignored component of the bonding mechanism, is an important factor in US investors decision to hold shares in cross-listed firms. We find that compared to US firms, cross-listed firms are less likely to use equity in takeovers of US targets. Further, cross-listed firms from countries with poorer legal protections are less likely to finance with equity and pay higher premiums than cross-listed firms from countries with better legal protections. Using analysts' coverage and institutional following as proxies for financial intermediary monitoring, we find some support for the importance of reputational bonding. The evidence suggests that while cross-listing reduces barriers to investment, there are limits to its ability to completely subsume both the legal environment and the importance of the monitoring of financial intermediaries. This further suggests that the extent of actual legal and regulatory bonding by cross-listed firms may be more limited than often assumed. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Burns, Natasha; Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How the Internet affects output and performance at community banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeYoung, Robert; Lang, William W.; Nolle, Daniel L.
Internet web sites have become an important alternative distribution channel for most banking institutions. However, we still know little about the impact of this delivery channel on bank performance. We observe 424 community banks among the first wave of US banks to adopt transactional banking web sites in the late-1990s, and compare the change in their 1999-2001 financial performance to that of 5175 branching-only community banks. Whereas today virtually all viable community banking franchises offer the Internet banking channel, studying this earlier time period allows us to make clean comparisons between subsamples of "brick-and-mortar" and "click-and-mortar" community banks. We find that Internet adoption improved community bank profitability, chiefly through increased revenues from deposit service charges. Internet adoption was also associated with movements of deposits from checking accounts to money market deposit accounts, increased use of brokered deposits, and higher average wage rates for bank employees. We find little evidence of changes in loan portfolio mix. Our findings suggest that these initial click-and-mortar banks (and their customers) used the Internet channel as a complement to, rather than a substitute for, physical branches. (c) Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>DeYoung, Robert; Lang, William W.; Nolle, Daniel L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>ATM surcharge bans and bank market structure: The case of Iowa and its neighbors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hannan, Timothy H.
It is frequently claimed that high ATM surcharges actually attract customers to the banks that impose them, particularly if they operate large ATM networks. By exploiting as "natural experiments" two events associated with the lifting of surcharge bans in Iowa and in the states that neighbor Iowa, this paper seeks to test for the implications of this phenomenon as it applies to the market shares of banking institutions and to several aspects of market structure. Consistent with predictions, results of "difference-in-difference" analyses suggest that the retail account shares of larger market participants increased relative to those of smaller competitors, market concentration increased, and the number of market competitors decreased after the lifting of surcharge bans - all relative to what would have occurred had there been no change in authority to surcharge. (c) Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hannan, Timothy H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the Internet delivery channel changing banks' performance? The case of Spanish banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hernando, Ignacio; Nieto, Maria J.
In spite of the conspicuous use of the Internet as a delivery channel, there is a relative dearth of empirical studies that provide a quantitative analysis of the impact of the Internet on banks' financial performance. This paper attempts to fill this gap by identifying and estimating the impact of the adoption of a transactional web site on financial performance using a sample of 72 commercial banks operating in Spain over the period 1994-2002. The impact on banks' performance of transactional web adoption takes time to appear. The adoption of the Internet as a delivery channel involves a gradual reduction in overhead expenses (particularly, staff, marketing and IT). This effect is statistically significant after one and a half years after adoption. The cost reduction translates into an improvement in banks' profitability, which becomes significant after one and a half years in terms of ROA and after three years in terms of ROE. The paper also concludes that the Internet is being used as a complement to, rather than a substitute for, physical branches. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hernando, Ignacio; Nieto, Maria J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating the Nordea experiment: Evidence from market and accounting data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldberg, Lawrence G.; Sweeney, Richard J.; Wihlborg, Clas G.
This paper discusses results and difficulties of comparing banks' performance based on publicly available data for the case of Nordea, a pan-Nordic bank created through mergers of important national banks. The objective is to determine whether Nordea's unique strategy of functional integration across four countries can be advantageous. For stock-market data, however, Nordea does not have stable betas on risk factors, and thus the comparables method must be used with great care. The Nordea holding company performed about as well as the comparables, both in terms of stock-market and accounting data. Nordea banks in individual countries outperformed comparable holding companies; by arithmetic, Nordea non-bank operations are not as profitable as its bank operations. In event studies, the data lend only the weakest support to the hypothesis that the market viewed Nordea's acquisitions as adding value. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goldberg, Lawrence G.; Sweeney, Richard J.; Wihlborg, Clas G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of bank consolidation on small business credit availability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Craig, Steven G.; Hardee, Pauline
This paper examines how banking consolidation has affected small businesses credit. Using the Survey of Small Business Finances, the empirical model examines how credit supply to small firms responds to larger banks, and whether the non-bank supply of credit has offset decreases in credit from banks. Using an empirical model to correct for sample selection, large banks are found to lower the probability of obtaining credit for small businesses, and this lower probability is not offset by increased total loans. Non-bank institutions are found to make up much, but not all, of the decrease. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Craig, Steven G.; Hardee, Pauline</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cyclicality in catastrophic and operational risk measurements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Linda; Bali, Turan G.
Using equity returns for financial institutions we estimate both catastrophic and operational risk measures over the period 1973-2003. We find evidence of cyclical components in both the catastrophic and operational risk measures obtained from the generalized Pareto distribution and the skewed generalized error distribution. Our new, comprehensive approach to measuring operational risk shows that approximately 18% of financial institutions' returns represent compensation for operational risk. However, depository institutions are exposed to operational risk levels that average 39% of the overall equity risk premium. Moreover, operational risk events are more likely to be the cause of large unexpected catastrophic losses, although when they occur, the losses are smaller than those resulting from a combination of market risk, credit risk or other risk events. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allen, Linda; Bali, Turan G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convergence and risk-return linkages across financial service firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elyasiani, Elyas; Mansur, Iqbal; Pagano, Michael S.
We examine the risk and return linkages across US commercial banks, securities firms, and life insurance companies during the 1991-2001 period. After controlling for changes in the broader stock market, interest rates, and foreign currency values, we find that return and risk interdependencies across these financial firms are significant and size-varying; larger institutions display stronger volatility transmission linkages, while smaller ones exhibit more prominent return-related linkages. The tighter link in risk among large financial institutions (FIs) suggests stronger convergence, employment of common models of risk measurement and risk management, and more intense inter-industry competition, particularly between large banks and large securities firms, compared to smaller institutions. Lack of risk spillover among smaller FIs confirms the intuition that they typically assume more localized and idiosyncratic risk. The co-movement of stock returns among smaller FIs has been helped by the effects of locally based factors, such as economic conditions and state regulations, on all such institutions, and a less diversified product set. Differences in spillover patterns between large and smaller institutions have implications on investment choices and mergers and acquisitions in the industry. Introduction of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (1999) has had dissimilar effects on the riskiness of large versus smaller life insurance and securities firms, and an insignificant effect on commercial banks. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elyasiani, Elyas; Mansur, Iqbal; Pagano, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value at risk and the cross-section of hedge fund returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Gokcan, Suleyman; Liang, Bing
Using two large hedge fund databases, this paper empirically tests the presence and significance of a cross-sectional relation between hedge fund returns and value at risk (VaR). The univariate and bivariate portfolio-level analyses as well as the fund-level regression results indicate a significantly positive relation between VaR and the cross-section of expected returns on live funds. During the period of January 1995 to December 2003, the live funds with high VaR outperform those with low VaR by an annual return difference of 9%. This risk-return tradeoff holds even after controlling for age, size, and liquidity factors. Furthermore, the risk profile of defunct funds is found to be different from that of live funds. The relation between downside risk and expected return is found to be negative for defunct funds because taking high risk by these funds can wipe out fund capital, and hence they become defunct. Meanwhile, voluntary closure makes some well performed funds with large assets and low risk fall into the defunct category. Hence, the risk-return relation for defunct funds is more complicated than what implies by survival. We demonstrate how to distinguish live funds from defunct funds on an ex ante basis. A trading rule based on buying the expected to live funds and selling the expected to disappear funds provides an annual profit of 8-10% depending on the investment horizons. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Gokcan, Suleyman; Liang, Bing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The return to retail and the performance of US banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirtle, Beverly J.; Stiroh, Kevin J.
The US banking industry is experiencing a renewed focus on retail banking, a trend often attributed to the stability and profitability of retail activities. This paper examines the impact of banks' retail intensity on performance from 1997 to 2004 by developing three complementary definitions of retail intensity (retail loan share, retail deposit share, and branches per dollar of assets) and comparing these measures with both equity market and accounting measures of performance. We find that an increased focus on retail banking across US banks is linked with significantly lower equity market and accounting returns for all banks, but lower volatility for only the largest banking companies. We conclude that retail banking may be a relatively stable activity, but it is also a low return one. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hirtle, Beverly J.; Stiroh, Kevin J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO auctions and private information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Ji-Chai; Lee, Yi-Tsung; Liu, Yu-Jane
IPO auctions, which provide an impartial way of determining IPO pricing and share allocations, offer a natural setting for examining whether institutional investors possess private information, and for measuring how valuable their information is. Analyzing detailed bidding data from Taiwan's discriminatory (pay-as-bid) auctions, we find that, relative to retail investors, institutional investors tend to bid higher in auctions when IPO shares are more valuable, and that underpricing is larger in auctions with relatively higher institutional bids. These results imply that institutional investors are better informed about IPO value, and that they obtain higher information rents when they bid higher relative to retail investors. We estimate the value of institutional investors' private information to be worth about 8.68% of return, which is the extra rate of return they command on their informational advantages over retail investors. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Ji-Chai; Lee, Yi-Tsung; Liu, Yu-Jane</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The emergence of market monitoring in Japanese banks: Evidence from the subordinated debt market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Imai, Masami
This paper uses a unique data set on the spreads of subordinated debts issued by Japanese banks to investigate the presence of market monitoring. The results show that subordinated debt investors punished weak banks by requiring higher interest rates. Moreover, I find that the spreads and the sensitivity of spreads to Moody's bank ratings both increased dramatically after the Japanese government allowed a large city bank, Hokkaido Takushoku Bank, to fail and passed the Financial Reform Act and the Rapid Revitalization Act in the late 1990s. These results suggest that the decline of conjectural guarantee led to the emergence of market monitoring. In addition, I find the relationship between spreads and accounting measures of bank risk. to be quite fragile. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Imai, Masami</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploiting short-run predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomes, Francisco J.
This paper measures the utility gains from exploiting short-run predictability in the volatility of stock returns in a dynamic model in the the presence of transaction costs, short-selling constraints and estimation risk. We find that utility gains are quite significant, both ex ante and out-of-sample. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gomes, Francisco J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the behavioral differences between professional and amateur investors after the weekend</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Venezia, Itzhak; Shapira, Zur
This paper compares the trading patterns of amateur and professional investors during the days following the weekend. The comparison is based on all the daily transactions of a large sample of both amateurs and professionally managed investors in a major brokerage house in Israel from 1994 to 1998. We find that weekends influence both amateurs and professional investors; however they affect them in opposite directions. Individuals increase both their buy and sell activities, and their propensity to sell rises more than their propensity to buy. Professionals on the other hand tend to perform fewer buy as well as sell trades after the weekend, but unlike individuals, the drop in their activity is almost the same for buy trades and for sell trades. The results agree with previous hypotheses raised in the literature, which were not directly tested, about the effects of the weekend on the predisposition to trade of individuals and institutions in other markets. We also find that returns on the Israeli Stock Market Index are correlated in general with the behavioral patterns exhibited by the investors in our sample. In particular the returns on the days following the weekend are lower than those in other weekdays in a manner consistent with the behavioral patterns we found. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Venezia, Itzhak; Shapira, Zur</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme co-movements and extreme impacts in high frequency data in finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Zhengjun; Shinki, Kazuhiko
Extreme co-movement and extreme impact problems are inherently stochastic control problems, since they will influence the decision taken today and ultimately influence a decision taken in the future. Extreme co-movements among financial assets have been reported in the literature. However, extreme impacts have not been carefully studied yet. In this paper, we use the newly developed methodology to further explore extreme co-movements and extreme impacts in financial market. Particularly, two FX spot rates are studied. Based on the results of our analysis with FX returns, we conclude that there exist extreme co-movements and extreme impacts in FX returns and care has to be taken when we employ portfolio optimization models, especially models without the ability of handling extreme dependencies. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhang, Zhengjun; Shinki, Kazuhiko</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Correlation expansions for CDO pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glasserman, Paul; Suchintabandid, Sira
This paper develops numerical approximations for pricing collateralized debt obligations (CDOs) and other portfolio credit derivatives in the multifactor Normal Copula model. A key aspect of pricing portfolio credit derivatives is capturing dependence between the defaults of the elements of the portfolio. But, compared with an independent-obligor model, pricing in a model with correlated defaults is more challenging. Our approach strikes a balance by reducing the problem of pricing in a model with correlated defaults to calculations involving only independent defaults. We develop approximations based on power series expansions in a parameter that scales the underlying correlations. These expansions express a CDO tranche price in a multifactor model as a series of prices in independent-obligor models, which are easy to compute. The approach builds on a classical approximation for multivariate Gaussian probabilities; we introduce an alternative representation that greatly reduces the number of terms required to evaluate the coefficients in the expansion. We also apply this method to the underlying problem of computing joint probabilities of multivariate normal random variables for which the correlation matrix has a factor structure. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Glasserman, Paul; Suchintabandid, Sira</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technical analysis compared to mathematical models based methods under parameters mis-specification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blanchet-Scalliet, Christophette; Diop, Awa; Gibson, Rajna; Talay, Denis; Tanre, Etienne
In this study, we compare the performance of trading strategies based on possibly mis-specified mathematical models with a trading strategy based on a technical trading rule. In both cases, the trader attempts to predict a change in the drift of the stock return occurring at an unknown time. We explicitly compute the trader's expected logarithmic utility of wealth for the various trading strategies. We next rely on Monte Carlo numerical experiments to compare their performance. The simulations show that under parameter mis-specification, the technical analysis technique out-performs the optimal allocation strategy but not the Model and Detect strategies. The latter strategies dominance is confirmed under parameter mis-specification as long as the two stock returns' drifts are high in absolute terms. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blanchet-Scalliet, Christophette; Diop, Awa; Gibson, Rajna; Talay, Denis; Tanre, Etienne</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>United States current account deficits: A stochastic optimal control analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stein, Jerome L.
The "Pessimists" and the "Optimists" disagree whether the US external deficits and the associated buildup of US net foreign liabilities are problems that require urgent attention. A warning signal should be that the debt ratio deviates significantly from the optimal ratio. The optimal debt ratio or debt burden should take into account the vulnerability of consumption to shocks from the productivity of capital, the interest rate and exchange rate. The optimal debt ratio is derived from inter-temporal optimization using Dynamic Programming, because the shocks are unpredictable, and it is essential to have a feedback control mechanism. The optimal ratio depends upon the risk adjusted net return and risk aversion both at home and abroad. On the basis of alternative estimates, we conclude that the Pessimists' fears are justified on the basis of trends. The trend of the actual debt ratio is higher than that of the optimal ratio. The Optimists are correct that the current debt ratio is not a menace, because the current level of the debt ratio is not above the corresponding level of the optimum ratio. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stein, Jerome L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal life insurance purchase and consumption/investment under uncertain lifetime</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pliska, Stanley R.; Ye, Jinchun
In this paper, we consider optimal insurance and consumption rules for a wage earner whose lifetime is random. The wage earner is endowed with an initial wealth, and he also receives an income continuously, but this may be terminated by the wage earner's premature death. We use dynamic programming to analyze this problem and derive the optimal insurance and consumption rules. Explicit solutions are found for the family of CRRA utilities, and the demand for life insurance is studied by examining our solutions and doing numerical experiments. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pliska, Stanley R.; Ye, Jinchun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidation of a large block of stock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pemy, M.; Zhang, Q.; Yin, G.
In the financial engineering literature, stock-selling rules are mainly concerned with liquidation of the security within a short period of time. This is practically feasible only when a relative smaller number of shares of a stock is involved. Selling a large position in a market place normally depresses the market if sold in a short period of time, which would result in poor filling prices. In this paper, we consider the liquidation strategy for selling a large block of stock by selling much smaller number of shares over a longer period of time. In particular, we treat the selling rule problem by using a fluid model in the sense that the number of shares are treated as fluid (continuous) and the corresponding liquidation is dictated by the rate of selling over time. The objective is to maximize the expected overall return. The underlying problem may be formulated as a stochastic control problem with state constraints. Method of constrained viscosity solution is used to characterize the dynamics governing the optimal reward function and the associated boundary conditions. Numerical examples are reported to illustrate the results. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pemy, M.; Zhang, Q.; Yin, G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inter-temporal optimization in a stochastic environment: Introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stein, J. L.; Zheng, Ziyu
nan</description><author>Stein, J. L.; Zheng, Ziyu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk assessment for credit portfolios: A coupled Markov chain model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaniovski, Y. M.; Pflug, G. Ch
Credit portfolios, as for instance Collateralized Debt Obligations (CDO's) consist of credits that are heterogeneous both with respect to their ratings and the involved industry sectors. Estimates for the transition probabilities for different rating classes are well known and documented. We develop a Markov chain model, which uses the given transition probability matrix as the marginal law, but introduces correlation coefficients within and between industry sectors and between rating classes for the joint law of migration of all components of the portfolio. We have found a generating function for the one step joint distribution of all assets having non-default credit ratings and a generating function of the loss distribution. The numerical simulations presented here verify that the average number of defaults is not affected by the correlation coefficients, but the percentiles of the number of defaults are heavily dependent upon them. In particular, for strongly correlated assets, the distribution of the number of defaults follows a "cascade" pattern nesting in non-overlapping intervals. As a result, the probability of a large number of defaults is higher for correlated assets than for non-correlated ones. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaniovski, Y. M.; Pflug, G. Ch</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using Tucker's theorem of the alternative to simplify, review and expand discrete arbitrage theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kallio, Markku; Ziemba, William T.
For valuing derivatives and other assets in securities and commodities markets, arbitrage pricing theory has been a major approach for decades. This paper derives fundamental arbitrage pricing results in finite dimensions in a simple unified framework using Tucker's theorem of the alternative. Frictionless results, that is perfect market results, plus imperfect market results such as those with dividends, periodic interest payments, transaction costs, different interest rates for lending and borrowing, shorting costs and constrained short selling are presented. While the results are mostly known and appear in various places, our contribution is to present them in a coherent and comprehensive fashion with very simple proofs. The analysis yields a simple procedure to prove new results and some are presented for cases with imperfect market frictions. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kallio, Markku; Ziemba, William T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regime switching based portfolio selection for pension funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frauendorfer, Karl; Jacoby, Ulrich; Schwendener, Alvin
This paper shows how a mean variance criterion can be applied to a multi period setting in order to obtain efficient portfolios in an asset and liability context. The optimization model allows for rebalancing activities, transaction costs, stochastic volatilities for both assets and liabilities. Furthermore, a general framework for the projection of pension fund liabilities as well as for the generation of asset returns is given. In a further step the dynamics of the liability maturity structure is modeled as customized index, whose volatility and correlation with asset returns become integral components of the applied regime switching approach. The numerical results illustrate the diversification of the assets and its risk return pattern in dependency of the liability dynamics. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frauendorfer, Karl; Jacoby, Ulrich; Schwendener, Alvin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial prediction with constrained tail risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trindade, A. Alexandre; Uryasev, Stan; Shapiro, Alexander; Zrazhevsky, Grigory
A new class of asymmetric loss functions derived from the least absolute deviations or least squares loss with a constraint on the mean of one tail of the residual error distribution, is introduced for analyzing financial data. Motivated by risk management principles, the primary intent is to provide "cautious" forecasts under uncertainty. The net effect on fitted models is to shape the residuals so that on average only a prespecified proportion of predictions tend to fall above or below a desired threshold. The loss functions are reformulated as objective functions in the context of parameter estimation for linear regression models, and it is demonstrated how optimization can be implemented via linear programming. The method is a competitor of quantile regression, but is more flexible and broader in scope. An application is illustrated on prediction of NDX and SPX index returns data, while controlling the magnitude of a fraction of worst losses. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Trindade, A. Alexandre; Uryasev, Stan; Shapiro, Alexander; Zrazhevsky, Grigory</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Covariance complexity and rates of return on assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>MacLean, Leonard C.; Foster, Michael E.; Ziemba, William T.
This paper considers the estimation of the expected rate of return on a set of risky assets. The approach to estimation focuses on the covariance matrix for the returns. The structure in the covariance matrix determines shared information which is useful in estimating the mean return for each asset. An empirical Bayes estimator is developed using the covariance structure of the returns distribution. The estimator is an improvement on the maximum likelihood and Bayes-Stein estimators in terms of mean squared error. The effect of reduced estimation error on accumulated wealth is analyzed for the portfolio choice model with constant relative risk aversion utility. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>MacLean, Leonard C.; Foster, Michael E.; Ziemba, William T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fundamental indexation via smoothed cap weights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Chen; Chen, Rong; Bassett, Gilbert W.
If prices of individual stocks are unbiased but noisy approximations to fundamental values, there will be a gap in returns between the standard cap-weighted market portfolio and the one based on fundamentals. The discrepancy occurs because, relative to fundamentals, cap-weights are too large (small) for stocks with positive (negative) deviations from fundamental values. It follows that the usual cap-weighted portfolio will underperform relative to the fundamental-based portfolio as long as prices revert to fundamental values. This has led Arnott et al. to propose new market indices based on a firm's fundamental size as measured by its revenues, number of employees, and so on. In this paper we follow the same principle but propose to estimate fundamental weights using a smoothed average of standard cap-weights. Since the putative excess returns of a fundamentals-weighted portfolio requires reversion to fundamental values, and because fundamental values are likely to change slowly, we can estimate current fundamentals by smoothing the time series of a stock's noisy prices. The determination of fundamental size in terms of accounting data is thereby replaced by a simple estimate based on price history. We derive expressions for expected returns of the market capitalization-based and fundamentals-based portfolios under various assumptions about (i) the random deviations from fundamental values and (ii) the change in fundamentals over time. We present empirical comparisons between portfolios and find the returns of the fundamentals-based portfolios exceed the standard indices by an amount comparable to the prior estimates that used accounting data to determine size. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Chen; Chen, Rong; Bassett, Gilbert W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spot and derivative pricing in the EEX power market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bierbrauer, Michael; Menn, Christian; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Truck, Stefan
Using spot and futures price data from the German EEX Power market, we test the adequacy of various one-factor and two-factor models for electricity spot prices. The models are compared along two different dimensions: (1) We assess their ability to explain the major data characteristics and (2) the forecasting accuracy for expected future spot prices is analyzed. We find that the regime-switching models clearly outperform its competitors in almost all respects. The best results are obtained using a two-regime model with a Gaussian distribution in the spike regime. Furthermore, for short and medium-term periods our results underpin the frequently stated hypothesis that electricity futures quotes are consistently greater than the expected future spot, a situation which is denoted as contango. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bierbrauer, Michael; Menn, Christian; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Truck, Stefan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing exotic options with L-stable Pade schemes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khaliq, A. Q. M.; Voss, D. A.; Yousuf, M.
In this paper we develop a strongly stable (L-stable) and highly accurate method for pricing exotic options. The method is based on Pade schemes and also utilizes partial fraction decomposition to address issues regarding accuracy and computational efficiency. Due to non-smooth payoffs, which cause discontinuities in the solution (or its derivatives), standard A-stable methods are prone to produce large and spurious oscillations in the numerical solutions which would mislead to estimating options accurately. The proposed method does not suffer these drawbacks while being easy to implement on concurrent processors. Numerical results are presented for digital options, butterfly spread and barrier options in one and two assets. In addition, the methods are tested on the Heston stochastic volatility model. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khaliq, A. Q. M.; Voss, D. A.; Yousuf, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A numerical method to price exotic path-dependent options on an underlying described by the Heston stochastic volatility model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ballestra, Luca Vincenzo; Pacelli, Graziella; Zirilli, Francesco
We consider the problem of pricing European exotic path-dependent derivatives on an underlying described by the Heston stochastic volatility model. Lipton has found a closed form integral representation of the joint transition probability density function of underlying price and variance in the Heston model. We give a convenient numerical approximation of this formula and we use the obtained approximated transition probability density function to price discrete path-dependent options as discounted expectations. The expected value of the payoff is calculated evaluating an integral with the Monte Carlo method using a variance reduction technique based on a suitable approximation of the transition probability density function of the Heston model. As a test case, we evaluate the price of a discrete arithmetic average Asian option, when the average over n = 12 prices is considered, that is when the integral to evaluate is a 2n = 24 dimensional integral. We show that the method proposed is computationally efficient and gives accurate results. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ballestra, Luca Vincenzo; Pacelli, Graziella; Zirilli, Francesco</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discrete hedging of American-type options using local risk minimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coleman, Thomas F.; Levchenkov, Dmitriy; Li, Yuying
Local risk minimization and total risk minimization discrete hedging have been extensively studied for European options [e.g., Schweizer, M., 1995. Variance-optimal hedging in discrete time. Mathematics of Operation Research 20, 1-32; Schweizer, M., 2001. A guided tour through quadratic hedging approaches. In: Jouini, E., Cvitanic, J., Musiela, M., Option pricing, interest rates and risk management, Cambridge University Press, pp. 538-574]. In practice, hedging of options with American features is more relevant. For example, equity linked variable annuities provide surrender benefits which are essentially embedded American options. In this paper we generalize both quadratic and piecewise linear local risk minimization hedging frameworks to American options. We illustrate that local risk minimization methods outperform delta hedging when the market is highly incomplete. In addition, compared to European options, distributions of the hedging costs are typically more skewed and heavy-tailed. Moreover, in contrast to quadratic local risk minimization, piecewise linear risk minimization hedging strategies can be significantly different, resulting in larger probabilities of small costs but also larger extreme cost. (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Coleman, Thomas F.; Levchenkov, Dmitriy; Li, Yuying</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditions on option prices for absence of arbitrage and exact calibration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cousot, Laurent
Under the assumption of absence of arbitrage, European option quotes on a given asset must satisfy well-known inequalities, which have been described in the landmark paper of Merton [Merton, R., 1973. Theory of rational option pricing. Bell Journal of Economics and Management Science 4 (1), 141-183]. If we further assume that there is no interest rate volatility and that the underlying asset continuously pays deterministic dividends, cross-maturity inequalities must also be satisfied by the bid and ask option prices. In this paper, we show that there exists an arbitrage-free model, which is consistent with the option quotes, if these inequalities are satisfied. One implication is that all static arbitrage strategies are linear combinations, with positive weights, of those described here. We also characterize admissible default probabilities for models which are consistent with given option quotes. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cousot, Laurent</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation of synthetic CDOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iscoe, Ian; Kreinin, Alexander
In this paper, we consider the valuation of a synthetic collateralized debt obligation (CDO), a pool of underlying credit risky securities, "partitioned" into several tranches, each of which absorbs losses in accordance with its size and seniority. We derive a closed-form solution for credit spreads of the tranches of homogeneous pools and find an approximation for the credit spreads of inhomogeneous pools. The method leads to an accurate estimation of the credit spreads of synthetic CDOs and can be used in risk management applications. Crown Copyright (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Iscoe, Ian; Kreinin, Alexander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A dynamic model of active portfolio management with benchmark orientation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhao, Yonggan
d This paper studies optimal dynamic portfolios for investors concerned with the performance of their portfolios relative to a benchmark. Assuming that asset returns follow a multi-linear factor model similar to the structure of Ross (1976) [Ross, S., 1976. The arbitrage theory of the capital asset pricing model. Journal of Economic Theory, 13, 342-360] and that portfolio managers adopt a mean tracking error analysis similar to that of Roll (1992) [Roll, R., 1992. A mean/variance analysis of tracking error: Journal of Portfolio Management, 18, 13-22], we develop a dynamic model of active portfolio management maximizing risk adjusted excess return over a selected benchmark. Unlike the case of constant proportional portfolios for standard utility maximization, our optimal portfolio policy is state dependent, being a function of time to investment horizon, the return on the benchmark portfolio, and the return on the investment portfolio. We define a dynamic performance measure which relates portfolio's return to its risk sensitivity. Abnormal returns at each point in time are quantified as the difference between the realized and the model-fitted returns. Risk sensitivity is estimated through a dynamic matching that minimizes the total fitted error of portfolio returns. For illustration, we analyze eight representative mutual funds in the U.S. market and show how this model can be used in practice. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhao, Yonggan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalized DEA model of fundamental analysis and its application to portfolio optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edirisinghe, N. C. P.; Zhang, X.
Fundamental analysis is used in asset selection for equity portfolio management. In this paper, a generalized data envelopment analysis (DEA) model is developed to analyze a firm's financial statements over time in order to determine a relative financial strength indicator (RFSI) that is predictive of firm's stock price returns. RFSI is based on maximizing the correlation between the DEA-based score of financial strength and the stock market performance. This maximization involves a difficult binary nonlinear program that requires iterative re-configuration of parameters of financial statements as inputs and outputs. We utilize a two-step heuristic algorithm that combines random sampling and local search optimization. The proposed approach is tested with 230 firms from various US technology-industries to determine optimized RFSI indicators for stock selection. Then, those selected stocks are used within portfolio optimization models to demonstrate the usefulness of the scheme for portfolio risk management. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Edirisinghe, N. C. P.; Zhang, X.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives and risk taking in hedge funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kouwenberg, Roy; Ziemba, William T.
We study how incentive fees and manager's own investment in the fund affect the investment strategy of hedge fund managers. We find that loss averse managers increase the risk of the fund's investment strategy with higher incentive fees. However, risk taking is greatly reduced if a substantial amount of the manager's own money (at least 30%) is in the fund. Using the Zurich hedge fund universe, we test the relation between risk taking and incentive fees empirically. Hedge funds with incentive fees have significantly lower mean returns (net of fees), while downside risk is positively related to the incentive fee level. Fund of funds charging large incentive fees achieve relatively high mean returns, but with significantly higher risk as well. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kouwenberg, Roy; Ziemba, William T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A model for tax advantages of portfolios with many assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Birge, John R.; Yang, Song
Taxable portfolios present challenges for optimization models with even a limited number of assets. Holding many assets, however, has a distinct tax advantage over holding few assets. In this paper, we develop a model that takes an extreme view of a portfolio as a continuum of assets to gain the broadest possible advantage from holding many assets. We find the optimal strategy for trading in this portfolio in the absence of transaction costs and develop bounding approximations on the optimal value. We compare the results in a simulation study to a portfolio consisting only of a market index and show that the multi-asset portfolio's tax advantage can lead either to significant consumption or bequest increases. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Birge, John R.; Yang, Song</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium with investors using a diversity of deviation measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rockafellar, R. Tyrrell; Uryasev, Stan; Zabarankin, M.
It has been argued that investors who optimize their portfolios with attention paid only to mean and standard deviation will all end up choosing some multiple of a certain master fund portfolio. Justification for the capital asset pricing model of classical portfolio theory, which relates individual assets to such a master fund, has come from this direction in particular. Attempts have been made to provide solid mathematical support by showing that the imputed behavior of investors is a consequence of price equilibrium in a market in which assets are traded subject to budget constraints, and optimization is carried out with respect to utility functions that depend only on mean and standard deviation. In recent years, reliance on standard deviation has come under increasing criticism because of inconsistencies in its effect on portfolio preferences. One response has been to introduce generalized measures of deviation which lead to alternative master funds. The market implications of such extensions of theory have hitherto been unclear, but in this paper the existence of equilibrium is established in circumstances where nonstandard deviations are admitted. Equilibrium is guaranteed even when different investors use different measures of deviation and thereby end up with portfolios scaled from different master funds. Whether they employ the same measure or not, they may impose caps on deviation, which likewise may be different. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rockafellar, R. Tyrrell; Uryasev, Stan; Zabarankin, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special issue - Risk management and quantitative approaches in finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>AitSahlia, Farid
nan</description><author>AitSahlia, Farid</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interlinking securities settlement systems: A strategic commitment?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kauko, Karlo
Central securities depositories (CSDs) in Europe have opened mutual links, but most of them are seldom used. Why are idle links established? By allowing a foreign CSD to offer services through the link, the domestic CSD invites competition. By inviting competition the domestic CSD can commit itself not to charge monopoly fees for secondary market services. This enables it to charge higher fees for securities issuance in the primary market. It is shown that commitment via an idle link can be optimal for a profit maximising CSD. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kauko, Karlo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accounting for distress in bank mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koetter, M.; Bos, J. W. B.; Heid, F.; Kolari, J. W.; Kool, C. J. M.; Porath, D.
Most bank merger studies do not control for hidden bailouts, which may lead to biased results. In this study we employ a unique data set of approximately 1000 mergers to analyze the determinants of bank mergers. We use undisclosed information on banks' regulatory intervention history to distinguish between distressed and non-distressed mergers. Among merging banks, we find that improving financial profiles lower the likelihood of distressed mergers more than the likelihood of nondistressed mergers. The likelihood to acquire a bank is also reduced but less than the probability to be acquired. Both distressed and non-distressed mergers have worse CAMEL profiles than non-merging banks. Hence, non-distressed mergers may be motivated by the desire to forestall serious future financial distress and prevent regulatory intervention. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koetter, M.; Bos, J. W. B.; Heid, F.; Kolari, J. W.; Kool, C. J. M.; Porath, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implied volatility and future portfolio returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Prithviraj S.; Doran, James S.; Peterson, David R.
Prior studies find that the OBOE volatility index (VIX) predicts returns on stock market indices, suggesting implied volatilities measured by VIX are a risk factor affecting security returns or an indicator of market inefficiency. We extend prior work in three important ways. First, we investigate the relationship between future returns and current implied volatility levels and innovations. Second, we examine portfolios sorted on book-to-market equity, size, and beta. Third, we control for the four Fama and French [Fama, E., French, K., 1993. Common risk factors in the returns on stocks and bonds. Journal of Financial Economics 33, 3-56.] and Carhart [Carhart, M., 1997. On persistence in mutual fund performance. Journal of Finance, 52, 57-82.] factors. We find that VIX-related variables have strong predictive ability. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Banerjee, Prithviraj S.; Doran, James S.; Peterson, David R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does sovereign debt ratings news spill over to international stock markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Gama, Paulo M.
The evidence here indicates that sovereign debt rating and credit outlook changes of one country have an asymmetric and economically significant effect on the stock market returns of other countries over 1989-2003. There is a negative reaction of 51 basis points (two-day return spread vis-a-vis the US) to a credit ratings downgrade of one notch in a common information spillover around the world. Upgrades, however, have no significant impact on return spreads of countries abroad. Closeness (e.g., geographic proximity) and emerging market status amplify the effect of a spillover. Downgrade spillover effects at the industry level are more pronounced in traded goods and small industries. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Gama, Paulo M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are current syndicated loan alliances related to past alliances?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Champagne, Claudia; Kryzanowski, Lawrence
The odds of a current syndicate relationship between two lenders depend upon their previous alliances. The odds are significantly higher [lower] and strongest for a current lead-participant relationship with a continuation [reversal] of their previous roles. To illustrate, the odds are nearly four times higher when two lenders have allied in the previous 5 years. The strength of lead-participant syndicate relationships between two lenders with same-ordered roles is most sensitive to the lead bank's reputation and informationally opaque participants tend to have stronger relationships with lead banks. Lenders exhibit home bias in their syndicate alliances since ongoing relationships are stronger with domestic counterparts. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Champagne, Claudia; Kryzanowski, Lawrence</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Yield-factor volatility models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perignon, Christophe; Smith, Daniel R.
The term structure of interest rates is often summarized using a handful of yield factors that capture shifts in the shape of the yield curve. In this paper, we develop a comprehensive model for volatility dynamics in the level, slope, and curvature of the yield curve that simultaneously includes level and LARCH effects along with regime shifts. We show that the level of the short rate is useful in modeling the volatility of the three yield factors and that there are significant LARCH effects present even after including a level effect. Further, we find that allowing for regime shifts in the factor volatilities dramatically improves the model's fit and strengthens the level effect. We also show that a regime-switching model with level and LARCH effects provides the best out-of-sample forecasting performance of yield volatility. We argue that the auxiliary models often used to estimate term structure models with simulation-based estimation techniques should be consistent with the main features of the yield curve that are identified by our model. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Perignon, Christophe; Smith, Daniel R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer expectations and short-horizon return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalotay, Egon; Gray, Philip; Sin, Samantha
Lettau and Ludvigson [Lettau, M., Ludvigson, S, 2001. Consumption, aggregate wealth and expected stock returns. Journal of Finance 56, 815-849] argue that fluctuations from the equilibrium ratio of consumption to wealth (My) reflect changing expectations of asset returns and document significant short-horizon predictability based on My. This paper further explores the role of consumer expectations in modeling time variation of expected equity returns by considering two measures of consumer expectations: (i) consumer behavior as reflected in My, and (ii) a more-direct measure of expectations captured by the Index of Consumer Sentiment (ICS). We report strong regression-based evidence of return predictability based on My, which remains evident even after accounting for various sources of estimation risk. However, the regression-based evidence of predictability does not necessarily imply that shifts in aggregate consumption and the components of aggregate wealth give rise to economically significant investment signals. The survey-based measure of expectations (ICS) is shown to complement the behavioral measure (cay) but has no apparent stand-alone predictive value in forecasting equity returns. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kalotay, Egon; Gray, Philip; Sin, Samantha</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Partial acquisitions, the acquisition probability hypothesis, and the abnormal returns to partial targets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhigbe, Aigbe; Martin, Anna D.; Whyte, Ann Marie
The acquisition of a partial stake in a target firm has been positively linked to the likelihood that the target will be involved in a follow on full acquisition involving either the original bidder or a third party bidder. Existing studies provide only suggestive evidence of this linkage by comparing the abnormal returns to partial targets that are ultimately acquired to those that are not. Using a sample of partial acquisitions, we identify characteristics that impact the probability of a full acquisition and provide a tangible link between partial target gains and the ex ante probability of acquisition. Partial targets experience positive announcement effects, and the gains are greater for subsequently acquired targets. Partial bids initiated by corporate bidders are more likely to result in a full acquisition, and the size of the acquired stake and the level of institutional ownership are positively linked to the probability of acquisition. Further, the partial target gains are positively linked to the ex ante probability of acquisition even after controlling for any increased monitoring and discipline that the partial bidder is expected to impose. The findings are robust across various time horizons and model specifications. (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Akhigbe, Aigbe; Martin, Anna D.; Whyte, Ann Marie</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cost efficiency in the European securities settlement and depository industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Cayseele, Patrick; Wuyts, Christophe
We examine whether the European settlement and custody institutions operate in an efficient way. To do this, we start from an analytically founded discussion regarding the activities performed by the operators in this sector. Based on the insights obtained, we estimate both a translog cost function and a constant elasticity of substitution-quadratic cost function. From the results obtained, there clearly are economies of scale in this industry. Moreover, also economies of scope between the activities performed are present. These findings imply that probably further consolidation is ahead, and that separating certain activities from others can only be done at a cost in terms of efficiency. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Van Cayseele, Patrick; Wuyts, Christophe</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Settling for efficiency - A framework for the European securities transaction industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Serifsoy, Baris; Weiss, Marco
Despite a lot of restructuring and many innovations in recent years, the securities transaction industry in the European Union is still a highly inefficient and inconsistently configured system for cross-border transactions. This paper analyzes the functions performed, the institutions involved and the parameters concerned that shape market and ownership structure in the industry. Of particular interest are microeconomic incentives of the main players that can be in contradiction to social welfare. We develop a framework and analyze three consistent systems for the securities transaction industry in the EU that offer superior efficiency than the current, inefficient arrangement. Some policy advice is given to select the `best' system for the Single European Financial Market. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Serifsoy, Baris; Weiss, Marco</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Guess what: It's the settlements! Vertical integration as a barrier to efficient exchange consolidation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koeppl, Thorsten V.; Monnet, Cyril
Exchanges and other trading platforms are often vertically integrated to carry out trading and settlement as one operation. We show that these vertical silos can prevent the full realization of efficiency gains from horizontal consolidation of trading and settlement platforms. When costs of settlement are private information, a merger of vertical silos cannot be designed to always ensure efficient trading and settlement after the merger. We also show, however, that efficiency can be guaranteed either by merging the trading platforms and delegating the operation of settlement platforms to independent agents or by forcing competition across vertical silos through cross-listings. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koeppl, Thorsten V.; Monnet, Cyril</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock exchange business models and their operative performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Serifsoy, Baris
In recent years stock exchanges have been increasingly diversifying their operations into related business areas such as derivatives trading, post-trading services and software sales. This trend can be observed most notably among profit-oriented trading venues. While the pursuit for diversification is likely to be driven by the attractiveness of these investment opportunities, it is yet an open question whether certain integration activities are also efficient, both from a social welfare and from the exchanges' perspective. Academic contributions so far analyzed different business models primarily from the former perspective, whereas there is only little literature considering their impact on the exchange itself. By employing a panel data set of 28 stock exchanges for the years 1999-2003, we seek to shed light on this topic by comparing the technical efficiency and factor productivity of exchanges with different business models. Our findings suggest that exchanges that diversify into related activities are mostly less efficient than exchanges that remain focused on the cash market. In particular, we find no evidence that vertically integrated exchanges are more efficient. However, they seem to possess a substantially stronger factor productivity growth than other business models. We presume that integration activity comes at the cost of increased operational complexity which outweigh potential synergies between related activities and therefore leads to technical inefficiencies. Our findings contribute to the ongoing discussion about the drawbacks and merits of vertical integration. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Serifsoy, Baris</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The industrial organization of post-trade clearing and settlement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milne, Alistair
The introduction to this special issue reviews the literature on the industrial organization of securities market clearing and settlement, covering institutional, theoretical, and empirical contributions, including both papers in this special issue and previous studies. Clearing and settlement is an important but under-researched network industry. Recent theoretical research has characterized the network externalities in clearing and settlement and explored the economic efficiency of various alternative industrial structures. Initial empirical research has identified substantial economies of both scale and scope and important interactions with trading platforms. More research is needed to elaborate these theoretical insights and improve our understanding of the economics of this major industry. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Milne, Alistair</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Elements of the Euro area - Integrating financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gereben, Aron
nan</description><author>Gereben, Aron</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodities and commodity derivatives, modeling and pricing for agriculturals, metals and energy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marossy, Zita
nan</description><author>Marossy, Zita</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign exchange markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Naszodi, Anna
nan</description><author>Naszodi, Anna</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cyclical effects of the Basel II capital requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heid, Frank
Capital requirements play a key role in the supervision and regulation of banks. The Basel Committee on Banking Supervision is in the process of changing the current framework by introducing risk sensitive capital charges. Some fear that this will unduly increase the volatility of regulatory capital. Furthermore, by limiting the banks' ability to lend, capital requirements may exacerbate an economic downturn. The paper examines the problem of capital-induced lending cycles and. their pro-cyclical effect on the macroeconomy in greater detail. It finds that the capital buffer that banks hold on top of the required minimum capital plays a crucial role in mitigating the impact of the volatility of capital requirements. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heid, Frank</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking market conditions and deposit interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosen, Richard J.
This paper shows that the impact of market structure on bank deposit interest rates is complex. Both market size structure and multimarket bank presence have independent effects on rates. There is evidence that mid-size banks were more aggressive competitors than other banks, but that the effect of market structure on deposit rates has evolved over time, with mega-banks recently becoming more aggressive competitors. This may be related to the growth of mega-banks in many markets. These findings have implications for existing theories of deposit pricing and, by extension, antitrust policy in banking. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rosen, Richard J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy probability changes and the differential informativeness of bond upgrades and downgrades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Yongtae; Nabar, Sandeep
Prior studies have found that stock returns around announcements of bond upgrades are insignificant, but that stock prices respond negatively to announcements of bond downgrades. This asymmetric stock market reaction suggests either that bond downgrades are timelier than upgrades, or that voluntary disclosures by managers preempt upgrades but not downgrades. This study investigates these conjectures by examining changes in firms' probabilities of bankruptcy (assessed using bankruptcy prediction models) and voluntary disclosure activity around rating change announcements. The results indicate that the assessed probability of bankruptcy decreases before bond upgrades, but not after. By contrast, the assessed probability of bankruptcy increases both before and after bond downgrades. We also find that controlling for potential wealth-transfer related rating actions, which can impact stock returns differently, does not alter our results. Tests of press releases and earnings forecasts issued by firms suggest that the differential informativeness of upgrades and downgrades is not caused by differences in pre-rating change voluntary disclosures by upgraded and downgraded firms. The results support the hypothesis that downgrades are timelier than upgrades. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Yongtae; Nabar, Sandeep</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Daily mutual fund flows and redemption policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greene, Jason T.; Hodges, Charles W.; Rakowski, David A.
We examine how redemption policies affect daily fund flows in open-end mutual funds. Since short-term trading of fund shares, as manifested in daily fund flows, can have an adverse impact on returns to the fund's shareholders, mutual funds might find it desirable to discourage short-term trading through the use of redemption fees. However, if daily fund flows are due to fund shareholders legitimate liquidity demands, the redemption fee would have little effect on daily fund flows and possibly adversely affect fund shareholders by imposing a liquidity cost on them. We find that the likelihood of a fund charging a redemption fee is largely a function of its overall fee structure. We also use a sample of funds that imposed redemption fees to examine whether the distribution of daily fund flows changes after the initiation of the redemption fee. We find that the redemption fee is an effective tool in controlling the volatility of fund flows. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Greene, Jason T.; Hodges, Charles W.; Rakowski, David A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade classification algorithms for electronic communications network trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakrabarty, Bidisha; Li, Bingguang; Nguyen, Vanthuan; Van Ness, Robert A.
Ellis et al. [Ellis, K., Michaely, R., O'Hara, M., 2000. The accuracy of trade classification rules: Evidence from Nasdaq. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 35 (4), 529-551] find that trade classification rules have limited success in classifying trades which execute inside the quotes. We reconfirm this result and propose an alternative algorithm to improve the classification accuracy for trades inside the quotes. This alternative algorithm improves the overall success rate for classifying trades, especially for trades that occur inside the quotes. Additionally, we show that the Lee and Ready [Lee, C., Ready, M., 1991. Inferring trade direction from intraday data. Journal of Finance 46, 733-747] and Ellis et al. (2000) trade classification algorithms provide biased estimates of the actual effective spreads and price impacts, while our algorithm provides statistically unbiased estimates of actual effective spreads and price impacts. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chakrabarty, Bidisha; Li, Bingguang; Nguyen, Vanthuan; Van Ness, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory harmonization and the development of private equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, Douglas; Johan, Sofia
This paper introduces a new dataset from 100 Dutch institutional investors' domestic and international asset private equity allocations. The data indicate that the perceived comparative dearth of regulations of private equity funds impedes institutional investor participation in private equity funds, particularly in relation to the lack of transparency. The data further indicate that the perceived importance of regulatory harmonization of institutional investors has increased Dutch institutional investor allocations to domestic and international private equity funds. The Financieel Toetsingskader (regulation of portfolio management standards such as matching of assets and liabilities) has had the most pronounced and robust effect, followed by Basel II (regulation of risk management and disclosure standards) and the International Financial Reporting Standards (regulation of reporting standards and transparency). (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cumming, Douglas; Johan, Sofia</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing nondiversifiable credit risk in the corporate Eurobond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abaffy, J.; Bertocchi, M.; Dupacova, J.; Moriggia, V.; Consigli, G.
The price of defaultable or credit-risky bonds differs from the equivalent maturity price of a risk-free bond for a well identified number of factors: the positive probability of default prior to the bond maturity, the estimated loss given default, that depends on the adopted assumption on the recovery rate for that class, see Duffie and Singleton [Duffie, D., Singleton, K.J., 1999. Modeling term structures of defaultable bonds. Rev. Financ. Stud. 12, 687-720] for several models of recovery rates, the probability that the bond issuer will migrate from the current rating class to a lower class. In this study we apply two well-known modelling approaches, due to Jarrow et al. [Jarrow, R.A., Lando, D., Turnbull, S.M., 1997. A Markov model for the term structure of credit risk spreads. Rev. Financ. Stud. 10, 481-523] and Schonbucher [Schonbucher, P.J., 2002. A tree implementation of a credit spread model for credit. J. Comput. Finance 6 (2), 175-196] to price specifically two risk sources affecting the evolution of bond prices over time: the risk to move from a current risk class to a different one over the bond residual life, and the risk associated with comovements of the credit spread curves and the risk-free term structure. The former is referred to as transition risk, the latter as cor-relation risk. The analysis is conducted extending appropriately to a multinomial setting the classical discrete binomial model of the term structure formulated by Black et al. [Black, F., Derman, E., Toy, W., 1990. A one-factor model of interest rates and its application to treasury bond options. Financ. Analysts J. (January/February), 33-39], applied previously by Abaffy et al. [Abaffy, J., Bertocchi, M., Dupacova, J., Moriggia, V., 2000. On generating scenarios for bond portfolios. Bull. Czech Econom. Soc. 11, 3-27, and references ibidem] and many other authors in literature. The generalised model, with transition [by Jarrow et al.] and correlation risk [by Schonbucher], is applied to a large dataset of corporate spreads to evaluate the sensitivity of the isolated risk sources on the fair price of risky bonds traded in the Eurobond market. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abaffy, J.; Bertocchi, M.; Dupacova, J.; Moriggia, V.; Consigli, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Journal of banking and finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaniovski, Y.; Murgia, M.; Pflug, G.
nan</description><author>Kaniovski, Y.; Murgia, M.; Pflug, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility clustering, leverage effects, and jump dynamics in the US and emerging Asian equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daal, Elton; Naka, Atsuyuki; Yu, Jung-Suk
This paper proposes asymmetric GARCH-Jump models that synthesize autoregressive jump intensities and volatility feedback in the jump component. Our results indicate that these models provide a better fit for the dynamics of the equity returns in the US and emerging Asian markets, irrespective whether the volatility feedback is generated through a common GARCH multiplier or a separate measure of volatility in the jump intensity function. We also find that they can capture several distinguishing features of the return dynamics in emerging markets, such as, more volatility persistence, less leverage effects, fatter tails, and greater contribution and variability of the jump component. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Daal, Elton; Naka, Atsuyuki; Yu, Jung-Suk</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The eurosystem money market auctions: A banking perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Craig, Ben; Fecht, Falko
This paper analyzes the individual bidding behavior of German banks in the money market auctions conducted by the ECB from the beginning of 2000:IIIQ to the end of 2001:IQ. Our approach takes a variety of characteristics of the individual banks into account, particularly variables that capture the different use of liquidity and the different attitude towards liquidity risk of the individual banks. It turns out that these characteristics are reflected in banks' bidding behavior. Thus, our study contributes to a deeper understanding of the way liquidity risk is managed in the banking sector. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Craig, Ben; Fecht, Falko</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Centralised order books versus hybrid order books: A paired comparison of trading costs on NSC (Euronext Paris) and SETS (London Stock Exchange)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gajewski, Jean-Francois; Gresse, Carole
This article compares the cost of trading large capitalisation equities on the hybrid order-driven segment of the London Stock Exchange and the centralised electronic order book of Euronext. Using samples of stocks matched according to economic sector, free float capitalisation, and trading volume, our study shows that transaction costs are lower on the centralised order book than on the hybrid order book. The presence of dealers outside the electronic order book favours the frequency of large trades, but is associated with higher execution costs for all other trades and higher adverse selection and inventory costs inside the order book. (c) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Gajewski, Jean-Francois; Gresse, Carole</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does post-crisis restructuring decrease the availability of banking services? The case of Turkey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Damar, H. Evren
This study examines the relationship between post-crisis bank consolidation and the number of bank branches in Turkey. Using a unique data set, the analysis addresses several issues related to the impact of market characteristics on branching behavior. The findings suggest that sales of failed institutions by the central authority lead to branch closures in small and uncompetitive markets where the buyer does not have a prior presence. Contrary to popular belief, mergers between healthy institutions do not always cause a decrease in the number of branches; rather, they are shown to increase the availability of banking services in concentrated markets. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Damar, H. Evren</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Japan's banking crisis: An event-study perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miyajima, Hideaki; Yafeh, Yishay
We calculate abnormal stock returns for Japanese non-financial companies around major events associated with the banking crisis (1995-2000), and find that not all companies were equally sensitive to the malaise of the banking sector: the most affected were small, leveraged, low-tech companies with low credit ratings and low market to book ratios. This is consistent with "credit crunch" theories (companies with limited access to financial markets are sensitive to changes in bank lending) and with claims that innovation is rarely financed by bank debt. We do not find much evidence on the alleged misallocation of loans to support ailing bank clients. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Miyajima, Hideaki; Yafeh, Yishay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Day-of-the-week effect in the Taiwan foreign exchange market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ke, Mei-Chu; Chiang, Yi-Chein; Liao, Tung Liang
This study uses stochastic dominance with and without risk-free assets to examine whether trading days can affect patterns of the day-of-the-week effect in the Taiwan foreign exchange market. Our results generally indicate that higher returns appear on the first three days of the week across different trading-day regimes in the Taiwan foreign exchange market, confirming day-of-the-week effect. Allocating part of investors' assets in risk-free assets is useful in distinguishing returns among weekdays for all currencies. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ke, Mei-Chu; Chiang, Yi-Chein; Liao, Tung Liang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are there windows of opportunity for convertible debt issuance? Evidence for Western Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dutordoir, Marie; Van de Gucht, Linda
This paper hypothesizes that hot convertible debt windows represent periods with lower convertible debt-related financing costs. Supporting this premise, we find that the stock price impact of Western European convertible debt announcements is significantly less negative during hot convertible debt windows. Importantly, this result holds while controlling for equity and straight debt issuance volumes and for macroeconomic conditions. In addition, stockholders are less sensitive to issuer-and issue-specific financing costs during hot convertible debt markets. Overall, these findings indicate that hot convertible debt markets represent windows of opportunity for convertible debt issuance. Firms with high idiosyncratic financing costs act accordingly by timing their convertible debt offering during a hot market. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dutordoir, Marie; Van de Gucht, Linda</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on the price- and cost structure of retail payment services in the Swedish banking sector 2002</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gulbourg, Gabriela; Segendorff, Bjorn
We estimate private costs in the Swedish banking sector for the production of payment services and investigate to what extent the price structure reflects the estimated cost structure. We find that (i) banks tend to use two-part tariffs but (ii) variable costs are poorly reflected in transaction fees towards both consumers and corporate customers. (iii) There exist large cross subsidies between different payment services, foremost from acquiring card payments to cash distribution to the public, while payment services as a whole are not subsidized. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gulbourg, Gabriela; Segendorff, Bjorn</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund flows and investor returns: An empirical examination of fund investor timing ability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friesen, Geoffrey C.; Sapp, Travis R. A.
We examine the timing ability of mutual fund investors using cash flow data at the individual fund level. Over 1991-2004 equity fund investor timing decisions reduce fund investor average returns by 1.56% annually. Underperformance due to poor timing is greater in load funds and funds with relatively large risk-adjusted returns. In particular, the magnitude of investor underperformance due to poor timing largely offsets the risk-adjusted alpha gains offered by good-performing funds. Investors in both actively managed funds and index funds exhibit poor investment timing. We demonstrate that our empirical results are consistent with investor return-chasing behavior. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Friesen, Geoffrey C.; Sapp, Travis R. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quote-based competition, market share, and execution quality in NASDAQ-listed securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Kee H.; Chuwonganant, Chairat
We show that competitive quotes help increase dealer market share on NASDAQ, despite the fact that a large proportion of order flow is preferenced. We find that decimal pricing and the introduction of new trading platforms such as SuperSOES and SuperMontage have significantly changed the effect of quote aggressiveness on dealer market share. In particular, decimal pricing reduces (increases) the price (size) elasticity, SuperSOES increases the size elasticity, and SuperMontage increases both the size and price elasticity of dealer market share. We also show that market centers provide greater price improvements and faster executions when they post competitive quotes. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, Kee H.; Chuwonganant, Chairat</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privatization as an agency problem: Auctions versus private negotiations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fluck, Zsuzsanna; John, Kose; Ravid, S. Abraham
This paper investigates the design of privatization mechanisms in emerging market economies characterized by political constraints that limit the set of viable privatization options. Our objective is to explain the striking diversity of mechanisms observed in practice and the frequent use of an apparently sub-optimal privatization mechanism: private negotiations. We develop a simple model in which privatization is to be carried out by a government agent, who plays favorites among bidders but is potentially disciplined by losing his private benefits of staying in office. If the political environment is such that the privatization agent himself aims at raising the fair value for the company, then privatization auctions and private negotiations are equally successful in raising public revenues. If, however, political considerations distort the agent's incentives, it may be that a seemingly transparent auction will raise less revenue, than opaque private negotiations. We also show that information disclosure laws may have negative welfare implications: they may help the privatization agent to collude with some of the bidders to the disadvantage of non-colluding bidders. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fluck, Zsuzsanna; John, Kose; Ravid, S. Abraham</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday volume and volatility relations with and without public news</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Darrat, Ali F.; Zhong, Maosen; Cheng, Louis T. W.
This paper reexamines the dynamic relation between intraday trading volume and return volatility of large and small NYSE stocks in two partitioned samples, with and without identifiable public news. We argue that the sequential information arrival hypothesis (SIAH) can be tested only in periods containing public news. After partitioning the sample into periods with and without public news, we find bi-directional Granger-causality between volume and volatility in the presence of public information as hypothesized by the SIAH. Our analysis further suggests that return volatility is higher in the periods with public news, while trading volume is significantly higher in the no-news period; perhaps owing to the importance of private information for trading stocks. Using the sample without public news, we find evidence that volume Granger-causes volatility without feedback. These results are broadly consistent with behavioral models like the overconfidence and biased self-attribution model of [Daniel, K., Hirshleifer, D., Subrahmanyam, A., 1998. Investor psychology and security market under- and over-reactions. Journal of Finance 53, 1839-1885]. It appears that overconfident investors overrate the precision of their private news signals and therefore trade too aggressively in the absence of public news; when public news arrives, investors' biased self-attribution triggers excessive return volatility. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Darrat, Ali F.; Zhong, Maosen; Cheng, Louis T. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The trading behavior of institutions and individuals in Chinese equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ng, Lilian; Wu, Fei
This paper employs a unique data set to analyze the trading behavior of 4.74 million individual and institutional investors across Mainland China. Results show that groups of individual investors with varying trade values (as proxies for wealth levels) engage in different trading strategies. Chinese institutions are momentum investors, while less wealthy Chinese individual investors at large are contrarian investors. The results also indicate that a small group of wealthiest Chinese individuals tend to behave like institutions when they buy stocks, and behave like less wealthy individuals when they sell. Furthermore, only the trading activities of institutions and of wealthiest individuals can affect future stock volatility, but those of Chinese individual investors at large have no predictive power for future stock returns. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ng, Lilian; Wu, Fei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do managers time the market? Evidence from open-market share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Konan; Ikenberry, David L.; Lee, Inmoo
A contentious debate exists over whether executives possess market timing skills when announcing certain corporate transactions. Pseudo-market timing, however, has recently emerged as an important alternative hypothesis as to why the appearance of timing might be evident when, in fact, none exists. We reconsider this debate in the context of share repurchases. Consistent with prior studies, we also report evidence of abnormal stock performance following buyback announcements. Pseudo-market timing, however, does not appear to be a viable explanation. Our results are more consistent with the notion that managers possess timing ability, at least in the context of share repurchases. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Konan; Ikenberry, David L.; Lee, Inmoo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The happy story of small business financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vos, Ed; Yeh, Andy Jia-Yuh; Carter, Sara; Tagg, Stephen
We examine two data sets, one from the UK (n = 15,750) and one from the US (n = 3239), to show that SME financial behaviour demonstrates substantial financial contentment, or 'happiness'. We find fewer than 10% of the UK firms seek significant growth and only 1.32% of US firms list a shortage of capital other than working capital as a problem. Financial performance indicators (growth, return on assets, profit margin) were not found to be determinants of SME financing activities, as might be expected in a 'rational' risk-return environment. Younger and less educated SME owners more actively use external financing - even though more education reduces the fear of loan denial - while older and more educated ('wiser') SME owners are found to be being less likely to seek or use external financing. The contentment hypothesis for SME financing also extends to high-growth firms in that we show that they participate more in the loan markets than low-growth firms. By way of contrast to the finance gap hypothesis, the contentment hypothesis observes the importance of social networks (connections) [for finance] and confirms the 'connections - happiness' link-age in the literature on happiness while doubting the theoretical suitability of Jensen and Meckling [Jensen, M., Meckling, W., 1976. Theory of the firm: Managerial behavior, agency costs, and ownership structure. Journal of Financial Economics 3, 305-360.] base-case analysis for SMEs. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vos, Ed; Yeh, Andy Jia-Yuh; Carter, Sara; Tagg, Stephen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the choice of performance measure influence the evaluation of hedge funds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eling, Martin; Schuhmacher, Frank
The Sharpe ratio is adequate for evaluating investment funds when the returns of those funds are normally distributed and the investor intends to place all his risky assets into just one investment fund. Hedge fund returns differ significantly from a normal distribution. For this reason, other performance measures for hedge fund returns have been proposed in both the academic and practice-oriented literature. In conducting an empirical study based on return data of 2763 hedge funds, we compare the Sharpe ratio with 12 other performance measures. Despite significant deviations of hedge fund returns from a normal distribution, our comparison of the Sharpe ratio to the other performance measures results in virtually identical rank ordering across hedge funds. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V.. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eling, Martin; Schuhmacher, Frank</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do secondary shares in the IPO process have a negative effect on aftermarket performance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brau, James C.; Li, Mingsheng; Shi, Jing
We revisit and extend the topic of secondary share sales and revisions in IPOs. First we test to determine if secondary share sales constitute a negative signal that is captured in aftermarket performance. We find secondary share sales in general are not correlated with poorer initial or long-run performance, but selling by officers and directors is associated with poorer long-run returns. Second, we examine if secondary share revisions (1) reflect selling shareholders' attempts to conceal private information or (2) are contingent upon whether a firm can reach its goal of raising sufficient capital. We find empirical support for a capital goal, but not for concealment. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brau, James C.; Li, Mingsheng; Shi, Jing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of the disposition of assets in a joint venture</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mantecon, Tomas; Chatfield, Robert E.
The final disposition of assets at the conclusion of joint venture arrangements is important to an understanding of the motivation to pursue a joint venture and the wealth created by these collaborations. A comparison between conventional asset sales and asset sales occurring within a joint venture structure shows that the total wealth created is larger if the assets have been under shared control in a joint venture. Our results support the contention that the establishment of a joint venture creates an opportunity for a relationship-based exchange of information that can serve as a mechanism to transfer assets in the presence of a high degree of asymmetric information. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mantecon, Tomas; Chatfield, Robert E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International asset pricing models and currency risk: Evidence from Finland 1970-2004</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antell, Jan; Vaihekoski, Mika
In this paper we investigate whether global, local and currency risks are priced in the Finnish stock market using conditional international asset pricing models. We take the view of a US investor. The estimation is conducted using a modified version of the multivariate GARCH framework of [De Santis, G., Gerard, B., 1998. How big is the premium for currency risk? Journal of Financial Economics 49, 375-412]. For a sample period from 1970 to 2004, we find the world risk to be time-varying. While local risk is not priced for the USA, the local component is significant and time-varying for Finland. Currency risk is priced in the Finnish market, but is not time-varying using the De Santis and Gerard specification. This suggests that the linear specification for the currency risk may not be adequate for non-free floating currencies. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Antell, Jan; Vaihekoski, Mika</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special section: Global financial services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global financial services and a global single currency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
purpose of this paper is to highlight the evolution of financial institutions in the context of increasingly volatile foreign exchange markets. The paper discusses the importance of the formation of a single currency in the US in the 19th century and the formation of the Euro in the 20th century for reducing volatility in foreign exchange markets that have assisted financial institutions' international business expansion. The paper also considers some of the key assumptions of an optimal currency theorem such as labour mobility and argues that in the 21st century, more comprehensive financial market integration and a single global currency could emerge, provided that capital mobility and hence foreign capital flows continue meeting labour in the host countries for production rather than the other way round. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does market size structure affect competition? The case of small business lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Rosen, Richard J.; Udell, Gregory F.
Market size structure refers to the distribution of shares of different size classes of local market participants, where the sizes are inclusive of assets both within and outside the local market. We apply this new measure of market structure in two empirical analyses of the US banking industry to address concerns regarding the effects of the consolidation in banking. Our quantity analysis of the likelihood that small businesses borrow from large versus small banks and our small business loan price analysis that includes market size structure as well as conventional measures yield very different findings from most of the literature on bank size and small business lending. Our results do not suggest a significant net advantage or disadvantage for large banks in small business lending overall, or in lending to informationally opaque small businesses in particular. We argue that the prior research that excluded market size structure may be misleading and offer some likely explanations of why our results differ. (c) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Rosen, Richard J.; Udell, Gregory F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock returns, dividend yield, and book-to-market ratio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Xiaoquan; Lee, Bong-Soo
A dividend yield model has been widely used in previous research that relates stock market valuations to cash flow fundamentals. Given controversies about using dividends as a proxy for cash flows, a loglinear book-to-market model has recently been proposed. However, these models rely on the assumption that dividend yield and book-to-market ratio are both stationary, and empirical evidence for this is, at best, mixed. We develop a new model, the loglinear cointegration model, that explains future profitability and excess stock returns in terms of a linear combination of log book-to-market ratio and log dividend yield. The loglinear cointegration model performs better than the log dividend yield model and the log book-to-market model in terms of cross-equation restriction tests and forecasting performance comparisons. The superior performance of the loglinear cointegration model suggests that the linear combination may be a better indicator of intrinsic fundamentals than the dividend yield or the book-to-market ratio separately. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jiang, Xiaoquan; Lee, Bong-Soo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relationship between risk and expected return in Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leon, Angel; Nave, Juan M.; Rubio, Gonzalo
We employ MIDAS (mixed data sampling) to study the risk-expected return trade-off in several European stock indices. Using MIDAS, we report that in most indices there is a significant positive relationship between risk and expected return. This strongly contrasts with the result we obtain when we employ both symmetric and asymmetric GARCH models for conditional variance. We also find that asymmetric specifications of the variance process within the MIDAS framework improve the relationship between risk and expected return. As an additional application, we analyze the extent to which European stock markets are integrated, which is a particularly relevant issue, especially following the launch of the Euro in January 1999. Finally, we propose a bivariate MIDAS specification to test the pricing significance of the hedging component within an intertemporal risk-return tradeoff with multiple European market indices. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leon, Angel; Nave, Juan M.; Rubio, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial development, bank discrimination and trade credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ge, Ying; Qiu, Jiaping
Non-state owned firms in China grow tremendously with limited support from banks. This provides a unique setting to test how firms in a country with poorly developed financial institutions fund their prosperous growth opportunities. This paper compares the use of an important non-formal financial channel, trade credit, between state and non-state owned firms in China. We find that, compared to state owned firms, non-state owned firms use more trade credit. We further show that this higher usage is primarily for financing rather than transactional purposes. The results suggest that, in a country with a poorly developed formal financial sector, firms can support their growth through non-formal financial channels that largely rely on implicit contractual relation. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ge, Ying; Qiu, Jiaping</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Amazing discovery: Vincenz Bronzin's option pricing models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zimmermann, Heinz; Hafner, Wolfgang
In 1908, Vinzenz Bronzin, a professor of mathematics at the Accademia di Commercio e Nautica in Trieste, published a booklet in German entitled Theorie der Pramiengeschafte (Theory of Premium Contracts) which is an old type of option contract. Almost like Bachelier's now famous dissertation (1900) [Bachelier, Louis, 1900, 1964. Theorie de la speculation, Annales Scientitiques de F Ecole Normale Superieure, Paris, Ser. 3, 17, pp. 21-88. (English translation in: The random character of stock market prices (Ed. Paul Cootner), MIT-Press (1964), pp. 17-79)], the work seems to have been forgotten shortly after it was published. However, almost every element of modern option pricing can be found in Bronzin's book. In particular, he uses the normal distribution to derive a pricing equation which comes surprisingly close to the Black-Scholes-Merton formula. (c) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Zimmermann, Heinz; Hafner, Wolfgang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate valuation around the world: The effects of governance, growth, and openness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chua, Choong Tze; Eun, Cheol S.; Lai, Sandy
The purpose of this paper is to provide a comprehensive analysis of corporate valuation around the world. Specifically, we (i) document and compare corporate valuation around the world, and (ii) identify the key factors that drive cross-country differences in valuation. In doing so, we utilize the country-level Tobin's q (CTQ), computed as the ratio of the aggregate market value to book value of all assets held by all public firms domiciled in a country, which amounts to the Tobin's q for the 'market portfolio' of the country. The key findings of the paper are: First, CTQ varies greatly across countries, ranging from 0.73 for Venezuela to 2.11 for Finland, with the international mean of 1.30 during our sample period 1999-2004. Despite the steady integration of the world economy in recent years, corporate valuation remains starkly different across countries. Second, apart from the effect of corporate governance, cross-country differences in corporate valuation are significantly driven by the growth options of countries represented by the R&amp;D intensities, capital expenditures, and GDP growth. In addition, the degree of capital market openness has a significant, independent effect on valuation. Third, our regression analyses show that CTQ varies directly with shareholder rights, enforcement of insider trading laws, GDP growth, R&amp;D intensity, and the degree of capital market openness. The key findings remain robust to the inclusion of inflation and industry effects. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chua, Choong Tze; Eun, Cheol S.; Lai, Sandy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are embedded calls valuable? Evidence from agency bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>King, Tao-Hsien Dolly
This paper examines the call option values embedded in callable agency bonds. For FHLB, FNMA, and SLMA bonds, call value estimates range from 1.23% of par to 1.47% on average, which are between those for the treasury and corporate debt securities. FHLMC bonds, on the other hand, have an average call value estimate of 2.85%. Call values are significantly larger for bonds with a longer remaining maturity and greater default risk. Most interestingly, call values in the call protection period are significantly larger than those in the callable period except for the SLMA bonds, whereas previous studies on corporate debt find no significant difference in call values between these two periods. In general, call value exhibits a downward trend over time as the callable bond approaches maturity. Also, call value is inversely related to the level of interest rates. Interest rate drops are usually accompanied by an increase in Call values. An analysis of the determinants of call values suggests the following conclusions. First, call values are negatively related to short-term interest rates and the slope of the yield curve, and positively related to coupon rate and remaining maturity. Second, bonds with a greater amount of call protection have smaller call values, which is in contrast with the finding in a previous study on corporate debt that call protection period has little effect on call value. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>King, Tao-Hsien Dolly</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial contagion and the role of the central bank</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Castiglionesi, Fablo
We investigate the role of a central bank (CB) in preventing and avoiding financial contagion. The CB, by imposing reserve requirements on the banking system, trades off the cost of reducing the resources available for long-term investment with the benefit of raising liquidity to face an adverse shock that could cause contagious crises. We argue that contagion is not due to the structure of the interbank deposit market, but to the impossibility to sign contracts contingent on unforeseen contingencies. As long as incomplete contracts are present, the CB may have a useful role in curbing contagion. Moreover, the CB allows the banking system to reach first-best allocation in all the states of the world when the notion of incentive-efficiency is considered. If the analysis is restricted to constrained-efficiency, the CB still avoids contagion without, however, reaching first-best consumption allocation. The model provides a rationale for reserve requirements without the presence of fiat money or asymmetric information. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Castiglionesi, Fablo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Traffic light options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jorgensen, Peter Lochte
This paper introduces, prices, and analyzes traffic light options. The traffic light option is an innovative structured OTC derivative developed independently by several London-based investment banks to suit the needs of Danish life and pension (L&amp;P) companies, which must comply with the traffic light solvency stress test system introduced by the Danish Financial Supervisory Authority (DFSA) in June 2001. This monitoring system requires L&amp;P companies to submit regular reports documenting the sensitivity of the companies' base capital to certain pre-defined market shocks the red and yellow; light scenarios. These stress scenarios entail drops in interest rates as well as in stock prices, and traffic light options are thus designed to pay off and preserve sufficient capital when interest rates and stock prices fall simultaneously. Sweden's FSA implemented a traffic light system in January 2006, and supervisory authorities in many other European countries have implemented similar regulation. Traffic light options are therefore likely to attract the attention of a wider audience of pension fund managers in the future. Focusing on the valuation of the traffic light option we set up a Black-Scholes/Hull-White model to describe stock market and interest rate dynamics, and analyze the traffic light option in this framework. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jorgensen, Peter Lochte</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond durations: Corporates vs. Treasuries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kraft, Holger; Munk, Claus
We compare the durations (the percentage price sensitivity with respect to the default-free short rate) of corporate and Treasury bonds in the reduced-form, intensity-based credit risk modeling framework. In a frequently used intensity-based model for corporate bond valuation we provide an example showing that, given the parameter estimates found in empirical studies, the duration of a corporate coupon bond may very well be larger than the duration of a similar Treasury bond. This finding contrasts with conclusions of previous studies. In a general, intensity-based recovery of market value framework we provide a simple sufficient condition for when the duration of a corporate bond will be smaller than that of a similar Treasury bond. We also provide an upper bound on the duration of the corporate coupon bond. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kraft, Holger; Munk, Claus</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Theories of bank behavior under capital regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>VanHoose, David
This paper reviews academic studies of bank capital regulation in an effort to evaluate the intellectual foundation for the imposition of the Basel I and Basel II systems of risk-based capital requirements. The theoretical literature yields general agreement about the immediate effects of capital requirements on bank lending and loan rates and the longer-term impacts on bank ratios of equity to total or risk-adjusted assets. This literature produces highly mixed predictions, however, regarding the effects of capital regulation on asset risk and overall safety and soundness for the banking system as a whole. Thus, the intellectual foundation for the present capital-regulation regime is not particularly strong. The mixed conclusions in the academic literature on banking certainly do not provide unqualified support for moving to an even more stringent and costly system of capital requirements. These widely ambiguous results do suggest, however, that assessing the implications of capital regulation for balance-sheet risk and monitoring effort in diverse banking systems is an important agenda for future theoretical research in the banking area. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>VanHoose, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm value, illiquidity risk and liquidity insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moretto, Michele; Tamborini, Roberto
Our interest here concerns liquidity supply to firms. We first examine the relation between firm value and access to liquidity supply, and then we investigate the existence conditions and efficiency properties of financial contracts with a liquidity covenant in a continuous-time, infinite-horizon stochastic model of a repeated firm-investors relationship where the key problem is the mutual commitment between the two parties. To model this problem we consider liquidity supply as a stochastic "regulator mechanism" that prevents the firm's ability to pay from falling below a predefined threshold (here the market fixed coupon), and we then apply recent developments in dynamic programming techniques for "regulated processes" to obtain a close form solution for the firm's value. Our main finding is that efficient, i.e. actuarially fair and renegotiation-proof contracts emerge in the absence of perfect commitment as the firm and the investor can exert mutual threat of termination. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moretto, Michele; Tamborini, Roberto</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit portfolios: What defines risk horizons and risk measurement?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ebnoether, Silvan; Vanini, Paolo
The strong autocorrelation between economic cycles demands that we analyze credit portfolio risk in a multiperiod setup. We embed a standard one-factor model in such a setup. We discuss the calibration of the model to Standard &amp; Poor's ratings data in detail. But because single-period risk measures cannot capture the cumulative effects of systematic shocks over several periods, we define an alternative risk measure, which we call the time-conditional expected shortfall (TES), to quantify credit portfolio risk over a multiperiod horizon. (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Ebnoether, Silvan; Vanini, Paolo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bidder returns in bancassurance mergers: Is there evidence of synergy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fields, L. Paige; Fraser, Donald R.; Kolarl, James W.
We provide evidence on the potential for bidder wealth gains in bancassurance mergers by examining a sample of such mergers in the United States and abroad. These combinations are expected to produce positive wealth gains if there are synergies between these two types of financial firms. We find positive bidder wealth effects that are significantly related to economies of scale (as measured by the size of the target relative to the bidder), potential economies of scope, and the locations of the bidders and targets. These results suggest that the bancassurance architectural structure for financial firms does offer some benefits and thus may become more prominent in future years. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fields, L. Paige; Fraser, Donald R.; Kolarl, James W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price differences between equity classes. Corporate control, foreign ownership or liquidity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Odegaard, Bernt Arne
This paper is the first comprehensive study of price differences for dual class equity at the Oslo Stock Exchange. It analyzes the relative importance of corporate control, foreign ownership restrictions and stock market liquidity for the price differences. The Norwegian market has the peculiar feature that in part of the sample period non-voting shares were trading at a premium to voting shares, i.e., what is usually termed the "voting premium" was negative. This result can be rationalized by restrictions on foreign ownership. In the later part of the period, with no regulatory restrictions on foreign ownership, the voting premium is positive, and related to corporate governance and liquidity. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Odegaard, Bernt Arne</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidation triggers and the valuation of equity and debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galai, Dan; Raviv, Alon; Wiener, Zvi
Many bankruptcy codes implicitly or explicitly contain net-worth covenants, which provide the firm's bondholders with the right to force reorganization or liquidation if the value of the firm falls below a certain threshold. In practice, however, default does not necessarily lead to immediate change of control or to liquidation of the firm's assets by its debtholders. To consider the impact of this on the valuation of corporate securities, we develop a model in which liquidation is driven by a state variable that accumulates with time and severity of distress. We model a dynamic grace period for the liquidation event. Recent or severe distress events may have greater impact on the liquidation trigger. Our model can be applied to a wide array of bankruptcy codes and jurisdictions. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Galai, Dan; Raviv, Alon; Wiener, Zvi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical comparison of continuous-time models of implied volatility indices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dotsis, George; Psychoylos, Dimitris; Skladopoulos, George
We explore the ability of alternative popular continuous-time diffusion and jump-diffusion processes to capture the dynamics of implied volatility indices over time. The performance of the various models is assessed under both econometric and financial metrics. To this end, data are employed from major European and American implied volatility indices and the rapidly growing CBOE volatility futures market. We find that the addition of jumps is necessary to capture the evolution of implied volatility indices under both rnetrics. Mean reversion is of second-order importance though. The results are consistent across the various metrics. markets, and construction methodologies. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dotsis, George; Psychoylos, Dimitris; Skladopoulos, George</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Joint size and ownership specialization in bank lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delgado, J.; Salas, V.; Saurina, J.
During the period 1996-2003 consolidation reduces the size diversity of Spanish banks but diversity in ownership forms increases as savings banks and cooperatives gain market share. This paper examines the implications of these structural changes in Spanish credit markets in terms of banks' specialization (large or small borrowers, relational or transactional lending) and consequent credit availability for small and opaque firms. We find that size-of-the-borrower/size-of-the-bank specialization follows a different pattern in savings banks than in commercial banks, suggesting lower organizational diseconomies of size in the former than in the latter, which helps to explain the increase in ownership diversity over time. We also find that savings banks and cooperatives specialize relatively more in relational lending than commercial banks so ownership diversity assures funding for small firms even if bank consolidation continues. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Delgado, J.; Salas, V.; Saurina, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan underpricing and the provision of merger advisory services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Linda; Peristiani, Stavros
This paper investigates the primary and secondary syndicated bank loan market to analyze the effect on pricing when the financial institution commingles syndicated lending with merger advisory services. In particular, we investigate the connection between the acquirer's choice of financial advisor in a merger and future financing commitments. We find evidence of underpricing of syndicated bank loans in both the primary and secondary market. In the primary market, we show that non-acquisition loans granted by merger advisors to acquiring firms after the merger announcement date are charged a lower all-in-spread relative to acquisition loans if there has been a prior lending relationship. Consistent with this finding, we find that syndicated bank loans for non-acquisition purposes arranged by the acquirer's advisor after the merger announcement date trade in the secondary market at a significant discount. Since the terms on these non-acquisition loans are not set upon merger announcement, they are most subject to risk shifting and underpricing agency problems. These findings offer evidence consistent with the existence of loss leader and potentially conflicted loans (priced at below-market terms) that are offered by the acquirer's relationship bank advisor in order to win merger advisory business. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allen, Linda; Peristiani, Stavros</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The liquidity of bank assets and banking stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wagner, Wolf
This paper shows that an increased liquidity of bank assets, paradoxically, increases banking instability and the externalities associated with banking failures. This is because even though higher asset liquidity directly benefits stability by encouraging banks to reduce the risks on their balance sheets and by facilitating the liquidation of assets in a crisis, it also makes crises less costly for banks. As a result, banks have an incentive to take on an amount of new risk that more than offsets the positive direct impact on stability. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wagner, Wolf</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock exchange governance initiatives: Evidence from the Italian STARs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gleason, Kimberly C.; Madura, Jeff; Subrahmanyam, Vijaya
Can a stock exchange improve corporate governance and transparency by designating companies that exhibit superior corporate governance? In 2000, the Borsa Italiana created a mid-cap segment with strong listing standards, which is composed of firms (called STARS) that follow stricter standards of transparency, disclosure, monitoring and liquidity. We find that STAR firms exhibit governance characteristics not observed in non-STAR firms, such as a higher incidence of audit and executive committees and higher debt ratios. They experienced a modestly favorable share price response upon the implementation of the STAR initiative. Moreover, they experienced significantly higher buy and hold returns and transparency after the initiative. Several governance characteristics are cross-sectionally associated with performance following the STAR initiative. Overall, the results suggest that firms may be willing to improve governance when they are endorsed by a credible agency for doing so, and such improvements may lead to better performance. The STAR initiative may serve as a model that can be adapted by other stock exchanges to promote transparency and governance. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gleason, Kimberly C.; Madura, Jeff; Subrahmanyam, Vijaya</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on the importance of overnight information in risk management models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Nicholas
This paper examines the economic value of overnight information to users of risk management models. In addition to the information revealed by overseas markets that trade during the (domestic) overnight period, this paper exploits information generated via recent innovations in the structure of financial markets. In particular, certain securities (and associated derivative products) can now be traded at any time over a 24-h period. As such, it is now possible to make use of information generated by trading, in (almost) identical securities, during the overnight period. Of the securities that are available over such time periods, S&amp;P 500 related products are by far the most actively traded and are, therefore, the subject of this paper. Using a variety of conditional volatility models that allow time-dependent information flow within (and across) three different S&amp;P 500 markets, the results show that overnight information flow has a significant impact on the conditional volatility of daytime traded S&amp;P 500 securities. Moreover (time-consistent) forecasts from models that incorporate overnight information are shown to have economic value to risk managers. In particular, Value-at-Risk (VaR) models based on these conditional volatility models are shown to be more accurate than VaR models that ignore overnight information. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Taylor, Nicholas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modelling the economic value of credit rating systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jankowitsch, Rainer; Pichler, Stefan; Schwaiger, Walter S. A.
In this paper we develop a model of the economic value of credit rating systems. Increasing international competition and changes in the regulatory framework driven by the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision (Basel II) called forth incentives for banks to improve their credit rating systems. An improvement of the statistical power of a rating system decreases the potential effects of adverse selection, and, combined with meeting several qualitative standards, decreases the amount of regulatory capital requirements. As a consequence, many banks have to make investment decisions where they have to consider the costs and the potential benefits of improving their rating systems. In our model the quality of a rating system depends on several parameters such as the accuracy of forecasting individual default probabilities and the rating class structure. We measure effects of adverse selection in a competitive one-period framework by parameterizing customer elasticity. Capital requirements are obtained by applying the current framework released by the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision. Results of a numerical analysis indicate that improving a rating system with low accuracy to medium accuracy can increase the annual rate of return on a portfolio by 30-40 bp. This effect is even stronger for banks operating in markets with high customer elasticity and high loss rates. Compared to the estimated implementation costs banks could have a strong incentive to invest in their rating systems. The potential of reduced capital requirements on the portfolio return is rather weak compared to the effect of adverse selection. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jankowitsch, Rainer; Pichler, Stefan; Schwaiger, Walter S. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge fund portfolio construction: A comparison of static and dynamic approaches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giamouridis, Daniel; Vrontos, Ioannis D.
This article studies the impact of modeling time-varying covariances/correlations of hedge fund returns in terms of hedge fund portfolio construction and risk measurement. We use a variety of static and dynamic covariance/correlation prediction models and compare the optimized portfolios' out-of-sample performance. We find that dynamic covariance/correlation models construct portfolios with lower risk and higher out-of-sample risk-adjusted realized return. The tail-risk of the constructed portfolios is also lower. Using a mean-conditional-value-at-risk framework we show that dynamic covariance/correlation models are also successful in constructing portfolios with minimum tail-risk. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giamouridis, Daniel; Vrontos, Ioannis D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank ownership and performance. Does politics matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Micco, Alejandro; Panizza, Ugo; Yanez, Monica
This paper uses a new dataset to reassess the relationship between bank ownership and bank performance, providing separate estimations for developing and industrial countries. It finds that state-owned banks located in developing countries tend to have lower profitability and higher costs than their private counterparts, and that the opposite is true for foreign-owned banks. The paper finds no strong correlation between ownership and performance for banks located in industrial countries. Next, in order to test whether the differential in performance between public and private banks is driven by political considerations, the paper checks whether this differential widens during election years; it finds strong support for this hypothesis. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Micco, Alejandro; Panizza, Ugo; Yanez, Monica</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-varying risk aversion and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, George
This paper uses a variant of the consumption-based representative agent model in Campbell and Cochrane [Campbell, J.Y., Cochrane, J.H., 1999. By force of habit: Consumption-based explanation of aggregate stock market behavior. Journal of Political Economy 107, 205-251] to study how investors' time-varying risk aversion affects asset prices. First, we show that a countercyclical variation of risk aversion drives a procyclical conditional risk premium. Second, we show that with a small value for the volatility of the log surplus consumption ratio, a large value of risk aversion may not determine whether the equity premium and the risk-free rate puzzles can be resolved or not. Third, we show that countercyclical risk aversion may not help explain the predictability of long-horizon stock returns, the univariate mean-reversion of stock prices and the "leverage effect" in return volatility. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, George</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, transmission and bank pricing policies: Evidence from Belgian loan and deposit markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Graeve, Ferre; De Jonghe, Olivier; Vander Vennet, Rudi
This paper addresses the pass-through from market interest rates to retail bank interest rates. The paper advocates a heterogeneous approach and applies it to the Belgian banking market. A substantial proportion of the heterogeneity in bank pricing policies can be explained by the bank lending channel and the relative market power hypothesis. The results also suggest that the long-term pass-through is typically less than one-for-one, rejecting the completeness hypothesis. While there is no convincing evidence for asymmetry in retail rates, large deviations from equilibrium mark-ups are faster reduced than small deviations. Overall, conditions for corporate loans are more competitive compared to consumer loans. Demand and savings deposits have, by far, the most rigid prices. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Graeve, Ferre; De Jonghe, Olivier; Vander Vennet, Rudi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Switching costs and relationship profits in bank lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vesala, Timo
This paper studies how the cost of switching banks affects the profits available from relationship based lending when the relationship produces inside information. Lower switching cost compounds the adverse selection problem, discouraging outsider banks to depress loan rates. The adverse selection effect eases off along with higher switching cost, leading to more aggressive bidding and thereby reduction in insider profits. Above a certain threshold, however, the adverse selection effect vanishes completely and the insider profits turn increasing in the switching cost. The model predicts that the availability of relationship credit is non-monotonously related to the magnitude of the switching cost. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vesala, Timo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of network size on bank branch performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirtle, Beverly
Despite significant technological innovation in retail banking services delivery, the number of US bank branches has grown steadily over time. Further, more and more of these branches are held by banks with large branch networks. This paper assesses the implications of these developments by examining measures of branch performance and asking how these measure vary across institutions with different branch network sizes. Our findings suggest that banks with mid-sized branch networks may be at a competitive disadvantage in branching activities. We find no systematic relationship between branch network size and overall institutional profitability, perhaps because banking organizations optimize the size of their branch network operations as part of an overall strategy involving both branch-based and non-branch-based activities. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hirtle, Beverly</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A computational approach to the optimal structure of bank input prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stanhouse, Bryan; Ingram, Matthew
Most bank deposits contain an embedded option which permits the depositor to withdraw funds at will. Demand deposits generally allow costless withdrawal, while time deposits often require payment of an early withdrawal penalty. Managing the risk that depositors will exercise their withdrawal option is an important aspect of input pricing. This paper acknowledges the threat of deposit withdrawal and then solves for the optimal structure of bank deposit rates. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stanhouse, Bryan; Ingram, Matthew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Actual share repurchases, timing and liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ginglinger, Edith; Hamon, Jacques
Research on the impact of open market share repurchases has been hindered by the lack of data available on actual share repurchases in many countries, including the US. Using a previously unused database containing detailed information on 36,848 repurchases made by 352 French firms, we show that corporate share repurchases have a significant adverse effect on liquidity as measured by bid-ask spread or depth. Our results also indicate that share repurchases largely reflect contrarian trading rather than managerial timing ability. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ginglinger, Edith; Hamon, Jacques</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The adjustment of credit ratings in advance of defaults</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guettler, Andre; Wahrenburg, Mark
This paper assesses biases in credit ratings and lead-lag relationships for near-to-default issuers with multiple ratings by Moody's and S&amp;P. Based on defaults from 1997 to 2004, we find evidence that Moody's seems to adjust its ratings to increasing default risk in a timelier manner than S&amp;P. Second, credit ratings by the two US-based agencies are not subject to any home preference. Third, given a downgrade (upgrade) by the first rating agency, subsequent downgrades (upgrades) by the second rating agency are of greater magnitude in the short term. Fourth, harsher rating changes by one agency are followed by harsher rating changes in the same direction by the second agency. Fifth, rating changes by the second rating agency are significantly more likely after downgrades than after upgrades by the first rating agency. Additionally, we find evidence for serial correlation in rating changes up to 90 days subsequent to the rating change of interest after controlling for rating changes by the second rating agency. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guettler, Andre; Wahrenburg, Mark</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market price accounting and depositor discipline: The case of Japanese regional banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spiegel, Mark M.; Yamori, Nobuyoshi
We examine the determinants of Japanese regional bank pricing-to-market decisions and their impact on the intensity of depositor discipline, in the form of the sensitivity of deposit growth to bank financial conditions. To obtain consistent estimates, we first model and estimate the bank pricing-to-market decision and then estimate the intensity of depositor discipline after conditioning for that decision. We find that banks were less likely to adopt market price accounting the larger were their unrealized securities losses. We also find statistically significant evidence of depositor discipline among banks that elected to price to market. Our results indicate that depositor discipline was more intense for the subset of banks that adopted market price accounting. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Spiegel, Mark M.; Yamori, Nobuyoshi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bubbles in the dividend-price ratio? Evidence from an asymmetric exponential smooth-transition model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McMillan, David G.
Recent stock price movements have led to a re-examination of the present value model. An increasing belief is that although dividends and prices are indeed cointegrated, they may exhibit non-linear dynamics in the process of reversion. This paper implements an empirical model designed to capture two possible explanations for such non-linearity, namely transaction costs and noise traders. Utilising data from a number of countries we show that the dynamics of the log dividend yield are, first, characterised by an inner random walk regime, where the benefits of engaging in trade do not outweigh the costs and so the process moves randomly. Second, a reverting outer regime where the dynamics of reversion differ between positive and negative deviations, such that price rises greater than the level supported by dividends exhibit a greater degree of persistence than price falls relative to dividends. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McMillan, David G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>FDI versus exports: Evidence from German banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buch, Claudia M.; Lipponer, Alexander
We use a new bank-level dataset to study the FDI-versus-exports decision for German banks. We extend the literature on multinational firms in two directions. First, we simultaneously study FDI and the export of cross-border financial services. Second, we test recent theories on multinational firms which show the importance of firm heterogeneity [Helpman, E., Melitz, MJ., Yeaple, S.R., 2004. Export versus FDI. American Economic Review 94 (1), 300-316]. Our results show that FDI and cross-border services are complements rather than substitutes. Heterogeneity of banks has a significant impact on the internationalization decision. More profitable and larger banks are more likely to expand internationally than smaller banks. They have more extensive foreign activities, and they are more likely to engage in FDI in addition to cross-border financial services. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buch, Claudia M.; Lipponer, Alexander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retail banking and behavioral financial engineering: The case of structured products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Wolfgang; Perst, Achim
We apply cumulative prospect theory and hedonic framing to evaluate discount reverse convertibles (DRCs) and reverse convertible bonds (RCBs) as important examples of structured products from a boundedly rational investor's point of view. While common expected utility theory would also conclude that DRCs and RCBs are of interest to investors with moderate return expectations and underestimated stock return volatility, that theory would overestimate the market success of DRCs and underestimate that of RCBs in comparison to a situation with bounded rationality. Hedonic framing and relatively low subjectively felt competence levels of investors are decisive for the demand for RCBs. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Breuer, Wolfgang; Perst, Achim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate credit risk modeling and the macroeconomy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carling, Kenneth; Jacobson, Tor; Linde, Jesper; Roszbach, Kasper
Despite a surge in the research efforts put into modeling credit and default risk during the past decade, few studies have incorporated the impact that macroeconomic conditions have on business defaults. In this paper, we estimate a duration model to explain the survival time to default for borrowers in the business loan portfolio of a major Swedish bank over the period 1994-2000. The model takes both firm-specific characteristics, such as accounting ratios and payment behaviour, loan-related information, and the prevailing macroeconomic conditions into account. The output gap, the yield curve and consumers' expectations of future economic development have significant explanatory power for the default risk of firms. We also compare our model with a frequently used model of firm default risk that conditions only on firm-specific information. The comparison shows that while the latter model can make a reasonably accurate ranking of firms' according to default risk, our model, by taking macro conditions into account, is also able to account for the absolute level of risk. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carling, Kenneth; Jacobson, Tor; Linde, Jesper; Roszbach, Kasper</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contracting costs and the window of opportunity for straight debt issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnaswami, Sudha; Yaman, Devrim
We analyze whether fluctuation in economy-wide factors cause time-series variation in the contracting costs of moral hazard, adverse selection, and financial distress for a sample of straight debt issues. We find that the announcement period abnormal returns to debt issues are more negative in periods of higher interest rates and in industry downturns. When we partition the impact of each issue- and firm-specific measure of contracting costs across high and low levels of each economy-wide variable, we find that only the measures of agency cost are significant in general, and measures of financial distress become relevant for those debt issues that constitute a leverage increase for the firms. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Krishnaswami, Sudha; Yaman, Devrim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate use of derivatives and excess value of diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, J. Barry; Pantzalis, Christos; Park, Jung Chul
We provide a link between diversification discount and corporate use of financial derivatives. We show that diversified firms benefit from financial risk management. Our findings are consistent with the notion that derivative usage lowers information asymmetry and thereby reduces the negative valuation effects of diversification. Our evidence complements the earlier findings of both the risk management literature and diversification discount literature and is robust to controls for endogeneity and information asymmetry levels. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, J. Barry; Pantzalis, Christos; Park, Jung Chul</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond segmentation: The case of China's repo markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, Longzhen; Zhang, Chu
This paper explores the reasons behind the discrepancy between interest rates in China's two repurchase agreement (repo) markets, the interbank repo market and the exchange-traded repo market. The repo rates in the exchange market are at times, significantly higher than those in the interbank market, especially in the first three years of the 2000-2005 sample period. While market segmentation clearly hinders arbitrage, the causes of the repo rate discrepancy are related to the alternative investment opportunities available to market participants and to the volatility differences in the repo rates. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fan, Longzhen; Zhang, Chu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Profitability of momentum strategies in international markets: The role of business cycle variables and behavioural biases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antoniou, Antonios; Lam, Herbert Y. T.; Paudyal, Krishna
The paper investigates whether business cycle variables and behavioural biases can explain the profitability of momentum trading in three major European markets. Unlike previous studies, the paper nests both risk-based and behavioural-based variables in a two-stage model specification in an attempt to explain momentum profits. The findings show that, although momentum profitability in European markets is unexplained by conditional asset pricing models, it is attributable to asset mispricing that systematically varies with global business conditions. In addition, behavioural variables do not appear to matter much. Thus risk factors, which are undetected thus far and are largely attributable to the business cycle, could explain the momentum payoffs in European stock markets. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Antoniou, Antonios; Lam, Herbert Y. T.; Paudyal, Krishna</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-sectional learning and short-run persistence in mutual fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huij, Joop; Verbeek, Marno
Using monthly return data of more than 6400 US equity mutual funds we investigate short-run performance persistence over the period 1984-2003. We sort funds into rank portfolios based on past performance, and evaluate the portfolios' out-of-sample performance. To cope with short ranking periods, we employ an empirical Bayes approach to measure past performance more efficiently. Our main finding is that when funds are sorted into decile portfolios based on 12-month ranking periods, the top decile of funds earns a statistically significant, abnormal return of 0.26 percent per month. This effect persists beyond load fees, and is mainly concentrated in relatively young, small cap/growth funds. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huij, Joop; Verbeek, Marno</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pricing of leverage products: An empirical investigation of the German market for 'long' and 'short' stock index certificates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wilkens, Sascha; Stoimenov, Pavel A.
This paper describes the first thorough empirical analysis of the pricing of leverage products in the German retail market. These mainly exchange-traded products with an impressive trading volume are frequently advertised as long and short futures contracts, although they are theoretically equivalent to one-sided barrier options. Issuers' daily quotes for stock index products are compared to (i) theoretical values derived from the prices of Eurex options and to (ii) boundaries obtained from semi-static superhedging strategies. For the vast majority of products, bid and ask quotes significantly exceed both theoretical values and upper hedging boundaries, thus providing almost risk-free profits for the issuers. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wilkens, Sascha; Stoimenov, Pavel A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do central banks react to the stock market? The case of the Bundesbank</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bohl, Martin T.; Siklos, Pierre L.; Werner, Thomas
In this paper, we ask whether the Bundesbank, prior to the European Central Bank taking responsibility for monetary policy in 1999, reacted systematically to stock price movements. In contrast to the results for the US, our empirical findings show a generally weak relationship between German stock returns and short-term interest rates at the daily and the monthly frequency. The results are extremely robust to alternative model specifications. The evidence is inconsistent with the hypothesis of a systematic reaction of the Bundesbank to German stock prices. However, we do find that, as in the US, the Bundesbank may have reacted to the stock market crash of 1987 by loosening monetary policy. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bohl, Martin T.; Siklos, Pierre L.; Werner, Thomas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-run returns following open market share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McNally, William J.; Smith, Brian F.
Past studies find abnormal returns to buying after repurchase program announcements. We analyze the profitability of trading after both program announcements and individual repurchase trade publication using different trading strategies - market and limit orders. The analysis of trades is possible because of a unique Canadian data set. The highest abnormal returns are earned by companies on their own repurchase trades which benefits the non-tendering shareholders. For the public investor, we find no strategies that, in practice, would earn abnormal returns to buying after program announcements. However, there is qualified evidence of abnormal returns to a limit order strategy following publication of individual repurchase trades. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McNally, William J.; Smith, Brian F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPOs, trade sales and liquidations: Modelling venture capital exits using survival analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giot, Pierre; Schwienbacher, Armin
This paper examines the dynamics of exit options for US venture capital funds. Using a sample of more than 20,000 investment rounds, we analyze the time to 'IPO', 'trade sale' and 'liquidation' for 6000 VC-backed firms. We model these exit times using competing risks models, which allow for a joint analysis of exit type and exit timing. The hazard rate for IPOs are clearly non-monotonic with respect to time. As time flows, VC-backed firms first exhibit an increased likelihood of exiting to an IPO. However, after having reached a plateau, non-exited investments have fewer possibilities of IPO exits as time increases. This sharply contrasts with trade sale exits, where the hazard rate is less time-varying. We further provide evidence on the impact of economic factors such as syndicate size and composition, geographical location and VC value adding, on exit outcomes. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giot, Pierre; Schwienbacher, Armin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio efficiency and discount factor bounds with conditioning information: An empirical study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abhyankar, Abhay; Basu, Devraj; Stremme, Alexander
Stochastic discount factor bounds provide a useful diagnostic too] for testing asset pricing models by specifying a lower bound on the variance of any admissible discount factor. In this paper, we provide a unified derivation of such bounds in the presence of conditioning information, which allows us to compare their theoretical and empirical properties. We find that, while the location of the 'unconditionally efficient (UE)' bounds of [Ferson, W., Siegel, A., 2001. The efficient use of conditioning information in portfolios. Journal of Finance 56 (3), 967-982] is statistically indistinguishable from the (theoretically) optimal bounds of [Gallant, R., Hansen, L., Tauchen, G., 1990. Using conditional moments of asset payoffs to infer the volatility of intertemporal marginal rates of substitution. Journal of Econometrics 45 (1), 141-179] (GHT), the former exhibit better sampling properties. We demonstrate that the difference in sampling variability of the UE and GHT bounds is due to the different behavior of the efficient return weights underlying their construction. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abhyankar, Abhay; Basu, Devraj; Stremme, Alexander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of bond tender premiums and the percentage tendered</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mann, Steven V.; Powers, Eric A.
We analyze a large sample of US corporate bond tender offers to understand what affects tender premiums as well as the percentage of bonds tendered. For the average (median) tender offer, the tender price is 5.55% (3.24%) greater than the pre-tender market price while the percentage of bonds tendered is 82.3% (94.6%). Premiums offered by firms are greater when the firm is simultaneously soliciting consents to amend restrictive covenants and when the bond has a greater number of restrictive covenants. Premiums are also greater when long-term risk-free yields are low and the yield curve is flatter - conditions where a firm might want to lock in favorable long-term rates by issuing new debt and retiring old debt. Bondholders respond to higher tender premiums by tendering a greater percentage of their bonds - a 1% increase in tender premium increases the tendering rate by approximately 9%. Bondholders also tender a greater percentage of bonds possessing less desirable characteristics such as a short remaining maturity or bonds that are simultaneously undergoing consent solicitations. Finally, we find that tender offers are easier to complete when bond ownership concentration is greater. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mann, Steven V.; Powers, Eric A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulation fair disclosure and the market's reaction to analyst investment recommendation changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornett, Marcia Millon; Tehranian, Hassan; Yalcin, Atakan
Previous research has shown that affiliated analysts (those who are working for investment banks that underwrite securities for companies) have an incentive to provide optimistically biased recommendations from selective information they are given by the firm. In an effort to halt such activities, as of October 2000, Regulation Fair Disclosure (RegFD) prohibits selective disclosure of material non-public information by public companies to privileged individuals (such as favored research analysts) and requires broad, non-exclusionary disclosure of such information. We examine firms' stock price reactions to investment recommendation changes from affiliated analysts versus unaffiliated analysts from October 1998 to November 2002, around the passage of RegFD. Similar to previous research, we find that investors reacted more significantly to recommendation downgrades by affiliated analysts than to those by unaffiliated analysts prior to the passage of RegFD. However, we find that the difference in the reactions to recommendation changes is not present after the passage of RegFD. We also find that stock price reactions to analysts' (both affiliated and unaffiliated) recommendation changes decreased significantly after the passage of RegFD. Thus, RegFD appears to have curbed the selective disclosure of information (particularly negative information) by firms to affiliated analysts. Further, the smaller reactions to recommendation changes by all analysts after RegFD may reflect a change in analysts' behavior (irrespective of information that is available) or a response by corporate managers to withhold information rather than risking a violation of fair disclosure rules. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cornett, Marcia Millon; Tehranian, Hassan; Yalcin, Atakan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The collateral value of fine art</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McAndrew, Clare; Thompson, Rex
In this paper, we examine the effect of implicit seller reserves on the estimation of value-at-risk based on historical asset sales data. We direct our examination toward how and whether fine art might prove an appropriate form of loan collateral for banks and other financial institutions. Using a data set of French Impressionist paintings brought to auction from 1985 to 200 1, we control for the effect of works that are bought in-house to construct a distribution of potential sale values that corrects for sample selection bias. It turns out that the downside risk surrounding deviations of auction prices from expert presale estimates depends critically on how buy-ins are incorporated. If downside risk is assessed solely on historical experience with successful auction sales, the data appear to support loan-to-value ratios between 50% and a 100% larger than loan-to-value ratios that countenance the existence of seller reserves. The auction process, however, is quantifiable and can reveal the necessary risk information required for loan consideration. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McAndrew, Clare; Thompson, Rex</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-run performance of global versus domestic initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Congsheng; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.
This paper investigates the long-run performance of global IPOs as compared to purely domestic ones made by US industrial companies. We find that global IPOs not only underperform, the market but also underperform their domestic counterparts in the three years after issuance. Moreover, global issues with a larger global tranche are more prone to long-run underperformance. The results are consistent with the window of opportunity hypothesis that investors are overly optimistic about the future prospects of firms engaging in global offerings, and underperformance occurs as unduly high expectations are corrected over time. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Congsheng; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Restructuring, consolidation and competition in Latin American banking markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yildirim, H. Semih; Philippatos, George C.
This study examines the competitive conditions in the banking industries of eleven Latin American countries for the period 1993-2000. For these countries, the time interval under examination corresponds to an era characterized by substantial reforms to restructure their banking systems, increased consolidation and foreign bank penetration. The banks in our sample are found to be earning their revenues as if operating under monopolistic competition, as in many other developed and emerging financial systems. The results indicate that, overall, market concentration is not significantly related with competitive conduct. At the country level, however, we do observe a decline in competition for Brazil, Chile, and Venezuela in late 1990s which may be attributable to increased consolidation. Further, we observe that deregulation and opening up of the financial markets for foreign participation serves as an important catalyst to increase the competitiveness of banking markets. Higher degree of competition in the sector, in return, is associated with reduced bank margins and profitability but improved cost efficiency. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yildirim, H. Semih; Philippatos, George C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial market development and the importance of internal cash: Evidence from international data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Islam, Saiyid S.; Mozumdar, Abon
We examine the impact of financial market development on the extent to which firms have to rely on internal capital for making investments. Using international data from 31 countries for the 19871997 period, we find evidence of a negative relationship between financial market development and the importance of internal capital. The evidence is consistent across different estimation procedures, alternative measures of financial constraints and cash flow, and the use of bootstrapped standard errors. Finally, we find that the distortionary effect of negative cash flow observations reported earlier for US data extends to international data as well. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Islam, Saiyid S.; Mozumdar, Abon</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition without fungibility: Evidence from alternative market structures for derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Sohnke M.; Fehle, Frank
In this paper, we compare option contracts from a traditional derivatives exchange to bank-issued options, also referred to as covered warrants. While bank-issued option markets and traditional derivatives exchanges exhibit significant structural differences such as the absence of a central counterparty for bank-issued options, they frequently exist side-by-side, and the empirical evidence shows that there is significant overlap in their product offerings although options are not fungible between the two markets. The empirical analysis indicates that bid-ask spreads in either market are lowered by 1-2% due to competition from the other market, providing evidence that the benefits of competing market structures are available in the absence of fungibility. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bartram, Sohnke M.; Fehle, Frank</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Markov switching models predict excess foreign exchange returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dueker, Michael; Neely, Christopher J.
This paper merges the literature on technical trading rules with the literature on Markov switching to develop economically useful trading rules. The Markov models' out-of-sample, excess returns modestly exceed those of standard technical rules and are profitable over the most recent subsample. A portfolio of Markov and standard technical rules outperforms either set individually, on a risk-adjusted basis. The Markov rules' high excess returns contrast with mixed performance on statistical tests of forecast accuracy. There is no clear source for the trends, but permitting the mean to depend on higher moments of the exchange rate distribution modestly increases returns. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dueker, Michael; Neely, Christopher J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privatization and stock market liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bortolotti, Bernardo; de Jong, Frank; Nicodano, Giovanna; Schindele, Ibolya
This paper shows that share issue privatization (SIP) is a major source of domestic stock market liquidity in 19 developed economies. Particularly, privatization IPOs have a negative effect on the price impact - measured by the ratio of the absolute return on the market index to turnover. This result is robust to the inclusion of controls for other observable and unobservable factors, having also considered the endogenous nature of the decision to privatize. We also provide evidence of a positive spillover of SIP on the liquidity of private companies. This cross-asset externality is one implication of liquidity theories emphasizing the improved risk diversification opportunities and risk sharing brought about by privatization. This externality stems from both domestic privatization IPOs and cross-listings. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bortolotti, Bernardo; de Jong, Frank; Nicodano, Giovanna; Schindele, Ibolya</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking relationships and access to equity capital markets: Evidence from Japan's main bank system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kutsuna, Kenji; Smith, Janet Kihohn; Smith, Richard L.
We study the role of banking relationships in IPO underwriting. When a firm in Japan goes public, it can engage an investment bank that is related through a common main bank, or can select an alternative investment bank. The main bank relationship can be an efficient way for the investment bank to acquire information generated by the main bank, but may give rise to conflicts of interest. We find that main bank relationships give small issuers increased access to equity capital markets, but that issuers of large IPOs often switch to non-related investment banks that are capable of managing large offerings. While investment banks seek to exploit bargaining power with related issuers, issuers respond to expected high issue cost by switching to non-related investment banks. The net result is that total issue costs through related and non-related investment banks are similar. With respect to aftermarket performance and use of proceeds, we find no evidence of conflict of interest or self-dealing for either the main bank or the investment bank. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kutsuna, Kenji; Smith, Janet Kihohn; Smith, Richard L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Basel II and bank lending to emerging markets: Evidence from the German banking sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liebig, Thilo; Porath, Daniel; Weder, Beatrice; Wedow, Michael
This paper investigates whether the new Basel Accord will induce a change in bank lending to emerging markets using a comprehensive new data set on German banks' foreign exposure. We test two interlinked hypotheses on the conditions under which the change in the regulatory capital would leave lending flows unaffected. This would be the case if (i) the new regulatory capital requirement remains below the economic capital and (ii) banks' economic capital to emerging markets already adequately reflects risk. On both accounts the evidence indicates that the new Basel Accord should have a limited effect on lending to emerging markets. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liebig, Thilo; Porath, Daniel; Weder, Beatrice; Wedow, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rates and efficiency in medieval wool forward contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bell, Adrian R.; Brooks, Chris; Dryburgh, Paul
While it is commonly believed that derivative instruments are a recent invention, we document the existence of forward contracts for the sale of wool in medieval England around 700 years ago. The contracts were generally entered into by English monasteries, who frequently sold their wool for up to 20 years in advance to mostly foreign and particularly Italian merchants. Employing a unique source of data collected by hand from the historical records, we determine the interest rates implied in these transactions and we also examine the efficiency of the forward and spot markets. The calculated interest rates average around 20%, in accordance with available information concerning the interest rates used in other types of transactions at that time. Perhaps surprisingly, we also find little evidence of informational inefficiencies in these markets. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bell, Adrian R.; Brooks, Chris; Dryburgh, Paul</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited participation and the closed-end fund discount</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Youngsoo; Lee, Bong Soo
In this paper, we present economic forces that affect the closed-end fund share price using a simple two-period model with limited participation. We characterize three economic forces: management fee, principal-agent problem effect and diversification benefit effect. The role of the management fee is consistent with recent studies by Ross [Ross S., 2002. Neoclassical finance, alternative finance and the closed end fund puzzle. European Financial Management 8, 129-137, Ross, S., 2002. A neoclassical look at behavioral finance: closed end funds. The Princeton lectures in finance 111] and findings of various empirical studies [e.g., Kumar, R., Noronha, G.M., 1992. A re-examination of the relationship between closed-end fund discounts and expenses. Journal of Financial Research 15(2) Summer, 139-147; Russel, P.S., 2005. Closed-end fund pricing: The puzzle, the explanations, and some new evidence, Journal of Business and Economic Studies 11(l), 34-49; Gemmill, G., Thomas, D.C., 2002. Noise trading, costly arbitrage, and asset prices: Evidence from closed end funds. Journal of Finance 57(6), 2571-2594]. The model's principal-agent problem effect is consistent with empirical findings by Brickley et al. [Brickley, James, Steven Manaster, Schallheim, James, 1991. The tax-timing option and the discounts on closed-end investment companies. Journal of Business 64, 287-312] of positive relation between the fund discount and the average variance of the constituent assets in the fund portfolio. In addition, it provides a theoretical framework for empirical studies, which examine the role of agency costs [Barclay, Michael J., Clifford G. Holderness, Jeffrey Pontiff, 1993. Private benefits from block ownership and discounts on closed-end funds. Journal of Financial Economics 33, 263-291] and compensation contracts [Coles, J., Suay, J., Woodbury, D., 2000. Fund advisor compensation in closed-end funds. Journal of Finance 55 (3), 1385-1414; Deli, Daniel N., 2002. Mutual fund advisory contracts: An empirical Investigation. Journal of Finance 57(l), 109-133] on the behavior of fund managers and fund discounts. The model's diversification benefit effect supports the result in [Bonser-Neal C., Brauer,G., Neal, R.., Wheatley, S., 1990. International investment restrictions and closed-end country fund prices. Journal of Finance 45, 523-547] that announcement of financial market liberalization is associated with a decrease in the fund premium. It also supports the findings of [Kumar, R., Noronha, G.M., 1992. A re-examination of the relationship between closed-end fund discounts and expenses. Journal of Financial Research 15(2) Summer, 139-147; Chay, J.B., Trzcinka, Charles A., 1999. Managerial performance and the cross-sectional pricing of closed-end funds. Journal of Financial Economics 52, 379-408] of a positive relation between current premium and the risk-adjusted return over the following year. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Youngsoo; Lee, Bong Soo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home sweet home: Home bias and international diversification among individual investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karlsson, Anders; Norden, Lars
A striking feature of international portfolio investment is the extent to which equity portfolios are concentrated in the domestic market of the investor. We investigate differences in home bias on an individual level by studying portfolios formed as a part of the new defined contribution pension plan in Sweden. We estimate the likelihood of home bias and use individuals' demographic and socioeconomic features as explanatory variables. Our findings indicate that the likelihood of home bias is caused by both rational and irrational factors. Moreover, we relate home bias to investors' desire to hedge against inflation, sophistication and overconfidence. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Karlsson, Anders; Norden, Lars</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management and optimization in finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krokhmal, P.; Rockafellar, R. T.
nan</description><author>Krokhmal, P.; Rockafellar, R. T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic portfolio selection with process control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>MacLean, L.; Zhao, Y. G.; Ziemba, W.
The risk inherent in the accumulation of investment capital depends on the true return distributions of the risky assets, the accuracy of estimated returns, and the investment strategy. This paper considers risk control with Value-at-Risk and Conditional Value-at-Risk, using control limits to determine times for portfolio rebalancing. Optimal strategies and control limits are determined for a geometric Brownian motion asset pricing model with random parameters. The approaches to risk control are applied to the fundamental problem of investment in stocks, bonds, and cash over time. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>MacLean, L.; Zhao, Y. G.; Ziemba, W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The magnitude of a market crash can be predicted</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Novak, S. Y.; Beirlant, J.
Could the magnitude of the stock market crash of 19.10.1987 be predicted on the base of the data available on the eve of "the black Monday"? How far can the financial market fall, say, once in 40 years? We demonstrate that modern methods of Extreme Value Theory can help in answering these questions. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Novak, S. Y.; Beirlant, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An approximation method for analysis and valuation of credit correlation derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Egami, M.; Esteghamat, K.
This paper presents a model for approximating the value of a basket of default-correlated assets and analyzes subordinate tranches in securitized debt obligations. The model is calibrated to an intensity-based Simulation of correlated defaults and represents an alternative computation method to full Monte Carlo simulation. Timing of individual obligor defaults are driven by intensity processes and collateral value is modeled with a jump-diffusion process where the number of jumps corresponds to the total number of defaults in the asset pool. This approach allows decomposition of subordinate obligations in terms of a collection of simpler securities and yields useful risk management information. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Egami, M.; Esteghamat, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Utility-based performance measures for regression models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friedman, C.; Sandow, S.
We measure regression model performance (as perceived by a conservative investor betting on a complete market) via the out-of-sample expected utility for the allocation that maximizes expected utility under a most adverse model-consistent measure. This robust allocation is optimal under the minimum generalized relative entropy (MGRE) measure. We analyze our performance measure in the (practical) case of an investor whose utility function is a member of a three-parameter logarithmic family with it wide range of possible risk aversions. Here, our performance measure is independent of the market prices, and the MGRE measure minimizes the Kullback-Leibler relative entropy. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Friedman, C.; Sandow, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset and liability management for insurance products with minimum guarantees: The UK case</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Consiglio, A.; Saunders, D.; Zenios, S. A.
Modern insurance products are becoming increasingly complex, offering various guarantees, surrender options and bonus provisions. A case in point are the with-profits insurance policies offered by UK insurers. While these policies have been offered in some form for centuries, in recent years their structure and management have become substantially more involved. The products are particularly complicated due to the wide discretion they afford insurers in determining the bonuses policyholders receive. In this paper, we study the problem of an insurance firm attempting to structure the portfolio underlying its with-profits fund. The resulting optimization problem, a non-linear program with stochastic variables, is presented in detail. Numerical results show how the model can be used to analyze the alternatives available to the insurer, such as different bonus policies and reserving methods. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Consiglio, A.; Saunders, D.; Zenios, S. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Applying CVaR for decentralized risk management of financial companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mulvey, J. M.; Erkan, H. G.
Over the past decade, financial companies have merged diverse areas including investment banking, insurance, retail banking, and trading operations. Despite this diversity, many global financial firms suffered severe losses during the recent recession. To reduce enterprise risks and increase profits, we apply a decentralized risk management strategy based on a stochastic optimization model. We extend the decentralized approach with the CVaR risk-metric, showing the advantages of CVaR over traditional risk measures such as value-at-risk. An example taken from the earthquake insurance area illustrates the concepts. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mulvey, J. M.; Erkan, H. G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implied migration rates from credit barrier models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albanese, C.; Chen, O. X.
The risk-neutral credit migration process captures quantitative information which is relevant to the pricing theory and risk management of credit derivatives. In this article, we derive implied migration rates by means of a recently introduced credit barrier model which is calibrated on the basis of aggregate information such as credit migration rates and credit spread curves. The model is characterized by an underlying stochastic process that represents credit quality, and default events are associated to barrier crossings. The stochastic process has state dependent volatility and jumps which are estimated by using empirical migration and default rates. A risk-neutralizing drift and forward liquidity spreads are estimated to consistently match the average spread Curves corresponding to all the various ratings. The implied migration rates obtained with Our credit barrier model are then compared with those obtained via the Kijima-Komoribayashi model. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Albanese, C.; Chen, O. X.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minimizing CVaR and VaR for a portfolio of derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, S.; Coleman, T. F.; Li, Y.
Value at risk (VaR) and conditional value at risk (CVaR) are frequently used as risk measures in risk management. Compared to VaR, CVaR is attractive since it is a coherent risk measure. We analyze the problem Of Computing the optimal VaR and CVaR portfolios. We illustrate that VaR and CVaR minimization problems for derivatives portfolios are typically ill-posed. We propose to include cost as an additional preference criterion for the CVaR optimization problem. We demonstrate that, with the addition of a proportional cost, it is possible to compute an optimal CVaR derivative investment portfolio with significantly fewer instruments and comparable CVaR and VaR, A computational method based on a smoothing technique is proposed to solve a simulation based CVaR optimization problem efficiently. Comparison is made with the linear programming approach for solving the simulation based CVaR optimization problem. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Alexander, S.; Coleman, T. F.; Li, Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The hidden dangers of historical simulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pritsker, M.
Many large financial institutions compute the Value-at-Risk (VaR) of their trading portfolios using historical simulation based methods, but the methods' properties are not well understood. This paper theoretically and empirically examines the historical simulation method, a variant of historical simulation introduced by Boudoukh et al. [Boudoukh, J., Richardson, M., Whitelaw, R., 1998. The best of both worlds, Risk 11(May) 64-67] (BRW), and the filtered historical simulation method (FHS) of Barone-Adesi et al. [Barone-Adesi, G., Bourgoin F., Giannopoulos, K., 1998. Don't look back. Risk 11(August) 100-104; Barone-Adesi, G., Giannopoulos K., Vosper L., 1999. VaR without correlations for nonlinear portfolios. Journal of Futures Markets 19(April) 583-602]. The historical simulation and BRW methods are both under-responsive to changes in conditional risk; and respond to changes in risk in an asymmetric fashion: measured risk increases when the portfolio experiences large losses, but not when it earns large gains. The FHS method is promising, but its risk estimates are variable in small samples, and its assumption that correlations are constant is violated in large samples. Additional refinements are needed to account for time-varying correlations; and to choose the appropriate length of the historical sample period. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pritsker, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A moment computation algorithm for the error in discrete dynamic hedging</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Primbs, J. A.; Yamada, Y.
This paper develops a computational approach to determining the moments of the distribution of the error in a dynamic hedging or payoff replication strategy under discrete trading. In particular, an algorithm is developed for portfolio affine trading strategies, which lead to portfolio dynamics that are affine in the portfolio variable. This structure can be exploited in the computation of moments of the hedging error of such a strategy, leading to a lattice based backward recursion similar in nature to lattice based pricing techniques, but not requiring the portfolio variable. We use this algorithm to analyze the performance of portfolio affine hedging strategies under discrete trading through the moments of the hedging error. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Primbs, J. A.; Yamada, Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multi-period stochastic optimization models for dynamic asset allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hibiki, N.
Institutional investors manage their strategic asset mix over time to achieve favorable returns subject to various uncertain ties, policy and legal constraints, and other requirements. One may use a multi-period portfolio optimization model in order to determine an optimal asset mix. The concept of scenarios is typically employed for modeling random parameters in a multi-period stochastic programming model, and scenarios are constructed via a tree structure. Recently, an alternative stochastic programming model with Simulated paths was proposed by Hibiki [Hibiki, N., 2001b. A hybrid simulation/tree multi-period stochastic programming model for optimal asset allocation. Ill: Takahashi, H. (Ed.). The Japanese Association of Financial Econometrics and Engineering. WEE Journal 89-119 (ill Japanese); Hibiki, N., 2003. A hybrid simulation/tree stochastic optimization model for dynamic asset allocation. In: Scherer, B. (Ed.), Asset and Liability Management Tools: A Handbook for Best Practice, Risk Books, pp. 269-294], and it is called a hybrid model. The advantage of the simulated path structure compared to the tree structure is to give a better accuracy to describe uncertainties of asset returns. In this paper, we compare the two types Of multi-period stochastic optimization models, and clarify that the hybrid model can evaluate and control risk better than the scenario tree model using some numerical tests. According to the numerical results, an efficient frontier of the hybrid model with the fixed-proportion strategy dominates that of the scenario tree model when we evaluate them on simulated paths. Moreover, optimal solutions of the hybrid model are more appropriate than those of the scenario tree model. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hibiki, N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient fund of hedge funds construction under downside risk measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morton, D. P.; Popova, E.; Popova, I.
We consider portfolio allocation in which the underlying investment instruments are hedge funds. We consider a family of utility functions involving the probability of outperforming a benchmark and expected regret relative to another benchmark. Non-normal return vectors with prescribed marginal distributions and correlation structure are modeled and simulated using the normal-to-anything method. A Monte Carlo procedure is used to obtain, and establish the quality of, a solution to the associated portfolio optimization model. Computational results are presented on a problem in which we construct a fund of 13 CSFB/Tremont hedge-fund indices. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morton, D. P.; Popova, E.; Popova, I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A linearly implicit predictor-corrector scheme for pricing American options using a penalty method approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khaliq, A. Q. M.; Voss, D. A.; Kazmi, S. H. K.
Pricing of ail American option is complicated since at each time we have to determine not only the option value but also whether or not it should be exercised (early exercise constraint). This makes the valuation of ail American option a free boundary problem. Typically at each time there is a particular value of the asset, which marks the boundary between two regions: to one side one should hold the option and to other side one should exercise it. Assuming that investors act optimally, the value of ail American option cannot fall below the value that would be obtained if it were exercised early. Effectively, this means that the American option early exercise feature transforms the original linear pricing partial differential equation into it nonlinear one. We consider a penalty method approach in which the free and moving boundary is removed by adding a small and continuous penalty term to the Black-Scholes equation; consequently,the problem can be solved on a fixed domain. Analytical Solutions of the Black-Scholes model of American option problems are seldom available and hence such derivatives must be priced by stable and efficient numerical techniques. Standard numerical methods involve the need to solve a system of nonlinear equations, evolving from the finite difference discretization of the nonlinear Black-Scholes model, at each time step by a Newton-type iterative procedure. We implement a novel linearly implicit scheme by treating the nonlinear penalty term explicitly, while maintaining superior accuracy and stability properties compared to the well-known theta-methods. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khaliq, A. Q. M.; Voss, D. A.; Kazmi, S. H. K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal credit limit management under different information regimes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leippold, M.; Vanini, P.; Ebnoether, S.
Credit limit management is of paramount importance for successful short-term credit risk management, even more so when the situation in credit and financial markets is tense. We consider a continuous-time model where the credit provider and the credit taker interact within a game-theoretic framework under different information structures. The model with complete information provides decision-theoretic insights into the problem of optimal limit policies and motivates more complicated information structures. Moving to a partial information setup, incentive distortions emerge that are not in the bank's interest. We discuss how these distortions can effectively be reduced by ail incentive-compatible contract. Finally, we provide some practical implications of our theoretical results. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leippold, M.; Vanini, P.; Ebnoether, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio optimization with stochastic dominance constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dentcheva, D.; Ruszczynski, A.
We consider the problem of constructing a portfolio of finitely many assets whose return rates are described by a discrete joint distribution. We propose a new portfolio optimization model involving stochastic dominance constraints on the portfolio return rate. We develop optimality and duality theory for these models. We construct equivalent optimization models with utility functions. Numerical illustration is provided. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dentcheva, D.; Ruszczynski, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing methods and hedging strategies for volatility derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Windcliff, H.; Forsyth, P. A.; Vetzal, K. R.
We explore the valuation and hedging of discretely observed volatility derivatives using three different models for the price of the underlying asset: Geometric Brownian motion with constant volatility, a local volatility surface, and jump-diffusion. We begin by comparing the effects on valuation of variations in contract design, Such as the differences between specifying log returns or actual returns and incorporating caps on the level of realized volatility. We then focus on the difficulties associated with hedging these products. Delta hedging strategies are ineffective for hedging volatility derivatives since they require very frequent rebalancing. Moreover, they provide limited protection in the jump-diffusion context. We study the performance of a hedging strategy for volatility swaps that establishes small, fixed positions in vanilla options at each volatility observation. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Windcliff, H.; Forsyth, P. A.; Vetzal, K. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interaction of credit and liquidity risks: Modelling and valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zheng, H.
In this paper we discuss the interaction of default risk and liquidity risk on pricing financial contracts. We show that two risks are almost indistinguishable if the underlying contract has non-negative values; however, if it can take both positive and negative values then these two risks demand different risk premiums depending on their loss rates and distributions. We discuss a structural default model and a discrete time default model with exponentially distributed liquidity shocks. We show that short-term yield spreads are dominated by liquidity risk rather than credit risk. We suggest a two-stage procedure to calibrate the model with one scalar optimization problem and one linear programming problem. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zheng, H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on the "risk-adjusted" price-concentration relationship in banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brewer, E.; Jackson, W. E.
Price-concentration studies in banking typically find a significant and negative relationship between consumer deposit rates (i.e., prices) and market concentration. This implies highly concentrated banking markets are "bad" for depositors. It also provides support for the Structure-Conduct-Performance hypothesis and rejects the Efficient-Structure hypothesis. However, these studies have focused almost exclusively on supply-side control variables and neglected demand-side variables when estimating the reduced form price-concentration relationship. For example, previous studies have not included in their analysis bank-specific risk variables as measures of cross-sectional derived deposit demand. We find that when bank-specific risk variables are included in the analysis the magnitude of the relationship between deposit rates and market concentration decreases by over 50%. We offer an explanation for these results based on the correlation between a bank's risk profile and the structure of the market in which it operates. These results suggest that it may be necessary to reconsider the well-established assumption that higher market concentration necessarily leads to anticompetitive deposit pricing behavior by commercial banks. This has direct implications for the antitrust evaluations of bank merger and acquisition proposals by regulatory agencies. And, in a more general sense, these results suggest that any Structure-Conduct-Performance based study that does not explicitly consider the possibility of very different risk profiles of the firms analyzed may indeed miss a very important set of explanatory variables. And, thus, the results from those studies may be spurious. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brewer, E.; Jackson, W. E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of intraday patterns in price clustering on the Tokyo Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ohta, W.
Stock prices tend to cluster at round numbers, a phenomenon observed in many markets. Using tick-by-tick transaction data, this article studies price clustering on the Tokyo Stock Exchange, which is a computerized limit order market. As for the intraday pattern, the degree of price clustering is greatest at the market opening. Then, it decreases during the first half hour and reaches a stable level. It does not increase again near the market closing. There is no clear difference in clustering between call auctions and continuous auctions. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ohta, W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reactions of Japanese markets to changes in credit ratings by global and local agencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, J.; Shin, Y. S.; Moore, W. T.
We examine data from the mid-1980s to 2003 to investigate whether stock prices set on the Tokyo Stock Exchange for Japanese firms react more strongly to changes in credit ratings of global rating agencies than of local agencies. This offers a strong test of relative influence of the two groups of rating agencies. We hypothesize that global raters will have more influence, but given that the two global agencies, Moody's and Standard and Poors, are headquartered in the United States, analysis of stocks of Japanese firms listed on US exchanges would confound the results to the extent there is a home bias for raters. We find that global agencies are more influential than the two major local raters, Japan Rating and Investment Information and Japan Credit Rating Agency, for rating downgrades. Thus for credit downgrades, global raters are more influential than local ones even in the local market. Consistent with previous research, we find that upgrades are benign events, and this holds true for global as well as local agencies. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, J.; Shin, Y. S.; Moore, W. T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation impact of Sarbanes-Oxley: Evidence from disclosure and governance within the financial services industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhigbe, A.; Martin, A. D.
The Sarbanes-Oxley (Sarbox) legislation aimed to reduce the opacity of financial statements and improve the integrity of financial reporting by enhancing corporate disclosure and governance practices. We estimate the valuation effects of Sarbox for fir-ins in the financial services industry and find that, except for securities firms, these firms significantly benefited from its adoption. As hypothesized, these positive effects may be attributed to expected improvement in the transparency of the relatively opaque financial services firms. We find that the cross-sectional variation in the valuation effects can be explained by disclosure and governance characteristics. Several of the significant factors are supportive of a compliance cost hypothesis. In particular, we find that the effects were less favorable for firms with less independent audit committees, without a financial expert on the audit committee, with less financial statement footnote disclosures, with less involved CEOs, and if they were smaller. In addition, reflecting the value of stronger governance, more favorable effects occurred for firms with a greater degree of independence of the board and the board committees, when there is greater motivation and ability of board members to monitor the firm, and with a greater degree of institutional ownership. Lastly, we find the wealth effects of firms viewed as non-compliant are significantly lower than firms viewed as compliant, and the variation across the group of non-compliant firms is explained by disclosure and governance measures. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akhigbe, A.; Martin, A. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposit insurance and international bank liabilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hulzinga, H.; Nicodeme, G.
This paper examines the responsiveness of external bank liabilities to deposit insurance policies for a sample of developed countries. External bank liabilities held by non-banks are found to increase after the introduction of explicit deposit insurance. Deposit insurance schemes tend to exclude interbank deposits from coverage and the response of external interbank liabilities to deposit insurance appears to be varied. Neither external non-bank nor external interbank liabilities are found to be materially affected by deposit insurance design. This suggests that international competition in the area of deposit insurance design - as possible under the EU deposit insurance directive of 1994 - would be fruitless. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hulzinga, H.; Nicodeme, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance, shareholder rights and firm diversification: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiraporn, P.; Kim, Y. S.; Davidson, W. N.; Singh, M.
Grounded in agency theory, this study investigates how the strength of shareholder rights influences the extent of firm diversification and the excess value attributable to diversification. The empirical evidence reveals that the strength of shareholder rights is inversely related to the probability to diversify. Furthermore, firms where shareholder rights are more suppressed by restrictive corporate governance suffer a deeper diversification discount. Specifically, we document a 1.1-1.4% decline in firm value for each additional governance provision imposed on shareholders. An explicit distinction is made between global and industrial diversification. Our results support agency theory as an explanation for the value reduction in diversified firms. The evidence in favor of agency theory appears to be more pronounced for industrial diversification than for global diversification. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiraporn, P.; Kim, Y. S.; Davidson, W. N.; Singh, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does stock option-based executive compensation induce risk-taking? An analysis of the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, C. R.; Steiner, T. L.; Whyte, A. M.
We investigate the relation between option-based executive compensation and market measures of risk for a sample of commercial banks during the period of 1992-2000. We show that following deregulation, banks have increasingly employed stock option-based compensation. As a result, the structure of executive compensation induces risk-taking, and the stock of option-based wealth also induces risk-taking. The results are robust across alternative risk measures, statistical methodologies, and model specifications. Overall, our results support a management risk-taking hypothesis over a managerial risk aversion hypothesis. Our results have important implications for regulators in monitoring the risk levels of banks. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, C. R.; Steiner, T. L.; Whyte, A. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economy-wide bond default rates: A maximum expected utility approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sandow, S.; Friedman, C.; Gold, M.; Chang, P.
We consider the 12-month moving average aggregate default rate of S&amp;P-rated US-bonds. We estimate the conditional probability distribution of this default rate as a function of a weighted average bond rating, a lagged default rate and a preliminary predictor that is based oil lagged new issuance. Our modeling approach is asymptotically optimal for an expected utility maximizing investor. The resulting conditional probability density is consistent with our intuition. We measure the model's performance by the out-of-sample expected utility. According to this measure, our model clearly outperforms a simple regression model, a regression model with ARMA error terms and a Poisson model. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sandow, S.; Friedman, C.; Gold, M.; Chang, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio selection using hierarchical Bayesian analysis and MCMC methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greyserman, A.; Jones, D. H.; Strawderman, W. E.
This paper contributes to portfolio selection methodology using a Bayesian forecast of the distribution of returns by stochastic approximation. New hierarchical priors oil the mean vector and covariance matrix of returns are derived and implemented. Comparison's between this approach and other Bayesian methods are studied with simulations on 25 years of historical data on global stock indices. It is demonstrated that a fully hierarchical Bayes procedure produces promising results warranting more study. We carried out a numerical optimization procedure to maximize expected utility using the MCMC (Monte Carlo Markov Chain) samples from the posterior predictive distribution. This model resulted in an extra 1.5 percentage points per year in additional portfolio performance (oil top of the Hierarchical Bayes model to estimate mu and Sigma and use the Markowitz model), which is quite a significant empirical result. This approach applies to a large class of utility functions and models for market returns. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Greyserman, A.; Jones, D. H.; Strawderman, W. E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Untitled</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szego, G.
nan</description><author>Szego, G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A value-of-information approach to measuring risk in multi-period economic activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pflug, G. C.
In this paper, we discuss measures of risk for uncertain outcomes of economic activity, which are based on the notion of the value of full information in stochastic programs. Information is measured in terms of sigma-algebras. For multi-period income streams information is represented by filtrations, i.e. sequences of sigma-algebras. The basic properties of our risk measures are multi-period coherence ("diversification decreases risk"), compound concavity ("random alternatives increase risk") and convex monotonicity ("insurance decreases risk"). (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pflug, G. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gains from structured product markets: The case of reverse-exchangeable securities (RES)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benet, B. A.; Giannetti, A.; Pissaris, S.
'' Structured products '' (SP) have recently been introduced onto organized markets in the United States. Payoffs for such financially-engineered securities typically combine stock, bond and contingent claims features. In this paper attention is focused upon reverse-exchangeable securities (RES), an important and rapidly growing segment of the American SP market. First we undertake a replication of RES payout with a linear portfolio of publicly traded securities in a simple no-arbitrage framework. It is thereby possible to estimate theoretically '' fair '' terms of issuance, and contrast these with actual terms. We conclude that there is a significant pricing bias in favor of the issuing financial institution. Credit enhancement resulting from observed positive correlation between the RES terminal payoff and issuer financial performance is proposed as explanation for the apparent pricing discrepancy. Market completeness and possible tax advantages may also play a role in SP demand and the rapid expansion of this new derivatives market. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benet, B. A.; Giannetti, A.; Pissaris, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fitting prices with a complete model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Figa-Talamanca, G.; Guerra, M. L.
The aim of this paper is to introduce some methodologies for parameter estimation in Hobson and Rogers stochastic volatility model (1998). We pay a specific attention to the so-called feedback parameter, which is shown to be crucial for the model to fit correctly the smile curve of implied volatility and we introduce different procedures for the estimation of the volatility parameters. We finally test the pricing capability of the model on market options prices on the FTSE100 and the S&amp;P500 Indexes, according to the estimation methodologies introduced. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Figa-Talamanca, G.; Guerra, M. L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes and dividend clientele: Evidence from trading and ownership structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Y. T.; Liu, Y. J.; Roll, R.; Subrahmanyam, A.
Although dividend clientele have been studied over several decades, their existence remains controversial. We study the interaction of dividends and taxes by exploiting a unique dataset from Taiwan, where the capital gains tax is zero. We find strong evidence of a clientele effect. Agents subject to high rates of taxation on dividends tend to hold stocks with lower dividends and sell (buy) stocks that raise (lower) dividends. Agents in lower tax brackets behave in the opposite manner. After legalization of repurchases in 2000, firms with higher concentrations of more heavily taxed shareholders were more apt to begin repurchase programs. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Y. T.; Liu, Y. J.; Roll, R.; Subrahmanyam, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>