<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF16</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Access to external finance: Theory and evidence on the impact of monetary policy and firm-specific characteristics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bougheas, S.; Mizen, P.; Yalcin, C.
This paper examines firms' access to bank and market finance when allowance is made for differences in firm-specific characteristics. A theoretical model determines the characteristics such as size, risk and debt that would determine firms' access to bank or market finance; these characteristics can result in greater (or lesser) tightening of credit when interest rates increase. An empirical evaluation of the predictions of the model is conducted on a large panel of UK manufacturing firms. We confirm that small, young and risky firms are more significantly affected by tight monetary conditions than large, old and secure firms. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bougheas, S.; Mizen, P.; Yalcin, C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are labor-saving technologies lowering employment in the banking industry?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fung, M. K.
Labor statistics show that the average labor hours per dollar of banking output fell by more than 30% between 1992 and 2002. The proliferation of labor-saving technologies was widely believed to be the major reason. While the first-round effect of a labor-saving technology with a given level of output is a reduction in required labor per unit of output, the second-round effect is a reduction in wage costs that will increase output. Analytically, a given type of labor-saving technology is more likely to have a positive effect on employment if the elasticity of substitution between capital and labor, the price elasticity of demand, and the cost-reducing impact of the new technology are sufficiently large. The main empirical findings of this study are that labor-saving technologies, and the spillovers of these technologies, are associated with higher firm-level employment. These results seem robust to a wide range of specifications and controls. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fung, M. K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Issue costs in the Eurobond market: The effects of market integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Melnik, A.; Nissim, D.
This study compares the issuance costs of Eurobonds before and after the completion of the Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) in 2002. We find that the introduction of the Euro has significantly reduced the issue cost of Euro-denominated bonds compared to bonds denominated in the legacy currencies. The reduction in issue cost is not due to a decrease in underwriter compensation, but rather to the elimination of underpricing (the difference between the market price after trading commences and the offering price). Underwriter fee has declined substantially after the completion of the EMU, but this decline has been offset by an increase in underwriter spread (the difference between the offering price and the guaranteed price to the issuer), leaving total underwriter compensation unchanged. The EMU is also associated with significant reductions in bond maturity and syndicate size, consistent with its expected effects on liquidity and issue costs in the Eurobond market. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Melnik, A.; Nissim, D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Immunization using a stochastic-process independent multi-factor model: The Portuguese experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bravo, J. M. V.; da Silva, C. M. P.
In this paper, we evaluate the relative immunization performance of the M-vector proposed by Nawalkha and Chambers (1997) [Nawalkha, S.K., Chambers, D.R., 1997. The M-vector model: derivation and testing of extensions to M-squared. The Journal of Portfolio Management 23, 92-98], using data for the Portuguese government debt market. Empirical results show that: (i) immunization models (single- and multi-factor) remove most of the interest rate risk underlying a more naive maturity strategy; (ii) duration-matching portfolios constrained to include the maturity bond and formed using a single-factor model provide the best immunization performance overall, particularly in highly volatile term structure environments and shorter holding periods; (iii) varying the rebalancing frequency and the investment horizon shows that these results are less robust for Portugal than for other countries. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bravo, J. M. V.; da Silva, C. M. P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment banker reputation and two-stage combination carve-outs and spin-offs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thompson, T. H.; Apilado, V.
This study examines whether investment banker reputation impacts the initial period returns of two stage combinations (carve-outs followed by spin-offs). All prior literature regarding investment banker reputation is based on single-stage events (IPOs). An analysis is conducted of all completed two-stage carve-outs/spin-offs from 1981 to 2002. Findings indicate that underwriters for two-stage combinations retain their reputation in contrast with the single-stage findings of Carter et al. [Carter, R.B., Dark, F.H., Piwowar, M.S., 2002. IPOs and underwriter reputation: Redeeming the value of reputation. Working Paper, Iowa State University] that investment bankers redeemed (cashed-in) their reputation. Also, this study finds that the Carter et al. reputation factors dominate the Loughran and Ritter [Loughran, T., Ritter, J.R., 2002. Why don't issuers get upset about leaving money on the table in IPOs? The Review of Financial Studies 15 (2), 413-443] reputation factors. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thompson, T. H.; Apilado, V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unconditional return disturbances: A non-parametric simulation approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tompkins, R. G.; D'Ecclesia, R. L.
Simulation methods are extensively used in Asset Pricing and Risk Management. The most popular of these simulation approaches, the Monte Carlo, requires model selection and parameter estimation. In addition, these approaches can be extremely computer intensive. Historical simulation has been proposed as a non-parametric alternative to Monte Carlo. This approach is limited to the historical data available. In this paper, we propose an alternative historical simulation approach. Given a historical set of data, we define a set of standardized disturbances and we generate alternative price paths by perturbing the first two moments of the original path or by reshuffling the disturbances. This approach is either totally non-parametric when constant volatility is assumed; or semi-parametric in presence of GARCH(1,1) volatility. Without a loss in accuracy, it is shown to be much more powerful in terms of computer efficiency than the Monte Carlo approach. It is also extremely simple to implement and can be an effective tool for the valuation of financial assets. We apply this approach to simulate pay off values of options on the S&amp;P 500 stock index for the period 1982-2003. To verify that this technique works, the common back-testing approach was used. The estimated values are insignificantly different from the actual S&amp;P 500 options payoff values for the observed period. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tompkins, R. G.; D'Ecclesia, R. L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of bank entry in the Japanese corporate bond underwriting market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Takaoka, S.; McKenzie, C. R.
The 1993 Japanese financial system reform allowed banks to enter the underwriting market for corporate bonds through bank-owned security subsidiaries. This paper examines empirically whether underwriting commissions and yield spreads on corporate straight bonds issued domestically fell as a result of this bank entry. The empirical results show that bank entry significantly lowers both underwriting commissions and yield spreads. Commissions charged by banks are significantly lower than those charged by investment houses. Lending and share-holding relationships between the issuer and underwriter are not important in determining commissions or yield spreads. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Takaoka, S.; McKenzie, C. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payout policy, taxes, and the relation between returns and the bid-ask spread</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gottesman, A. A.; Jacoby, G.
Recent evidence demonstrates that corporate payout policy has shifted from the nearly exclusive use of dividend payout to the inclusion of stock repurchase, primarily through open markets. This trend has been attributed to the tax advantages associated with repurchase relative to dividends. In this paper, we introduce personal taxation and stock repurchase to reexamine the relation between returns and the bid-ask spread. Our model provides insight into the nature of this relation. Tests performed using NYSE, AMEX, and NASDAQ data provide empirical support of our theoretical conclusions. We conclude that the firm's choice of payout policy influences the relation between returns and spreads. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gottesman, A. A.; Jacoby, G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discrete versus continuous state switching models for portfolio credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucas, A.; Klaassen, P.
Dynamic models for credit rating transitions are important ingredients for dynamic credit risk analyses. We compare the properties of two such models that have recently been put forward. The models mainly differ in their treatment of systematic risk, which can be modeled either using discrete states (e.g., expansion versus recession) or continuous states. It turns out that the implied asset correlations and default rate volatilities for discrete state switching models are implausibly low compared to empirical estimates from the literature. We conclude that care has to be taken when discrete state regime switching models are employed for dynamic credit risk management. As a side result of our analysis, we obtain indirect evidence that asset correlations may change over the business cycle. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lucas, A.; Klaassen, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating product market competition: Methodology and application</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kedia, S.
In oligopolies, firms behave strategically and commit to actions that elicit favorable responses from rivals. Firm actions consequently are a function of the nature of these strategic interactions. In this paper, we develop a methodology for the empirical estimation of strategic interactions in product markets. We then apply our measure of strategic interactions to CEO compensation. We use quarterly data on profits and sales from Compustat to estimate the slope of firm's reaction function. When the slope is negative and marginal profits decrease with an increase in the rival's actions the firm is classified as a strategic substitute. When the slope is positive and marginal profits increase with an increase in the rival's actions the firm is classified as a strategic complement. As predicted by theory, we find significant evidence that strategic substitutes decrease the pay for performance incentives of their CEOs. On the other hand, strategic complements significantly increase CEO pay for performance incentives. The empirical measure developed can be used to test a wide variety of strategic models. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kedia, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral-based lending in emerging markets: Evidence from Thailand</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkhoff, L.; Neuberger, D.; Suwanaporn, C.
This paper examines the role and determinants of collateral in emerging markets compared to mature ones. Analyzing a data set of 560 credit files of Thai commercial banks, we find that both the incidence and degree of collateralization are higher there than in developed markets. Thai banks use collateral primarily to reduce the higher credit risks of small and relatively young firms. Long credit relationships do not reduce collateral requirements by lowering information asymmetry. Market imperfections result from housebanks demanding higher collateral than non-housebanks, suggesting a lock-in effect for their borrowers, and from larger banks realizing higher collateral claims. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Menkhoff, L.; Neuberger, D.; Suwanaporn, C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank capital and loan asymmetry in the transmission of monetary policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kishan, R. P.; Opiela, T. P.
Utilizing a bank-lending channel framework, we investigate the effects of expansionary and contractionary policy separately on the loan behavior of low-capital and high-capital banks, and between pre-Basel/FDICIA and post-Basel/FDICIA periods. Our results show that lowcapital banks are adversely affected by contractionary policy. Expansionary policy, however, is not effective in stimulating the loan growth of low-capital banks. These results are consistent with lending channel predictions, but only hold in the post-Basel/FDICIA period when the capital constraint is stringent relative to the pre-Basel/FDICIA period. These asymmetric policy results have implications for the interaction of monetary and capital regulatory policies. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kishan, R. P.; Opiela, T. P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integrating market and credit risk: A simulation and optimisation perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jobst, N. J.; Mitra, G.; Zenios, S. A.
We introduce a modelling paradigm which integrates credit risk and market risk in describing the random dynamical behaviour of the underlying fixed income assets. We then consider an asset and liability management (ALM) problem and develop a multistage stochastic programming model which focuses on optimum risk decisions. These models exploit the dynamical multiperiod structure of credit risk and provide insight into the corrective recourse decisions whereby issues such as the timing risk of default is appropriately taken into consideration. We also present an index tracking model in which risk is measured (and optimised) by the CVaR of the tracking portfolio in relation to the index. In-sample as well as out-of-sample (backtesting) experiments are undertaken to validate our approach. The main benefits of backtesting, that is, ex-post analysis are that (a) we gain insight into asset allocation decisions, and (b) we are able to demonstrate the feasibility and flexibility of the chosen framework. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jobst, N. J.; Mitra, G.; Zenios, S. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysis of criteria VaR and CVaR</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kibzun, A. I.; Kuznetsov, E. A.
Criteria VaR (Value-at-Risk) and CVaR (Conditional Value-at-Risk), which are well-known in financial mathematics, are compared. Some connection between them is established. Ways of choice a level of confidence probability for the quantile optimization problem are suggested. The ways are based on some equations of balance between VaR and CVaR. Examples are discussed. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kibzun, A. I.; Kuznetsov, E. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Master funds in portfolio analysis with general deviation measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rockafellar, R. T.; Uryasev, S.; Zabarankin, M.
Generalized measures of deviation are considered as substitutes for standard deviation in a framework like that of classical portfolio theory for coping with the uncertainty inherent in achieving rates of return beyond the risk-free rate. Such measures, derived for example from conditional value-at-risk and its variants, can reflect the different attitudes of different classes of investors. They lead nonetheless to generalized one-fund theorems in which a more customized version of portfolio optimization is the aim, rather than the idea that a single "master fund" might arise from market equilibrium and serve the interests of all investors. The results that are obtained cover discrete distributions along with continuous distributions. They are applicable therefore to portfolios involving derivatives, which create jumps in distribution functions at specific gain or loss values, well as to financial models involving finitely many scenarios. Furthermore, they deal rigorously with issues that come up at that level of generality, but have not received adequate attention, including possible lack of differentiability of the deviation expression with respect to the portfolio weights, and the potential nonuniqueness of optimal weights. The results also address in detail the phenomenon that if the risk-free rate lies above a certain threshold, the usually envisioned master fund Must be replaced by one of alternative type, representing a "net short position" instead of a "net long position" in the risky instruments. For nonsymmetric deviation measures, the second type need not just be the reverse of the first type, and there can sometimes even be an interval for the risk-free rate in which no master fund of either type exists. A notion of basic fund, in place of master fund, is brought in to get around this difficulty and serve as a single guide to optimality regardless of such circumstances. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rockafellar, R. T.; Uryasev, S.; Zabarankin, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment and financing activity following calls of convertible bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alderson, M. J.; Betker, B. L.; Stock, D. R.
The staged financing hypothesis of Mayers [Mayers, D., 1998. Why firms issue convertible bonds: The matching of financial and real investment options. Journal of Financial Economics 47, 83-102] predicts that investment and financing activity will increase following in the money convertible bond calls. The prediction for out of the money convertible calls is different: no increase is expected. We study the rate of both corporate investment and external financing around forced conversions using benchmarks that are analogous to those recommended by Barber and Lyon [Barber, B., Lyon, J., 1996. Detecting abnormal operating performance: The empirical power and specification of test statistics. Journal of Financial Economics 41, 359-400]. We also examine the cross-section of changes in investment and financing activity. Conversion-forcing firms exhibit an increase in both capital expenditures and debt financing around the year of the convertible bond call; however, the same result holds for the sample firms that conducted out-of-the-money convertible calls. Further, there is no relation between changes in investment activity and changes in debt issuance at the firm level. The evidence is inconsistent with the notion that forced conversions serve as a catalyst for staged financing and investment. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alderson, M. J.; Betker, B. L.; Stock, D. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comprehensive analysis of the short-term interest-rate dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, T. G.; Wu, L. R.
This paper provides a comprehensive analysis of the short-term interest-rate dynamics based on three different data sets and two flexible parametric specifications. The significance of nonlinearity in the short-rate drift declines with increasing maturity for the interest-rate series used in the study. Using a flexible diffusion specification and incorporating GARCH volatility and non-normal innovation reduce the need for a nonlinear drift specification. Finally, the nonlinear drift specification performs better than the linear drift specification only when the short-term interest-rate levels reach historical highs. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, T. G.; Wu, L. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic benefit of powerful credit scoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blochlinger, A.; Leippold, M.
We study the economic benefits from using credit scoring models. We contribute to the literature by relating the discriminatory power of a credit scoring model to the optimal credit decision. Given the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve, we derive (a) the profit-maximizing cutoff and (b) the pricing curve. Using these two concepts and a mixture thereof, we study a stylized loan market model with banks differing in the quality of their credit scoring model. Even for small quality differences, the variation in profitability among lenders is large and economically significant. We end our analysis by quantifying the impact on profits when information leaks from a competitor's scoring model into the market. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blochlinger, A.; Leippold, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium exchange rates in Central and Eastern Europe: A meta-regression analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balazs, E.; Halpern, L.
This paper analyses the ever-growing literature on equilibrium exchange rates in the new EU member states of Central and Eastern Europe in a quantitative manner using meta-regression analysis. The results indicate that the real misalignments reported in the literature are systematically influenced, inter alia, by the underlying theoretical concepts (Balassa-Samuelson effect, behavioral equilibrium exchange rate, fundamental equilibrium exchange rate) and by the econometric estimation methods. The important implication of these findings is that a systematic analysis is needed in terms of both alternative economic and econometric specifications to assess equilibrium exchange rates. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balazs, E.; Halpern, L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection and the liquidity of cross-listed securities: Evidence from the ADR market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, H. M.
Using 'American depository receipt' (ADR) data on various countries, this paper sets out to investigate the relationship between investor protection and firm liquidity. Since weak investor protection leads to greater expropriation by managers, and thus greater asymmetric information costs, liquidity providers will incur relatively higher costs and will therefore offer higher bid-ask spreads. The empirical results demonstrate that the liquidity costs of poor investor protection were more significant during the period of the Asian financial crisis when the expected agency costs were particularly severe. This issue is further analyzed by investigating whether there is any evidence of increases in the vulnerability of ADRs of firms operating in countries with relatively poor investor protection mechanisms during periods of financial crisis. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, H. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary transmission via the administered interest rates channel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chong, B. S.; Liu, M. H.; Shrestha, K.
This paper examines the dynamics of administered interest rate changes in response to changes in the benchmark money market rate in Singapore. Our results show that the administered rates' adjustment speed differs across both financial institutions and financial products. The financial institutions' administered (lending and deposit) rates, moreover, are more rigid when they are below their equilibrium level than when they are above. Our finding, hence, implies that the speed of monetary transmission is not uniform across all sectors of the economy and that a tightening monetary policy takes a longer time to impact the economy than an expansionary monetary policy. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chong, B. S.; Liu, M. H.; Shrestha, K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of macroeconomic and regulatory factors on bank efficiency: A non-parametric analysis of Hong Kong's banking system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drake, L.; Hall, M. J. B.; Simper, R.
This paper assesses the relative technical efficiency of institutions operating in a market that has been significantly affected by environmental and market factors in recent years, the Hong Kong banking system. These environmental factors are specifically incorporated into the efficiency analysis using the innovative slacks-based, second stage Tobit regression approach advocated by Fried et al. [Fried, H.O., Schmidt, S.S., Yaisawarng, S., 1999. Incorporating the operating environment into a nonparametric measure of technical efficiency. Journal of Productivity Analysis 12, 249-267]. A further innovation is that we also employ Tone's [Tone, K., 2001. A slacks-based measure of efficiency in data envelopment analysis. European Journal of Operational Research 130, 498-509] slacks-based model (SBM) to conduct the data envelopment analysis (DEA), in addition to the more traditional approach attributable to Banker, Charnes and Cooper (BCC) [Banker, R.D., Charnes, A., Cooper, W.W., 1984. Some models for estimating technical and scale efficiencies in data envelopment analysis. Management Science 30, 1078-1092]. The results indicate: high levels of technical inefficiency for many institutions; considerable variations in efficiency levels and trends across size groups and banking sectors; and also differential impacts of environmental factors on different size groups and financial sectors. Surprisingly, the accession of Hong Kong to the People's Republic of China, episodes of financial deregulation, and the 1997/1998 South East Asian crisis do not seem to have had a significant independent impact on relative efficiency. However, the results suggest that the impact of the last-mentioned may have come via the adverse developments in the macroeconomy and in the housing market. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Drake, L.; Hall, M. J. B.; Simper, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure policies in Europe: Survey evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brounen, D.; De Jong, A.; Koedijk, K.
In this paper we present the results of an international survey among 313 CFOs on capital structure choice. We document several interesting insights on how theoretical concepts are being applied by professionals in the UK, the Netherlands, Germany, and France and we directly compare our results with previous findings from the US our results emphasize the presence of pecking-order behavior. At the same time this behavior is not driven by asymmetric information considerations. The static trade-off theory is confirmed by the importance of a target debt ratio in general, but also specifically by tax effects and bankruptcy costs. Overall, we find remarkably low disparities across countries, despite the presence of significant institutional differences. We find that private firms differ in many respects from publicly listed firms, e.g. listed firms use their stock price for the timing of new issues. Finally, we do not find substantial evidence that agency problems are important in capital structure choice. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brounen, D.; De Jong, A.; Koedijk, K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are labour markets in the new member states sufficiently flexible for EMU?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boeri, T.; Garibaldi, P.
New Member States (NMS) coming from central planning are often advised against early Euro adoption because of their rigid labour markets. But are labour markets so rigid in these countries? We argue in this paper that this is not the case. Labour market institutions are no more "rigid" than among current EMU Members whilst wage bargaining institutions are actually better equipped for microeconomic wage flexibility than in the EU-15. NMS also achieved substantial reallocation of jobs and workers in the transition to markets, display relatively large job turnover rates and are reducing their regional mismatch. The view that NMS have rigid labour markets is fuelled by the low job content of growth in the region. But there is evidence that the latter is related to productivity enhancing job destruction in the aftermath of prolonged labour hoarding. Reduced-form employment equations estimated in this paper also suggest that tight fiscal policies, rather than being harmful to job creation, may actually improve the employment performance of the region. Our interpretation of this result is that loose fiscal policies weaken the confidence of investors and crowd-out private employment growth through generous pay rises to civil servants. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boeri, T.; Garibaldi, P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange rate pass-through in EMU acceding countries: Empirical analysis and policy implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coricelli, F.; Jazbec, B.; Masten, I.
Countries that joined the European Union in 2004 have to decide when to adopt the Euro. This decision depends on the evaluation of the relative costs and benefits associated with giving up the exchange rate instrument. Recent empirical work on several new EU members has questioned the role of the exchange rate as a shock absorber, thus downplaying the potential costs in terms of macroeconomic stabilization. In this paper, we address the issue from a different perspective, emphasizing the role of pass-through from exchange rate to domestic inflation in new EU members. The focus is on four countries (Czech Republic, Hungary, Poland and Slovenia -NM-4) that have adopted some form of floating or managed exchange rate regimes. The paper reports empirical results indicating high pass-through coefficients and links them to the degree of policy accommodation. High exchange rate pass-through in NM-4 indicates that stabilization of nominal exchange rates would lower inflationary pressures and help fulfill criteria to enter the EMU. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coricelli, F.; Jazbec, B.; Masten, I.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The IMF in a world of private capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eichengreen, B.; Kletzer, K.; Mody, A.
In analyzing the IMF attempts to stabilize private capital flows, we contrast cases where banks and bondholders do the lending. Consistent with banks' natural advantage in monitoring, they reduce spreads as they obtain more information through repeat transactions with borrowers. By comparison, repeat borrowing has little influence in bond markets, where publicly-available information dominates. But spreads on bonds are lower when they are issued in conjunction with an IMF-supported program, as if the existence of a program conveys positive information to bondholders. The influence of IMF monitoring in bond markets is especially pronounced for countries vulnerable to liquidity crises. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eichengreen, B.; Kletzer, K.; Mody, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy issues relevant to transition and emerging market economies - Papers from the 10th Dubrovnik Economic Conference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wachtel, P.
nan</description><author>Wachtel, P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downside risk and asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Post, T.; van Vliet, P.
We analyze if the value-weighted stock market portfolio is stochastic dominance (SD) efficient relative to benchmark portfolios formed on size, value, and momentum. In the process, we also develop several methodological improvements to the existing tests for SD efficiency. Interestingly, the market portfolio seems third-order SD(TSD) efficient relative to all benchmark sets. By contrast, the market portfolio is inefficient if we replace the TSD criterion with the traditional mean-variance criterion. Combined these results suggest that the mean-variance inefficiency of the market portfolio is caused by the omission of return moments other than variance. Especially downside risk seems to be important for explaining the high average returns of small/value/winner stocks. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Post, T.; van Vliet, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity risk in securities settlement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Devriese, J.; Mitchell, J.
This paper studies the potential impact on securities settlement systems (SSSs) of a major market disruption, caused by the default of the largest player. A multi-period, multi-security model with intraday credit is used to simulate direct and second-round settlement failures triggered by the default, as well as the dynamics of settlement failures, arising from a lag in settlement relative to the date of trades. The effects of the defaulter's net trade position, the numbers of securities and participants in the market, and participants' trading behavior are also analyzed. We show that in SSSs - contrary to payment systems - large and persistent settlement failures are possible even when ample liquidity is provided. Central bank liquidity support to SSSs thus cannot eliminate settlement failures due to major market disruptions. This is due to the fact that securities transactions involve a cash leg and a securities leg, and liquidity can affect only the cash side of a transaction. Whereas a broad program of securities borrowing and lending might help, it is precisely during periods of market disruption that participants will be least willing to lend securities. Settlement failures can continue to occur beyond the period corresponding to the lag in settlement. This is due to the fact that, upon observation of a default, market participants must form expectations about the impact of the default, and these expectations affect current trading behavior. If, ex post, fewer of the previous trades settle than expected, new settlement failures will occur. This result has interesting implications for financial stability. On the one hand, conservative reactions by market participants to a default - for example by limiting the volume of trades - can result in a more rapid return of the settlement system to a normal level of efficiency. On the other hand, limitation of trading by market participants can reduce market liquidity, which may have a negative impact on financial stability. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Devriese, J.; Mitchell, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economies of scale and technological development in securities depository and settlement systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmiedel, H.; Malkamaki, M.; Tarkka, J.
This paper investigates the existence and extent of economies of scale in depository and settlement systems. Evidence from 16 settlement institutions across different regions for the years 1993-2000 indicates the existence of significant economies of scale. The degree of such economies, however, differs by size of settlement institution and region. While smaller settlement service providers reveal a high potential of economies for scale, larger institutions show an increasing trend toward cost effectiveness. Clearing and settlement systems in countries in Europe and Asia report substantially larger economies of scale than those of the US system. European cross-border settlement seems to be more cost intensive than that on a domestic level, reflecting chiefly complexities of EU international securities settlement systems and differences in the scope of international settlement service providers. The evidence also reveals that investments in implementing new systems and upgrades of settlement technology continuously improved cost effectiveness over the sample period. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schmiedel, H.; Malkamaki, M.; Tarkka, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining cross-border large-value payment flows: Evidence from TARGET and EURO1 data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosati, S.; Secola, S.
We analysed the distribution of the TARGET cross-border interbank payment flows from both a cross-section and a time-series point of view using average daily data for the period 1999-2002. Our findings were, first, that "location matters" in the sense that bilateral payment flows seem to reflect an organisation of interbank trading between countries in which the size of the banking sector, geographic proximity and cultural similarities play a significant role. This result was also confirmed by a model developed drawing on the gravity models literature. Second, we found that the payment traffic in TARGET is strongly affected by technical market deadlines. In addition, such traffic is positively related mainly to the liquidity conditions and to the turnover of the euro area money market (particularly the unsecured overnight segment). Our model also provides a good explanation of the determinants of the interbank payments settled in the EURO 1 system. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rosati, S.; Secola, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolution of international stock and bond market integration: Influence of the European Monetary Union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, S. J.; Moshirian, F.; Wu, E.
This paper examines the dynamic relationship between daily stock and government bond returns of selected countries over the past decade to infer the state and progress of inter-financial market integration. We proceed to empirically investigate the influence of the European Monetary Union (EMU) on time variations in inter-stock-bond market integration/segmentation dynamics using a two-step procedure: First, we document the downward trends in time-varying conditional correlations between stock and bond market returns in European countries, Japan and the US. Second, we investigate the causality and determinants of this interdependent relationship, in particular, whether the various macroeconomic convergence criteria associated with the EMU have played a significant role. We find that real economic integration and the reduction in currency risk have generally had the desired effect on financial integration but monetary policy integration may have created uncertain investor sentiments on the economic future of the EMU, thereby stimulating a flight to quality phenomenon. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, S. J.; Moshirian, F.; Wu, E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time and dynamic volume-volatility relation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, X. Q. E.; Chen, P.; Wu, C. C.
This paper examines volume and volatility dynamics by accounting for market activity measured by the time duration between two consecutive transactions. A time-consistent vector autoregressive (VAR) model is employed to test the dynamic relationship between return volatility and trades using intraday irregularly spaced transaction data. The model is used to identify the informed and uninformed components of return volatility and to estimate the speed of price adjustment to new information. It is found that volatility and volume are persistent and highly correlated with past volatility and volume. The time duration between trades has a negative effect on the volatility response to trades and correlation between trades. Consistent with microstructure theory, shorter time duration between trades implies higher probability of news arrival and higher volatility. Furthermore, bid-ask spreads are serially dependent and strongly affected by the informed trading and inventory costs. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xu, X. Q. E.; Chen, P.; Wu, C. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International corporate investment and the relationships between financial constraint measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cleary, S.
This paper uses international panel data to examine the interrelationships among some commonly used measures of financial constraint. The analysis reveals the following insights: (1) firms with stronger financial positions are more investment-cash flow sensitive than firms with weaker financial positions even after controlling for size and dividend payout and (2) higher payout firms are more investment-cash flow sensitive than lower payout firms even after controlling for size and financial strength. Evidence regarding the impact of firm size that is documented originally becomes much weaker once financial health and dividend payout behavior are controlled for. Finally, additional analysis reveals that many of these results may be driven by the fact that firms possessing high cash flow volatility display lower investment-cash flow sensitivities. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cleary, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank concentration, competition, and crises: First results</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, T.; Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Levine, R.
Motivated by public policy debates about bank consolidation and conflicting theoretical predictions about the relationship between bank concentration, bank competition and banking system fragility, this paper studies the impact of national bank concentration, bank regulations, and national institutions on the likelihood of a country suffering a systemic banking crisis. Using data on 69 countries from 1980 to 1997, we find that crises are less likely in economies with more concentrated banking systems even after controlling for differences in commercial bank regulatory policies, national institutions affecting competition, macroeconomic conditions, and shocks to the economy. Furthermore, the data indicate that regulatory policies and institutions that thwart competition are associated with greater banking system fragility. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, T.; Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Levine, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging volatility risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brenner, M.; Ou, E. Y.; Zhang, J. E.
Volatility risk plays an important role in the management of portfolios of derivative assets as well as portfolios of basic assets. This risk is currently managed by volatility "swaps" or futures. However, this risk could be managed more efficiently using options on volatility that were proposed in the past but were never introduced mainly due to the lack of a cost efficient tradable underlying asset. The objective of this paper is to introduce a new volatility instrument, an option on a straddle, which can be used to hedge volatility risk. The design and valuation of such an instrument are the basic ingredients of a successful financial product. In order to value these options, we combine the approaches of compound options and stochastic volatility. Our numerical results show that the straddle option is a powerful instrument to hedge volatility risk. An additional benefit of such an innovation is that it will provide a direct estimate of the market price for volatility risk. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brenner, M.; Ou, E. Y.; Zhang, J. E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inferring the default rate in a population by comparing two incomplete default databases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dwyer, D. W.; Stein, R. M.
It is often the case in default modeling that the need arises to calibrate a model to some prior probability of default. In many situations, a researcher may not know the true prior default rate for the population because the data set at hand is itself incomplete, either with respect to default identification (hidden defaults) or default under reporting. In situations where a researcher has access to two incomplete default data sets, for example in the case of two banks that have merged, it is possible to infer the number of "missing" defaults, which we demonstrate in this short note. We discuss an approach to estimating this quantity and show an example in which we infer the number of missing defaults in the combined legacy databases of the former Moody's Risk Management Services and the former KMV Corporation. While calibration is one application of this approach, the method is a general one that can be applied in other settings as well. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dwyer, D. W.; Stein, R. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special Section: Aspects of International Financial Services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, F.
nan</description><author>Moshirian, F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aspects of international financial services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, F.
The purpose of this paper is to discuss the issues related to international financial services, particularly foreign direct investment in banking. The paper discusses the challenges of measuring incomes generated from the activities or multinational banks, including their international lending and direct investment in host countries. The paper highlights the complementary role of FDI and trade in financial services and discusses investment in banking services. The patterns of FDI in banking in Eastern European countries, Latin America and East Asia are also analysed with a focus on the costs and benefits of FDI in banking in the emerging countries. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure and firm performance: A new approach to testing agency theory and an application to the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, A. N.; di Patti, E. B.
Corporate governance theory predicts that leverage affects agency costs and thereby influences firm performance. We propose a new approach to test this theory using profit efficiency, or how close a firm's profits are to the benchmark of a best-practice firm facing the same exogenous conditions. We are also the first to employ a simultaneous-equations model that accounts for reverse causality from performance to capital structure. We find that data on the US banking industry are consistent with the theory, and the results are statistically significant, economically significant, and robust. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Berger, A. N.; di Patti, E. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank portfolio exposure to emerging markets and its effects on bank market value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fissel, G. S.; Goldberg, L.; Hanweck, G. A.
This study estimates a model of banking company equity returns taking into consideration book value and market value measures of their exposure to emerging markets debt. In this estimation, general systematic market factors, such as the rate of return on the S&amp;P500 stock index and yields on a constant maturity 5-year Treasury note, are held constant such that the exposure variables are accounting for effects due to banks' exposure to emerging market debt. The results, although not uniform among banking companies, support the hypothesis that the extent of exposure to emerging market debt are factored into the valuation of banking company equity contemporaneously. The inclusion of a market value indicator adds to the explanation of equity returns of some banks. It is also clear that knowing the extent of the exposure on a book value basis is important information alone that may allow investors to take account of or evaluate the effects of changes in banking company equity valuation from LDC debt exposures. We also perform an event study for three major debt crises to determine whether the market recognizes the effects of these events on bank valuation. The event study results show that there is little information from identifying the time period of the crises on banking company equity returns. Explanations for this are that the information of these possible crises has been embedded in bank changes in exposure and that the market valuation of the emerging market debt is already accounted for by our model. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fissel, G. S.; Goldberg, L.; Hanweck, G. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The X-efficiency of commercial banks in Hong Kong</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kwan, S. H.
Using the stochastic frontier approach to investigate the cost efficiency of commercial banks in Hong Kong, this paper found that the average X-efficiency of Hong Kong banks was about 16-30% of observed total costs. However, X-efficiency was found to decline over time, indicating that Hong Kong banks were operating closer to the cost frontier than before, consistent with technological innovations in the banking industry. Furthermore, the average large bank was found to be less efficient than the average small bank, but the size effect appears to be related to differences in portfolio characteristics among different size banks. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kwan, S. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real effective exchange rate volatility and growth: A framework to measure advantages of flexibility vs. costs of volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bagella, M.; Beechetti, L.; Hasan, I.
By devising a real effective exchange rate (REER) index where bilateral exchange rates are weighted for relative trade shares, we find that the REER volatility (differently from the bilateral exchange rate volatility with the dollar) has significant impact oil growth of per capita income after controlling for other variables traditionally considered in conditional convergence estimates. We also find that this (cost of volatility) effect can be reconciled with the concurring negative and significant effect on growth of the adoption of a fixed exchange rate regime (advantage of flexibility effect), where the latter may be also interpreted as the cost of choosing pegged regimes without harmonization of rules and macroeconomic policies with main trading partners. The adoption of an REER volatility measure, instead of a bilateral exchange rate with the dollar, has the advantage of making it possible a joint test for these two effects. This is because, while fixed exchange rate regimes are strongly negatively correlated, and almost collinear, with bilateral exchange rate volatility with the dollar, the correlation is much weaker when considering our REER volatility measure. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bagella, M.; Beechetti, L.; Hasan, I.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear term structure dependence: Copula functions, empirics, and risk implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Junker, M.; Szimayer, A.; Wagner, N.
This paper documents nonlinear cross-sectional dependence in the term structure of US-Treasury yields and points out risk management implications. The analysis is based on a Kalman filter estimation of a two-factor affine model which specifies the yield curve dynamics. We then apply a broad class of copula functions for modeling dependence in factors spanning the yield curve. Our sample of monthly yields in the 1982-2001 period provides evidence of upper tail dependence in yield innovations; i.e., large positive interest rate shocks tend to occur under increased dependence. In contrast, the best-fitting copula model coincides with zero lower tail dependence. This asymmetry has substantial risk management implications. We give an example in estimating bond portfolio loss quantiles and report the biases which result from an application of the normal dependence model. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Junker, M.; Szimayer, A.; Wagner, N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A further look at household portfolio choice and health status</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkowitz, M. K.; Qlu, J. P.
This paper investigates the effect of changes in health status on household financial wealth and financial portfolio choice. It is shown that the impact of health events on household financial and non-financial wealth is asymmetric. A diagnosis of a new disease leads to a larger decrease in financial wealth than in non-financial wealth. Moreover, we find that the puzzle pertaining to the relationship between health status and portfolio choice discussed in the extant literature generally disappears after controlling for differences in the amount of financial assets held by healthy and sick people. The results suggest that the effect of changes in health status on household financial portfolios is indirect. A health shock significantly reduces household total financial wealth, in turn leading households to restructure the composition of their financial assets. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berkowitz, M. K.; Qlu, J. P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank loan losses-given-default: A case study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dermine, J.; de Carvalho, C. N.
The empirical literature on credit risk has relied mostly on the corporate bond market to estimate losses in the event of default. The reason for this is that, as bank loans are private instruments, few data on loan losses are publicly available. The contribution of this paper is to apply mortality analysis to a unique set of micro-data oil defaulted bank loans of a European bank. The empirical results relate to the timing of recoveries oil bad and doubtful bank loans, the distribution of cumulative recovery rates, their economic determinants and the direct costs incurred by that bank on recoveries on bad and doubtful loans. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dermine, J.; de Carvalho, C. N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging the value of waiting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyle, G. W.; Guthrie, G. A.
We analyze the optimal hedging policy of a firm that has flexibility in the timing of investment. Conventional wisdom suggests that hedging adds value by alleviating the under-investment problem associated with capital market frictions. However, our model shows that hedging also adds value by allowing investment to be delayed in circumstances where the same frictions would cause it to commence prematurely. Thus, hedging can have the paradoxical effect of reducing investment. We also show that greater timing flexibility increases the optimal quantity of hedging, but has a non-monotonic effect on the additional value created by hedging. These results may help explain the empirical findings that investment rates do not differ between hedgers and non-hedgers, and that hedging propensities do not depend on standard measures of growth opportunities. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boyle, G. W.; Guthrie, G. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure and political patronage: The case of Malaysia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fraser, D. R.; Zhang, H.; Derashid, C.
This paper extends prior work on the links between political patronage and capital structure in developing economics. Three proxies of political patronage are developed and applied to a group of Malaysian firms over a 10-year period. We find a positive and significant link between leverage and each of the three measures of political patronage. We also find evidence of an indirect link between political patronage and capital structure through firm size and profitability. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fraser, D. R.; Zhang, H.; Derashid, C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spanish Treasury bond market liquidity and volatility pre- and post-European Monetary Union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diaz, A.; Merrick, J. J.; Navarro, E.
Spain enacted a number of important debt management initiatives in 1997 to prepare its Treasury bond market for European Monetary Union. We interpret the impacts of these changes through shifts in a bond liquidity "life cycle" function. Furthermore, we highlight the importance of expected average future liquidity in explaining Spanish bond liquidity premiums. We also uncover pricing biases that support the Spanish. Treasury's tactical decision to target high-coupon, premium bonds in its pre-EMU debt exchanges. Finally, we show that EMU has been associated with both it decrease in bond yield volatility and all increase in pricing efficiency. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Diaz, A.; Merrick, J. J.; Navarro, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio implications of systemic crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kole, Erik; Koedijk, Kees; Verbeek, Marno
Systemic crises can have grave consequences for investors in international equity markets, because they cause the risk-return trade-off to deteriorate severely for a longer period. We propose a novel approach to include the possibility of systemic crises in asset allocation decisions. By combining regime switching models with Merton [Merton, R.C., 1969. Lifetime portfolio selection under uncertainty: The continuous time case. Review of Economics and Statistics 51, 247-257]-style portfolio construction, our approach captures persistence of crises much better than existing models. Our analysis shows that incorporating systemic crises greatly affects asset allocation decisions, while the costs of ignoring them is substantial. For an expected utility maximizing US investor, who can invest globally these costs range from 1.13% per year of his initial wealth when he has no prior information on the likelihood of a crisis, to over 3% per month if a crisis occurs with almost certainty. If a crisis is taken into account, the investor allocates less to risky assets, and particularly less to the crisis prone emerging markets. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kole, Erik; Koedijk, Kees; Verbeek, Marno</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on efficiency and productivity growth in the Korean Banking Industry, 1992-2002</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Kang H.; Weber, William L.
In this paper we present estimates of Korean bank inefficiency and productivity change for the period 1992-2002 that are derived from the directional technology distance function. Our method controls for loan losses that are an undesirable by-product arising from the production of loans and allows the aggregation of individual bank inefficiency and productivity growth to the industry level. Our findings indicate that technical progress during the period was more than enough to offset efficiency declines so that the banking industry experienced productivity growth. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Park, Kang H.; Weber, William L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A pioneer in Finance: Marshall Sarnat, 1929-2006 - Obituary</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szego, Giorgio
nan</description><author>Szego, Giorgio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of heterogeneous risk on the early adoption of Internet banking technologies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauer, Keldon; Hein, Scott E.
Financial service providers have increasingly offered customers new remote access to such services, with Internet banking being the latest example. While Internet banking has been available for years, the early adoption by customers of this technology was disappointing to most. This paper examines the demand for remote access to banking accounts by consumers and finds that when the technology is new, the traditional risk return models including variables allowing for heterogeneous risk add power in modeling the adoption decision. Perceived risks in Internet banking are seen to be responsible for some of the hesitation to adopt. Ironically, older consumers are found to be less likely to adopt Internet banking regardless of their risk tolerances. However, younger consumers are found to be early adopters only when they have relatively high levels of risk tolerance. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bauer, Keldon; Hein, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How to fend off shoulder surfing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roth, V.; Richter, K.
Magnetic stripe cards are in common use for electronic payments and cash withdrawal. Reported incidents document that criminals easily pickpocket cards or skim them by swiping them through additional card readers. Personal identification numbers (PINs) are obtained by shoulder surfing, through the use of mirrors or concealed miniature cameras. Both elements, the PIN and the card, are generally sufficient to give the criminal full access to the victim's account. In this paper, we present alternative PIN entry methods to which we refer as cognitive trapdoor games. These methods make it significantly harder for a criminal to obtain PINs even if he fully observes the entire input and output of a PIN entry procedure. We also introduce the idea of probabilistic cognitive trapdoor games, which offer resilience to shoulder surfing even if the criminal records a PIN entry procedure with a camera. We studied the security as well as the usability of our methods. The result support the hypothesis that our primary mechanism strikes a balance between security and usability that is of practical value. In this article, we give a detailed account of our mechanisms and their evaluation. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roth, V.; Richter, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation ratios and price deviations from fundamentals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coakley, Jerry; Fuertes, Ana-Maria
This paper sheds light on US stock price deviations from fundamentals by analyzing the time-series dynamics of post-1870 S&amp;P valuation ratios. It employs a non-linear, two-regime framework that allows for different behavior over phases of the stock market cycle. Persistence in the ratios implies prolonged price deviations from fundamentals stemming from short run continuation fueled by investor sentiment during bull markets. However, the pull from fundamentals ensures that valuation ratios and prices move toward their equilibrium levels in bear markets. Impulse response functions highlight sluggish adjustment and indicate that the effects of positive shocks are more pronounced and long-lasting in bull markets. The main conclusion is that, while market sentiment plays an important transitory role, valuation ratios do mean revert and so prices reflect fundamentals in the long run. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coakley, Jerry; Fuertes, Ana-Maria</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Candlestick technical trading strategies: Can they create value for investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marshall, Ben R.; Young, Martin R.; Rose, Lawrence C.
We conduct the first robust study of the oldest known form of technical analysis, candlestick charting. Candlestick technical analysis is a short-term timing technique that generates signals based on the relationship between open, high, low, and close prices. Using an extension of the bootstrap methodology, which allows for the generation of random open, high, low and close prices, we find that candlestick trading strategies do not have value for Dow Jones Industrial Average (DJIA) stocks. This is further evidence that this market is informationally efficient. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marshall, Ben R.; Young, Martin R.; Rose, Lawrence C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Confidence intervals for probabilities of default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanson, Samuel; Schuermann, Til
In this paper we conduct a systematic comparison of confidence intervals around estimated probabilities of default (PD) using several analytical approaches as well as parametric and nonparametric bootstrap methods. We do so for two different PD estimation methods, cohort and duration (intensity), with 22 years of credit ratings data. We find that the bootstrapped intervals for the duration-based estimates are relatively tight when compared to either analytic or bootstrapped intervals around the less efficient cohort estimator. We show how the large differences between the point estimates and confidence intervals of these two estimators are consistent with non-Markovian migration behavior. Surprisingly, even with these relatively tight confidence intervals, it is impossible to distinguish notch-level PDs for investment grade ratings, e.g. a PDAA- from a PDA+. However, Once the speculative grade barrier is crossed, we are able to distinguish quite cleanly notch-level estimated PDs. Conditioning on the state of the business cycle helps: it is easier to distinguish adjacent PDs in recessions than in expansions. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanson, Samuel; Schuermann, Til</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the short-term predictability of exchange rates: A BVAR time-varying parameters approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarantis, Nicholas
In this paper we propose a Bayesian vector autoregressive model with time-varying parameters (BVAR-TVP) to examine the short-term predictability of exchange rates. An important contribution of the paper is the application of the BVAR-TVP model, for the first time, to daily data using information from financial markets. Another contribution is the production of forecasts in real time at the very short horizon of one-trading day-ahead typically used by traders and investors in financial markets. We employ financial criteria and recently developed statistical tests to assess the exchange rate predictability. We find that the BVAR-TVP model outperforms the random walk for all exchange rates. These forecast gains are due primarily to the time-variation of coefficients, and secondly to information from other financial markets. It is shown that international investors could have made statistically significant excess profits if they had followed an inter-day trading strategy based on the buy/sell signals generated by the model's one-day-ahead exchange rate forecasts, even after allowing for transaction costs and risk factors. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sarantis, Nicholas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital regulation, heterogeneous monitoring costs, and aggregate loan quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kopecky, Kenneth J.; VanHoose, David
This paper develops a banking-sector framework with heterogeneous loan monitoring costs. Banks are exposed to the moral hazard behavior of borrowers and endogenously choose whether to monitor their loans to eliminate this exposure. After analyzing an unregulated banking system, we examine several cases in which regulatory capital requirements bind the notional loan supplies of various subsets of banks. To gauge the impact of capital requirements, we define loan 'quality' in terms of either the ratio of monitored to total loans or the ratio of monitoring banks to total bank population. Under the assumption of a specific cross-sectional distribution of banks, our simulations show that the imposition of binding capital requirements on a previously unregulated banking system unambiguously increases the market loan rate and reduces aggregate lending, but has an ambiguous effect on loan 'quality'. Nevertheless, once capital requirements are in place, the simulations indicate that regulators can contribute to higher overall loan 'quality' by toughening capital requirements. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kopecky, Kenneth J.; VanHoose, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factor based index tracking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corielli, Francesco; Marcellino, Massimillano
Stock index tracking requires to build a portfolio of stocks (a replica) whose behavior is as close as possible to that of a given stock index. Typically, much fewer stocks should appear in the replica than in the index, and there should be no low frequency or integrated (persistent) components in the tracking error. The latter property is not satisfied by many commonly used methods for index tracking. These are based on the in-sample minimization of a loss function, but do not take into account the dynamic properties of the index components. Moreover, most existing methods do not take into account the known structure of the index weight system. In this paper we represent the index components with a dynamic factor model. In this model the price of each stock in the index is driven by a set of common and idiosyncratic factors. Factors can be either integrated or stationary. We develop a procedure that, in a first step, builds a replica that is driven by the same persistent factors as the index. This procedure is grounded in recent results which suggest the application of principal component analysis for factor estimation even for integrated processes. In a second step, it is also possible to refine the replica so that it minimizes a specific loss function, as in the traditional approach. In both steps the replica weights depend on the existing information on the index weights system. An extended set of Monte Carlo simulations and an application to the most widely used index in the European stock market, the EuroStoxx50 index, provide substantial support for our approach. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Corielli, Francesco; Marcellino, Massimillano</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility effects of institutional trading in foreign stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiyachantana, Chiraphol N.; Jain, Pankaj K.; Jiang, Christine; Wood, Robert A.
This paper examines the impact of institutional trades on volatility in international stocks across 43 countries. There is a temporary volatility spike during the trade execution period, merely reflecting the price impact costs faced by the institutions. Cross sectional regressions suggest that trade imbalances, enforcement of insider trading laws, stock prices, and an emerging market classification are positively associated with temporary volatility increases whereas the presence of market makers and better shareholders' rights dampen such increases. In the long term, institutional trades do not destabilize markets as the levels of volatility after their trades are almost identical to their pre-decision levels. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiyachantana, Chiraphol N.; Jain, Pankaj K.; Jiang, Christine; Wood, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A credit risk model for large dimensional portfolios with application to economic capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nystrom, Kaj; Skoglund, Jimmy
In this paper we develop a multi-period and multi-state portfolio credit risk model which is applicable to large dimensional portfolios like for example retail and mortgage portfolios. The model includes a methodology for estimation and simulation of systematic transition risk through a model for stochastic migration, a methodology for the modelling of recoveries in the case of stochastic collaterals as well as an approach to dimension reduction of the portfolio. One important application of our model is economic capital (EC) and a concept of EC based on the analogy with classical risk theory is introduced and the questions of allocation as well as risk-adjusted pricing based on the allocation of EC are structured and described. The model is illustrated by an extensive numerical example giving a concretization of the model as well as of several of the concepts introduced. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nystrom, Kaj; Skoglund, Jimmy</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dark side of diversification: The case of US financial holding companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stiroh, Kevin J.; Rumble, Adrienne
Potential diversification benefits are one reason why US financial holding companies are offering a growing range of financial services. This paper examines whether the observed shift toward activities that generate fees, trading revenue, and other non-interest income has improved the performance of US financial holding companies (FHCs) from 1997 to 2002. We find evidence that diversification benefits exist between FHCs, but these gains are offset by the increased exposure to non-interest activities, which are much more volatile but not necessarily more profitable than interest-generating activities. Within FHCs, however, marginal increases in revenue diversification are not associated with better performance, while marginal increases in non-interest income are still associated with lower risk-adjusted profits. The key finding that diversification gains are more than offset by the costs of increased exposure to volatile activities represents the dark side of the search for diversification benefits and has implications for supervisors, managers, investors, and borrowers. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stiroh, Kevin J.; Rumble, Adrienne</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical evaluation of the overconfidence hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chuang, Wen-I.; Lee, Bong-Soo
Recently, several behavioral finance models based on the overconfidence hypothesis have been proposed to explain anomalous findings, including a short-term continuation (momentum) and a long-term reversal in stock returns. We characterize the overconfidence hypothesis by the following four testable implications: First, if investors are overconfident, they overreact to private information and underreact to public information. Second, market gains make overconfident investors trade more aggressively in subsequent periods. Third, excessive trading of overconfident investors in securities markets contributes to the observed excessive volatility. Fourth, overconfident investors underestimate risk and trade more in riskier securities. To document the presence of overconfidence in financial markets, we empirically evaluate these four hypotheses using aggregate data. Overall, we find empirical evidence in support of the four hypotheses. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chuang, Wen-I.; Lee, Bong-Soo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional ownership changes and returns around analysts' earnings forecast release events: Evidence from Taiwan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, An-Sing; Hong, Bi-Shia
Traditional data sources do not have institutional holding data on a daily basis. Because of this, most prior empirical studies of institutional herding have focused on quarterly or annual data. The problem, however, with using quarterly or annual data on institutional holdings is that these data may not reveal institutional herding if it occurs over a shorter time interval. For this study, we make use of data from the Taiwan Stock Exchange (TSE). Unlike traditional data sources, the TSE provides daily institutional holdings information. The use of this detailed data allows us to make more interesting analysis and inferences. In this study, we examine the relationship between institutional ownership changes and returns localized around analysts' earnings forecast release events. Analysis of institutional ownership and return data around the earnings release event allows us to investigate institutional herding and feedback behavior in a different level. Our major results are as follows: (1) there exists a relation between company specific attributes and institutional herding, (2) observed changes in institutional ownership and contemporaneous return are mainly the results of interday price impact of herding, (3) institutional investors show evidence of being informed traders in buying but not selling. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chen, An-Sing; Hong, Bi-Shia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The history and performance of concept stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsieh, Jim; Walkling, Ralph A.
This study investigates the performance of firms with extremely high levels of market to sales value ("concept stocks"). To many observers, these stocks appear overvalued. However, proponents argue that because of their unique characteristics, traditional pricing models fail to value these firms correctly. Ex post, the debate can be resolved through an analysis of the long-term performance of concept stocks. En route to testing the implied overpricing hypothesis we document several important findings. First, the identity and characteristics of concept stocks have changed markedly over time. Although the obvious recent examples are internet and biotech stocks, concept stocks vary widely by industry over the past four decades. The industries containing the most popular concept stocks evolve from oil and gas extraction in the 1960s and 1970s, to computer and office equipment in the 1980s, and to computer-related services in the 1990s. Second, although concept stocks tend to be young, small, growth stocks in the 1990s, they exhibit a wide range of characteristics throughout the sample period. Third, the relative pricing of concept stocks (compared to either a control sample or the entire population) has changed dramatically over time. The average concept stock sold for approximately three times sales in the late 1960s and 1970s, five times sales in the 1980s and nearly 17 times sales in the 1990s. Finally, we find evidence supporting the overpricing hypothesis. Concept stocks under-perform significantly in the long run. This under-performance is more severe for Nasdaq firms and in the most recent two decades. The results are separate from glamour, IPO, industry, or contrarian effects and remain after an extensive sensitivity analysis. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hsieh, Jim; Walkling, Ralph A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large market shocks and abnormal closed-end-fund price behaviour</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuertes, Ana-Maria; Thomas, Dylan C.
This paper investigates the short-term price behaviour of closed-end funds following eight large market-wide shocks. The findings, from a sample of 63 funds continuously traded on the London Stock Exchange, indicate that prices overreact relative to equilibrium given by net asset values. The speed of reversion in discounts following market-wide shocks is slower than that following fund-specific shocks of a similar magnitude. The post-shock persistence in discounts is related more to the ease of arbitrage rather than to liquidity, as proxied by fund size, or to the speed of recovery in the broader market. The discount decays more slowly for those funds that are difficult to arbitrage. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fuertes, Ana-Maria; Thomas, Dylan C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition on the Nasdaq and the growth of electronic communication networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fink, Jason; Fink, Kristin E.; Weston, James P.
This paper examines the growth of electronic communication networks (ECNs) and their competitive impact on the Nasdaq. We find that the development of these alternative trading platforms is associated with tighter quoted, effective, and relative bid-ask spreads, greater depths, and less concentrated markets. Further, our results show that an increase in ECN trading may have caused some traditional market makers (wholesaler and national retail dealers) to exit the market for market making. Overall, Our results suggest that ECNs provide a source of competition to traditional Nasdaq dealers. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fink, Jason; Fink, Kristin E.; Weston, James P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retail deposit fees and multimarket banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hannan, Timothy H.
This paper reports a systematic examination of the determinants of deposit-related retail banking fees using a set of survey data that is unusual for its size, specificity, and sampling properties. The analysis focuses explicitly on six different fees associated with checking accounts and automated teller machine (ATM) usage. A preliminary analysis documents that, on average, multimarket banks charge substantially higher fees than do typically smaller, single-market banks. A more detailed econometric analysis yields results consistent with predictions of recent models. In particular, it finds that the greater the presence of multimarket banks in the local market, the higher are the retail deposit fees of single-market banks (except in highly concentrated markets) and the weaker is the positive relationship between those fees and market concentration. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hannan, Timothy H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What explains household stock holdings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shum, Pauline; Faig, Miquel
This is an empirical study of the determinants of stock holdings using data from the US Survey of Consumer Finances from 1992 to 2001. There is a great heterogeneity in the way households form their portfolios. Stock ownership is positively correlated with various measures of wealth, age, retirement savings, and having sought financial advice. It is negatively correlated with holdings of alternative risky investments, such as investments in private businesses, and with the willingness to undertake non-financial investments in the future. While we can predict reasonably well who holds stocks, we have less predictive power about the share of stocks owned by those who hold positive amounts. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shum, Pauline; Faig, Miquel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alternative measures of the Federal Reserve Banks' cost of equity capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barnes, Michelle L.; Lopez, Jose A.
The Monetary Control Act of 1980 requires the Federal Reserve System to provide payment services to depository institutions through the 12 Federal Reserve Banks at prices that fully reflect the costs a private-sector provider would incur, including a cost of equity capital (COE). Although Fama and French [Fama, E.F., French, K.R., 1997. Industry costs of equity. Journal of Financial Economics 43, 153-193] conclude that COE estimates are "woefully" and "unavoidably" imprecise, the Reserve Banks require such an estimate every year. We examine several COE estimates based on the CAPM model and compare them using econometric and materiality criteria. Our results suggest that the benchmark CAPM model applied to a large peer group of competing firms provides a COE estimate that is not clearly improved upon by using a narrow peer group, introducing additional factors into the model, or taking account of additional firm-level data, such as leverage and line-of-business concentration. Thus, a standard implementation of the benchmark CAPM model provides a reasonable COE estimate, which is needed to impute costs and set prices for the Reserve Banks' payments business. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barnes, Michelle L.; Lopez, Jose A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Switching costs and adverse selection in the market for credit cards: New evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calem, P. S.; Gordy, M. B.; Mester, L. J.
To explain persistence of credit card interest rates at relatively high levels, Calem and Mester (AER, 1995) argued that informational barriers create switching costs for high-balance customers. As evidence, using data from the 1989 Survey of Consumer Finances, they showed that these households were more likely to be rejected when applying for new credit. In this paper, we revisit the question using the 1998 and 2001 SCF. Further, we use new information on card interest rates to test for pricing effects consistent with information-based switching costs. We find that informational barriers to competition persist, although their role may have declined. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calem, P. S.; Gordy, M. B.; Mester, L. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Benefits from a changing payment technology in European banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Humphrey, David; Willesson, Magnus; Bergendahl, Gorah; Lindblom, Ted
An "output characteristics" cost function is used to identify payment sources of technical change in European banking and estimate associated benefits. As the share of electronic payments in 12 European countries rose from 0.43 in 1987 to 0.79 in 1999 and ATMs expanded while the number of branch offices was constant, bank operating costs are $32 billion lower than they otherwise might have been, saving 0.38% of the 12 nations' GDP. Policies facilitating these changes (antitrust exemptions to weakly coordinate implementation of payment service pricing) would permit benefits to be more fully realized. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Humphrey, David; Willesson, Magnus; Bergendahl, Gorah; Lindblom, Ted</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A new measure of cross-sectional risk and its empirical implications for portfolio risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galluccio, Stefano; Roncoroni, Andrea
Litterman et al. [Litterman, R., Scheinkman, J., Weiss, L., 1991. Volatility and the yield curve. Journal of Fixed Income I (June), 49-53] and Engle and Ng [Engle, R.F., Ng, V.K., 1993. Time-varying volatility and the dynamic behavior of the term structure. Journal of Money, Credit and Banking 25(3), 336-349] provide empirical evidence of a relation between yield curve shape and volatility. This study offers theoretical support for that finding in the general context of cross-sectional time series. We introduce a new risk measure quantifying the link between cross-sectional shape and market risk. A simple econometric procedure allows us to represent the risk experienced by cross-sections over a time period in terms of independent factors reproducing possible cross-sectional deformations. We compare our risk measure to the traditional cross-yield covariance according to their relative performance. Empirical investigation in the US interest rate market shows that (1) cross-shape risk factors outperform cross-yield risk factors (i.e., yield curve level, slope, and convexity) in explaining the market risk of yield curve dynamics; (2) hedging multiple liabilities against cross-shape risk delivers superior trading strategies compared to those stemming from cross-yield risk management. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Galluccio, Stefano; Roncoroni, Andrea</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The forward bias in the ECU: Peso risks vs. fads and fashions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sercu, Piet; Vinaimont, Tom
Forward rates of European currencies against the private and official ECU exhibit a bias similar to the one found in other data: the Cumby-Obstfeld-Fama (COF) regression coefficients are systematically below unity, and two thirds of them are negative. We use the discount of the private ECU relative to the official ECU as a measure of market scepticism or mistrust. In one view, this sentiment is based on peso risk: fears of realignments, and possibly also the risk of a meltdown of the private ECU relative to the official one. Alternatively, the discount just reflects fads and fashions. Dichotomizing the data on the basis of the size of the discount in the private ECU, we find that the COF beta strongly depends on the degree of mistrust and that the negative COF coefficients are generated by typically less than 20% of the data. But the pattern fits the fads and fashion view better than the peso theory. If the sentiment factor contains a conventional risk premium at all, then this risk premium is definitely not the one predicted by Bansal [Bansal, R., 1997. An exploration of the forward premium puzzle in currency markets. Review of Financial Studies 10, 369-403]. Nor is the sentiment factor proxying for Huisman et al.'s [Huisman, R., Koedijk, K., Kool, C., Nissen, F., 1998. Extreme support for uncovered interest parity. Journal of International Money and Finance 17, 211-228] transaction-cost effects. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sercu, Piet; Vinaimont, Tom</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What is in it for us? Network effects and bank payment innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milne, A.
The developed world exhibits substantial but poorly understood differences in the efficiency and quality of low value payment services. This paper compares payment arrangements in the UK, Norway, Sweden, and Finland, and discusses the impact of network effects on incentives to adopt new payments technology. A model is presented, in which private benefits for investment in shared interbank payments infrastructure are weak. In contrast, due to 'account externalities', there are strong incentives for investment in intra-bank payment systems. These two features, distinguishing bank payments from other network industries, can help explain some of the observed cross-country differences in payment arrangements. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Milne, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Frontiers in payment and settlement systems: Introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saunders, Anthony; Scholnick, Barry
nan</description><author>Saunders, Anthony; Scholnick, Barry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank efficiency: The role of bank strategy and local market conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bos, J. W. B.; Kool, C. J. M.
In this paper we focus on the assumption of a common efficient frontier when performing an efficiency study for the banking sector. The fact that environmental factors that are not appropriately controlled may easily bias efficiency estimates. First, we estimate a common cost and profit frontier. In this first stage, as an innovation to the literature, we use exogenously computed input prices rather than the normally used endogenous input prices. Second, we regress the estimated inefficiencies on a set of a bank's strategic choices, local banking market variables, and local (regional) macro variables. For the analysis, we use a unique dataset of 401 largely independent cooperative local banks in the Netherlands for the years 1998 and 1999. Our results show that the use of exogenous input prices rather than endogenous input prices is particularly important for the cost frontier as the spread in cost inefficiencies becomes larger and more plausible. Our second stage results suggest that most of the estimated inefficiency indeed is managerial (X-) inefficiency. Environmental factors do play a role, but only to a limited extent. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bos, J. W. B.; Kool, C. J. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gerald O. Bierwag (February 4, 1936 February 15, 2005)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaufman, George
nan</description><author>Kaufman, George</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking and finance in an integrating Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bos, Jaap W. B.; Knot, Klaas H. W.; Kool, Clemens J. M.
nan</description><author>Bos, Jaap W. B.; Knot, Klaas H. W.; Kool, Clemens J. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected versus unexpected monetary policy impulses and interest rate pass-through in euro-zone retail banking markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kleimeier, Stefanie; Sander, Harald
This paper investigates the interest rate pass-through in the euro-zone's retail banking markets by differentiating between expected and unexpected monetary policy impulses. The paper introduces interest futures as measures of expected interest rates into pass-through studies. By allowing various specifications of the pass-through process, including asymmetric adjustment, we find a faster pass-through in loan markets when interest rate changes are correctly anticipated. In contrast, deposit markets are found to be more rigid. Overall, our results suggest that a well-communicated monetary policy is important for a speedier and a more homogenous pass-through but may also be complemented by competition policies. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kleimeier, Stefanie; Sander, Harald</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic depositor discipline in US banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maechler, Andrea M.; McDill, Kathleen M.
This paper captures banks' dynamic response to depositor discipline. Recognizing that the price and quantity response of uninsured deposits in the face of deteriorating fundamentals needs to be modeled as an endogenous process, we investigate how depositor discipline constrains banks' behavior by extracting the impact of an exogenous rise in interest rates on the quantity of uninsured deposits. We find that good banks can raise uninsured deposits by raising their price, while weak banks cannot. This suggests that depositor discipline not only raises the cost of choosing a higher level of risk but also may, at very high levels of risk, effectively constrain bank managers' behavior. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maechler, Andrea M.; McDill, Kathleen M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal ratings systems, implied credit risk and the consistency of banks' risk classification policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobson, Tor; Linde, Jesper; Roszbach, Kasper
This paper aims at improving our understanding of internal risk rating systems (IRS) at large banks, of the way in which they are implemented, and at verifying if IRS produce consistent estimates of banks' loan portfolio credit risk. An important property of our work is that the size of our data set allows us to derive measures of credit risk without making any assumptions about correlations between loans, by applying Carey's [Carey, Mark, 1998. Credit risk in private debt portfolios. Journal of Finance LIII (4), 1363-1387] non-parametric Monte Carlo re-sampling method. We find substantial differences between the implied loss distributions of two banks with equal "regulatory" risk profiles; both expected losses and the credit loss rates at a wide range of loss distribution percentiles vary considerably. Such variation will translate into different levels of required economic capital. Our results also confirm the quantitative importance of size for portfolio credit risk: for common parameter values, we find that tail risk can be reduced by up to 40% by doubling portfolio size. Our analysis makes clear that not only the formal design of a rating system, but also the way in which it is implemented (e.g. a rating grade composition; the degree of homogeneity within rating classes) can be quantitatively important for the shape of credit loss distributions and thus for banks' required capital structure. The evidence of differences between lenders also hints at the presence of differentiated market equilibria, that are more complex than might otherwise be supposed: different lending or risk management "styles" may emerge and banks strike their own balance between risk-taking and (the cost of) monitoring (that risk). (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacobson, Tor; Linde, Jesper; Roszbach, Kasper</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign banks and credit stability in Central and Eastern Europe. A panel data analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Haas, Ralph; van Lelyveld, Iman
We examine whether foreign and domestic banks in Central and Eastern Europe react differently to business cycles and banking crises. Our panel dataset comprises data of more than 250 banks for the period 1993-2000, with information on bank ownership and mode of entry. During crisis periods domestic banks contracted their credit base, whereas greenfield foreign banks did not. Also, home country conditions matter for foreign bank growth, as there is a significant negative relationship between home country economic growth and host country credit by greenfields. Finally, greenfield foreign banks' credit growth is influenced by the health of the parent bank. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Haas, Ralph; van Lelyveld, Iman</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency of the Polish banking industry: Foreign versus domestic banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Havrylchyk, Okena
The present paper investigates the efficiency of the Polish banking industry between 1997 and 2001. Our preferred methodology is Data Envelopment Analysis, which allows us to distinguish between cost, allocative, technical, pure technical, and scale efficiency. Additionally, we perform a number of tests to investigate whether domestic and foreign banks come from the same population. Finally, we attempt to shed light on the determinants of efficiency. Our results indicate that bank efficiency has not improved during the years analyzed. Whereas greenfield banks have achieved higher levels of efficiency than domestic banks, foreign banks that acquired domestic institutions have not succeeded in enhancing their efficiency. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Havrylchyk, Okena</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>System identification in noisy data environments: An application to six Asian stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Los, Cornelis A.
This paper analyzes the systematic relationship between the stock market valuations, the nominal GDPs and the interest rates of six Asian countries, using not "single equation regression", but an alternative methodology based on complete, multidirectional, least squares projections in the tradition of Frisch (1934). We compare the results with the spectral analysis of the information matrices and determine the noise levels. The objective is to extract the multidimensional economic system structures from the noisy empirical observations. This complete methodology sharply contrasts with the incomplete methodology of Fama [Fama, E.F., 1990. Stock returns, expected returns, and real activity. Journal of Finance 45, 1089-1108] and Schwert [Schwert, G.W., 1990. Stock returns and real activity: A century of evidence. Journal of Finance 45, 1237-1257], etc., who presume planal relations, fit them to the multidimensional data by only one prejudiced unidirectional projection, thereby ignoring between 75% and 92% of the available covariance information and not publishing all possible model projections. The results in this paper show that the analyzed countries are better analyzed using such complete multidirectional LS projections, even though the analysis is combinatorially much more complex. All six Asian financial-economic systems are high data noise environments, in which it is very difficult to separate the systematic signals from the noise. Because of these high noise levels, spectral analysis is very unreliable. We identify Taiwan's stock market, economy and financial market to be rationally coherent. In contrast, Malaysia, Singapore, Philippines and Indonesia's show only partially coherent systems, while no coherent system can be identified among Japan's data. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Los, Cornelis A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The contribution of market makers to liquidity and efficiency of options trading in electronic markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eldor, Rafi; Hauser, Shmuel; Pilo, Batia; Shurki, Itzik
This paper examines the contribution of market makers to the liquidity and the efficiency of the options market in a unique setup of an order-driven computerized trading system, in which market makers and other participants operate under equitable conditions. The main findings are: (1) liquidity increased - a 60% increase in trading volume and a 35% decrease of bid-ask spreads,- (2) the efficiency of shekel-euro options trading improved - deviations from put-call parity decreased significantly by 12%, and skewness decreased by about 30%. We also find that the net cost to the exchange is out weighted by the benefit to the trading public and that the presence of market makers encouraged trading between other participants far beyond their own trading. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eldor, Rafi; Hauser, Shmuel; Pilo, Batia; Shurki, Itzik</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign credit ratings: Guilty beyond reasonable doubt?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mora, Nada
This paper questions the view that credit rating agencies aggravated the East Asian crisis by excessively downgrading those countries. I find that ratings are, if anything, sticky rather than procyclical. Assigned ratings exceeded predicted ratings before the crisis, mostly matched predicted ratings during the crisis period, and did not increase as much as predictions in the period after the crisis. Ratings are also found to react to non-macroeconomic factors such as lagged spreads and a country's default history. Therefore it is questionable that ratings exacerbate the boom-bust cycle if they are simply reacting to news, whether macroeconomic or market. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mora, Nada</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Realized volatility and transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Choon Chat; Fong, Wai Mun
This paper re-examines the impact of number of trades, trade size and order imbalance on daily stock returns volatility. In contrast to prior studies, we estimate daily volatility using realized volatility obtained by summing up intraday squared returns. Consistent with the theory of quadratic variation, realized volatility estimates are shown to be less noisy than standard volatility measures such as absolute returns used in previous studies. In general, our results confirm [Jones, C.M., Kaul, G., Lipson, M.L., 1994. Transactions, volume, and volatility. Review of Financial Studies 7, 631-651] that number of trades is the dominant factor behind the volume-volatility relation. Neither trade size nor order imbalance adds significantly more explanatory power to realized volatility beyond number of trades. This finding is robust to different time periods, firm sizes and regression specifications. The implications of our results for microstructure theory are discussed. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Choon Chat; Fong, Wai Mun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-varying risk premia and the cross section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Hui
This paper develops and estimates a heteroskedastic variant of Campbell's [Campbell, J., 1993. Intertemporal asset pricing without consumption data. American Economic Review 83, 487-512] ICAPM, in which risk factors include a stock market return and variables forecasting stock market returns or variance. Our main innovation is the use of a new set of predictive variables, which not only have superior forecasting abilities for stock returns and variance, but also are theoretically motivated. In contrast with the early authors, we find that Campbell's ICAPM performs significantly better than the CAPM. That is, the additional factors account for a substantial portion of the two CAPM-related anomalies, namely, the value premium and the momentum profit. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guo, Hui</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics of realized volatilities and correlations: An empirical study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferland, Rene; Lalancette, Simon
This study examines two important issues underlying realized volatility and correlation estimators. First, an empirical inquiry is conducted to assess whether Bax and Eurodollar futures tick-by-tick data can be characterized as marked-point processes. Second, ARMA, neural network, GARCH-BEKK, and naive volatility and correlation forecasts are compared in an out-of-sample context when a trader prices an interest rate spread option based on those forecasts and simultaneously delta-hedges her position. Other loss functions are also considered. Competing volatility forecasts are also compared to implied volatilities. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferland, Rene; Lalancette, Simon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management at rights issues thresholds - Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Qiao; Du, Bin; Sun, Qian
Burgstahler and Dichev (BD) (Burgstahler, David, Ilia, Dichev, 1997. Earnings management to avoid earnings decreases and losses. Journal of Accounting and Economics 23(l), 99-126.) and Degorge, Patel, and Zeckhauser (DPZ) (Degeorge, Franscois, Patel, Jayendu, Zeckhauser, Richard, 1999. Earnings management to exceed thresholds. Journal of Business 72(1), 1-33.) examine earnings management among American firms by looking at actual distributions around critical thresholds. Chinese firms must meet minimal ROE requirements if they are to have rights issues. Using a distribution approach, we examine whether Chinese firms manipulate their earnings to meet the regulatory requirements. Our empirical findings indicate that Chinese firms indeed heavily engaged in earnings management to meet the rights issue thresholds during the period 1994-2002. In addition, we show that these firms changed their behavior in response to changes in regulatory requirements. Furthermore, we analyse the pervasiveness of this practice and the means used in earnings management at the relevant ROE thresholds. Our findings have direct policy implications for the China Securities Regulatory Committee (CSRC). (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yu, Qiao; Du, Bin; Sun, Qian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market discipline and deposit insurance reform in Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Imai, Masami
On April 1, 2002, the Japanese government lifted a blanket guarantee of all deposits and began limiting the coverage of time deposits. This paper uses this deposit insurance reform as a natural experiment to investigate the relationship between deposit insurance coverage and market discipline. I find that the reform raised the sensitivity of interest rates on deposits, and that of deposit quantity to default risk. In addition, the interest rate differentials between partially insured large time deposits and fully insured ordinary deposits increased for risky banks. These results suggest that the deposit insurance reform enhanced market discipline in Japan. I also find, however, that too-big-to-fail (TBTF) policy became a more important determinant of interest rates and deposit allocation after the reform, thereby partially offsetting the positive effects of the deposit insurance reform on overall market discipline. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Imai, Masami</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic growth and the stability and efficiency of the financial sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blejer, Mario I.
It has been claimed that the ability of emerging markets to adopt optimal stabilization policies is hampered by a number of factors. Among them, it has been recently emphasized the role of financial instability, inefficiencies, and financial market imperfections. It is claimed here that the current financial regulatory paradigm, embodied in Basel II, may improve financial stability but reinforces cyclicality. Therefore, countries should emphasize financial efficiency since it would lead to enhanced financial stability, without increasing cyclicality. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blejer, Mario I.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial stability: A worthy goal, but how feasible?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poloz, Stephen S.
Financial stability has proved elusive. Despite the success of central banks in controlling inflation, economies continue to experience periods of exchange rate overvaluation, stock market volatility and housing price bubbles that affect individuals very deeply. This note speculates that such financial volatility may be the product of three factors, (a) successful inflation targeting, (b) the existence of nonlinearities and differential economic dynamics, and (c) the recent evolution of key structural parameters in the economy. If so, then central banks might better focus on making financial systems more resilient than on trying to develop more sophisticated policies aimed at reducing financial volatility. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Poloz, Stephen S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A framework for assessing financial stability?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goodhart, C. A. E.
I worked as a consultant in the Financial Stability Department (FSD) of the Bank of England for several years (2002-2004). In this paper I reflect on issues relating to the work of such an FSD, starting with the difficulty of defining or measuring 'financial stability'. Stress tests are commonly used, but, for an FSD, should relate to the system as a whole, not just to individual institutions. FSDs need to assess the probability, virulence and speed of occurrence of potential shocks. There is a need to develop appropriate analytical models. The focus on capital adequacy has diverted attention from concern about having sufficient liquidity. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goodhart, C. A. E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary and financial stability: Here to stay?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borio, Claudio
We argue that changes in the monetary and financial regimes over the last twenty years or so have been subtly altering the dynamics of the economy and hence the challenges that monetary and prudential authorities face. In particular, the current environment may be more vulnerable to the occasional build up of financial imbalances, i.e. over-extensions in (private sector) balance sheets, which herald economic weakness and unwelcome disinflation down the road, as they unwind. As a result, achieving simultaneous monetary and financial stability in a lasting way may call for refinements to current monetary and prudential policy frameworks. These refinements would entail a firmer long-term focus, greater symmetry in policy responses between upswings and downswings, with greater attention to actions during upswings, and closer coordination between monetary and prudential authorities. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V, All rights reserved.</description><author>Borio, Claudio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real exchange rates in small open OECD and transition economies: Comparing apples with oranges?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Egert, Balazs; Lommatzsch, Kirsten; Lahreche-Revil, Amina
We find that productivity gains in tradables cause an appreciation of the real exchange rate via both tradable and nontradable prices in the CEE-5 and have no affect in the Baltic countries, while they lead to a depreciation of the real exchange rate of tradables in OECD economics that overcompensates the appreciation due to nontradable prices. Rising net foreign liabilities lead to a real appreciation in the Baltic countries instead of the expected depreciation found in OECD and CEE-5 countries. These differences are due to the different impact of the fundamentals on the real exchange rate depending on the time horizon studied. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Egert, Balazs; Lommatzsch, Kirsten; Lahreche-Revil, Amina</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>M&amp;As performance in the European financial industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manuel Campa, Jose; Hernando, Ignacio
This paper looks at the performance record of M&amp;As that took place in the European Union financial industry in the period 1998-2002. First, the paper reports evidence on shareholder returns from the merger. Merger announcements implied positive excess returns to the shareholders of the target company around the date of the announcement, with a slight positive excess-return on the 3-months period prior to announcement. Returns to shareholders of the acquiring firms were essentially zero around announcement. One year after the announcement, excess returns were not significantly different from zero for both targets and acquirers. The paper also provides evidence on changes in the operating performance for the subsample of merges involving banks. M&amp;As usually involved targets with lower operating performance than the average in their sector. The transaction resulted in significant improvements in the target banks performance beginning on average 2 years after the transaction was completed. Return on equity of the target companies increased by an average of 7%, and these firms also experience efficiency improvements. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Manuel Campa, Jose; Hernando, Ignacio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing growth-indexed bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chamon, Marcos; Mauro, Paolo
Growth-indexed bonds have been suggested as a way of reducing the procyclicality of emergingmarket countries' fiscal policies and the likelihood of costly debt crises. Investor attitude surveys suggest that pricing difficulties are seen as a considerable obstacle. In an effort to reduce such concerns, this article presents a simple way of pricing growth-indexed bonds. As a pleasant by-product, the analysis tracks the quantitative implications of an increase in the share of growth-indexed bonds in total debt, measuring the ensuing decline in the probability of default and the reduction in the spreads at which standard bonds can be issued. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chamon, Marcos; Mauro, Paolo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decomposing the effects of financial liberalization: Crises vs. growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ranciere, Romain; Tornell, Aaron; Westermann, Frank
We present a new empirical decomposition of the effects of financial liberalization on economic growth and on the incidence of crises. Our empirical estimates show that the direct effect of financial liberalization on growth by far outweighs the indirect effect via a higher propensity to crisis. We also discuss several models of financial liberalization and growth whose predictions are consistent with our empirical findings. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ranciere, Romain; Tornell, Aaron; Westermann, Frank</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of foreign currency debt in financial crises: 1880-1913 versus 1972-1997</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bordo, Michael D.; Meissner, Christopher M.
We show that exposure to foreign currency debt does not necessarily increase the risk of having a financial crisis. Some countries do not suffer from financial fragility despite original sin. Before 1913 British offshoots and Scandinavia afflicted with it avoided financial meltdowns. Today many advanced countries have original sin, but few have had crises. In both periods, aggregate balance sheet mismatches are associated with a greater likelihood of a crisis. The evidence suggests that foreign currency debt is dangerous when mis-managed. This is part of the difference between developed countries and emerging markets both of which borrow in foreign currency. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bordo, Michael D.; Meissner, Christopher M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fiscal adjustment in EU countries: A balance sheet approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milesi-Ferretti, Gian Maria; Moriyama, Kenji
Several European Union countries have recently implemented or are envisaging fiscal operations which improve budgetary figures but have no structural impact on government finances. We evaluate some of these measures using a balance sheet approach. In particular, we examine the degree to which reductions in government debt in EU countries has been accompanied by a decumulation of government assets. In the runup to Maastricht we find a strong correlation between changes in government liabilities and government assets, and larger declines in government assets in countries starting from higher public debt levels. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Milesi-Ferretti, Gian Maria; Moriyama, Kenji</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do deficits tell us about debt? Empirical evidence on creative accounting with fiscal rules in the EU</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Hagen, Juergen; Wolff, Guntrarn B.
Fiscal rules, such as the excessive deficit procedure and the stability and growth pact (SGP), aim at constraining government behavior. [Milesi-Ferretti, G., 2003. Good, bad or ugly? On the effects of fiscal rules with creative accounting, Journal of Public Economics, 88, 377-394] develops a model in which governments circumvent such rules by reverting to creative accounting. The amount of this depends on the reputation cost for the government and the economic cost of sticking to the rule. We provide empirical evidence of creative accounting in the European Union. We find that the SGP rules have induced governments to use stock-flow adjustments, a form of creative accounting, to hide deficits. The tendency to substitute stock-flow adjustments for budget deficits is especially strong for the cyclical component of the deficit, as in times of recession the cost of reducing the deficit is particularly large. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>von Hagen, Juergen; Wolff, Guntrarn B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction: Crises, financial stability and macroeconomic policy. Papers from the 11th Dubrovnik Economic Conference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wachtel, Paul; Vujcic, Boris
nan</description><author>Wachtel, Paul; Vujcic, Boris</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Marshall Sarnat: 1929-2006 - Obituary</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Haim
nan</description><author>Levy, Haim</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme spectral risk measures: An application to futures clearinghouse margin requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cotter, John; Dowd, Kevin
This paper applies the extreme-value (EV) generalised pareto distribution to the extreme tails of the return distributions for the S&amp;P500, FT100, DAX, Hang Seng, and Nikkei225 futures contracts. It then uses tail estimators from these contracts to estimate spectral risk measures, which are coherent risk measures that reflect a user's risk-aversion function. It compares these to VaR and expected shortfall (ES) risk measures, and compares the precision of their estimators. It also discusses the usefulness of these risk measures in the context of clearinghouses setting initial margin requirements, and compares these to the SPAN measures typically used. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cotter, John; Dowd, Kevin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market structure and competitive conditions in the Arab GCC banking system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Al-Muharrami, Saeed; Matthews, Kent; Khabari, Yusuf
This paper investigates the market structure of Arab GCC banking industry during the years of 1993-2002 using the most frequently applied measures of concentration k-bank concentration ratio (CRk) and Herfindahl-Hirschman Index (HHI) and evaluates the monopoly power of banks over the ten years period using the 'H-statistic' by Panzar and Rosse. The results show that Kuwait, Saudi Arabia and UAE have moderately concentrated markets and are moving to less concentrated positions. The measures of concentration also show that Qatar, Bahrain and Oman are highly concentrated markets. The Panzar-Rosse H-statistics suggest that banks in Kuwait, Saudi Arabia and the UAE operate under perfect competition; banks in Bahrain and Qatar operate under conditions of monopolistic competition; and we are unable to reject monopolistic competition for the banking market in Oman. (c) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Al-Muharrami, Saeed; Matthews, Kent; Khabari, Yusuf</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of mean reversion of bank profitability on post-merger performance in the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knapp, Morris; Gart, Alan; Chaudhry, Mukesh
This research study examines the tendency for serial correlation in bank holding company profitability, finding significant evidence of reversion to the industry mean in profitability. The paper then considers the impact of mean reversion on the evaluation of post-merger performance of bank holding companies. The research concludes that when an adjustment is made for the mean reversion, post-merger results significantly exceed those of the industry in the first 5 years after the merger. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Knapp, Morris; Gart, Alan; Chaudhry, Mukesh</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on the Wang and Wang measure of the quality of the compass rose</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitchell, Heather; McKenzie, Michael D.
H. Wang and C. Wang [Visibility of the compass rose in financial asset returns: A quantitative study, J. Bank. Financ. 26 (2002), 1099-1111] derive a measure of the visibility of the radial patterns that appear in a plot of current and past returns, which are more commonly known as the compass rose. In theory, this measure should be positively related to the tick/volatility ratio. In practice however, we find that this relationship does not hold for higher tick/volatility ratios that are common to stock market data. Thus, the use of this measure is limited in real world applications. We propose a correction factor that improves the behaviour of the quality measure over higher tick/volatility ratios, however, further research is required to fully identify and correct the problem. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mitchell, Heather; McKenzie, Michael D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Small and medium-size enterprises: Access to finance as a growth constraint</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli
This paper presents recent research on access to finance by small and medium-size enterprises (SMEs). SMEs form a large part of private sector in many developed and developing countries. While cross-country research sheds doubt on a causal link between SMEs and economic development, there is substantial evidence that small firms face larger growth constraints and have less access to formal sources of external finance, potentially explaining the lack of SMEs' contribution to growth. Financial and institutional development helps alleviate SMEs' growth constraints and increase their access to external finance and thus levels the playing field between firms of different sizes. Specific financing tools such as leasing and factoring can be useful in facilitating greater access to finance even in the absence of well-developed institutions, as can systems-of credit information sharing and a more competitive banking structure. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic announcements and asymmetric volatility in bond returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Goeij, Peter; Marquering, Wessel
This study analyses the impact of macroeconomic news announcements on the conditional volatility of bond returns. Using daily returns on the 1, 3, 5 and 10 year US Treasury bonds, we find that announcement shocks have a strong impact on the dynamics of bond market volatility. Our results provide empirical evidence that the bond market incorporates the implications of macroeconomic announcement news faster than other information. Moreover, after distinguishing between types of macroeconomic announcements, releases of the employment situation and producer price index are especially influential at the intermediate and long end of the yield curve, while monetary policy seem to affect short-term bond volatility. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Goeij, Peter; Marquering, Wessel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should banks own equity stakes in their borrowers? A contractual solution to hold-up problems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mahrt-Smith, Jan
This paper develops a model to answer the question whether a bank should hold a share of the equity of a borrowing firm. The model shows that a small equity stake held by the bank can have a significant and positive impact on the lending relationship. The benefit of bank equity participation arises from the reduced ability of the bank to extract rents from the firm in multiple rounds of financing. This, in turn, improves the firm's incentive to make investments in profitable projects that require future outside finance. The benefit is likely to be significant for small to medium size firms, growth firms, and firms with ongoing capital needs. The paper addresses, from a corporate finance perspective, the current debate about whether banks should be allowed to own equity stakes in corporations - and how large these equity stakes should be. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mahrt-Smith, Jan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank loan supply and monetary policy transmission in Germany: An assessment based on matching impulse responses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huelsewig, Oliver; Mayer, Eric; Wollmershaeuser, Timo
This paper addresses the credit channel in Germany by using aggregate data. We present a stylized model of the banking firm in which banks decide on their loan supply in the light of expectations about the future course of monetary policy. Applying a VAR model, we estimate the response of bank loans to a monetary policy shock taking account of the reaction of the output level and the loan rate. We estimate our model to evaluate the response of bank loans by matching the theoretical impulse responses with the empirical impulse responses to a monetary policy shock. Evidence in support of the credit channel can be reported. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huelsewig, Oliver; Mayer, Eric; Wollmershaeuser, Timo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of large shareholding on information asymmetry and stock liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Attig, Najah; Fong, Wai-Ming; Gadhoum, Yoser; Lang, Larry H. P.
Prior studies, such as Claessens et al.'s [Claessens, S., Djankov, S., Fan, J., Lang, L., 2002. Disentangling the incentive and entrenchment effects of large shareholding. Journal of Finance 57, 2741-2771], suggest that deviation between ultimate control and ownership decreases firm value (due to the entrenchment effects of large shareholding). Using a sample of Canadian firms, we study the relation of ultimate control and ownership with an important dimension of stock liquidity - bid - ask spread. We find that stocks with greater deviations between ultimate control and ownership have a larger information asymmetry component of their bid-ask spread and wider bid-ask spread. Our results are consistent with the notion that the ultimate owners of these stocks may have selfish agendas. To increase the probability of the agendas being implemented, the firms may have poor information disclosure, resulting in poor stock liquidity. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Attig, Najah; Fong, Wai-Ming; Gadhoum, Yoser; Lang, Larry H. P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Scale economies, X-efficiency, and convergence of productivity among bank holding companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fung, Michael K.
Are the less productive banks catching up to the more productive ones and, if so, how quickly and by what means? The objective of this study is to answer these questions by looking for convergence in productivity among bank holding companies (BHCs) in the US Past research has identified two major factors governing productivity in the banking sector-scale economies and X-efficiency. If the gains from scale economies decline with firm size and if the only difference between BHCs lies in their initial size, then the initially smaller BHCs should eventually catch up to the initially larger ones because the former tend to grow more quickly. However, the findings from this study do not support this hypothesis of "absolute convergence". Indeed, the findings show strong evidence for "conditional convergence", which means that the steady-state productivity to which a BHC is converging is conditional on the BHCs own level of X-efficiency. Conditional convergence implies that initial differences in X-efficiency among BHCs can, between them, create permanent differences in steady-state productivity. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fung, Michael K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit channel, trade credit channel, and inventory investment: Evidence from a panel of UK firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guariglia, Alessandra; Mateut, Simona
In this paper, we use a panel of 609 UK firms over the period 1980-2000 to test for the existence of a trade credit channel of transmission of monetary policy, and for whether this channel plays an offsetting effect on the traditional credit channel. We estimate error-correction inventory investment equations augmented with the coverage ratio and the trade credit to assets ratio, differentiating the effects of the latter variables across firms more or less likely to face financing constraints, and firms making a high or low use of trade credit. Our results suggest that both the credit and the trade credit channels operate in the UK, and that the latter channel tends to weaken the former. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guariglia, Alessandra; Mateut, Simona</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The strategic use of corporate venture financing for securing demand</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Riyanto, Yohanes E.; Schwienbacher, Armin
This paper focuses on the strategic role of corporate venture financing carried out by a corporation (a headquarter). When the headquarter finances a venture through its corporate venture-financing arm, it can increase the complementarity between products of the venture and the headquarter. The effect of having an increase in complementarity is a softening of ex post product market competition with rival products. Hence, in deciding whether to finance the venture, the headquarter faces a trade-off between, on the one hand, being more aggressive ex post in the product market, and, on the other hand, using venture financing to soften ex post competition with substitute products. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Riyanto, Yohanes E.; Schwienbacher, Armin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor monitoring and differences in mutual fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>James, Christopher; Karceski, Jason
A number of mutual funds cater exclusively to institutional investors. Although institutional funds might be a natural place to look for "smart money", agency costs associated with delegated monitoring may lead to less monitoring and worse overall performance. We split institutional funds based on proxies for the degree of investor oversight, and we find that institutional funds with low initial investment requirements and funds with retail mates perform significantly worse than other institutional funds both before and after adjusting for risk and expenses. Tracking error is especially important in the flow-performance relationship of institutional funds with high minimum investment requirements. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>James, Christopher; Karceski, Jason</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification benefits and persistence of US-based global bond funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Polwitoon, Sirapat; Tawatnuntachai, Oranee
This paper examines diversification benefits and performance persistence of 188 US-based global bond funds that survived and were defunct during the period of 1993-2004. Consistent with managed fund literature, global funds underperform broad-based benchmark indexes; however, the underperformance is less than the funds' expense ratio. The results using both simple and time-varying frameworks suggest that global funds provide higher total return and comparable risk-adjusted return to domestic bond funds. For US investors specializing in domestic bond funds, global funds can enhance return by 0.5-1% per year without increasing risk. Global funds also provide incremental diversification benefits to equity fund investors. The funds exhibit short-run performance persistence, but this is difficult for investors to exploit, especially in long-run. Global funds show no return seasonality during the sample period. On a risk-adjusted basis, larger and newer funds and funds with long maturity and low expense ratio perform well. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Polwitoon, Sirapat; Tawatnuntachai, Oranee</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International stock-bond correlations in a simple affine asset pricing model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>d'Addona, Stefano; Kind, Axel H.
We use an affine asset pricing model to jointly value stocks and bonds. This enables us to derive endogenous correlations and to explain how economic fundamentals influence the correlation between stock and bond returns. The presented model is implemented for G7 post-war economies and its in-sample and out-of-sample performance is assessed by comparing the correlations generated by the model with conventional statistical measures. The affine framework developed in this paper is found to generate stock bond correlations that are in line with empirically observed figures. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>d'Addona, Stefano; Kind, Axel H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on the non-convexity problem in some shopping-time and human-capital models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cysne, Rubens Penha
Several works in the shopping-time and in the human-capital literature, due to the non-concavity of the underlying Hamiltonian, use first-order conditions in dynamic optimization to characterize necessity, but not sufficiency, in intertemporal problems. This note selects some works in these two areas and shows that optimality can be characterized, and some results quantitatively improved, by means of an application of Arrow's [Arrow, K. J., 1968. Applications of control theory to economic growth. In: Dantzig, G.B., Veinott Jr., A.F. (Eds.), Mathematics of the Decisions Sciences. American Mathematical Society, Providence, RI] sufficiency theorem. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cysne, Rubens Penha</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why firm access to the bond market differs over the business cycle: A theory and some evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santos, Joao A. C.
This paper presents a theory of firm access to the bond market in which information gathering agencies are valuable but alter the relative cost of bond financing across firms and over the business cycle. The theory builds on the assumption that information frictions prevent these agencies from rating firms correctly all of the time. As a result, the cost of bond financing becomes dependent on the state of the economy and the "quality" of the signal provided by these agencies' ratings. In addition, when the mix of bond issuers becomes riskier, as happens in recessions, bond financing becomes more expensive for mid-quality firms. Bond financing may even become more expensive to all firms, in which case mid-quality firms will be affected the most. The analysis of the bonds issued in the last two decades by American firms shows that split ratings, our proxy for the "quality" of the rating agencies' signal, do not affect the relative cost of bond financing across firms in expansions, but they do increase the relative cost of this funding source for mid-credit quality issuers in recessions. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Santos, Joao A. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On time-scaling of risk and the square-root-of-time rule</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danielsson, Jon; Zigrand, Jean-Pierre
Many financial applications, such as risk analysis, and derivatives pricing, depend on time scaling of risk. A common method for this purpose is the square-root-of-time rule where an estimated quantile of a return distribution is scaled to a lower frequency by the square root of the time horizon. This paper examines time scaling of quantiles when returns follow a jump diffusion process. We demonstrate that when jumps represent losses, the square-root-of-time rule leads to a systematic underestimation of risk, whereby the degree of underestimation worsens with the time horizon, the jump intensity and the confidence level. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Danielsson, Jon; Zigrand, Jean-Pierre</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International transmission of inflation among G-7 countries: A data-determined VAR analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Jian; Guo, Hui; Wang, Zijun
We investigate the international transmission of inflation among G-7 countries using data-determined vector autoregression analysis, as advocated by Swanson and Granger [Swanson, N., Granger, C., 1997. Impulse response functions based on a causal approach to residual orthogonalization in vector autoregressions. Journal of the American Statistical Association 92, 357-367]. Over the period 1973-2003, we find that unexpected changes in US inflation have large effects on inflation in other countries, although they are not always the dominant international factor. Similarly, shocks to some other countries also have a statistically and economically significant influence on US inflation. Moreover, our evidence indicates that US inflation has become less vulnerable to foreign shocks since the early 1990s, mainly because of the diminished influence from Germany and France. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yang, Jian; Guo, Hui; Wang, Zijun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantitative models for operational risk: Extremes, dependence and aggregation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chavez-Demoulin, V.; Embrechts, P.; Neslehova, J.
Due to the new regulatory guidelines known as Basel 11 for banking and Solvency 2 for insurance, the financial industry is looking for qualitative approaches to and quantitative models for operational risk. Whereas a full quantitative approach may never be achieved, in this paper we present some techniques from probability and statistics which no doubt will prove useful in any quantitative modelling environment. The techniques discussed are advanced peaks over threshold modelling, the construction of dependent loss processes and the establishment of bounds for risk measures under partial information, and can be applied to other areas of quantitative risk management. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chavez-Demoulin, V.; Embrechts, P.; Neslehova, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A more complete conceptual framework for SME finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Udell, Gregory F.
We propose a more complete conceptual framework for analysis of SME credit availability issues. In this framework, lending technologies are the key conduit through which government policies and national financial structures affect credit availability. We emphasize a causal chain from policy to financial structures, which affect the feasibility and profitability of different lending technologies. These technologies, in turn, have important effects on SME credit availability. Financial structures include the presence of different financial institution types and the conditions under which they operate. Lending technologies include several transactions technologies plus relationship lending. We argue that the framework implicit in most of the literature is oversimplified, neglects key elements of the chain, and often yields misleading conclusions. A common oversimplification is the treatment of transactions technologies as a homogeneous group, unsuitable for serving informationally opaque SMEs, and a frequent misleading conclusion is that large institutions are disadvantaged in lending to opaque SMEs. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Udell, Gregory F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market value impact of operational loss events for US banks and insurers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cummins, J. David; Lewis, Christopher M.; Wei, Ran
This paper conducts an event study analysis of the impact of operational loss events on the market values of banks and insurance companies, using the OpVar database. We focus on financial institutions because of the increased market and regulatory scrutiny of operational losses in these industries. The analysis covers all publicly reported banking and insurance operational risk events affecting publicly traded US institutions from 1978 to 2003 that caused operational losses of at least $10 million - a total of 403 bank events and 89 insurance company events. The results reveal a strong, statistically significant negative stock price reaction to announcements of operational loss events. On average, the market value response is larger for insurers than for banks. Moreover, the market value loss significantly exceeds the amount of the operational loss reported, implying that such losses convey adverse implications about future cash flows. Losses are proportionately larger for institutions with higher Tobin's Q ratios, implying that operational loss events are more costly in market value terms for firms with strong growth prospects. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cummins, J. David; Lewis, Christopher M.; Wei, Ran</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimation of rating class transition probabilities with incomplete data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maehlmann, Thomas
This paper shows that the well known "duration" and "cohort" methods for estimating transition probabilities of external bond ratings are not suitable for internal rating data. More precisely, the duration method cannot and the cohort method should not be used in connection with banks' ratings generated from internal models. Structural differences within the borrower monitoring process of banks and rating agencies are responsible for this result. A Maximum Likelihood (ML) estimation procedure, which accounts for the peculiarities of internal bank ratings, is introduced and applied to data from a German bank. The empirical results indicate that the differences between cohort and ML transition matrices are both, statistically and economically significant. Furthermore, evidence of rating reversals, business cycle dependent transition probabilities and on the factors which determine the borrower monitoring intensity of banks is provided. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maehlmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The wealth effect of forced bank mergers and cronyism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chong, Beng-Soon; Liu, Ming-Hua; Tan, Kok-Hui
This study examines the impact of forced bank mergers on the shareholders' wealth of Malaysian banks. Forced bank mergers, which are the result of direct government intervention in the consolidation of the banking industry, are generally rare. Unlike the findings on voluntary mergers and acquisitions, our study shows that the forced merger scheme destroys economic value in aggregate and the acquiring banks tend to gain at the expense of the target banks. Further analysis shows that the contrasting forced merger finding is linked to cronyism. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chong, Beng-Soon; Liu, Ming-Hua; Tan, Kok-Hui</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interventions in the Yen-dollar spot market: A story of price, volatility and volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Suk-Joong; Sheen, Jeffrey
We test the effectiveness of Bank of Japan (BOJ)'s foreign exchange interventions on conditional first and second moments of exchange rate returns and traded volumes, using a bivariate EGARCH model of the Yen/USD market from 5-13-1991 to 3-16-2004. We also estimate a friction model of BOJ's intervention reaction function based on reducing short-term market disorderliness and supplementing domestic monetary policy. Important finding of this study are that: (i) we find ineffectiveness of BOJ interventions in influencing exchange rate trends pre-1995, in general, but effectiveness post-1995; (ii) FED intervention amplified the effectiveness of the BOJ transactions; (iii) interventions amplified market volatility and volumes through a 'learning by trading' process; (iv) BOJ's interventions were based on 'leaning against the wind' motivations on the exchange rate trend and volumes; and (v) BOJ interventions were vigorously used in support of domestic monetary policy objectives post-1995. Though some of our findings confirm recent studies, our analysis goes deeper to provide new findings with important implications for central banks and foreign exchange market participants. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Suk-Joong; Sheen, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio selection with a drawdown constraint</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Gordon J.; Baptista, Alexandre M.
When identifying optimal portfolios, practitioners often impose a drawdown constraint. This constraint is even explicit in some money management contracts such as the one recently involving Merrill Lynch' management of Unilever's pension fund. In this setting, we provide a characterization of optimal portfolios using mean-variance analysis. In the absence of a benchmark, we find that while the constraint typically decreases the optimal portfolio's standard deviation, the constrained optimal portfolio can be notably mean-variance inefficient. In the presence of a benchmark such as in the Merrill Lynch-Unilever contract, we find that the constraint increases the optimal portfolio's standard deviation and tracking error volatility. Thus, the constraint negatively affects a portfolio manager's ability to track a benchmark. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, Gordon J.; Baptista, Alexandre M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deviations from purchasing power parity under different exchange rate regimes: Do they revert and, if so, how?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarno, Lucio; Valente, Giorgio
We propose an empirical model for deviations from long-run purchasing power parity (PPP) that simultaneously accounts for three key features: (i) adjustment toward PPP may occur via nominal exchange rates and relative prices at different speeds; (ii) different exchange rate regimes may generate regime shifts in the structural dynamics of PPP deviations; (iii) nonlinear reversion toward PPP in response to shocks. This empirical framework encompasses and synthesizes much previous empirical research. Using over a century of data for the G5 countries, we provide evidence that long-run PPP holds, the relative importance of nominal exchange rates and prices in restoring PPP varies over time and across different exchange rate regimes, and reversion to PPP occurs nonlinearly, at a speed that is fairly consistent with the nominal rigidities suggested by conventional open economy models. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sarno, Lucio; Valente, Giorgio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the estimation and comparison of short-rate models using the generalised method of moments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faff, Robert; Gray, Philip
Subsequent to the influential paper of [Chan, K.C., Karolyi, G.A., Longstaff, F.A., Sanders, A.B., 1992. An empirical comparison of alternative models of the short-term interest rate. Journal of Finance 47, 1209-1227], the generalised method of moments (GMM) has been a popular technique for estimation and inference relating to continuous-time models of the short-term interest rate. GMM has been widely employed to estimate model parameters and to assess the goodness-of-fit of competing short-rate specifications. The current paper conducts a series of simulation experiments to document the bias and precision of GMM estimates of short-rate parameters, as well as the size and power of [Hansen, L.P., 1982. Large sample properties of generalised method of moments estimators. Econometrica 50, 1029-1054], J-test of over-identifying restrictions. While the J-test appears to have appropriate size and good power in sample sizes commonly encountered in the short-rate literature, GMM estimates of the speed of mean reversion are shown to be severely biased. Consequently, it is dangerous to draw strong conclusions about the strength of mean reversion using GMM. In contrast, the parameter capturing the levels effect, which is important in differentiating between competing short-rate specifications, is estimated with little bias. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faff, Robert; Gray, Philip</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of factoring for financing small and medium enterprises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klapper, Leora
Factoring is explicitly linked to the value of a supplier's accounts receivable and receivables are sold, rather than collateralized, and factored receivables are not part of the estate of a bankrupt firm. Therefore, factoring may allow a high-risk supplier to transfer ifs credit risk to higher quality buyers. Empirical tests find that factoring is larger in countries with greater economic development and growth and developed credit information bureaus. "Reverse factoring" may mitigate the problem of borrowers' informational opacity if only receivables from high-quality buyers are factored. We illustrate the case of the Nafin reverse factoring program in Mexico. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Klapper, Leora</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>UK bank services for small business: How competitive is the market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heffernan, Shelagh
This study is the first to employ an econometric model to examine the pricing behaviour of British financial institutions with respect to key bank products/services offered to small and medium sized enterprises (SMEs) including current accounts, investment accounts, business loans, and mortgages. A mean group approach is used on a panel of monthly data to gauge individual banks' reactions to identify factors influencing the setting of deposit and loan rates, and to assess the competitive structure that best describes the UKs SME banking market. Though the results should be interpreted with caution, the empirical evidence is suggestive of a complex oligopoly. Policies directed at improving information and making it easier for small businesses to change banks/accounts would reduce inertia and improve competition among financial institutions. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heffernan, Shelagh</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business collateral and personal commitments in SME lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Voordeckers, Wim; Steijvers, Tensie
Using a database of SME credit approvals from a large Belgian bank, this paper extends the empirical evidence on the determinants of collateral by examining the determinants of business collateral simultaneously with the determinants of personal collateral/commitments. Our results suggest that firm and relationship characteristics seem to be more important determinants of collateral/commitment protection than loan and lender characteristics. Family firms are more likely to offer a higher degree of collateral/commitment protection while introducing competition between banks decreases this likelihood. The collateral requirement decreases in the length of the bank-borrower relationship. Furthermore, trade credit seems to have a signalling effect. The 'lazy banks hypothesis' was not supported. Our results suggest that beside risk arguments, also commercial arguments help explain the pledging of collateral. Using a continuation-ratio logit model, we discover several differences in the determinants of the collateralisation decision and the determinants of the type of collateral/commitments. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Voordeckers, Wim; Steijvers, Tensie</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>African SMES, networks, and manufacturing performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biggs, Tyler; Shah, Manju Kedia
This paper examines the role of private support institutions in determining small and medium enterprise (SMES) growth and performance in Sub-Saharan Africa (SSA). It finds that SMES in SSA get around market failures and lack of formal institutions by creating private governance systems in the form of long-term business relationships and tight, ethnically based, business networks. There are important links between these informal governance institutions and SME performance. Networks raise the performance of "insiders" and, in the sparse business environments of the SSA region, have attendant negative consequences for market participation of "outsiders," such as indigenous-African SMES. This is indicated through the determinants of access to supplier credit. Policy interventions will be needed to improve the platform for relation-based governance mechanisms and to address the exclusionary effects of tight networks. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Biggs, Tyler; Shah, Manju Kedia</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Historical financing of small- and medium-size enterprises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cull, Robert; Davis, Lance E.; Lamoreaux, Naomi R.; Rosenthal, Jean-Laurent
We focus on the economies of the North Atlantic Core during the 19th and early 20th centuries and find that an impressive variety of local financial institutions emerged to supply the needs of SMEs wherever there was sufficient demand for their services. Although these intermediaries had significant weaknesses, they were able to tap into local information networks and so extend credit to firms that were too young or small to secure funds from large regional or national institutions. In addition, by raising the return to savings for local households, they helped to mobilize significant new resources for economic development. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cull, Robert; Davis, Lance E.; Lamoreaux, Naomi R.; Rosenthal, Jean-Laurent</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The influence of financial and legal institutions on firm size</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav
Theory does not predict an unambiguous relationship between a country's financial and legal institutions and firm size. Using data on the largest industrial firms for 44 countries, we find that firm size is positively related to financial intermediary development, the efficiency of the legal system and property rights protection. We do not find any evidence that firms are larger in order to internalize the functions of the banking system or to compensate for the general inefficiency of the legal system. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business environment and the incorporation decision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demirguc-Kunt, Ash; Love, Inessa; Maksimovic, Vojislav
Using firm-level data from 52 countries we investigate how a country's institutions and business environment affect firm's organizational choices and what impact the organizational form has on access to finance and growth. We find that businesses are more likely to choose the corporate form in countries with developed financial sectors and efficient legal systems, strong shareholder and creditor rights, low regulatory burdens and corporate taxes and efficient bankruptcy processes. Corporations report fewer financing, legal and regulatory obstacles than unincorporated firms and this advantage is greater in countries with more developed institutions and favourable business environments. We do find some evidence of higher growth of incorporated businesses in countries with good financial and legal institutions. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Demirguc-Kunt, Ash; Love, Inessa; Maksimovic, Vojislav</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction: Special section on operational risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cummins, J. David; Embrechts, Paul
nan</description><author>Cummins, J. David; Embrechts, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Thirty years of continuous-time finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barone-Adesi, G.
nan</description><author>Barone-Adesi, G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From measure changes to time changes in asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geman, H.
The goal of the paper is to review the last 35 years of continuous-time finance by focusing on two major advances: (i) The powerful elegance of the martingale representation for primitive assets and attainable contingent claims in more and more general settings, thanks to the probabilistic tool of probability change and the economic flexibility in the choice of the numeraire relative to which prices are expressed. This numeraire evolved over time from the money market account to a zero-coupon bond or a stock price, lastly to strictly positive quantities involved in the Libor or swap market models and making the pricing of caps or swaptions quite efficient. (ii) The persistent central role of Brownian motion in finance across the 20th century: even when the underlying asset price is a very general semi-martingale, the no-arbitrage assumption and Monroe theorem [Monroe, 1., 1978. Processes that can be embedded in Brownian motion. Annals of Probability 6, 42-56] allow us to write it as Brownian motion as long as we are willing to change the time. The appropriate stochastic clock can be shown empirically to be driven by the cumulative number of trades, hence by market activity. Consequently, starting with a general multidimensional stochastic process S defined on a probability space (Omega,F,F-t,P) and representing the prices of primitive securities, the no-arbitrage assumption allows, for any chosen numeraire, to obtain a martingale representation for S under a probability measure Q(S) equivalent to P. This route will be particularly beneficiary for the pricing of complex contingent claims. Alternatively, changing the clock, i.e., changing the filtration (F-t), we can recover the Brownian motion and normality of returns. In all cases martingales appear as the central representation of asset prices, either through a measure change or through a time change. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Geman, H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unspanned stochastic volatility and fixed income derivatives pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casassus, J.; Collin-Dufresne, P.; Goldstein, B.
We propose a parsimonious 'unspanned stochastic volatility' model of the term structure and study its implications for fixed-income option prices. The drift and quadratic variation of the short rate are affine in three state variables (the short rate, its long-term mean and variance) which follow a joint Markov (vector) process. Yet, bond prices are exponential affine functions of only two state variables, independent of the current interest rate volatility level. Because this result holds for an arbitrary volatility process, such a process can be calibrated to match fixed income derivative prices. Furthermore, this model can be 'extended' (by relaxing the time-homogeneity) to fit any arbitrary term structure. In its 'HJM' form, this model nests the analogous stochastic equity volatility model of Heston (190) [Heston, S.L., 1993. A closed form solution for options with stochastic volatility. Review of Financial Studies 6, 327-343]. In particular, if the volatility process is specified to be affine, closed-form solutions for interest rate options obtain. We propose an efficient algorithm to compute these prices. An application using data on caps and floors shows that the model can capture very well the implied Black spot volatility surface, while simultaneously fitting the observed term structure. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Casassus, J.; Collin-Dufresne, P.; Goldstein, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The saga of the American put</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barone-Adesi, G.
The American put is one of the oldest problems in mathematical finance. We review the development of the relevant literature over the last 40 years. Today the mainstream computational problems have been solved satisfactorily and the target of research is shifting towards the development of further insights into the value of timing investment decisions. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barone-Adesi, G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management implications of time-inconsistency: Model updating and recalibration of no-arbitrage models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, A.; Corielli, F.
A widespread approach in the implementation of asset pricing models is based on the periodic recalibration of its parameters and initial conditions to eliminate any conflict between model-implied and market prices. Modern no-arbitrage market models facilitate this procedure since their solution can usually be written in terms of the entire initial yield curve. As a result, the model fits (by construction) the interest rate term structure. This procedure is, however, generally time inconsistent since the model at time t = 0 completely specifies the set of possible term structures for any t &gt; 0. In this paper, we analyze the pros and-cons of this widespread approach in pricing and hedging, both theoretically and empirically. The theoretical section of the paper shows (a) under which conditions recalibration improves the hedging errors by limiting the propagation of an initial error, (b) that recalibration introduces time-inconsistent errors that violate the self-financing argument of the standard replication strategy. The empirical section of the paper quantifies the trade-off between (a) and (b) under several scenarios. First, we compare this trade-off for two economies with and without model specification error. Then, we discuss the trade-off when the underlying economy is not Markovian. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buraschi, A.; Corielli, F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing with heterogeneous beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, S.
This paper studies the dynamic behavior of security prices in the presence of investors' heterogeneous beliefs. We provide a tractable continuous-time pure-exchange model and highlight the mechanism through which investors' differences of opinion enter into security prices. In the determination of equilibrium, we employ a representative investor with stochastic weights and solve for all economic quantities in closed form, including the perceived market prices of risk and interest rate. The basic analysis is generalized to incorporate multiple sources of risk, disagreement about nonfundamentals, and multiple investors. Other applications involving multiple goods and nominal asset pricing within monetary economies are discussed. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Basak, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intertemporal asset allocation: A comparison of methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Detemple, J.; Garcia, R.; Rindisbacher, M.
This paper compares two recent Monte Carlo methods advocated for the computation of optimal portfolio rules. The candidate methods are the approach based on Monte Carlo with Malliavin Derivatives (MCMD) proposed by Detemple, Garcia and Rindisbacher [Detemple et al., 2003. A Monte-Carlo method for optimal portfolios. Journal of Finance 58, 401-406] and the approach based on Monte Carlo with regression (MCR) of Brandt, Goyal, Santa-Clara and Stroud [Brandt et al., 2003. A simulation approach to dynamic portfolio choice with an application to learning about return predictability. Working paper, Wharton School]. Our comparisons are carried out in the context of various intertemporal portfolio choice problems with two assets, a risky asset and a riskless asset, and different configurations of the state variables. The specifications studied include a linear model with a single state variable admitting an exact solution and a non-linear model with two state variables that requires a purely numerical resolution. The accuracies of the candidate methods are compared. We provide, in particular, efficiency plots displaying the speed-accuracy trade-off for various selections of the relevant simulation and discretization parameters. MCMD is shown to dominate in all the settings considered. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Detemple, J.; Garcia, R.; Rindisbacher, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large traders, hidden arbitrage, and complete markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jarrow, R.; Protter, P.
This paper studies hidden arbitrage opportunities in markets where large traders affect the price process, and where the market is complete (in the classical sense). The arbitrage opportunities are "hidden" because they occur on a small set of times (typically of Lebesgue measure zero). These arbitrage opportunities occur naturally in markets where a large trader supports the price of some asset or commodity, for example corporate stock repurchase plans, government interest rate or foreign currency intervention, and price support by investment banks in IPOs. We also illustrate immediate arbitrage opportunities generated by usual market activity at specific points in time, for example the issuance date of an IPO or the inclusion date of a new stock in the S&amp;P 500 index. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jarrow, R.; Protter, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit risk modeling with affine processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffie, D.
This article combines an orientation to credit risk modeling with an introduction to affine Markov processes, which are particularly useful for financial modeling. We emphasize corporate credit risk and the pricing of credit derivatives. Applications of affine processes that are mentioned include survival analysis, dynamic term-structure models, and option pricing with stochastic volatility and jumps. The default-risk applications include default correlation, particularly in first-to-default settings. The reader is assumed to have some background in financial modeling and stochastic calculus. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duffie, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling time series information into option prices: An empirical evaluation of statistical projection and GARCH option pricing model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, A. S.; Leung, M. T.
This paper compares the empirical performances of statistical projection models with those of the Black-Scholes (adapted to account for skew) and the GARCH option pricing models. Empirical analysis on S&amp;P500 index options shows that the out-of-sample pricing and projected trading performances of the semi-parametric and nonparametric projection models are substantially better than more traditional models. Results further indicate that econometric models based on nonlinear projections of observable inputs perform better than models based on OLS projections, consistent with the notion that the true unobservable option pricing model is inherently a nonlinear function of its inputs. The econometric option models presented in this paper should prove useful and complement mainstream mathematical modeling methods in both research and practice. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, A. S.; Leung, M. T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical credit cycles and capital buffer formation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koopman, S. J.; Lucas, A.; Klaassen, P.
We model 1927-1997 US business failure rates using an unobserved components time series model. Clear evidence is found of cyclical behavior in default rates. We also detect significant longer term movements in default rates and default correlations. In a multi-year backtest experiment we show that accommodation of default rate dynamics has important consequences for credit risk capitalization requirements. Static or myopic variants of credit portfolio models miss significant periods of credit risk accumulation. Empirically congruent dynamic models by contrast provide more timely warning signals of credit risk build-up. In this way they may mitigate some of the pro-cyclicality concerns. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koopman, S. J.; Lucas, A.; Klaassen, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the importance of systematic risk factors in explaining the cross-section of corporate bond yield spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>King, T. H. D.; Khang, K.
In this paper we examine the importance of systematic equity market factors in explaining the cross-sectional variation in yield spreads on corporate debt. Based on a sample of 1771 corporate bonds over the period from January 1985 to March 1998, we find that once the default-related variables are con trolled for, bond betas or sensitivities to aggregate equity market risks have very limited explanatory power. This is in contrast to [Elton, E.J., Gruber, M.J., 2001. Explaining the rate spread on corporate bonds. Journal of Finance 56, 247-277] who find that market factors tied to expected returns are predominantly important, but who do not control for these variables (i.e. the relevant variables from structural models), possibly biasing their estimates. On the other hand, our finding that the systematic factors exhibit some limited explanatory power suggests that the standard contingent claims approach may not fully apply. This finding is consistent with previous research that bond betas are not completely irrelevant once market frictions are introduced. Overall, the evidence provides empirical support for the proposition that structural models capture important elements of corporate bond yield spread determination and equity market systematic factors are by no means predominant. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>King, T. H. D.; Khang, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital requirements and business cycle regimes: Forward-looking modelling of default probabilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pederzoli, C.; Torricelli, C.
This paper proposes a forward-looking model for time-varying capital requirements, which finds application within Basel II. The model rests on the relationship between default rates and the business cycle: by positing two regimes, expansion and recession, and by forecasting the associated probabilities, the default probability for each rating class is defined as the expected value of a default rate whose distribution is a mixture of an expansion and a recession distribution. The application to US data over the forecasting period 1971-2002 provides evidence that the model makes it possible to preserve the risk sensitivity of the capital requirement and at the same time to dampen procyclicality. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pederzoli, C.; Torricelli, C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How should Central Banks determine and control their bank note inventory?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massoud, N.
This paper looks at a relatively unresearched but important area in money and banking namely the provision of currency by the Central Bank. One of the most important functions of Central Banking is the provision of liquidity to the economy. However, in fulfilling this function, Central Banks have to be prepared for unexpected money demand shocks as well as production, transportation and cost of capital constraints. The paper develops a dynamic cost minimizing note inventory model that solves for the Central Bank's optimal note order size and frequency. As part of the modeling exercise a value at risk model is used to solve for an inventory "cushion." (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Massoud, N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sources of liquidity for NYSE-listed non-US stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bacidore, J. M.; Battallo, R.; Galpin, N.; Jennings, R.
We examine the components of displayed (quoted) liquidity and the amount of non-displayed liquidity on the NYSE for a sample of non-US stocks. Consistently with prior work, non-US stocks have less displayed liquidity than similar US stocks. Extending prior research, we find that this is true both in the limit order book and on the floor. As Domowitz et al. [Domowitz, I., Glen, J., Madhavan, A., 1998. International cross-listing and order flow migration: Evidence from and emerging market. Journal of Finance 53, 2001-2027] posit, non-US stocks from transparent/linked home markets have more displayed NYSE liquidity when the home market is open but non-US stocks from opaque/non-linked home markets have more NYSE displayed liquidity when the home market is closed. Non-US and US stocks have similar supplies of non-displayed liquidity, consistent with the idea that the conditional nature of non-displayed liquidity allows NYSE traders to mitigate adverse selection problems inherent in trading non-US stocks. Our results imply that non-US stocks have less total (displayed plus non-displayed) liquidity than US stocks. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bacidore, J. M.; Battallo, R.; Galpin, N.; Jennings, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital market equilibrium with externalities, production and heterogeneous agents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beltratti, A.
The paper studies general equilibrium in an economy with externalities, production and heterogeneous agents. The model developed builds on Brock [Brock, W.A., 1982. Asset prices in a production economy. In: McCall, J.J. (Ed.), The Economics of Information and Uncertainty. University of Chicago Press, Chicago, pp. 1-43] and Merton [Merton, R.C., 1987. A simple model of capital market equilibrium with incomplete information. Journal of Finance 42, 483-510]; it involves both a stock market and a market for loans, together with negative externalities produced by a subset of firms. Importantly, the technological production structure of the firms is reflected in the properties of the shares traded in the stock market. Agents are heterogeneous in their financial choices, potentially discriminating against the firms producing a negative externality. The model sheds light on the utility costs of the discriminating behavior and on the impact on the price of the stock issued by the firm which is responsible for the externality. The model is used to study the factors which may magnify or reduce the impact of discrimination. A set of discriminated firms may be seriously affected only if the discriminating investors command a large portion of overall wealth and/or they do not represent important diversification instruments. The model can be applied to understanding the effects of socially responsible investment, whereby investors discriminate against companies belonging to some sectors which are perceived as socially dangerous or unethical. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beltratti, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of dealer markets and trading costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, K. H.; Kim, Y.
In this study we examine the temporal dynamics of dealer market share and their ramification for competition and trading costs using a large sample of NASDAQ securities. Our results show that although the total market share of the top five dealers is relatively stable over time, there is significant monthly variation in the composition of the top five dealers. We show that market share turbulence among top dealers is another form of competition that narrows bid-ask spreads, especially for stocks with less competitive market structure. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, K. H.; Kim, Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry aspects of takeovers and divestitures: Evidence from the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Powell, R.; Yawson, A.
This paper examines takeover and divestiture activity at the industry level for the population of UK firms over the period 1986-2000. Consistent with US research, takeovers in the UK cluster both across industries and over time. The evidence for divestitures indicates clustering across industries only. The paper further investigates whether broad and specific industry shocks (e.g., growth, free cash flow, concentration, deregulation, foreign competition, technology, stock market performance) explain takeover and divestiture clustering at the industry level. The results suggest that broad shocks increase (decrease) the likelihood of takeovers (divestitures), although not significantly for takeovers. Specific industry shocks that increase the likelihood of takeover activity include low growth, the threat of foreign competition and high stock market performance. For divestitures, high industry concentration and deregulation increase activity. Little evidence is found for deregulation as a significant factor in explaining takeover activity. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Powell, R.; Yawson, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An examination of alternative CAPM-based models in UK stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fletcher, J.; Kihanda, J.
We evaluate the performance of unconditional and conditional versions of seven stochastic discount factor models in UK stock returns between January 1975 and December 2001. We find that the conditional four-moment capital asset pricing model (CAPM) has the best performance among the models we consider in terms of the lowest [Hansen, L.P., Jagannathan, R., 1997. Assessing specification errors in stochastic discount factor models. Journal of Finance 52, 591-607] distance measure and explaining the time-series predictability of industry portfolio excess returns. Conditional models also do a better job than unconditional models. However we find that the superior performance of the conditional four-moment CAPM, and conditional models in general, arises in part due to overfitting the data. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fletcher, J.; Kihanda, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are structured products 'fairly' priced? An analysis of the German market for equity-linked instruments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoimenov, P. A.; Wilkens, S.
Based on a unique data set, this paper examines the pricing of equity-linked structured products in the German market. The daily closing prices of a large variety of structured products are compared to theoretical values derived from the prices of options traded on the Eurex (European Exchange). For the majority of products, the study reveals large implicit premiums charged by the issuing banks in the primary market. A set of driving factors behind the issuers' pricing policies is identified, for example, underlying and type of implicit derivative(s). For the secondary market, the product life cycle is found to be an important pricing parameter. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stoimenov, P. A.; Wilkens, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio preferences of foreign institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, R.; Klapper, L.; Wysocki, P. D.
This paper examines the investment allocation choices of actively-managed US mutual funds in emerging market equities after the market crises of the 1990s. We analyze both courtry- and firm-level disclosure and institutional policies that influence mutual funds' allocation choices relative to major stock market indices. At the country level, we find that US funds invest more in open emerging markets with stronger accounting standards, shareholder rights, and legal frameworks. At the firm level, US funds are found to invest more in firms that adopt discretionary policies such as greater accounting transparency and the issuance of an ADR. Our results suggest that steps can be taken both at the country and the firm level to create an environment conducive to foreign institutional investment. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, R.; Klapper, L.; Wysocki, P. D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An appreciation of Lawrence G Goldberg</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saunders, A.
nan</description><author>Saunders, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comment on "optimal portfolio selection in a value-at-risk framework"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, H. H.
This comment discusses some errors in [Journal of Banking and Finance 25 (2001) 1789]. Given the portfolio rate of return is normally distributed, the following can be inferred. First, taking expected portfolio return rate as the benchmark of value-at-risk (VaR), the risk-return ratio collapses to a multiple of the Sharpe index. However, using risk-free rate as the benchmark, then above inference does not hold. Second, whether the benchmark of VaR is expected portfolio return rate or the risk-free rate, the optimal asset allocations for maximizing the risk-return ratio and Sharpe index are identical. (c) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, H. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee stock options as warrants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eberhart, A. C.
Previous studies ignore the fact that employee stock options are warrants because these options have been an insignificant component of firms' capital structures. I show that this assumption is no longer correct. For example, for more than 36%, of my sample firms, employee stock options represent a more significant claim on firm value than the firm's debt and preferred stock combined. Moreover, in contrast to the suggestions of previous research, I show that employee stock options are a significant claim on firms throughout the economy, including larger firms, older firms, and firms in "Old Economy" industries. Finally, I show that the presumption in prior studies that employee stock options are not warrants causes a potential misunderstanding of the risk-shifting interests of securityliolders and biases the analysis of capital structure issues. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eberhart, A. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privatization and bank performance in developing countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubakri, N.; Cosset, J. C.; Fischer, K.; Guedhami, O.
We examine the postprivatization performance of 81 banks from 22 developing countries. Our results suggest that: (i) On average, banks chosen for privatization have a lower economic efficiency, and a lower solvency than banks kept under government ownership. (ii) In the postprivatization period, profitability increases but, depending on the type of owner, efficiency, risk exposure and capitalization may worsen or improve. However, (iii) Over time, privatization yields significant improvements in economic efficiency and credit risk exposure. (iv) We also find that newly privatized banks that are controlled by local industrial groups become more exposed to credit risk and interest rate risk after privatization. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubakri, N.; Cosset, J. C.; Fischer, K.; Guedhami, O.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank privatization in developing and developed countries: Cross-sectional evidence on the impact of economic and political factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, E.; Nash, R. C.; Netter, J. M.
We examine how political, institutional, and economic factors are related to a country's decision to privatize state-owned banks. Using a panel of 101 countries from 1982 to 2000, we find that political factors significantly affect the likelihood of bank privatization only in developing countries. Specifically, in non-OECD countries, bank privatization is more likely the more accountable the government is to its people. In contrast, none of our political variables affects the bank privatization decision in developed countries. Economic factors (such as the quality of the nation's banking sector) are significant determinants of bank privatization in both OECD and non-OECD nations. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boehmer, E.; Nash, R. C.; Netter, J. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of bank privatization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Megginson, W. L.
This paper surveys the empirical literature examining bank privatization. We begin by documenting the extent of, theoretical rationale for, and measured performance of state-owned banks around the world, and then assess why many governments have chosen to privatize their often very large state-owned banking sectors. The empirical evidence clearly shows that state-owned banks are less efficient than privately owned banks, and that state domination of banking imposes increasingly severe penalties on those countries with the largest state banking sectors. On the other hand, there is little in the empirical record to suggest that privatization alone transforms the efficiency of divested banks, especially when these are only partially privatized. Privatization generally improves performance, but by far less than is typically observed in studies of non-financial industries. An increasingly common outcome of large-scale bank privatization programs is foreign ownership of many nations' banking sector, which evidence suggests is usually positive in an economic sense, but problematic politically. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Megginson, W. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank privatization in developing countries: A summary of lessons and findings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, G. R. G.; Cull, R.; Shirley, M. M.
Although a large and growing literature shows that privatization can improve the performance of non-financial enterprises, there is less evidence on how it affects the performance of the banking sector. This paper summarizes the results from the papers in the special issue of the Journal of Banking and Finance on bank privatization. It concludes that although bank privatization usually improves bank efficiency, gains are greater when the government fully relinquishes control, when banks are privatized to strategic investors, when foreign banks are allowed to participate in the privatization process and when the government does not restrict competition. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Clarke, G. R. G.; Cull, R.; Shirley, M. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to the special issue on bank privatization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, G. R. G.; Cull, R.; Megginson, W.
nan</description><author>Clarke, G. R. G.; Cull, R.; Megginson, W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fair insurance guaranty premia in the presence of risk-based capital regulations, stochastic interest rate and catastrophe risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duan, J. C.; Yu, M. T.
A multiperiod model is developed to measure the costs posed to the guaranty fund in a setting that incorporates risk-based capital regulations, interest rate risk and the possibility of catastrophic losses. The guaranty contract is modeled as a put option on the asset of the insurance company with a stochastic strike price and an uncertain maturity. The impacts of the key factors of this model are examined numerically and shown to make material differences in the costs to the guaranty fund. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duan, J. C.; Yu, M. T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection, prospect theory, and earnings management: An international comparison of the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shen, C. H.; Chih, H. L.
This paper raises three issues related to the earnings management (EM) of banks across 48 countries. First, does earnings management of banks exist in all 48 countries? Second, what is the incentive of banks to manage earnings? Third, why does EM vary across countries? To answer these three questions, two thresholds (viz., a threshold of zero earnings and a threshold of zero earnings change) are employed. The answer to the first question above is that banks in more than two-thirds of the 48 countries sampled are found to have managed their earnings. With respect to the second question, prospect theory is used to provide an answer. The relationship between return and risk is positive for high earnings groups, but is negative for low earnings banks. Finally, as to the last question, stronger protection of investors and greater transparency in accounting disclosure can reduce banks' incentives to manage earnings. Also, higher real GDP per capita decreases the degree of earnings management. It is seen that stronger enforcement of laws can counter intuitively result in stronger earnings management. However, this effect appears in low-income countries only, and not in high-income countries. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shen, C. H.; Chih, H. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Re-examining the asymmetric predictability of conditional variances: The role of sudden changes in variance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ewing, B. T.; Malik, F.
The existence of "spillover effects" in financial markets is well documented and multivariate time series techniques have been used to study the transmission of conditional variances among large and small market value firms. Earlier research has suggested that volatility surprises to large capitalization firms are a reliable predictor of the volatility of small capitalization firms. A related line of research has examined how regime shifts in volatility may account for a considerable amount of the persistence in volatility. However, these studies have focused on univariate modeling and many have imposed regime changes on a priori grounds. This paper re-examines the asymmetry in the predictability of the volatilities of large versus small market value firms allowing for sudden changes in variance. Our method of analysis extends the existing literature in two important ways. First, recent advances in time series econometrics allow us to detect the time periods of sudden changes in volatility of large cap and small cap stocks endogenously using the iterated cumulated sums of squares (ICSS) algorithm. Second, we directly incorporate the information obtained on sudden changes in volatility in a Bivariate GARCH model of small and large cap stock returns. Our findings indicate that accounting for volatility shifts considerably reduces the transmission in volatility and, in essence, removes the spillover effects. We conclude that ignoring regime changes may lead one to significantly overestimate the degree of volatility transmission that actually exists between the conditional variances of small and large firms. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ewing, B. T.; Malik, F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A test for rational bubbles in the NASDAQ stock index: A fractionally integrated approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cunado, J.; Gil-Alana, L. A.; de Gracia, F. P.
In this paper we test for the presence of rational bubbles in the NASDAQ stock market index over the period 1994:06-2003:11 by means of a methodology based on fractional processes. The results suggest that the existence of bubbles depends on the sampling frequency used in the analysis. We cannot reject the unit root hypothesis when using monthly data on price-dividend ratios, which according to the present value model suggests the existence of rational bubbles. However, we reject this hypothesis in favor of fractional alternatives when using daily and weekly data. This might be explained by the temporal aggregation and/or the sample sizes used in the application. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cunado, J.; Gil-Alana, L. A.; de Gracia, F. P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is learning a dimension of risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, M.; Simonov, A.
We empirically assess how the uncertainty induced by investors' learning about the fundamentals affects stock returns. We identify two components of induced uncertainty: learning uncertainty and dispersion of beliefs. We characterize these in terms of their relationship to uncertainty about the fundamentals as estimated by surveys of economic forecasters and to measures of uncertainty embedded in derivative markets (open interest and implied volatility). We show that both learning uncertainty and dispersion of beliefs are conditionally priced. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Massa, M.; Simonov, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring systemic risk: A risk management approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lehar, A.
This paper proposes a new method to measure and monitor the risk in a banking system. Standard tools that regulators require banks to use for their internal risk management are applied at the level of the banking system to measure the risk of a regulator's portfolio. Using a sample of international banks from 1988 until 2002, 1 estimate the dynamics and correlations between bank asset portfolios. To obtain measures for the risk of a regulator's portfolio, I model the individual liabilities that the regulator has to each bank as contingent claims on the bank's assets. The portfolio aspect of the regulator's liability is explicitly considered and the methodology allows a comparison of sub-samples from different countries. Correlations, bank asset volatility, and bank capitalization increase for North American and somewhat for European banks, while Japanese banks face deteriorating capital levels. In the sample period, the North American banking system gains stability while the Japanese banking sector becomes more fragile. The expected future liability of the regulator varies substantially over time and is especially high during the Asian crisis starting in 1997. Further analysis shows that the Japanese banks contribute most to the volatility of the regulator's liability at that time. Larger and more profitable banks have lower systemic risk and additional equity capital reduces systemic risk only for banks that are constrained by regulatory capital requirements. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lehar, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks, financial markets, and social welfare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marini, F.
This paper constructs a general equilibrium model of banking and financial markets. The model allows to compare financial systems in which banks have access to financial markets with financial systems in which banks do not have access to financial markets. Allen and Gale [A welfare comparison of intermediaries and financial markets in Germany and the US. European Economic Review 39 (1995) 179-209] find that the Anglo-Saxon model of financial intermediation in which financial markets play a dominant role does'not necessarily improve social welfare in comparison with the German model in which banks dominate. Our model provides a theoretical foundation for this view. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marini, F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tests of the expectations hypothesis: Resolving the anomalies when the short-term rate is the federal funds rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thornton, D. L.
The expectations hypothesis (EH) of the term structure plays an important role in the analysis of monetary policy, where shorter-term rates are assumed to be determined by the market's expectation for the overnight federal funds rate. With two exceptions, tests using the effective federal funds rate as the short-term rate easily reject the EH. These exceptions are when the EH is tested over the nonborrowed reserve targeting period and when the test is performed only using data for settlement Wednesdays - the last day of bank reserve maintenance period. This paper argues that these exceptions are anomalous: in the former case, the failure to reject the EH occurs when economic analysis suggests that the market should be less able to forecast the federal funds rate. In the latter case, it occurs when there are sharp spikes in the funds rate that cannot improve materially the market's ability to forecast the funds rate. Additional analysis shows that these anomalous results are a consequence of the procedure used to test the EH. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thornton, D. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational bubbles or persistent deviations from market fundamentals?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koustas, Z.; Serletis, A.
Tests for fractional integration in the S&amp;P 500 log dividend yield are conducted in order to test the proposition that exogenous shocks have permanent effects. The presence of a unit root in the log dividend yield is consistent with 'rational bubbles' in stock prices. Our findings, based on tests for fractional integration, yield robust rejections of the null hypothesis of rational bubbles. The results strongly suggest that the log dividend yield is mean reverting. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koustas, Z.; Serletis, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The implied jump risk of LIBOR rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, K. G.; Ting, C.; Warachka, M.
This paper examines implied parameters from options on LIBOR futures. Jump-diffusion models are found to offer superior in-sample and out-of-sample performance when compared to their pure diffusion counterpart. The need to incorporate stochastic jump magnitudes into LIBOR dynamics is also documented. In addition, empirical evidence reveals that the jump component in LIBOR rates is important for pricing their derivatives. Furthermore, variation in jump risk often coincides with Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) decisions and a small subset of macroeconomic announcements. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lim, K. G.; Ting, C.; Warachka, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic stock market integration driven by the European Monetary Union: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, S. J.; Moshirian, F.; Wu, E.
We examine the influence of the European Monetary Union (EMU) on the dynamic process of stock market integration over the period 2 January 1989-29 May 2003 using a bivariate EGARCH framework with time-varying conditional correlations. We find that there has been a clear regime shift in European stock market integration with the introduction of the EMU. The EMU has been necessary for stock market integration as unidirectional causality was found. Linear systems regression analysis shows that the increase in both regional and global stock market integration over this period was significantly driven in part, by macroeconomic convergence associated with the introduction of the EMU and financial development levels. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, S. J.; Moshirian, F.; Wu, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring the value of strategic alliances in the wake of a financial implosion: Evidence from Japan's financial services sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiou, I.; White, L. J.
This paper examines the wealth effects of financial-institution strategic alliances on the shareholders of the newly allied firms. Our paper is different from most previous studies, in that we focus on financial institutions, we employ Japanese data for the late 1990s, and we study whether different types of alliances result in differing magnitudes of stock market responses. We find that a strategic alliance, on average, increases the value of the partner firms. Second, the gains from the alliance are spread more widely among the partners than would be suggested by a random alternative. Third, smaller partners tend to experience larger percentage gains. Fourth, the market values inter-group alliance announcements more than intragroup alliance announcements. Fifth, we do not find a significant difference in the abnormal returns shown by domestic-foreign alliances and domestic-domestic alliances. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiou, I.; White, L. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do privatized banks in middle- and low-income countries perform better than rival banks? An intra-industry analysis of bank privatization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Otchere, I.
This paper presents a comprehensive analysis of the pre- and post-privatization operating performance and stock market performance of privatized banks and their rivals in middle- and low-income countries. First, we find that privatization announcements elicit negative abnormal returns for rival banks. The effects are more pronounced for subsequent tranche sales where the proportion of government ownership in the privatized bank is reduced. Second, we observe that the privatized banks underperformed the benchmark index in the long run. Investors who bought shares of the privatized banks on the first day of trading and held them for 5 years (instead of investing in the market index) lost 24% of their wealth. The underperformance is consistent with the negative long run returns that have been documented for initial public offerings. Third, we document marginal improvements in the post-privatization operating performance of the privatized banks. Though the privatized banks in middle- and low-income countries are better capitalized than rival banks, they carry higher problem loans and are overstaffed relative to other private banks in the post-privatization period. Since most of the sample firms are partially privatized, we submit that perhaps the continued government ownership of the privatized banks might have hindered managers' ability to restructure the firms. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Otchere, I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns to acquirers of privatizing financial services firms: An international examination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gleason, K.; McNulty, J. E.; Pennathur, A. K.
While the literature reports improved performance for privatizing firms, banking markets are different. Many privatizing financial services firms face unique problems such as an overhang of problem loans and weak credit cultures and legal systems. We investigate the returns to successful bidders in privatization acquisitions of financial services firms, examine short-horizon performance, and test whether such acquisitions result in a change in risk for the bidding firm. Our results show that the cumulative abnormal returns to shareholders of bidding firms are positive, perhaps reflecting initial optimism that the foreign firm acquiring the privatizing firm would share in the success associated with privatization. Bidders also experience an increase in their total risk following the acquisition. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gleason, K.; McNulty, J. E.; Pennathur, A. K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate valuation and the resolution of bank insolvency in East Asia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Djankov, S.; Jindra, J.; Klapper, L. F.
We examine the valuation effect of the resolution of a bank's insolvency on commercial clients. Our sample includes 29 insolvent banks in Indonesia, Korea, and Thailand that serve as main creditors for 269 publicly traded companies. Our findings suggest that a bank relationship adds value to a firm, and that this value depends on investors' certainty in the continuity of the banking relationship. Significant cumulative returns for 50 days following the event date suggest that the type of resolution has real effects on the performance of related firms above initial expectations. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Djankov, S.; Jindra, J.; Klapper, L. F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of UK building society conversion on pricing behaviour</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heffernan, S.
The Building Society Act.. 1986, allowed British building societies to convert from mutual to plc bank status - quoted on the stock market. Eight mutuals converted in the period 1995-2000. This study examines the pricing behaviour of the converted mutuals and remaining building societies to address the question of whether a change in ownership structure caused managers of the new stock banks to place profit/shareholder concerns ahead of the interests of the customer/owners of mutual building societies. Econometric tests using monthly interest rate data (1995-2001) on deposit products and mortgages confirm that managers began to set prices which would improve profits, at the expense of depositors and mortgagees. Deposit/mortgage rates were found to be permanently lower/higher post-conversion, the converts responded more rapidly to changes in the market rate of interest. and the new banks offered proportionately more rip-offs than the remaining building societies. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heffernan, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives for risk-taking in banking - A unified approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jeitschko, T. D.; Jeung, S. D.
It is often claimed that well-capitalized banks are less inclined to increase asset risk. because the option value of deposit insurance decreases with capitalization. However, bankers, regulators and some academics challenge this view. Since the traditional view relies on studies that neglect the managerial agency problem and do not consider "higher-risk, higher-return" assets, we revisit the issue assuming that three agents - deposit insurers, shareholders, and managers - all influence banks' risk levels. We examine four distinct assumptions on the characteristics of risk-return profiles and derive conditions under which banks' risk decreases or increases with capitalization. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jeitschko, T. D.; Jeung, S. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privatization under incomplete information and bankruptcy risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerji, S.; Errunza, V. R.
We study privatization under moral hazard and adverse selection. We show that if the fraction of efficient investors is either insignificant or productivity differences between efficient and inefficient investors are negligible, the government would offer a pooling contract and sell the same fraction of equity to both types of investors. The lower the productivity difference. the greater the equity stake offered to investors. On the other hand, if the fraction of efficient investors is significant or productivity differentials are large, the optimal policy consists of a dual method of privatization in which it offers two methods of privatization to outside investors. The first method consists of a sale of 100% equity together with a subsidy and charges higher price. Under the second option. the investor pays a smaller price but buys less than 100% equity without any subsidy. Efficient investors opt for the first method while inefficient investors prefer the second. The dual privatization method screens investors and provides them with maximum incentives to invest while minimizing the risk of post-privatization bankruptcy. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Banerji, S.; Errunza, V. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and hedging interest rate options: Evidence from cap-floor markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, A.; Subrahmanyam, M. G.
We examine the pricing and hedging performance of interest rate option pricing models using daily data on US dollar cap and floor prices across both strike rates and maturities. Our results show that fitting the skew of the underlying interest rate probability distribution provides accurate pricing results within a one-factor framework. However, for hedging performance introducing a second stochastic factor is more important than fitting the skew of the underlying distribution. This constitutes evidence against claims in the literature that correctly specified and calibrated one-factor models could replace multi-factor models for consistent pricing and hedging of interest rate contingent claims. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gupta, A.; Subrahmanyam, M. G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous product differentiation in credit markets: What do borrowers pay for?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, M.; Kristiansen, E. G.; Vale, B.
This paper studies strategies pursued by banks in order to differentiate their services and soften competition. More specifically we analyze whether bank's ability to avoid losses, its capital ratio. or bank size can be used as strategic variables to make banks different and increase the interest rates banks can charge their borrowers in equilibrium. Using a panel of data covering Norwegian banks between 1993 and 1998 we find empirical support that the ability to avoid losses. measured by the ratio of loss provisions, may act as such a strategic variable. A likely interpretation is that borrowers use high-quality low-loss banks to signal their creditworthiness to other stakeholders. This supports the hypothesis that high-quality banks serve as certifiers for their borrowers. Furthermore. this suggests that not only lenders and Supervisors but also borrowers may discipline banks to avoid losses. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, M.; Kristiansen, E. G.; Vale, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of asset allocation advice: Evidence from The Economist's quarterly portfolio poll</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Annaert, J.; De Ceuster, M. J. K.; Van Hyfte, W.
This study analyzes the economic importance of portfolio advice for an investor with an international and multiple-asset investment strategy. We construct portfolios based upon the asset allocation and security market advice of major international investment bankers and analyze the performance using weight-based techniques. Our results indicate that portfolio advisers are not able to outperform passive benchmarks. They do not realize superior performance either through appropriate timing or selection skills. Apparent market timing skills as measured by the Portfolio Change Measure are to a large extent an artifact caused by serial correlation in the return indices used. Likewise, the apparent short-run performance persistence is more due to the serial correlation in returns than to active portfolio selection strategies. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Annaert, J.; De Ceuster, M. J. K.; Van Hyfte, W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio performance measurement using APM-free kernel models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayadi, M. A.; Kryzanowski, L.
A general asset-pricing framework is used to derive a conditional asset-pricing kernel that accounts efficiently for time variation in expected returns and risk. and is suitable to perform (un)conditional evaluations of passive and dynamic investment strategies. The positive abnormal unconditional performance of Canadian equity mutual funds over the period 1989-1999 becomes negative with conditioning, and is robust to the removal of ex post index mimickers. The reversal in the size-based performance results with limited information conditioning is alleviated somewhat with an expansion of the conditioning set. The performance statistics are weakly sensitive to changes in the level of relative risk aversion of the uninformed investor. Unconditional positive performances based on averages of individual fund performances lose their significance when cross-correlations are accounted for using the block-bootstrap method. Estimates of survivorship bias due to the elimination of funds with shorter lives. which range from 36 to 58 basis points per year, are stable across performance models but differ across groupings by fund objective. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ayadi, M. A.; Kryzanowski, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic risk does not matter: A re-examination of the relationship between average returns and average volatilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wei, S. X.; Zhang, C.
A recent study by Goyal and Santa-Clara [J. Finance 58 (2003) 9751 finds a significantly positive relationship between average stock returns and pre-determined average return volatility measures, while finding no relationship between the average return and its own volatility. The result is interpreted as evidence that idiosyncratic risk matters in asset pricing. We re-examine the issue in extended sample periods and find the proclaimed positive relationship is not substantiated. Our analysis indicates that the above-mentioned positive. relationship is mainly driven by the data in the 1990s. The trading strategy suggested by Goyal and Santa-Clara to exploit the return predictability by pre-determined volatility does not yield sustained economic gains. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Wei, S. X.; Zhang, C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption habit and international stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Y. M.; Zhong, M. S.
We use the consumption-based asset pricing model with habit formation to study the predictability and cross-section of returns from the international equity markets. We find that the predictability of returns from many developed countries' equity markets is explained in part by changing prices of risks associated with consumption relative to habit at the world as well as local levels. We also provide an exploratory investigation of the cross-sectional implications of the model under the complete world market integration hypothesis and find that the model performs mildly better than the traditional consumption-based model. the unconditional and conditional world CAPMs and a three-factor international asset pricing model. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Y. M.; Zhong, M. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on execution costs for stock index futures: Information versus liquidity effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, H.; Brailsford, T.; Frino, A.
This paper examines execution costs and the impact of trade size for stock index futures using price-volume transaction data from the London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange. Consistent with Subrahmanyam [Rev. Financ. Stud. 4 (1991) 11] we find that effective half spreads in the stock index futures market are small compared to stock markets, and that trades in stock index futures have only a small permanent price impact. This result is important as it helps to better understand the success of equity index products such as index futures and Exchange Traded Funds. We also find that there is no asymmetry in the post-trade price reaction between purchases and sales for stock index futures across various trade sizes. This result is consistent with the conjecture in Chan and Lakonishok [J. Financ. Econ. 33 (1993) 173] that the asymmetry surrounding block trades in stock markets is due to the high cost of short selling and the general reluctance of traders to short sell on stock markets. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berkman, H.; Brailsford, T.; Frino, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global diversification and bidder gains: A comparison between cross-border and domestic acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moeller, S. B.; Schlingemann, F. P.
We provide empirical evidence on how cross-border acquisitions from the perspective of an US acquirer differ from domestic transactions based on stock and operating performance measures. For a sample of 4430 acquisitions between 1985 and 1995 and controlling for various factors we find that US firms who acquire cross-border targets relative to those that acquire domestic targets experience significantly lower announcement stock returns of approximately 1% and significantly lower changes in operating performance. Stock returns are negatively associated with an increase in both global and industrial diversification. Cross-border takeover activity has increased during the past decade and the observed difference in bidder gains is more pronounced for the latter half of the sample period. We find that bidder returns are positively related to takeover activity in the target country and to a legal system offering better shareholder rights. With the exception of the UK, the target country's degree of economic restrictiveness is negatively related to bidder returns. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moeller, S. B.; Schlingemann, F. P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The choice of the distribution of asset returns: How extreme value theory can help?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longin, F.
One of the issues of risk management is the choice of the distribution of asset returns. Academics and practitioners have assumed for a long time (for more than three decades) that the distribution of asset returns is a Gaussian distribution. Such an assumption has been used in many fields of finance: building optimal portfolio, pricing and hedging derivatives and managing risks. However, real financial data tend to exhibit extreme price changes such as stock market crashes that seem incompatible with the assumption of normality. This article shows how extreme value theory can be useful to know more precisely the characteristics of the distribution of asset returns and finally help to chose a better model by focusing on the tails of the distribution. An empirical analysis using equity data of the US market is provided to illustrate this point. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Longin, F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value-at-risk versus expected shortfall: A practical perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yamai, Y.; Yoshiba, T.
Value-at-Risk (VaR) has become a standard risk measure for financial risk management. However, many authors claim that there are several conceptual problems with VaR. Among these problems, an important one is that VaR disregards any loss beyond the VaR level. We call this problem the "tail risk". In this paper, we illustrate how the tail risk of VaR can cause serious problems in certain cases, cases in which expected shortfall can serve more aptly in its place. We discuss two cases: concentrated credit portfolio and foreign exchange rates under market stress. We show that expected shortfall requires a larger sample size than VaR to provide the same level of accuracy. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yamai, Y.; Yoshiba, T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coherent risk measures under filtered historical simulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannopoulos, K.; Tunaru, R.
Recent studies have strongly criticised conventional VaR models for not providing a coherent risk measure. Acerbi provides the intuition for an entire family of coherent measures of risk known as "spectral risk measures" [Spectral measures of risk: A coherent representation of subjective risk aversion. Journal of Banking and Finance 26 (7) (2002) 1505-1518]. In this study we illustrate how the Filtered Historical Simulation [Barone-Adesi, G., Bourgoin, F., Giannopoulos, K., 1998. Don't look back. Risk 11, 100-104; Barone-Adesi, Giannopoulos, K., Vosper, L., 1999. VaR without correlations for non-linear portfolios. Journal of Futures Markets 19, 583-602], can provide an improved methodology for calculating the Expected Shortfall. Thereafter, we prove that these new risk measures are spectral and are coherent as well, following Acerbi. Furthermore, we provide the statistical error formula that allows to calculate the error for our model. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giannopoulos, K.; Tunaru, R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>