<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF6</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Are hazard models superior to traditional bankruptcy prediction approaches? A comprehensive test</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauer, Julian; Agarwal, Vineet
In recent years hazard models, using both market and accounting information, have become state of the art in predicting firm bankruptcies. However, a comprehensive test comparing their performance against the traditional accounting-based approach or the contingent claims approach is missing in the literature. Using a complete database of UK Main listed firms between 1979 and 2009, our Receiver Operating Characteristics (ROC) curve analysis shows that the hazard models are superior to the alternatives. Further, our information content tests demonstrate that the hazard models subsume all bankruptcy related information in the Taffler (1983) z-score model as well as in Bharath and Shumway (2008) contingent claims-based model. Finally, using a mixed regime competitive loan market with different costs of misclassification, the economic benefit of using the Shumway (2001) hazard model is clear, particularly when the performance is judged with return on risk weighted assets computed under Basel III. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bauer, Julian; Agarwal, Vineet</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of CDS trading on the bond market: Evidence from Asia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shim, Ilhyock; Zhu, Haibin
This paper investigates the impact of CDS trading on the development of the bond market in Asia. In general, CDS trading has lowered the cost of issuing bonds and enhanced the liquidity in the bond market. The positive impact is stronger for smaller firms, non-financial firms and those firms with higher liquidity in the CDS market. These empirical findings support the diversification and information hypotheses in the literature. Nevertheless, CDS trading has also introduced a new source of risk. There is strong evidence that, at the peak of the recent global financial crisis, those firms included in CDS indices faced higher bond yield spreads than those not included. (C) 2013 Bank for International Settlements. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shim, Ilhyock; Zhu, Haibin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unexpected tails in risk measurement: Some international evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tolikas, Konstantinos
Risk management critically depends on the assumptions made about the distribution of stock returns. This paper applies extreme value methods to investigate the limiting distribution of the extreme returns of the NIKKEI225, FTSE100 and S&amp;P500 indices as well as the indices of some of largest sectors in Japan, UK and US. The results indicate that the much celebrated Generalised Extreme Value distribution does not provide the most accurate description of the minima since the Generalised Logistic distribution performs better due to its ability to better capture the fat tails of returns. The time varying nature of extremes is also confirmed while a simulation exercise adds to the robustness of our results. It is also shown that the findings may have important implications for risk models, such as VaR and Expected Shortfall, since risk measures which cannot capture the fatness of tails of the empirical distribution function of returns may lead to serious underestimation of downside risk. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Tolikas, Konstantinos</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does gold offer a better protection against losses in sovereign debt bonds than other metals?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agyei-Ampomah, Sam; Gounopoulos, Dimitrios; Mazouz, Khelifa
It is a commonly held view that gold protects investors' wealth in the event of negative economic conditions. In this study, we test whether other metals offer similar or better investment opportunities in periods of market turmoil. Using a sample of 13 sovereign bonds, we show that other precious metals, palladium in particular, offer investors greater compensation for their bond market losses than gold. We also find that industrial metals, especially copper, tend to outperform gold and other precious metals as hedging vehicles and safe haven assets against losses in sovereign bonds. However, the outcome of the hedge and safe haven properties is not always consistent across the different bonds. Finally, our analysis suggests that copper is the best performing metal in the period immediately after negative bond price shocks. Crown Copyright (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agyei-Ampomah, Sam; Gounopoulos, Dimitrios; Mazouz, Khelifa</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of the financial crisis on bank run risk - Danger of the days after</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goedde-Menke, Michael; Langer, Thomas; Pfingsten, Andreas
We examine the developments of depositor knowledge, attitudes, and behavior throughout the recent financial crisis and discuss their impact on bank run risk. Based on a self-collected data set surveying depositors before (2007), at (2008), and after the peak of the crisis (2009), we observe a worrying dynamic pattern. At the peak, depositors knew more about deposit insurance, placed more importance on deposit security, and slightly raised their deposits. However, in the aftermath of the crisis the enhanced depositor knowledge proved to be non-permanent while the increased importance of deposit security and the exposure of depositors persisted. The proportion of completely uninformed, strongly involved, and highly exposed depositors, who carry the highest risk of triggering a bank run, was reduced around the peak of the crisis but rebounded strongly afterwards, even exceeding pre-crisis levels. These findings point to a higher bank run risk in the aftermath than during the financial crisis. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goedde-Menke, Michael; Langer, Thomas; Pfingsten, Andreas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market power in CEE banking sectors and the impact of the global financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Efthyvoulou, Georgios; Yildirim, Canan
The aim of this study is to undertake an up-to-date assessment of market power in Central and Eastern European banking markets and explore how the global financial crisis has affected market power and what has been the impact of foreign ownership. Three main results emerge. First, while there is some convergence in country-level market power during the pre-crisis period, the onset of the global crisis has put an end to this process. Second, bank-level market power appears to vary significantly with respect to ownership characteristics. Third, asset quality and capitalization affect differently the margins in the pre-crisis and the crisis periods. While in the pre-crisis period the impacts are similar for all banks regardless of ownership status, in the crisis period non-performing loans have a negative effect and capitalization a positive effect only for domestically-owned banks. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Efthyvoulou, Georgios; Yildirim, Canan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Riskiness-minimizing spot-futures hedge ratio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yi-Ting; Ho, Keng-Yu; Tzeng, Larry Y.
In this paper, we propose a new spot-futures hedging method that determines the optimal hedge ratio by minimizing the riskiness of hedged portfolio returns, where the riskiness is measured by the index of Aumann and Serrano (2008). Unlike the risk measurements widely used in the literature, the riskiness index employed in our method satisfies monotonicity with respect to stochastic dominance. We also provide an empirical example to demonstrate how to estimate and test this optimal hedge ratio in equity data by the method-of-moments. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Yi-Ting; Ho, Keng-Yu; Tzeng, Larry Y.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank systemic risk and macroeconomic shocks: Canadian and US evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calmes, Christian; Theoret, Raymond
This paper investigates how banks, as a group, react to macroeconomic risk and uncertainty; more specifically, it examines the relationship between bank systemic risk and changes and disruptions in economic conditions. Adopting the methodology of Beaudry et al. (2001), we introduce a new estimation procedure based on EGARCH to refine the framework developed by Baum et al. (2002, 2004, 2009) and Quagliariello (2007, 2009), and we analyze the relationship in the current industry context- i.e., in the context of market-based banking. Our results confirm that banks tend to behave more homogeneously vis-A-vis macroeconomic uncertainty. In particular, we find that both the cross-sectional dispersion of loans-to-assets and the cross-sectional dispersion of non-interest income share shrink during slow growth episodes, and particularly during financial crises, when the resilience of the banking system is at its lowest. More importantly, our main findings indicate that the cross-sectional dispersion of loans-to-assets has increased in the last decade, whereas the cross-sectional dispersion of non-interest income share appears to be more volatile and sensitive to macroeconomic shocks. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calmes, Christian; Theoret, Raymond</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mountain or molehill? Downward biases in the conglomerate discount measure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rudolph, Christin; Schwetzler, Bernhard
The Berger and Ofek (1995) excess value measure, comparing a conglomerate's actual market value to an imputed value based on standalones, has become the standard method to determine value effects of diversification. In this paper, we address a significant bias in this procedure stemming from the difference in cash holdings between diversified and standalone firms. Excess values are based on firm values, including corporate cash positions. As standalones hold significantly more cash, the imputed cash value is higher than the conglomerate's actual cash value, resulting in a downward biased excess value. We thus propose to calculate excess values based on enterprise values, replacing total debt by net debt. Based on an extensive US sample, we show that there is significantly less evidence of a diversification discount when adjusting for the cash bias. In terms of average dollar losses, the firm value-based models overestimate the conglomerate discount by at least 25%. Apart from removing the cash bias, we propose a second modification to the excess value measure, arguing that standalone industry multipliers should be calculated using geometric mean aggregation instead of median aggregation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rudolph, Christin; Schwetzler, Bernhard</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cojumps in stock prices: Empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilder, Dudley; Shackleton, Mark B.; Taylor, Stephen J.
We examine contemporaneous jumps (cojumps) among individual stocks and a proxy for the market portfolio. We show, through a Monte Carlo study, that using intraday jump tests and a coexceedance criterion to detect cojumps has a power similar to the cojump test proposed by Bollerslev et al. (2008). However, we also show that we should not expect to detect all common jumps comprising a cojump when using such coexceedance based detection methods. Empirically, we provide evidence of an association between jumps in the market portfolio and cojumps in the underlying stocks. Consistent with our Monte Carlo evidence, moderate numbers of stocks are often detected to be involved in these (systematic) cojumps. Importantly, the results suggest that market-level news is able to generate simultaneous large jumps in individual stocks. We also find evidence of an association between systematic cojumps and Federal Funds Target Rate announcements. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gilder, Dudley; Shackleton, Mark B.; Taylor, Stephen J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial reporting quality, debt maturity and investment efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cutillas Gomariz, Ma Fuensanta; Sanchez Ballesta, Juan Pedro
This study, conducted with a sample of Spanish listed companies during the period 1998-2008, examines the role of financial reporting quality and debt maturity in investment efficiency. The results show that financial reporting quality mitigates the overinvestment problem. Likewise, lower debt maturity can improve investment efficiency, reducing both overinvestment and underinvestment problems. We further find that financial reporting quality and debt maturity are mechanisms with some degree of substitution in enhancing investment efficiency: firms with lower (higher) use of short-term debt, exhibit higher (lower) financial reporting quality effect on investment efficiency. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cutillas Gomariz, Ma Fuensanta; Sanchez Ballesta, Juan Pedro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flexible dependence modeling of operational risk losses and its impact on total capital requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brechmann, Eike; Czado, Claudia; Paterlini, Sandra
Operational risk data, when available, are usually scarce, heavy-tailed and possibly dependent. In this work, we introduce a model that captures such real-world characteristics and explicitly deals with heterogeneous pairwise and tail dependence of losses. By considering flexible families of copulas, we can easily move beyond modeling bivariate dependence among losses and estimate the total risk capital for the seven- and eight-dimensional distributions of event types and business lines. Using real-world data, we then evaluate the impact of realistic dependence modeling on estimating the total regulatory capital, which turns out to be up to 38% smaller than what the standard Basel approach would prescribe. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brechmann, Eike; Czado, Claudia; Paterlini, Sandra</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is recovery risk priced?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schlaefer, Timo; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese
Recovery risk to explain corporate debt premia has not received much attention so far, most likely due to the difficulties around decomposing the expected loss. We exploit the fact that differently-ranking debt instruments of the same issuer face identical default risk but different default-conditional recovery rates. This allows us to isolate implied recovery under the T-forward measure without any of the rigid assumptions employed by prior studies. We find a pronounced systematic component in recovery rates for which investors should receive a premium. Comparisons to physical realizations show that the premium is quite time-stable and similar for different debt seniorities. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schlaefer, Timo; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relationship between liquidity risk and credit risk in banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Imbierowicz, Bjoern; Rauch, Christian
This paper investigates the relationship between the two major sources of bank default risk: liquidity risk and credit risk. We use a sample of virtually all US commercial banks during the period 1998-2010 to analyze the relationship between these two risk sources on the bank institutional-level and how this relationship influences banks' probabilities of default (PD). Our results show that both risk categories do not have an economically meaningful reciprocal contemporaneous or time-lagged relationship. However, they do influence banks' probability of default. This effect is twofold: whereas both risks separately increase the PD, the influence of their interaction depends on the overall level of bank risk and can either aggravate or mitigate default risk. These results provide new insights into the understanding of bank risk and serve as an underpinning for recent regulatory efforts aimed at strengthening banks (joint) risk management of liquidity and credit risks. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Imbierowicz, Bjoern; Rauch, Christian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate tax aggression and debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Shannon; Tong, Naqiong; Tucker, Alan L.
We provide a tradeoff model of the capital structure that allows leverage to be a function of a firm's choice of tax aggressiveness. The model's testable implications are supported empirically. Debt use is inversely related to corporate tax aggression for most firms, and the relation is economically important. This substitution effect is especially evident for firms exhibiting high tax-shelter prediction scores. The effect attenuates for benign forms of tax avoidance and during the recent credit crisis period. For the most profitable firms, debt and tax aggression are complements. Our results extend the empirical findings of Graham and Tucker (2006). (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Shannon; Tong, Naqiong; Tucker, Alan L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling and predicting the CBOE market volatility index</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandes, Marcelo; Medeiros, Marcelo C.; Scharth, Marcel
This paper performs a thorough statistical examination of the time-series properties of the daily market volatility index (VIX) from the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE). The motivation lies not only on the widespread consensus that the VIX is a barometer of the overall market sentiment as to what concerns investors' risk appetite, but also on the fact that there are many trading strategies that rely on the VIX index for hedging and speculative purposes. Preliminary analysis suggests that the VIX index displays long-range dependence. This is well in line with the strong empirical evidence in the literature supporting long memory in both options-implied and realized variances. We thus resort to both parametric and semiparametric heterogeneous autoregressive (HAR) processes for modeling and forecasting purposes. Our main findings are as follows. First, we confirm the evidence in the literature that there is a negative relationship between the VIX index and the S&amp;P 500 index return as well as a positive contemporaneous link with the volume of the S&amp;P 500 index. Second, the term spread has a slightly negative long-run impact in the VIX index, when possible multicollinearity and endogeneity are controlled for. Finally, we cannot reject the linearity of the above relationships, neither in sample nor out of sample. As for the latter, we actually show that it is pretty hard to beat the pure HAR process because of the very persistent nature of the VIX index. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fernandes, Marcelo; Medeiros, Marcelo C.; Scharth, Marcel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The global financial crisis and integration in European retail banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rughoo, Aarti; Sarantis, Nicholas
The aim of this paper is twofold. Firstly, to investigate the integration process within the European Union retail banking sector by analysing deposit and lending rates to the household sector during the period 2003-2011. Secondly, to assess the impact of the 2008 global financial crisis on the banking integration process, an area that is yet unexplored. An important contribution of the paper is the application of the recently developed Phillips and Sul (2007a) panel convergence methodology which has not hitherto been employed in this area. This method analyses the degree as well as the speed of convergence, identifies the presence of club formation, and measures the behaviour of each country's transition path relative to the panel average. The empirical results point to the presence of convergence in all deposit and lending rates to the household sector up to 2007. In sharp contrast, the null of convergence is rejected in all deposit and credit markets after the onset of the 2008 financial crisis. These results show that the global crisis has had a detrimental effect on the banking integration process. We find some convergence in a few sub-clusters of countries but the rate of convergence is typically slow and several countries are identified as diverging altogether. In addition, we find that the credit market, in general, is far more heterogeneous than the savings market. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rughoo, Aarti; Sarantis, Nicholas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate bond returns and the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aboody, David; Hughes, John S.; Ozel, N. Bugra
We examine effects of government actions and related accounting policies on the corporate bond market implied by changes in relations between aggregate bond returns and cash flow and discount rate news. We capture the influence of risk by partitioning bonds into investment and speculative grades. We use earnings changes as a proxy for cash flow news and T-Bill rate changes as a proxy for discount rate news. As expected, during non-crisis periods, we observe a positive relation between earnings changes and bond returns and a negative relation for T-Bill rate changes. A combination of government bailouts of large financial institutions and mark-to-market accounting preserves the positive relation for earnings changes during the crisis for investment grade bonds, while absence of these factors leads to an insignificant relation for speculative grade. Intervention by the Federal Reserve to induce lower interest rates as earnings were declining, a flight to safety shifting demand from corporate bonds to T-Bills, and low cost funds invested in risk free investments explain a reversal of the relation between bond returns and T-Bill rate changes for both grades. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aboody, David; Hughes, John S.; Ozel, N. Bugra</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership structure and performance: Evidence from the public float in IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michel, Allen; Oded, Jacob; Shaked, Israel
We investigate whether the post-IPO market performance of IPO stocks is related to the percentage of shares issued to the public, namely, the public float. We demonstrate that a non-linear relation exists between the public float and post-IPO returns. Specifically, as public float increases, long-run returns decrease for low levels of public float and increase for high levels of public float. This relation persists even after controlling for various firm characteristics. The best long-term performers are firms that sell either very little or sell most of their stock in the IPO. We suggest that the choice of public float level creates a trade-off between incentives to insiders and power granted to outsiders. This trade-off determines the non-linear relation found between the public float and long-run returns. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Michel, Allen; Oded, Jacob; Shaked, Israel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Chrysler effect: The impact of government intervention on borrowing costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anginer, Deniz; Warburton, A. Joseph
This paper studies intercreditor conflict arising from political interference in the bankruptcy process. The U.S. government's intervention in the 2009 reorganizations of Chrysler and GM purportedly elevated claims of the auto union over those of the automakers' senior creditors in violation of bankruptcy priority rules. Critics predicted that businesses would experience an increase in their borrowing costs because of the risk that politically-powerful junior claimants might now leap-frog other creditors. We examine the financial market where this effect would be most detectible, the market for bonds of highly unionized companies. We find no evidence that bondholders of unionized firms reacted negatively to the government intervention and reject the claim that investors viewed the reorganizations as establishing a precedent for priority jumping by organized labor. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anginer, Deniz; Warburton, A. Joseph</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large controlling shareholders and stock price synchronicity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubaker, Sabri; Mansali, Hatem; Rjiba, Hatem
This paper examines the effect of controlling shareholders on stock price synchronicity by focusing on two salient corporate governance features in a concentrated ownership setting, namely, ultimate cash flow rights and the separation of voting and cash flow rights (i.e., excess control). Using a unique dataset of 654 French listed firms spanning 1998-2007, this study provides evidence that stock price synchronicity increases with excess control, supporting the argument that controlling shareholders tend to disclose less firm-specific information to conceal opportunistic practices. Additionally, this study shows that firms with substantial excess control are more likely to experience stock price crashes, consistent with the conjecture that controlling shareholders are more likely to hoard bad information when their control rights exceed their cash flow rights. Another important finding is that firms' stock prices are less synchronous and less likely to crash when controlling shareholders own a large fraction of cash flow rights. This is consistent with the argument that controlling shareholders have less incentive to adopt poor disclosure policies and to accumulate bad news, since high cash flow ownership aligns their interests with those of minority investors. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubaker, Sabri; Mansali, Hatem; Rjiba, Hatem</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underwriter reputation and the quality of certification: Evidence from high-yield bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andres, Christian; Betzer, Andre; Limbach, Peter
This paper provides primary evidence of whether certification via reputable underwriters is beneficial to investors in the corporate bond market. We focus on the high-yield bond market in which certification of issuer quality is most valuable to investors owing to low liquidity and issuing firms' high opacity and default risk. We find bonds underwritten by the most reputable underwriters to be associated with significantly higher downgrade and default risk. Investors seem to be aware of this relation, as we further find the private information conveyed via the issuer-reputable underwriter match to have a significantly positive effect on at-issue yield spreads. Our results are consistent with the market-power hypothesis, and contradict the traditional certification hypothesis and underlying reputation mechanism. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andres, Christian; Betzer, Andre; Limbach, Peter</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ultimate recovery mixtures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altman, Edward I.; Kalotay, Egon A.
We propose a relatively simple, accurate and flexible approach to forecasting the distribution of defaulted debt recovery outcomes. Our approach is based on mixtures of Gaussian distributions, explicitly conditioned on borrower characteristics, debt instrument characteristics and credit conditions at the time of default. Using Moody's Ultimate Recovery Database, we show that our mixture specification yields more accurate forecasts of ultimate recoveries on portfolios of defaulted loans and bonds on an out-of-sample basis than popular regression-based estimates. Further, the economically interpretable outputs of our model provide a richer characterization of how conditioning variables affect recovery outcomes than competing approaches. The latter benefit is of particular importance in understanding shifts in the relative likelihood of extreme recovery outcomes that tend to be realized more frequently than observations near the distributional mean. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Altman, Edward I.; Kalotay, Egon A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dealing with cross-firm heterogeneity in bank efficiency estimates: Some evidence from Latin America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goddard, John; Molyneux, Philip; Williams, Jonathan
This paper contributes to the bank efficiency literature through an application of recently developed random parameters models for stochastic frontier analysis. We estimate standard fixed and random effects models, and alternative specifications of random parameters models that accommodate cross-sectional parameter heterogeneity. A Monte Carlo simulations exercise is used to investigate the implications for the accuracy of the estimated inefficiency scores of estimation using either an under-parameterized, over-parameterized or correctly specified cost function. On average, the estimated mean efficiencies obtained from random parameters models tend to be higher than those obtained using fixed or random effects, because random parameters models do not confound parameter heterogeneity with inefficiency. Using a random parameters model, we analyse the evolution of the average rank cost efficiency for Latin American banks between 1985 and 2010. Cost efficiency deteriorated during the 1990s, particularly for state-owned banks, before improving during the 2000s but prior to the sub-prime crisis. The effects of the latter varied between countries and bank ownership types. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goddard, John; Molyneux, Philip; Williams, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm growth and efficiency in the banking industry: A new test of the efficient structure hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Homma, Tetsushi; Tsutsui, Yoshiro; Uchida, Hirofumi
In this paper we propose a new test of the efficient structure (ES) hypothesis, which predicts that efficient firms come out ahead in competition and grow as a result. Our test has significant advantages over existing ones, because it is more direct, and can jointly test the so-called quiet-life hypothesis, which predicts that in a concentrated market firms do not minimize costs. We then apply this test to large banks in Japan. Consistent with the ES hypothesis, we find that more efficient banks become larger. We also find that market concentration reduces banks' efficiency, which supports the quiet-life hypothesis. These findings imply that there is an intriguing growth-efficiency dynamic throughout banks' life cycle, although our findings also suggest that the ES hypothesis dominates the quiet-life hypothesis in terms of economic impact. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Homma, Tetsushi; Tsutsui, Yoshiro; Uchida, Hirofumi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk and bank consolidation: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weiss, Gregor N. F.; Neumann, Sascha; Bostandzic, Denefa
This paper analyzes the systemic risk effects of bank mergers to test the "concentration-fragility" hypothesis. We use the marginal expected shortfall as well as the lower tail dependence between a bank's stock returns and a relevant bank sector index to capture the merger-related change in an acquirer's contribution to systemic risk. In our empirical analysis of a dataset of international domestic and cross-border mergers, we find clear evidence for a significant increase in the merging banks', the combined banks' as well as their competitors' contribution to systemic risk following mergers, thus confirming the "concentration-fragility" hypothesis. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Weiss, Gregor N. F.; Neumann, Sascha; Bostandzic, Denefa</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do ethics imply persistence? The case of Islamic and socially responsible funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abdelsalam, Omneya; Duygun, Meryem; Carlos Matallin-Saez, Juan; Tortosa-Ausina, Emili
We analyze the performance persistence of Islamic and Socially Responsible Investment (SRI) mutual funds. We adopt a multi-stage strategy in which, in the first stage, partial frontiers' approaches are considered to measure the performance of the different funds in the sample. In the second stage, the results yielded by the partial frontiers are plugged into different investment strategies based on a recursive estimation methodology whose persistence performance is evaluated in the third stage of the analysis. Results indicate that, for both types of funds, performance persistence actually exists, but only for the worst and, most notably, best funds. This result is robust not only across methods (and different choices of tuning parameters within each method) but also across both SRI and Islamic funds-although in the case of the latter persistence was stronger for the best funds. The persistence of SRI and Islamic funds represents an important result for investors and the market, since it provides information on both which funds to invest in and which funds to avoid. Last but not least, the use of the aforementioned techniques in the context of mutual funds could also be of interest for the non-conclusive literature. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abdelsalam, Omneya; Duygun, Meryem; Carlos Matallin-Saez, Juan; Tortosa-Ausina, Emili</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization, competition and monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, Jung-Hyun; Breton, Regis
We analyze the impact of loan securitization on competition in the loan market. Using a dynamic loan market competition model where borrowers face both exogenous and endogenous costs to switch between banks, we uncover a competition softening effect of securitization that allows banks to extract rents in the primary loan market. By reducing monitoring incentives, securitization mitigates winner's curse effects in future stages of competition thereby decreasing ex ante competition for initial market share. Due to this competition softening effect, securitization can adversely affect loan market efficiency while leading to higher equilibrium profits for banks. This effect is driven by primary loan market competition, not by the exploitation of informational asymmetries in the secondary market for loans. We also argue that banks can use securitization as a strategic response to an increase in competition, as a tool to signal a reduction in monitoring intensity for the sole purpose of softening ex ante competition. Our result suggests that securitization reforms focusing exclusively on informational asymmetries in markets for securitized products may overlook competitive conditions in the primary market. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahn, Jung-Hyun; Breton, Regis</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default prediction with dynamic sectoral and macroeconomic frailties</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Peimin; Wu, Chunchi
This paper extends the macroeconomic frailty model to include sectoral frailty factors that capture default correlations among firms in a similar business. We estimate sectoral and macroeconomic frailty factors and their effects on default intensity using the data for Japanese firms from 1992 to 2010. We find strong evidence for the presence of sectoral frailty factors even after accounting for the effects of observable covariates and macroeconomic frailty on default intensity. The model with sectoral frailties performs better than that without. Results show that accounting for the sources of unobserved sectoral default risk covariations improves the accuracy of default probability estimation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Peimin; Wu, Chunchi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A sheep in wolf's clothing: Can a central bank appear tougher than it is?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nijskens, Rob
Central banks (CBs) in Europe and the US have been providing virtually unlimited amounts of liquidity to banks for quite some time now. This may lead banks to expect that these CBs will be lenient in the future. Will this expectation be justified? I present a model in which a commercial bank, subject to idiosyncratic liquidity shocks, faces uncertainty about whether the CB is tough (Hawk) or lenient (Dove). Specifically, the CB knows its nature, but the bank does not. When uncertainty is high, the CB can use this to its advantage and try to build a reputation for toughness. In response, the bank chooses higher liquidity reserves in equilibrium. Furthermore, increasing bank capital and penalty rates make it easier to build a reputation, while bailouts by the fiscal government make it more difficult. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nijskens, Rob</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The interest rate pass-through in the Euro area during the global financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hristov, Nikolay; Huelsewig, Oliver; Wollmershaeuser, Timo
This paper uses panel vector autoregressive (VAR) models for euro area member countries to explore the widening of retail bank interest rate spreads that emerged in the course of the global financial crisis. We find that the interest rate pass-through was generally complete on impact before the outbreak of the financial crisis, but became significantly distorted in the period thereafter, which hampered the effectiveness of monetary policy. Empirical evidence suggests that the decrease in the interest rate pass-through can be related to a change in the structural parameters characterizing the economies and a substantial increase in the average size of structural shocks. DSGE model simulations show that an increase in the frictions that banks are subject to can explain the decrease in the retail bank interest rate pass-through. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hristov, Nikolay; Huelsewig, Oliver; Wollmershaeuser, Timo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of liquidity and solvency risk on the inclusion of bond covenants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cook, Douglas O.; Fu, Xudong; Tang, Tian
Studies have analyzed the impact of firm and issue characteristics but not liquidity and solvency components of financial distress on the use of bond covenants. Using a comprehensive database of corporate bonds from 2001 to 2012, we find that firm liquidity, measured by standardized Lambda, has a negative statistical and economic impact on the inclusion of all categories and sub-categories of restrictive bond covenants. Developed from financial statement information by Emery and Lyons (1991), Lambda is designed as a coverage ratio that, under certain distribution assumptions, maps into the probability of a firm being unable to pay its short-term bills. The strongest solvency proxy is the 10-year credit default swap (CDS) spread which is significant across the categories and sub-categories for investment and payment covenants, weakly significant for the subordinated debt sub-category of the subsequent financing covenant, but strongly significant for the control poison put sub-category of event covenants. This evidence supports a model that uses SLambda as a proxy for liquidity risk and the 10-year CDS spread as a proxy for solvency risk. The liquidity/covenant relationship is dampened when firms have access to commercial paper funding or bank loans. However, during the recent financial crisis liquidity event this liquidity/covenant relationship was enhanced especially for firms which were dependent on commercial paper during this time when the commercial paper market was deteriorating. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cook, Douglas O.; Fu, Xudong; Tang, Tian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial globalisation and sustainable finance: Implications for policy and practice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aziakpono, Meshach; Bauer, Rob; Kleimeier, Stefanie
nan</description><author>Aziakpono, Meshach; Bauer, Rob; Kleimeier, Stefanie</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate forecasts, state price densities and risk premium from Euribor options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivanova, Vesela; Gutierrez, Josep Maria Puigvert
In this paper we study option-implied interest rate forecasts and the development of risk premium and state prices in the Euribor futures option market. Using parametric and non-parametric statistical calibration, we transform the risk-neutral option implied densities for the Euribor futures rate into real-world densities. We investigate the period from the introduction of the Euro in 1999 until December 2012. The estimated densities are used to provide a measure for the interest rate risk premium and state prices implicit in the futures market. We find that the real-world option-implied distributions can be used to forecast the futures rate, while the forecasting ability of the risk-neutral distributions is rejected. The state price densities in the market show a U-shaped curve suggesting that investors price higher states with high and low rates compared to the expected spot rate. However, we show that, in general, state prices have a more pronounced right tail, implying that investors are more risk averse to increasing interest rates. We also document a negative market price of interest rate risk which generates positive premium for the futures contract. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ivanova, Vesela; Gutierrez, Josep Maria Puigvert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does global liquidity drive commodity prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beckmann, Joscha; Belke, Ansgar; Czudaj, Robert
This paper tackles the question of whether a cross-sectional perspective on monetary policy is capable of explaining movements in global commodity prices. In this vein, we contribute to the rich literature on global liquidity in two different ways: on the one hand, to achieve a global series in terms of common monetary policy shocks, we propose a distinction between common and idiosyncratic factors across economies, as proposed by Bai and Ng (2004). Our second innovation stems from the consideration of a Markov-switching vector error correction model when analyzing time-varying short-run dynamics. Having identified the long-run structure which includes a proportional relationship between commodity prices and global liquidity in the first step, our results indeed show that the impact of a global liquidity measure on different commodity prices is significant and varies over time. One regime approximately accounts for times where commodity prices significantly adjust to disequilibria, while the second regime is characterized by either a weak or no commodity price adjustment. The fact that global liquidity also reacts to disequilibria in a specific regime demonstrates the two-way causality between monetary policy and commodity prices. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beckmann, Joscha; Belke, Ansgar; Czudaj, Robert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Openness and the finance-growth nexus</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herwartz, Helmut; Walle, Yabibal M.
Rajan and Zingales (2003) hypothesize that openness trade and financial is a crucial determinant of financial development. The main policy implication emerging from this hypothesis is that openness should be promoted as a means of facilitating economic growth through financial development. While subsequent research confirms that openness affects financial development, we study whether finance continues to be growth promoting as economies become increasingly open a key implicit assumption behind the policy recommendation. Using data from 78 economies for the period 1981-2006, we find that very high levels of financial openness generally erode the growth-promoting role of financial development while high trade openness strengthens it. These worldwide findings by and large hold for subsamples of Sub-Saharan African, Latin American and OECD economies. Notable exceptions are the invariance of the finance-growth (FG) nexus on trade openness in OECD economies and the positive effect of financial openness on the FG link in Latin American economies. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Herwartz, Helmut; Walle, Yabibal M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discretionary ratings and the pricing of subprime mortgage-backed securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lugo, Stefano
Using a dataset of Home Equity Loan securities issued up to June 2007 and rated by Moody's and/or S&amp;P, this paper investigates how discretionary ratings are priced by the market. To this end, a measure of relative rating inflation (Rating Bias) observable at issuance is proposed. The way Rating Bias is priced changes significantly between Investment Grade (IG) and Speculative Grade (SG) securities. Rating Bias is only partially discounted for IG tranches, whereas it is correctly priced for SG ones. Less sophisticated institutional investors are often restrained from investing in securities rated lower than triple-A, double-A or A; however, these alternative thresholds do not appear to play a role as relevant as that of the IG-SG boundary. Rating Bias is also found to have an asymmetric impact on spreads: the relevance of actual over expected ratings is greater for tranches receiving evaluations that are higher (rather than lower) than expected. Taken together, these pieces of empirical evidence point toward ratings-based regulation as an important explanation for the observed mispricing of structured finance products. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lugo, Stefano</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit constraints and spillovers from foreign firms in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Natasha; Milner, Chris; Riano, Alejandro
This paper examines whether credit constraints affect Chinese firms' absorption of productivity spillovers originating from the activity of foreign-owned firms. Using firm-level data for 2001-2005, we find evidence of positive spillovers originating from foreign-owned firms from countries other than Hong Kong, Macau and Taiwan for non-state owned Chinese firms operating in the same industry and province. Using an index of external finance dependence to Measure credit constraints, we find that only non-state-owned firms operating in industries with external finance dependence below the index median exhibit significantly positive spillovers from the activity of foreign firms. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agarwal, Natasha; Milner, Chris; Riano, Alejandro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State ownership, soft-budget constraints, and cash holdings: Evidence from China's privatized firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Megginson, William L.; Ullah, Barkat; Wei, Zuobao
We study the relation between state ownership and cash holdings in China's share-issue privatized firms from 2000 to 2012. We find that the level of cash holdings increases as state ownership declines. For the average firm in our sample, a 10 percentage-point decline in state ownership leads to an increase of about RMB 55 million in cash holdings. This negative relation can be attributable to the soft-budget constraint (SBC) inherent in state ownership. The Chinese financial system is dominated by the state-owned banks, an environment very conducive for the SBC effect We further examine and quantify the effect of state ownership on the value of cash and find that the marginal value of cash increases as state ownership declines. The next RMB added to cash reserves of the average firm is valued at RMB 0.96 by the market. The marginal value of cash in firms with zero state ownership is RMB 036 higher than in firms with majority state ownership. The SBC effect exacerbates agency problems inherent in state-controlled enterprises, contributing to their lower value of cash. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Megginson, William L.; Ullah, Barkat; Wei, Zuobao</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank liquidity, stock market participation, and economic growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mattana, Elena; Panetti, Ettore
We develop a growth model with banks and markets to reconcile the observed decreasing trend in the relative liquidity of many financial systems around the world with the increasing household participation in direct market trades. At low levels of economic development, the presence of fixed entry costs prevents the agents from accessing the market, and pushes them towards the banks, which provide high relative liquidity. We characterize the threshold after which the agents are rich enough to access the market, where the relative liquidity is lower, and show that the relative liquidity of the whole financial system (banks and markets) drops because of the increasing market participation. We provide some evidence consistent with this theoretical prediction: a one-unit increase in an index of securities market liberalization leads to a drop in the relative liquidity of between 17 and 27 per cent. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mattana, Elena; Panetti, Ettore</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global governance: Global banks and shadow banks supervision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does deposit insurance affect bank risk? Evidence from the recent crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anginer, Deniz; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Zhu, Min
Deposit insurance is widely offered in a number of countries as part of a financial system safety net to promote stability. An unintended consequence of deposit insurance is the reduction in the incentive of depositors to monitor banks which lead to excessive risk-taking. We examine the relation between deposit insurance and bank risk and systemic fragility in the years leading up to and during the recent financial crisis. We find that generous financial safety nets increase bank risk and systemic fragility in the years leading up to the global financial crisis. However, during the crisis, bank risk is lower and systemic stability is greater in countries with deposit insurance coverage. Our findings suggest that the "moral hazard effect" of deposit insurance dominates in good times while the "stabilization effect" of deposit insurance dominates in turbulent times. The overall effect of deposit insurance over the full sample we study remains negative since the destabilizing effect during normal times is greater in magnitude compared to the stabilizing effect during global turbulence. In addition, we find that good bank supervision can alleviate the unintended consequences of deposit insurance on bank systemic risk during good times, suggesting that fostering the appropriate incentive framework is very important for ensuring systemic stability. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anginer, Deniz; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Zhu, Min</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank risk within and across equilibria</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agur, Itai
The global financial crisis highlighted that the financial system can be most vulnerable when it seems most stable. This paper models non-linear dynamics in banking. Small shocks can lead from an equilibrium with few bank defaults straight to a full freeze. The mechanism is based on amplification between adverse selection on banks' funding market and moral hazard in bank monitoring. Our results imply trade-offs between regulators' microprudential desire to shield individual weak banks and the macroprudential consequences of doing so. Moreover, limiting bank reliance on wholesale funding always reduces systemic risk, but limiting the correlation between bank portfolios does not. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agur, Itai</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can European bank bailouts work?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schoenmaker, Dirk; Siegmann, Arjen
Cross-border banking needs cross-border recapitalisation mechanisms. Each mechanism, however, suffers from the financial trilemma, which is that cross-border banking, national financial autonomy and financial stability are incompatible. In this paper, we study the efficiency of different burden-sharing agreements for the recapitalisation of the 30 largest banks in Europe. We consider bank bailouts for these banks in a simulation framework with stochastic country-specific bailout benefits. Among the burden sharing rules, we find that the majority and qualified-majority voting rules come close to the efficiency of a bailout mechanism with a supranational authority. Even a unanimous voting rule works better than home-country bailouts, which are very inefficient. If we assume additional systemic risk benefits, the efficiency of burden sharing rules comes close to the supranational solution. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schoenmaker, Dirk; Siegmann, Arjen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploiting commodity momentum along the futures curves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Groot, Wilma; Karstanje, Dennis; Zhou, Weili
This study examines novel momentum strategies in commodities futures markets that incorporate term-structure information. We show that momentum strategies that invest in contracts on the futures curve with the largest expected roll-yield or the strongest momentum earn significantly higher risk-adjusted returns than a traditional momentum strategy, which only invests in the nearest contracts. Moreover, when incorporating conservative transaction costs we observe that our low-turnover momentum strategy more than doubles the net return compared to a traditional momentum strategy. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Groot, Wilma; Karstanje, Dennis; Zhou, Weili</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Too close for comfort? Geographic propinquity to political power and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pantzalis, Christos; Park, Jung Chul
We show that firm headquarters' geographic proximity to political power centers (state capitals) is associated with higher abnormal returns. Consistent with the notion that this effect is rooted in social network links, we find it is more pronounced in communities with high levels of sociability and political values' homophily, and that it dissipates when firms move their headquarters to another state. Finally, in line with the view, that investors perceive such networks to be associated with political risk, we find that this effect is particularly strong when there are substantial levels of corruption, dependency on government spending, and politicians' turnover. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pantzalis, Christos; Park, Jung Chul</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cost of capital and optimal financing policy in a dynamic setting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karpavicius, Sigitas
This paper revisits the Modigliani-Miller propositions on the optimal financing policy and cost of capital in a dynamic setting. In an environment without taxes and bankruptcy costs, the results are generally consistent with the Modigliani-Miller Propositions 1 and 2. However, the first proposition should be presented and interpreted more carefully, as given firm characteristics, there is only one optimal capital structure. Thus, a firm's capital structure is relevant. A relaxation of assumptions about either taxes or bankruptcy costs leads to conclusions that are generally different from those in Modigliani and Miller (1958). The model predicts that leverage and sales-to-capital ratios decrease but firm size and capital stock increase with the subjective discount factor of the firm's manager if there are taxes and bankruptcy costs. The empirical analysis supports these predictions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Karpavicius, Sigitas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The rise of UK Seasoned Equity Offerings (SEOs) fees during the financial crisis: The role of institutional shareholders and underwriters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levis, Mario; Meoli, Michele; Migliorati, Katrin
This paper investigates the increase in underwriting fees for UK SEOs since the beginning of the financial crisis in mid-2007. We develop and test a number of hypotheses related to the role of institutional shareholders and underwriters involved in the issuing process. We find that the rise in fees is related to the strengthening of the relative negotiating position of a specific underwriter in comparison to a specific issuer and to the growing influence of institutional shareholders with short-term investment horizons. Our evidence suggests that there may be reasonable grounds for considering potential conflicts of interest due to the dual role of institutional shareholders as investors and sub-underwriters. On the other hand, the ownership size of large shareholders and the reputation of underwriters have a moderating effect on fees, while the nationality of the institutional shareholders, the concentration of the investment bank industry and the experience of corporate issuers are not related to underwriting fees. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Levis, Mario; Meoli, Michele; Migliorati, Katrin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of correlation dynamics in sector allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalotychou, Elena; Staikouras, Sotiris K.; Zhao, Gang
This paper assesses the economic value of modeling conditional correlations for mean-variance portfolio optimization. Using sector returns in three major markets we show that the predictability of models describing empirical regularities in correlations such as time-variation, asymmetry and structural breaks leads to significant performance gains over the static covariance strategy. Investors would be willing to pay a fee of up to 983 basis points to switch from the static to the dynamic correlation portfolio and about 100 basis points more for capturing asymmetries and shifts in correlations. The gains are robust to the crisis, transaction costs and are most pronounced for monthly rebalancing. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kalotychou, Elena; Staikouras, Sotiris K.; Zhao, Gang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking risk and macroeconomic fluctuations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Yi; Zeng, Zhixiong
This paper develops a model of banking frictions and banking risk. As a sort of systemic risk, changes in banking risk lead to fluctuations in aggregate economic activity. We decompose the macroeconomic effect of a banking risk shock into a pure default effect and a risk-aversion effect when risk sharing among investors is imperfect. When the shock generates a bank risk spread similar to the peak value during the Global Financial Crisis, the overall effect is a decline in employment by 4.66%. The default effect leads to a 3.40% employment decline by a "within-model" measure, and a 3.51 decline by a "between-model" measure. The remaining is attributed to the risk-aversion effect. A practical implication of our analysis is that by developing financial safety net and improving risk sharing among investors, the society can mitigate the adverse macroeconomic effects of banking risk shocks to some extent, but cannot eliminate all of them. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jin, Yi; Zeng, Zhixiong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rehypothecation dilemma: Impact of collateral rehypothecation on derivative prices under bilateral counterparty credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sakurai, Yuji; Uchida, Yoshihiko
Rehypothecation is the practice where a derivatives dealer reuses collateral posted from its end user in over-the-counter (OTC) derivatives markets. Although rehypothecation benefits the end user through cost reduction of derivative trades, it also creates additional counterparty credit risk since the end user may not receive the collateral back when the dealer suddenly defaults. To evaluate the benefits and risks of rehypothecation, we propose a derivative pricing framework with bilateral counterparty credit risk that determines the amount of rehypothecable collateral. We also model the realistic features of derivative trades: two different types of collateral, the time delay of collateral posting and the rating-dependent collateral agreement. We apply our pricing framework to cross currency swaps and investigate the impact of rehypothecation on the swap spreads. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sakurai, Yuji; Uchida, Yoshihiko</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and the dynamics of capital structure: New evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Ya-Kai; Chou, Robin K.; Huang, Tai-Hsin
The effects of corporate governance on optimal capital structure choices have been well documented, though without offering empirical evidence about the impact of corporate governance quality on the adjustment speed toward an optimal capital structure. This study simultaneously considers two effects of debt originating from agency theory the takeover defense and the disciplinary effects of debt on the speed of adjustment to the optimal capital structure. Corporate governance has a distinct effect on the speed of capital structure adjustment: weak governance firms that are underlevered tend to adjust slowly to the optimal capital structure, because the costs of the disciplinary role of debt outweigh the benefits of using debt as a takeover defense tool. Although overlevered weak governance firms also adjust slowly, they do so because they are reluctant to decrease their leverage toward the target level to deter potential raiders, especially if they face a serious takeover threat. Therefore, this study finds that both overlevered and underlevered firms with weak governance adjust slowly toward their target debt levels, though with different motivations. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Ya-Kai; Chou, Robin K.; Huang, Tai-Hsin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Socially responsible funds and market crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nofsinger, John; Varma, Abhishek
Compared to matched conventional mutual funds, socially responsible mutual funds outperform during periods of market crises. This dampening of downside risk comes at the cost of underperforming during non-crisis periods. Investors seeking downside protection would value the asymmetry of these returns. This asymmetric return pattern is driven by the mutual funds that focus on environmental, social, or governance (ESG) attributes and is especially pronounced in ESG funds that use positive screening techniques. Furthermore, the observed patterns are attributed to the funds' socially responsible attributes and not the differences in fund portfolio management or the characteristics of the companies in fund portfolios. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nofsinger, John; Varma, Abhishek</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does bank ownership affect lending behavior? Evidence from the Euro area</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferri, Giovanni; Kalmi, Panu; Kerola, Eeva
We analyze the differences in lending policies across banks characterized by different types of ownership, using micro-level data on Euro area banks during the period 1999-2011 to detect possible variations in bank lending supply responses to changes in monetary policy. Our results identify a general difference between stakeholder and shareholder banks: following a monetary policy contraction, stakeholder banks decrease their loan supply to a lesser extent than shareholder banks. A detailed analysis of the effect among stakeholder banks reveals that cooperative banks continued to smooth the impact of tighter monetary policy on their lending during the crisis period (2008-2011), whereas savings banks did not. Stakeholder banks' propensity to smooth their lending cycles suggests that their presence in the economy has the potential to reduce credit supply volatility. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferri, Giovanni; Kalmi, Panu; Kerola, Eeva</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-selling, margin-trading, and price efficiency: Evidence from the Chinese market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Eric C.; Luo, Yan; Ren, Jinjuan
China launched a pilot scheme in March 2010 to lift the ban on short-selling and margin-trading for stocks on a designated list. We find that stocks experience negative returns when added to the list. After the ban is lifted, price efficiency increases while stock return volatility decreases. Panel data regressions reveal that intensified short-selling activities are associated with improved price efficiency. Short-sellers trade to eliminate overpricing by selling stocks with higher contemporaneous returns following a downward trend, and their trades predict future returns. In contrast, we find intensified margin-trading activities for stocks with lower contemporaneous returns, and these trades have no return predictive power. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Eric C.; Luo, Yan; Ren, Jinjuan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank pay caps, bank risk, and macroprudential regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thanassoulis, John
This paper studies the consequences of a regulatory pay cap in proportion to assets on bank risk, bank value, and bank asset allocations. The cap is shown to lower banks' risk and raise banks' values by acting against a competitive externality in the labour market. The risk reduction is achieved without the possibility of reduced lending from a Tier 1 increase. The cap encourages diversification and reduces the need a bank has to focus on a limited number of asset classes. The cap can be used for Macroprudential Regulation to encourage banks to move resources away from wholesale banking to the retail banking sector. Such an intervention would be targeted: in 2009 a 20% reduction in remuneration would have been equivalent to more than 150 basis points of extra Tier 1 for UBS, for example. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thanassoulis, John</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry around operational risk announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barakat, Ahmed; Chernobai, Anna; Wahrenburg, Mark
Operational risk incidences are likely to increase the degree of information asymmetry between firms and investors. We analyze operational risk disclosures by US financial firms during 1995-2009 and their impact on different measures of information asymmetry in the firms' equity markets. Effective spreads and the price impact of trades are shown to increase around the first announcements of such events and to revert after the announcement of their settlement. This is especially pronounced for internal fraud and business practices related events. Market makers respond to higher information risk around the first press cutting date by increasing the quoted depth to accommodate an increase in trading volumes. The degree of information asymmetry around operational risk events may be influenced by the bank's risk management function and the bank's governance structure. We indeed find that information asymmetry increases more strongly after events' first announcements when firms have weaker governance structures lower board independence ratios, lower equity incentives of executive directors, and lower levels of institutional ownership. In contrast, the firms' risk management function has little to no impact on information asymmetry. We interpret this as evidence that the risk management function is primarily driven by regulatory compliance needs. The results of this study contribute to our understanding of information asymmetry around operational risk announcements. They help to shed light on the role that regulation and corporate governance can play in order to establish effective disclosure practices and to promote a liquid and transparent securities market. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Barakat, Ahmed; Chernobai, Anna; Wahrenburg, Mark</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A new set of improved Value-at-Risk backtests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ziggel, Daniel; Berens, Tobias; Weiss, Gregor N. F.; Wied, Dominik
We propose a new set of formal backtests for VaR-forecasts that significantly improve upon existing backtesting procedures. Our new test of unconditional coverage can be used for both one-sided and two-sided testing, which leads to a significantly increased power. Second. we stress the importance of testing the property of independent and identically distributed (i.i.d.) VaR-exceedances and propose a simple approach that explicitly tests for the presence of clusters in VaR-violation processes. Results from a simulation study indicate that our tests significantly outperform competing backtests in several distinct settings. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ziggel, Daniel; Berens, Tobias; Weiss, Gregor N. F.; Wied, Dominik</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Japanese candlesticks help solve the trader's dilemma?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Detollenaere, Benoit; Mazza, Paolo
In this paper, we investigate whether Japanese candlesticks can help traders to find the best trade-off between market timing and market impact costs. Based on fixed-effect panel regressions on a sample of 81 European stocks, we show that implicit transaction costs are better characterized by using specific Japanese candlesticks patterns. Although market timing costs are not lower when Hammer-like and Doji configurations occur, market impact costs are significantly lower when and after a Doji structure occurs. We further check the potential gains through order submission simulations and find that submission strategies based on the occurrence of Doji result in significantly lower market impact cost than random submission strategies. These findings are of great interest for investors who look for occasional liquidity pools to execute their orders inexpensively such as institutional traders or hedgers. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Detollenaere, Benoit; Mazza, Paolo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Funding advantage and market discipline in the Canadian banking sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beyhaghi, Mehdi; D'Souza, Chris; Roberts, Gordon S.
We employ a comprehensive data set and a variety of methods to provide evidence on the magnitude of large banks' funding advantage in Canada in addition to the extent to which market discipline exists across different securities issued by the Canadian banks. The banking sector in Canada provides a unique setting in which to examine market discipline along with the prospects of proposed reforms because Canada has no history of government bailouts, and an implicit government guarantee has been in effect consistently since the 1920s. We find that large banks have a funding advantage over small banks after controlling for bank-specific and market risk factors. Large banks on average pay 80 basis points and 70 basis points less, respectively, on their deposits and subordinated debt. Working with hand-collected market data on debt issues by large banks, we also find that market discipline exists for subordinated debt and not for senior debt. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beyhaghi, Mehdi; D'Souza, Chris; Roberts, Gordon S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting US recessions: The role of sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christiansen, Charlotte; Eriksen, Jonas Nygaard; Moller, Stig Vinther
We study the role of sentiment variables as predictors for US recessions. We combine sentiment variables with either classical recession predictors or common factors based on a large panel of macroeconomic and financial variables. Sentiment variables hold vast predictive power for US recessions in excess of both the classical recession predictors and the common factors. The strong importance of the sentiment variables is documented both in-sample and out-of-sample. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christiansen, Charlotte; Eriksen, Jonas Nygaard; Moller, Stig Vinther</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The great entanglement: The contagious capacity of the international banking network just before the 2008 crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garratt, Rodney J.; Mahadeva, Lavan; Svirydzenka, Katsiaryna
Systemic risk among the network of international banking groups arises when financial stress threatens to crisscross many national boundaries and expose imperfect international coordination. To assess this risk, we consider three decades of data on the cross-border interbank market. We use Rosvall and Bergstrom's (2008) information theoretic map equation to partition banking groups from 21 countries into modules that reveal the contagious capacity of the network. We show that in the late 1980s four important financial centers formed one large super cluster that was highly contagious in terms of transmission of stress within its ranks, but less contagious on a global scale. But the expansion leading to the 2008 crisis left more transmitting hubs sharing the same total influence as a few large modules had previously. We show that this greater entanglement meant the network was more broadly contagious, and not that risk was more shared. Thus, our analysis contributes to our understanding as to why defaults in US sub-prime mortgages spread quickly through the global financial system. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garratt, Rodney J.; Mahadeva, Lavan; Svirydzenka, Katsiaryna</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ex-ante implications of sovereign default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malik, Samreen
I study how the possibility of default on external debts affects other capital allocation decisions in a small open economy. In the model, default has an option value derived from the randomization over ex-post default regimes, which depends on country-specific productivity shocks. This feature of default reduces incentives for ex-ante diversification, which would reduce exposure to the productivity shock. As a result, if the economys debt to capital ratio is allowed to cross a fixed threshold (identified in the model), the unique equilibrium exhibits an allocation of capital that is less productive in expectation and more volatile than in a benchmark model without default. The model therefore captures a number of salient features of emerging and less developed countries, where low levels of international risk-sharing have gone hand-in-hand with frequent and recurring default events. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malik, Samreen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Semiparametric estimation of multi-asset portfolio tail risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dias, Alexandra
When correlations between assets turn positive, multi-asset portfolios can become riskier than single assets. This article presents the estimation of tail risk at very high quantiles using a semiparametric estimator which is particularly suitable for portfolios with a large number of assets. The estimator captures simultaneously the information contained in each individual asset return that composes the portfolio, and the interrelation between assets. Noticeably, the accuracy of the estimates does not deteriorate when the number of assets in the portfolio increases. The implementation is as easy for a large number of assets as it is for a small number. We estimate the probability distribution of large losses for the American stock market considering portfolios with ten, fifty and one hundred assets of stocks with different market capitalization. In either case, the approximation for the portfolio tail risk is very accurate. We compare our results with well known benchmark models. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dias, Alexandra</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reprint of: The impact of enterprise risk management on the marginal cost of reducing risk: Evidence from the insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckles, David L.; Hoyt, Robert E.; Miller, Steve M.
We test the hypothesis that practicing enterprise risk management (ERM) reduces firms' cost of reducing risk. Adoption of ERM represents a radical paradigm shift from the traditional method of managing risks individually to managing risks collectively allowing ERM-adopting firms to better recognize natural hedges, prioritize hedging activities towards the risks that contribute most to the total risk of the firm, and optimize the evaluation and selection of available hedging instruments. We hypothesize that these advantages allow ERM-adopting firms to produce greater risk reduction per dollar spent. Our hypothesis further predicts that, after implementing ERM, firms experience profit maximizing incentives to lower risk. Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that firms adopting ERM experience a reduction in stock return volatility. We also find that the reduction in return volatility for ERM-adopting firms becomes stronger over time. Further, we find that operating profits per unit of risk (ROA/return volatility) increase post ERM adoption. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eckles, David L.; Hoyt, Robert E.; Miller, Steve M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sell-side analysts' career concerns during banking stresses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nolte, Ingmar; Nolte, Sandra; Vasios, Michalis
We propose a new approach to examine sell-side analysts' career concerns by relating their forecast boldness to their employers' news flows. Specifically, we use banking sector news to proxy for the severity of career concerns. Analysts follow more closely the consensus forecast when the prospects of the banking sector are negative (and vice versa). The effect is both economically and statistically significant after controlling for various firm, analyst, brokerage house, and forecasting characteristics, as well as sector and economy wide effects. The more established analysts, in terms of reputation and experience, are generally unaffected by banking sector news. In contrast, their less established peers tend to cluster their forecasts near the consensus after a sequence of negative news flows for banks. Collectively, our results support the notion that during banking stresses when job security is low analysts' tendency to imitate others increases. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nolte, Ingmar; Nolte, Sandra; Vasios, Michalis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The influence of buy-side analysts on mutual fund trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frey, Stefan; Herbst, Patrick
We present evidence on the trading and performance impact of buy-side analysts. Using data provided by a large global asset manager, we relate buy-side analysts' recommendations to fund transactions on a daily basis. We show that buy-side analysts significantly influence trading decisions: Fund managers strongly follow recent recommendation revisions, even after controlling for other trading determinants. Positive abnormal returns to buy-side analysts' revisions are also reflected in the performance of mutual fund trades: Trades triggered by buy-side recommendations have higher returns than other trades. Overall, the impact of buy-side analysts is more pronounced than that of sell-side analysts. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frey, Stefan; Herbst, Patrick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of international equity investment: Do they differ between institutional and noninstitutional investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roque, Vanda; Cortez, Maria Ceu
In this paper we investigate whether the determinants of international equity investment differ between investors with different degrees of sophistication. For this purpose, we analyse and compare the determinants of international equity investment of institutional and noninstitutional investors from 20 OECD countries (US not included) in the period 2001-2009. The results show that there are significant differences in the determinants of international equity investment between institutional and noninstitutional investors. In particular, noninstitutional investors tend to exhibit a more pronounced preference for equities of geographical nearby, contiguous and more transparent countries than institutional investors. The preference for more developed equity markets and the contrarian behaviour are also significantly more pronounced for noninstitutional than for institutional investors. These results support the argument that international equity investment of less sophisticated investors is more affected by information costs and familiarity than that of more sophisticated investors. Moreover, business cycles exert an influence on international equity investment decisions of both institutional and noninstitutional investors. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roque, Vanda; Cortez, Maria Ceu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The search for financial stability: Models, policies and prospects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duygun, Meryem; Nolte, Ingmar; Sa, Filipa; Shaban, Mohamed
nan</description><author>Duygun, Meryem; Nolte, Ingmar; Sa, Filipa; Shaban, Mohamed</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A novel equity valuation and capital allocation model for use by long-term value-investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajaratnam, Myuran; Rajaratnam, Bala; Rajaratnam, Kanshukan
We present a novel asset pricing model that captures the investment wisdom and stock-selection approach of the long-term value-investors Benjamin Graham and Warren Buffett. Taking a longer term view of business prospects and business risks, we explicitly consider the time period in which a business enjoys a competitive advantage over its peers as the central tenet of our model and capture the eventual demise of this competitive advantage in a probabilistic manner. Assuming that our investor has log utility, our model answers the question of capital allocation in a two-asset scenario. The model does not enforce the Efficient Market Hypothesis and is shown to explain some well-known empirical studies on stock returns. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rajaratnam, Myuran; Rajaratnam, Bala; Rajaratnam, Kanshukan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trademarking status and economic efficiency among commercial banks: Some evidence for the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duygun, Meryem; Sena, Vania; Shaban, Mohamed
As competition in the banking sector has intensified over the last two decades, commercial banks have started to use trademarks to differentiate their products and services from those offered by their competitors. Less clear are the implications of the trademarking activities on the commercial banks' performance. In this paper, we compare the cost and profit efficiency of trademarking and non-trademarking banks in the UK, over the period 2001-2013 using stochastic frontier methods. We use Propensity Score Matching techniques to identify a sample of non-trademarking banks which share the same characteristics as the trademarking banks to ensure that variations in the efficiency between the commercial banks in our sample can be attributed to their trademarking status only. We then explicitly test the hypothesis that trademarldng and non-trademarking banks share the same cost and profit frontiers. We cannot reject the hypothesis of a common cost and profit frontier. We also find that trademarking banks tend to be more profit efficient than non-trademarking banks while there is no significant difference between the cost efficiency scores of trademarking and non-trademarldng banks. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duygun, Meryem; Sena, Vania; Shaban, Mohamed</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Correlated bank runs, interbank markets and reserve requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Canon, Carlos; Margaretic, Paula
This article extends the application of global games of Goldstein and Pauzner (2005) in the banking model of Diamond and Dybvig (1983) to account for correlation in the quality of banks' long term investment, when banks are linked through cross deposits and there is a central bank. The goal is to study how these elements affect the deposit contract that banks offer to depositors and the ex ante probability of a bank run. We show that the coexistence of a central bank, which determines banks' reserve requirements, and an interbank market, which redistributes reserves, leads to a smaller probability of a bank run and to fewer inefficient bank runs, relative to the case with no central bank and no interbank market. By adequately choosing the level of reserves to store, the central bank can improve the equilibrium outcome and allow banks to offer a higher interim payment to depositors, relative to the situation with no cross deposits. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Canon, Carlos; Margaretic, Paula</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integrating corporate ownership and pension fund structures: A general equilibrium approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ebrahim, M. Shahid; Mathur, Ike; ap Gwilym, Rhys
This paper studies pension fund design in the context of investment in the debt and equity of a firm. We employ a general equilibrium framework to demonstrate that: (i) the asset location 'puzzle' is purely a partial equilibrium phenomenon, conceived in a risk neutral setting, that disappears with the introduction of sufficient risk aversion; (ii) the inability of policy makers to manage an economy with multiple firms yields a mixed equilibrium, where bonds are observed in both taxable and tax-deferred accounts; and (iii) the Pareto-efficient pension plan comprises of a defined benefit plan. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ebrahim, M. Shahid; Mathur, Ike; ap Gwilym, Rhys</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of economic news on bond prices: Evidence from the MTS platform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paiardini, Paola
Although there is an extensive literature on the impact of macroeconomic announcements on asset prices, the bond market has received less attention than the foreign exchange and equity markets, even less if we consider the European market. This paper uses high-frequency intra-day data over a three-year period to investigate the impact of regularly scheduled macroeconomic news and monetary policy announcements on the returns of the Italian government bond market, the largest one in the Euro-zone. With respect to the previous papers, we use a much broader set of announcements, 68, and a relatively novel dataset (MTS). We find that 25 news have a significant impact on bond returns and that almost all announcements are incorporated into prices within 20 min from the release. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Paiardini, Paola</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund herding in response to hedge fund herding and the impacts on stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiao, Yawen; Ye, Pengfei
We examine whether mutual funds and hedge funds herd after each other and the associated impacts on stock prices. We find strong evidence that mutual funds herd into or out of stocks following the herd of hedge funds: mutual funds' herding measure is positively related to last quarter's hedge fund herding. In contrast, hedge funds do not follow mutual funds. Mutual funds' following of hedge funds leads to a sharp price reversal in the next quarter, whereas hedge fund herding itself does not destabilize prices. Further, a mutual fund's following intensity increases with its past performance. The top 30% of mutual funds most active in following hedge funds do so persistently and drastically increase their herding subsequent to intense herding by hedge funds. They are also the group driving the above price reversals. Overall, our evidence is consistent with the reputational incentives of mutual fund herding and the associated price destabilization effects. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiao, Yawen; Ye, Pengfei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk allocation under liquidity constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Csoka, Peter; Herings, P. Jean-Jacques
Risk allocation games are cooperative games that are used to attribute the risk of a financial entity to its divisions. In this paper, we extend the literature on risk allocation games by incorporating liquidity considerations. A liquidity policy specifies state-dependent liquidity requirements that a portfolio should obey. To comply with the liquidity policy, a financial entity may have to liquidate part of its assets, which is costly. The definition of a risk allocation game under liquidity constraints is not straightforward, since the presence of a liquidity policy leads to externalities. We argue that the standard worst case approach should not be used here and present an alternative definition. We show that the resulting class of transferable utility games coincides with the class of totally balanced games. It follows from our results that also when taking liquidity considerations into account there is always a stable way to allocate risk. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Csoka, Peter; Herings, P. Jean-Jacques</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank risk and national governance in Asia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williams, Barry
The role of national governance upon bank-level risk in the Asian region is analysed. Improvements in national governance are risk reducing at the bank level in developed nations in the Asian region, and over the longer run for those nations affected by the Asian Financial Crisis. A U-shaped relationship between bank risk and bank capital is found, and it is argued that the risk reducing impact of increased capital holdings is close to satiation for developed nations in particular. Evidence of risk seeking due to 'too big to fail' effects is observed; with improved national governance able to partially offset some of the moral hazard due to size in developed nations, but not in developing nations. In developing nations increased size interacts with improved national governance to result in increased bank risk. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Williams, Barry</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finding the core: Network structure in interbank markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>In't Veld, Daan; van Lelyveld, Iman
This paper investigates the network structure of interbank markets. Using a dataset of interbank exposures in the Netherlands, we corroborate the recent hypothesis that the core periphery model is a 'stylised fact' of interbank markets. We find a core of highly connected banks intermediating between periphery banks and pay particular attention to model selection. Our analysis can help improve systemic risk assessments, especially as more granular data is becoming available. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>In't Veld, Daan; van Lelyveld, Iman</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of hedge fund share restrictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Xin
Nearly one in five hedge funds change their share restrictions (e.g., lockup) from 2007 to 2012. Using a large panel dataset, this paper is the first to empirically examine the incidence, determinants, and consequences of share restriction changes. We find that funds with high asset liquidity and low liquidity risk are more likely to decrease share restrictions and funds with good performance are more likely to increase share restrictions. A hazard model indicates that funds who actively manage liquidity concerns live longer by adjusting share restrictions. We examine whether changes in share restrictions create an endogeneity bias in the share illiquidity premium (Aragon, 2007) and find that 18% of the premium can be explained by the dynamic nature of contract changes. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Xin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit rating dynamics and competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirth, Stefan
I analyze the market for credit ratings with competition between more than two rating agencies. How can honest rating behavior be achieved, and under which conditions can a new honest rating agency successfully invade a market with inflating incumbents? My model predicts cyclic dynamics if sophisticated investors have a high impact on agencies' reputation. In contrast, if trusting investors have the main impact, then the dynamics exhibits a saddle point rather than cycles. In this case, regulatory support for honest rating agencies is only needed for a limited time, but the effect is sustainable in the long run. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hirth, Stefan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Central bank liquidity provision and collateral quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koulischer, Francois; Struyven, Daan
Should central banks lend against low quality collateral? We characterize efficient central bank collateral policy in a model where a bank borrows from the interbank market or the central bank. Collateral has favorable incentive effects but is costly to transfer to lenders who value the collateral less because of imperfect collateral quality. We show that a fall in the quantity or the quality of the bank's collateral can increase interest rates in the economy even with a constant policy rate. A looser central bank collateral policy can reduce the spread, alleviate the credit crunch and increase output. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koulischer, Francois; Struyven, Daan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The poor are twice cursed: Wealth inequality and inefficient credit market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coco, Giuseppe; Pignataro, Giuseppe
This paper investigates the role of unobservable wealth differences on credit market equilibrium, given there is also asymmetric information concerning effort preferences and choices. In equilibrium, poor but able entrepreneurs may subsidise the rich and incompetent or be excluded. As a result, investment may exceed or fall short of the optimal level. Low inequality may deliver conditions for perfect screening and an efficient level of investment. The equilibrium with cross subsidisation is consistent with otherwise puzzling empirical observations. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coco, Giuseppe; Pignataro, Giuseppe</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stress testing interest rate risk exposure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abdymomunov, Azamat; Gerlach, Jeffrey
In the current low interest rate environment, the possibility of a sudden increase in rates is a potentially serious threat to financial stability. As a result, analyzing interest rate risk (IRR) is critical for financial institutions and supervisory agencies. We propose a new method for generating yield-curve scenarios for stress testing banks' exposure to IRR based on the Nelson-Siegel (1987) yield-curve model. We show that our method produces yield-curve scenarios with a wider variety of slopes and shapes than scenarios generated by the historical and hypothetical methods typically used in the banking industry and proposed in the literature. We stress test the economic value of equity of a bank balance sheet based on Call Report data from a large U.S. bank. We show that our method provides more information about the bank's exposure to IRR using fewer yield-curve scenarios than the alternative historical and hypothetical methods. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abdymomunov, Azamat; Gerlach, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Homeownership, informality and the transmission of monetary policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elgin, Ceyhun; Uras, Burak R.
Cross-country aggregate data exhibits a strong (positive) relationship between the size of the informal employment and aggregate homeownership rates. We investigate this empirical observation using a cash-in-advance model with housing markets and argue that the rate of inflation is important in explaining the nexus between informality and homeownership rates. Specifically, we uncover a novel monetary transmission mechanism and show that households with informal employment desire to economize on their short-term cash usage and avoid periodic rental payments when (i) informality is associated with constrained business investment finance, and (ii) inflation expectations are high. Our empirical and theoretical findings highlight an important interaction between the conduct of monetary policy and the performance of housing markets. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elgin, Ceyhun; Uras, Burak R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial fragility in the Great Moderation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bezemer, Dirk; Grydaki, Maria
A nascent literature explores the measurement of financial fragility. This paper considers evidence for rising financial fragility during the 1984-2007 Great Moderation in the U.S. The literature suggests that macroeconomic stability combined with strong growth of credit to asset markets, in asset prices and in credit relative to output are all indicators of rising financial fragility. We show each of these trends in the Great Moderation. We derive the testable implication that in the Great Moderation credit growth is driven more by past credit growth and less by output growth (Allen and Gale, 2000), relative to pre-Great Moderation years. Results from a VAR model estimated on quarterly data for 1955-2007 are consistent with the hypothesis. This invites a reinterpretation of the Great Moderation. Our methodology may help understand when a credit boom turns into a credit bubble, and contributes to the development of methods of measuring financial fragility. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bezemer, Dirk; Grydaki, Maria</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What types of banks profit most from fees charged? A cross-country examination of bank-specific and country-level determinants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tennant, David; Sutherland, Richard
The perception that banks are exploiting customers through their fee-charging practices in a bid to maximize profits, has fuelled widespread public interest in identifying the banks that profit most heavily from fees. Using hierarchical cross-country regression analyses, this paper seeks to answer the question what types of banks profit most from fees charged? It also highlights the country level factors that influence banks' ability to profit from fees charged. The factors at the country level distinguish between those that relate specifically to the financial services industry and broader macroeconomic indicators. The paper also identifies three channels through which national culture impacts banks' ability to make high profits from fees. This paper uses the most comprehensive set of explanatory variables in studies of this nature. It has also extended the spatial scope of previous studies on bank fees by including data on banks from 46 developed and developing countries. In light of swelling public pressure on governments to do 'something' about bank fees, ill-advised measures are highlighted. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tennant, David; Sutherland, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed trading before positive vs. negative earnings surprises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Tae-Jun; Lee, Youngjoo; Song, Kyojik Roy
This paper investigates whether institutional investors trade profitably around the announcements of positive or negative earnings surprises. Using Korean data over the period of 2001-2010, we find that information asymmetry is larger before negative earnings surprises (earnings shock) among investors and that the trading volume decreases only before earnings shock announcements due to the severe information asymmetry. We also find that institutions sell their stocks prior to earnings shock announcements whereas individual and foreign investors do not anticipate bad news. Finally, we find that institutional trade imbalance is positively related to the post-announcement abnormal returns of negative events. This study complements and extends prior literature on informed trading around earnings announcements by documenting evidence that domestic institutions exploit their superior information around particularly earnings shock announcements. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Park, Tae-Jun; Lee, Youngjoo; Song, Kyojik Roy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the distribution of total default losses on the Spanish financial system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia-Cespedes, Ruben; Moreno, Manuel
This paper quantifies the credit risk loss distribution of the Spanish financial system by introducing a general Monte Carlo importance sampling (IS) approach. We start obtaining all the required information for the standard credit risk model. Then we quantify the loss distribution under the standard IS method and allocate the total risk over the different institutions in the Spanish financial system. We extend the current IS framework to deal with more general assumptions like random recoveries and market valuation. We also study the variability of the risk measures over the business cycle and the possible variability due to the model parameters uncertainty. Our results show that this approach can be very useful for banking supervisors from a macroprudential point of view and that the risk allocation can vary considerably depending on the valuation model under analysis. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garcia-Cespedes, Ruben; Moreno, Manuel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Options resilience during extreme volatility: Evidence from the market events of May 2010</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cakici, Nusret; Goswami, Gautam; Tan, Sinan
Using intraday trades and quotes data, we study the stock options market before, during, and after the market events of May 6, 2010. Focusing on the S&amp;P 500 and S&amp;P 100 stock options, we explore if the options market provided any discernible signals that forewarned the extreme volatility on that day and whether the recovery was fast and without a permanent impact. We find that the options market reacted to the volatility- rather than predicting it, and almost all of the variables are indistinguishable from their previous levels in the next few trading days. Intraday empirical analysis suggests that most of the impact was over within a few hours from the peak of market volatility. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cakici, Nusret; Goswami, Gautam; Tan, Sinan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO duality and firm performance: Evidence from an exogenous shock to the competitive environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Tina; Zhao, Shan
Regulators and governance activists are pressuring firms to abolish CEO duality (the Chief Executive Officer is also the Chairman of the Board). However, the literature provides mixed evidence on the relation between CEO duality and firm performance. Using the exogenous shock of the 1989 Canada-United States Free Trade Agreement, we find that duality firms outperform non-duality firms by 3-4% when their competitive environments change. Further, the performance difference is larger for firms with higher information costs and better corporate governance. Our results underscore the benefits of CEO duality in saving information costs and making speedy decisions. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yang, Tina; Zhao, Shan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>House prices, capital inflows and macroprudential policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mendicino, Caterina; Punzi, Maria Teresa
This paper evaluates the monetary and macroprudential policies that mitigate the procyclicality arising from the interlinkages between current account deficits and financial vulnerabilities. We develop a two-country dynamic stochastic general equilibrium (DSGE) model with heterogeneous households and collateralised debt. The model predicts that external shocks are important in driving current account deficits that are coupled with run-ups in house prices and household debt. In this context, optimal policy features an interest-rate response to credit and a LTV ratio that countercyclically responds to house price dynamics. By allowing an interest-rate response to changes in financial variables, the monetary policy authority improves social welfare, because of the large welfare gains accrued to the Savers. The additional use of a countercyclical LTV ratio that responds to house prices, increases the ability of borrowers to smooth consumption over the cycle and is Pareto improving. Domestic and foreign shocks account for a similar fraction of the welfare gains delivered by such a policy. (c) 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Mendicino, Caterina; Punzi, Maria Teresa</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does bank market power affect SME financing constraints?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ryan, Robert M.; O'Toole, Conor M.; McCann, Fergal
This paper examines the extent to which bank market power alleviates or magnifies SME credit constraints using a large panel dataset of more than 118,000 SMEs across 20 European countries over the period 2005-2008. To our knowledge, this is the first study to examine bank market power and SME credit constraints in an international, developed economy setting. Moreover, our study is the first to address a number of econometric considerations simultaneously, in particular by controlling for the availability of profitable investment opportunities using a structural Q model of investment. Our results strongly support the market power hypothesis, namely, that increased market power results in increased financing constraints for SMEs. Additionally, we find that the relationship exhibits heterogeneity across firm size and opacity in a manner that suggests that the true relationship between bank market power and financing constraints might not be fully explained by the existing theory. Finally, we find that the effect of bank market power on financing constraints increases in financial systems that are more bank dependent. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ryan, Robert M.; O'Toole, Conor M.; McCann, Fergal</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroprudential and monetary policies: Implications for financial stability and welfare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rubio, Margarita; Carrasco-Gallego, Jose A.
In this paper, we analyze the implications of macroprudential and monetary policies for business cycles, welfare, and financial stability. We consider a dynamic stochastic general equilibrium (DSGE) model with housing and collateral constraints. A macroprudential rule for the loan-to-value ratio (LTV), which responds to credit growth, interacts with a traditional Taylor rule for monetary policy. We compute the optimal parameters of these rules both when monetary and macroprudential policies act in a coordinated and in a non-coordinated way. We find that both policies acting together unambiguously improves the stability of the system. In both cases, this interaction is welfare improving for the society, especially in the case of the non-coordinated game. There is though a trade-off between borrowers and savers. However, borrowers can compensate the saver's welfare loss a la Kaldor-Hicks to achieve a Pareto-superior outcome. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rubio, Margarita; Carrasco-Gallego, Jose A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News sentiment in the gold futures market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smales, Lee A.
This article utilises commodity specific news Sentiment data provided by Thomson Reuters News Analytics to examine the relationship between news sentiment and returns in the gold futures market over the period 2003-2012. There is an asymmetric response to news releases with negative news sentiment invoking a greater contemporaneous response in returns of gold futures. There is evidence to support the supposition that net trader positions significantly impact the identified sentiment relationship with the effect greatest when traders are holding positions contrary to their natural position; this may be explained by constraints imposed on traders in terms of credit availability, exchange imposed limits, or inventory required for physical settlement. Recession, and associated changes in credit costs, impact the size of net positions and the news sentiment/return relationship. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Smales, Lee A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit spread changes within switching regimes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chun, Olfa Maalaoui; Dionne, Georges; Francois, Pascal
Empirical studies on credit spread determinants are predicated on the presence of a single-regime over the entire sample period and thus find limited explanatory power. A single-regime model hides the fact that explanatory variables take on different loadings across changing patterns in credit spreads. In a model with endogenous regimes for credit spreads or with monetary regimes, we find that market, default, and liquidity factors have superior explanatory power because of their interaction with the regime. Lower improvements are found when the regime is defined according to the credit supply regime or the NBER regimes (announced and official). (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chun, Olfa Maalaoui; Dionne, Georges; Francois, Pascal</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutions and the turn-of-the-year effect: Evidence from actual institutional trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lynch, Andrew; Puckett, Andy; Yan, Xuemin
Using a large proprietary database of institutional trades, we investigate whether institutional investors drive the turn-of-the-year (TOY) effect. Institutions that engage in window dressing, tax-loss selling, or risk shifting will contribute to the TOY effect by selling small, poorly performing stocks at the end of December and/or buying those same stocks at the beginning of January. We find abnormal pension fund selling in small stocks with poor past performance during the final trading days in December, providing some support for the window dressing hypothesis. However, we find little evidence that institutional tax-loss selling or risk-shifting trading strategies contribute to TOY returns. Furthermore, stocks with no institutional trading around the year-end exhibit considerably stronger TOY return patterns than stocks in which institutions trade. Taken together, our results suggest that institutions play a limited role in driving the TOY effect. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lynch, Andrew; Puckett, Andy; Yan, Xuemin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The q-theory explanation for the external financing effect: New evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Yuan; Lam, F. Y. Eric C.; Wei, K. C. John
Several studies document a robust negative association between net external financing and average stock returns, which is referred to as the external financing effect. Using total asset growth as a comprehensive measure of overall corporate investment and total profitability gross of R&amp;D expenditures as a measure of true economic profitability, we provide new evidence in support of the q-theory explanation for the external financing effect. We also test the market timing explanation for the external financing effect but fail to document supportive evidence. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Yuan; Lam, F. Y. Eric C.; Wei, K. C. John</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-varying expected momentum profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Dongcheol; Roh, Tai-Yong; Min, Byoung-Kyu; Byun, Suk-Joon
This paper examines the time variations of expected momentum profits using a two-state Markov switching model with time-varying transition probabilities to evaluate the empirical relevance of recent rational theories of momentum profits. We find that in the expansion state the expected returns of winner stocks are more affected by aggregate economic conditions than those of loser stocks, while in the recession state the expected returns of loser stocks are more affected than those of winner stocks. Consequently, expected momentum profits display strong procyclical variations. We argue that the observed momentum profits are the realization of such expected returns and can be interpreted as the procyclicality premium. We provide a plausible explanation for time-varying momentum profits through the differential effect of leverage and growth options across business cycles. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights</description><author>Kim, Dongcheol; Roh, Tai-Yong; Min, Byoung-Kyu; Byun, Suk-Joon</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unobserved systematic risk factor and default prediction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qi, Min; Zhang, Xiaofei; Zhao, Xinlei
We conduct a thorough analysis on the role played by the unobserved systematic risk factor in default prediction. We find that this latent factor outweighs the observed systematic risk factors and can substantially improve the in-sample predictive accuracy at the firm, rating group, and aggregate levels. Thus it might be helpful to include the unobserved systematic risk factor when simulating portfolio credit losses. However, we also find that this factor only marginally improves out-of-sample model performance. Therefore, although the models we investigated all show reasonably good ability to rank order firms by default risk, accurate prediction of default rate remains challenging even when the unobserved systematic risk factor is considered. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Qi, Min; Zhang, Xiaofei; Zhao, Xinlei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does competition influence the bank lending channel in the euro area?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fungacova, Zuzana; Solanko, Laura; Weill, Laurent
This paper examines how competition influences the bank lending channel in the euro area countries. Using a large panel of banks from 12 euro area countries for the period 2002-2010 we analyze the reaction of loan supply to monetary policy actions depending on the degree of bank competition. We find that the effect of monetary policy on bank lending is dependent on bank competition: the transmission of monetary policy via the bank lending channel is less pronounced for banks with extensive market power. Further investigation shows that banks with less market power were more sensitive to monetary policy only before the financial crisis. These results suggest that bank market power has a significant impact on the effectiveness of monetary policy. Therefore,wide variations in the level of bank market power may lead to asymmetric effects of the single monetary policy. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fungacova, Zuzana; Solanko, Laura; Weill, Laurent</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit CARD Act of 2009: What did banks do?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jambulapati, Vikram; Stavins, Joanna
The Credit CARD Act of 2009 was intended to prevent practices in the credit card industry that lawmakers viewed as deceptive and abusive. Among other changes, the Act restricted issuers' account closure policies, eliminated certain fees, and made it more difficult for issuers to change terms on credit card plans. Critics of the Act argued that because of the long lag between approval and implementation of the law, issuing banks would be able to take preemptive actions that might disadvantage cardholders before the law could take effect. Using credit bureau data as well as individual data from a survey of U.S. consumers, we test whether banks closed consumers' credit card accounts or otherwise restricted access to credit just before the enactment of the CARD Act. Because the period prior to the enactment of the CARD Act coincided with the financial crisis and recession, causality in this case is particularly difficult to establish. We find evidence that a higher fraction of credit card accounts were closed following the Federal Reserve Board's adoption of its credit card rules, but not between May 2009, when the CARD Act was signed, and when most of its provisions became law in February 2010. However, we do find evidence that banks deteriorated terms of credit card plans at a higher rate during this period, especially lowered the credit limits. Among the survey respondents whose bank accounts were closed during that period, account holders were much more likely to close their own credit card accounts than to have them closed by their card issuers. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jambulapati, Vikram; Stavins, Joanna</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Yes, the CAPM is testable</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guermat, Cherif
It is well-known that cross-sectional tests of the CAPM are problematic. The market indexes used in empirical tests are likely to be inefficient ex ante, which could lead to spurious results even in the absence of sampling errors. This problem has led many to express serious doubt on the testability of the CAPM. In this paper I show that the CAPM is indeed testable. This paper builds on the seminal paper by Kandel and Stambaugh (1995) and proposes a two-step procedure for testing the CAPM. The first step uses a simple combination of the coefficients of determination from both Ordinary Least Squares and Generalised Least Squares estimations. This step tests whether the index used in the empirical test is efficient and whether there are no omitted factors. The second step tests the hypothesis that the efficient index is the market portfolio. The two-step approach enables testing the CAPM regardless of whether the true expected return generating process is a CAPM or a non-CAPM. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guermat, Cherif</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macro-Networks: An application to euro area financial accounts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Castren, Olli; Rancan, Michela
This paper develops a financial network, designated the "Macro-Network", that depicts the connections between the main financial and non-financial sectors of the economy in the various financial instruments of the euro area. The Macro-Network comprises of linkages across financial and non-financial Sectors in each country. These country-level sector networks are then connected by the cross-border links between the individual banking sectors. Using the Macro-Network to simulate financial shocks, we find that the propagation effects depend on the underlying network structure, which evolves overtime. After the financial crisis, bilateral linkages contracted sharply, reflecting the surge in counterparty risk and the de-leveraging processes. Nonetheless, our analysis suggests that even after this process, vulnerabilities remained in the euro area financial system, while a more diversified portfolio of cross-border exposures might mitigate the shock effects. We identify sectors which are most relevant for the propagation of financial shocks in the Macro-Network. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Castren, Olli; Rancan, Michela</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal portfolio selection with life insurance under inflation risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kwak, Minsuk; Lim, Byung Hwa
This paper investigates a continuous-time optimal consumption, investment, and life insurance decision problem of a family under inflation risk. In the financial market, there is a liquid inflation-linked index bond market which can be utilized to hedge the inflation risk. The explicit solutions are derived for constant relative risk aversion (CRRA) utility case by using martingale approach. The roles of index bond are investigated and it is verified that the index bond may have different roles depending on the market parameters. We analyze the effects of parameters on the optimal strategies with focus on the optimal demand for index bond and the optimal life insurance premium. Especially, the changes of expected inflation rate and volatility of inflation rate can have both positive and negative impacts on the life insurance premium and their quantitative impacts are considerable. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kwak, Minsuk; Lim, Byung Hwa</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm value in crisis: Effects of firm-level transparency and country-level institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Enikolopov, Ruben; Petrova, Maria; Stepanov, Sergey
Recent empirical research suggests that country-level and firm-level governance institutions are substitutes with respect to their effect on firm value. In this paper we demonstrate that during a crisis these institutions may actually become complements. Specifically, we find that the decline in companies' valuation during the financial crisis of 2007-2009 was more sensitive to firm-level transparency in countries with stronger investor protection. We propose a theoretical model that reconciles our findings with the results in the literature. In our model, during "normal times" strong firm-level governance is crucial to attract outside financing in countries with weak investor protection, but is less important in countries with good investor protection. During a crisis, however, investment opportunities decline even in countries with strong investor protection, and, as a result, relative importance of firm-level governance increases in such places. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Enikolopov, Ruben; Petrova, Maria; Stepanov, Sergey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification and systemic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Raffestin, Louis
Portfolio diversification makes investors individually safer but creates connections between them through common asset holdings. Such connections create "endogenous covariances" between assets and investors, and enhance systemic risk by propagating shocks swiftly through the system. We provide a theoretical model in which shocks spread through constrained selling from N diversified portfolio investors in a network of asset holdings with home bias, and study the desirability of diversification by comparing the multivariate distribution of implied losses for every level of diversification. There may be a region on the parameter set for which the propagation effect dominates the individually safer one. We derive analytically the general element of the covariance between two assets i and j. We find agents may minimize their exposure to endogenous risk by spreading their wealth across more and More distant assets. The resulting network enhances systemic stability. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Raffestin, Louis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust minimum variance portfolio with L-infinity constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xing, Xin; Hu, Jinjin; Yang, Yaning
Portfolios selected based on the sample covariance estimates may not be stable or robust, particularly so in situations with a large number of assets. The l(1) or l(2) norm constrained portfolio optimization method has been used as a robust method to control the sparsity or to shrink the estimated weights of assets. In this paper, we propose to add an additional l(infinity) norm constraint or to add a pairwise l(infinity) norm constraint in the l(1) norm constrained minimum-variance portfolio (MVP) problem. The l(infinity) constraint controls the largest absolute component of the weight vector and the pairwise l(infinity) constraint encourages retaining the cluster structure of highly correlated assets in MVP optimization. By simulation study and analysis of empirical data, we find that the proposed portfolios often have better out-of-sample performance in terms of Sharpe ratios, variances and turn-overs than existing popular portfolio strategies including the l(1) norm constrained MVP, l(2) norm constrained MVP and the 1/N portfolio. In addition, we provide moment shrinkage interpretations of the new strategies and an upper bound of errors in the approximation of the empirical optimal portfolio risk based on the theoretical optimal portfolio risk. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xing, Xin; Hu, Jinjin; Yang, Yaning</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do banks really monitor? Evidence from CEO succession decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marshall, Andrew; McCann, Laura; McColgan, Patrick
We demonstrate that banks play an important monitoring role in CEO succession that is not observed for other types of lenders, particularly public bondholders. There is a stronger relation between cash flow performance and forced CEO turnover for firms issuing bank debt during the year of CEO turnover than for firms not issuing bank debt, and bank debt issuance increases the likelihood of external CEO succession. The stock price reaction to CEO succession is higher when bank monitoring is prevalent. Our results are consistent with theories of relationship banking that propose a valuable monitoring role for well informed, incentivized bank lenders. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marshall, Andrew; McCann, Laura; McColgan, Patrick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring aggregate risk: Can we robustly identify asset-price boom-bust cycles?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borgy, Vladimir; Clerc, Laurent; Renne, Jean-Paul
We investigate the extent to which it is possible to detect asset-price booms and banking crises according to alternative identification strategies and we assess their robustness. We find some evidence that house price-booms are more likely to turn into costly recession or to trigger a banking crisis than stock-price booms. Resorting both to a non-parametric approach and a discrete-choice (logit) model, we analyze the ability of a wide set of indicators to robustly explain costly asset-price booms. According to our results, real long-term interest rates and real stock prices tend to increase the probability of a costly housing-price boom, whereas real GDP tends to increase the probability of a costly stock-price boom. Interestingly, the credit-to-GDP gap indicator, sometimes put forward in the literature as a key reference for setting countercyclical capital buffers, does not seem to be a robust leading indicator of costly booms or banking crises. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Borgy, Vladimir; Clerc, Laurent; Renne, Jean-Paul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of banking system reform on investment-cash flow sensitivity: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsai, Ying-Ju; Chen, Yi-Pei; Lin, Chi-Ling; Hung, Jung-Hua
This study investigates the effect of banking system reform on the investment behavior of Chinese listed firms. We find that the politically-oriented investment problem for state-controlled listed companies is mitigated by the reform due to foreign participation in the management of Chinese banks. The problem of underinvestment in non-state-controlled listed companies also appears to be alleviated due to an increase of bank loans. We include leverage in our analysis and the main findings are robust. The results provide evidence that Chinese banking system reform has increased the efficiency of resource allocation, easing investment distortions in state-controlled listed companies and reducing financial constraints in non-state-controlled listed companies. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tsai, Ying-Ju; Chen, Yi-Pei; Lin, Chi-Ling; Hung, Jung-Hua</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The IPO underwriting market share in China: Do ownership and quality matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Chao; Shi, Haina; Xu, Haoping
This paper investigates the determinants of initial public offering (IPO) underwriting market share in China. Using a sample of underwriters in China's IPO market during 2004-2012, we find the following results. First, underwriting quality is overall positively related to underwriting market share. Second, individual underwriting quality measures are significantly related to market share as well: Affiliated star analysts are valued by both state-owned enterprise (SOE) and non-SUE (NSOE) issuers. The post-IPO performance of previous clients (industry specialization) is a significant determinant of market share in the SUE (NSOE) IPO market. Third, central government ownership of underwriters is a significant determinant of market share in the SUE market. Finally, a further test on regulatory change shows that underwriting quality is playing an increasingly important role in enhancing underwriting market share in China's new issue reform era. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Chao; Shi, Haina; Xu, Haoping</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modelling the U.S. sovereign credit rating</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Polito, Vito; Wickens, Mike
This paper proposes a new methodology for generating sovereign credit ratings. These are determined by mapping the probability that the debt-GDP ratio might exceed a maximum debt limit at some point in the future into a credit rating. The debt limit can be either ad hoc or based on the financial ability of a government to change fiscal policy in the future to meet its outstanding obligations. When applied to quarterly U.S. data from 1970 to 2011, two clear instances are found in which the U.S. sovereign credit rating would have been downgraded on this basis: during the 1970s oil crisis and in the aftermath of the Lehman collapse in 2008. This result is robust to several alternative views on the maximum borrowing capacity of the U.S. economy. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Polito, Vito; Wickens, Mike</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric increasing trends in dependence in international equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Okimoto, Tatsuyoshi
This paper investigates asymmetric increasing trends in dependence in major international equity markets. To this end, we develop a multiple-regime smooth-transition copula GARCH model and address several important questions, including the number of regimes and the existence of increasing asymmetric trends in dependence. Our results suggest that two or three regimes are sufficient for describing the dependence trends in international equity markets over the last 35 years with significant asymmetric increases. In addition, the implied time-series of three dependence measures show a wide variety of dynamics, demonstrating the usefulness of our framework to describe asymmetric increasing dependence trends. Finally, we evaluate the economic significance of our empirical finding based on the 99% Value at Risk and expected shortfall. Our result indicates that both risk measures have increased approximately 20% over the last 35 years in major equity markets. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Okimoto, Tatsuyoshi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stability analysis of financial contagion due to overlapping portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caccioli, Fabio; Shrestha, Munik; Moore, Cristopher; Farmer, J. Doyne
Common asset holdings are widely believed to have been the primary vector of contagion in the recent financial crisis. We develop a network approach to the amplification of financial contagion due to the combination of overlapping portfolios and leverage, and we show how it can be understood in terms of a generalized branching process. This can be used to compute the stability for any particular configuration of portfolios. By studying a stylized model we estimate the circumstances under which systemic instabilities are likely to occur as a function of parameters such as leverage, market crowding, diversification, and market impact. Although diversification may be good for individual institutions, it can create dangerous systemic effects, and as a result financial contagion gets worse with too much diversification. There is a critical threshold for leverage; below it financial networks are always stable, and above it the unstable region grows as leverage increases. Note that our model assumes passive portfolio management during a crisis; however, we show that dynamic deleveraging during a crisis can amplify instabilities. The financial system exhibits "robust yet fragile" behavior, with regions of the parameter space where contagion is rare but catastrophic whenever it occurs. Our model and methods of analysis can be calibrated to real data and provide simple yet powerful tools for macroprudential stress testing. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caccioli, Fabio; Shrestha, Munik; Moore, Cristopher; Farmer, J. Doyne</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do we know about the impact of government interventions in the banking sector? An assessment of various bailout programs on bank behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hryckiewicz, Aneta
Systemic banking crises have placed enormous pressure on national governments to intervene. The empirical literature, however, is inconclusive on what an optimal bailout program should look like to mitigate the negative consequences of government interventions in the banking sector. We find that, in general government interventions have a negative impact on banking sector stability, significantly increasing its risk. In particular, we find that among bailout measures, nationalization and asset management companies (AMCs) contribute most to the risk effect and that among liquidity support mechanisms, public guarantees are the largest contributor to the risk effect. However, we also find that by making an appropriate choice of intervention mechanisms, governments can mitigate the negative consequences stemming from the above-mentioned effects. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hryckiewicz, Aneta</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Press freedom, externally-generated transparency, and stock price informativeness: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Jeong-Bon; Zhang, Hao; Li, Liuchuang; Tian, Gaoliang
This paper examines the impact of press freedom on stock price informativeness in a sample of firms from 50 countries. We find a significant relation between more press freedom and lower stock price synchronicity. Our results suggest that the freedom of the press can enhance the information environment of stock markets. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Jeong-Bon; Zhang, Hao; Li, Liuchuang; Tian, Gaoliang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can we forecast the implied volatility surface dynamics of equity options? Predictability and economic value tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernales, Alejandro; Guidolin, Massimo
We examine whether the dynamics of the implied volatility surface of individual equity options contains exploitable predictability patterns. Predictability in implied volatilities is expected due to the learning behavior of agents in option markets. In particular, we explore the possibility that the dynamics of the implied volatility surface of individual stocks may be associated with movements in the volatility surface of S&amp;P 500 index options. We present evidence of strong predictable features in the cross-section of equity options and of dynamic linkages between the volatility surfaces of equity and S&amp;P 500 index options. Moreover, time-variation in stock option volatility surfaces is best predicted by incorporating information from the dynamics in the surface of S&amp;P 500 options. We analyze the economic value of such dynamic patterns using strategies that trade straddle and delta-hedged portfolios, and find that before transaction costs such strategies produce abnormal risk-adjusted returns. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bernales, Alejandro; Guidolin, Massimo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sentiment and the MAX effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fong, Wai Mun; Toh, Benjamin
Bali et al. (2011) uncover a new anomaly (the "MAX effect") related to investors' desire for stocks with lottery-like payoffs. Specifically, stocks with high maximum daily returns (high MAX) over the past month perform poorly relative to stocks with low maximum daily returns (low MAX) over the past month. We show that the MAX effect is strongly dependent on investor sentiment and is mainly due to the poor performance of high MAX stocks rather than high returns of low MAX stocks. Investors' desire to gamble in high MAX stocks is not limited to individual investors but is also present amongst some institutions. Controlling for past sentiment reduces the significance of the MAX effect. Our findings provide a behavioral underpinning to recent "optimal beliefs" theories (Brunnermeier et al., 2007) where investor optimism generates a preference for lottery-type securities. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fong, Wai Mun; Toh, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loss severities on residential real estate debt during the Great Recession</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersson, Fredrik; Mayock, Tom
This study develops estimates of expected loss severities on mortgage exposures using data from Florida during the Great Recession. This paper marks the first attempt at addressing sample selectivity in the context of loss models. We also construct measures of home equity that are more accurate than those employed in previous studies. We find that failing to address sample selection and the use of noisy equity measures in loss models can bias loss estimates significantly. We also find significantly higher loss severities and a greater sensitivity of loss severity to equity than what previous studies report. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Andersson, Fredrik; Mayock, Tom</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The existence and persistence of household financial hardship: A Bayesian multivariate dynamic logit framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Sarah; Ghosh, Pulak; Taylor, Karl
We investigate the existence and persistence of financial hardship at the household level using data from the British Household Panel Survey. Our modelling strategy makes three important contributions to the existing literature on household finances. Firstly, we model nine different types of household financial problems within a joint framework, allowing for correlation in the random effects across the nine equations. Secondly, we develop a dynamic framework in order to model the persistence of financial problems over time by extending our multi-equation framework to allow the presence or otherwise of different types of financial problems in the previous time period to influence the probability that the household currently experiences such problems. Our third contribution relates to the possibility that experiencing financial problems may be correlated with sample attrition. We model missing observations in the panel in order to allow for such attrition. Our modelling framework allows us to identify any persistence in financial problems over time as well as any interdependence that may exist between different types of financial problems. Our findings reveal interesting variations in the determinants of experiencing different types of financial problems including demographic and regional differences. Our findings also highlight persistence in experiencing financial problems over time as well as the role that saving on a regular basis can play in mitigating current financial problems. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Sarah; Ghosh, Pulak; Taylor, Karl</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How to make regulators and shareholders happy under Basel III</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmaltz, Christian; Pokutta, Sebastian; Heidorn, Thomas; Andrae, Silvio
In addition to the Basel II capital ratio, Basel III requires banks to respect additional ratios, such as leverage ratio, liquidity coverage ratio and net stable funding ratio. Banks are required to be compliant with all four constraints simultaneously. Our article provides a framework for banks to help their search for an optimal transition from Basel II to Basel III. Recognizing that banks' return and the four constraints are of linear type, this search can be formulated as a linear program and solved by standard software. Incorporating uncertainty on future defaults, risk weights and withdrawals and formulating the problem as a Chance constrained model does not only yield optimal transition strategies but also determines the internal thresholds for the Basel III-ratios. Our approach needs two standard inputs from controlling: profit margins per product and non-financial adjustment costs to expand or cut back business. The adjustment cost can be used to calibrate the model to the current business mix. This calibration can be done by bank outsiders and allows the model to be used in impact studies to replace ad hoc strategies. To highlight its practicality, we apply our model to a typical German bank with a business mix that complies with Basel II, but not with the Basel III-, capital-, leverage- and net stable funding-ratio. Assuming that its business model is optimal under Basel II, we find that this bank would achieve compliance restructuring its funding side by replacing interbank funding by capital and retail deposits. Additional uncertainty would amplify the magnitude of the changes, but would still affect the same positions. These findings are robust against alternative margin definitions and adjustment cost levels. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schmaltz, Christian; Pokutta, Sebastian; Heidorn, Thomas; Andrae, Silvio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and employment: Evidence from US banking reforms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boustanifar, Hamid
Economic theory offers competing hypotheses about how the cost and availability of finance influence labor market outcomes. Making use of the U.S. banking reforms between the 1970s and the 1990s as a quasi-natural experiment, this paper studies the impact of credit market development on employment. This paper documents the significant effects of these reforms on employment growth. Potential channels between finance and employment are also investigated. Changes in the growth of the number of self-employed individuals, the entry and exit of firms, and investment growth do not explain most of the employment growth following the reforms. The reforms had a substantially higher impact in industries with higher labor intensity, which is consistent with the idea that labor has fixed costs that need to be financed. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boustanifar, Hamid</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Domestic investor protection and foreign portfolio investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giofre, Maela
This paper investigates the impact of domestic investor protection on equity cross-border investment. We bring to light the lower sensitivity of foreign investment to destination countries' corporate governance for those investors enjoying a higher degree of investor protection at home. This evidence is consistent with diminishing marginal returns of corporate governance in portfolio choice. Investors benefiting from high levels of rights protection at home recognize that a large fraction of their portfolio, the domestic one, significantly contributes to the optimal level of corporate governance in portfolios. Consequently, these investors are less demanding about this dimension when constructing their foreign portfolios. As an unintended consequence, all other things being equal, assets issued by foreign countries with good investor protection are severely penalized in portfolios held by investing countries featuring higher standards of corporate governance. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giofre, Maela</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do investors put their money where their mouth is? Stock market expectations and Investing behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Merkle, Christoph; Weber, Martin
To understand how real investors use their beliefs and preferences in investing decisions, we examine a panel survey of self-directed online investors at a UK bank. The survey asks for return expectations, risk expectations, and risk tolerance of these investors in three-month intervals between 2008 and 2010. We combine the survey data with investors' actual trading data and portfolio holdings. We find that investor beliefs have little predictive power for immediate trading behavior. The exception is a positive effect of increases in return expectation on buying activity. Portfolio risk levels and changes are more systematically related to return and risk expectations. In line with financial theory, risk taking increases with return expectations and decreases with risk expectations. In response to their expectations, investors also adjust the riskiness of assets they trade. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Merkle, Christoph; Weber, Martin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of the sovereign debt crisis on the activity of Italian banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albertazzi, Ugo; Ropele, Tiziano; Sene, Gabriele; Signoretti, Federico Maria
We examine the implications of the sovereign debt tensions on the Italian credit market by estimating the effect of the 10-year BTP-Bund spread on a wide array of bank interest rates, categories of loans and income statement variables. We exploit the heterogeneity between large and small intermediaries to assess to what extent the transmission of sovereign risk differed in relation with different banks' balance-sheet characteristics and business strategies. Regarding the cost of funding, we find that changes in the BTP-Bund spread have a sizeable effect on the interest rates on term deposits and newly issued bonds but virtually no effect on overnight deposits. Furthermore, the sovereign spread significantly affects the cost of credit for firms and households and exerts a negative effect on loan growth. All these results are magnified when considering alone the five largest banks, which are typically less capitalized, have a larger funding gap and incidence of bad loans and rely more on non-traditional banking activities. Sovereign tensions also affect the main items of banks' income statement. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Albertazzi, Ugo; Ropele, Tiziano; Sene, Gabriele; Signoretti, Federico Maria</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring bilateral spillover and testing contagion on sovereign bond markets in Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claeys, Peter; Vasicek, Borek
The global financial crisis rapidly spread across borders and financial markets, and also distressed EU bond markets. The crisis did not hit all markets in the same way. We measure the strength and direction of linkages between 16 EU sovereign bond markets using a factor-augmented version of the VAR model in Diebold and Yilmaz (2009). We then provide a novel test for contagion by applying the multivariate structural break test of Qu and Perron (2007) on this FAVAR detecting significant sudden changes in shock transmission. Results indicate substantial spillover, especially between EMU countries, with Belgium, Italy and Spain being key markets during the financial crisis. Contagion has been a rather rare phenomenon limited to a few well defined moments of uncertainty on financial assistance packages for Greece, Ireland and Portugal. Most of the frequent surges in market co-movement are driven by larger shocks rather than by contagion. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Claeys, Peter; Vasicek, Borek</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does auditor choice matter to foreign investors? Evidence from foreign mutual funds worldwide</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chou, Julia; Zaiats, Nataliya; Zhang, Bohui
This study explores whether a firm's auditor choice affects its ability to access foreign equity capital. Using the equity holdings of 35,665 foreign mutual funds from 30 countries for the period 1998-2009, we find evidence that appointing a Big 4 auditor is associated with the increased level of foreign mutual fund ownership in firms. Our results are robust when conditioned on firm-level information asymmetries, country-level information disclosure quality, and when employing the Enron-Andersen fiasco as the natural experiment. Furthermore, appointing Big 4 auditors is particularly important for firms to attract foreign capital during the 2008 global financial crisis. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chou, Julia; Zaiats, Nataliya; Zhang, Bohui</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Applying a macro-finance yield curve to UK quantitative Easing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chadha, Jagjit S.; Waters, Alex
We estimate a macro-finance yield curve model for both the nominal and real forward curve for the UK from 1993 to 2008. Our model is able to accommodate a number of key macroeconomic variables and allows us to estimate the instantaneous response of the yield curve and so gauge the impact of Quantitative Easing on forward rates. We find that 10 year nominal interest rates on average are lower by 46 basis points which can largely be explained by three main channels: portfolio balance; liquidity premium and signalling but there is no sizeable impact on real interest rates. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chadha, Jagjit S.; Waters, Alex</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the Euro-zone on the Mend? Latin American examples to analyze the Euro question</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cavallo, Eduardo A.; Fernandez-Arias, Eduardo; Powell, Andrew
Several European countries face challenges reminiscent of those faced by the emerging economies of Latin America. The economic booms in some peripheral Euro-zone countries financed by large capital inflows; the credit and asset price booms and then the busts including Sudden Stops in capital flows; the strong interaction between sovereign debt and domestic banking systems; the role of foreign banks and contagion; and all in the context of a fixed exchange rate, are familiar plotlines for Latin American audiences. For those Euro-zone countries that built up large Euro-denominated external liabilities, Latin America's experience is particularly relevant and worrisome. Still, Europe may be in a better position to navigate a path out of the crisis given cooperative mechanisms that were absent in Latin America, particularly the availability of massive liquidity support. Nonetheless, while such support buys time, it does not guarantee success. This paper argues that reflecting on Latin America's experience provides useful lessons for Europe to improve the chances for a successful resolution. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cavallo, Eduardo A.; Fernandez-Arias, Eduardo; Powell, Andrew</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early warning systems and systemic banking crises in low income countries: A multinomial logit approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caggiano, Giovanni; Calice, Pietro; Leonida, Leone
This paper estimates an early warning system (EWS) for predicting systemic banking crises in a sample of low income countries in Sub-Saharan Africa. Since the average duration of crises in this sample of countries is longer than one year, the predictive performance of standard binomial logit models is likely to be hampered by the so-called crisis duration bias. The bias arises from the decision to either treat crisis years after the onset of a crisis as non-crisis years or remove them altogether from the model. To overcome this potential drawback, we propose a multinomial logit approach, which is shown to improve the predictive power of our EWS compared to the binomial logit model. Our results suggest that crisis events in low income countries are associated with low economic growth, drying up of banking system liquidity and widening of foreign exchange net open positions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caggiano, Giovanni; Calice, Pietro; Leonida, Leone</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the contribution of banks, insurance and other financial services to systemic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernal, Oscar; Gnabo, Jean-Yves; Guilmin, Gregory
The aim of this paper is to contribute to the debate on systemic risk by assessing the extent to which distress within the main different financial sectors, namely, the banking, insurance and other financial services industries contribute to systemic risk. To this end, we rely on the Delta CoVaR systemic risk measure introduced by Adrian and Brunnermeier (2011). In order to provide a formal ranking of the financial sectors with respect to their contribution to systemic risk, the original Delta CoVaR approach is extended here to include the Kolmogorov-Smimov test developed by Abadie (2002), based on bootstrapping. Our empirical results reveal that in the Eurozone, for the period ranging from 2004 to 2012, the other financial services sector contributes relatively the most to systemic risk at times of distress affecting this sector. In turn, the banking sector appears to contribute more to systemic risk than the insurance sector. By contrast, the insurance industry is the systemically riskiest financial sector in the United States for the same period, while the banking sector contributes the least to systemic risk in this area. Beyond this ranking, the three financial sectors of interest are found to contribute significantly to systemic risk, both in the Eurozone and in the United States. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bernal, Oscar; Gnabo, Jean-Yves; Guilmin, Gregory</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modelling long run comovements in equity markets: A flexible approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martins, Luis F.; Gabriel, Vasco J.
International equity markets linkages are characterized by nonlinear dependence and asymmetries. We investigate shifts in long run comovements in stock markets by means of an 'interrupted' Markov switching cointegration specification. This flexible approach allow us to study to what extent documented changes in global integration are permanent, or whether market linkages are subject to changes. Using an illustrative sample from 1980 to 2012 for USA, UK and Hong Kong stock price indices, we find evidence of interrupted cointegration across these markets between May 1997 and April 2002, which is consistent with the decoupling of stock prices from fundamentals during the dot-com bubble. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Martins, Luis F.; Gabriel, Vasco J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial contagion and asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fry-McKibbin, Renee; Martin, Vance L.; Tang, Chrismin
Asset market interconnectedness can give rise to significant contagion risks during periods of financial crises that extend beyond the risks associated with changes in volatilities and correlations. These channels include the transmission of shocks operating through changes in the higher order comoments of asset returns, including changes in coskewness arising from changes in the interaction between volatility and average returns across asset markets. These additional contagion channels have nontrivial implications for the pricing of options through changes in the payoff probability structure and more generally, in the management of financial risks. The effects of incorrectly pricing risk has proved to be significant during many financial crises, including the subprime crisis from mid 2007 to mid 2008, the Great Recession beginning 2008 and the European debt crisis from 2010. Using an exchange options model, the effects of changes in the comoments of asset returns across asset markets are investigated with special emphasis given to understanding the effects on hedging risk during financial crises. The results reveal that by not correctly pricing the risks arising from higher order moments during financial crises, there is significant mispricing of options, while hedged portfolios during noncrisis periods become exposed to price movements in times of crises. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fry-McKibbin, Renee; Martin, Vance L.; Tang, Chrismin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Defending against speculative attacks - It is risky, but it can pay off</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erler, Alexander; Bauer, Christian; Herz, Bernhard
While currency crises are typically considered to be painful and costly events, a closer look reveals that economic developments after a speculative attack differ considerably. Monetary authorities can play a central role in determining the economic course and costs of currency crises. They have to decide whether to defend or not to defend the domestic currency giving rise to three different types of crises: (i) an immediate depreciation if the central bank does not intervene and either (ii) a successful defense or (iii) an unsuccessful defense in the case of an intervention. We find that a central bank has two options to mitigate the costs of speculative attacks, namely an immediate depreciation and a successful defense. If a central bank intervenes she might be able to stabilize the exchange rate only temporarily and risks to ultimately fail facing the worst of the three scenarios with the highest economic costs. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Erler, Alexander; Bauer, Christian; Herz, Bernhard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Innovation and financial liberalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, James B.
This paper attempts to shed some light on the role of financial sector policies in generating new knowledge, drawing on the experience of one of the fastest growing and largest developing countries. Using time series data for India over the period 1963-2005, the results indicate that interest rate restraints help generate ideas. Other financial repressionist policies, in the form of high reserve and liquidity requirements, as well as significant directed credit controls, appear to have a dampening effect on ideas production. These results lend some support to the argument that some form of financial sector reforms may help stimulate economic growth via increasing technological innovation. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, James B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payday loans and consumer financial health</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhutta, Neil
The annualized interest rate for a payday loan often exceeds 10 times that of a typical credit card, yet this market grew immensely in the 1990s and 2000s, elevating concerns about the risk payday loans pose to consumers and whether payday lenders target minority neighborhoods. This paper employs individual credit record data, and Census data on payday lender store locations, to assess these concerns. Taking advantage of several state law changes since 2006 and, following previous work, within-state-year differences in access arising from proximity to states that allow payday loans, I find little to no effect of payday loans on credit scores, new delinquencies, or the likelihood of overdrawing credit lines. The analysis also indicates that neighborhood racial composition has little influence on payday lender store locations conditional on income, wealth and demographic characteristics. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bhutta, Neil</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of private equity and venture capital on sales and employment growth in small and medium-sized businesses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paglia, John K.; Harjoto, Maretno A.
We study the effects private equity (PE) and venture capital (VC) financing have on small and mid-sized single entity business establishments from 1995 to 2009. We focus on single entity establishments to cleanly examine the impact of PE and VC financing on establishments' organic growth. This study reveals that PE and VC financing have positive impacts on single entity business establishments' net sales and employment growth. The impact of PE financing on establishments' growth is slower and smaller than VC financing. However, we find that the benefit of PE financing lasts longer than VC financing. We also find that ethnic minority, female, and foreign business owners are less likely to receive PE and VC financing. Finally, we find evidence that although establishments with government contracts are more likely to receive PE and VC financing, those contracts fail to produce marginal post-funding growth and employment benefits. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Paglia, John K.; Harjoto, Maretno A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO inside debt holdings and risk-shifting: Evidence from bank payout policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Srivastav, Abhishek; Armitage, Seth; Hagendorff, Jens
Bank payouts divert cash to shareholders, while leaving behind riskier and less liquid assets to repay debt holders in the future. Bank payouts, therefore, constitute a type of risk-shifting that benefits equity holders at the expense of debt holders. In this paper, we provide insights on how CEO incentives stemming from inside debt (primarily defined benefit pensions and deferred compensation) impact bank payout policy in a manner that protects debt holder interests. We show that CEOs with higher inside debt relative to inside equity are associated with more conservative bank payout policies. Specifically, CEOs paid with more inside debt are more likely to cut payouts and to cut payouts by a larger amount. Reductions in payouts occur through a decrease in both dividends and repurchases. Our results also hold over a subsample of TARP banks where we expect the link between risk-shifting and payouts to be of particular relevance because it involves wealth transfers from the taxpayer to equity holders. We conclude that inside debt can help in addressing risk-shifting concerns by aligning the interests of CEOs with those of creditors, regulators, and in the case of TARP banks, the taxpayer. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Srivastav, Abhishek; Armitage, Seth; Hagendorff, Jens</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting volatility of the U.S. oil market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haugom, Erik; Langeland, Henrik; Molnar, Peter; Westgaard, Sjur
We examine the information content of the CBOE Crude Oil Volatility Index (OVX) when forecasting realized volatility in the WTI futures market. Additionally, we study whether other market variables, such as volume, open interest, daily returns, bid-ask spread and the slope of the futures curve, contain predictive power beyond what is embedded in the implied volatility. In out-of-sample forecasting we find that econometric models based on realized volatility can be improved by including implied volatility and other variables. Our results show that including implied volatility significantly improves daily and weekly volatility forecasts; however, including other market variables significantly improves daily, weekly and monthly volatility forecasts. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Haugom, Erik; Langeland, Henrik; Molnar, Peter; Westgaard, Sjur</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The home bias is here to stay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Haim; Levy, Moshe
Over the last 15 years, dramatically decreasing foreign investment costs have not reduced the home bias. We show that the home bias induced by a given cost is proportional to the factor rho/(1-rho), where rho is the average correlation between markets. This factor is very sensitive to the correlation, especially when the correlation is high. Empirically, correlations have been steadily increasing from 0.4 in the 90's to about 0.9 today. Thus, the decreasing extra costs are increasingly magnified, explaining the persistence of the home bias, and predicting its continuation. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Levy, Haim; Levy, Moshe</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling and monitoring risk acceptability in markets: The case of the credit default swap market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madan, Dilip B.
Minimal discounted distorted expectations across a range of stress levels are employed to model risk acceptability in markets. Interactions between discounting and stress levels used in measure changes are accommodated by lowering discount rates for the higher stress levels. Acceptability parameters represent a maximal and minimal discount rate, a maximal stress level and the speed of rate reduction in response to stress. An explicit model relating credit default swap (CDS) prices to default probabilities is formulated with a view to making the default risk market acceptable. Data on CDS prices and default probabilities for the six major US banks obtained from the Risk Management Institute of the National University of Singapore is employed to estimate parameters defining acceptability and the movements in market implied recovery rates. We observe that the financial crisis saw an increase in the maximal discount rate and its spread over the minimal rate along with an increase in the maximal stress level being demanded for acceptability and a stable pattern for the speed of rate adjustment through the period. The maximal rate, rate spread and stress levels have come down but with periods in the interim where they have peaked as they did in the crisis. Recovery rates have oscillated and they did fall substantially but have recovered towards 40 percent near the end of the period. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Madan, Dilip B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pricing of G7 sovereign bond spreads - The times, they are a-changin</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Agostino, Antonello; Ehrmann, Michael
Against the background of the current debate about fiscal sustainability in several advanced economies, this paper estimates determinants of G7 sovereign bond spreads, using high-frequency proxies for market expectations about macroeconomic fundamentals and allowing for time-varying parameters. The paper finds substantial asymmetry in the importance of country fundamentals and considerable time variations in the pricing of risks. There has been a reduced pricing of several risk factors in the years preceding the financial crisis, and either an over-pricing of risk or the pricing of a re-denomination risk of euro area bonds during the European sovereign debt crisis, a pattern that does not apply to the non-euro area G7 bonds. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>D'Agostino, Antonello; Ehrmann, Michael</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-sample density forecasts with affine jump diffusion models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yun, Jaeho
We conduct out-of-sample density forecast evaluations of the affine jump diffusion models for the S&amp;P 500 stock index and its options' contracts. We also examine the time-series consistency between the model-implied spot volatilities using options &amp; returns and only returns. In particular, we focus on the role of the time-varying jump risk premia. Particle filters are used to estimate the model-implied spot volatilities. We also propose the beta transformation approach for recursive parameter updating. Our empirical analysis shows that the inconsistencies between options &amp; returns and only returns are resolved by the introduction of the time-varying jump risk premia. For density forecasts, the time-varying jump risk premia models dominate the other models in terms of likelihood criteria. We also find that for medium-term horizons, the beta transformation can weaken the systematic effect of misspecified AJD models using options &amp; returns. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yun, Jaeho</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option implied volatilities and the cost of issuing equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fodor, Andy; Gokkaya, Sinan
The structure of a firm-commitment Seasoned Equity Offering (SEO) resembles a put-option underwritten by an investment bank syndicate (Smith, 1977). Employing implied volatilities from issuers' stock options as a direct forward-looking measure, this paper examines the impact of expected price risk around SEO issue dates on the direct cost of issuing equity. Using a comprehensive sample of 1208 SEOs between 1996 and 2009, we find issuers with higher option implied volatilities raise less external equity capital and pay higher investment bank fees in the stock market, ceteris paribus. The effect of implied volatility on the investment bank fees is stronger for larger issuers with lower pre-SEO abnormal realized stock volatilities, and for SEOs with higher expected price pressures around issue dates. These relationships are robust to adjustments for correlations among control variables, sample selection bias and also simultaneous determination of offer size and SEG fees. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Fodor, Andy; Gokkaya, Sinan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Religious holidays, investor distraction, and earnings announcement effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pantzalis, Christos; Ucar, Erdem
We examine price reactions to U.S. firms' earnings announcements during Easter week in order to analyze whether and how the religious holiday calendar impacts investors' information processing. We find that there is an asymmetric pattern of immediate and delayed responses to earnings surprises experienced during Easter, entailing similar immediate reactions to both good and bad news and a stronger delayed response to bad news. Moreover, local religious characteristics affect investor's response to firm news, The results are consistent with a religion-induced distraction effect on investors' information processing ability. We also show that this effect can form the basis for a profitable trading strategy. The findings highlight the importance of religion for firms' information environment and for the local component of stock prices. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pantzalis, Christos; Ucar, Erdem</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private information flow and price discovery in the U.S. treasury market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, George J.; Lo, Ingrid
Using intraday data, we identify the intensity of private information flow in the U.S. Treasury market. Our results show that the intensity of private information flow is highly correlated with public information shocks and higher for longer maturity bonds. More importantly, we find that bond price changes associated with high intensity of private information flow tend to be persistent, whereas those associated with low intensity of private information flow are more likely reversed. While public information and private information are the main determinants of bond price variations on days with news announcements, private information and liquidity shocks are important determinants of bond price variations on days with no significant events. Finally, we show that the depth of limit order book is inversely related to the intensity of private information flow. Nevertheless, informed dealers do not seem to use hidden orders to disguise their trading intentions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, George J.; Lo, Ingrid</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How useful is the Marginal Expected Shortfall for the measurement of systemic exposure? A practical assessment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Idier, Julien; Lame, Gildas; Mesonnier, Jean-Stephane
We explore the practical relevance from a supervisor's perspective of a popular market-based indicator of the exposure of a financial institution to systemic risk, the Marginal Expected Shortfall (MES). The MES of an institution can be defined as its expected equity loss when the market itself is in its left tail. We estimate the dynamic MES recently proposed by Brownlees and Engle (2012) for a panel of 68 large US banks over the last decade and a half. Running panel regressions of the MES on bank characteristics, we first find that the MES can be roughly rationalized in terms of standard balance-sheet indicators of bank financial soundness and systemic importance. We then ask whether the cross section of the MES can help to identify ex ante, i.e. before a crisis unfolds, which institutions are more likely to suffer the most severe losses ex post, i.e. once it has unfolded. Unfortunately, using the 2007-2009 crisis as a natural experiment, we find that some standard balance-sheet ratios are better able than the MES to predict large equity losses conditionally to a true crisis. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Idier, Julien; Lame, Gildas; Mesonnier, Jean-Stephane</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home equity lines of credit and the unemployment rate: Have unemployed consumers borrowed themselves into the next financial crisis?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michel, Norbert; Lajaunie, John P.; Lawrence, Shari; Fanguy, Ronnie
Some economists argue the recent recovery has been so meager because many consumers have lost their main source of income and maxed-out their home-equity borrowings. Further, banks that were able to make consumer loans did so with less security because home prices fell so dramatically. This paper argues that at least part of that recovery story is purely anecdotal and, in fact, incorrect. In spite of the precipitous decline in home prices, the original price increases were so large that many homeowners still have/had adequate equity in their homes to borrow. The paper presents evidence that the average quarterly increase in aggregate home equity line of credit (HELOC) lending after housing prices began their decline is, statistically, no different than the average quarterly increase in HELOC lending before housing prices began their downward trend. The evidence also suggests that increased HELOC lending during the recession is not correlated with higher unemployment. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Michel, Norbert; Lajaunie, John P.; Lawrence, Shari; Fanguy, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can interest rates really control house prices? Effectiveness and implications for macroprudential policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shi, Song; Jou, Jyh-Bang; Tripe, David
This paper investigates how changes in the central bank policy and retail mortgage rates affected real housing prices in New Zealand during the period 1999-2009. We find that real interest rates are significantly and positively related to real housing prices, indicating that increases in the policy rate may not be effective in depressing real housing prices. By testing interest rates, we also find some evidence of housing price bubbles. Our findings suggest that the central bank could have limited housing price bubbles if it had started to intervene in the housing market prior to 2003. Our results set international exemplars for using policy rates or macroprudential tools to cool the housing market, where the extent of policy rate adjustments is limited by internal or external economic factors. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shi, Song; Jou, Jyh-Bang; Tripe, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does it pay to be ethical? Evidence from the FTSE4Good</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belghitar, Yacine; Clark, Ephraim; Deshmukh, Nitin
The empirical mean-variance evidence comparing the performance of Socially Responsible Investments (SRI) and conventional investments suggests that there is no significant difference between the two. This paper re-examines the problem in the context of Marginal Conditional Stochastic Dominance (MCSD), which can accommodate any return distribution or concave utility function. Our results provide strong evidence that there is a financial price to be paid for socially responsible investing. Indices composed of socially responsible firms are MCSD dominated by trademarked indices composed of conventional firms as well as by indices carefully matched by size and industry with the firms in the SRI indices. Zero cost portfolios created by shorting the SRI index and using the proceeds to invest in the conventional index generate higher average returns, lower variance and higher skewness than either of the two indices standing alone. They also MCSD dominate the SRI and conventional indices standing alone. (C) 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/).</description><author>Belghitar, Yacine; Clark, Ephraim; Deshmukh, Nitin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The fast track IPO - Success factors for taking firms public with SPACs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, Douglas; Hass, Lars Helge; Schweizer, Denis
Special Purpose Acquisition Companies (SPACs) are shells initiated with the sole intent of acquiring a single privately held company. SPAC shareholders vote on this acquisition, and in this paper we identify the factors that affect approval probability. Surprisingly, the data indicate more experienced managers and boards do not enhance the probability of deal approval. Similarly, glamor underwriters and larger underwriter syndicates are less likely to be associated with successful SPACs. Further, we find a negative relation between the presence of active investor (hedge funds and private equity funds) shareholdings in a SPAC and approval probability. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cumming, Douglas; Hass, Lars Helge; Schweizer, Denis</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural breaks in volatility spillovers between international financial markets: Contagion or mere interdependence?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jung, R. C.; Maderitsch, R.
This paper conducts an investigation of volatility transmission between stock markets in Hong Kong, Europe and the United States covering the time period from 2000 up to 2011. Using intra-daily data we compute realized volatility time series for the three markets and employ a Heterogeneous Autoregressive Distributed Lag Model as our baseline econometric specification. Motivated by the presence of various crisis events contained in our sample, we detect time-variation and structural breaks in volatility spillovers. Particularly during the financial crisis of 2007, we find effects consistent with the notion of contagion, suggesting strong and sudden increases in the cross-market synchronization of chronologically succeeding volatilities. Investigating the role of mean breaks and conditional heteroskedasticity in the realized volatilities, however, we find the latter to be the main driver of breaks in volatility spillovers. Taking the volatility of realized volatilities into account, we find no evidence of contagion anymore. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jung, R. C.; Maderitsch, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does the stock market react to the announcement of green policies?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ramiah, Vikash; Martin, Belinda; Moosa, Imad
We investigate the impact of 19 announcements of environmental regulation on the equities listed on the Australian Stock Exchange over the period 2005-2011. Using a well-established event study methodology, we assess whether these announcements are value constructive or destructive for equity investors. Additionally, we estimate the change in systematic risk following the announcements. Our results show that the Australian market was particularly sensitive to the carbon pollution reduction scheme (CPRS) announcement. A cumulative abnormal return of -31% was recorded in the alternative energy sector after Australia submitted its target range to the Copenhagen Accord. We observe that a move towards a greener nation has a mixed effect on abnormal returns with apparent sector-by-sector differences. Green policies appear to affect the long-term systematic risk of industries, leading to the diamond risk phenomenon. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ramiah, Vikash; Martin, Belinda; Moosa, Imad</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic optimal portfolio choice in a jump-diffusion model with investment constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Xing; Zhang, Kun
We consider the dynamic portfolio choice problem in a jump-diffusion model, where an investor may face constraints on her portfolio weights: for instance, no-short-selling constraints. It is a daunting task to use standard numerical methods to solve a constrained portfolio choice problem, especially when there is a large number of state variables. By suitably embedding the constrained problem in an appropriate family of unconstrained ones, we provide some equivalent optimality conditions for the indirect value function and optimal portfolio weights. These results simplify and help to solve the constrained optimal portfolio choice problem in jump-diffusion models. Finally, we apply our theoretical results to several examples, to examine the impact of no-short-selling and/or no-borrowing constraints on the performance of optimal portfolio strategies. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jin, Xing; Zhang, Kun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regional economic development, strategic investors, and efficiency of Chinese city commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Jianjun; Harimaya, Kozo; Yamori, Nobuyoshi
We investigate the effect of strategic investors on bank efficiency in the context of regional economic development. The data on Chinese city commercial banks operating regionally are well-suited for the study. Our findings suggest that strategic investors significantly increase efficiency in Chinese city commercial banks, while the effect of strategic investors on the efficiency of Chinese city commercial banks is negatively correlated to the level of regional economic development. The negative correlation of the effect of strategic investors on Chinese city commercial banks' efficiency with regional economic development may be explained by the mix of local official promotion system and city Commercial banks' governance structure. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Jianjun; Harimaya, Kozo; Yamori, Nobuyoshi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial intermediation, competition and risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fethi, Meryem Duygun; Fiordelisi, Franco; Monferra, Stefano
nan</description><author>Fethi, Meryem Duygun; Fiordelisi, Franco; Monferra, Stefano</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of banking regulation on cross-border lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fidrmuc, Jarko; Hainz, Christa
Banking regulations often differ between countries: Some regulators require banks to document their evaluation of firms' creditworthiness, which determines the banks' choice of lending technology. In a theoretical model, we study how differences in regulation influence competition between domestic and foreign banks and analyze the effect of regulatory harmonization on cross-border lending. We predict that lending rates are lower and access to credit is easier for firms in a border region if the national regulations differ. Using unique bank- and firm-level data from Germany, we show that firms in a border region have better access to credit if regulation differs. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fidrmuc, Jarko; Hainz, Christa</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market crises and Basel capital requirements: Could Basel III have been different? Evidence from Portugal, Ireland, Greece and Spain (PIGS)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rossignolo, Adrian F.; Fethi, Meryem Duygun; Shaban, Mohamed
Basel III represents a crucial step in strengthening the capital rules underlying banking operations, aimed at reducing the probability and severity of a systemic crisis. Alongside two supplementary capital buffers, the Basel Committee of Banking Supervision imposed severe pressure on the Value-at-Risk based Internal Models Approach in order to increase. This is to increase the capital base by adding the stressed Value-at-Risk component in an effort to reduce reliance on internal models while keeping the Standardized Approach avenue open. However, even though those measures might appear theoretically correct, evidence gathered for long and short exposures in Portugal, Italy, Greece and Spain highlights several defects in Basel III. We emphasize that leptokurtic models, primarily those derived from Extreme Value Theory, should be enforced in the regulations given their superior performance in market crises, and that Basel II could have shielded against 2008 mayhem provided that heavy-tailed techniques had been employed. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rossignolo, Adrian F.; Fethi, Meryem Duygun; Shaban, Mohamed</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The interbank market after the financial turmoil: Squeezing liquidity in a "lemons market" or asking liquidity "on tap"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Socio, Antonio
After August 2007 the plumbing system that supplied banks with wholesale funding, the interbank market, failed because toxic assets obstructed the pipes. Banks were forced to squeeze liquidity in a "lemons market" or to ask for liquidity "on tap" from central banks. This paper disentangles the two components of the 3-month Euribor-Eonia swap spread, credit and liquidity risk and then evaluates the decomposition. The main finding is that credit risk increased before the key events of the crisis, while liquidity risk was mainly responsible for the subsequent increases in the Euribor spread and then reacted to the systemic responses of the central banks, especially in October 2008. Moreover, the level of the spread between May 2009 and February 2010 was influenced mainly by credit risk, suggesting that European banks were still in a "lemons market" and relied on liquidity "on tap" even before sovereign debt crisis unfolded in Europe. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Socio, Antonio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of reputational risk in the banking sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fiordelisi, Franco; Soana, Maria-Gaia; Schwizer, Paola
What determines reputational loss following operational losses in banking? The purpose of this paper is to empirically address this question. We estimate the reputational risk for a large sample of banks in Europe and the US between 2003 and 2008. We have two main results. First, we provide evidence that there is the probability that reputational damage increases as profits and size increase. Second, we show that a higher level of capital invested and intangible assets reduce the probability of reputational damage. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fiordelisi, Franco; Soana, Maria-Gaia; Schwizer, Paola</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relationship lending, hierarchical distance and credit tightening: Evidence from the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cotugno, Matteo; Monferra, Stefano; Sampagnaro, Gabriele
This paper examines the firms' credit availability during the 2007-2009 financial crisis using a dataset of 5331 bank-firm relationships provided by borrowers' credit folders of three Italian banks. It aims to test whether a strong lender-borrower relationship can produce less credit rationing for borrowing firms even during a credit crunch period. The results show that exclusivity of the relationship can mitigate the firm credit rationing. We also verify the influence of lending organizational structure during crisis. A new measure of distance in lending technologies has been introduced: the hierarchical distance calculated as the distance between the branch that originates the loan and the location of the hierarchical level responsible for financing decision. Our findings document a negative impact of distance on credit availability, consistent with the idea that proximity facilitates the transmission of soft information. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cotugno, Matteo; Monferra, Stefano; Sampagnaro, Gabriele</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value creation in banking through strategic alliances and joint ventures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amici, Alessandra; Fiordelisi, Franco; Masala, Francesco; Ricci, Ornella; Sist, Federica
A large number of studies (DeYoung et al., 2009) analyze merger outcomes in the financial industry, while other forms of business cooperation are still poorly investigated. Our paper examines results of strategic alliances and joint ventures in European and US banking over the period 1999-2009. First, we estimate abnormal returns around the deal announcement date and then these are regressed on a large set of explanatory variables. We show that joint ventures create shareholder value when involving non-banking financial partners and allowing banks to expand abroad, while international strategic alliances tend to destroy shareholder value. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amici, Alessandra; Fiordelisi, Franco; Masala, Francesco; Ricci, Ornella; Sist, Federica</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust portfolio choice with ambiguity and learning about return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branger, Nicole; Larsen, Linda Sandris; Munk, Claus
We analyze the optimal stock-bond portfolio under both learning and ambiguity aversion. Stock returns are predictable by an observable and an unobservable predictor, and the investor has to learn about the latter. Furthermore, the investor is ambiguity-averse and has a preference for investment strategies that are robust to model misspecifications. We derive a closed-form solution for the optimal robust investment strategy. We find that both learning and ambiguity aversion impact the level and structure of the optimal stock investment. Suboptimal strategies resulting either from not learning or from not considering ambiguity can lead to economically significant losses. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Branger, Nicole; Larsen, Linda Sandris; Munk, Claus</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overreaction of country ETFs to US market returns: Intraday vs. daily horizons and the role of synchronized trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Ariel; Lieberman, Offer
In this paper we study the intraday price formation process of country Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs). We identify specific parts of the US trading day during which Net Asset Values (NAVs), currency rates, premiums and discounts, and the S&amp;P 500 index have special effects on ETF prices, and characterize a special intraday and overnight updating structure between these variables and country ETF prices. Our findings suggest a structural difference between synchronized and non-synchronized trading hours. While during synchronized trading hours ETF prices are mostly driven by their NAV returns, during non-synchronized trading hours the S&amp;P 500 index has a dominant effect. This effect also exceeds the one that the S&amp;P 500 index has on the underlying foreign indices and suggests an overreaction to US market returns when foreign markets are closed. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Levy, Ariel; Lieberman, Offer</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading on inside information: Evidence from the share-structure reform in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tong, Wilson H. S.; Zhang, Shaojun; Zhu, Yanjian
We examine stock trading activities in days before Chinese listed firms made public announcement to start share-structure reform. There is significant evidence that, relative to a benchmark period, institutional investors bought more event firms' shares in the last two trading days prior to announcement. Randomization tests show significant differences in institutional trading activities between event firms and matched control firms, which suggests that some institutions had inside information. Moreover, large trades.account for a significant proportion of daily stock price changes in the last 2 days. The evidence is consistent with the prediction by Holden and Subrahmanyam (1992) that, when multiple informed investors acquire the same piece of information, they will trade aggressively. We also find that over the reform period, the median share value change of event firms is 6% higher than that of control firms. Our findings have important implications for enforcement of insider trading regulations in China. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tong, Wilson H. S.; Zhang, Shaojun; Zhu, Yanjian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregation of exponential smoothing processes with an application to portfolio risk evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sbrana, Giacomo; Silvestrini, Andrea
In this paper we propose a unified framework to analyse contemporaneous and temporal aggregation of a widely employed class of integrated moving average (IMA) models. We obtain a closed-form representation for the parameters of the contemporaneously and temporally aggregated process as a function of the parameters of the original one. These results are useful due to the close analogy between the integrated GARCH (1,1) model for conditional volatility and the IMA (1,1) model for squared returns, which share the same autocorrelation function. In this framework, we present an application dealing with Value-at-Risk (VaR) prediction at different sampling frequencies for an equally weighted portfolio composed of multiple indices. We apply the aggregation results by inferring the aggregate parameter in the portfolio volatility equation from the estimated vector IMA (1,1) model of squared returns. Empirical results show that VaR predictions delivered using this suggested approach are at least as accurate as those obtained by applying standard univariate methodologies, such as RiskMetrics. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sbrana, Giacomo; Silvestrini, Andrea</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance is good for the poor but it depends where you live</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rewilak, Johan
I examine whether or not the incomes of the poor systematically grow with average incomes, and whether financial development enhances the incomes of the poorest quintile. Following the methodology of Dollar and Kraay (2002), I find, once extending Dollar and Kraay's data, their findings are robust to the Lucas critique and economic growth is important for poverty reduction universally. However, in comparison to other authors' work I show financial development aids the incomes of the poor in certain regions, whilst it may be detrimental in others. This proposes evidence against a "one size fits all" model adding a further contribution to the literature on financial development and poverty. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rewilak, Johan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overseas listing as a policy tool: Evidence from China's H-shares</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Qian; Tong, Wilson H. S.; Wu, Yujun
We investigate why the Chinese government chooses to perform share issue privatization (SIP) of its state-owned enterprises (SOEs) in Hong Kong, despite the benefit of facilitating the domestic stock market development if performing SIP in China (Subrahmanyam and Titman, 1999) and the higher cost to list in Hong Kong. We address this issue by arguing that the positive effect of SIPs on the development of the domestic market may have limitations, especially when the domestic market is not well developed and cannot absorb rapid and large-scale SIP activities. To maintain domestic market order, it may be optimal to carry out SIP in overseas markets. Furthermore, by listing shares in developed overseas markets, SOEs from the less developed countries could leverage on the overseas markets' better accounting, governance, and legal standards. By examining a sample of 92 Chinese firms listed in Hong Kong and the relevant control samples of purely domestically listed Chinese firms during the period of 1993-2006, we find supporting evidence for both arguments. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Qian; Tong, Wilson H. S.; Wu, Yujun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy risk, costs and corporate diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singhal, Rajeev; Zhu, Yun
This paper studies the impact of diversification on firms that file for Chapter 11 bankruptcy. Prior research suggests that diversification affects both the probability and costs of distress. Treating bankruptcy as a special case of distress, we find that diversification reduces the likelihood of bankruptcy and liquidation in Chapter 11, which is consistent with the coinsurance hypothesis. However, we observe higher bankruptcy costs as measured by time spent in Chapter 11 and inefficient segment investment for diversified firms. Our evidence is consistent with the idea that diversification provides benefits to managers in terms of job security rather than to firms. Our findings may help firms to make diversification decisions and creditors determine lending policies toward different forms of organizations. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Singhal, Rajeev; Zhu, Yun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private equity performance under extreme regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, Douglas; Zambelli, Simona
This study investigates the impact of excessive regulation on private equity (PE) returns and firm performance. History shows that extreme regulation and prohibition reduce the supply of capital and raise returns (e.g., as with drugs and diamonds). However, for value-added investors such as PE funds, extreme regulation also reduces the quality of capital and fund involvement. The net effect on returns is therefore ambiguous and heretofore not studied. With a new unique dataset, this paper empirically examines the performance of PE investments in Italy when leveraged buyouts are strictly regulated. The data show that extreme regulation reduces not only the supply of capital, but also PE returns and firm performance, as well as the likelihood of an IPO exit. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cumming, Douglas; Zambelli, Simona</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disclosures of material weaknesses by Japanese firms after the passage of the 2006 Financial Instruments and Exchange Law</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernobai, Anna; Yasuda, Yukihiro
We investigate the disclosures of material weaknesses in internal control mandated for Japanese firms under the 2006 Financial Instruments and Exchange Law. We find that the presence of a material weakness is more likely for firms that are younger, have better growth prospects, have a volatile operating environment, are financially constrained, and have weak governance structures. We examine the role of Japan's main banks in this process and find that the likelihood of a material weakness is higher for firms with stronger links with their main banks. We also show that the financial health of the main banks themselves-proxied for by the banks' BIS ratios and bad loan ratios increases the likelihood of a material weakness in affiliated firms. This paper provides novel insights into the determinants of material weaknesses of Japanese firms since the passage of the law. Results from this study contribute to the literature on material weaknesses and relationship banking. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chernobai, Anna; Yasuda, Yukihiro</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prestigious stock exchanges: A network analysis of international financial centers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cetorelli, Nicola; Peristiani, Stavros
In this paper, we use methods from social network analysis to assess the relative importance of financial centers around the world. Using data from virtually the entire universe of global equity activity, we present complete rankings for 45 separate locations for the period 1990-2006. Our analysis constructs a network measure of prestige based on their ability to attract global IPOs. U.S. exchanges are effectively the unique hosts for cross-border equity activity from many other locations. Moreover, they are the destination of choice for most companies coming from locations with highly prestigious exchanges. We also document the emergence of several competing stock exchanges from developed and emerging market economies. The ascent of these stock markets, however, might reflect improved conditions in a growing global market rather than a decline in the competitiveness of U.S. exchanges. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cetorelli, Nicola; Peristiani, Stavros</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systematic stress tests with entropic plausibility constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Thomas; Csiszar, Imre
Stress tests with handpicked scenarios might misrepresent risks either because dangerous scenarios are not considered or because the scenarios considered are too implausible. To overcome these two pitfalls we propose a systematic search for the worst case within a relative entropy ball of sufficiently plausible scenarios. For this purpose we use mixed scenarios, which are risk factor distributions rather than realisations. A Maximum Loss theorem explicitly gives the worst case distribution. The method is illustrated in a number of example applications: linear and quadratic portfolios, stressed default probabilities, stressed correlations, macroeconomic stress tests. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Breuer, Thomas; Csiszar, Imre</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information transfers and learning in financial markets: Evidence from short selling around insider sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakrabarty, Bidisha; Shkilko, Andriy
We document significant increases in short positions on days when company insiders sell their firms' shares. Short selling increases before insider sales are publicly reported and often before insiders finish selling. Furthermore, the magnitude of short selling activity is consistent with short sellers' knowledge of the insider's rank (e.g., CEO, CFO, or a lower-ranked manager) and with knowledge of the unobservable size of the insider's trading position. We show that short sellers' superior timing is consistent with (i) monitoring of order flow and (ii) obtaining price-relevant information from brokerages that execute insider sales. Some of our results extend to insider purchases. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chakrabarty, Bidisha; Shkilko, Andriy</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing at home and abroad: Different costs, different people?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christelis, Dimitris; Georgarakos, Dimitris
We investigate US households' direct investment in stocks, bonds and liquid accounts and their foreign counterparts, in order to identify the different participation hurdles affecting asset investment domestically and overseas. To this end, we estimate a trivariate probit model with three further selection equations that allows correlations among unobservables of all possible asset choices. Our results point to the existence of a second hurdle that stock owners need to overcome in order to invest in foreign stocks. On the other hand, we find little evidence for additional pecuniary or informational costs associated with investment in foreign bonds and liquid accounts. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christelis, Dimitris; Georgarakos, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Safety-net benefits conferred on difficult-to-fail-and-unwind banks in the US and EU before and during the great recession</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carbo-Valverde, Santiago; Kane, Edward J.; Rodriguez-Fernandez, Francisco
This paper investigates the links between regulatory arbitrage, financial instability, and taxpayer loss exposures. We model and estimate ex ante safety-net benefits from increased leverage and asset volatility at a sample of large banks in US and Europe during 2003-2008. Hypothesis tests indicate that, in both crisis and precrisis years, difficult-to-fail-and-unwind (DFU) banks enjoyed substantially higher ex ante benefits than other institutions. Compared to the US sample, safety-net benefits prove significantly larger for DFU firms in Europe and bailout decisions are less driven by asset size. Introducing a proxy for differences in government susceptibility to regulatory capture helps to explain bailout decisions in Europe. Our findings suggest that authorities in both venues could better contain safety-net benefits if they refocused their information systems on monitoring volatility as well as capital. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carbo-Valverde, Santiago; Kane, Edward J.; Rodriguez-Fernandez, Francisco</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political-economy of pension plans: Impact of institutions, gender, and culture</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Raj; Goodell, John W.
National pension systems are an important part of financial intermediation and worker welfare in most countries, but how and why do they differ internationally? Controlling for important political, economic and social institutions, we document that international differences in pension progressivity, or how pensions reflect lifetime earnings, are negatively related to masculinity, uncertainty avoidance, individualism, long-term orientation, employment rights, average pension levels, social trust and economic inequality. We also find that pension progressivity is positively related to the economic and societal role of women, the extent of Catholicism; as well as political voice and accountability. These results provide important insights for both public policy and MNC managers. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, Raj; Goodell, John W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Households' foreign currency borrowing in Central and Eastern Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fidrmuc, Jarko; Hake, Mariya; Stix, Helmut
Foreign currency loans represent an important feature of recent financial developments in CEECs. This might pose a serious challenge for macroeconomic stability. Against this background, we study the determinants of foreign currency loans of households, using data on the behavior of households in nine CEECs. Our results reveal that foreign currency loans are driven by households' lack of trust in the stability of the local currency and in domestic financial institutions. Moreover, special factors including remittances and expectations of euro adoption play an important role in selected regions. The financial crisis reduced foreign currency borrowing, but there is some indication this effect might be only temporary. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fidrmuc, Jarko; Hake, Mariya; Stix, Helmut</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privatization and globalization: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubakri, Narjess; Cosset, Jean-Claude; Debab, Nassima; Valery, Pascale
This paper examines the link between globalization-measured by foreign direct investment (FDI) and foreign portfolio investment (FPI) - and privatization of state-owned enterprises, in a multi-country sample that focuses on developing countries. We hypothesize that privatization has an effect on FDI/FPI as the process of fostering private sector participation is often accompanied by liberalization reforms, and by allocations of substantial shares of newly privatized firms to foreign investors. Similarly, we expect FDI/FPI to foster privatization efforts as new capital inflows, technology and managerial skills that accompany FDI/FPI make the environment more prone to competition, providing governments with incentives to privatize inefficient firms that need to be turned around. This relation is assessed in two ways, first in a dynamic panel using a generalized method of moments approach, and second through panel causality tests. We find a bi-directional positive relation between privatization proceeds and globalization, particularly in the case of FDI. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubakri, Narjess; Cosset, Jean-Claude; Debab, Nassima; Valery, Pascale</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Building legal indexes to explain recovery rates: An analysis of the French and English bankruptcy codes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blazy, Regis; Chopard, Bertrand; Nigam, Nirjhar
The paper analyzes the characteristics of bankruptcy procedures that may impact on creditors' recoveries. We propose 132 legal indexes accounting for the main functions of bankruptcy codes: namely, the accessibility of the procedures, their ability to disclose information, the protection of debtor's assets, the coordination of the claimants and their decision power, and the sanction of management. The French procedures are more protective of the debtor's assets and prioritize the coordination of claims. In England, liquidation procedures protect more secured claims, while unsecured creditors have more decision power under reorganization procedures. Our indexes are then used to explain recovery rates on a set of 833 bankrupt SMEs. Several bankruptcy rules are associated with higher recoveries: namely, accessibility of the procedure, protection of the debtor's assets, protection of claims, and sanction of faulty management. On the contrary, information disclosure has negative impact on recoveries, probably due to the breach in confidentiality. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blazy, Regis; Chopard, Bertrand; Nigam, Nirjhar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can prospect theory be used to predict an investor's willingness to pay?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erner, Carsten; Klos, Alexander; Langer, Thomas
Cumulative prospect theory (CPT) is widely considered to be the most successful descriptive theory for decision making under risk and uncertainty. Sophisticated methods have been developed to reliably elicit CPT parameters on an individual basis. The aim of this paper is to analyze whether such methods are suited to be applied in real world situations, particularly in the context of investment counseling for retail investors. Specifically, we examine whether CPT parameters elicited via standardized computer tools are successful in predicting an individual's preference for different structured financial products. Surprisingly, we find only low predictive power of the elicited CPT parameters on the WTP. Using a second set of experiments, we examine possible explanations for the low prediction quality. Overall, we have to conclude that it is too much of a leap to draw conclusions about the attractiveness of complex financial products from CPT parameters elicited via simple lotteries. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Erner, Carsten; Klos, Alexander; Langer, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changing the rules again: Short selling in connection with public equity offers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Autore, Don M.; Gehy, Dominique
We study the impact of two recent regulations that impose restrictions on short selling. First, since October 2007 any investor that short sells a firm's stock is prohibited from purchasing shares in the firm's seasoned equity offering (SEO) if the short occurred in the five days prior to the offering (pursuant to an amendment to Rule 105). Previously Rule 105 only disallowed investors from covering a pre-issue short sale with shares purchased in the offering. We hypothesize that the amended rule has the unintended consequence of greater discounting for overnight offers, which are not announced in advance, because the rule excludes some potential buyers and thereby forces underwriters to set lower offer prices to fully distribute the offer. The evidence supports this hypothesis. Second, we examine the impact of the SEC's 2008 Emergency Order that greatly curtails naked short selling on all stocks under its jurisdiction. We find that the Emergency Order is associated with large increases in discounting for offers announced in advance, suggesting that the removal of naked short sellers is associated with reduced pre-SEO pricing efficiency. Taken together, the results imply that recent restrictions on short selling have significant unintended effects on the capital raising process. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Autore, Don M.; Gehy, Dominique</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does it help to have friends in high places? Bank stock performance and congressional committee chairmanships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gropper, Daniel M.; Jahera, John S.; Park, Jung Chul
Does a politician with power in the U.S. Congress positively affect the value of firms headquartered in their home state? We investigate this question by examining the profitability and stock performance of commercial banks. Banks can be enormously influenced by the political and regulatory environment. We find that banks headquartered in states where a Senator or member of the House of Representatives serves as the chairman on their respective banking committee in Congress outperform banks headquartered in other states. In addition, we find that this "chair effect" is more pronounced when the committee chairs are strongly aligned with other politicians in Congress, when they are more experienced, and when banks are clustered in the home state, suggesting that the potential benefits generated from chairmanship are in more demand. Overall, our results suggest that there are some important value implications of a local politician's power in Congress. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gropper, Daniel M.; Jahera, John S.; Park, Jung Chul</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is bank default risk systematic?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fiordelisi, Franco; Marques-Ibanez, David
We evaluate the impact of commonly used indicators of bank distress on broad (i.e. sector and country) risks. This issue deserves special attention in the banking industry where there is a strong degree of inter-connectedness among institutions and the default of a single bank may cause a cascading failure, which could potentially bankrupt the entire system. Using several measures of individual bank risk our results show that these measures have a direct impact on European banking (i.e. systemic) stock market risk. We also provide strong evidence suggesting that, for listed banks, default risk tends to be systematic (i.e. non-diversiflable). (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Fiordelisi, Franco; Marques-Ibanez, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of credit rating announcements on credit default swap spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Finnerty, John D.; Miller, Cameron D.; Chen, Ren-Raw
We document the ability of the credit default swap (CDS) market to anticipate favorable as well as unfavorable credit rating change (RC) announcements based on more extensive samples of credit rating events and CDS spreads than previous studies. We obtain four new results. In contrast to prior published studies, we find that corporate RC upgrades do have a significant impact on CDS spreads even though they are still not as well anticipated as downgrades. Second, CreditWatch (CW) and Outlook (OL) announcements, after controlling for prior credit rating events, lead to significant CARs at the time positive CW and OL credit rating events are announced. Third, we extend prior results by showing that changes in CDS spreads for non-investment-grade credits contain information useful for estimating the probability of negative credit rating events. Fourth, we find that the CDS spread impact of upgrades but not downgrades is magnified during recessions and that upgrades and downgrades also differ as to the impact of simultaneous CW/OL announcements, investment-grade/speculative-grade crossovers, current credit rating, market volatility, and industry effects. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Finnerty, John D.; Miller, Cameron D.; Chen, Ren-Raw</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A robust optimization approach to asset-liability management under time-varying investment opportunities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guelpinar, Nalan; Pachamanova, Dessislava
This paper presents an asset liability management model based on robust optimization techniques. The model explicitly takes into consideration the time-varying aspect of investment opportunities. The emphasis of the proposed approach is on computational tractability and practical appeal. Computational studies with real market data study the performance of robust-optimization-based strategies, and compare it to the performance of the classical stochastic programming approach. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guelpinar, Nalan; Pachamanova, Dessislava</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance, product market competition and cash management in IPO firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jain, Bharat A.; Li, Joanne; Shao, Yingying
This study evaluates the link between CEO governance heterogeneity, power structure of the firm, and product market competition on various facets of post-IPO cash policy. Our results suggest that post-IPO cash holdings as well as marginal value of cash reserves are higher under a founder CEO governance regime relative to non-founder CEOs. Concentrating board power in the hands of founder CEOs however, reduces their ability to maintain higher post-IPO cash reserves. Our results also suggest that product market competition influences both the level and marginal value of cash reserves in the hands of founder CEOs. Further, we find that stronger internal governance reduces the tendency of IPO firms to deploy excess cash reserves to fund internal investments in excess of industry rivals. Finally, our results suggest that excess cash reserves in competitive industry environments lead to superior post-IPO operating performance. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jain, Bharat A.; Li, Joanne; Shao, Yingying</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does it pay to have friends? Social ties and executive appointments in banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Kick, Thomas; Koetter, Michael; Schaeck, Klaus
We exploit a unique sample to analyze how homophily (affinity for similar others) and social ties affect career outcomes in banking. We test if these factors increase the probability that the appointee to an executive board is an outsider without previous employment at the bank compared to being an insider. Homophily based on age and gender increase the chances of the outsider appointments. Similar educational backgrounds, in contrast, reduce the chance that the appointee is an outsider. Greater social ties also increase the probability of an outside appointment. Results from a duration model show that larger age differences shorten tenure significantly, whereas gender similarities barely affect tenure. Differences in educational backgrounds affect tenure differently across the banking sectors. Maintaining more contacts to the executive board reduces tenure. We also find weak evidence that social ties are associated with reduced profitability, consistent with cronyism in banking. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Kick, Thomas; Koetter, Michael; Schaeck, Klaus</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crossing takeover premiums and mix of payment: An empirical test of contractual setting in M&amp;A transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de la Bruslerie, Hubert
The analyses of the tender offer premiums and of the means of payment should not be performed separately. In the empirical literature, these two variables are often considered independently, although they may have an endogenous relationship in a contractual setting. Using a sample of European M&amp;As over the 2000-2010 decade, we show that these two variables are jointly set in a contractual empirical approach. The relationship between the percentage of cash and the offer premium is positive: higher premiums yield payments with more cash. We highlight that the payment choice is not a continuum between full cash and full share payments. Two different regimes of payment in M&amp;A transactions are empirically characterized. We analyze the major determinants of M&amp;A terms when the offer premium and the means of payment are jointly set. The underlying rationale of an asymmetry of information and a risk-sharing calculus is found to be significant in the setting of the agreement. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de la Bruslerie, Hubert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear portfolio selection using approximate parametric Value-at-Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cui, Xueting; Zhu, Shushang; Sun, Xiaoling; Li, Duan
As the skewed return distribution is a prominent feature in nonlinear portfolio selection problems which involve derivative assets with nonlinear payoff structures, Value-at-Risk (VaR) is particularly suitable to serve as a risk measure in nonlinear portfolio selection. Unfortunately, the nonlinear portfolio selection formulation using VaR risk measure is in general a computationally intractable optimization problem. We investigate in this paper nonlinear portfolio selection models using approximate parametric Value-at-Risk. More specifically, we use first-order and second-order approximations of VaR for constructing portfolio selection models, and show that the portfolio selection models based on Delta-only, Delta-Gamma-normal and worst-case Delta-Gamma VaR approximations can be reformulated as second-order cone programs, which are polynomially solvable using interior-point methods. Our simulation and empirical results suggest that the model using Delta-Gamma-normal VaR approximation performs the best in terms of a balance between approximation accuracy and computational efficiency. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cui, Xueting; Zhu, Shushang; Sun, Xiaoling; Li, Duan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and innovation: Evidence from financial services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bos, Jaap W. B.; Kolari, James W.; van Lamoen, Ryan C. R.
This paper presents new evidence on the relationship between competition and innovation by extending previous literature from manufacturing to financial services. We introduce a new measure of overall innovation by estimating and enveloping annual minimum cost frontiers to create a global frontier. The distance to the global frontier constitutes each bank's technology gap, which decreases if the bank manages to innovate. Our innovation measure enables us to derive and estimate the model of Aghion et al. (2005b) at the firm level for the US banking industry. Based on individual bank Call Report data for the period 1984-2004, consistent with theoretical and empirical work by Aghion et al., we find evidence of an inverted-U relationship between competition and innovation that is robust over several different specifications. Further evidence on major structural changes in the US banking industry indicates that banks moved beyond their optimal innovation level and that interstate banking deregulation resulted in lower bank innovation. Policy implications to financial reform and prudential regulation are discussed also. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bos, Jaap W. B.; Kolari, James W.; van Lamoen, Ryan C. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Old captains at the helm: Chairman age and firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Waelchli, Urs; Zeller, Jonas
This paper examines whether the chairmen of the boards (COBs) impose their life cycles on the firms over which they preside. Using a large sample of unlisted firms, we find a robust negative relation between COB age and firm performance. COBs age much like 'ordinary' people. Their cognitive abilities deteriorate, and they experience significant shifts in motivation. Deteriorating cognitive abilities are the main driver of the performance effect that we observe. The results imply that succession planning problems in unlisted firms are real. Mandatory retirement age clauses cannot solve these problems. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Waelchli, Urs; Zeller, Jonas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk measures: The simpler the better?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rodriguez-Moreno, Maria; Ignacio Pena, Juan
This paper estimates and compares two groups of high-frequency market-based systemic risk measures using European and US interbank rates, stock prices and credit derivatives data from 2004 to 2009. Measures belonging to the macro group gauge the overall tension in the financial sector and micro group measures rely on individual institution information to extract joint distress. We rank the measures using three criteria: (i) Granger causality tests, (ii) Gonzalo and Granger metric, and (iii) correlation with an index of systemic events and policy actions. We find that the best systemic measure in the macro group is the first principal component of a portfolio of Credit Default Swap (CDS) spreads whereas the best measure in the micro group is the multivariate densities computed from CDS spreads. These results suggest that the measures based on CDSs outperform measures based on interbank rates or stock market prices. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rodriguez-Moreno, Maria; Ignacio Pena, Juan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who moves first? An intensity-based measure for information flows across stock exchanges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kehrle, Kerstin; Peter, Franziska J.
In this paper we propose an innovative measure for information flows between stock exchanges. We develop an intensity-based information share using Russell's (1999) autoregressive conditional intensity model. Thereby we maintain the irregular nature of financial high frequency data and use durations and timing of price changes to determine the informationally dominant market. From our empirical application to US-listed Canadian stocks we conclude that the home market mostly reflects information first. On the basis of a cross-sectional analysis we find a positive correlation between the intensity-based information share and liquidity. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kehrle, Kerstin; Peter, Franziska J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of debt collection practices on loss given default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Chulwoo; Jang, Youngmin
In this article, we propose an LCD model that is solely based on legal and internal debt collection actions. Our model is supported by empirical tests in which it performs better than a usual firm specific model. This result is noteworthy when we recall that the model has only binary variables that indicate whether an action was taken. Our model can be applied to update the LCD of distressed firms in a timely manner reflecting the actions taken during the debt collection period. It also can be used to assess the effect of a recovery action and to determine whether to apply an action to certain types of debt. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Han, Chulwoo; Jang, Youngmin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual investor perceptions and behavior during the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoffmann, Arvid O. I.; Post, Thomas; Pennings, Joost M. E.
Combining monthly survey data with matching trading records, we examine how individual investor perceptions change and drive trading and risk-taking behavior during the 2008-2009 financial crisis. We find that investor perceptions fluctuate significantly during the crisis, with risk tolerance and risk perceptions being less volatile than return expectations. During the worst months of the crisis, investors' return expectations and risk tolerance decrease, while their risk perceptions increase. Towards the end of the crisis, investor perceptions recover. We document substantial swings in trading and risk-taking behavior that are driven by changes in investor perceptions. Overall, individual investors continue to trade actively and do not de-risk their investment portfolios during the crisis. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hoffmann, Arvid O. I.; Post, Thomas; Pennings, Joost M. E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>R&amp;D sensitivity to asset sale proceeds: New evidence on financing constraints and intangible investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borisova, Ginka; Brown, James R.
We examine the intersection between corporate divestitures of tangible assets and investment in intangible capital (R&amp;D) to provide new tests for the impact financing constraints have on real activity. A positive R&amp;D sensitivity to asset sale proceeds indicates binding financing constraints since cash inflows from tangible asset sales are negatively correlated with productivity shocks and not otherwise connected to intangible investment via non-financial channels. Using a variety of estimation approaches, we document a strong, positive link between cash inflows from fixed asset sales and corporate R&amp;D investment, but only among firms most likely facing binding financing constraints. These results offer robust evidence that financing frictions impact the increasingly important yet understudied intangible corporate investments that drive innovative activity, and they highlight a previously unexplored but potentially valuable use of proceeds from fixed asset divestitures. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Borisova, Ginka; Brown, James R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do star analysts know more firm-specific information? Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Nianhang; Chan, Kam C.; Jiang, Xuanyu; Yi, Zhihong
Using a unique database in China, we extend the literature to further distinguish the information production role of star vs. non-star analysts. We confirm the general conclusion of a positive association between analyst coverage and stock return synchronicity measured by a firm's R-2 in China. The findings from star analysts, however, show that star analyst coverage actually decreases stock return synchronicity. We contend that the firm-specific human capital in star analysts helps the analysts overcome the challenges of information production in an emerging market. The superior firm-specific human capital argument of star analysts is further supported by the negative association of star analysts' firm-specific experiences and stock return synchronicity. Our conclusions are robust to different specifications of star analyst presence and different definitions of analysts' firm-specific experiences. We also find that star analysts exhibit a more accurate earnings forecast than non-star analysts. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xu, Nianhang; Chan, Kam C.; Jiang, Xuanyu; Yi, Zhihong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A look inside AMLF: What traded and who benefited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akay, Ozgur; Griffiths, Mark D.; Kotomin, Vladimir; Winters, Drew B.
The Federal Reserve's AMLF program was designed to provide liquidity to money market funds (MMFs). Between September 2008 and May 2009, the program made $217 billion in non-recourse loans to depository institutions and bank holding companies to purchase asset-backed commercial paper from MMFs. JP Morgan and State Street dominated the program, accounting for over 90% of all loans made. Our analysis suggests that JP Morgan exhibited more self-dealing behavior than State Street. We find that JP Morgan and State Street earned economically and statistically significant cumulative returns of 2.28% and 2.49% (respectively) over the first seven days of the program after controlling for market returns and heteroscedasticity. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akay, Ozgur; Griffiths, Mark D.; Kotomin, Vladimir; Winters, Drew B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the degree of operating efficiency gains from a potential bank merger and acquisition: A DEA bootstrapped approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Halkos, George E.; Tzeremes, Nickolaos G.
We propose a bootstrapped Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA)-based procedure to pre-calculate and pre-evaluate the short-run operating efficiency gains of a potential bank merger or acquisition (M&amp;A). As an illustrative example, we apply our proposed procedure to investigate the degree of operating efficiency gains of 45 possible bank M&amp;As in the Greek banking industry over the period from 2007 to 2011. The results reveal that a year before and a year after the initiation of the Greek fiscal crisis, the majority of the potential bank M&amp;As under examination were unable to generate short-run operating efficiency gains. In addition, our results for 2011 indicate that the majority of bank M&amp;As can lead to short-run operating efficiency gains. Finally, the empirical findings support the view that a merger or acquisition between efficient banks does not ensure an efficient bank M&amp;A. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Halkos, George E.; Tzeremes, Nickolaos G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>