<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF8</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Valuation of insurers' contingent capital with counterparty risk and price endogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lo, Chien-Ling; Lee, Jin-Ping; Yu, Min-Teh
This study develops a structural framework to value insurers' contingent capital with counterparty risk (CR) and overcomes the problem of price endogeneity (PE) in the valuation model. Our results on the focal contingent capital instrument - catastrophe equity put option (CatEPut) - indicate that prices can be significantly overestimated without considering CR and be significantly underestimated without considering PE. This study also examines how CatEPuts affect the buyer's probability of default (PD). Our results show that buying a CatEPut lowers the PD for high-risk insurers, but not necessarily so for low-risk insurers; however, without taking CR and PE into account, one may significantly overestimate the credit enhancement provided by the CatEPuts. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lo, Chien-Ling; Lee, Jin-Ping; Yu, Min-Teh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust portfolio choice with uncertainty about jump and diffusion risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branger, Nicole; Larsen, Linda Sandris
We analyze the portfolio planning problem of an ambiguity averse investor. The stock follows a jump-diffusion process. We find that there are pronounced differences between ambiguity aversion with respect to diffusion risk and jump risk. Ignoring ambiguity with respect to jump risk causes larger losses in an incomplete market, whereas ignoring ambiguity with respect to diffusion risk is more severe in a complete market. For a deterministic jump size we show that the loss from market incompleteness is always increasing in the level of ambiguity aversion with respect to one risk factor and decreasing in the level of ambiguity aversion with respect to the other risk factor. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Branger, Nicole; Larsen, Linda Sandris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did capital infusions enhance bank recovery from the great recession?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Wei; Kolari, James W.; Tippens, T. Kyle; Fraser, Donald R.
This paper investigates the long-run recovery experience of US banks that received capital infusions under the Capital Purchase Program (CPP), a part of the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP). Based on a dynamic recovery model, our results show that recovering CPP banks tended to be in better financial condition than other CPP banks. Long-run event study analyses of common stock prices reveal that, in the quarter after repayment of TARP funds, CPP banks experienced economically large and significant buy-and-hold wealth gains of 14%, equivalent to approximately $329 billion. We conclude that TARP was successful in fostering bank financial and stock price recovery. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Liu, Wei; Kolari, James W.; Tippens, T. Kyle; Fraser, Donald R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate leverage and the collateral channel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Norden, Lars; van Kampen, Stefan
We investigate whether and how corporate leverage depends on the structure of corporate assets. Based on a large panel dataset of US firms from 1990 to 2010, we show that property, plant and equipment are important drivers of the collateral channel, while inventories and receivables are less important. The collateral channel is more pronounced for firms that have to rely on banks and trade creditors to raise debt finance, but it has become weaker for these firms after the start of the financial crisis. Our study provides new evidence on the cross-sectional and time-varying importance of the collateral channel for corporate leverage. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Norden, Lars; van Kampen, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic valuation of liquidity timing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karstanje, Dennis; Sojli, Elvira; Tham, Wing Wah; van der Wel, Michel
This paper conducts a horse-race of different liquidity proxies using dynamic asset allocation strategies to evaluate the short-horizon predictive ability of liquidity on monthly stock returns. We assess the economic value of the out-of-sample power of empirical models based on different liquidity measures and find three key results: liquidity timing leads to tangible economic gains; a risk-averse investor will pay a high performance fee to switch from a dynamic portfolio strategy based on various liquidity measures to one that conditions on the Zeros measure (Lesmond et al., 1999); the Zeros measure outperforms other liquidity measures because of its robustness in extreme market conditions. These findings are stable over time and robust to controlling for existing market return predictors or considering risk-adjusted returns. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Karstanje, Dennis; Sojli, Elvira; Tham, Wing Wah; van der Wel, Michel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limiting losses may be injurious to your wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grauer, Robert R.
Theory tells us that if return distributions are independent overtime, an expected utility maximizing logarithmic-utility investor will almost surely accumulate the most long-run wealth. This paper examines the robustness of the result. Specifically, it examines the expected and unexpected long-run and short-run consequences of imposing Value at Risk and other loss constraints on power-utility investors with a numerical example and empirically in an asset-allocation setting covering the 1934-2008 period. In addition, it examines the expected and unexpected long-run consequences of imposing Conditional Value at Risk constraints on power-utility and prospect-theory (kinked linear-utility) investors. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grauer, Robert R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who gets credit after bankruptcy and why? An information channel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen-Cole, Ethan; Duygan-Bump, Burcu; Montoriol-Garriga, Judit
Conventional wisdom holds that individuals find it difficult to obtain new credit post-bankruptcy. Using credit bureau data, we test this hypothesis and show that more than 90% of bankrupt individuals receive credit shortly after filing. Individuals with good credit history prior to filing have reduced credit availability after bankruptcy while those with ex-ante low credit quality receive more credit. We show that credit supplied to low quality individuals is severely curtailed during the financial crisis. We also find that the default probability on new debt increases after bankruptcy, especially among individuals with high ex-ante credit score. These findings are consistent with an information channel, in which bankruptcy reveals new information about a borrower's credit quality. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cohen-Cole, Ethan; Duygan-Bump, Burcu; Montoriol-Garriga, Judit</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of diverse measures of default risk on UK stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Jie; Hill, Paula
A number of recent papers examine the relationship between default risk and equity returns, and the results are mixed. These studies employ different measures of default risk and we find that correlations between eight diverse measures of default risk tend to be less than 50%. Nonetheless, we find that the relationship between stock returns and diverse measures of default risk tends to be consistent; default risk is a significant determinant of stock returns and this relationship is "hump backed", as predicted by Garlappi and Yan (2011). (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved,</description><author>Chen, Jie; Hill, Paula</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the predictability of stock prices: A case for high and low prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caporin, Massimiliano; Ranaldo, Angelo; de Magistris, Paolo Santucci
This paper contributes to technical analysis (TA) literature by showing that the high and low prices of equity shares are largely predictable only on the basis of their past realizations. Moreover, using their forecasts as entry/exit signals can improve common TA trading strategies applied on US equity prices. We propose modeling high and low prices using a simple implementation of a fractional vector autoregressive model with error correction (FVECM). This model captures two fundamental patterns of high and low prices: their cointegrating relationship and the long-memory of their difference (i.e., the range), which is a measure of volatility. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Caporin, Massimiliano; Ranaldo, Angelo; de Magistris, Paolo Santucci</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wall Street's bailout bet: Market reactions to house price releases in the presence of bailout expectations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loeffler, Gunter; Posch, Peter N.
The rise and subsequent collapse of US house prices was one of the factors underlying the recent financial crisis. One could expect that the crisis brought increased attention to the housing market and thus led to stronger market reactions to house price news. We find that reactions indeed change, but with a peculiar twist: from September 2008 on, good news from the housing market are associated with falling US stock prices, and vice versa. The likely explanation, for which we provide cross-sectional evidence, is that falling house prices increased the market's trust in a government bailout, thereby increasing market valuations of firms that were expected to benefit from government rescue measures. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loeffler, Gunter; Posch, Peter N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rethinking banking and finance: Money, markets and models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duygun, Meryem; Shaban, Mohamed; Soriano, Pilar; Tortosa-Ausina, Emili
nan</description><author>Duygun, Meryem; Shaban, Mohamed; Soriano, Pilar; Tortosa-Ausina, Emili</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intertemporal efficiency analysis of sales teams of a bank: Stochastic semi-nonparametric approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eskelinen, Juha; Kuosmanen, Timo
The primary role of a bank branch is evolving from a service provider towards a sales channel. Previous branch-level studies of sales efficiency consider a static setting of a single time period, ignoring the stochastic nature of sales outcomes. In this paper, we examine efficiency and performance of sales teams in a bank branch network over time, taking into account the changing demand and operational conditions, as well as random disturbances. The intertemporal sales frontier is estimated from the panel of monthly data over the years 2007-2010 using the stochastic semi-nonparametric envelopment of data (StoNED) method. The efficiency scores of sales teams and the trajectories of performance over time allow managers and the sales force to learn from past events and to develop the managerial and work practices across the network. While this study focuses on the case of a specific bank, some of the innovative features of our approach are applicable to sales efficiency assessment in other banks and financial institutions, as well as other network-based sales organizations. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eskelinen, Juha; Kuosmanen, Timo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Schumpeterian competition and efficiency among commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duygun, Meryem; Sena, Vania; Shahan, Mohamed
In this paper, we aim to fill the gap in the banking literature by quantifying the impact that the Schumpeterian competition mode - i.e. competition through the launch of new products (or new varieties of products) - has on the cost and profit efficiency of a sample of commercial banks based in the United Kingdom. We estimate both a cost and an alternative profit frontier on an unbalanced panel of UK commercial banks over the period 2001-2012. The intensity of competition through product innovation is proxied by the trademark intensity (i.e. the ratio between the number of trademarks registered in a given year by all the commercial banks - net of the trademarks registered by the bank under observation - and the employment in the sector) in the commercial banking sector. Our results show that the (lagged) trademark intensity in the commercial banking sector does affect negatively the mean cost and profit efficiency in the sector but there is evidence that as trademark intensity increases in the sector, commercial banks react by improving their cost and profit efficiency. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duygun, Meryem; Sena, Vania; Shahan, Mohamed</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO underwriting and subsequent lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hsuan-Chi; Ho, Keng-Yu; Weng, Pei-Shih
This study investigates the relation between IPO underwriting and subsequent lending. We find that when a bank underwrites a firm's IPO, the bank is more likely to provide the issuer with future loans at a lower cost, compared to banks without an IPO underwriting relationship. The evidence also suggests that the underwriting banks share information surplus with the IPO firms in the post-IPO loans, supporting the cost-saving hypothesis. Overall, the evidence for the relation between prior IPO underwriting and subsequent lending supports the notion that firms can derive value from investment bank relationships. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Hsuan-Chi; Ho, Keng-Yu; Weng, Pei-Shih</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does deregulation induce competition in the market for corporate control? The special case of banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghosh, Chinmoy; Petrova, Milena
Using a sample of 936 acquisitions of commercial banks, we examine the relation between the probability to engage in value-reducing acquisitions and corporate governance structures, as well as the relation between acquirer announcement-period abnormal stock returns and antitakeover indices and measures, and how these relations were affected by the change in the market for corporate control, caused by deregulation due to the implementation of the Interstate Banking and Branching Efficiency Act of 1994 and the Financial Service Modernization Act of 1999. We find that prior to deregulation there is no relation between probability to engage in value destroying acquisitions or acquirer returns and antitakeover indices, whereas after the adoption of the FSMA, probability to engage in value destroying acquisitions and the stock market reaction to bidder M&amp;A announcements are both significantly related to governance indexes and measures. Our findings further confirm the linkage between the market for corporate control, antitakeover indices and firm value. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ghosh, Chinmoy; Petrova, Milena</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ratings based capital adequacy for securitizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luetzenkirchen, Kristina; Roesch, Daniel; Scheule, Harald
This paper develops a framework to measure the exposure to systematic risk for pools of asset securitizations and measures empirically whether current ratings-based rules for regulatory capital of securitizations under Basel II and Basel III reflect this exposure. The analysis is based on a comprehensive US dataset on asset securitizations for the time period between 2000 and 2008. We find that the shortfall of regulatory capital during the Global Financial Crisis is strongly related to ratings. In particular, we empirically show that insufficient capital is allocated to tranches with the highest rating. These tranches account for the greatest part of the total issuance volumes. Furthermore, this paper is the first to calibrate risk weights which account for systematic risk and provide sufficient capital buffers to cover the exposure during similar economic downturns. These policy-relevant findings suggest a re-calibration of RBA risk weights and may contribute to the current efforts by the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision and others to re-establish sustainable securitization markets and to improve the stability of the financial system. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Luetzenkirchen, Kristina; Roesch, Daniel; Scheule, Harald</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market capitalization and Value-at-Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dias, Alexandra
The potential of economic variables for financial risk measurement is an open field for research. This article studies the role of market capitalization in the estimation of Value-at-Risk (VaR). We test the performance of different VaR methodologies for portfolios with different market capitalization. We perform the analysis considering separately financial crisis periods and non-crisis periods. We find that VaR methods perform differently for portfolios with different market capitalization. For portfolios with stocks of different sizes we obtain better VaR estimates when taking market capitalization into account. We also find that it is important to consider crisis and non-crisis periods separately when estimating VaR across different sizes. This study provides evidence that market fundamentals are relevant for risk measurement. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dias, Alexandra</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidation equilibrium with seniority and hidden CDO</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gourieroux, C.; Heam, J. C.; Monfort, A.
The aim of our paper is to price credit derivatives written on a single name when this name is a bank. Indeed, due to the special structure of the balance sheet of a bank and to the interconnections with other institutions of the financial system, the standard pricing formulas do not apply and their use can imply severe mispricing. The pricing of credit derivatives written on a single bank name requires a joint analysis of the risks of all banks directly or indirectly interconnected with the bank of interest. Each name cannot be priced in isolation, but the banking system must be treated as a whole. It is necessary to analyze the contagion of losses among banks, especially the equilibrium of joint defaults and recovery rates at liquidation time. We show the existence and uniqueness of such an equilibrium. Then the standard pricing formulas are modified by adding a premium to capture the contagion effects. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gourieroux, C.; Heam, J. C.; Monfort, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unintended consequences of the increased asset threshold for FDICIA internal controls: Evidence from U.S. private banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Justin Yiqiang; Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lobo, Gerald J.
We examine the unintended consequences of the 2005 increase from $500 million to $1 billion in the asset threshold for the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act (FDICIA) internal control reporting requirements. We focus on a test sample of banks that increased their total assets from between $100 million and $500 million prior to the change in regulation to between $500 million and $1 billion within two years following the change. These "affected" banks are no longer subject to the internal control requirements but would have been had the regulation not been changed. We hypothesize that these affected banks are likely to make riskier loans, which will increase the likelihood of failure during the crisis period. We find evidence consistent with this hypothesis. Affected banks have higher likelihood of failure during the crisis period than banks from two different control samples. We also find that auditor reputation (i.e., whether the bank is audited by a Big 4 auditor or an industry specialist auditor) has a moderating effect on the likelihood of failure for these affected banks. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jin, Justin Yiqiang; Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lobo, Gerald J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank ownership and lending patterns during the 2008-2009 financial crisis: Evidence from Latin America and Eastern Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cull, Robert; Peria, Maria Soledad Martinez
This paper examines the impact of bank ownership on credit growth in developing countries before and during the 2008-2009 crisis. Using bank-level data for countries in Eastern Europe and Latin America, we analyze the growth of banks' total gross loans as well as the growth of corporate, consumer, and residential mortgage loans. While domestic private banks in Eastern Europe and Latin America contracted their loan growth rates during the crisis, there are notable differences in foreign and government-owned bank credit growth across regions. In Eastern Europe, foreign bank total lending fell by more than domestic private bank credit. These results are primarily driven by reductions in corporate loans. Furthermore, government-owned banks in Eastern Europe did not act counter-cyclically. The opposite is true in Latin America, where the growth of government-owned banks' corporate and consumer loans during the crisis exceeded that of domestic and foreign banks. Contrary to the case of foreign banks in Eastern Europe, those in Latin America did not fuel loan growth prior to the crisis. Also, there are less pronounced and robust differences in the behavior of foreign and domestic banks during the crisis in Latin America. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cull, Robert; Peria, Maria Soledad Martinez</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do companies delist voluntarily from the stock market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pour, Eilnaz Kashefi; Lasfer, Meziane
We analyse the motives and market valuation of voluntarily delisting from the London Stock Exchange. We show that firms that delist voluntarily are likely to have come to the market to rebalance their leverage rather than to finance their growth opportunities. During their quotation life, their leverage and insider ownership remained very high, they did not raise equity capital, and their profitability, growth opportunities, and trading volume declined substantially. They also generate negative pre-event and announcement date excess returns. These results hold even after controlling for agency, asymmetric information, and liquidity effects, and suggest that firms delist voluntarily when they fail to benefit from listing. Overall, these firms destroyed shareholder value and they should not have come to the market. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pour, Eilnaz Kashefi; Lasfer, Meziane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset sales in the mutual fund industry: Who gains?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Fan; Sanger, Gary C.; Slovin, Myron B.
We analyze gains from intercorporate sales of mutual fund subsidiaries, using mandated SEC disclosures to assess the performance of mutual funds transferred by these transactions. Sellers are financial conglomerates (banks) using equity-based deals to transfer poorly performing funds to highly focused asset management companies. The transferred funds experience significant improvements in risk-adjusted returns, efficiency, and asset growth. These improvements are closely correlated with the gains in wealth to buyers and sellers at deal announcements, indicating the market efficiently capitalizes expected performance improvements. Our results provide evidence that these transactions transfer assets to acquirers better able to manage them, generating gains for fund holders and buyer and seller shareholders. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Fan; Sanger, Gary C.; Slovin, Myron B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculations in option markets enhance allocation efficiency with heterogeneous beliefs and learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qin, Zhenjiang
Many studies investigate the impact of heterogeneous beliefs in the first moment, while very few in the second moment. This is partially due to continuous-time setup which makes it difficult to incorporate heterogeneous beliefs in the second moment. In a two-period exponential-normal model with Bayesian learning, I demonstrate that heterogeneous prior variances give rise to the economic value of option markets. Investors speculate in option market and public information improves allocation efficiency of markets only when there is heterogeneity in prior variances. Heterogeneity in mean is neither a necessary nor a sufficient condition for generating speculations in option markets. With heterogeneous beliefs, options are non-redundant assets which can facilitate side-betting and enable investors to take advantage of the disagreements and the differences in confidence. This fact leads to a higher growth rate in the investors' certainty equivalents and, thus, a higher equilibrium interest rate. Furthermore, option exhibits a unique feature of enabling signal precision to affect the ex ante risk premium of underlying asset, which quadratic derivative and stock do not have. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Qin, Zhenjiang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture capital and new business creation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Popov, Alexander; Roosenboom, Peter
Using a comprehensive database of firms from 21 European countries over the period 1998-2008, we find that venture capital investment has a positive effect on the rate of new business creation. This is especially true in countries with higher entry costs, higher protection of intellectual property rights, and lower taxes on capital gains. Our results suggest that, controlling for country and industry characteristics, venture capital is beneficial to bringing new ideas to the marketplace in the shape of new companies. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Popov, Alexander; Roosenboom, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-term bank balance sheet management: Estimation and simulation of risk-factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Birge, John R.; Judice, Pedro
We propose a dynamic framework which encompasses the main risks in balance sheets of banks in an integrated fashion. Our contributions are fourfold: (1) solving a simple one-period model that describes the optimal bank policy under credit risk; (2) estimating the long-term stochastic processes underlying the risk factors in the balance sheet, taking into account the credit and interest rate cycles; (3) simulating several scenarios for interest rates and charge-offs; and (4) describing the equations that govern the evolution of the balance sheet in the long run. The models that we use address momentum and the interaction between different rates. Our results enable simulation of bank balance sheets over time given a bank's lending strategy and provides a basis for an optimization model to determine bank asset-liability management strategy endogenously. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Birge, John R.; Judice, Pedro</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product market competition and the cost of bank loans: Evidence from state antitakeover laws</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Waisman, Maya
The extant literature documents a positive relationship between a firm's takeover vulnerability and its agency cost of debt. Using state antitakeover laws as an exogenous measure of variation in takeover vulnerability, I investigate whether product market competition has a disciplinary effect that can lower a firm's cost of bank loans. After taking into account the industry composition of borrowers, I find that banks charge higher spreads to borrowers that are vulnerable to takeovers, but only in concentrated industries. In the absence of disciplinary competitive pressure, the effect of takeover vulnerability on the cost of bank loans is mitigated for larger firms, firms followed by analysts, firms with existing credit ratings, non-family firms, and for borrowers with shorter maturity loans or loans with covenants and collateral in place. Taken together, the results suggest that the effect of governance on the cost of financing is not homogenous across all industries, and that concentrated industry firms may need to use supplementary governance mechanisms to mitigate debt holder agency problems. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Waisman, Maya</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Moment-based estimation of stochastic volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bregantini, Daniele
This paper makes use of the distributional information contained in high-frequency data to test for the specification of the functional form of the volatility process within the class of stochastic volatility models. Ito's calculus is implemented in order to obtain the first and second conditional moment of the driving stochastic differential equation for the volatility process. These analytical expressions are augmented by their lag and lag squared and are used to form the corresponding GMM estimator. The base case stochastic volatility model is extended to allow for the leverage effect and jumps in returns. Empirical estimation confirms the presence of fast mean reversion in volatility and jumps in returns for the 5-min S&amp;P 500 stock market index. Further estimation results also seem to indicate the presence of jumps in the volatility process that are correlated to the jumps in returns. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bregantini, Daniele</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are stock market crises contagious? The role of crisis definitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mierau, Jochen O.; Mink, Mark
Financial contagion studies generally examine whether co-movement between markets increases during a crisis. We use a flexible co-movement measure to examine how conclusions of such analyses depend on the sample chosen as the 'crisis'. To this end, we analyse stock market co-movement during the 1997 Asian crisis and the 2007 global financial crisis for all possible source countries and for all possible time periods or extreme return quantiles. This way we account for the main crisis dating approaches adopted in the literature. Our results suggest there is no clear relationship between excess co-movement and commonly used crisis samples. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mierau, Jochen O.; Mink, Mark</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>TARP funds distribution and bank loan supply</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Lei
This paper investigates the determinants of the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) funds distribution to banks and the stimulus effect of TARP investments on credit supply in the economy. Using banks' political and regulatory connections as instruments, this paper finds that TARP investments increased bank loan supply by an annualized rate of 6.36% for banks with below median Tier 1 capital ratios. This increase is found in all major types of loans and can be translated into $404 billion of additional loans for all TARP banks. On average, TARP banks employed about one-third of their TARP capital to support new loans and kept the rest to strengthen their balance sheets. Furthermore, there is little evidence that loans made by TARP banks had lower quality than those by non-TARP banks. In sum, this paper shows a positive stimulus effect of TARP on credit supply during the 2008-2009 financial crisis. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Lei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank/sovereign risk spillovers in the European debt crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Bruyckere, Valerie; Gerhardt, Maria; Schepens, Glenn; Vander Vennet, Rudi
This paper investigates contagion between bank and sovereign default risk in Europe over the period 2007-2012. We define contagion as excess correlation, i.e. correlation between banks and sovereigns over and above what is explained by common factors, using CDS spreads at the bank and at the sovereign level. Moreover, we investigate the determinants of contagion by analyzing bank-specific as well as country-specific variables and their interaction. Using the EBA's disclosure of sovereign exposures of banks, we provide empirical evidence that three contagion channels are at work: a guarantee channel, an asset holdings channel and a collateral channel. We find that banks with a weak capital buffer, a weak funding structure and less traditional banking activities are particularly vulnerable to risk spillovers. At the country level, the debt ratio is the most important driver of contagion. Furthermore, the impact of government interventions on contagion depends on the type of intervention, with outright capital injections being the most effective measure in reducing spillover intensity. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Bruyckere, Valerie; Gerhardt, Maria; Schepens, Glenn; Vander Vennet, Rudi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The intraday impact of company responses to exchange queries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drienko, Jozef; Sault, Stephen J.
This study investigates Australia's unique continuous disclosure regime using intraday data on the Australian Securities Exchange (ASX) over the period January 2010-April 2012. We examine abnormal returns and trading volumes that accrue to shareholders immediately after an announcement responding to a trading induced query. The use of intraday data permits us to examine the direct impact of these events, and the length of time the market takes to incorporate this information with a higher degree of precision than the research currently on offer. The study is framed within an event study methodology, with a number of robustness measures: a matched sample approach; analysis of cross-sectional determinants; the removal of penny stocks; and, procedures to account for sample selection bias. We find significant share price reversals following a query announcement, with a reversal of 33% by the end of the widest event interval. Our study also provides evidence that the market takes up to 60 min to impound this information. Overall, we provide support for the efficacy of the query framework administered by the ASX. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Drienko, Jozef; Sault, Stephen J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do sovereign credit rating changes affect private investment?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chen, Hsien-Yi; Chang, Chong-Chuo; Yang, Shu-Ling
Sovereign credit rating changes have an influence on real private investment of re-rated countries. We find significant increases in private investment growth following upgrades in sovereign ratings. These increases, however, are transitory. We also find significant, temporary declines in private investment growth following sovereign rating downgrades. The results hold after accounting for re-rated countries' growth opportunities, endogeneity, and other factors that could affect private investment. The irreversible nature of investment may be the explanation for the temporary changes in the growth rates of physical capital investment associated with revisions in sovereign credit ratings. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chen, Hsien-Yi; Chang, Chong-Chuo; Yang, Shu-Ling</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing determinants of bond yield spreads with Bayesian Model Averaging</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maltritz, Dominik; Molchanov, Alexander
This paper analyzes determinants of country default risk in emerging markets, reflected by sovereign yield spreads. The results reported so far in the literature are heterogeneous with respect to significant explanatory variables. This could indicate a high degree of uncertainty about the "true" regression model. We use Bayesian Model Averaging as the model selection method in order to find the variables which are most likely to determine credit risk. We document that total debt, history of recent default, currency depreciation, and growth rate of foreign currency reserves as well as market sentiments are the key drivers of yield spreads. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maltritz, Dominik; Molchanov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing deviation, misvaluation comovement, and macroeconomic conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Eric C.; Luo, Yan; Ren, Jinjuan
We measure an individual stock's misvaluation based on the deviation of its price from predicted intrinsic value. Both under- and overvalued stocks identified by this misvaluation measure exhibit greater valuation uncertainty and arbitrage difficulty, and the misvaluation measure strongly predicts stock returns incremental to size, book-to-market ratio, past returns, and various return anomalies. Based on the misvaluation measure, we form a misvaluation factor and find that stock return covariances with this factor possess significant and robust return predictive power. We further show that the misvaluation factor predicts future economic conditions, providing additional insight into the real effect of systematic misvaluation in the stock market. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chang, Eric C.; Luo, Yan; Ren, Jinjuan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Federal Reserve's balance sheet and overnight interest rates: Empirical modeling of exit strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marquez, Jaime; Morse, Ari; Schlusche, Bernd
This paper provides a comprehensive study of the interplay between the Federal Reserve's balance sheet and overnight interest rates. We model both the supply of and the demand for excess reserves. Treating outright securities holdings of the Federal Reserve as a policy tool, we estimate the effects of unconventional monetary policy on overnight funding rates. Further, we offer the first empirical assessment of the FOMC's principles of the exit strategy. Assuming a path for removing monetary policy accommodation that is consistent with the FOMC's exit principles, we project that the federal funds rate increases to 70 basis points by 2016, settling in a corridor bracketed by the discount rate and the interest rate on excess reserves, as excess reserves of depository institutions decline to near zero. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Marquez, Jaime; Morse, Ari; Schlusche, Bernd</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A spatial analysis of international stock market linkages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asgharian, Hossein; Hess, Wolfgang; Liu, Lu
We employ spatial econometrics techniques to investigate to what extent countries' economic and geographical relations affect their stock market co-movements. Among the relations that we analyze, bilateral trade proves to be best suited to capture co-variations in returns. We find a strong effect of a unit shock to three regionally dominant countries, namely the US, the UK, and Japan, on other countries through the trade linkage. The degree of stock market dependence increases and the importance of proximity decreases over time and during recessions. We also analyze several regional crises and find a large impact of Thailand on its trade neighbors during the Asian crisis. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asgharian, Hossein; Hess, Wolfgang; Liu, Lu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A stochastic frontier approach to modelling financial constraints in firms: An application to India (vol 36, pg 1311, 2012)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhaumik, Sumon Kumar; Das, Pranab Kumar; Kumbhakar, Subal C.
nan</description><author>Bhaumik, Sumon Kumar; Das, Pranab Kumar; Kumbhakar, Subal C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear dynamics in discretionary accruals: An analysis of bank loan-loss provisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balboa, Marina; Lopez-Espinosa, German; Rubia, Antonio
Several studies have analyzed discretionary accruals to address earnings-smoothing behaviors in the banking industry. We argue that the characteristic link between accruals and earnings may be nonlinear, since both the incentives to manipulate income and the practical way to do so depend partially on the relative size of earnings. Given a sample of 15,268 US banks over the period 1996-2011, the main results in this paper suggest that, depending on the size of earnings, bank managers tend to engage in earnings-decreasing strategies when earnings are negative ("big-bath"), use earnings-increasing strategies when earnings are positive, and use provisions as a smoothing device when earnings are positive and substantial ("cookie-jar" accounting). This evidence, which cannot be explained by the earnings-smoothing hypothesis, is consistent with the compensation theory. Neglecting nonlinear patterns in the econometric modeling of these accruals may lead to misleading conclusions regarding the characteristic strategies used in earnings management. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balboa, Marina; Lopez-Espinosa, German; Rubia, Antonio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global imbalances and the intertemporal external budget constraint: A multicointegration approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Camarero, Mariam; Lluis Carrion-i-Silvestre, Josep; Tamarit, Cecilio
This paper analyzes the external solvency of a group of 23 OECD countries for the period 1970-2012. The empirical strategy adopted underlines the increasing importance of the financial channel for the external adjustment as proposed in Gourinchas and Rey (2007). We unify the traditional approaches to testing for external sustainability considering the stock-flow system created by the variables representing the external relationships of an open economy. External sustainability is tested using several types of cointegration and multicointegration tests. The results obtained point to weak sustainability in the flows analysis, whereas some degree of strong sustainability is found for up to six countries in the stock-flow approach. Among these countries we find both non-European economies, such as Japan and New Zealand, and Euro-area members, especially those with more restricted access to financing in the international markets. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Camarero, Mariam; Lluis Carrion-i-Silvestre, Josep; Tamarit, Cecilio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supervisors as information producers: Do stress tests reduce bank opaqueness?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Petrella, Giovanni; Resti, Andrea
Supervisory stress tests assess the impact of an adverse macroeconomic scenario on the profitability and capitalisation of a large number of banks. The results of such stress test exercises have recently been disclosed to the public in an attempt to restore confidence and to curb bank opaqueness by helping investors distinguish between sound and fragile institutions. In an unprecedented effort for transparency, the 2011 European Union stress test lead to the release of some 3400 data points for each of the 90 participating banks. This makes it an ideal setting to investigate a number of hypotheses on the information role of the stress tests. In this paper we examine the 2011 European stress test exercise to assess whether and how it affected bank stock prices. Our event study analysis shows that the test's results were considered relevant by investors. The market did not simply look at the detailed historical data which was released after the tests, but also attached considerable importance to variables measuring each bank's vulnerability to the simulated downturn scenario. The latter include proxies for liquidity risk and model risk. Information on sovereign debt holdings, while affecting market reaction on a univariate basis, is not statistically significant in a multivariate setting. We also find that the market is not able to anticipate the test results and this is consistent with the idea of greater bank opaqueness prior to the disclosure of the stress test results. Overall, our analysis shows that stress tests produce valuable information for market participants and can play a role in mitigating bank opacity. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Petrella, Giovanni; Resti, Andrea</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, signaling and non-walking through the book: Effects on order choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Valenzuela, Marcela; Zer, Ilknur
We investigate the effects of competition and signaling in a pure order driven market and examine the trading patterns of agents when walking through the book is not allowed. Our results suggest that the variables capturing the cost of a large market order are not informative for an impatient trader under this market mechanism. We also document that the competition effect is not present only at the top of the book but persistent beyond the best quotes. Moreover, it dominates the signaling effect for both a limit order and a market order trader. Finally, we show that institutional investors' order submission strategies are characterized by only a few pieces of the limit order book information. This is consistent with informed traders placing orders based on their own private valuations rather than the state of the book. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Valenzuela, Marcela; Zer, Ilknur</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>SME financing and the choice of lending technology in Italy: Complementarity or substitutability?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartoli, Francesca; Ferri, Giovanni; Murro, Pierluigi; Rotondi, Zeno
This paper investigates SME financing in Italy. The literature distinguishes between two main different lending technologies (LTs) for SMEs: transactional and relationship LTs. We find that banks lend to SMEs by using both LTs together, independently of the size and proximity of borrowers. Moreover, we show that the use of soft information decreases the probability of firms being credit rationed. Finally, we find that more soft information is produced when the bank uses relationship LT as primary technology individually or coupled with transactional LT. Our results support the view that LTs can be complementary, but reject the hypothesis that substitutability among LTs is somehow possible for outsiders by means of hardening of soft information. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bartoli, Francesca; Ferri, Giovanni; Murro, Pierluigi; Rotondi, Zeno</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing systemic risks and predicting systemic events</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lo Duca, Marco; Peltonen, Tuomas A.
The paper develops a framework for assessing systemic risks and for predicting systemic events, i.e. periods of extreme financial instability with potential real costs. It contributes to the literature on the prediction of financial crises mainly in two ways: first, it uses a Financial Stress Index for identifying the starting date of systemic financial crises. Second, it uses discrete choice models that combine both domestic and global indicators of macro-financial vulnerabilities to predict systemic financial crises. The performance of the models is evaluated in a framework that takes into account policy maker's preferences between missing crises and issuing false alarms. Our analysis shows that combining indicators of domestic and global macro-financial vulnerabilities substantially improves the models' ability to forecast systemic financial crises. Our framework also displays a good out-of-sample performance in predicting the ongoing Global Financial Crisis, (C) 2012 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lo Duca, Marco; Peltonen, Tuomas A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of Eonia swap rates before and during the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hernandis, Lucia; Torro, Hipolit
Before August 2007, implied forward rates in the overnight interest swap rates closely reflected market expectations about the future path of the Eonia, and therefore, about the future course of the ECB's monetary policy stance. Nevertheless, this link was weakened considerably during the most acute episode of the financial crisis. Using the expectations hypothesis of the term structure as a benchmark model for the determination of the overnight interest swap rates, we find that after May 2010 the monetary transmission mechanism was partially restored when the ECB implemented various 'unconventional measures' in response to the financial crisis. On the contrary, liquidity and credit risks are still present in unsecured deposit markets, distorting the pricing and transmission of the ECB monetary policy stance along the Euribor rates. These results should be of interest for regulators, financial institutions, and researchers in European money markets. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hernandis, Lucia; Torro, Hipolit</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional Value-at-Risk, spectral risk measures and (non-)diversification in portfolio selection problems - A comparison with mean-variance analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandtner, Mario
We study portfolio selection under Conditional Value-at-Risk and, as its natural extension, spectral risk measures, and compare it with traditional mean-variance analysis. Unlike the previous literature that considers an investor's mean-spectral risk preferences for the choice of optimal portfolios only implicitly, we explicitly model these preferences in the form of a so-called spectral utility function. Within this more general framework, spectral risk measures tend towards corner solutions. If a risk free asset exists, diversification is never optimal. Similarly, without a risk free asset, only limited diversification is obtained. The reason is that spectral risk measures are based on a regulatory concept of diversification that differs fundamentally from the reward-risk tradeoff underlying the mean-variance framework. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brandtner, Mario</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-country effects of regulatory capital arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milcheva, Stanimira
One reason for the recent asset price bubbles in many developed countries could be regulatory capital arbitrage. Regulatory and legal changes can help traditional banks to move their assets off their balance sheets into the lightly regulated shadows and thus enable regulatory arbitrage through the securitized sector. This paper adopts a global vector autoregression (GVAR) methodology to assess the effects of regulatory capital arbitrage on equity prices, house prices and economic activity across 11 OECD countries/regions. A counterfactual experiment disentangles the effects of regulatory arbitrage following a change in the net capital rule for investment banks in April 2004 and the adoption of the Basel II Accord in June 2004. The results provide evidence for the existence of an international finance multiplier, with about half of the countries overshooting U.S. impulse responses. The counterfactual shows that regulatory arbitrage via the U.S. securitized sector may enhance the cross-country reallocation of capital from housing markets towards equity markets. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Milcheva, Stanimira</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodity and equity markets: Some stylized facts from a copula approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delatte, Anne-Laure; Lopez, Claude
In this paper, we propose to identify the dependence structure that exists between returns on equity and commodity futures and its development over the past 20 years. The key point is that we do not impose any dependence structure, but let the data select it. To do so, we model the dependence between commodity (metal, agriculture and energy) and stock markets using a flexible approach that allows us to investigate whether the co-movement is: (i) symmetrical and frequent, (ii) (a) symmetrical and mostly present during extreme events and (iii) asymmetrical and mostly present during extreme events. We also allow for this dependence to be time-varying from January 1990 to February 2012. Our analysis uncovers three major stylised facts. First, we find that the dependence between commodity and stock markets is time-varying, symmetrical and occurs most of the time (as opposed to mostly during extreme events). Second, not allowing for time-varying parameters in the dependence distribution generates a bias towards an evidence of tail dependence. Similarly, considering only tail dependence may lead to false evidence of asymmetry. Third, a growing co-movement between industrial metals and equity markets is identified as early as 2003; this co-movement spreads to all commodity classes and becomes unambiguously stronger with the global financial crisis after Fall 2008. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Delatte, Anne-Laure; Lopez, Claude</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional quality thresholds and the finance - Growth nexus</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Law, Siong Hook; Azman-Saini, W. N. W.; Ibrahim, Mansor H.
Using an innovative threshold estimation technique, this study examines whether the growth effect of financial development in countries with distinct levels of institutional development differs. The results demonstrate that there is a threshold effect in the finance-growth relationship. Specifically, we found that the impact of finance on growth is positive and significant only after a certain threshold level of institutional development has been attained. Until then, the effect of finance on growth is nonexistent. This finding suggests that the financial development-growth nexus is contingent on the level of institutional quality, thus supporting the idea that better finance (i.e., financial markets embedded within a sound institutional framework) is potent in delivering long-run economic development (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Law, Siong Hook; Azman-Saini, W. N. W.; Ibrahim, Mansor H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do newspaper articles on card fraud affect debit card usage?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kosse, Anneke
This paper investigates the impact of newspaper articles about skimming fraud on debit card usage in the Netherlands using daily transaction data and daily newspaper announcements from January 1st 2005 to December 31st 2008. Key finding is that articles about skimming fraud significantly affect same day debit card usage. The direction and strength of the media effects strongly depend on the specific characteristics of the publications, such as type of fraud addressed and their position in the newspaper, but above all on the frequency with which they come out. The effects, however, are economically small compared to other factors, such as calendar and holiday effects, and do not sustain or accumulate in the long run. Yet, some first cost calculations demonstrate that the impact of media attention on total retail payments efficiency is not to be underestimated. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kosse, Anneke</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent developments in financial markets and banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andriosopoulos, Kostas; Pasiouras, Fotis; Zopounidis, Constantin
nan</description><author>Andriosopoulos, Kostas; Pasiouras, Fotis; Zopounidis, Constantin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is M&amp;A different during a crisis? Evidence from the European banking sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beltratti, Andrea; Paladino, Giovanna
The financial crisis has affected the landscape of the banking sector around the world. We use a sample of transactions carried out by European acquirers in 2007-2010 to study the acquirer's stock price market reaction to both announcements and completions of acquisitions. At the aggregate level, we find that there are no significant abnormal returns around the announcement of an acquisition while there are positive abnormal returns at completions. We study the cross-sectional determinants of abnormal returns and find that announcement returns are mainly explained by the acquirer bank characteristics, while completion returns mainly depend on opacity of the target and on the drop in idiosyncratic volatility associated with a reduction of uncertainty. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beltratti, Andrea; Paladino, Giovanna</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market discipline during crisis: Evidence from bank depositors in transition countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, Iftekhar; Jackowicz, Krzysztof; Kowalewski, Oskar; Kozlowski, Lukasz
The Central European banking industry is dominated by foreign-owned banks. During the recent crisis, for the first time since the transition, foreign parent companies were frequently in a worse financial condition than their subsidiaries. This situation created a unique opportunity to study new aspects of market discipline exercised by non-financial depositors. Using a comprehensive data set, we find that the recent crisis did not change the sensitivity of deposit growth rates to accounting risk measures. We establish that depositors' actions were more strongly influenced by negative press rumors concerning parent companies than by fundamentals. The impact of rumors was especially perceptible when rumors turned out ex post to be founded. Additionally, we document that public aid announcements were primarily interpreted by depositors as confirmation of a parent company's financial distress. Our results indicate that depositors react rationally to sources of information other than financial statements; this discovery has policy implications, as depositor discipline is usually the only viable and universal source of market discipline for banks in emerging economies. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasan, Iftekhar; Jackowicz, Krzysztof; Kowalewski, Oskar; Kozlowski, Lukasz</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-selling, switching costs and imperfect competition in British banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhao, Tianshu; Matthews, Kent; Murinde, Victor
This paper attempts to evaluate the competitiveness of British banking in the presence of cross-selling and switching costs during 1993-2008. It presents estimates of a model of banking behaviour that encompasses switching costs as well as cross-selling of loans and off-balance sheet transactions. The evidence from panel estimation of the model indicates that the consumer faced high switching costs in the loan market in the latter part of the sample period, as a result of weaker competitiveness in the loan market. Additionally, the weaker competitiveness in the loan market appears to facilitate the cross-selling behaviour of British banks, which helps explain the rapid growth of non-interest income during the last two decades. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhao, Tianshu; Matthews, Kent; Murinde, Victor</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial supervision regimes and bank efficiency: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaganis, Chrysovalantis; Pasiouras, Fotios
There exists a lively debate as for the appropriate architecture of the financial supervision regime, with a long list of theoretical advantages and disadvantages associated with each one of its key dimensions. The present study investigates whether and how bank profit efficiency is influenced by the central bank's involvement in financial supervision, the unification of financial authorities, and the independence of the central bank. The results show that efficiency decreases as the number of the financial sectors that are supervised by the central bank increases. Additionally, banks operating in countries with greater unification of supervisory authorities are less profit efficient. Finally, central bank independence has a negative impact on bank profit efficiency. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gaganis, Chrysovalantis; Pasiouras, Fotios</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information disclosure, CEO overconfidence, and share buyback completion rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andriosopoulos, Dimitris; Andriosopoulos, Kostas; Hoque, Hafiz
An open market share buyback is not a firm commitment, and there is limited evidence on whether firms repurchase the intended shares. Unlike US studies, we use data from unique UK regulatory and disclosure environment that allows to accurately measure the share buyback completion rates. We show that information disclosure and CEO overconfidence are significant determinants of the share buyback completion rate. In addition, we find that large and widely held firms that conduct subsequent buyback programs and have a past buyback completion reputation exhibit higher completion rates. Finally, we assess whether other CEO characteristics affect buyback completion rates and find that firms with senior CEOs who hold external directorships and have a longer tenure as CEO are more likely to complete the buyback programs. In sum, our results suggest there is a clear relationship between information disclosure, CEO overconfidence, and buyback completion rates. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andriosopoulos, Dimitris; Andriosopoulos, Kostas; Hoque, Hafiz</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-marketability and the value of employee stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abudy, Menachem; Benninga, Simon
We adapt the Benninga et al. (2005) framework to value employee stock options (ESOs). The model quantifies non-diversification effects, is computationally simple, and provides an endogenous explanation of ESO early-exercise. Using a proprietary dataset of ESO exercise events we measure the non-marketability ESO discount. We find that the ESO value on the grant date is approximately 45% of a similar plain vanilla Black-Scholes value. The model is aligned with empirical findings of ESOs, gives an exercise boundary of ESOs and can serve as an approximation to the fair value estimation of share-based employee and executive compensation. Using the model we give a numerical measure of non-diversification in an imperfect market. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abudy, Menachem; Benninga, Simon</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit and liquidity components of corporate CDS spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coro, Filippo; Dufour, Alfonso; Varotto, Simone
This paper investigates the role of credit and liquidity factors in explaining corporate CDS price changes during normal and crisis periods. We find that liquidity risk is more important than firm-specific credit risk regardless of market conditions. Moreover, in the period prior to the recent "Great Recession" credit risk plays no role in explaining CDS price changes. The dominance of liquidity effects casts serious doubts on the relevance of CDS price changes as an indicator of default risk dynamics. Our results show how multiple liquidity factors including firm specific and aggregate liquidity proxies as well as an asymmetric information measure are critical determinants of CDS price variations. In particular, the impact of informed traders on the CDS price increases when markets are characterised by higher uncertainty, which supports concerns of insider trading during the crisis. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coro, Filippo; Dufour, Alfonso; Varotto, Simone</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of commodity markets: What gain for investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayan, Paresh Kumar; Narayan, Seema; Sharma, Susan Sunila
In this paper we study whether the commodity futures market predicts the commodity spot market. Using historical daily data on four commodities oil, gold, platinum, and silver we find that they do. We then show how investors can use this information on the futures market to devise trading strategies and make profits. In particular, dynamic trading strategies based on a mean-variance investor framework produce somewhat different results compared with those based on technical trading rules. Dynamic trading strategies suggest that all commodities are profitable and profits are dependent on structural breaks. The most recent global financial crisis marked a period in which commodity profits were the weakest. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Narayan, Paresh Kumar; Narayan, Seema; Sharma, Susan Sunila</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multidimensional risk and risk dependence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Polanski, Arnold; Stoja, Evarist; Zhang, Ren
Evaluating multiple sources of risk is an important problem with many applications in finance and economics. In practice this evaluation remains challenging. We propose a simple non-parametric framework with several economic and statistical applications. In an empirical study, we illustrate the flexibility of our technique by applying it to the evaluation of multidimensional density forecasts, multidimensional Value at Risk and dependence in risk. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Polanski, Arnold; Stoja, Evarist; Zhang, Ren</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying the balance sheet and the lending channels of monetary transmission: A loan-level analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aysun, Uluc; Hepp, Ralf
We make a novel attempt at comparing the strength of the lending and balance sheet channels of monetary transmission. To make this comparison, we use loan-level data to determine how borrower balance sheets and bank liquidity are related to bank lending decisions and how monetary policy can affect these relationships. The key innovation in this paper is the use of loan-level data. This enables us to measure the independent effects of the two channels and directly account for borrower balance sheets and lender liquidity instead of using proxies. Our results show that the balance sheet channel is the main mechanism through which monetary policy shocks are transmitted to the economy and that the lending channel does not play a significant role. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aysun, Uluc; Hepp, Ralf</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is local bias a cross-border phenomenon? Evidence from individual investors' international asset allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baltzer, Markus; Stolper, Oscar; Walter, Andreas
Extant literature consistently documents that investors tilt their domestic equity portfolios towards regionally close stocks (local bias). We hypothesize that individual investors' local bias is not limited to the domestic sphere but instead also determines their international investment decisions. Our results confirm the presence of a cross-border local bias. Specifically, we show (i) that the stockholdings of individual investors living within regional proximity to a foreign country display a significantly lower foreign investment bias towards investment opportunities in that country and (ii) that this drop in foreign investment bias levels is disproportionately driven by investments in regionally close neighbor-country companies. The impact of cross-border local bias on investors' bilateral foreign equity investments is economically significant and holds even after controlling for previously identified explanations of international asset allocation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baltzer, Markus; Stolper, Oscar; Walter, Andreas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effectiveness and valuation of political tax minimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hill, Matthew D.; Kubick, Thomas R.; Lockhart, G. Brandon; Wan, Huishan
We find evidence suggesting that corporate lobbying for tax purposes over the period 1999-2009 is one method by which firms managed corporate taxes. Furthermore, tax management strategies employed by these politically active firms were valued by shareholders. Firms lobbying on tax issues have lower book effective taxes and greater discretionary permanent differences in GAAP and IRS taxable income. Investors place a premium on lobbying activities for tax purposes unless the firm already has a low effective tax rate or very high book-tax differences. We conclude that lobbying political officials is one method by which firms manage risks attendant an aggressive tax strategy. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hill, Matthew D.; Kubick, Thomas R.; Lockhart, G. Brandon; Wan, Huishan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure choice and company taxation: A meta-study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feld, Lars P.; Heckemeyer, Jost H.; Overesch, Michael
This paper provides a quantitative review of the empirical literature on the tax impact on corporate debt financing. Synthesizing the evidence from 48 previous studies, we find that this impact is substantial. In particular, the tax rate proxy determines the outcome of primary analyses. Measures like the simulated marginal tax rate (Graham, 1996) avoid a downward bias in estimates for the debt response to tax. Moreover, econometric specifications and the set of control-variables affect tax effects. Accounting for misspecification biases by means of meta-regressions, we predict a marginal tax effect on the debt ratio of about 0.27. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Feld, Lars P.; Heckemeyer, Jost H.; Overesch, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do bank regulation, supervision and monitoring enhance or impede bank efficiency?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barth, James R.; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Seade, Jesus; Song, Frank M.
The recent global financial crisis has spurred renewed interest in identifying those reforms in bank regulation that would work best to promote bank development, performance and stability. Building upon three recent world-wide surveys on bank regulation (Barth et al., 2004, 2006, 2008), we contribute to this assessment by examining whether bank regulation, supervision and monitoring enhance or impede bank operating efficiency. Based on an un-balanced panel analysis of 4050 banks observations in 72 countries over the period 1999-2007, we find that tighter restrictions on bank activities are negatively associated with bank efficiency, while greater capital regulation stringency is marginally and positively associated with bank efficiency. We also find that a strengthening of official supervisory power is positively associated with bank efficiency only in countries with independent supervisory authorities. Moreover, independence coupled with a more experienced supervisory authority tends to enhance bank efficiency. Finally, market-based monitoring of banks in terms of more financial transparency is positively associated with bank efficiency. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barth, James R.; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Seade, Jesus; Song, Frank M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive compensation and the cost of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kabir, Rezaul; Li, Hao; Veld-Merkoulova, Yulia V.
This study examines how different components of executive compensation affect the cost of debt. We find that debt-like and equity-like pay components have differing effects: an increase in defined benefit pensions is associated with lower bond yield spread, while higher share holdings lead to higher spreads. In addition, we find that stock options have a mixed impact on the cost of debt whereas cash bonus has no significant impact. Overall, our results indicate that corporate bondholders are fully aware of both risk-taking and risk-avoiding incentives created by various executive pay components. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kabir, Rezaul; Li, Hao; Veld-Merkoulova, Yulia V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition in fragmented markets: New evidence from the German banking industry in the light of the subprime crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moch, Nils
Of all of the EU member states, Germany has the largest banking market. However, not all German banking institutions necessarily face fierce competition. Because the industry is highly fragmented, strict separation of the three existing banking pillars may impede competition, with negative effects on financial stability. We assess the competitive stances of 1,888 universal banks from 2001 to 2009 by using the Panzar-Rosse revenue test. We find evidence that measuring competition at an average country level does not necessarily generate valid evaluations of fragmented markets. In addition, we find no clear indication that either the particular objectives of cooperative and savings banks or the legal protection of these institutions impedes competition or discriminates against private banks. Therefore, as long as the relationship between competition and financial stability is dubious, the overall effect and the social costs or benefits of political measures that influence the structure of the German banking market are at least questionable. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moch, Nils</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does market structure matter on banks' profitability and stability? Emerging vs. advanced economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mirzaei, Ali; Moore, Tomoe; Liu, Guy
We empirically investigate the effects of market structure on profitability and stability for 1929 banks in 40 emerging and advanced economies over 1999-2008 by incorporating the traditional structure-conduct-performance (SCP) and relative-market-power (RMP) hypotheses. We observe that a greater market share leads to higher bank profitability being biased toward the RMP hypothesis in advanced economies, yet neither of the hypotheses is supported for profitability in emerging economies. The SCP appears to exert a destabilising effect on advanced banks, suggesting that a more concentrated banking system may be vulnerable to financial instability, however, the RMP seems to perform a stabilising effect in both economies. Evidence also highlights that profitability and stability increase with an increased interest-margin revenues in a less competitive environment for emerging markets. Overall, these results suggest that although policy measures to promote competition may dampen economic rent, excessive implementation may have an undesired destabilising impact on banks. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mirzaei, Ali; Moore, Tomoe; Liu, Guy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital controls in Brazil - Stemming a tide with a signal?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jinjarak, Yothin; Noy, Ilan; Zheng, Huanhuan
Controls on capital inflows have been experiencing a renaissance since 2008, with several prominent emerging markets implementing them in recent years. We focus on Brazil, which instituted five changes in its capital account regime in 2008-2011. Using the synthetic control method, we construct counterfactuals (i.e., Brazil with no policy change) for each of these changes. We find no evidence that any tightening of controls was effective in reducing the magnitudes of capital inflows, but we observe some modest and short-lived success in preventing further declines in inflows when the capital controls were relaxed. We hypothesize that price-based capital controls' only perceptible effect is to be found in the content of the signal they broadcast regarding the government's larger intentions and sensibilities. In the case of Brazil, its left-of-center government's willingness to remove controls was perceived as a noteworthy indication that the government was not as hostile to the international financial markets as many expected it to be. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jinjarak, Yothin; Noy, Ilan; Zheng, Huanhuan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board characteristics and Chinese bank performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liang, Qi; Xu, Pisun; Jiraporn, Pornsit
Using a sample of 50 largest Chinese banks during the period of 2003-2010, we explore a comprehensive set of board characteristics (size, composition and functioning of the board) and analyze their impacts on bank performance and bank asset quality in China. We find that the number of board meetings and the proportion of independent directors have significantly positive impacts on both bank performance and asset quality while board size has a significantly negative impact on bank performance. We find new evidence that the degree of bank boards' political connection is negatively correlated with bank performance and asset quality. The findings suggest that the board of directors plays a significant role in bank governance in China. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liang, Qi; Xu, Pisun; Jiraporn, Pornsit</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic effects of idiosyncratic volatility and liquidity on corporate bond spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalimipalli, Madhu; Nayak, Subhankar; Perez, M. Fabricio
We study the dynamic impact of idiosyncratic volatility and bond liquidity on corporate bond spreads over time and empirically disentangle both effects. Using an extensive data set, we find that both idiosyncratic volatility and liquidity are critical mainly for the distress portfolios, i.e., low-rated and short-term bonds; for others only volatility matters. The effects of volatility and liquidity shocks on bond spreads were both exacerbated during the recent financial crisis. Liquidity shocks are quickly absorbed into bonds prices; however, volatility shocks are more persistent and have a long-term effect. Our results overall suggest significant differences between how volatility and liquidity dynamically impact bond spreads. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kalimipalli, Madhu; Nayak, Subhankar; Perez, M. Fabricio</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sarbanes-Oxley Act and corporate credit spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nejadmalayeri, Ali; Nishikawa, Takeshi; Rao, Ramesh P.
Stock market reaction suggests that despite improved disclosure and increased accountability, Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) is too costly and not beneficial. Noting that bondholders are likely to reap the many potential benefits of SOX without bearing the brunt of costs, we examine how SOX affected corporate credit spreads to better assess its benefits. SOX has led to a significant structural decline in spreads of at least 27 basis points. Riskier firms (low rating, long maturity, high leverage, and small size) and firms closely related to SOX major provisions (earning variability, managerial trading, and corporate governance) experience greater declines in spreads. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nejadmalayeri, Ali; Nishikawa, Takeshi; Rao, Ramesh P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate lobbying, political connections, and the bailout of banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blau, Benjamin M.; Brough, Tyler J.; Thomas, Diana W.
Political involvement has long been shown to be a profitable investment for firms that seek favorable regulatory conditions or support in times of economic distress. But how important are different types of political involvement for the timing and magnitude of political support? To answer this question, we take a comprehensive look at the lobbying expenditures and political connections of banks that were recipients of government support under the 2008 Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP). We find that politically-engaged firms were not only more likely to receive TARP funds, but they also received a greater amount of TARP support and received the support earlier than firms that were not politically involved. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blau, Benjamin M.; Brough, Tyler J.; Thomas, Diana W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do firms use the trade credit channel to manage growth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferrando, Annalisa; Mulier, Klaas
While many theories of accounts payable and receivable are related to firm performance, there has not been a direct test whether firms actively use them to manage their growth. We argue that it is not just the accounts payable but also the accounts receivable that matter. While the former help to alleviate imperfections in the financial market, the latter do so in the product market. Using over 2.5 million observations for 600.000 firms in 8 euro area countries in the period 1993-2009, we show that firms use the trade credit channel to manage growth. In countries where the trade credit channel is more present, the marginal impact is lower, but the total impact is still higher. Further, firms that are more vulnerable to financial market imperfections, rely more on the trade credit channel to manage growth. Finally, we show that also the overall conditions of the financial market matter for the importance of the trade credit channel for growth. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferrando, Annalisa; Mulier, Klaas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional investor stability and crash risk: Monitoring versus short-termism?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Callen, Jeffrey L.; Fang, Xiaohua
This study tests two opposing views of institutional investors-monitoring versus short-termism. We present evidence that institutional investor stability is negatively associated with 1-year-ahead stock price crash risk, consistent with the monitoring theory of institutional investors but not the short-termism theory. Our findings are shown to be robust to alternative empirical specifications, estimation methods and endogeneity concerns. In addition, we find that institutional ownership by public pension funds (bank trusts, investment companies, and independent investment advisors) is significantly negatively (positively) associated with future crash risk, consistent with findings that pension funds more actively monitor management than other types of institutions. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Callen, Jeffrey L.; Fang, Xiaohua</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of idiosyncratic volatility on stock returns: A cross-sectional study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khovansky, Serguey; Zhylyevskyy, Oleksandr
This paper proposes a new approach to estimate the idiosyncratic volatility premium. In contrast to the popular two-pass regression method, this approach relies on a novel GMM-type estimation procedure that uses only a single cross-section of return observations to obtain consistent estimates. Also, it enables a comparison of idiosyncratic volatility premia estimated using stock returns with different holding periods. The approach is empirically illustrated by applying it to daily, weekly, monthly, quarterly, and annual US stock return data over the course of 2000-2011. The results suggest that the idiosyncratic volatility premium tends to be positive on daily return data, but negative on monthly, quarterly, and annual data. They also indicate the presence of a January effect. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khovansky, Serguey; Zhylyevskyy, Oleksandr</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial contagion and depositor monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasman, Augusto; Samartin, Margarita; Van Bommel, Jos
This paper analyzes market discipline in a many-bank economy where contagion and bank runs interact. We present a model with differently-informed depositors, where those depositors that are more informed have incentives to monitor banks' investments. It is shown that when banks are undercapitalized, and the probability of success of the risky asset is low, depositors might prefer a contract that is subject to bank runs in the interim period to a contract that allows banks to gamble with their funds and maintain their investment.The results of the paper emphasize the benefits of private monitoring of banks in order to promote market discipline. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasman, Augusto; Samartin, Margarita; Van Bommel, Jos</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Canonical vine copulas in the context of modern portfolio management: Are they worth it?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Low, Rand Kwong Yew; Alcock, Jamie; Faff, Robert; Brailsford, Timothy
In the context of managing downside correlations, we examine the use of multi-dimensional elliptical and asymmetric copula models to forecast returns for portfolios with 3-12 constituents. Our analysis assumes that investors have no short-sales constraints and a utility function characterized by the minimization of Conditional Value-at-Risk (CVaR). We examine the efficient frontiers produced by each model and focus on comparing two methods for incorporating scalable asymmetric dependence structures across asset returns using the Archimedean Clayton copula in an out-of-sample, long-run multi-period setting. For portfolios of higher dimensions, we find that modeling asymmetries within the rnarginals and the dependence structure with the Clayton canonical vine copula (CVC) consistently produces the highest-ranked outcomes across a range of statistical and economic metrics when compared to other models incorporating elliptical or symmetric dependence structures. Accordingly, we conclude that CVC copulas are 'worth it' when managing larger portfolios. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Low, Rand Kwong Yew; Alcock, Jamie; Faff, Robert; Brailsford, Timothy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio reallocation and exchange rate dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ding, Liang; Ma, Jun
This paper explains exchange rate dynamics by linking financial customers' foreign exchange order flow with their dynamic portfolio reallocation. For any currency pair in a particular period, one currency has higher assets return than the other and can be considered the high-return-currency (HRC). Financial institutions attempt to hold more HRC assets when they become more risk-loving or the relative return of the assets is expected to increase. Such a portfolio reallocation generates buy order toward the HRC and the currency appreciates. As the HRC changes over time, the direction that the relative return and risk appetite affect the exchange rate varies in different regimes. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ding, Liang; Ma, Jun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics of credit spread moments of European corporate bond indexes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alizadeh, Amir H.; Gabrielsen, Alexandros
Traditional quantitative credit risk models assume that changes in credit spreads are normally distributed but empirical evidence shows that they are likely to be skewed, fat-tailed, and change behaviour over time. Not taking into account such characteristics can compromise calculation of loss probabilities, pricing of credit derivatives, and profitability of trading strategies. Therefore, the aim of this study is to investigate the dynamics of higher moments of changes in credit spreads of European corporate bond indexes using extensions of GARCH type models that allow for time-varying volatility, skewness and kurtosis of changes in credit spreads as well as a regime-switching GARCH model which allows for regime shifts in the volatility of changes in credit spreads. Performance evaluation methods are used to assess which model captures the dynamics of observed distribution of the changes in credit spreads, produces superior volatility forecasts and Value-at-Risk estimates, and yields profitable trading strategies. The results presented can have significant implications for risk management, trading activities, and pricing of credit derivatives. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alizadeh, Amir H.; Gabrielsen, Alexandros</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behind the scenes of abandoning a fixed exchange rate regime</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Hyunju
This paper explores the process of abandoning a fixed exchange rate regime during sudden stops in a small open economy. The Bank of Korea's exchange rate policy reports during the East Asian crisis suggest that its fixed exchange rate regime was forced to collapse due to the depletion of usable foreign reserves, which resulted from the credit policy of the Korean central bank to support domestic banks in need of foreign currency liquidity. To capture the Korean crisis experience, I build a quantitative small open economy model in which, in response to the country risk premium shock, the foreign-currency credit policy of a central bank under fixed regime leads to the exhaustion of international reserves and consequent exchange rate regime shift. This model does well at replicating the observed contraction in Korean aggregate variables. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kang, Hyunju</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuing catastrophe derivatives under limited diversification: A stochastic dominance approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perrakis, Stylianos; Boloorforoosh, Ali
We present a new approach to the pricing of catastrophe event (CAT) derivatives that does not assume a fully diversifiable event risk. Instead, we assume that the event occurrence and intensity affect the return of the market portfolio of an agent that trades in the event derivatives. Based on this approach, we derive values for a CAT option and a reinsurance contract on an insurer's assets using recent results from the option pricing literature. We show that the assumption of unsystematic event risk seriously underprices the CAT option. Last, we present numerical results for our derivatives using real data from hurricane landings in Florida. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Perrakis, Stylianos; Boloorforoosh, Ali</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Suppliers' and customers' information asymmetry and corporate bond yield spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Tsung-Kang; Liao, Hsien-Hsing; Kuo, Hui-Ju; Hsieh, Yu-Ling
This study investigates the information asymmetry effects of suppliers and customers on a firm's bond yield spreads by employing American bond market data from 2001 to 2008. This study finds that both suppliers' and customers' information asymmetry effects significantly explain a firm's bond yield spreads. Besides, the information asymmetry effects of more important suppliers and customers are more significant than those of less important ones. The results are robust even after controlling for other well-known firth specific and economic variables. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Tsung-Kang; Liao, Hsien-Hsing; Kuo, Hui-Ju; Hsieh, Yu-Ling</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing the expectations hypothesis of the term structure with permanent-transitory component models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casalin, Fabrizio
This study proposes a new application of Permanent-Transitory Component Models (PTCMs) to test the Expectation Hypothesis of the Term Structure (EHTS). Unlike previous approaches, tests based on PTCMs can simultaneously detect departures from rational expectations and time varying term premia. We set out analytically and empirically the links across previous tests and PTCMs. We also show that PTCMs identify an additional restriction for rational expectations, on top of the one-to-one relationship between forward and spot rates, that must be imposed in estimations of term premia. Data for the short-end of the US term structure suggest that both factors contribute to the rejection of the EHTS. Moreover, the empirical estimates of term premia are persistent and exhibit sign fluctuations. Their stochastic properties depend crucially on whether the additional restriction for rational expectations is imposed in estimation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Casalin, Fabrizio</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A tale of two regimes: Theory and empirical evidence for a Markov-modulated jump diffusion model of equity returns and derivative pricing implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Charles; Fuh, Cheng-Der; Lin, Shih-Kuei
We provide closed-form solutions for a continuous time, Markov-modulated jump diffusion model in a general equilibrium framework for options prices under a variety of jump diffusion specifications. We further demonstrate that the two-state model provides the leptokurtic return features, volatility smile, and volatility clustering observed empirically for the Dow Jones Industrial Average (DJIA) and its component stocks. Using 10 years of stock return data, we confirm the existence of jump intensity switching and clustering, illustrate transition probabilities, and verify superior empirical fit over competing Poisson-style models. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Charles; Fuh, Cheng-Der; Lin, Shih-Kuei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Connected board of directors: A blessing or a curse?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheung, Yan-Leung; Chung, Cheong-Wing; Tan, Weiqiang; Wang, Wenming
This study attempts to identify the connection between the board of directors (BoD) and the controlling shareholder. We investigate how this connection affects the corporate governance practice and market performance of Hong Kong listed firms. Our results reveal that close connections between the BoD and the controlling shareholder have a negative effect on corporate governance practice. Our findings also indicate a lower market valuation for firms with a connected BoD. The evidence suggests that the market discounts the value of firms with a connected BoD. The evidence seems to reinforce the importance of the role of independent non-executive directors (INEDs) to enhance the independence of BoD. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cheung, Yan-Leung; Chung, Cheong-Wing; Tan, Weiqiang; Wang, Wenming</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A re-examination of exposure to exchange rate risk: The impact of earnings management and currency derivative usage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Feng-Yi; Hsin, Chin-Wen; Shiah-Hou, Shin-Rong
In an attempt to explain the weak evidence of priced exchange rate risk, we hypothesize that in addition to currency derivative usages, earnings management serves as another factor contributing to a reduction in exchange rate exposure. Our evidence reveals that earnings management activities, particularly those undertaken for the purpose of income smoothing, significantly reduce firm-specific exchange rate exposure, and that such role is particularly important if appropriate currency derivative instruments are limited. These results complement prior attempts to explain the puzzle of unpriced exchange rate risk. The investigation also highlights the importance of recognizing different managerial purposes behind discretionary accruals. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Feng-Yi; Hsin, Chin-Wen; Shiah-Hou, Shin-Rong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Eliminating entry barriers for the provision of banking services: Evidence from 'banking correspondents' in Brazil</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Assuncao, Juliano
This paper shows that the contractual arrangement of 'banking correspondents' has eliminated entry barriers for the provision of banking services in Brazil. With the bank correspondents, banks are allowed to reach the almost 2200 municipalities without bank branches in 2000, connecting 45 million people to the financial sector. The evidence is based on the estimation of an entry model of financial providers in Brazilian municipalities. I estimate a zero population entry threshold for banking correspondents for the period from 2002 to 2007. The estimated population entry thresholds for bank branches in the same period are relatively stable at approximately 8000-9000 people. The population entry thresholds for the second to fifth players for banking correspondents are also consistently lower than those for bank branches. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Assuncao, Juliano</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prospect theory and trading patterns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yao, Jing; Li, Duan
Reference dependence, loss aversion, and risk seeking for losses together comprise the preference-based component of prospect theory that sets its value function apart from the standard risk-aversion model. Using an elasticity analysis, we show that this distinctive preference component serves to underpin negative-feedback trading propensities, but cannot manifest itself in behavior directly or holistically at the individual-choice level. We then propose and demonstrate that the market interaction between prospect-theory investors and regular CRRA investors allows this preference component to dominate in equilibrium behavior and hence helps to reestablish the intuitive link between prospect-theory preferences and negative-feedback trading patterns. In the model, the interaction also reconciles the contrarian behavior of prospect-theory investors with asymmetric volatility and short-term return reversal. The results suggest that prospect-theory preferences can lead investors to behave endogenously as contrarian noise traders in the market interaction process. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yao, Jing; Li, Duan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank capital, interbank contagion, and bailout policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Suhua; Yang, Yunhong; Zhang, Gaiyan
This paper develops a theoretical framework in which asset linkages in a syndicated loan agreement can infect a healthy bank when its partner bank fails. We investigate how capital constraints affect the choice of the healthy bank to takeover or liquidate the exposure held jointly with the failing bank, and how the bank's ex ante optimal capital holding and possibility of contagion are affected by anticipation of bail-out policy, capital requirements and the joint exposure. We identify a range of factors that strengthen or weaken the possibility of contagion and bailout. Recapitalization with common stock rather than preferred equity injection dilutes existing shareholder interests and gives the bank a greater incentive to hold capital to cope with potential contagion. Increasing the minimum regulatory capital does not necessarily reduce contagion, while the requirement of holding conservation capital buffer could increase the bank's resilience to avoid contagion. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tian, Suhua; Yang, Yunhong; Zhang, Gaiyan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model uncertainty and VaR aggregation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Embrechts, Paul; Puccetti, Giovanni; Rueschendorf, Ludger
Despite well-known shortcomings as a risk measure, Value-at-Risk (VaR) is still the industry and regulatory standard for the calculation of risk capital in banking and insurance. This paper is concerned with the numerical estimation Of the VaR for a portfolio position as a function of different dependence scenarios on the factors of the portfolio. Besides summarizing the most relevant analytical bounds, including a discussion of their sharpness, we introduce a numerical algorithm which allows for the computation of reliable (sharp) bounds for the VaR of high-dimensional portfolios with dimensions d possibly in the several hundreds. We show that additional. positive dependence information will typically not improve the upper bound substantially. In contrast higher order marginal information on the model, when available, may lead to strongly improved bounds. Several examples of practical relevance show how explicit VaR bounds can be obtained. These bounds can be interpreted as a measure of model uncertainty induced by possible dependence scenarios. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Embrechts, Paul; Puccetti, Giovanni; Rueschendorf, Ludger</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst forecasts and European mutual fund trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franck, Alexander; Kerl, Alexander
This paper addresses the questions whether European mutual fund managers rely on sell-side analyst information and whether this behavior impacts fund performance. Results show that mutual funds significantly increase (decrease) their holdings in stocks when any of the consensus forecast measures increases (decreases) within the quarter prior to the observation period. Furthermore, mutual fund managers primarily attribute high information value to consensus forecast revisions that contain positive information, that are based on a sufficiently high number of inputs, and with more unanimous inputs to the consensus. Finally, following sell-side research seems to be beneficial for mutual fund managers since our results show that stock trades that are in line with analyst forecast revisions significantly outperform trades that are contrary to analyst research. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Franck, Alexander; Kerl, Alexander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal smooth consumption and annuity design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruhn, Kenneth; Steffensen, Mogens
We propose an optimization criterion that yields extraordinary consumption smoothing compared to the well known results of the life-cycle model. Under this criterion we solve the related consumption and investment optimization problem faced by individuals with preferences for intertemporal stability in consumption. We find that the consumption and investment patterns demanded under the optimization criterion is in general offered as annuity benefits from products in the class of 'Formula Based Smoothed Investment-Linked Annuities'. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bruhn, Kenneth; Steffensen, Mogens</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing discrete path-dependent options under a double exponential jump-diffusion model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuh, Cheng-Der; Luo, Sheng-Feng; Yen, Ju-Fang
We provide methodologies to price discretely monitored exotic options when the underlying evolves according to a double exponential jump diffusion process. We show that discrete barrier or lookback options can be approximately priced by their continuous counterparts' pricing formulae with a simple continuity correction. The correction is justified theoretically via extending the corrected diffusion method of Siegmund (1985). We also discuss the jump effects on the performance of this continuity correction method. Numerical results show that this continuity correction performs very well especially when the proportion of jump volatility to total volatility is small. Therefore, our method is sufficiently of use for most of time. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fuh, Cheng-Der; Luo, Sheng-Feng; Yen, Ju-Fang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do bank regulations affect board independence? A cross-country analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Li; Song, Frank M.
Based on the hand-collected board structure data of 277 listed banks across 55 countries, and the bank regulation and supervision database compiled by the World Bank, this paper provides the first cross-country assessment of the impacts of bank regulations on board independence of banks. In line with Beck et al. (2006), we examine the effects of two types of regulation policies, the first involving the empowerment of supervisory agencies to monitor and discipline banks directly, and the second focusing on encouraging private monitoring of banks through requiring disclosure of more accurate and complete information. We find that empowering official supervisory agencies to discipline banks directly reduces board independence, but encouraging private sector monitoring of banks increases it. The findings suggest that the first type of regulations tends to crowd out the internal governance of banks, while the second crowds in it. We also find that the legal system with better investor rights protection and better contracts enforcement not only increases board independence but also enhances the crowding in effect of promoting private monitoring and decreases the crowding out effect of direct official supervision on board independence. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Li; Song, Frank M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying the interaction between stock market returns and trading flows of investor types: Looking into the day using daily data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uelkue, Numan; Weber, Enzo
This paper introduces a new method for identifying the simultaneity between returns and trading flows. The proposed method enables us to identify the intraday interaction using daily data, and provides measures of the information content of trading flows, and their instantaneous response to public information and information revealed by market prices. Applying this method to daily data on investor types from the Korea Stock Exchange, we find significant intraday bi-directional interaction between flows and returns and their latent common drivers, altering some of the results of the previous literature based on Cholesky assumptions. Thus, we obtain a number of new insights concerning the behavior of investor types. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Uelkue, Numan; Weber, Enzo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants and effects of CEO-employee pay ratios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faleye, Olubunmi; Reis, Ebru; Venkateswaran, Anand
We study the determinants and effects of the relative compensation of top executives and lower-level employees. First, we show that CEO-employee pay ratios depend on the balance of power between the CEO (relative to the board) and ordinary employees (relative to management). Second, our results suggest that employees do not perceive higher pay ratios as an inequitable outcome to be redressed via costly behaviors that lower productivity. We do not find a negative relation between relative pay and employee productivity, either in our full sample or in subsamples where employees are well-informed about executive pay and are protected against career retributions. Rather, we find that productivity increases with relative pay when the firm has fewer employees who are well-informed, and when promotion decisions are predominantly merit-based. We also find that firm value and operating performance both increase with relative pay. We conclude that ordinary employees appear to perceive an opportunity in higher pay ratios but the extent to which such perception incentivizes them depends on the likelihood of success in a series of sequential promotion tournaments. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faleye, Olubunmi; Reis, Ebru; Venkateswaran, Anand</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is gold a safe haven or a hedge for the US dollar? Implications for risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reboredo, Juan C.
We assess the role of gold as a safe haven or hedge against the US dollar (USD) using copulas to characterize average and extreme market dependence between gold and the USD. For a wide set of currencies, our empirical evidence revealed (1) positive and significant average dependence between gold and USD depreciation, consistent with the fact that gold can act as hedge against USD rate movements, and (2) symmetric tail dependence between gold and USD exchange rates, indicating that gold can act as an effective safe haven against extreme USD rate movements. We evaluate the implications for mixed gold-currency portfolios, finding evidence of diversification benefits and downside risk reduction that confirms the usefulness of gold in currency portfolio risk management. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Reboredo, Juan C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment in financial literacy and saving decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jappelli, Tullio; Padula, Mario
We present an intertemporal consumption model of investment in financial literacy. Consumers benefit from such investment because financial literacy allows them to increase the returns on wealth. Since literacy depreciates over time and has a cost in terms of current consumption, the model delivers an optimal investment in literacy. Furthermore, literacy and wealth are determined jointly, and are positively correlated over the life-cycle. The model drives our empirical approach to the analysis of the effect of financial literacy on wealth and saving and indicates that the stock of financial literacy early in life is a valid instrument in the regression of wealth on financial literacy. Using microeconomic and aggregate data, we find strong support for the model's predictions. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jappelli, Tullio; Padula, Mario</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>VI seminar on risk, financial stability and banking of the Banco Central do Brasil</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tabak, Benjamin Miranda
nan</description><author>Tabak, Benjamin Miranda</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default and bankruptcy in an entrepreneurial economy with incomplete markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carvalho, Jaimilton; Divino, Jose Angelo; Orrillo, Jaime
We build a general equilibrium model with incomplete markets, production, default, and bankruptcy. The existence of equilibrium is proved. Theoretically, under appropriate conditions, we show that the reduced-form entrepreneurial equilibrium and profit-maximization entrepreneurial equilibrium, as defined by Magill and Quinzii (1996), are equivalent. In addition, we find an inverse relationship between the economy real interest rate and the probability of default. This result is empirically tested by applying the Cox proportional hazards model with time-dependent covariates for a sample of sole proprietorships' unsecured credit operations in the Brazilian economy. The estimates confirm the findings from the theoretical model. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carvalho, Jaimilton; Divino, Jose Angelo; Orrillo, Jaime</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Funding liquidity risk: Definition and measurement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drehmann, Mathias; Nikolaou, Kleopatra
Funding liquidity risk has played a key role in all historical banking crises. Nevertheless, a measure for funding liquidity risk based on publicly available data remains so far elusive. We address this gap by showing that aggressive bidding at central bank auctions reveals funding liquidity risk. We can extract an insurance premium from banks' bids which we propose as a measure of funding liquidity risk. Using a unique data set consisting of all bids in all auctions for the main refinancing operation conducted at the ECB between June 2005 and October 2008 we find that funding liquidity risk is typically stable and low, with occasional spikes especially around key events during the recent crisis. We also document downward spirals between funding liquidity risk and market liquidity. As measurement without clear definitions is impossible, we initially provide definitions of funding liquidity and funding liquidity risk. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Drehmann, Mathias; Nikolaou, Kleopatra</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business credit information sharing and default risk of private firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dierkes, Maik; Erner, Carsten; Langer, Thomas; Norden, Lars
We investigate whether and how business credit information sharing helps to better assess the default risk of private firms. Private firms represent an ideal testing ground because they are smaller, more informationally opaque, riskier, and more dependent on trade credit and bank loans than public firms. Based on a representative panel dataset that comprises private firms from all major industries, we find that business credit information sharing substantially improves the quality of default predictions. The improvement is stronger for older firms and those with limited liability, and depends on the sharing of firms' payment history and the number of firms covered by the local credit bureau office. The value of soft business credit information is higher the smaller the firms and the lower their distance from the local credit bureau office. Furthermore, in spatial and industry analyses we show that the higher the value of business credit information the lower the realized default rates. Our study highlights the channel through which business credit information sharing adds value and the factors that influence its strength. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dierkes, Maik; Erner, Carsten; Langer, Thomas; Norden, Lars</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size matters: Optimal calibration of shrinkage estimators for portfolio selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMiguel, Victor; Martin-Utrera, Alberto; Nogales, Francisco J.
We carry out a comprehensive investigation of shrinkage estimators for asset allocation, and we find that size matters-the shrinkage intensity plays a significant role in the performance of the resulting estimated optimal portfolios. We study both portfolios computed from shrinkage estimators of the moments of asset returns (shrinkage moments), as well as shrinkage portfolios obtained by shrinking the portfolio weights directly. We make several contributions in this field. First, we propose two novel calibration criteria for the vector of means and the inverse covariance matrix. Second, for the covariance matrix we propose a novel calibration criterion that takes the condition number optimally into account. Third, for shrinkage portfolios we study two novel calibration criteria. Fourth, we propose a simple multivariate smoothed bootstrap approach to construct the optimal shrinkage intensity. Finally, we carry out an extensive out-of-sample analysis with simulated and empirical datasets, and we characterize the performance of the different shrinkage estimators for portfolio selection. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeMiguel, Victor; Martin-Utrera, Alberto; Nogales, Francisco J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk measurement: Multivariate GARCH estimation of CoVaR</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Girardi, Giulio; Erguen, A. Tolga
We modify Adrian and Brunnermeier's (2011) CoVaR, the VaR of the financial system conditional on an institution being in financial distress. We change the definition of financial distress from an institution being exactly at its VaR to being at most at its VaR. This change allows us to consider more severe distress events, to backtest CoVaR, and to improve its consistency (monotonicity) with respect to the dependence parameter. We define the systemic risk contribution of an institution as the change from its CoVaR in its benchmark state (defined as a one-standard deviation event) to its CoVaR under financial distress. We estimate the systemic risk contributions of four financial industry groups consisting of a large number of institutions for the sample period June 2000 to February 2008 and the 12 months prior to the beginning of the crisis. We also investigate the link between institutions' contributions to systemic risk and their characteristics. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Girardi, Giulio; Erguen, A. Tolga</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetry in government bond returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fujiwara, Ippei; Koerber, Lena Mareen; Nagakura, Daisuke
Is there asymmetry in the distribution of government bond returns in developed countries? Can asymmetries be predicted using financial and macroeconomic variables? To answer the first question, we provide evidence for asymmetry in government bond returns in particular for short maturities. This finding has important implications for modeling and forecasting government bond returns. For example, widely used models for yield curve analysis such as the affine term structure model assume symmetrically distributed innovations. To answer the second question, we find that liquidity in government bond markets predicts the coefficient of skewness with a positive sign, meaning that the probability of a large and negative excess return is more likely in a less liquid market. In addition, a positive realized return is associated with a negative coefficient of skewness, or a small probability of a large and negative return in the future. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fujiwara, Ippei; Koerber, Lena Mareen; Nagakura, Daisuke</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product market power, industry structure, and corporate earnings management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Datta, Sudip; Iskandar-Datta, Mai; Singh, Vivek
This is the first study to establish a link between product market power of firms and the degree of earnings management. We hypothesize and document a significant and robust association between (a) a firm's product market pricing power and its degree of earnings management, and (b) industry competitiveness and the degree of earnings management in the industry. Our study reveals that firms with inferior product market pricing power engage in greater discretionary earnings accruals, adding a new dimension to our understanding of the transparency and informativeness of firms' financial statements. These findings are mirrored at the industry level where we document that more competitive industries are associated with greater earnings manipulation. The empirical evidence has direct implication on the informativeness and earnings quality of firms based on their product market power and competitiveness. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Datta, Sudip; Iskandar-Datta, Mai; Singh, Vivek</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did the crisis induce credit rationing for French SMEs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kremp, Elizabeth; Sevestre, Patrick
This paper focuses on the access of independent French SMEs to bank lending and analyzes whether the observed evolution of credit to SMEs over the recent period was "demand driven" as a result of the decrease in firms' activity and investment projects or was "supply driven" with an increase in credit "rationing" stemming from a more cautious behavior of banks. Based on a sample of around 60,000 SMEs, we come to the conclusion that, despite the stronger standards used by banks when granting credit, French SMEs do not appear to have been strongly affected by credit rationing since 2008. This result goes against the common view that SMEs suffered from a strong credit restriction during the crisis but is perfectly in line with the results of several surveys about the access to finance of SMEs recently conducted in France. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kremp, Elizabeth; Sevestre, Patrick</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit default swap spreads and variance risk premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Hao; Zhou, Hao; Zhou, Yi
We find that the firm-level variance risk premium has a prominent explanatory power for credit spreads in the presence of market- and firm-level control variables established in the existing literature. Such predictability complements that of the leading state variable-the leverage ratio-and strengthens significantly with a lower firm credit rating, longer credit contract maturity, and model-free implied variance. We provide further evidence that (1) the variance risk premium has a cleaner systematic component than implied variance or expected variance, (2) the cross-section of firms' variance risk premia capture systematic variance risk in a stronger way than firms' equity returns in capturing market return risk, and (3) a structural model with stochastic volatility can reproduce the predictability pattern of variance risk premia for credit spreads. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Hao; Zhou, Hao; Zhou, Yi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A geographically weighted approach to measuring efficiency in panel data: The case of US saving banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tabak, Benjamin M.; Miranda, Rogerio Boueri; Fazio, Dimas M.
This paper discusses a new approach to controlling for the environment when estimating efficiency. In response to the literature on the international comparison of bank efficiency, we draw the attention to a local dimension of comparison. By introducing geographical weights and estimating local frontiers for each US savings bank in the 2001-09 period, we find that the bank technical performance is higher for most banks in comparison to a fixed-effects approach. This result highlights the importance of taking into account the local environment and constraints while analyzing banks' performance, so as not to consider the factors that are exogenous to these institutions as inefficiencies. Further analysis could improve the weighs calculation by employing other measures of interconnectedness besides geographical distance. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tabak, Benjamin M.; Miranda, Rogerio Boueri; Fazio, Dimas M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The timing of 52-week high price and momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhootra, Ajay; Hur, Jungshik
We propose a new momentum strategy based on the timing of a stock's 52-week high price. We find that the stocks that attained the 52-week high price in the recent past significantly outperform the stocks that attained the 52-week high price in the distant past. In particular, the top 10% of the stocks with the most recent 52-week high price outperform the bottom 10% of the stocks with most distant 52-week high price by 0.70% per month. Further, conditioning on the recency of 52-week high price significantly increases the profitability of momentum strategy based on the nearness of current price to the 52-week high price. Specifically, the average monthly return of this strategy is about twice as large for stocks with recent 52-week high price as compared with stocks with distant 52-week high price. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhootra, Ajay; Hur, Jungshik</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lessons from the evolution of foreign exchange trading strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neely, Christopher J.; Weller, Paul A.
The adaptive markets hypothesis posits that trading strategies evolve as traders adapt their behavior to changing circumstances. This paper studies the evolution of trading strategies for a hypothetical trader who chooses portfolios from foreign exchange (forex) technical rules in major and emerging markets, the carry trade, and US equities. The results show that a backtesting procedure to choose optimal portfolios improves upon the performance of nonadaptive rules. We also find that forex trading alone dramatically outperforms the S&amp;P 500, with much larger Sharpe ratios over the whole sample, but there is little gain to coordinating forex and equity strategies, which explains why practitioners consider these tools separately. Forex trading returns dip significantly in the 1990s but recover by the end of the decade and have been markedly superior to an equity position since 1998. Overall, trading rule returns still exist in forex markets-with substantial stability in the types of rules-though they have migrated to emerging markets to a considerable degree. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Neely, Christopher J.; Weller, Paul A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Federal Reserve financial crisis lending programs and bank stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cyree, Ken B.; Griffiths, Mark D.; Winters, Drew B.
We use an E-GARCH model to estimate the wealth effects of Federal Reserve lending during the financial crisis to Investment banks (I-Banks), "Too Big to Fail" (TBTF) banks, and "traditional" commercial banks. Borrowing from the Term Auction Facility program has negative wealth effects for all banks and I-banks in particular. We also find that the market view of the liquidity programs changed across the sample sub-periods. I-Bank and TBTF bank borrowing from the discount window is initially viewed positively, however continued use of the discount window and the Term Auction Facility was generally (though not universally) viewed negatively. Commercial Paper Funding Facility program participation is consistently positive only for traditional banks and programs that focus on the purchase of specific securities (e.g., commercial paper) to address specific problems also appear to primarily benefit traditional banks. The inconsistency of results across the time periods of the crisis is telling as market participants struggled to discern what access to these programs meant. (C) 2013 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cyree, Ken B.; Griffiths, Mark D.; Winters, Drew B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantifying structural subsidy values for systemically important financial institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ueda, Kenichi; di Mauro, B. Weder
Claimants to Systemically Important Financial Institutions (SIFIs) would receive transfers when governments are forced into bailouts. Ex ante, this bailout expectation lowers SIFIs' daily funding costs. The funding cost advantage reflects both the structural level of the government support and the time-varying market valuation for such a support. Based on a large worldwide sample of banks, we estimate the value of the structural subsidy, by exploiting expectations of state support embedded in credit ratings and by applying the long-run average value of the rating bonus. The value of the structural subsidy was already sizable, 60 basis points (bp), as of the end-2007, before the crisis. It increased to 80 bp by the end-2009. (C) 2013 International Monetary Fund. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ueda, Kenichi; di Mauro, B. Weder</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Risk Map: A new tool for validating risk models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colletaz, Gilbert; Hurlin, Christophe; Perignon, Christophe
This paper presents a new method to validate risk models: the Risk Map. This method jointly accounts for the number and the magnitude of extreme losses and graphically summarizes all information about the performance of a risk model. It relies on the concept of a super exception, which is defined as a situation in which the loss exceeds both the standard Value-at-Risk (VaR) and a VaR defined at an extremely low probability. We then formally test whether the sequences of exceptions and super exceptions are rejected by standard model validation tests. We show that the Risk Map can be used to validate market, credit, operational, or systemic risk estimates (VaR, stressed VaR, expected shortfall, and CoVaR) or to assess the performance of the margin system of a clearing house. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Colletaz, Gilbert; Hurlin, Christophe; Perignon, Christophe</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemically important banks and financial stability: The case of Latin America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tabak, Benjamin M.; Fazio, Dimas M.; Cajueiro, Daniel O.
This paper addresses the issue on how bank size and market concentration affect performance and risks in 17 Latin American countries between 2001 and 2008. The objective is to evaluate whether a too-big-to-fail behavior has been present in the region. Surprisingly, we do not find evidence to support a higher fragility of large Latin American banks. Our results show that systemically important financial institutions appear to outperform others in terms of both cost and profit without the need of taking more risks. This result holds even in concentrated markets, i.e., where there are few dominant banks and many others with small size in relation to the market. A highly unequal banking market in terms of assets, however, is detrimental for the performance of smaller banks and it also decreases stability of the whole system. We conclude that regulators should deal with market concentration by reducing the size gap between large and small banks, instead of dealing specifically with systemically important banks. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tabak, Benjamin M.; Fazio, Dimas M.; Cajueiro, Daniel O.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A statistically robust decomposition of mutual fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agnesens, Julius
Previous decompositions of risk-adjusted mutual fund performance might deliver biased results. In this paper, we provide new reliable insights on the drivers of mutual fund performance by decomposing risk-adjusted performance of U.S. equity mutual funds using the Generalized Calendar Time regression model. According to our results, out of all previously considered fund characteristics, only the negative effect of lagged fund size and the positive effects of lagged performance and lagged family size remain highly significant. Our analysis further suggests that much of the variation in previous empirical results can be attributed to methodological issues. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agnesens, Julius</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry and international strategic alliances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Owen, Sian; Yawson, Alfred
This paper examines how information asymmetry affects cross-border strategic alliance formation by US firms over the period 2000-2008. We construct a measure, information costs, based on both geographical distance and the proportion of worldwide GDP the partner's home country represents. Consistent with our expectations, we find an inverse association between information costs and cross-border strategic alliances. When considering the proportion of alliances formed with publicly quoted overseas partners, we find this is unaffected by the level of information costs but rather the level of stock market development, tax rate and general economic conditions. Information costs are, however, significantly negatively related to alliances with overseas private organizations. Our results offer clear support for the on-going importance of information asymmetry in corporate decision making. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Owen, Sian; Yawson, Alfred</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial literacy and its consequences: Evidence from Russia during the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klapper, Leora; Lusardi, Annamaria; Panos, Georgios A.
The ability of consumers to make informed financial decisions improves their ability to develop sound personal finance. This paper uses a panel data set from Russia, an economy in which household debt has grown at an astounding rate, to examine the importance of financial literacy and its effects on behavior. The paper studies both the financial and real consequences of financial illiteracy. Even though consumer borrowing increased very rapidly in Russia, only 41% of respondents demonstrate an understanding of interest compounding and only 46% can answer a simple question about inflation. Financial literacy is positively related to participation in financial markets and negatively related to the use of informal sources of borrowing. Moreover, individuals with higher financial literacy are significantly less likely to report experiencing a negative income shock during 2009 and have greater availability of unspent income and higher spending capacity. The relationship between financial literacy and availability of unspent income is higher in 2009, suggesting that financial literacy may better equip individuals to deal with macroeconomic shocks. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Klapper, Leora; Lusardi, Annamaria; Panos, Georgios A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A case study of short-sale constraints and limits to arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easton, Steve; Pinder, Sean; Uylangco, Katherine
This paper uses a unique data set of trades in a unique pair of securities that enables the precise identification of individual broker activity and the trade direction of that activity. We find direct evidence that the imposition (removal) of short-sale constraints limits (generates) trading activity consistent with brokers exploiting apparent mispricing. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Easton, Steve; Pinder, Sean; Uylangco, Katherine</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank liquidity, the maturity ladder, and regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Haan, Leo; van den End, Jan Willem
We investigate the liquidity management of 62 Dutch banks between January 2004 and March 2010, when these banks were subject to a liquidity regulation that is very similar to Basel Ill's Liquidity Coverage Ratio (LCR). We find that most banks hold more liquid assets against their stock of liquid liabilities, such as demand deposits, than strictly required under the regulation. More solvent banks hold fewer liquid assets against their stock of liquid liabilities, suggesting an interaction between capital and liquidity buffers. However, this interaction turns out to be weaker during a crisis. Although not required, some banks consider cash flows scheduled beyond 1 month ahead when setting liquidity asset holdings, but they seldom look further ahead than 1 year. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Haan, Leo; van den End, Jan Willem</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of the incidence of U.S. Mortgage Loan Modifications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Been, Vicki; Weselcouch, Mary; Voicu, Ioan; Murff, Scott
This paper combines data on the performance of mortgage loans with detailed borrower, neighborhood, and property characteristics to examine the factors that determine the outcomes of seriously delinquent loans. We employ multinomial logit models in a hazard framework to explain how loan, borrower, property, servicer and neighborhood characteristics affect which of the following four outcomes results from a seriously delinquent loan: (1) the borrower cures the delinquency; (2) the borrower and lender agree to modify the loan; (3) the borrower suffers a liquidation (short sale, deed in lieu, foreclosure auction sale or REO); or (4) the loan remains delinquent. In particular, we focus on mortgage modification. We find that the outcomes of delinquent loans are significantly related to: current LW, FICO scores, especially risky loan characteristics, the servicer of the loan, neighborhood housing price appreciation, and whether the borrower received foreclosure counseling. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Been, Vicki; Weselcouch, Mary; Voicu, Ioan; Murff, Scott</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The second moment matters! Cross-sectional dispersion of firm valuations and expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Danling
Behavioral theories predict that firm valuation dispersion in the cross-section ("dispersion") measures aggregate overpricing caused by investor overconfidence and should be negatively related to expected aggregate returns. This paper develops and tests these hypotheses. Consistent with the model predictions, I find that measures of dispersion are positively related to aggregate valuations, trading volume, idiosyncratic volatility, past market returns, and current and future investor sentiment indexes. Dispersion is a strong negative predictor of subsequent short- and long-term market excess returns. Market beta is positively related to stock returns when the beginning-of-period dispersion is low and this relationship reverses when initial dispersion is high. A simple forecast model based on dispersion significantly outperforms a naive model based on historical equity premium in out-of-sample tests and the predictability is stronger in economic downturns. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jiang, Danling</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross-sectional relation between conditional heteroskedasticity, the implied volatility smile, and the variance risk premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ederington, Louis H.; Guan, Wei
This paper estimates how the shape of the implied volatility smile and the size of the variance risk premium relate to parameters of GARCH-type time-series models measuring how conditional volatility responds to return shocks. Markets in which return shocks lead to large increases in conditional volatility tend to have larger variance risk premia than markets in which the impact on conditional volatility is slight. Markets in which negative (positive) return shocks lead to larger increases in future volatility than positive (negative) return shocks tend to have downward (upward) sloping implied volatility smiles. Also, differences in how volatility responds to return shocks as measured by GARCH-type models explain much, but not all, of the variations in excess kurtosis and multi-period skewness across different markets. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ederington, Louis H.; Guan, Wei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification and heterogeneity of investor beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiao, Jie; Qiu, Bin; Yan, An
In the paper, we find that diversification reduces the heterogeneity of investor beliefs on firm value. We obtain this finding by comparing not only between diversified and focused firms but also between diversifying and non-diversifying mergers. We also find that the reduced heterogeneity of investor beliefs on a diversified firm relative to its focused peers is negatively associated with its contemporaneous excess value and positively associated with its future excess value. Overall, our results contribute to the understanding about how corporate organization structure affects the heterogeneity of investor beliefs and further firm value. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiao, Jie; Qiu, Bin; Yan, An</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Better than the original? The relative success of copycat funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Verbeek, Marno; Wang, Yu
We construct hypothetical copycat funds to investigate the performance of free-riding strategies that duplicate the disclosed asset holdings of actively managed mutual funds. On average, copycat funds are able to generate performance that is comparable to their target mutual funds, taking into account transaction costs and expenses. However, their relative success increased significantly after 2004 when the SEC imposed quarterly disclosure regulations on all mutual funds. We also find substantial cross-sectional dispersion in the relative performance of copycat funds. Free-riding on the portfolios disclosed by past winning funds and funds that disclose representative holdings generates significantly better performance net of trading costs and expenses than the vast majority of mutual funds. The results indicate that free-riding on disclosed fund holdings is an attractive strategy and suggest that mutual funds can suffer from the information disclosure requirements. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Verbeek, Marno; Wang, Yu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial constraints of private firms and bank lending behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Behr, Patrick; Norden, Lars; Noth, Felix
We investigate whether and how financial constraints of private firms depend on bank lending behavior. Bank lending behavior, especially its scale, scope and timing, is largely driven by bank business models which differ between privately owned and state-owned banks. Using a unique dataset on private small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) we find that an increase in relative borrowings from local state-owned banks significantly reduces firms' financial constraints, while there is no such effect for privately owned banks. Improved credit availability and private information production are the main channels that explain our result. We also show that the lending behavior of local state-owned banks can be sustainable because it is less cyclical and neither leads to more risk taking nor underperformance. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Behr, Patrick; Norden, Lars; Noth, Felix</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>ETF arbitrage: Intraday evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marshall, Ben R.; Nguyen, Nhut H.; Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat
We use two extremely liquid S&amp;P 500 ETFs to analyze the prevailing trading conditions when mispricing allowing arbitrage opportunities is created. While these ETFs are not perfect substitutes, our correlation and error correction results suggest investors view them as close substitutes. Spreads increase just before arbitrage opportunities, consistent with a decrease in liquidity. Order imbalance increases as markets become more one-sided and spread changes become more volatile which suggests an increase in liquidity risk. The price deviations are followed by a tendency to quickly correct back towards parity. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marshall, Ben R.; Nguyen, Nhut H.; Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private equity benchmarks and portfolio optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, Douglas; Hass, Lars Helge; Schweizer, Denis
Portfolio optimization using private equity is typically based on one of three indices: listed private equity, transaction-based private equity, or appraisal value-based private equity indices. However, we show that none of these indices is fully suitable for portfolio optimization. We introduce here a new benchmark index for venture capital and buyouts, which is updated monthly, adjusted for autocorrelation (de-smoothing), and available contemporaneously. We illustrate how our benchmark enables superior quantitative portfolio optimization. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cumming, Douglas; Hass, Lars Helge; Schweizer, Denis</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overconfident individual day traders: Evidence from the Taiwan futures market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuo, Wei-Yu; Lin, Tse-Chun
A specific day-trading policy in Taiwan futures market allows an investigation of the performance of day traders. Since October 2007, investors who characterize themselves as "day traders" by closing their day-trade positions on the same day enjoy a 50% reduction in the initial margin. Because we can identify day traders ex ante, we have a laboratory to explore trading behavior without the contamination of potential behavioral biases. Our results show that the 3470 individual day traders in the sample incur on average a significant loss of 61,500 (26,700) New Taiwan dollars after (before) transaction costs over October 2007-September 2008. This implies that day traders are not only overconfident about the accuracy of their information but also biased in their interpretations of information. We also find that excessive trading is hazardous only to the overconfident losers, but not to the winners. Last, we provide evidence that more experienced individual investors exhibit more aggressive day trading behavior, although they do not learn their types or gain superior trading skills that could mitigate their losses. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kuo, Wei-Yu; Lin, Tse-Chun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank audit practices and loan loss provisioning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahl, Drew
I empirically examine the evolution of loan loss accounting across banks that differ categorically by external auditing practice. Using a partial adjustment model, and a sample of 75,505 observations on affiliated banks, 1995-2009, I find evidence of convergence across audit categories in target ratios of provisions for loan losses to nonaccrual loans. This is consistent with a standardized method of accounting for "impaired" loans. I observe less convergence, on the other hand, in target ratios of provisions for loan losses to loans, which appears to accommodate a role for managerial discretion. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dahl, Drew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal retirement with unemployment risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jang, Bong-Gyu; Park, Seyoung; Rhee, Yuna
This paper investigates the optimal retirement of an individual in the presence of involuntary unemployment risks and borrowing constraints in a complete market with frictions. We use an intensity model and loading factors to illustrate the involuntary unemployment risks and frictions in unemployment insurance markets. Using reasonably calibrated parameters, we observe that high involuntary unemployment intensity and loading factors could be important explanations for the empirical findings emphasized in recent studies. We also find that an individual with high leisure demand after retirement reduces consumption during retirement and increases stockholdings as retirement time approaches. (C) 2013 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jang, Bong-Gyu; Park, Seyoung; Rhee, Yuna</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposit market competition, wholesale funding, and bank risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Craig, Ben R.; Dinger, Valeriya
Empirical research on the effect of bank competition on bank risk has so far produced very inconclusive results. In this paper we revisit this long-standing debate and propose a new empirical approach that is concentrated on the relationship between deposit market competition and bank risk. This approach closely follows the traditional theoretical views of the competition and risk relationship and is focused on testing the classical moral hazard problem of the bank: deposit market competition raises the optimal risk choice of the bank by raising the costs of bank liabilities. Since banks can substitute between retail and wholesale funding, we relate deposit market competition to wholesale market conditions and examine their joint effect on the risk of bank assets. The analysis is based on a unique, comprehensive dataset, which combines retail deposit rate data with data on bank characteristics and data on local deposit market features for a sample of 589 US banks. Our results support the notion of a risk-enhancing effect of deposit market competition. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Craig, Ben R.; Dinger, Valeriya</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do banks respond to shocks? A dynamic model of deposit-taking institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dia, Enzo
This paper proposes a dynamic model of the optimal choices of a bank that benefits from market power and takes into account the impact of the deposit generation process. Interbank lending/borrowing emerges as a buffer that assists the bank in smoothing intertemporal adjustments in interdependent loan and deposit choices. The bank smooths the impact of interest-rates shocks on its customers to minimize the adjustments over time of the stocks of deposits and loans. It does not, however, provide insurance against negative shocks of real origin that increase its expected default costs. The predictions of the model help to shed light on the available empirical evidence and to analyze some recent developments of the banking industry. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dia, Enzo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Have the GIPSI settled down? Breaks and multivariate stochastic volatility models for, and not against, the European financial integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gebka, Bartosz; Karoglou, Michail
We investigate the integration of the European peripheral financial markets with Germany, France, and the UK using a combination of tests for structural breaks and return correlations derived from several multivariate stochastic volatility models. Our findings suggest that financial integration intensified in anticipation of the Euro, further strengthened by the EMU inception, and amplified in response to the 2007/2008 financial crisis. Hence, no evidence is found of decoupling of the equity markets in more troubled European countries from the core. Interestingly, the UK, despite staying outside the EMU, is not worse integrated with the GIPSI than Germany or France. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gebka, Bartosz; Karoglou, Michail</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate social responsibility and earnings forecasting unbiasedness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becchetti, Leonardo; Ciciretti, Rocco; Giovannelli, Alessandro
We investigate the relationship between corporate social responsibility (CSR) and I/B/E/S analysts' earnings per share (EPS) forecasts using a large sample of US firms for 1992-2011. Based on literature findings, we decompose the CSR effect into four factors: accounting opacity, corporate governance, stakeholder risk, and overinvestment. We find that all of them significantly affect both the absolute forecast error on EPS and its standard deviation controlling for forecast horizon: number of analysts and forecasts: and year, industry, and broker house effects. Consistently with our ex ante hypotheses, overinvestment, stakeholder risk, and accounting opacity have a positive effect, increasing both dependent variables, while corporate governance quality has a negative effect. A crucial aspect of our findings is that high CSR quality in terms of the four factors (i.e., accounting transparency, high corporate governance quality, stakeholder risk mitigation, and absence of overinvestment) contributes to making earnings forecasts unbiased as unbiasedness is generally met in the subsample of the Top CSR quality companies and markedly violated in the subsample of the Bottom CSR companies. We also document that overinvestment and stakeholder risk are sufficient to produce this effect. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Becchetti, Leonardo; Ciciretti, Rocco; Giovannelli, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment horizon, risk, and compensation in the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Livne, Gilad; Markarian, Garen; Mironov, Maxim
This paper examines the relation between the investment horizon of banks and their CEO compensation, and its consequences for risk and performance. We find that banks with short-term investment intensity pay more cash bonus, exhibit higher risk and perform more poorly than banks with longer-term investment intensity. This evidence is broadly consistent with the view that short-term means of compensation encouraged a short-term investment focus, which in turn led to both higher risk and resulted in poorer performance, culminating in the sub-prime crisis. The inverse risk-performance relation suggests pay schemes were incongruent with shareholders' interest. Moreover, pay arrangements used in banks prior to the subprime crisis exposed banks to the ex-post settling up problem (the clawback problem). (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Livne, Gilad; Markarian, Garen; Mironov, Maxim</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option-implied correlation between iTraxx Europe Financials and Non-Financials Indexes: A measure of spillover effect in European debt crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hui, Cho-Hoi; Lo, Chi-Fai; Lau, Chun-Sing
This paper proposes an analytic method to estimate the option-implied correlation embedded in options on the iTraxx Europe CDS indexes. The option-implied correlation is suggested as a measure of the spill-over effect of default risk between the financial and corporate sectors in Europe. In particular, the correlation between the iTraxx Financials and Non-Financials sub-indexes is estimated from options on the iTraxx Main Index, which is considered as a basket option with the two sub-indexes being its underlyings. The abrupt changes of the realized correlation anticipated information of the corresponding option prices. The sovereign default risk, funding liquidity risk, level of risk aversion, and equity market performance are identified to be significant determinants of the option-implied correlation, implying interdependence amongst various markets during the European debt crisis. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hui, Cho-Hoi; Lo, Chi-Fai; Lau, Chun-Sing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Saving-based asset-pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dreyer, Johannes K.; Schneider, Johannes; Smith, William T.
This paper explores the implications of a novel class of preferences for the behavior of asset prices. Following a suggestion by Marshall (1920), we entertain the possibility that people derive utility not only from consumption, but also from the very act of saving. These "saving-based" preferences are related to models of habit formation and the spirit of capitalism, but incorporate the feature that people have anticipatory habits because they care about the future accumulation of wealth. We derive the Euler equations for these preferences and estimate them with GMM. Our estimates suggest that the preference for saving is economically significant. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dreyer, Johannes K.; Schneider, Johannes; Smith, William T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Compensation incentives of credit rating agencies and predictability of changes in bond ratings and financial strength ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milidonis, Andreas
Over the past decade there has been mixed evidence on the lead-lag relation between issuer-paid and investor-paid credit rating agencies. We investigate the lead-lag relationship for changes in bond ratings (BRs) and financial strength ratings (FSRs), for the US insurance industry, where FSRs impose market discipline. First, we find that changes in issuer-paid BRs are led by changes in investor-paid BRs, even over a period that issuer-paid agencies have improved their timeliness. Second, information flows in both directions between changes in issuer-paid BRs and FSRs. Third, issuer-paid FSRs are predictable by investor-paid BRs. Fourth, the lead effect of investor-paid downgrades is economically significant as it is associated with an unconditional, post-event, 30-day cumulative abnormal return of -4%. This return is a result of investor-paid downgrades in BRs, which predict more downgrades in the following 90 days (same period return of -11%). (C) 2013 Elsevier K.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Milidonis, Andreas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Persistency of financial distress amongst Italian households: Evidence from dynamic models for binary panel data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giarda, Elena
This paper builds on existing studies on households' financial distress and provides new evidence on the determinants of financial hardship in Italy and its persistence over time. It suggests a quantitative definition of financial distress based on the distribution of net wealth, and tests whether the probability of experiencing financial difficulty is persistent over time, using (random and fixed effects) dynamic models for binary panel data. The analysis exploits the longitudinal component of the Bank of Italy Survey on Household Income and Wealth for the period 1998-2006. Its results show that, after accounting for unobserved heterogeneity, past values of the outcome variable play a large part in explaining the probability of experiencing financial distress. In addition, the probability of financial vulnerability decreases with income and greater sophistication of the household portfolio and, at least in one of the model specifications, increases in areas with higher unemployment rates. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giarda, Elena</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the forward premium puzzle disappear over the horizon?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Snaith, Stuart; Coakley, Jerry; Kellard, Neil
This paper provides the first comprehensive study of the horizon effect in tests of the forward rate unbiasedness hypothesis. It estimates Fama regressions employing 1-month through to 10-year horizon data for the five most heavily traded US dollar currency pairs pre-crisis 1980-2006. In contrast with extant studies, it fully deals with the econometric problems of long horizon regressions by means of a novel heteroskedastic- and autocorrelation-consistent bootstrap. The regression results confirm a clear horizon effect in that the slope coefficient approaches unity as the forward contract maturity is extended. The puzzle disappears at the 3-year horizon and beyond for all currencies. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Snaith, Stuart; Coakley, Jerry; Kellard, Neil</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks' capital buffer, risk and performance in the Canadian banking system: Impact of business cycles and regulatory changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guidara, Alaa; Lai, Van Son; Soumare, Lssouf; Tchana, Fulbert Tchana
Using quarterly financial statements and stock market data from 1982 to 2010 for the six largest Canadian chartered banks, this paper documents positive co-movement between Canadian banks' capital buffer and business cycles. The adoption of Basel Accords and the balance sheet leverage cap imposed by Canadian banking regulations did not change this cyclical behavior of Canadian bank capital. We find Canadian banks to be well-capitalized and that they hold a larger capital buffer in expansion than in recession, which may explain how they weathered the recent subprime financial crisis so well. This evidence that Canadian banks ride the business and regulatory periods underscores the appropriateness of a both micro- and a macro-prudential "through-the-cycle" approach to capital adequacy as advocated in the proposed Basel III framework to strengthen the resilience of the banking sector. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guidara, Alaa; Lai, Van Son; Soumare, Lssouf; Tchana, Fulbert Tchana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting liquidity-adjusted intraday Value-at-Risk with vine copulas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weiss, Gregor N. F.; Supper, Hendrik
We propose to model the joint distribution of bid-ask spreads and log returns of a stock portfolio by using Autoregressive Conditional Double Poisson and GARCH processes for the marginals and vine copulas for the dependence structure. By estimating the joint multivariate distribution of both returns and bid-ask spreads from intraday data, we incorporate the measurement of commonalities in liquidity and comovements of stocks and bid-ask spreads into the forecasting of three types of liquidity-adjusted intraday Value-at-Risk (L-IVaR). In a preliminary analysis, we document strong extreme comovement's in liquidity and strong tail dependence between bid-ask spreads and log returns across the firms in our sample thus motivating our use of a vine copula model. Furthermore, the backtesting results for the L-IVaR of a portfolio consisting of five stocks listed on the NASDAQ show that the proposed models perform well in forecasting liquidity-adjusted intraday portfolio profits and losses. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Weiss, Gregor N. F.; Supper, Hendrik</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting bear and bull stock markets with dynamic binary time series models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nyberg, Henri
Despite the voluminous empirical research on the potential predictability of stock returns, much less attention has been paid to the predictability of bear and bull stock markets. In this study, the aim is to predict U.S. bear and bull stock markets with dynamic binary time series models. Based on the analysis of the monthly U.S. data set, bear and bull markets are predictable in and out of sample. In particular, substantial additional predictive power can be obtained by allowing for a dynamic structure in the binary response model. Probability forecasts of the state of the stock market can also be utilized to obtain optimal asset allocation decisions between stocks and bonds. It turns out that the dynamic probit models yield much higher portfolio returns than the buy-and-hold trading strategy in a small-scale market timing experiment. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nyberg, Henri</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank ownership, privatization, and performance: Evidence from a transition country</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Chunxia; Yao, Shujie; Feng, Genfu
This paper combines the static effect of ownership and the dynamic effect of privatization on bank performance in China over 1995-2010, reporting a significantly higher performance by private intermediaries - joint stock commercial banks and city commercial banks - relative to state-owned commercial banks. However, publicly traded banks, subject to multiple monitoring and vetting in capital markets, perform better regardless of ownership status. The privatization of banks has improved performance with respect to revenue inflow and efficiency gains in the short- or long-run (initial public offerings). The positive long-run effect is more relevant and. significant for banking institutions with minority foreign ownership. Moreover, this paper innovatively estimates interest income efficiency and non-interest income efficiency at the same time. The results suggest that Chinese banks are much more efficient in generating interest income than raising non-interest revenue, although the latter aspect has improved significantly during the sample period. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Chunxia; Yao, Shujie; Feng, Genfu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are extreme returns priced in the stock market? European evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Annaert, Jan; De Ceuster, Marc; Verstegen, Kurt
This paper revisits some recently found evidence in the literature on the cross-section of stock returns for a carefully constructed dataset of euro area stocks. First, we confirm recent results for US data and find evidence of a negative cross-sectional relation between extreme positive returns and average returns after controlling for characteristics such as momentum, book-to-market, size, liquidity and short term return reversal. We argue that this is the case because these stocks have lottery-like characteristics, which is attractive to certain investors. Also, these stocks tend to be very volatile so that arbitrageurs are discouraged from correcting potential mispricing. As a consequence, these stocks are often overpriced and hence face lower expected returns. Second, when we control for extreme returns, the recently found negative relationship between idiosyncratic risk and future returns is less robust. In our models, after adding maximum returns, the relationship is insignificant and sometimes even positive. We also find that idiosyncratic skewness and coskewness play an important role for asset pricing, as predicted by several theoretical models. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Annaert, Jan; De Ceuster, Marc; Verstegen, Kurt</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does banking competition alleviate or worsen credit constraints faced by small- and medium-sized enterprises? Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chong, Terence Tai-Leung; Lu, Liping; Ongena, Steven
Banking competition may enhance or hinder the financing of small and medium-sized enterprises. Using a survey on the financing of such enterprises in China, combined with detailed bank branch information, we investigate how concentration in local banking market affects the availability of credit. We find that lower market concentration alleviates financing constraints. The widespread presence of joint-stock banks has a larger effect on alleviating these constraints, than the presence of city commercial banks, while the presence of state-owned banks has a smaller effect. Crown Copyright (c) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chong, Terence Tai-Leung; Lu, Liping; Ongena, Steven</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate social responsibility in the banking industry: Motives and financial performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Meng-Wen; Shen, Chung-Hua
The current study investigates the association between corporate social responsibility (CSR) and financial performance (FP), and discusses the driving motives of banks to engage in CSR. Three motives, namely, strategic choices, altruism, and greenwashing, suggest that the relationship between CSR and FP is positive, non-negative, and non-existent, respectively. We obtained our sample, which covered 2003-2009, from the Ethical Investment Research Service (EIRIS) databank and Bankscope database. The data consists of 162 banks in 22 countries. We then classified the banks into four types based on their degree of engagement in CSR. This study proposes the use of an extended version of the Heckman two-step regression, in which the first step adopts a multinomial logit model, and the second step estimates the performance equation with the inverse Mills ratio generated by the first step. The empirical results show that CSR positively associates with FP in terms of return on assets, return on equity, net interest income, and non-interest income. In contrast, CSR negatively associates with non-performing loans. Hence, strategic choice is the primary motive of banks to engage in CSR. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Meng-Wen; Shen, Chung-Hua</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insiders' incentives for asymmetric disclosure and firm-specific information flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Li; Kim, Jeong-Bon; Pang, Lei
Recent research suggests that insiders' incentives for capturing cash flows affect price formation process in which insiders are inclined to withhold good news and to accelerate the release of bad news (Jin and Myers, 2006). We investigate whether insiders' incentives for private control benefit, proxied by control-ownership wedge, affect firm-specific return characteristics. We find that control-ownership wedge is negatively related to the likelihood of positive return jumps and positively related to the extent of asymmetric market reaction to good news rather than to bad news. Overall, our results support the notion that corporate insiders increase opaqueness and withhold good news in order to capture unexpected cash flow. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Li; Kim, Jeong-Bon; Pang, Lei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives the disappearing dividends phenomenon?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuo, Jing-Ming; Philip, Dennis; Zhang, Qingjing
We study the determinants of dividend payout policy and examine the role of liquidity, risk and catering in explaining the changes in propensity to pay. Our results indicate that risk plays a major role in firms' dividend policy. The evidence substantiates from a large sample of firms representing 18 countries over the sample period from 1989 to 2011. For firms in the US, France, UK and Other European markets, liquidity is additionally an important determinant of dividend policy. We find that, although catering incentives persist only among firms in common law countries and not in civil law countries, after adjusting for risk there is little support for catering theory even among firms incorporated in common law countries. Our results indicate that catering incentives reflect the risk-reward relationship in the changing propensity to pay dividends. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kuo, Jing-Ming; Philip, Dennis; Zhang, Qingjing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank regulatory capital and liquidity: Evidence from US and European publicly traded banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Distinguin, Isabelle; Roulet, Caroline; Tarazi, Amine
The theory of financial intermediation highlights various channels through which capital and liquidity are interrelated. Using a simultaneous equations framework, we investigate the relationship between bank regulatory capital and bank liquidity measured from on-balance sheet positions for European and US publicly traded commercial banks. Previous research studying the determinants of bank capital buffer has neglected the role of liquidity. On the whole, we find that banks decrease their regulatory capital ratios when they face higher illiquidity as defined in the Basel III accords or when they create more liquidity as measured by Berger and Bouwman (2009). However, considering other measures of illiquidity that focus more closely on core deposits in the United States, our results show that small banks strengthen their solvency standards when they are exposed to higher illiquidity. Our empirical investigation supports the need to implement minimum liquidity ratios concomitant to capital ratios, as stressed by the Basel Committee; however, our findings also shed light on the need to further clarify how to define and measure illiquidity and also on how to regulate large banking institutions, which behave differently than smaller ones. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Distinguin, Isabelle; Roulet, Caroline; Tarazi, Amine</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The wisdom of crowds: Mutual fund investors' aggregate asset allocation decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chalmers, John; Kaul, Aditya; Phillips, Blake
We find that the aggregate asset allocation decisions of US mutual fund investors depend on economic conditions. Both anticipated economic downturns and periods of turmoil lead investors to direct flow away from risky equity funds and towards lower-risk money market funds. These patterns are markedly stronger for investors in low cost and low turnover funds relative to investors in high cost and high turnover funds, consistent with sophisticated investors being more sensitive to changing conditions. Benchmarked against a buy-and-hold strategy, these asset allocation strategies reduce risk without degrading the risk-return trade-off. Our evidence suggests that individual investors, often dismissed as noise traders, collectively react to economic signals in a sensible manner when determining asset allocations. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chalmers, John; Kaul, Aditya; Phillips, Blake</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility spillovers and the effect of news announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, George J.; Konstantinidi, Eirini; Skiadopoulos, George
We examine the effect of US and European news announcements on the spillover of volatility across US and European stock markets. Using synchronously observed international implied volatility indices at a daily frequency, we find significant spillovers of implied volatility between US and European markets as well as within European markets. We observe a stark contrast in the effect of scheduled versus unscheduled news releases. Scheduled (unscheduled) news releases resolve (create) information uncertainty, leading to a decrease (increase) in implied volatility. Nevertheless, news announcements do not fully explain the volatility spillovers, although they do affect the magnitude of volatility spillovers. Our results are robust to extreme market events such as the recent financial crisis and provide evidence of volatility contagion across markets. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, George J.; Konstantinidi, Eirini; Skiadopoulos, George</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A public good approach to credit ratings - From concept to reality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duan, Jin-Chuan; Van Laere, Elisabeth
From the onset of the 2008-2009 financial crisis to the subsequent European sovereign debt crisis, credit rating agencies have been assigned considerable blame. Reforming the credit rating industry has hence become an important policy issue. In addition to the regulatory efforts in the context of accepting the for-profit business model of ratings, there is a growing realization that credit ratings bear the characteristics of a public good. Financial market participants need reliable, transparent and independent assessment of credit risks. Credit ratings are therefore better viewed as an infrastructure matter. However, the proposed regulations seem to have missed this point. This paper introduces a new approach to credit ratings undertaken by the Risk Management Institute at the National University of Singapore that is predicated on the provision of credit ratings as a public good. With a public good alternative in place, the currently predominant for-profit business model may be counterbalanced. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duan, Jin-Chuan; Van Laere, Elisabeth</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical analysis of marginal conditional stochastic dominance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clark, Ephraim; Kassimatis, Konstantinos
Stochastic dominance is a more general approach to expected utility maximization than the widely accepted mean-variance analysis. However, when applied to portfolios of assets, stochastic dominance rules become too complicated for meaningful empirical analysis, and, thus, its practical relevance has been difficult to establish. This paper develops a framework based on the concept of Marginal Conditional Stochastic Dominance (MCSD), introduced by Shalit and Yitzhaki (1994), to test for the first time the relationship between second order stochastic dominance (SSD) and stock returns. We find evidence that MCSD is a significant determinant of stock returns. Our results are robust with respect to the most popular pricing models. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Clark, Ephraim; Kassimatis, Konstantinos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of bank loan recovery rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khieu, Hinh D.; Mullineaux, Donald J.; Yi, Ha-Chin
Using Moody's Ultimate Recovery Database, we estimate a model for bank loan recoveries using variables reflecting loan and borrower characteristics, industry and macroeconomic conditions, and several recovery process variables. We find that loan characteristics are more significant determinants of recovery rates than are borrower characteristics prior to default. Industry and macroeconomic conditions are relevant, as are prepackaged bankruptcy arrangements. We examine whether a commonly used proxy for recovery rates, the 30-day post-default trading price of the loan, represents an efficient estimate of actual recoveries and find that such a proxy is biased and inefficient. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khieu, Hinh D.; Mullineaux, Donald J.; Yi, Ha-Chin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are two heads better than one? Evidence from the thrift crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Byrd, John; Fraser, Donald R.; Lee, D. Scott; Tartaroglu, Semih
We employ a natural experiment from the 1980s, predating the ubiquitous clamor for independence influenced corporate governance structures, to examine which governance mechanisms are associated with firm survival and failure. We find that thrifts were more likely to survive the thrift crisis when their CEO also chaired the firm's board of directors. On average, chair-holding CEOs undertook less aggressive lending policies than their counterparts who did not chair their boards. Consequently, taxpayer interests were protected by thrifts that bestowed both leadership posts to one person. This is an important policy issue, because taxpayers become the residual claimants for depository institutions that fail as a result of managers adopting risky strategies to exploit underpriced deposit insurance. Our findings corroborate recent evidence that manager-dominated firms resist shareholder pressure to adopt riskier investment strategies to exploit underpriced deposit insurance. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Byrd, John; Fraser, Donald R.; Lee, D. Scott; Tartaroglu, Semih</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio selection with mental accounts and background risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baptista, Alexandre M.
Das et al. (2010) develop a model where an investor divides his or her wealth among mental accounts with motives such as retirement and bequest. Nevertheless, the investor ends up selecting portfolios within mental accounts and an aggregate portfolio that lie on the mean-variance frontier. Importantly, they assume that the investor only faces portfolio risk. In practice, however, many individuals also face background risk. Accordingly, our paper expands upon theirs by considering the case where the investor faces background risk. Our contribution is threefold. First, we provide an analytical characterization of the existence and composition of the optimal portfolios within accounts and the aggregate portfolio. Second, we show that these portfolios lie away from the mean-variance frontier under fairly general conditions. Third, we find that the composition and location of such portfolios can differ notably from those of portfolios on the mean-variance frontier. (C) 2011 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baptista, Alexandre M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment timing under debt issuance constraint</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shibata, Takashi; Nishihara, Michi
This paper examines the optimal investment timing decision problem of a firm subject to a debt financing capacity constraint. We show that the investment thresholds have a U-shaped relation with the debt capacity constraint, in that they are increasing (decreasing) with the constraint for high (low) debt issuance capacity. Although the financing constraint distorts investment timing, it may encourage the constrained levered firm to overinvest compared with the non-constrained levered firm. Our result fits well with the related problems involving the internal financing constraint. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shibata, Takashi; Nishihara, Michi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic and bank-specific determinants of non-performing loans in Greece: A comparative study of mortgage, business and consumer loan portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Louzis, Dimitrios P.; Vouldis, Angelos T.; Metaxas, Vasilios L.
This paper uses dynamic panel data methods to examine the determinants of non-performing loans (NPLs) in the Greek banking sector, separately for each loan category (consumer loans, business loans and mortgages). The study is motivated by the hypothesis that both macroeconomic and bank-specific variables have an effect on loan quality and that these effects vary between different loan categories. The results show that, for all loan categories, NPLs in the Greek banking system can be explained mainly by macroeconomic variables (GDP, unemployment, interest rates, public debt) and management quality. Differences in the quantitative impact of macroeconomic factors among loan categories are evident, with non-performing mortgages being the least responsive to changes in the macroeconomic conditions. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Louzis, Dimitrios P.; Vouldis, Angelos T.; Metaxas, Vasilios L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploring the role of the realized return distribution in the formation of the implied volatility smile</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chalamandaris, Georgios; Rompolis, Leonidas S.
This article explores the role of the realized return distribution in the formation of the observed implied volatility smile using the framework of an adaptive expectations model. According to this framework investors update their expectations of future events, through which options are priced, by incorporating information from the underlying asset traded in the spot market. Our study is conducted at the level of cumulants which provide a complete description of investors expectations and can be considered as largely non-parametric with a minimal set of assumptions for the stochastic process that drives asset returns. The empirical results, based on the S&amp;P 500 index, support the significance of the realized distribution in the formation of the implied volatility smile. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chalamandaris, Georgios; Rompolis, Leonidas S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical evidence of the value of monitoring in joint ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mantecon, Tomas; Liu, Ian; Gao, Fei
Joint ownership of assets by two partners can have an adverse effect on the incentives to invest and can result in unstable and inefficient organizational structures. Control sharing, however, plays an important role in economic, political, and social institutions. There is scarce empirical evidence on the benefits of joint ownership in corporate finance. We analyze acquisitions of corporate assets by joint ventures to empirically ascertain the value of joint ownership in economic activities. The results indicate that firms experience significantly larger returns in joint acquisitions than in full-control acquisitions and that this difference is restricted to the sample of firms in which both partners share equal ownership in the target. These findings suggest that monitoring in joint ownership structures ameliorates the possibility of value-destroying corporate decisions. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mantecon, Tomas; Liu, Ian; Gao, Fei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of cross-sectional regression tests of the CAPM with non-zero pricing errors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murtazashvili, Irina; Vozlyublennaia, Nadia
We show that in the presence of non-zero pricing errors, the Fama-MacBeth (FM) cross-sectional regression test is very likely to either reject the Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM) when it (almost) holds or accept the model when it grossly fails. We investigate the case when pricing errors are correlated with betas and demonstrate that the test performance depends crucially on the correlation, cross-sectional distribution of betas, and several other parameter values. Even when the CAPM holds exactly (pricing errors are zero) the FM test is equally likely to either reject or accept the model when typical sample sizes are used. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Murtazashvili, Irina; Vozlyublennaia, Nadia</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The alpha and omega of fund of hedge fund added value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Darolles, Serge; Vaissie, Mathieu
In spite of a somewhat disappointing performance throughout the crisis, investors are showing interest in hedge funds. Still, funds of hedge funds keep on experiencing outflows. Can this phenomenon be explained by the failure of fund of hedge fund managers to deliver on their promise to add value through active management, or is it symptomatic of a move toward greater disintermediation in the hedge fund industry? We introduce a return-based attribution model allowing for a full decomposition of fund of hedge fund performance. The results of our empirical study suggest that funds of hedge funds are funds of funds like others. Strategic allocation turns out to be a crucial step in the investment process, in that it not only adds value over the long-term, but most importantly, it brings resilience precisely when investors need it the most. Fund picking, on the other hand, turns out to be a double-edged sword. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Darolles, Serge; Vaissie, Mathieu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm location and corporate debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arena, Matteo P.; Dewally, Michael
This study examines the influence of a firm's geographical location on corporate debt and provides evidence that the higher cost of collecting information on firms distant from urban areas has significant implications on a wide array of corporate debt characteristics. We find that rural firms face higher debt yield spreads and attract smaller and less prestigious bank syndicates than urban firms. Rural firms attempt to reduce their informational disadvantage by relying more on relationship banking. Our results on the effect of location on corporate debt are robust to the inclusion of an extensive set of firm and issue characteristics. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arena, Matteo P.; Dewally, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Correlation in credit risk changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pu, Xiaoling; Zhao, Xinlei
The current economic climate makes understanding credit risk correlation particularly important. After allowing for a comprehensive set of observable firm-specific, industry, market, and macroeconomic factors, there is an economically significant co-movement in credit default swap spreads that remains to be explained. Including a time dummy completely accounts for the remaining co-movement, confirming the existence of a systematic component that has been previously unaccounted for. Our findings suggest that it may be important to consider unobservable risk factor(s) in credit risk models. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Pu, Xiaoling; Zhao, Xinlei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-sectional performance and investor sentiment in a multiple risk factor model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Dave; Turtle, H. J.
Economists have long recognized the importance of information veracity in valuing risky securities. Market participants concerned about the credibility of information measures may require additional compensation to entice them to hold stocks with less transparent information. These same securities are expected to display greater sensitivities to measures of market sentiment. We find that investor sentiment sensitivities increase directly with multiple measures of opacity in the cross-section. Next we examine the extent to which sentiment sensitivities are priced in an asset pricing context. Using the Jha et al. (2009) model of conditional performance evaluation, we find an inverse relation between ex ante known investor sentiment and the marginal performance of opaque stocks. In contrast, translucent stocks exhibit relatively little variability in performance across levels of sentiment. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Dave; Turtle, H. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coincident correlations of growth and cash flow in banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahl, Drew
Prior empirical research indicates that loan growth in the banking industry is positively related to cash flow. I offer an alternative methodology that is better able to capture the effect of cash flow on loan growth while controlling for the potentially coincident effect of loan growth on cash flow. Using a sample of 171,389 observations on banks, 1986-2007, I find that causality runs more consistently from growth to cash flow than from cash flow to growth. This extends prior empirical research by Houston and James (1998) and Campello (2002) on cash flow sensitivities in the banking industry. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dahl, Drew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling and measuring intraday overreaction of stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kloessner, Stefan; Becker, Martin; Friedmann, Ralph
We introduce a model for stock prices consisting of a fundamental price process and a news impact curve, which allows for either overreaction, underreaction, or correct response to changes of the fundamental value. We further develop statistics based on OHLC data, which separately measure upside and downside overreaction. The distribution of these statistics under the hypothesis of correct response and fundamental prices following Brownian motions is used to derive tests for upside and downside overreaction. We show that more realistic and frequently used fundamental price processes with correct response leave the distribution of the test statistics widely unaffected or lead to conservative tests. Empirical application to different stock markets provides strong evidence for intraday overreaction, particularly to bad news. The economic significance of the discrimination induced by the proposed statistics is further illustrated by analyzing the performance of a simple buy on bad news strategy. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kloessner, Stefan; Becker, Martin; Friedmann, Ralph</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional investment horizon and investment-cash flow sensitivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Attig, Najah; Cleary, Sean; El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane
This paper examines the relevance of institutional investors' investment horizon, as reflected in the response of firm investment to internal cash flows. We argue that institutional investors with longer investment horizons have greater incentives and efficiencies to engage in effective monitoring. This improved monitoring mitigates asymmetric information and agency problems, and in turn reduces the wedge between the costs of internal and external funds. As a result, the sensitivity of firms' investment outlays to internal cash flows decreases in the presence of institutional investors with long-term investment horizons. Using a sample of 8402 US firms over the period 1981-2008, we provide empirical evidence consistent with these arguments. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Attig, Najah; Cleary, Sean; El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncovering the US term premium: An alternative route</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gil-Alana, Luis A.; Moreno, Antonio
The estimates of the US term premium crucially depend upon the ex-ante decision on whether the short-term rate is either an I(0) or an I(1) process. In this paper we estimate a fractionally integrated (I(d)) model which simultaneously determines both the order of integration of the short-term rate and the associated term premium. We show that the term premium experienced a sharp increase from essentially zero in mid-2007 to almost 3% in 2009. We also show that unemployment and term premium dynamics exhibit a very significant positive co-movement. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gil-Alana, Luis A.; Moreno, Antonio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does being your bank's neighbor matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana
This paper provides new evidence on the role of distance between banks and borrowers in bank lending. We argue that delegated monitors face higher costs of collecting information about nonlocal borrowers due to the difficulty of obtaining and verifying soft information over distances. Further, the higher information collection and monitoring costs associated with distance should be reflected in loan terms. Empirically, loan spreads are increasing in the distance between borrowers and lenders. Finally, banks are more likely to include covenant provisions or require collateral when lending to borrowers located far away. (C) 2011 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Closing and cloning in open-end mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hsiu-Lang; Gao, Sheldon; Hu, Xiaoqing
Using a unique dataset, we document that only those closed funds for which no new fund is subsequently launched continuously deliver positive abnormal returns. This suggests the existence of an optimal fund scale. In spite of the potential diseconomies of scale, a non-trivial proportion of closed funds have new funds cloned-the scale motive would not be a complete explanation for the closure. When managers of closed funds clone new funds, they receive greater public attention and thus can attract more fund flows and charge higher fees. Furthermore, better-performing closed fund managers attract more fund flows to their new siblings, making the closure an effective mechanism to extract economic rents. Overall, we find that closing and cloning is an attractive strategy for funds seeking to increase their management fees and funds with more managers in place. Aspects of the closed fund family also affect the launch decision of new siblings. (C) 2011 Elsevier By. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Hsiu-Lang; Gao, Sheldon; Hu, Xiaoqing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bouncing out of the banking system: An empirical analysis of involuntary bank account closures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, Dennis; Martinez-Jerez, F. Asis; Tufano, Peter
Using a new database, we document the determinants of involuntary consumer bank account closures. During 2001-2005, approximately 30 million debit accounts were involuntarily closed for excessive over-drafting. We focus on multiple factors to explain this phenomenon: household economics and financial decision-making ability, social capital, bank policies, and the alternative financial services sector. Involuntary closures are more frequent in US counties with a larger fraction of single mothers, lower education levels, lower wealth, and higher unemployment. Closures are higher in communities with high property crime rates and low electoral participation. Bank policies have an independent relation to closures, with counties having more competitive banking markets and more multi-market banks experiencing higher closure rates; bank structure also seems to affect the speed at which banks adjust their policies to changes in household income. Finally, using both national data and a state-level shift in regulation, we find evidence that access to payday lending leads to higher rates of involuntary account closure. (C) 2011 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campbell, Dennis; Martinez-Jerez, F. Asis; Tufano, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large shareholder diversification, corporate risk taking, and the benefits of changing to differential voting rights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauguess, Scott W.; Slovin, Myron B.; Sushka, Marie E.
We show how the change to differential voting rights allows dominant shareholders to retain control even after selling substantial economic ownership in the firm and diversifying their wealth. This unbundling of cash flow and control rights leads to more dispersed economic ownership and a closer alignment of dominant and dispersed shareholder interests. When insiders sell sizeable amounts of their economic interests, firms increase capital expenditures, strengthen corporate focus, divest non-core operations, and generate superior industry-adjusted performance. The change to differential voting rights both fosters corporate control activity and creates higher takeover premiums that are paid equally to all shareholders. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bauguess, Scott W.; Slovin, Myron B.; Sushka, Marie E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A careful re-examination of seasonality in international stock markets: Comment on sentiment and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamstra, Mark J.; Kramer, Lisa A.; Levi, Maurice D.
In questioning Kamstra. Kramer, and Levi's (2003) finding of an economically and statistically significant seasonal affective disorder (SAD) effect, Kelly and Meschke (2010) make errors of commission and omission. They misrepresent their empirical results, claiming that the SAD effect arises due to a "mechanically induced" effect that is non-existent, labeling the SAD effect a "turn-of-year" effect (when in fact their models and ours separately control for turn-of-year effects), and ignoring coefficient-estimate patterns that strongly support the SAD effect. Our analysis of their data shows, even using their low-power statistical tests, there is significant international evidence supporting the SAD effect. Employing modern, panel/time-series statistical methods strengthens the case dramatically. Additionally, Kelly and Meschke represent the finance, psychology, and medical literatures in misleading ways, describing some findings as opposite to those reported by the researchers themselves, and choosing selective quotes that could easily lead readers to a distorted understanding of these findings. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kamstra, Mark J.; Kramer, Lisa A.; Levi, Maurice D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings conference calls and stock returns: The incremental informativeness of textual tone</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Price, S. McKay; Doran, James S.; Peterson, David R.; Bliss, Barbara A.
Quarterly earnings conference calls are becoming a more pervasive tool for corporate disclosure. However, the extent to which the market embeds information contained in the tone (i.e. sentiment) of conference call wording is unknown. Using computer aided content analysis, we examine the incremental informativeness of quarterly earnings conference calls and the corresponding market reaction. We find that conference call linguistic tone is a significant predictor of abnormal returns and trading volume. Furthermore, conference call tone dominates earnings surprises over the 60 trading days following the call. The question and answer portion of the call has incremental explanatory power for the post-earnings-announcement drift and this significance is primarily concentrated in firms that do not pay dividends, illustrating differences in investor behavior based on the level of cash flow uncertainty. Additionally, we find that a context specific linguistic dictionary is more powerful than a more widely used general dictionary (Harvard IV-4 Psychosocial). (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Price, S. McKay; Doran, James S.; Peterson, David R.; Bliss, Barbara A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do CEOs gain more in foreign acquisitions than domestic acquisitions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozkan, Neslihan
This paper examines the impact of domestic and foreign acquisitions on chief executive officer (CEO) compensation packages using a sample of 147 completed bids by UK companies from 1999 to 2005. We find that foreign acquisitions lead to higher CEO compensation than domestic acquisitions. Overall, our findings suggest that CEOs have strong incentives to do foreign acquisitions rather than domestic acquisitions since they receive larger compensation following a foreign acquisition regardless of how poor firm performance is. Furthermore, we observe a positive and significant relation between CEO compensation and firm size during the pre-acquisition period for firms involved in foreign acquisitions, thus their CEOs would expect to increase their compensation package through foreign acquisitions. However, our results show that there is no significant link between firm size and CEO compensation during the pre-acquisition period for firms involved in domestic acquisitions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ozkan, Neslihan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Historical evidence on the finance-trade-growth nexus</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bordo, Michael D.; Rousseau, Peter L.
We study linkages between financial development, international trade, and long-run growth using data since 1880 for 17 now-developed "Atlantic" economies and a set of cross country and dynamic panel data models. We find that finance and trade reinforce each other in data before 1930, but that these effects do not persist after the Second World War. Financial development affects growth positively throughout the sample period, while trade affects growth strongly and independently after 1945. We attribute the rising importance of trade to major post-World War II changes in tariffs and quantity restrictions associated with the GATT, the establishment of the European Common Market, and the gradual elimination of capital controls after 1973. The findings are robust to the use of 'deep' fundamentals such as legal origin and indicators of the political environment as instruments for financial development and trade. Financial development, however, links more closely than trade to these fundamentals. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bordo, Michael D.; Rousseau, Peter L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Form versus substance: The effect of ownership structure and corporate governance on firm value in Thailand</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Connelly, J. Thomas; Limpaphayom, Piman; Nagarajan, Nandu J.
We examine the relation between the quality of corporate governance practices and firm value for Thai firms, which often have complex ownership structures. We develop a comprehensive measure of corporate governance and show that, in contrast to conventional measures of corporate governance, our measurement, on average, is positively associated with Tobin's q. Furthermore, we find that q values are lower for firms that exhibit deviations between cash flow rights and voting rights. We also find that the value benefits of complying with "good" corporate governance practices are nullified in the presence of pyramidal ownership structures, raising doubts on the effectiveness of governance measures when ownership structures are not transparent. We conclude that family control of firms through pyramidal ownership structures can allow firms to seemingly comply with preferred governance practices but also use the control to their advantage. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Connelly, J. Thomas; Limpaphayom, Piman; Nagarajan, Nandu J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Keep on smiling? The pricing of Quanto options when all covariances are stochastic</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branger, Nicole; Muck, Matthias
The paper introduces a model for the joint dynamics of asset prices which can capture both a stochastic correlation between stock returns as well as between stock returns and volatilities (stochastic leverage). By relying on two factors for stochastic volatility, the model allows for stochastic leverage and is thus able to explain time-varying slopes of the smiles. The use of Wishart processes for the covariance matrix of returns enables the model to also capture stochastic correlations between the assets. Our model offers an integrated pricing approach for both Quanto and plain-vanilla options on the stock as well as the foreign exchange rate. We derive semi-closed form solutions for option prices and analyze the impact of state variables. Quanto options offer a significant exposure to the stochastic covariance between stock prices and exchange rates. In contrast to standard models, the smile of stock options, the smile of currency options, and the price differences between Quanto options and plain-vanilla options can change independently of each other. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Branger, Nicole; Muck, Matthias</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coinsurance effect and bank lines of credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tong, Zhenxu
The coinsurance effect hypothesis predicts that firm diversification reduces financial constraints through imperfectly correlated cash flows among segments. We empirically test the hypothesis by studying the relation between coinsurance effect and bank lines of credit. We find that coinsurance effect is associated with a higher availability of bank lines of credit, and that diversified firms hold a higher level of bank lines of credit if they have higher investment opportunities and if they are bank-dependent. We find that diversified firms hold a higher fraction of corporate liquidity in the form of bank lines of credit due to the coinsurance effect. The findings are consistent with the coinsurance effect hypothesis and contribute to the debate on the value consequence of firm diversification by disclosing a specific channel through which firm diversification affects financial constraints. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tong, Zhenxu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio credit-risk optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iscoe, Ian; Kreinin, Alexander; Mausser, Helmut; Romanko, Oleksandr
This paper evaluates several alternative formulations for minimizing the credit risk of a portfolio of financial contracts with different counterparties. Credit risk optimization is challenging because the portfolio loss distribution is typically unavailable in closed form. This makes it difficult to accurately compute Value-at-Risk (VaR) and expected shortfall (ES) at the extreme quantiles that are of practical interest to financial institutions. Our formulations all exploit the conditional independence of counterparties under a structural credit risk model. We consider various approximations to the conditional portfolio loss distribution and formulate VaR and ES minimization problems for each case. We use two realistic credit portfolios to assess the in- and out-of-sample performance for the resulting VaR- and ES-optimized portfolios, as well as for those which we obtain by minimizing the variance or the second moment of the portfolio losses. We find that a Normal approximation to the conditional loss distribution performs best from a practical standpoint. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Iscoe, Ian; Kreinin, Alexander; Mausser, Helmut; Romanko, Oleksandr</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market power and reputational concerns in the ratings industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mariano, Beatriz
This paper studies the incentives of rating agencies to reveal the information that they obtain about their client firms. In the model, rating agencies seek to maximize their reputation and protect their market power. They observe public information and obtain either precise or noisy private information about a firm. Reputational concerns dictate that a rating reflects private information when it is precise. However, when private information is noisy, two situations arise. In a monopoly, the rating agency may ignore private information and issue a rating that conforms to public information. Under some conditions, it may even become cautious and issue bad ratings ignoring both types of information. With competition, however, it has incentives to contradict public information as a way to pretend that it holds precise private information. Moreover, it may become more likely to issue good ratings in an attempt to protect market power. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mariano, Beatriz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The home-institution bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McQueen, Grant; Stenkrona, Anders
We document a new investor preference we call the home-institution bias. Whereas the home-asset bias is a preference for domestic assets, the home-institution bias is a preference for domestic financial institutions. Our data come from Sweden's government-mandated retirement system. In cross-fund regressions, we find that funds offered by Swedish institutions received around 10 times more money than similar funds offered by foreign institutions. We show that this preference for home institutions is distinct from the home-asset preference, is not driven by information asymmetries, and is consistent with an underlying preference by individuals to deal with the familiar. Cross-individual regressions also support a behavioral explanation because the home-institution bias is strongest among financially-unsophisticated and provincial investors. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McQueen, Grant; Stenkrona, Anders</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenizing exogenous default barrier models: The MM algorithm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Forte, Santiago; Lovreta, Lidija
In this paper, we propose a Maximization-Maximization (MM) algorithm for the assessment of hidden parameters in structural credit risk models. Step M1 updates the value, volatility, and expected return on the firm's assets by maximizing the log-likelihood function for the time series of equity prices; Step M2 updates the default barrier by maximizing the equity holders' participation in the firm's asset value. The main contribution of the method lies in the M2 step, which allows for 'endogenizing' the default barrier in light of actual data on equity prices. Using a large international sample of companies, we demonstrate that theoretical credit spreads based on the MM algorithm offer the lowest CDS pricing errors when compared to other, traditional default barrier specifications: smooth-pasting condition value, maximum likelihood estimate, KMV's default point, and nominal debt. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Forte, Santiago; Lovreta, Lidija</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuing and pricing IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roosenboom, Peter
This paper investigates how underwriters set the IPO firm's fair value, an ex-ante estimate of the market value, using a unique dataset of 228 reports from French underwriters. These reports are issued before the IPO shares start trading on the stock market and detail how underwriters determined fair value. We document that underwriters often employ multiples valuation, dividend discount models and discounted cash flow (DCF) analysis to determine fair value but that all of these valuation methods suffer from a positive bias with respect to equilibrium market value. We also analyze how this fair value estimate is subsequently used as a basis for IPO pricing. We report that underwriters deliberately discount the fair value estimate when setting the preliminary offer price. Part of the intentional price discount can be recovered by higher price updates. We find that, controlling for other factors such as investor demand, part of underpricing stems from this intentional price discount. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roosenboom, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the risk-return trade-off in loan portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mencia, Javier
This paper proposes a methodology to analyse the risk and return of large loan portfolios in a joint setting. I propose a tractable model to obtain the distribution of loan returns from observed interest rates and default frequencies. I follow a sectoral approach that captures the heterogeneous cyclical features of different kinds of loans and yields moments in closed form. I investigate the validity of mean-variance analysis with a value at risk constraint and study its relationship with utility maximisation. Finally, I study the efficiency of corporate and household loan portfolios in an empirical application to the Spanish banking system. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mencia, Javier</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing with Second-Order Esscher Transforms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Monfort, Alain; Pegoraro, Fulvio
The purpose of the paper is to introduce, in a discrete-time no-arbitrage pricing context, a bridge between the historical and the risk-neutral state vector dynamics which is wider than the one implied by a classical exponential-affine stochastic discount factor (SDF) and to preserve, at the same time, the tractability and flexibility of the associated asset pricing model. This goal is achieved by introducing the notion of exponential-quadratic SDF or, equivalently, the notion of Second-Order Esscher Transform. The log-pricing kernel is specified as a quadratic function of the factor and the associated sources of risk are priced by means of possibly non-linear stochastic first-order and second-order risk-correction coefficients. Focusing on security market models, this approach is developed in the multivariate conditionally Gaussian framework and its usefulness is testified by the specification and calibration of what we name the Second-Order GARCH Option Pricing Model. The associated European Call option pricing formula generates a rich family of implied volatility smiles and skews able to match the typically observed ones. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Monfort, Alain; Pegoraro, Fulvio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Countercyclical contingent capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barucci, Emilio; Del Viva, Luca
We analyze the optimal capital structure of a bank issuing countercyclical contingent capital, i.e., notes to be converted into common shares in poor macroeconomic conditions. A comparison of the main effects produced by the countercyclical asset with the simple equity-debt capital structure, the non-countercyclical contingent capital and the countercyclical callable bond is conducted. We demonstrate that this type of asset reduces the spread of straight debt and is effective in reducing the asset substitution incentive. The reduction of bankruptcy costs is strong only when the countercyclicality feature is removed. Contingent capital is useful for macroprudential regulation and we show that the countercyclical feature is important depending on priorities (moderate the asset substitution incentive or reduce bankruptcy costs). (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barucci, Emilio; Del Viva, Luca</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment policy in family controlled fims</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Ronald C.; Duru, Augustine; Reeb, David M.
We explore the relation between family ownership and corporate investment policy. Our analysis centers on two incentives, risk aversion and extended investment horizons, which potentially influence the level and type of investments that family firms undertake. We find that family firms devote less capital to long-term investments than firms with diffuse ownership structures. When dividing long-term investment into its two components of R&amp;D and capital expenditures, we note that family firms, relative to nonfamily firms, prefer investing in physical assets relative to riskier R&amp;D projects. Additional tests indicate that family firms receive fewer patent citations per dollar of R&amp;D investment relative to nonfamily firms. Overall, all empirical results indicate that family preferences for lower firm risk, across all family sub-types, affects corporate R&amp;D spending and capital expenditures. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anderson, Ronald C.; Duru, Augustine; Reeb, David M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information demand and stock market volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vlastakis, Nikolaos; Markellos, Raphael N.
We study information demand and supply at the firm and market level using data for 30 of the largest stocks traded on NYSE and NASDAQ. Demand is approximated in a novel manner from weekly internet search volume time series drawn from the recently released Google Trends database. Our paper makes contributions in four main directions. First, although information demand and supply tend to be positively correlated, their dynamic interactions do not allow conclusive inferences about the information discovery process. Second, demand for information at the market level is significantly positively related to historical and implied measures of volatility and to trading volume, even after controlling for market return and information supply. Third, information demand increases significantly during periods of higher returns. Fourth. analysis of the expected variance risk premium confirms for the first time empirically the hypothesis that investors demand more information as their level of risk aversion increases. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vlastakis, Nikolaos; Markellos, Raphael N.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of foreign bank presence on firm entry and exit in transition economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Havrylchyk, Olena
This study investigates the impact of foreign bank penetration on firm entry in Central and Eastern Europe. Acquisition of domestic banks by foreign investors has lowered rates of firm creation, decreased the average size of entrants, and increased firm exit in industries with greater informational opacity, while entry of greenfield foreign banks appears to have spurred firm creation and exit. We modify the view in earlier studies that informational opacity equates with firm size, defining opacity in terms of technological characteristics for a given industry. We find the economic significance of foreign bank entry is larger for opaque industries than industries with large shares of small firms. The study provides evidence of increased credit constraints for start-ups in Central and Eastern Europe which is consistent with the theoretical proposition that the presence of foreign banks exacerbates informational asymmetries. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Havrylchyk, Olena</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The flow-performance relationship around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Keswani, Aneel; Miguel, Antonio F.; Ramos, Sofia B.
We use a new dataset to study how mutual fund flows depend on past performance across 28 countries. We show that there are marked differences in the flow-performance relationship across countries, suggesting that US findings concerning its shape do not apply universally. We find that mutual fund investors sell losers more and buy winners less in more developed countries. This is because investors in more developed countries are more sophisticated and face lower costs of participating in the mutual fund industry. Higher country-level convexity is positively associated with higher levels of risk taking by fund managers. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Keswani, Aneel; Miguel, Antonio F.; Ramos, Sofia B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting the empirical linkages between stock returns and trading volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Shiu-Sheng
This paper investigates whether the empirical linkages between stock returns and trading volume differ over the fluctuations of stock markets, i.e., whether the return-volume relation is asymmetric in bull and bear stock markets. Using monthly data for the S&amp;P 500 price index and trading volume from 1973M2 to 2008M10, strong evidence of asymmetry in contemporaneous correlation is found. As for a dynamic (causal) relation, it is found that the stock return is capable of predicting trading volume in both bear and bull markets. However, the evidence for trade volume predicting returns is weaker. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Shiu-Sheng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do investment banks listen to their own analysts?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jordan, Bradford D.; Liu, Mark H.; Wu, Qun
To what extent conflicts of interest affect the investment value of sell-side analyst research is an ongoing debate. We approach this issue from a new direction by investigating how asset-management divisions of investment banks use stock recommendations issued by their own analysts. Based on holdings changes around initiations, upgrades, and downgrades from 1993 to 2003, we find that these bank-affiliated investors follow recommendations from sell-side analysts in general, increasing (decreasing) their relative holdings following positive (negative) recommendations. More importantly, these investors respond more strongly to recommendations issued by their own analysts than to those issued by analysts affiliated with other banks, especially for recommendations on small and low-analyst-coverage firms. Thus, we find that investment banks "eat their own cooking," showing that these presumably sophisticated institutional investors view sell-side recommendations as having investment value, particularly when the recommendations come from their own analysts. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jordan, Bradford D.; Liu, Mark H.; Wu, Qun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Granularity adjustment for default risk factor model with cohorts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gourieroux, C.; Jasiak, J.
This paper examines granularity adjustments to parameter estimators in a default risk model with cohorts. The model is an extension of the Vasicek model (Vasicek, 1991) and includes a general factor and cohort specific factors. The granularity adjustments derived in the paper concern the mean and/or the variance of observed default frequencies and are easy to implement in practice. For illustration, the method is applied to the S&amp;P corporate ratings. The Granularity Adjusted (GA) estimators are compared to the unadjusted estimators in terms of their asymptotic properties and in finite sample. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gourieroux, C.; Jasiak, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did investors outsource their risk analysis to rating agencies? Evidence from ABS-CDOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maehlmann, Thomas
Based on a sample of 3254 floating rate tranches from 617 ABS-CDOs (collateralized debt obligations backed by asset-backed securities), this paper tests the "rating overdependence" hypothesis - i.e., that ratings of structured products are a sufficient statistic (in terms of predicting future credit performance) for yield spreads at origination. The paper's findings are fourfold. First, yield spreads at issuance predict future performance of ABS-CDO tranches even after controlling for the information contained in ratings. Second, the ability of yield spreads to predict future performance, however, is driven exclusively by ratings below AAA (and, to a lesser extent, also by the lowest priority AAA tranches), whereas spreads of super senior AAA tranches show no information content. Third, the predictive ability of yield spreads is lower for tranches from later vintages and for tranches from deals with more complex collateral pools. Fourth, the conditional correlation between ratings and spreads, in turn, is increasing in time and higher for tranches from complex deals. In sum, the evidence indicates that investors in (especially AAA) tranches from later and more complex deals have avoided performing costly due diligence on the securities they bought. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maehlmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme downside risk and expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Wei; Liu, Qianqiu; Rhee, S. Ghon; Wu, Feng
We propose a measure for extreme downside risk (EDR) to investigate whether bearing such a risk is rewarded by higher expected stock returns. By constructing an EDR proxy with the left tail index in the classical generalized extreme value distribution, we document a significantly positive EDR premium in cross-section of stock returns even after controlling for market, size, value, momentum, and liquidity effects. The EDR premium is more prominent among glamor stocks and when high market returns are expected. High-EDR stocks are generally characterized by high idiosyncratic risk, large downside beta, lower coskewness and cokurtosis, and high bankruptcy risk. The EDR premium persists after these characteristics are controlled for. Although Value at Risk (VaR) plays a significant role in explaining the EDR premium, it cannot completely subsume the EDR effect. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Wei; Liu, Qianqiu; Rhee, S. Ghon; Wu, Feng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subprime mortgage design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhardwaj, Geetesh; Sengupta, Rajdeep
This paper offers evidence on the design of subprime mortgages as bridge-financing products. We show that the viability of subprime mortgages was uniquely predicated on the appreciation of house prices over short horizons. High rates of early prepayments on subprime mortgages suggest the use of prepayments as an exit option. This paper argues that high early defaults on post-2004 originations can be explained when one considers high early prepayment rates for pre-2004 originations. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhardwaj, Geetesh; Sengupta, Rajdeep</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>