<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF17</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Functional gradient descent for financial time series with an application to the measurement of market risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Audrino, F.; Barone-Adesi, G.
The estimation and forecast of the volatility matrix are two of the main tasks of financial econometrics since they are essential ingredients in many practical applications. Unfortunately the use of classical multivariate methods in large dimensions is difficult because of the curse of dimensionality. We present a general semiparametric technique, based on functional gradient descent (FGD) and able to overcome most problems associated with a multivariate GARCH-type estimation. By testing the accuracy of the volatility estimates for the measurement of market risk on real data we provide empirical evidence of the strong predictive potential of the FGD approach, also in comparison to other standard methods. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Audrino, F.; Barone-Adesi, G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sensitivity analysis of VaR and Expected Shortfall for portfolios under netting agreements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fermanian, J. D.; Scaillet, O.
In this paper, we characterize explicitly the first derivative of the Value at Risk and the Expected Shortfall with respect to portfolio allocations when netting between positions exists. As a particular case, we examine a simple Gaussian example in order to illustrate the impact or netting agreements in credit risk management. Collateral issues are also dealt with. For practical purposes we further provide nonparametric estimators for sensitivities and derive their asymptotic distributions. An empirical application on a typical banking portfolio is finally provided. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fermanian, J. D.; Scaillet, O.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Migration correlation: Definition and efficient estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gagliardini, P.; Gourieroux, C.
The aim of this paper is to explain why cross-sectional estimated migration correlations displayed in the academic and professional literature can be either not consistent, or inefficient, and to discuss alternative approaches. The analysis relies on a model with stochastic migration in which the parameters of interest, that are migration correlations, are precisely defined. The impossibility of estimating consistently the migration correlations from cross-sectional data only is emphasized. We explain how to handle with individual rating histories, how to weight appropriately the cross-sectional estimators and how to estimate efficiently the joint migration probabilities at longer horizons. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gagliardini, P.; Gourieroux, C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to the symposium issue</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wachtel, P.
nan</description><author>Wachtel, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who pays for bank insolvency in transition and emerging economies?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mayes, D. G.
This paper explores the equity of the way losses from bank insolvencies and their avoidance through intervention by the authorities have been distributed over creditors, depositors, owners and the population at large in transition and emerging economies. It suggests a number of regulatory reforms that would alter the balance between seeking to avoid insolvency and lowering the costs of insolvency should it occur. It considers whether a lex specialis for dealing with problem banks by prompt corrective action and if necessary resolving them if their net worth falls to zero, at little or no cost to the taxpayer can be applied in the circumstances of transition and emerging economies. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mayes, D. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking crises and the design of safety nets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoggarth, G.; Jackson, P.; Nier, E.
Governments face conflicting objectives in terms of the provision and design of safety nets for banking systems. Safety nets may reduce market discipline and can thus increase the likelihood of a banking crisis. But safety nets are adopted because of the perceived benefits they will confer in either preventing a weak banking system from spilling over into a full-blown crisis or in enabling the government to handle a crisis more effectively. This paper provides evidence on the effects of government safety nets on both these aspects and discusses implications for policy. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hoggarth, G.; Jackson, P.; Nier, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why should the portfolios of mandatory, private pension funds be captive? (The foreign investment question)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Menil, G.
model of portfolio optimization, which takes account of the difference between the private and social cost of foreign investment, is used to analyze the relationship between capital shortages and the international diversification of mandatory, private pension funds in developing and transition countries. The socially optimal rate of foreign portfolio investment may be positive, even when access to international capital markets is limited. 1 propose replacing investment limits with a tax on foreign investments, equal to the difference between their social and private cost. The use of international pension swap is seen to be formally equivalent to the imposition of such a tax. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.A model of portfolio optimization, which takes account of the difference between the private and social cost of foreign investment, is used to analyze the relationship between capital shortages and the international diversification of mandatory, private pension funds in developing and transition countries. The socially optimal rate of foreign portfolio investment may be positive, even when access to international capital markets is limited. I propose replacing investment limits with a tax on foreign investments, equal to the difference between their social and private cost. The use of international pension swap is seen to be formally equivalent to the imposition of such a tax. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Menil, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does speed kill? Lending booms and their consequences in Croatia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kraft, E.; Jankov, L.
Recent research connects lending booms with increased risks of banking and currency crisis. Another strand of literature connects financial deepening with long-term growth. Together, these findings pose dilemmas for policymakers. In the case of Croatia, we find that rapid loan growth increased the probability of credit quality deterioration and stimulated current account and foreign debt problems. Conventional monetary tightening was not very effective, due to capital inflows. Unconventional measures such as capital controls also had limited effectiveness. We propose limiting negative impacts by pro-active monetary policy, more restrictive fiscal policy and increased capital requirements for fast-growing banks, rather than measures to prevent lending booms ex-ante. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kraft, E.; Jankov, L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early birds, late risers, and sleeping beauties: Bank credit growth to the private sector in Central and Eastern Europe and in the Balkans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cottarelli, C.; Dell'Ariccia, G.; Vladkova-Hollar, I.
Following a period of privatization and restructuring, commercial banks in Central and Eastern Europe and, more recently, in the Balkans have expanded rapidly their lending to the private sector. This paper studies whether these developments are consistent with a process of convergence and structural financial deepening by estimating an "equilibrium" level of the bank-credit-to-GDP ratio. It concluded that while there is no clear evidence that the recent increases in bank credit ratios is inconsistent with financial deepening, policy-makers will have to evaluate carefully its implications for macroeconomic developments and financial stability. (C) 2004 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cottarelli, C.; Dell'Ariccia, G.; Vladkova-Hollar, I.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cost efficiency of banks in transition: Evidence from 289 banks in 15 post-communist countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fries, S.; Taci, A.
To understand the transformation of banking in the post-communist transition, we examine the cost efficiency of 289 banks in 15 East European countries. We find that banking systems in which foreign-owned banks have a larger share of total assets have lower costs and that the association between a country's progress in banking reform and cost efficiency is non-linear. Early stages of reform are associated with cost reductions, while costs tend to rise at more advanced stages. Private banks are more efficient than state-owned banks, but there are differences among private banks. Privatised banks with majority foreign ownership are the most efficient and those with domestic ownership are the least. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fries, S.; Taci, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank performance, efficiency and ownership in transition countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonin, J. P.; Hasan, I.; Wachtel, P.
Using data from 1996 to 2000, we investigate the effects of ownership, especially by a strategic foreign owner, on bank efficiency for eleven transition countries in an unbalanced panel consisting of 225 banks and 856 observations. Applying stochastic frontier estimation procedures, we compute profit and cost efficiency taking account of both time and country effects directly. In second-stage regressions, we use the efficiency measures along with return on assets to investigate the influence of ownership type. With respect to the impact of ownership, we conclude that privatization by itself is not sufficient to increase bank efficiency as government-owned banks are not appreciably less efficient than domestic private banks. We find that foreign-owned banks are more cost-efficient than other banks and that they also provide better service, in particular if they have a strategic foreign owner. The remaining government-owned banks are less efficient in providing services, which is consistent with the hypothesis that the better banks were privatized first in transition countries. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bonin, J. P.; Hasan, I.; Wachtel, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The direct and indirect impact of bank privatization and foreign entry on access to credit in Argentina's provinces</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, G. R. G.; Crivelli, J. M.; Cull, R.
Privatization and increased foreign ownership transformed the Argentine banking sector during the 1990s. While both improved sector efficiency, there was concern that they might reduce access to credit outside of Buenos Aires. The results in this paper suggest that these fears were exaggerated. Provinces that privatized their banks suffered only temporary reductions in credit associated with cleaning the portfolio of the privatized banks. Typically, growth in lending by the privatized entity and by other banks restored credit to pre-privatization levels within a few years. In addition, increased foreign ownership coincided with more, not less, lending outside of Buenos Aires. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Clarke, G. R. G.; Crivelli, J. M.; Cull, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary convergence of the EU accession countries to the eurozone: A theoretical framework and policy implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Orlowski, L. T.
A flexible approach to direct inflation targeting offers the European Union accession countries a viable monetary policy choice that is believed to facilitate both the economic transition and the monetary convergence to the eurozone. Following this assumption, a model investigating the nexus between inflation and selected monetary variables in three EU accession countries: the Czech Republic, Poland and Hungary is advanced. The empirical analysis is aimed at explaining the sensitivity of the CPI-based inflation path in these countries to backward- as well as forward-looking expectations, nominal exchange rate fluctuations, the eurozone inflation impulses, and output changes. The analysis implies that the monetary convergence begins with flexible inflation targeting and concludes with a full-fledged euroization. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Orlowski, L. T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary policy transmission, interest rate rules and inflation targeting in three transition countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golinelli, R.; Rovelli, R.
In 1991, the rate of inflation in the Czech Republic, Hungary and Poland was 57%, 35% and 70%. At the end of 2001, it was everywhere below 8%. We set up a small structural macro model of these three economies to account for the process of disinflation. We show that a simple macro model, with forward-looking inflation and exchange rate expectations, can adequately characterize the relationship between the output gap, inflation, the real interest rate and the exchange rate during this period. This model allows us to assess the relative importance of the interest rate and exchange rate channels in determining the path of disinflation. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Golinelli, R.; Rovelli, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determination of capital controls: Which role do exchange rate regimes play?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Hagen, J.; Zhou, J. Z.
This paper investigates the role of exchange rate regime choices in the determination of capital controls in transition economies. We first use a simultaneous equations model to allow direct interactions between decisions on capital controls and on exchange rate regimes. We find that exchange rate regime choices strongly influence the imposition or removal of capital controls, but the feed-back effect is weak. We further estimate a single equation model for capital controls with exchange rate regime choices as independent variables, and we find that there is a hump-shaped relationship between exchange rate regime flexibility and capital control intensity. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>von Hagen, J.; Zhou, J. Z.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real and monetary convergence between the European Union's core and recent member countries: A rolling cointegration approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brada, J. C.; Kutan, A. M.; Zhou, S.
We use rolling cointegration to measure the convergence of base money, M2, the CPI and industrial output between Germany and France and recent EU members and some transition countries that are now joining the EU. Countries that joined the EU previously exhibit timevarying cointegration with the core countries over the 1980-2000 sample period. Cointegration for the transition economies was comparable for M2 and prices, but not for monetary policy and industrial output. Thus a peg to the Euro soon after accession is feasible for the East European countries, but the benefits of joining the Euro zone are as yet limited. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brada, J. C.; Kutan, A. M.; Zhou, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture capitalist value-added activities, fundraising and drawdowns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, D.; Fleming, G.; Suchard, J. A.
This paper is the first to introduce an analysis of the effect of different types of Venture capitalist value-added activities (financial, administrative. marketing. strategic/management) on fundraising. In addition, we include an analysis of the functional difference between committed funds and drawdowns front capital commitments vis-a-vis pension funds and venture capital funds. The new comprehensive data, collected by the Australian Bureau of Statistics for 1999-2001, enable controls for venture capitalist performance. risk, investment activity, and management and performance fees. The results indicate that significantly more capital is allocated to venture capitalists that provide financial and strategic/management expertise to entrepreneurial firms (as opposed to marketing and administrative expertise.). In addition. fundraising is greater among funds with higher returns and performance fees and lower fixed management fees. In contrast. drawdowns from capital commitments are greater among venture capital funds that provide financial and marketing expertise to investees (as opposed to strategic and administrative expertise), and among funds with higher performance fees and fixed management fees. Further, the results indicate an adverse impact on Venture capital fundraising from illiquidity attributable to a 2-year lock-up period in IPO exits over the period considered. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cumming, D.; Fleming, G.; Suchard, J. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sweep programs and optimal monetary aggregation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, B. E.; Dutkowsky, D. H.; Elger, T.
This paper examines the admissibility of monetary aggregate groupings for the US over 1993-2001, based upon weak separability. We investigate the impact of retail and commercial demand deposit sweep programs on the separability of monetary asset groupings. Weak separability is tested Using the Swofford-Whitney and Fleissig-Whitney tests. We use Varian's measurement error adjustment procedure to eliminate violations of the Generalized Axiom of Revealed Preference (GARP). When funds from both retail and commercial demand deposit sweep programs are placed within checkable deposits, all groupings, narrow and broad, pass GARP and weak separability. For groupings based on conventional money measures, tests tend to favor broad aggregates. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jones, B. E.; Dutkowsky, D. H.; Elger, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank lending and property prices in Hong Kong</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gerlach, S.; Pen, W. S.
This paper studies the relationship between residential property prices and bank lending in Hong Kong. This is an interesting topic for three reasons. First. swings M property prices have been extremely large and frequent in Hong Kong. Second, under the currency board regime. monetary policy cannot be used to guard against asset price swings. Third, despite the collapse in property prices since 1998, the banking sector remains sound. While the contemporaneous correlation between lending and property prices is large. our results suggest that the direction of influence goes from property prices to bank credit rather than conversely. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gerlach, S.; Pen, W. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The near-collapse of LTCM, US financial stock returns, and the fed</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kabir, M. H.; Hassan, M. K.
We examine both the contagion and the "too-big-to-fail" hypotheses in the context of the long-term capital management (LTCM) crisis in the US financial services industry. Our results show that those commercial and investments banks that were exposed to LTCM lost market values significantly around important events surrounding the near collapse of LTCM, but the losses experienced by investment banks are much higher than the losses faced by commercial banks. Smaller S&amp;L institutions and bigger insurance companies were also affected by the crisis, implying a form of contagion effect in the financial sector. We find some evidence of a "too-big-to-fail' policy with the involvement of the Fed in LTCM. as perceived by the markets. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kabir, M. H.; Hassan, M. K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Has competition in the Japanese banking sector improved?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uchida, H.; Tsutsui, Y.
This paper investigates whether competition in the Japanese banking sector has improved in the last quarter of the 20th century. By estimating the first order condition of profit maximization. together with the cost function and the inverse demand function. we found that competition had improved, especially in the 1970s and in the first half of the 1980s. The results fail to reject a Cournot oligopoly for city banks for most of the period, while they do reject it for regional banks for the overall period. This suggests that competition among city banks was stronger than that among regional banks. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Uchida, H.; Tsutsui, Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric return dynamics and technical trading strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nam, K.; Washer, K. M.; Chu, Q. C.
We investigate the profitability of technical trading strategies based on an asymmetric reverting property of stock returns. We identify an asymmetry in return dynamics for daily returns on the S&amp;P 500 index. Return dynamics evolve along a positive (negative) unconditional mean after a prior positive (negative) return. The trading strategies based on this asymmetry generate a positive return for buy signals. a negative return for sell signals. and a positive return for the spread between buy and sell signals. Our results imply that the observed asymmetry in return dynamics is the main source of profitability for the implied strategies. thereby. corroborating arguments for the usefulness of technical trading strategies. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nam, K.; Washer, K. M.; Chu, Q. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information content of bank loan announcements to Asian corporations during periods of economic uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boscaljon, B.; Ho, C. C.
In this study, changes in the borrower-lender relationship prior to and after the Asian crisis are examined. We find the lender quality is the most important determinant of the information content of bank loan announcements, as evidenced by differences in the banking systems of Hong Kong. Korea. Thailand and Taiwan. In addition, the results suggest that the commercial banking relationship is increasingly important in times of economic uncertainty. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boscaljon, B.; Ho, C. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are TIPS the "real" deal?: A conditional assessment of their role in a nominal portfolio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hunter, D. M.; Simon, D. P.
This paper documents predictable time-variation in the real return beta of US Treasury Inflation Protected Securities (TIPS) and in the Sharpe ratios of both indexed and conventional bonds. The conditional mean and volatility of both bonds and their conditional correlation first are estimated from predetermined variables. These estimates then are used compute conditional real return betas and Sharpe ratios. The time-variation in real return betas and the correlation between TIPS and nominal bonds coincides with major developments in the fixed-income market. One implication of this predictability is that portfolio managers call assess more efficiently the risk of investing in TIPS versus conventional bonds. Conditional Sharpe ratios indicate that over the sample period. TIPS had superior volatility-adjusted returns relative to nominal bonds. This finding is striking in view of the absence of a major inflation scare during the sample period from February 1997 through August 2001. but is loosely consistent with the possibility that TIPS elevated rather than reduced Treasury borrowing costs. On the other hand, mean-variance spanning tests; indicate that TIPS did not enhance the mean-variance efficiency of diversified portfolios. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hunter, D. M.; Simon, D. P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and hedging: Do credit derivatives increase bank risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Instefjord, N.
The objective of this paper is to investigate whether financial innovation of credit derivatives makes banks more exposed to credit risk. Although credit derivatives are important for hedging and securitizing credit risk - and thereby likely to enhance the Sharing of such risk - some commentators have raised concerns that they may destabilize the banking sector. This paper investigates this issue in a simple model driven by costs of financial distress. The analysis identifies two effects of credit derivatives innovation - they enhance risk sharing as suggested by the hedging argument - but they also make further acquisition of risk more attractive. The latter effect, if dominant, can therefore destabilize the banking sector. The critical factor is, perhaps surprisingly, the competitive nature of the existing underlying credit markets. As these markets become more elastic the threat of destabilization increases. The paper discusses issues related to bank regulation within the context of the model. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Instefjord, N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking and commerce: A liquidity approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haubrich, J. G.; Santos, J. A. C.
This paper looks at the advantages and disadvantages of mixing banking and commerce. using the "liquidity," approach to financial intermediation. Bringing a nonfinancial firm into a banking conglomerate may be advantageous because it makes it easier for the bank to dispose of assets seized in a loan default. The conglomerate's internal market increase's the liquidity of such assets and improves the bank's ability to perform financial intermediation. More generally, owning a nonfinancial firm may act either as a subsitute or a complement to commercial lending. In some cases, a bank will voluntarily refrain from making loans choosing to become a non-bank bank in an unregulated environment. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Haubrich, J. G.; Santos, J. A. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of non-financial factors in internal credit ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grunert, J.; Norden, L.; Weber, M.
Internal credit ratings are expected to gain in importance because of their potential use for determining regulatory capital adequacy and banks' increasing focus on the risk-return profile in commercial lending. Whereas the eligibility of financial factors as inputs for internal credit ratings is widely accepted, the role of non-financial factors remains ambiguous. Analyzing credit file data from four major German banks. we find evidence that the combined use of financial and non-financial factors leads to a more accurate prediction of future default events than the single use of each of these factors. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grunert, J.; Norden, L.; Weber, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial liberalisation, crisis, and restructuring: A comparative study of bank performance and bank governance in South East Asia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williams, J.; Nguyen, N.
This paper examines the impact of changes in bank governance on bank performance for a sample of commercial banks operating in SE Asia between 1990 and 2003. We identify bank governance in terms of bank ownership and measure bank performance as rank order alternative profit efficiency, technical change, and productivity. The period was characterised by financial deregulation, the Asian crisis and bank restructuring programmes. To resolve financial distress, SE Asian authorities implemented inter alia bank privatisation programmes and widened access for foreign ownership. Our results tend to support bank privatisation and the repeal of state ownership on economic grounds. We suggest the potential benefits of foreign ownership may take longer to be realised. For domestic private-owned banks, the challenge is improving bank efficiency. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Williams, J.; Nguyen, N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reward-risk portfolio selection and stochastic dominance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Giorgi, E.
The portfolio selection problem is traditionally modelled by two different approaches. The first one is based on an axiomatic model of risk-averse preferences, where decision makers are assumed to possess a utility function and the portfolio choice consists in maximizing the expected utility over the set of feasible portfolios. The second approach, first proposed by Markowitz is very intuitive and reduces the portfolio choice to a set of two criteria, reward and risk, with possible tradeoff analysis. Usually the reward-risk model is not consistent with the first approach, even when the decision is independent from the specific form of the risk-averse expected utility function, i.e. when one investment dominates another one by second-order stochastic dominance. In this paper we generalize the reward-risk model for portfolio selection. We define reward measures and risk measures by giving a set of properties these measures should satisfy. One of these properties will be the consistency with second-order stochastic dominance, to obtain a link with the expected utility portfolio selection. We characterize reward and risk measures and we discuss the implication for portfolio selection. (C) 2004 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>De Giorgi, E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the significance of expected shortfall as a coherent risk measure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inui, K.; Kijima, M.
This article shows that any coherent risk measure is given by a convex combination of expected shortfalls, and an expected shortfall (ES) is optimal in the sense that it gives the minimum value among the class of plausible coherent risk measures. Hence, it is of great practical interest to estimate the ES with given confidence level from the market data in a stable fashion. In this article, we propose an extrapolation method to estimate the ES of interest. Some numerical results are given to show the efficiency of our method. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Inui, K.; Kijima, M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What causes mean reversion in corporate bond index spreads? The impact of survival</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhanot, K.
Previous studies document that the spread between the yield on commonly used corporate bond indexes (e.g., Moody's Baa index) and a comparable maturity treasury bond exhibits mean reversion. An analytical model shows that a part of the observed negative relationship between changes in the spread and the level of spreads is a natural consequence of ratings based classification of bonds included in the index and the related effects of survival. Using data on individual corporate bonds over the period January 1985 to December 1996, 1 corroborate the analysis and illustrate the effects of survival. The result has several implications for parametric specifications of spread dynamics in the pricing of contingent claims, for the application of spreads in tests of asset pricing models (such as the conditional version of the CAPM) and for the use of spreads in business cycle forecasts. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhanot, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Complete markets, informed trading and equity option introductions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faff, R.; Hillier, D.
This paper proposes and tests a new hypothesis concerning the price impact of option introductions on the underlying asset. We argue that the leverage properties of options induce a higher level of informed trading in the aggregate market (underlying plus derivative), resulting in excess listing-day price movements in the newly optioned equity. Using an alternative dataset, our results suggest that this may be an explanation for the observed positive than negative excess listing-day returns of US optioned stocks over the past thirty years. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faff, R.; Hillier, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparing possible proxies of corporate bond liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Houweling, P.; Mentink, A.; Vorst, T.
We consider nine different proxies (issued amount, listed, euro, on-the-run, age, missing prices, yield volatility, number of contributors and yield dispersion) to measure corporate bond liquidity and use a four-variable model to control for interest rate risk, credit risk, maturity and rating differences between bonds. The null hypothesis that liquidity risk is not priced in our data set of euro corporate bonds is rejected for eight out of nine liquidity proxies. We find significant liquidity premia, ranging from 13 to 23 basis points. A comparison test between liquidity proxies shows limited differences between the proxies. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Houweling, P.; Mentink, A.; Vorst, T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Share price performance following actual share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, H.
Using unique actual daily share repurchase data front Hong Kong, this paper investigates share price performance surrounding and following actual share repurchases. It is found that repurchasing firms buy back shares following price drops, suggesting that they behave opportunistically when implementing actual share repurchases. On average, the initial 3-day market response to actual repurchases is about 0.43%. Repurchasing firms do not seem to exhibit superior abnormal performance over long horizons when they make actual share repurchases. However, the price performance of repurchasing firms varies across firm size and market-book value ratios, and shows a clear and consistent pattern. The market responds the most favorably to repurchases that are made by small and value (high book-to-market value) firms. Over a long horizon, there is some evidence that repurchases made by value firms show superior performance. The three-year buy-and-hold abnormal return, which is measured against a portfolio of control firms that are matched by size and book-to-market value ratios, is over 20%. At least, repurchases made by high book-to-market value firms, for which undervaluation is more likely to occur, can benefit long-term shareholders. &amp;COPY; 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhang, H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commitment or entrenchment?: Controlling shareholders and board composition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yeh, Y. H.; Woidtke, T.
This paper examines the determinants of board composition and firm valuation as a function of board composition in Taiwan - a country that features relatively weak protection for investors, firms with controlling shareholders, and pyramidal groups. The results suggest that there is poor governance when the board is dominated by members who are affiliated with the controlling family but good governance when the board is dominated by members who are not affiliated with the controlling family. in particular board affiliation is higher when negative entrenchment effects - measured by (1) divergence in control and cash flow rights, (2) family control, and (3) same CEO and Chairman - are strong and lower when positive incentive effects, measured by cash flow rights, are strong. Moreover, relative firm value is negatively related to board affiliation in family-controlled firms. Thus, the proportion of directors represented by a controlling family appears to be a reasonable proxy for the quality of corporate governance at the firm level when investor protection is relatively weak and it is difficult to determine the degree of separation between ownership and control. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yeh, Y. H.; Woidtke, T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real options, agency conflicts, and optimal capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mauer, D. C.; Sarkar, S.
We examine the impact of a stockholder-bondholder conflict over the timing of the exercise of an investment option on firm value and corporate financial policy. We find that an equity-maximizing firm exercises the option too early relative to a value-maximizing strategy, and we show how this problem can be characterized as one of overinvestment in risky investment projects. Equityholders' incentive to overinvest significantly decreases firm value and optimal leverage, and significantly increases the credit spread of risky debt. Numerical solutions illustrate how the agency cost of overinvestment and its effect on corporate financial policy vary with firm and project characteristics. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mauer, D. C.; Sarkar, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information frown in option prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ederington, L.; Guan, W.
In the SIP 500 options market, the information content of implied volatilities differs by strike in a frown pattern that is a rough mirror image of the implied volatility smile. Implied volatilities calculated from moderately high strike price options are both unbiased and efficient predictors of future volatility. Implied volatilities calculated from low and at-the-money strikes are biased and less efficient. This bias cannot be explained by market imperfections but is consistent with the hedging pressure argument of Bollen and Whaley [J. Finan. 59 (2004) 711] and Ederington and Guan [J. Derivat. 10 (2002) (Winter) 9]. We also find that a serious estimation bias results when the relations are estimated using panel data. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ederington, L.; Guan, W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and manager turnover: An unusual social experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aivazian, V. A.; Ge, Y.; Qiu, J. P.
This paper examines empirically the quality of the governance mechanisms of Chinese state-owned enterprises from 1994-1999, a period marked by substantial changes in policies affecting the governance structure of these firms. It shows that the restructuring of these enterprises according to corporate law improved the effectiveness of their governance system. Specifically, restructuring strengthened the links between manager turnover and firm performance. The results indicate that firm performance was significantly and negatively related to manager demotion for incorporated state-owned enterprises, while this relationship was insignificant for unincorporated enterprises. They also indicate that manager turnover was a viable incentive mechanism for improving future enterprise performance. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aivazian, V. A.; Ge, Y.; Qiu, J. P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adverse selection, brokerage coverage, and trading activity on the Tokyo Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, H. J.; Cai, J.; Hamao, Y.; Ho, R. Y. K.
Limit-order trading mechanisms, corporate ownership structure, and incentive structures in the Japanese brokerage industry differ from those in the US in several important ways. This paper exploits these differences to examine the joint and cross-sectional determinants of adverse selection costs, brokerage coverage, and trading activity for a large sample of Japanese firms traded on the Tokyo Stock Exchange. We find that adverse selection costs are associated with firm characteristics but not with ownership characteristics, which implies that adverse selection costs are affected by inside trading rather than inside holdings. We also find that while brokerage coverage reduces adverse selection costs, higher adverse selection costs lead more brokerage firms to enter the market because of the greater profit potential. Finally, we find that causality also runs both ways between brokerage coverage and trading volume: brokerage coverage increases trading volume and trading volume increases brokerage coverage. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahn, H. J.; Cai, J.; Hamao, Y.; Ho, R. Y. K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of junior debt issuance on senior unsecured debt's risk premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linn, S. C.; Stock, D. R.
Numerous studies have examined the impact of security issuance upon the value of preexisting debt and equity but the focus has largely been on changes in equity value. We examine changes in senior unsecured debt risk premiums that accompany new junior debt issues. Additionally, we test several hypotheses regarding the potential impacts of junior debt issues. Extant theory suggests senior debt value may be threatened under certain conditions by the issuance of junior debt. Our results indicate that when junior debt replaces bank debt, senior default risk premiums experience abnormal declines. The result is broadly consistent with the elevation of the senior unsecured debt by way of the elimination of a separate and more senior class of debt claimants. In contrast, we also find that larger junior bond issues are associated with abnormal increases in senior risk premiums, broadly consistent with issue size being correlated with negative information about firm cash flows. We find strong evidence of interaction effects. For example, replacement of bank debt results in greater changes in default risk premiums the larger the issue size. We also find lower credit ratings magnify other effects. For example, if the junior debt issued matures before the outstanding senior unsecured bond, senior risk premiums experience abnormal increases for lower rated debt. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Linn, S. C.; Stock, D. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relative default rates on corporate loans and bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Emery, K. M.; Cantor, R.
We use two alternative matched-set methodologies to examine for differences in loan and bond default rates among US non-financial corporate issuers. Under both methodologies, the data indicate that loan default rates are roughly 20% lower than the bond default rates due to issuers that default on their bonds but avoid bankruptcy and avoid defaulting on their loans. For a small number of European issuers, the data suggest a similar reduction in loan default rates relative to bond default rates. However, the European results differ qualitatively from the US results, due likely to differences in US and European bankruptcy regimes, as well as the larger role of bank debt on most European issuers' balance sheets. These results have important implications for investors, bank supervisors, and rating agencies that assess the relative expected credit losses on loans versus bonds. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Emery, K. M.; Cantor, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market returns: A note on temperature anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, M.; Wei, J.
This study investigates whether stock market returns are related to temperature. Research in psychology has shown that temperature significantly affects mood, and mood changes in turn cause behavioral changes. Evidence suggests that lower temperature can lead to aggression, while higher temperature can lead to both apathy and aggression. Aggression could result in more risk-taking while apathy could impede risk-taking. We therefore expect lower temperature to be related to higher stock returns and higher temperature to be related to higher or lower stock returns, depending on the trade-off between the two competing effects. We examine many stock markets world-wide and find a statistically significant, negative correlation between temperature and returns across the whole range of temperature. Apathy dominates aggression when temperature is high. The observed negative correlation is robust to alternative tests and retains its statistical significance after controlling for various known anomalies. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cao, M.; Wei, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating implied RNDs by some new confidence interval estimation techniques</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersson, M.; Lomakka, M.
This paper evaluates the precision of the parametric double lognormal and the non-parametric smoothing spline method for estimating risk-neutral distributions (RNDs) from observed option prices. By using a bootstrap technique, confidence bands are estimated for the risk-neutral distributions and the width of the confidence bands is used as a criterion when evaluating the precision of the two methods. Previous literature on estimating confidence bands has to a large extent been estimated using Monte Carlo methods. This paper argues that the bootstrap technique is to be preferred due to the non-normality feature of the error structure. Furthermore, it is shown that the inclusion of a heteroscedastic error structure improves the precision of the estimated RNDs. Our findings favour the smoothing spline method as it produces tighter confidence bands. In addition, an example of how to apply the estimated confidence bands in practice is also provided. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andersson, M.; Lomakka, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash-flow shortage as an endogenous bankruptcy reason</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uhrig-Homburg, M.
This paper develops a simple model for a leveraged firm and endogenizes the firm's bankruptcy point by assuming that equity issuance is costly. Equity-issuance costs reflect the difficulties in issuing new equity for firms that are close to financial distress. The resulting model captures cash-flow shortage as a reason to go bankrupt, though the equity value is positive. I analyze the optimal bankruptcy point as well as corporate bond prices and yield spreads for various levels of equity-issuance costs in order to study the impact of different liquidity constraints. Finally, I discuss the consequences on optimal capital structure. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Uhrig-Homburg, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership and operating performance of Chinese IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, C. Y.
We examine changes in operating performance of Chinese listed companies around their initial public offerings, and focus on the effect of ownership and ownership concentration on IPO performance changes. We document a sharp decline in post-issue operating performance of IPO firms. We also find that neither state ownership nor concentration of ownership is associated with performance changes, but there is a curvilinear relation between legal-entity ownership and performance changes and between concentration of non-state ownership and performance changes. Our results are robust to different performance measures and industry adjustments. These findings suggest that agency conflicts, management entrenchment, and large shareholders' expropriation co-exist to influence Chinese IPO performance, and the beneficial and detrimental effects of state shareholdings tend to offset each other. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, C. Y.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple large shareholders and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maury, B.; Pajuste, A.
This paper investigates the effects of having multiple large shareholders on the valuation of firms. Using data on Finnish listed firms, we show, consistent with our model, that a more equal distribution of votes among large blockholders has a positive effect on firm value. This result is particularly strong in family-controlled firms suggesting that families (which typically have managerial or board representation) are more prone to private benefit extraction if they are not monitored by another strong blockholder. We also show that the relation between multiple blockholders and firm value is significantly affected by the identity of these blockholders. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maury, B.; Pajuste, A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does judicial efficiency lower the cost of credit?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Laeven, L.; Majnoni, G.
We investigate the effect of judicial efficiency on banks' lending spreads for a large cross-section of countries. We measure bank interest rate spreads for 106 countries at the country level and for 32 countries at the level of individual banks. We find that judicial efficiency and inflation rates are the main drivers of interest rate spreads across countries. Our results suggest that improvements in judicial efficiency and judicial enforcement of debt contracts are critical to lowering the cost of financial intermediation for households and firms. &amp;COPY; 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Laeven, L.; Majnoni, G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial sector liberalization, bank privatization, and efficiency: Evidence from Pakistan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>di Patti, E. B.; Hardy, D. C.
The Pakistani banking system has been transformed over the past 15 years through liberalization, the entry of private banks, the privatization of public-sector banks, and the tightening of prudential regulations. The effects of these changes on bank productivity and relative efficiency are investigated using various techniques. Bank productivity in terms of profits has increased, and new entrants have been efficient, but the dispersion of efficiency remains wide. The privatized banks improved their profit efficiency in the period immediately following their privatization, but in the subsequent years only one significantly improved its efficiency, whereas the other did not differentiate itself in terms of efficiency from the remaining state-owned banks. The new private domestic banks generally proved to be among the most efficient, and sometimes out-performed the foreign banks. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>di Patti, E. B.; Hardy, D. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank privatization and performance: Empirical evidence from Nigeria</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, T.; Cull, R.; Jerome, A.
We assess the effect of privatization on performance in a panel of Nigerian banks for the period 1990-2001. We find evidence of performance improvement in nine banks that were privatized, which is remarkable given the inhospitable environment for true financial intermediation. Our results also suggest negative effects of the continuing minority government ownership on the performance of many Nigerian banks. Finally, our results complement aggregate indications of decreasing financial intermediation over the 1990s; banks that focused on investment in government bonds and non-lending activities enjoyed a relatively better performance. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, T.; Cull, R.; Jerome, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mexico's experiments with bank privatization and liberalization, 1991-2003</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haber, S.
During the 1990s Mexico conducted two experiments with its banking system. In the first experiment (1991-96) it privatized the banks. This experiment took place with weak institutions to enforce contract rights. It also took place without institutions that encourage prudent behavior by bankers. The result was reckless behavior by banks, and a collapse of the banking system. In the second experiment (1997-2003), Mexico reformed many of the institutions that promoted bank monitoring and it opened up the industry to foreign investment. It was less successful, however, in reforming the institutions that promote the enforcement of contract rights. The result was that bankers behaved prudently, but prudent behavior in the context of weak contract rights implies that banks are reluctant to extend credit to firms and households. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Haber, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>China's financial services industry: The intra-industry effects of privatization of the Bank of China Hong Kong</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Z. A.; Li, D. H.; Moshirian, F.
The purpose of this paper is to discuss and apply some of the key issues and lessons from similar privatization in other parts of the world to the partial privatization of the Bank of China Hong Kong (BOCHK). The empirical results of this paper indicate that some of the banks and non-bank financial institutions reacted negatively to the partial privatization announcements of the BOCHK. The empirical results also show that HSBC, the largest bank in Hong Kong had no significant reaction to the restructuring announcement or the listing announcement of the BOCHK. However, the Hang Seng Bank, the third largest bank in Hong Kong, suffered a loss after the announcement of the BOCHK listing. Compared with the banks and non-bank financial institutions in China, the BOCHK over-performed the rival firms in Mainland China 1 year after its partial privatization. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Z. A.; Li, D. H.; Moshirian, F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank privatization and productivity: Evidence for Brazil</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nakane, M. I.; Weintraub, D. B.
Over the last decade, the Brazilian banking industry has undergone major and deep transformations with several privatizations of state-owned banks, mergers and acquisitions, closing down of troubled banks, entry by foreign banks, etc. The purpose of this paper is to evaluate the impacts of these changes in banking total factor productivity. We first obtain measures of bank-level productivity by employing the techniques due to Levinsohn and Petrin [Levinsohn, J., Petrin, A., 2003. Estimating production functions using inputs to control for unobservables. Review of Economic Studies 70, 317-342]. We then relate such measures to a set of bank characteristics. Our main results indicate that state-owned banks are less productive than their private peers, and that privatization has increased productivity. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nakane, M. I.; Weintraub, D. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State bank transformation in Brazil - choices and consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, T.; Crivelli, J. M.; Summerhill, W.
This paper analyzes the different options - liquidation, federalization, privatization and restructuring - that the Brazilian state governments had for the transformation of their state banks under the PROES in the late 1990s. Specifically, this paper explores (i) the factors behind the states' choices and (ii) the effects of the transformation process on bank performance and efficiency. We find that states that were more dependent on federal transfers, whose banks were already under federal intervention and that established development agencies, were more likely to relinquish control over their banks and its transformation process. We find that privatized banks increased their performance, while restructured banks did not. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, T.; Crivelli, J. M.; Summerhill, W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and bank performance: A joint analysis of the static, selection, and dynamic effects of domestic, foreign, and state ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, A. N.; Clarke, G. R. G.; Cull, R.; Klapper, L.; Udell, G. F.
We jointly analyze the static, selection, and dynamic effects of domestic, foreign, and state ownership on bank performance. We argue that it is important to include indicators of all the relevant governance effects in the same model. "Nonrobustness" checks (which purposely exclude some indicators) support this argument. Using data from Argentina in the 1990s, our strongest and most robust results concern state ownership. State-owned banks have poor long-term performance (static effect), those undergoing privatization had particularly poor performance beforehand (selection effect), and these banks dramatically improved following privatization (dynamic effect), although much of the measured improvement is likely due to placing nonperforming loans into residual entities, leaving "good" privatized banks. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, A. N.; Clarke, G. R. G.; Cull, R.; Klapper, L.; Udell, G. F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privatization matters: Bank efficiency in transition countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonin, J. P.; Hasan, I.; Wachtel, P.
To investigate the impact of bank privatization in transition countries, we take the largest banks in six relatively advanced countries, namely, Bulgaria, the Czech Republic, Croatia, Hungary, Poland and Romania. Income and balance sheet characteristics and efficiency measures computed from stochastic frontiers are compared across four bank ownership types. Our empirical results support the hypotheses that foreign-owned banks are most efficient and government-owned banks are least efficient. In addition, the importance of attracting a strategic foreign owner in the privatization process is confirmed. However, counter to the conjecture that foreign banks cherry pick the most profitable opportunities, we find that domestic banks have a local advantage in pursuing fee-for-service business. Finally, we show that both the method and the timing of privatization matter to performance; specifically, voucher privatization does not lead to increased efficiency and early-privatized banks are more efficient than later-privatized banks, even though we find no evidence of a selection effect. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bonin, J. P.; Hasan, I.; Wachtel, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-term memories of developed and emerging markets: Using the scaling analysis to characterize their stage of development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Di Matteo, T.; Aste, T.; Dacorogna, M. M.
The scaling properties encompass in a simple analysis many of the volatility characteristics of financial markets. That is why we use them to probe the different degree of markets development. We empirically study the scaling properties of daily Foreign Exchange rates, Stock Market indices and fixed income instruments by using the generalized Hurst approach. We show that the scaling exponents are associated with characteristics of the specific markets and can be used to differentiate markets in their stage of development. The robustness of the results is tested by both Monte Carlo studies and a computation of the scaling in the frequency domain. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Di Matteo, T.; Aste, T.; Dacorogna, M. M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of war risk on US financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rigobon, R.; Sack, B.
This paper measures the effects of the risks associated with the war in Iraq on various US financial variables using a heteroskedasticity-based estimation technique. The results indicate that increases in war risk caused declines in Treasury yields and equity prices, a widening of lower-grade corporate spreads, a fall in the dollar, and a rise in oil prices. This "war risk" factor accounted for a considerable portion of the variances of these financial variables over the three months leading up to the arrival of coalition forces in central Baghdad. (c) 2004 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Rigobon, R.; Sack, B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International evidence on ethical mutual fund performance and investment style</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauer, R.; Koedijk, K.; Otten, R.
Using an international database containing 103 German, UK and US ethical mutual funds we review and extend previous research on ethical mutual fund performance. By applying a Carhart multi-factor model [Carhart, Journal of Finance 57 (1997) 57] we overcome the benchmark problem most prior ethical studies suffered from. After controlling for investment style, we find no evidence of significant differences in risk-adjusted returns between ethical and conventional funds for the 1990-2001 period. Our results also suggest that ethical mutual funds underwent a catching up phase. before delivering financial returns similar to those of conventional mutual funds. Finally, our performance estimates are robust to the inclusion of ethical indexes, which, surprisingly, are not incrementally capable of explaining ethical mutual fund return variation. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bauer, R.; Koedijk, K.; Otten, R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dollarization of bank deposits: Causes and consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Nicolo, G.; Honohan, P.; Ize, A.
This paper assesses the benefits and risks associated with dollarization of bank deposits. We provide novel empirical evidence on the determinants of deposit dollarization, its role in promoting financial development, and on whether dollarization is associated with financial instability. We find that: (a) the credibility of macroeconomic policy and the quality of institutions are both key determinants of cross-country variations in dollarization; (b) dollarization is likely to promote financial deepening only in a high inflation environment; and (c) financial instability is likely higher in dollarized economies. The implications of these findings for financial sector and monetary policies are briefly discussed. &amp;COPY; 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Nicolo, G.; Honohan, P.; Ize, A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm characteristics and the impact of emerging market liberalizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patro, D. K.; Wald, J. K.
We provide a firm level analysis of the impact of capital market liberalization in 18 emerging markets. Consistent with models of international asset pricing, we find that firms' stock returns increase during liberalization and that a majority of firms have lower mean returns and lower dividend yields after liberalization. We also find that emerging market firms have increased exposure to the world market and decreased exposure to the home market following liberalization. These changes in returns and exposures support the predictions of theoretical international asset pricing models. We also test and find support for the importance of size, local risk, foreign exchange risk, and cross-listing status in explaining the cross-section of changes in returns. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Patro, D. K.; Wald, J. K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information-based trading, price impact of trades, and trade autocorrelation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, K. H.; Li, M. S.; McInish, T. H.
In this study we show that both the price impact of trades and serial correlation in trade direction are positively and significantly related to the probability of information-based trading (PIN). The positive relation remains significant even after controlling for the effects of stock attributes. Higher trading activity (i.e., shorter intervals between trades) induces both larger price impact and stronger positive serial correlation in trade direction. The effect of time interval between trades on quote revision is stronger for stocks with higher PIN values. These results provide direct empirical support for the information models of trade and quote revision. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, K. H.; Li, M. S.; McInish, T. H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Some evidence of random walk behavior of Euro exchange rates using ranks and signs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belaire-Franch, J.; Opong, K. K.
This study utilises recently developed tests based on ranks and signs, in addition to the traditional variance ratio test, to examine the behavior of Euro exchange rates. We show that adjustments for multiple tests must be employed in order to avoid size distortions. Overall, such adjustments provide evidence consistent with random walk behavior of Euro exchange rates. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Belaire-Franch, J.; Opong, K. K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal clearing margin, capital and price limits for futures clearinghouses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shanker, L.; Balakrishnan, N.
We provide a model for a futures clearinghouse to use for setting optimal levels of clearing margin, capital and price limits, which minimizes the costs to clearing firms and simultaneously protects the clearinghouse from default by clearing firms. We show how to estimate the capital requirement, which supports the clearinghouse's residual default risk that is not covered by the clearing margin. We apply our model to the Winnipeg Commodity Exchange and demonstrate that price limits reduce the sum of optimal clearing margin and capital to a level that is substantially lower than that required in the absence of price limits. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shanker, L.; Balakrishnan, N.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relationship between short interest and stock returns in the Canadian market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ackert, L. F.; Athanassakos, G.
This paper provides new insight into the relationship between short sales and stock market returns using a sample of stocks sold short in Canada. Short interest is defined in relation to trading volume. The results strongly support the assertion that short sales and excess returns are contemporaneously negatively correlated in Canada. The paper further finds that excess returns are more negative for small firms because the supply of shortable shares is constrained for these firms. Excess returns are less negative for stocks with associated options and convertible bonds. Importantly, the evidence is consistent with the proposition that informed traders short sell Canadian interlisted. stocks in Canada, rather than the US, to exploit lower execution costs. Together the results suggest that less restrictive regulation of short sales will improve the efficiency of markets. &amp;COPY; 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ackert, L. F.; Athanassakos, G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk measurement - Introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adesi, G. B.
nan</description><author>Adesi, G. B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday price reversals in the US stock index futures market: A 15-year study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grant, J. L.; Wolf, A.; Yu, S.
This paper gives a long-term assessment of intraday price reversals in the US stock index futures market following large price changes at the market open. We find highly significant intraday price reversals over a 15-year period (November 1987-September 2002) as well as significant intraday reversals in our yearly and day-of-the-week investigations. Moreover, the strength of the intraday overreaction phenomenon seems more pronounced following large positive price changes at the market open. That being said, the question of whether a trader can consistently profit from this information remains open as the significance of intraday price reversals is sharply reduced when gross trading results are adjusted by a bid-ask proxy for transactions costs. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grant, J. L.; Wolf, A.; Yu, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The entry and the activity level of foreign banks in Italy: An analysis of the determinants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Magri, S.; Mori, A.; Rossi, P.
Although the theory of multinational banking has pointed out the importance of local profit opportunities, the empirical evidence is still poor and deserves further investigation. To this end, we analyse entry decisions and activity levels of foreign banks operating in Italy between 1983 and 1998. We consider 22 OECD countries, 10 of which had at least one bank (branch or subsidiary) in Italy. Entries and activity levels were related to the degree of economic integration as well as to the financial market features of the home country relative to Italy. Unlike other studies, besides economic integration, the relative profitability of the banking activity proves to be a significant variable in that it highlights the importance of local market conditions. In the past decade, increased competition in the Italian banking sector has reduced these profit opportunities, driving foreign banks towards more innovative sectors of financial intermediation. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Magri, S.; Mori, A.; Rossi, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>General equilibrium pricing of CPI derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lioui, A.; Poncet, P.
We examine the issue of pricing forward futures and option contracts written on the Consumer Price Index (CPI), the change of which is a measure of inflation affecting the economy. Traditional approaches postulate an exogenous process for the price level and then derive CPI derivatives prices by standard arbitrage arguments. By contrast, we build the general equilibrium of a continuous time monetary economy that is affected by both real and nominal shocks. The price level and thus the inflation rate are found endogenously and solutions for the prices of CPI derivatives are obtained, which are in closed form in a specialized version of the economy. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lioui, A.; Poncet, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price and volume effects of changes in MSCI indices - nature and causes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakrabarti, R.; Huang, W.; Jayaraman, N.; Lee, J.
Using changes in the MSCI Standard Country Indices for 29 countries between 1998 and 2001, we document that stock returns and volumes exhibit "index effects" in international markets similar to those detected by the studies of US stocks. The stocks added to the indices experience a sharp rise in prices after the announcement and a further rise during the period preceding the actual change, though part of the gain is lost after the actual change date. The stocks that are deleted from the indices, on the other hand, witness a steady and marked decline in their prices. Trading volumes increase significantly and remain at high levels after the change date for the added stocks. There are also considerable cross-country variations in these effects. Tests using data on various measures reflecting the different hypotheses fail to turn up any evidence in support of information effects. Our evidence appears to be more supportive of the downward sloping demand curve hypothesis. There is some evidence of price-pressure and mild evidence of liquidity effect, particularly in Japan and UK. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chakrabarti, R.; Huang, W.; Jayaraman, N.; Lee, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relationship between default prediction and lending profits: Integrating ROC analysis and loan pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stein, R. M.
In evaluating credit risk models, it is common to use metrics such as power curves and their associated statistics. However, power curves are not necessarily easily linked intuitively to common lending practices. Bankers often request a specific rule for defining a cut-off above which credit will be granted and below which it will be denied. In this paper we provide some quantitative insight into how such cut-offs can be developed. This framework accommodates real-world complications (e.g., "relationship" clients). We show that the simple cut-off approach can be extended to a more complete pricing approach that is more flexible and more profitable. We demonstrate that in general more powerful models are more profitable than weaker ones and we provide a simulation example. We also report results of another study that conservatively concludes a mid-sized bank might generate additional profits on the order of about $4.8 million per year after adopting a moderately more powerful model. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stein, R. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive stock options and incentive effects due to systematic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duan, J. C.; Wei, J.
Existing research on executive stock options mainly focuses on total risk when studying risk incentives. In this study, we use a GARCH option pricing framework to show that the incentive effects of executive stock options depend on the composition of risk. Controlling for total risk, the value of executive stock options increases with systematic risk and this effect is stronger when the total risk is low. Thus, when firms grant standard or non-indexed options, CEOs will have incentives to increase systematic risk even when the total risk remains constant. In contrast, indexed options will provide CEOs with incentives to reduce systematic risk. We therefore conclude that an optimal mix of indexed and non-indexed option grants will provide CEOs with incentives to take the desired level of systematic risk. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duan, J. C.; Wei, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank regulation and risk-taking incentives: An international comparison of bank risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gonzalez, F.
This paper uses a panel database of 251 banks in 36 countries to analyze the impact of bank regulation on bank charter value and risk-taking. After controlling for deposit insurance and for the quality of a country's contracting environment, the results indicate that regulatory restrictions increase banks' risk-taking incentives by reducing their charter value. Banks in countries with stricter regulation have a lower charter value, which increases their incentives to follow risky policies. These results corroborate a negative relation between regulatory restrictions and the stability of a banking system. Deposit insurance has a positive influence on bank charter value, mitigating the risk-shifting incentives it creates. This positive influence disappears when we control for the possible endogeneity of deposit insurance. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Gonzalez, F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Declining required reserves, funds rate volatility, and open market operations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demiralp, S.; Farley, D.
The standard view of the monetary transmission mechanism rests on the central bank's ability to manipulate the overnight interest rate by controlling reserve supply. In the 1990s, there was a significant decline in the level of reserve balances in the US accompanied at first by an increase in federal funds rate volatility. However, following this initial rise, volatility declined. In this paper, we find evidence of structural breaks in volatility. We estimate a Tobit model of temporary open market operations and conclude that there have been changes in the Desk's reaction function that played a major role in controlling volatility. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Demiralp, S.; Farley, D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deregulation, technological change, and the business-lending performance of large and small banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carter, D. A.; McNulty, J. E.
According to DeYoung et al. [Journal of Financial Services Research, 2004] deregulation and technological change has divided the US banking industry into two primary size-based groups: very large banks, specializing in the use of "hard" information to make standardized loans and smaller banks, specializing in the use of "soft" information and relationship development to make non-standardized loans. We evaluate business-lending performance for small and large banks over the 1993-2001 period. Small business lending by small banks is characterized by relationship development and non-standardized loans. Consistent with DeYoung et al.'s model, we find that, after controlling for market concentration, cost of funds, and a variety of other factors that might influence yields, smaller banks perform better than larger banks in the small business lending market. However, larger banks appear to have the advantage in credit card lending, a market characterized by impersonal relationships and standardized loans. Interestingly, we find evidence that larger banks have been making inroads in the market for the smallest business loans, a result consistent with the use of credit scoring by large banks to make very small business loans [Berger et al., Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking, 2004]. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carter, D. A.; McNulty, J. E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The use of stand alone warrants as unique capital raising instruments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Suchard, J. A.
This study documents a significant positive announcement effect for a unique capital raising tool, stand alone warrants, in the Australian market. The result is consistent with the models of Schultz [J. Financ. Econom. 34 (1993) 109] and Mayers [J. Financ. Econom. 47 (1998) 83] where a warrant is viewed positively by the market. The results of the model developed to analyse the determinants of the announcement effect, support variants of the information asymmetry hypothesis (proxied by major shareholder pre-commitment and issue size). (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Suchard, J. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition in markets with dominant firms: A note on the evidence from the Italian banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coccorese, P.
In this paper we consider the Italian banking industry, where the eight largest firms operate at a national level, manage about a half of total loans, and have a notably larger dimension than the other competitors. We estimate a structural model containing a behavioural parameter, in order to assess the market conduct of the largest banks for the period 1988-2000. Our finding is that, in spite of their noteworthy size and significant market share, these banks have been characterised by a more competitive conduct than the Bertrand-Nash outcome: this is in line with the results of the latest literature of the field, for which in the banking industry there is often no conflict between competition and concentration. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coccorese, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The simple economics of bank fragility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Vries, C. G.
Banks are linked through the interbank deposit market, participations like syndicated loans and deposit interest rate risk. The similarity in exposures carries the potential for systemic breakdowns. This potential is either strong or weak, depending on whether the linkages remain or vanish asymptotically. It is shown that the linearity of the bank portfolios in the exposures, in combination with a condition on the tails of the marginal distributions of these exposures, determines whether the potential for systemic risk is weak or strong. We show that if the exposures have marginal normal distributions the potential for systemic risk is weak, while if e.g. the Student distributions apply the potential is strong. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Vries, C. G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multivariate term structure models with level and heteroskedasticity effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christiansen, C.
The paper introduces and estimates a multivariate level-GARCH model for the long rate and the term-structure spread where the conditional volatility is proportional to the yth power of the variable itself (level effects) and the conditional covariance matrix evolves according to a multivariate GARCH process (heteroskedasticity effects). The long-rate variance exhibits heteroskedasticity effects and level effects in accordance with the square-root model. The spread variance exhibits heteroskedasticity effects but no level effects. The level-GARCH model is preferred above the GARCH model and the level model. GARCH effects are more important than level effects. The results are robust to the maturity of the interest rates. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christiansen, C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The lender of last resort</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goodhart, C. A. E.; Huang, H. Z.
This paper develops a model of the lender of last resort (LOLR) from a Central Bank (CB) viewpoint. The model in a static setting suggests that the CB would only rescue banks which are above a threshold size, consistent with the insight of "too big to fail". In a dynamic setting, CB's optimal policy in liquidity support depends on the trade off between contagion and moral hazard effects. Our results show that contagion is the key factor affecting CB's incentives in providing LOLR and they also provide a rationalization for "constructive ambiguity". (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goodhart, C. A. E.; Huang, H. Z.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An introduction to recent research on credit ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cantor, R.
nan</description><author>Cantor, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rating the rating agencies: Anticipating currency crises or debt crises?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sy, A. N. R.
We revisit the question whether sovereign ratings predict financial crises. In line with previous studies, we find that ratings do not predict currency crises and are instead downgraded expost. However, the likelihood of currency crisis and the implied probability of sovereign default are not closely linked in emerging markets post-1994. When debt crises are defined as sovereign distress - when spreads are higher than 1000 basis points or 10 percentage points - we find that access to international capital markets is reduced by half. In addition, although sovereign distress events last for typically 5.2 consecutive months, they call persist for longer periods up to nine quarters. Finally, lagged ratings and ratings changes, including negative outlooks and credit watches, are useful in anticipating sovereign distress. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sy, A. N. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informational efficiency of credit default swap and stock markets: The impact of credit rating announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Norden, L.; Weber, M.
This paper analyzes the response of stock and credit default swap (CDS) markets to rating announcements made by the three major rating agencies during the period 2000-2002. Applying event study methodology, we examine whether and how strongly these markets respond to rating announcements in terms of abnormal returns and adjusted CDS spread changes. First, we find that both markets not only anticipate rating downgrades, but also reviews for down-grade by all three agencies. Second, a combined analysis of different rating events within and across agencies reveals that reviews for downgrade by Standard &amp; Poor's and Moody's exhibit the largest impact on both markets. Third, the magnitude of abnormal performance in both markets is influenced by the level of the old rating, previous rating events and, only in the CDS market, by the pre-event average rating level of all agencies. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Norden, L.; Weber, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relationship between credit default swap spreads, bond yields, and credit rating announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hull, J.; Predescu, M.; White, A.
A company's credit default swap spread is the cost per annum for protection against a default by the company. In this paper we analyze data on credit default swap spreads collected by a credit derivatives broker. We first examine the relationship between credit default spreads and bond yields and reach conclusions on the benchmark risk-free rate used by participants in the credit derivatives market. We then carry out a series of tests to explore the extent to which credit rating announcements by Moody's are anticipated by participants in the credit default swap market. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hull, J.; Predescu, M.; White, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the consistency of ratings and bond market yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perraudin, W.; Taylor, A. P.
We study the consistency of the credit-risk orderings implicit in ratings and bond market yields. By analyzing errors in term structure estimates for bonds with particular ratings, we show that for significant periods, a quarter of some categories of high credit quality bonds are rated in a manner that is inconsistent with their pricing. Adjusting for economic determinants of spreads (tax, liquidity and risk premiums) and allowing for the dynamic adjustment of ratings and spreads largely eliminates the inconsistencies, however. (C) 2004 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Perraudin, W.; Taylor, A. P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factors affecting the valuation of corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.; Agrawal, D.; Mann, C.
An important body of literature in Financial Economics accepts bond ratings as a sufficient metric for determining homogeneous groups of bonds for estimating either risk-neutral probabilities or spot rate curves for valuing corporate bonds. In this paper we examine Moody's and Standard &amp; Poors ratings of corporate bonds and show they are not sufficient metrics for determining spot rate curves and pricing relationships. We investigate several bond characteristics that have been hypothesized as affecting bond prices and show that from among this set of measures default risk, liquidity, tax liability, recovery rate and bond age leads to better estimates of spot curves and for pricing bonds. This has implications for what factors affect corporate bond prices as well as valuing individual bonds. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.; Agrawal, D.; Mann, C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ratings versus market-based measures of default risk in portfolio governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loffler, G.
This paper assesses whether ratings or market-based credit risk measures are more suitable for formulating portfolio governance rules. Such rules, which consist of buy and sell restrictions, are commonly used in investment management. Based on data from 1983 to 2002, it is not evident that one of the two measures is superior. The relative power of the two measures in predicting defaults depend on the investor's investment horizon and risk appetite. The results support the agencies' claim that their policy of reducing rating volatility, which builds on the though-the-cycle approach and the avoidance of frequent rating reversals, is beneficial to bond investors. The results also suggest that widely used statistical measures of rating quality may be insufficient to judge the economic value of rating information in specific contexts. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loffler, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How rating agencies achieve rating stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altman, E. I.; Rijken, H. A.
Surveys on the use of agency credit ratings reveal that some investors believe that rating agencies are relatively slow in adjusting their ratings. A well-accepted explanation for this perception on the timeliness of ratings is the through-the-cycle methodology that agencies use. According to Moody's, through-the-cycle ratings are stable because they are intended to measure default risk over long investment horizons, and because they are changed only when agencies are confident that observed changes in a company's risk profile are likely to be permanent. To verify this explanation, we quantify the impact of the long-term default horizon and the prudent migration policy on rating stability from the perspective of an investor - with no desire for rating stability. This is done by benchmarking agency ratings with a financial ratio-based (credit-scoring) agency-rating prediction model and (credit-scoring) default-prediction models of various time horizons. We also examine rating-migration practices. The final result is a better quantitative understanding of the through-the-cycle methodology. By varying the time horizon in the estimation of default-prediction models, we search for a best match with the agency-rating prediction model. Consistent with the agencies' stated objectives, we conclude that agency ratings are focused on the long term. In contrast to one-year default prediction models, agency ratings place less weight on short-term indicators of credit quality. We also demonstrate that the focus of agencies on long investment horizons explains only part of the relative stability of agency ratings. The other aspect of through-the-cycle methodology - agency-rating migration policy - is an even more important factor underlying the stability of agency ratings. We find that rating migrations are triggered when the difference between the actual agency rating and the model predicted rating exceeds a certain threshold level. When rating migrations are triggered, agencies adjust their ratings only partially, consistent with the known serial dependency of agency-rating migrations. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Altman, E. I.; Rijken, H. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are credit ratings procyclical?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amato, J. D.; Furfine, C. H.
This paper studies the influence of the state of the business cycle on credit ratings. In particular, we assess whether rating agencies are excessively procyclical in their assignment of ratings. Our analysis is based on a model of ratings determination that takes into account factors that measure the business and financial risks of firms, in addition to indicators of macroeconomic conditions. Utilizing annual data on all US firms rated by Standard &amp; Poor's, we find that ratings do not generally exhibit excess sensitivity to the business cycle. In addition, we document that previously reported findings of a secular tightening of ratings standards are not robust to a more complete accounting of systematic changes to measures of risk. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amato, J. D.; Furfine, C. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measurement, estimation and comparison of credit migration matrices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jafry, Y.; Schuermann, T.
Credit migration matrices are cardinal inputs to many risk management applications; their accurate estimation is therefore critical. We explore two approaches: cohort and two variants of duration - one imposing, the other relaxing time homogeneity - and the resulting differences, both statistically through matrix norms and economically using a credit portfolio model. We propose a new metric for comparing these matrices based on singular values and apply it to credit rating histories of S&amp;P rated US firms from 1981-2002. We show that the migration matrices have been increasing in "size" since the mid-1990s, with 2002 being the "largest" in the sense of being the most dynamic. We develop a testing procedure using boot-strap techniques to assess statistically the differences between migration matrices as represented by our metric. We demonstrate that it can matter substantially which estimation method is chosen: economic credit risk capital differences implied by different estimation techniques can be as large as differences between economic regimes, recession vs. expansion. Ignoring the efficiency gain inherent in the duration methods by using the cohort method instead is more damaging than imposing a (possibly false) assumption of time homogeneity. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jafry, Y.; Schuermann, T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Confidence sets for continuous-time rating transition probabilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christensen, J. H. E.; Hansen, E.; Lando, D.
This paper addresses the estimation of default probabilities and associated confidence sets with special focus on rare events. Research on rating transition data has documented a tendency for recently downgraded issuers to be at an increased risk of experiencing further downgrades compared to issuers that have held the same rating for a longer period of time. To capture this non-Markov effect we introduce a continuous-time hidden Markov chain model in which downgrades firms enter into a hidden, 'excited' state. Using data from Moody's we estimate the parameters of the model, and conclude that both default probabilities and confidence sets are strongly influenced by the introduction of hidden excited states. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christensen, J. H. E.; Hansen, E.; Lando, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do government-linked companies underperform?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, F.; Sun, Q.; Tong, W. H. S.
Our comprehensive study of 30 Singapore government-linked companies (GLCs) covering the period 1964 to 1998 shows that share issue privatization has some positive impacts on their performance. However, there was no evidence that the GLCs were less profitable than a selected group of non-GLCs that match by size and industry. Taking a buy-and-hold strategy, we found that GLC stocks provide statistically equivalent returns relative to market or other control sample returns over various investment horizons of up to four years. Given that GLCs also perform as well as averages for the market and industry up to five years before their listing, we argue that Singapore's government-owned enterprises are comparable to privately run enterprises in efficiency. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Feng, F.; Sun, Q.; Tong, W. H. S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting currency volatility: A comparison of implied volatilities and AR(FI)MA models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pong, S. Y.; Shackleton, M. B.; Taylor, S. J.; Xu, X. Z.
We compare forecasts of the realized volatility of the pound, mark and yen exchange rates against the dollar, calculated from intraday rates, over horizons ranging from one day to three months. Our forecasts are obtained from a short memory ARMA model, a long memory ARFIMA model, a GARCH model and option implied volatilities. We find intraday rates provide the most accurate forecasts for the one-day and one-week forecast horizons while implied volatilities are at least as accurate as the historical forecasts for the one-month and three-month horizons. The superior accuracy of the historical forecasts, relative to implied volatilities, comes from the use of high frequency returns, and not from a long memory specification. We find significant incremental information in historical forecasts, beyond the implied volatility information, for forecast horizons up to one week. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pong, S. Y.; Shackleton, M. B.; Taylor, S. J.; Xu, X. Z.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Productivity change in European banking: A comparison of parametric and non-parametric approaches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casu, B.; Girardone, C.; Molyneux, P.
This paper compares parametric and non-parametric estimates of productivity change in European banking between 1994 and 2000. Productivity change has also been further decomposed into technological change, or change in best practice, and efficiency change. Both the parametric and non-parametric approaches consistently identify those systems that have benefited most (and least) from productivity change during the 1990s. The results also suggest that (where found) productivity growth has mainly been brought about by improvements in technological change and there does not appear to have been 'catch-up' by non-best-practice institutions. Competing methodologies sometimes identify conflicting findings for the sources of productivity for individual years. However, the two approaches generally do not yield markedly different results in terms of identifying the components of productivity growth in European banking during the 1990s. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Casu, B.; Girardone, C.; Molyneux, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consolidation and efficiency in the financial sector: A review of the international evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amel, D.; Barnes, C.; Panetta, F.; Salleo, C.
In response to fundamental changes in regulation and technology, the financial industry is undergoing an unprecedented wave of consolidation. A growing body of empirical literature measures the efficiency gains from mergers and acquisitions; however there is little sense of how the results might depend on the country, industry and time period analyzed. In this paper we review critically works that cover the main sectors of the financial industry (commercial and investment banks, insurance and asset management companies) in the major industrialized countries over the last 20 years, searching for common patterns that transcend national and sectoral peculiarities. We find that consolidation in the financial sector is beneficial up to a relatively small size, but there is little evidence that mergers yield economies of scope or gains in managerial efficiency. Crown Copyright (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amel, D.; Barnes, C.; Panetta, F.; Salleo, C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determining management behaviour in European banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williams, J.
This paper determines management behaviour for European savings banks between 1990 and 1998. Following the Granger causality approach of Berger and DeYoung [Journal of Banking and Finance 21 (1997) 849], we examine the intertemporal relationships between loan loss provision, efficiency and capitalisation for European banks. In so doing, we provide a robustness test of the Berger and DeYoung results for US banks. The possible relationships between the variables imply different modes of management behaviour namely bad management, bad luck, skimping, and moral hazard behaviour. The econometric results suggest that the most pressing management problem for European banks is bad management. Generally speaking, the European findings are inconsistent with previous results from the US. One notable difference in management behaviour between European and US banks is that the former do not appear to engage in skimping behaviour. The European results are sensitive to the number of lags included in the model. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Williams, J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks as delegated risk managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hakenes, H.
Risk management, although of major importance in the banking industry in practice, plays only a minor role in the theory of banking. We reduce this gap by putting forward a model in which risk managers - specialists that can find out correlations between risky assets - endogenously take over typical functions of banks. They grant loans, they consult on financial questions with firms that are threatened by bankruptcy, and they sign tailor-made hedge transactions with these firms. Delegation costs are innately low if banks assume the function of risk managers in an economy. Risk management can be seen as a core competence of banks. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hakenes, H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does poor legal enforcement make households credit-constrained?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fabbri, D.; Padula, M.
This paper analyzes the relation between the quality of the legal enforcement of loan contracts and the allocation of credit to households, both theoretically and empirically. We use a model of household credit market with secured debt contracts, where the judicial system affects the cost incurred by banks to actually repossess the collateral. The model shows that the working of the judicial system affects both the probability of being credit-con strained and the equilibrium amount of debt. In the empirical part, we test our predictions using data on Italian households and on the performance of Italian judicial districts. Controlling for household characteristics, unobserved heterogeneity at judicial district level and aggregate shocks, we document that an increment in the backlog of trials pending has a statistically and economically significant positive effect on the household probability of being turned down for credit. Furthermore, we show that moving a household from the high-cost judicial district (in southern Italy) to the low-cost judicial district would reduce his probability of being credit-constrained by 50% on average, other things being equal. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fabbri, D.; Padula, M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting bank performance with financial forecasts: A case of Taiwan commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kao, C.; Liu, S. T.
Data envelopment analysis (DEA) has been used as a tool for evaluating past accomplishments in the banking industry. However, due to a time lag, the results usually arrive too late for the evaluated banking institutions to react timely. This paper makes advanced predictions of the performances of 24 commercial banks in Taiwan based on their financial forecasts. The forecasts based on uncertain financial data are represented in ranges, instead of as single values. A DEA model for interval data is formulated to predict the efficiency. The predictions of the efficiency scores are also presented as ranges. We found that all the efficiency scores calculated from the data contained in the financial statements published afterwards fall within the corresponding predicted ranges of the efficiency scores which we had calculated from the financial forecasts. The results also show that even the bad performances of the two banks taken over by the Financial Restructuring Fund of Taiwan could actually be predicted in advance using this study. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kao, C.; Liu, S. T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do some lenders have information advantages? Evidence from Japanese credit market data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shin, G. H.; Kolari, J. W.
Using detailed Japanese credit data, we test for the existence of a credit market hierarchy. Empirical tests indicate that firms with information problems are more likely to carry higher proportions of relationship loans from main banks than non-main banks, holding constant risk and control factors. We further examine credit specialization on the part of lenders by testing the relationship between client firms' information and risk characteristics and the concentration of loans obtained from depository institutions versus other financial institutions. However, no significant differences in information superiority between these two types of financial institutions are found. We conclude that our evidence supports the credit market hierarchy hypothesis for Japanese main banks in particular but not depository institutions in general. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shin, G. H.; Kolari, J. W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance mechanisms in Spanish banks. Does ownership matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crespi, R.; Garcia-Cestona, M. A.; Salas, V.
This paper examines the governance of Spanish banks regarding two main issues. First, does poor economic performance activate governance interventions that favor the removal of executive directors and the merger of non-performing banks? And, second, does the relationship between governance intervention and economic performance vary with the ownership form of the bank? We find a negative relationship between performance and governance intervention for banks, but the results change for each form of ownership and each type of intervention. Internal-control mechanisms work for Independent Commercial banks, but Savings banks show weaker internal mechanisms of control and the only significant relationship between performance and governance intervention that appears is for mergers. The Spanish Savings banks, with a peculiar form of ownership that, in fact, implies a lack of ownership, give voice to several stakeholder groups with no clear allocation of property rights. Nevertheless, their economic performance is not generally affected. Product-market competition compensates for those weaker internal governance mechanisms, and non-performing banks are not fully protected from disappearing. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Crespi, R.; Garcia-Cestona, M. A.; Salas, V.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A new approach to modeling the dynamics of implied distributions: Theory and evidence from the S&amp;P 500 options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Panigirtzoglou, N.; Skiadopoulos, G.
This paper presents a new approach to modeling the dynamics of implied distributions. First, we obtain a parsimonious description of the dynamics of the S&amp;P 500 implied cumulative distribution functions by applying principal components analysis. Subsequently, we develop new arbitrage-free Monte Carlo simulation methods that model the evolution of the whole distribution through time as a diffusion process. Our approach generalizes the conventional approaches of modeling only the first two moments as diffusion processes, and it has important implications for "smile-consistent" option pricing and for risk management. The out-of-sample performance within a Value-at-Risk framework is examined. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Panigirtzoglou, N.; Skiadopoulos, G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underpricing and aftermarket performance of American depositary receipts (ADR) IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ejara, D. D.; Ghosh, C.
American depositary receipts (ADRs) are negotiable instruments representing foreign company shares traded in US dollars in the US capital market. We present comparative analyses of the pricing and aftermarket performance of Initial Public Offerings (IPOs) by ADRs and a matching sample of US firms over the 1990-2001 period. Offered by large, well-known multinationals, ADR IPOs go through a detailed scrutiny, and incur significant costs, during the pre-IPO period to recast financial statements in conformity with SEC rules and the US GAAP. This mitigates the information asymmetry between the IPO firm and investors. We categorize the ADR issuing country as developed or emerging, and our sample includes several cases of privatization of state owned corporations. The analyses indicate that (1) ADR IPOs are significantly less underpriced than comparable US IPOs; (2) IPOs from developed countries are more underpriced; and (3) Privatization IPOs are less underpriced than non-privatizations. The lower underpricing of ADR 1POs persists even after differential IPO attributes, the traditional proxies for information asymmetry and, the unique characteristics associated with ADR IPOs, are accounted for. We conclude that extant literature offers only partial explanation for this puzzling phenomenon. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ejara, D. D.; Ghosh, C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of organizational structure on efficiency: Evidence from the Spanish insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cummins, J. D.; Rubio-Misas, M.; Zi, H. M.
This paper provides new information on the effects of organizational structure on efficiency by analyzing Spanish stock and mutual insurers over the period 1989-1997. We test the efficient structure hypothesis, which predicts that the market will sort organizational forms into market segments where they have comparative advantages, and the expense preference hypothesis, which predicts that mutuals will be less efficient than stocks. Technical, cost, and revenue frontiers are estimated using data envelopment analysis. The results indicate that stocks and mutuals are operating on separate production, cost, and revenue frontiers and thus represent distinct technologies. In cost and revenue efficiency, stocks of all sizes dominate mutuals in the production of stock output vectors, and smaller mutuals dominate stocks in the production of mutual output vectors. Larger mutuals are neither dominated by nor dominant over stocks in the cost and revenue comparisons. Thus, large mutuals appear to be vulnerable to competition from stock insurers in Spain. Overall, the results are consistent with the efficient structure hypothesis but are generally not consistent with the expense preference hypothesis. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cummins, J. D.; Rubio-Misas, M.; Zi, H. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debtor-in-possession financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chatterjee, S.; Dhillon, U. S.; Ramirez, G. G.
Several recent papers have documented the benefits of debtor-in-possession (DIP) financing in the restructuring of firms in Chapter 11. However, the view on benefits is not unanimous and some legal scholars have raised doubts about DIP financing's effects on debt-holders and the possibility of expropriative wealth transfers. In this paper we address this issue by analyzing both stock and bond price data for a comprehensive sample of DIP loans and find significant positive abnormal stock and bond returns at the announcement of DIP loans. Also, we do not find evidence of wealth transfers from junior to senior debt-holders. Further, we examine the DIP loan process in detail and we document important institutional features of DIP loans such as maturity, covenants, fees and interest charges. We find evidence of intense monitoring using covenants. We also find higher fees and charges associated with DIP loans. We argue that overall the results are consistent with the information processing role of financial intermediaries. Crown Copyright (C) 2004 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chatterjee, S.; Dhillon, U. S.; Ramirez, G. G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of CRA agreements on community banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bostic, R. W.; Robinson, B. L.
We develop three empirical models to identify the impact of Community Reinvestment Act (CRA) agreements on the mortgage lending behavior of small banking institutions during the period 1990-1997. CRA agreements are pledges banking institutions make to extend levels of credit to targeted populations and are often used by institutions to reaffirm their commitment to the goals of the CRA. We hypothesize that CRA agreements increase the level of competition for mortgage loans in the targeted area, which in turn causes a reduction in the quantity of mortgage credit to be supplied by community banks. Consistent with the quantity hypothesis, the results show that CRA agreements are associated with less mortgage lending, including lending in lower-income communities (CRA lending) and in minority communities (minority lending), by small community lenders. Evidence does not support a second hypothesis - that community banks respond to the increased competition by providing credit to riskier individuals. (C) 2004 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bostic, R. W.; Robinson, B. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on the expectations hypothesis at the founding of the Fed</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kool, C. J. M.; Thornton, D. L.
One of the most influential tests of the expectations hypothesis is Mankiw and Miron [Q. J. Econ. 101 (1986) 211], who found that the spread between the long-term and short-term rates provided predictive power for the short-term rate before the Fed's founding but not after. They suggested that the failure of the expectations hypothesis after the Fed's founding was due to the Fed's practice of smoothing short-term interest rates. We show that their finding that the expectations hypothesis fares better prior to the Fed's founding is due to the fact that the test they employ tends to generate results that are more favorable to the expectations hypothesis during periods when there is extreme volatility in the short-term rate. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kool, C. J. M.; Thornton, D. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price discovery and volatility spillovers in index futures markets: Some evidence from Mexico</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhong, M. S.; Darrat, A. F.; Otero, R.
This paper investigates the hypotheses that the recently established Mexican stock index futures market effectively serves the price discovery function, and that the introduction of futures trading has provoked volatility in the underlying spot market. We test both hypotheses simultaneously with daily data from Mexico in the context of a modified EGARCH model that also incorporates possible cointegration between the futures and spot markets. The evidence supports both hypotheses, suggesting that the futures market in Mexico is a useful price discovery vehicle, although futures trading has also been a source of instability for the spot market. Several managerial implications are derived and discussed. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhong, M. S.; Darrat, A. F.; Otero, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cyclical correlations, credit contagion, and portfolio losses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giesecke, K.; Weber, S.
We model aggregate credit losses on large portfolios of financial positions contracted with firms subject to both cyclical default correlation and direct default contagion processes. Cyclical correlation is due to the dependence of firms on common economic factors. Contagion is associated with the local interaction of firms with their business partners. We provide an explicit normal approximation of the distribution of portfolio losses. We quantify the relation between the variability of global economic fundamentals, strength of local firm interaction, and the fluctuation of losses. We find that cyclical oscillations in fundamentals dominate average losses, while local interaction causes additional fluctuations of losses around their average. The strength of the contagion-induced loss variability depends on the complexity of the business partner network. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giesecke, K.; Weber, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Penny pricing and the components of spread and depth changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, K. H.; Charoenwong, C.; Ding, D. K.
Recent studies show that decimal pricing led to significant reductions in the spread and depth on the NYSE. In this paper, we examine how the observed changes in the spread and depth can be attributed to different factors. We show that stocks with higher proportions of one-tick spreads and odd-sixteenth quotes, and more frequent trading before decimalization experienced larger declines in the spread and depth afterwards. We interpret this result as evidence of reduced binding constraints and increased price competition under decimal pricing. We also find that decimal pricing led to nontrivial changes in select stock attributes, and that these changes exerted an additional impact on spreads and depths. Our results suggest that sub-penny pricing may further reduce the spreads of high-volume, low-risk, or low-price stocks. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, K. H.; Charoenwong, C.; Ding, D. K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Normal mixture diffusion with uncertain volatility: Modelling short- and long-term smile effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, C.
This paper introduces a parameterization of the normal mixture diffusion (NMD) local volatility model that captures only a short-term smile effect, and then extends the model so that it also captures a long-term smile effect. We focus on the 'binomial' NMD parameterization, so-called because it is based on simple and intuitive assumptions that imply the mixing law for the normal mixture log price density is binomial. With more than two possible states for volatility, the general parameterization is related to the multinomial mixing law. In this parsimonious class of complete market models, option pricing and hedging is straightforward since model prices and deltas are simple weighted averages of Black-Scholes prices and deltas. But they only capture a short-term smile effect, where leptokurtosis in the log price density decreases with term, in accordance with the 'stylised facts' of econometric analysis on ex-post returns of different frequencies and the central limit theorem. However, the last part of the paper shows that longer term smile effects that arise from uncertainty in the local volatility surface can be modeled by a natural extension of the binomial NMD parameterization. Results are illustrated by calibrating the model to several Euro-US dollar currency option smile surfaces. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of IMF-induced moral hazard</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dobeli, B.; Vanini, P.
Three channels through which the IMF rescue package may affect international lending can be distinguished: debtor-side moral hazard, creditor-side moral hazard, and debtor and creditor-side moral hazard. We show that if the rescue package fully benefits the debtor, no credit contract between him and the creditor arises. The other two kinds of moral hazard, where the creditor receives the rescue package either fully or in part, increase the scale of international lending relative to the case where no rescue package is forthcoming. The increase is larger if the creditor receives the whole rescue package than if it is shared between the creditor and the debtor. These results are based on the analysis of two sequential credit relationships, the first one between a bank and a government and the following one between the IMF and the government. Each of these credit relationships is characterized by asymmetric information and modeled by a moral hazard model. The two moral hazard models are linked by considering the different channels of the IMF rescue package. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dobeli, B.; Vanini, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the way to recovery: A nonparametric bias free estimation of recovery rate densities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Renault, O.; Scaillet, O.
In this paper we analyse recovery rates on defaulted bonds using the Standard &amp; Poor's/ PMD database for the years 1981-1999. Due to the specific nature of the data (observations lie within 0 and 1), we must rely on nonstandard econometric techniques. The recovery rate density is estimated nonparametrically using a beta kernel method. This method is free of boundary bias, and Monte Carlo comparison with competing nonparametric estimators show that the beta kernel density estimator is particularly well suited for density estimation on the unit interval. We challenge the usual market practice to model parametrically recovery rates using a beta distribution calibrated on the empirical mean and variance. This assumption is unable to replicate multimodal distributions or concentration of data at total recovery and total loss. We evaluate the impact of choosing the beta distribution on the estimation of credit Value-at-Risk. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Renault, O.; Scaillet, O.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The unintended consequences of grouping in tests of asset pricing models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grauer, R. R.; Janmaat, J. A.
We identify a number of unintended consequences of grouping when the capital asset pricing model is true and when it is false. When the model is true, grouping may cause fundamental problems with the most basic capital asset pricing and cross-sectional regression relationships. For example, with traditional grouping, the market portfolio is super-efficient-unless securities in each group are value weighted. Yet, when the model is grossly false, grouping may cause the model to appear to be absolutely correct. Ironically, the only way this can occur is when securities in each group are value weighted. To make matters worse, when the model is false, the slope of a cross-sectional regression of expected returns on betas fitted to grouped data may be either steeper or flatter than when the regression is fitted to ungrouped data. In other words, grouping may exacerbate the very problem it was meant to alleviate. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grauer, R. R.; Janmaat, J. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market- vs. bank-based financial systems: Do rights and regulations really matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ergungor, O. E.
In some countries, banks are firms' key source of financing. In others, firms look mainly to financial markets to meet their financial needs. Why should this be so? This paper provides an explanation tied to legal traditions. Civil-law courts are less effective than their common-law counterparts in resolving conflicts because they have less flexibility in interpreting the laws and creating new rules. Banks emerge in these economies as primary contract enforcers, leading to bank-oriented financial systems. Furthermore, because common-law courts enforce laws effectively, providing them with more detailed creditor and shareholder protection laws has a greater impact on the development of financial markets compared with civil-law systems. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ergungor, O. E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Correlated default with incomplete information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giesecke, K.
The recent accounting scandals at Enron, WorldCom, and Tyco were related to the misrepresentation of liabilities. We provide a structural model of correlated multi-firm default, in which public bond investors are uncertain about the liability-dependent barrier at which individual firms default. Investors form prior beliefs on the barriers, which they update with the default status information of firms arriving over time. Whenever a firm suddenly defaults, investors learn about the default threshold of closely associated business partner firms. This updating leads to "contagious" jumps in credit spreads of business partners. We characterize joint default probabilities and the default dependence structure as assessed by investors, where we emphasize the the modeling of dependence with copulas. A case study based on Brownian asset dynamics illustrates our results. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giesecke, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management of non-maturing liabilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalkbrener, M.; Willing, J.
Risk management of non-maturing liabilities is a relatively unstudied issue of significant practical importance. Non-maturing liabilities include most of the traditional deposit accounts like demand deposits, savings accounts and short time deposits and form the basis of the funding of depository institutions. Therefore, the asset and liability management of depository institutions depends crucially on an accurate understanding of the liquidity risk and interest rate risk profile of these deposits. In this paper we propose a stochastic three-factor model as general quantitative framework for liquidity risk and interest rate risk management for non-maturing liabilities. It consists of three building blocks: market rates, deposit rates and deposit volumes. We give a detailed model specification and present algorithms for simulation and calibration. Our approach to liquidity risk management is based on the term structure of liquidity, a concept which forecasts for a specified period and probability what amount of cash is available for investment. For interest rate risk management we compute the value, the risk profile and the replicating bond portfolio of non-maturing liabilities using arbitrage-free pricing under a variance-minimizing measure. The proposed methodology is demonstrated by means of a case study: the risk management of savings accounts. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kalkbrener, M.; Willing, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>General equilibrium real and nominal interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lioui, A.; Poncet, P.
We derive the general equilibrium short-term real and nominal interest rates in a monetary economy affected by technological and monetary shocks and where the price level dynamics is endogenous. Assuming fairly general processes for technology and money supply, we show that an inherent feature of our equilibrium is that any real variable dynamics, in particular that of the short-term real interest rate, is driven by both monetary and real factors. This money non-neutrality is generic, as it does not stem from any friction such as price stickiness, or from a particular utility function. Non-neutrality obtains because the ex ante cost of real money holdings is random due to inflation uncertainty. We then analyze in depth a specialized version of this economy in which the state variables follow square root processes, and the representative investor has a log separable utility function. The short-term nominal rate dynamics we obtain encompasses most of the dynamics present in the literature, from Vasicek and CIR to recent quadratic and, more generally, non-linear interest rate models. Moreover, our results pave the way to several new nominal term structures. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lioui, A.; Poncet, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The number and the closeness of bank relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Rheinbaben, J.; Ruckes, M.
We analyze a firm's optimal choice over the number of creditors and the extent of information disclosed to them. By dealing with many creditors and disclosing essential confidential information, a firm can keep its cost of credit low. This, however, is associated with a relatively high probability that valuable information leaks to competitors, leading to lower expected net returns from product market operations. The importance of these two countervailing effects varies with size, time, industry, and the form of the financial sector, which yields a number of empirically testable hypotheses. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>von Rheinbaben, J.; Ruckes, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The implied reserves of the Bank Insurance Fund</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Episcopos, A.
Option models of deposit insurance pricing view assessment rates as put option premiums. However, such models ignore the risk of guaranty fund default. This paper attempts to link risk-based premiums with guaranty fund reserves in a partial equilibrium setting, by employing a methodology based on options with credit risk. The value of full insurance per coverage period is expressed as a standard options premium and is decomposed into two parts. The explicit part is due to the available assets (reserves) of the guaranty fund, while the implicit part comes from federal support, contingent on the adequacy of reserves at the end of the coverage period. Implied reserves are derived under an exogenous insurance coverage rate as a policy parameter. The method is illustrated on a sample of 40 large bank holding companies and an extension to the case of several insured banks is provided. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Episcopos, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information transmission between the NASDAQ and Asian second board markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, B. S.; Rui, O. M.; Wang, S. S.
In the 1980s and early 1990s, the NASDAQ's success helped to prompt Singapore (SESDAQ), Japan (JASDAQ), Taiwan (TAISDAQ), and South Korea (KOSDAQ) to set up or formalize their own second board markets. In 1999, Malaysia (MESDAQ) and Hong Kong (GEM) followed suit. Given the growing importance of these second board markets, we examine whether there is any evidence of spillovers from NASDAQ returns and volatilities to Asian second board market returns and volatilities after controlling for spillovers from the NYSE, and whether these cross-country spillovers are strong relative to domestic spillovers from the corresponding main board markets. We employ EGARCH models, dynamic causality tests, and VAR-based forecast error decompositions using daily data of a recent sample period that includes the Asian financial crisis of 1997 and continues until April 20, 2001. There is strong evidence of lagged returns and volatility spillovers from the NASDAQ market to the Asian second board markets when we exclude contemporaneous main board market returns. There is also strong evidence of contemporaneous and lagged returns and volatility spillovers from the local main board markets to the corresponding second board markets. However, even in the presence of contemporaneous main board market returns, there are substantial spillovers from the lagged NASDAQ returns and volatilities to Asian second board market returns and volatilities. These findings are not sensitive to whether we use US dollar-based data or local currency-based data. Given the difference in the trading hours between the NASDAQ and Asian stock markets, we use available intra-day return data and Canadian return data. The findings seem quite robust: there is substantial information spillover from the NASDAQ to the Asian and Canadian second board markets. These findings indicate the existence of a substantial cross-country industry effect (or meteor shower effect), as well as a domestic market effect (or heat wave effect), and imply that both country diversification and industry diversification are important. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, B. S.; Rui, O. M.; Wang, S. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Scale economies, bank mergers, and electronic payments: A spline function approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Humphrey, D. B.; Vale, B.
This paper demonstrates the importance of using a flexible cost function specification when analyzing economics of scale and estimating the cost effect of banking mergers. The inflexibility of the translog cost function is illustrated and results are compared to more flexible spline and Fourier cost functions. Using these different approaches we predict the ex ante effect on average cost from mergers over 1987-1998 using a balanced panel of 130 Norwegian banks. On average mergers are predicted to lower costs. Predictions using the Fourier or spline approach are in overall agreement with computed actual average merger-cost changes ex post. Cost effects of electronic payments are also estimated and exceed cost reductions associated with mergers. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Humphrey, D. B.; Vale, B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign exchange exposure of exporting and importing firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pritamani, M. D.; Shome, D. K.; Singal, V.
The existing literature reports insignificant 'total' exposure for multinational or exporting firms, where total exposure incorporates both firm-specific and macroeconomic effects. We propose a dual-effect hypothesis to explain this result which seemingly contradicts conventional wisdom. According to our proposed hypothesis, firms are affected by both the domestic economy and foreign markets. These effects are at least partially offsetting for exporters and additive for importers. The resulting predictions of insignificant total exposure for exporters and positive total exposure for importers are borne out in our tests. The literature also reports insignificant 'residual' exposure for multinationals or exporting firms, where residual exposure estimates the firm-specific exposure. This result is explained by biases in the residual exposure estimates introduced by the choice of the value-weighted market index as the control portfolio. We propose an equally-weighted portfolio of purely domestic firms as an alternative portfolio to reduce such biases and report significantly negative exposure for exporters and significantly positive exposure for importers, as predicted by theory. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pritamani, M. D.; Shome, D. K.; Singal, V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed trading and order type</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooney, J. W.; Sias, R. W.
Each trader must choose between a limit order, a market order, or using a floor broker. We hypothesize that informed investors will: (1) concentrate their trading in floor broker orders and (2) sometimes trade patiently. Consistent with our hypotheses, empirical results suggest that most informed trading occurs through orders executed by floor brokers and that informed floor brokers are sometimes patient. Regardless of their patience, however, quote revisions following trade executions are consistent with the hypothesis that markets recognize that floor traders are more likely to be informed than other traders. As a result, informed trading moves equilibrium security values. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cooney, J. W.; Sias, R. W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural changes in volatility and stock market development: Evidence for Spain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eizaguirre, J. C.; Biscarri, J. G.; Hidalgo, F. P. D.
In this paper we review the factors that lead to changes in stock market volatility and use alternative methodologies of endogenous breakpoint detection in order to analyze whether the volatility of the Spanish stock market has changed significantly over the period 1941-2001. This period corresponds to years of profound development of both the financial and the productive sides of the economy in this country. The analysis of the Spanish stock market suggests that volatility has behaved in a different manner over the period 1941-2001: After three decades of low volatility, a structural break in volatility is detected in 1972, coinciding with the opening of the Spanish economy. From 1972 to 2001, the years of more intense financial development, the stock market presents a higher level of volatility and lower persistence. This effect is partly attributable to the increased growth of trading volume brought about by the economic development process. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eizaguirre, J. C.; Biscarri, J. G.; Hidalgo, F. P. D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign bank entry, deregulation and bank efficiency: Lessons from the Australian experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sturm, J. E.; Williams, B.
This study considers the impact of foreign bank entry on banking efficiency in Australia during the post-deregulation period 1988-2001. Using Data Envelopment Analysis, Malmquist Indices and stochastic frontier analysis, we find foreign banks more efficient than domestic banks, which however did not result in superior profits. Major Australian banks have used size as a barrier to entry to new entrants. Furthermore, bank efficiency has increased post-deregulation and the competition resulting from diversity in bank types was important to prompt efficiency improvements. Finally, the recession of the early 1990s resulted in a distinct shift in the process of efficiency changes. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sturm, J. E.; Williams, B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross-sectional determinants of inventory control and the subtle effects of ADRs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hansch, O.
This paper addresses the effects of international cross-listings on the domestic market by investigating the properties of market maker inventories on the London Stock Exchange. We find that the unit-root hypothesis can only be rejected for a fraction of dealer inventories, and that mean reversion is generally slow. Inter-stock variations in mean reversion can be explained by liquidity- and risk-related variables, as well as the availability of ADRs on other exchanges. We find that ADRs do have an appreciable and significant impact on dealer behaviour and trading costs. The findings have implications for our understanding of the subtleties of linkages between markets. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hansch, O.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The competitive implications of multimarket bank branching</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hannan, T. H.; Prager, R. A.
Retail banking markets have traditionally been viewed as locally limited. However, recent studies have found evidence that large multimarket banking organizations tend to offer uniform interest rates for retail deposit accounts throughout the area that they serve, at least within a given state. This uniform pricing phenomenon raises questions about the continued relevance of the concept of local banking markets for both research and antitrust purposes. We address this issue by employing a model designed to explain the pricing behavior of single-market banks that face competition from multimarket banks. Empirical results are found to be consistent with the many implications of the model. We find that even with multimarket banks present in the market, local market concentration influences the pricing behavior of single-market banks; however, this relationship weakens as the market share of multimarket banks grows. We also find that, on average, multimarket banks offer lower deposit interest rates than do single-market banks operating in the same market, and, in most cases, greater multimarket bank presence is associated with lower deposit interest rates offered by single-market banks. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hannan, T. H.; Prager, R. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are some mutual funds closed to new investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhao, X. G.
Fund families typically claim that closing a fund protects the fund's superior performance by preventing it from growing too large to be managed efficiently. Even though funds with better performance and larger size are more likely to be closed, there is no evidence that closing a fund can indeed protect its performance. Instead, fund closing decisions are more likely to be motivated by spillover effects - by closing a star fund, the fund family signals its superior performance and also brings investors' attention and investments to other funds in the family. Some evidence exists to suggest that the closing strategy is effective in generating higher inflows into the rest of the family, at least in the short run. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhao, X. G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Backtesting for risk-based regulatory capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kerkhof, J.; Melenberg, B.
In this paper we present a framework for backtesting all currently popular risk measurement methods for quantifying market risk (including value-at-risk and expected shortfall) using the functional delta method. Estimation risk can be taken explicitly into account. Based on a simulation study we provide evidence that tests for expected shortfall with acceptable low levels have a better performance than tests for value-at-risk in realistic financial sample sizes. We propose a way to determine multiplication factors, and find that the resulting regulatory capital scheme using expected shortfall compares favorably to the current Basel Accord backtesting scheme. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kerkhof, J.; Melenberg, B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of loan prepayment risk and deposit withdrawal risk on the optimal intermediation margin</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stanhouse, B.; Stock, D.
Numerous studies have analyzed how a bank's intermediation margin varies with respect to such factors as credit quality, funding risk, bank capital, deposit insurance and other factors. However, these studies ignore the potential that loans tend to prepay if interest rates decline and deposits tend to be withdrawn if interest rates rise. Taking this very fundamental fact into account, we derive optimal loan rates and deposit rates when the bank is subject to loan prepayments and deposit withdrawals. Among other things, we find that greater volatility of interest rates tends to increase the margin. The strength of the correlation between the level of interest rates and the propensity to prepay loans (withdraw deposits) also plays an interesting role. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stanhouse, B.; Stock, D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simulation based stress tests of banks' regulatory capital adequacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peura, S.; Jokivuolle, E.
Banks' holding of reasonable capital buffers in excess of minimum requirements could alleviate the procyclicality problem potentially exacerbated by the rating-sensitive capital charges of Basel II. Determining the sufficient buffer size is an important risk management task for banks, which the Basel Committee suggests should be approached via stress testing. We present here a simulation-based approach to stress testing of regulatory capital adequacy where rating transitions are conditioned on business-cycle phase, and which takes into account business-cycle dynamics. Our approach is an extension of a typical credit portfolio analysis in that we simulate actual bank capital and minimum capital requirements simultaneously. Actual bank capital (absent mark-to-market accounting) is driven by bank income and default losses, whereas capital requirements within Basel 11 are driven by rating transitions. The joint dynamics of these determine the necessary capital buffers, given a confidence level for regulatory capital adequacy chosen by bank management. We provide a tentative calibration of this confidence level to data on actual bank capital ratios, which enables a ceteris-paribus extrapolation of bank capital under the current regime to bank capital under Basel II. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Peura, S.; Jokivuolle, E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Franco Modighani (1918-2003)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schioppa, F. K. P.
nan</description><author>Schioppa, F. K. P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Franco Modighani (1918-2003)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarnat, M.
nan</description><author>Sarnat, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Franco Modighani (1918-2003)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szego, G.
nan</description><author>Szego, G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Start-up investment with scarce venture capital support</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kanniainen, V.; Keuschnigg, C.
Venture capitalists, representing informed capital, screen, monitor and advise start-up entrepreneurs. The paper reports three new results on venture capital (VC) finance and the evolution of the VC industry. First, there is an optimal VC portfolio size with a trade-off between the number of companies and the value of managerial advice. Second, advice tends to be diluted when the industry expands and VC skills remain scarce in the short-run. The delayed entry of experienced VCs eventually restores the quality of advice and leads to more focused company portfolios. Third, as a welfare result, VCs tend to provide too little advisory effort and to invest in too few companies. Testable implications are also discussed. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kanniainen, V.; Keuschnigg, C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-horizon regression tests of the theory of purchasing power parity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Serletis, A.; Gogas, P.
In this article we test the purchasing power parity (PPP) hypothesis during the recent floating exchange rate period, using quarterly data for 21 OECD countries. In doing so, we use the long-horizon regression approach developed by Fisher and Seater [American Economic Review 83 (1993) 402] and consider 60 bilateral intercountry relations. We investigate the power of the long-horizon regression tests, using the inverse power function of Andrews [Econometrica 57 (1989) 1059], and provide weak evidence in favor of PPP. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Serletis, A.; Gogas, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal consumption and investment strategies with stochastic interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Munk, C.; Sorensen, C.
We characterize the solution to the consumption and investment problem of a power utility investor in a continuous-time dynamically complete market with stochastic changes in the opportunity set. Under stochastic interest rates the investor optimally hedges against changes in the term structure of interest rates by investing in a coupon bond, or portfolio of bonds, with a payment schedule that equals the forward-expected (i.e. certainty equivalent) consumption pattern. Numerical experiments with two different specifications of the term structure dynamics (the Vasicek model and a three-factor non-Markovian Heath-Jarrow-Morton model) suggest that the hedge portfolio is more sensitive to the form of the term structure than to the dynamics of interest rates. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Munk, C.; Sorensen, C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market interactions in returns and volatilities between spot and forward shipping freight markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kavussanos, M. G.; Visvikis, I. D.
The lead-lag relationship in both returns and volatilities between spot and futures markets has been investigated extensively in the financial economics literature. Only a limited number of such studies have appeared on forward markets, primarily due to the lack of easy access to empirical data. This paper uses a unique database in over-the-counter Forward Freight Agreements (FFA) to investigate the issue. The underlying commodity is non-storable, being that of a shipping service, with the additional feature of transactions costs being higher in the spot market in comparison to the forward market. These features have interesting implications for the markets. At the practical level, the better understanding of the mean and variance dynamics can improve risk management and budget planning decisions. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kavussanos, M. G.; Visvikis, I. D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factors explaining the interest margin in the banking sectors of the European Union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maudos, J.; Fernandez de Guevara, J.
This study analyses the interest margin in the principal European banking sectors (Germany, France, the United Kingdom, Italy and Spain) in the period 1993-2000 using a panel of 15,888 observations, identifying the fundamental elements affecting this margin. Our starting point is the methodology developed in the original study by Ho and Saunders [Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis XVI (1981) 581-600] and later extensions, but widened to take banks' operating costs explicitly into account. Also, unlike the usual practice in the literature, a direct measure of the degree of competition (Lerner index) in the different markets is used. The results show that the fall of margins in the European banking system is compatible with a relaxation of the competitive conditions (increase in market power and concentration), as this effect has been counteracted by a reduction of interest rate risk, credit risk, and operating costs. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maudos, J.; Fernandez de Guevara, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political uncertainty and asset valuation: Evidence from business relocations in Canada</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tirtiroglu, D.; Bhabra, H. S.; Lel, U.
Quebec's drive for sovereignty from Canada has been the source of political uncertainty for decades in Canada. This paper studies empirically stock market's reaction to the announcements of business relocations from the province of Quebec to other provinces within Canada. Similar announcements about Toronto are used for control. Empirical results show that the market's reaction to the announcements of business relocations (a) from Quebec is positive, (b) from Toronto is negative, and (c) to Toronto is positive. The difference in abnormal returns between the Quebec and Toronto samples is positive and significant. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tirtiroglu, D.; Bhabra, H. S.; Lel, U.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitored financial equilibria</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madan, D. B.
The financial monitoring system is formalized as an economic primitive in addition to preferences, endowments, production sets and asset spans. New definitions of budget constraints and economic equilibria follow. The concept of a general equilibrium is then appropriately revised to accommodate this perspective on the role of a financial monitoring system. Implications for asset pricing are derived and the relationship of equilibria to risk management considerations is discussed. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Madan, D. B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral, type of lender and relationship banking as determinants of credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jimenez, G.; Saurina, J.
This paper analyses the determinants of the probability of default (PD) of bank loans. We focus the discussion on the role of a limited set of variables (collateral, type of lender and bank-borrower relationship) while controlling for the other explanatory variables. The study uses information on the more than three million loans entered into by Spanish credit institutions over a complete business cycle (1988-2000) collected by the Bank of Spain's Credit Register (Central de Informacion de Riesgos). We find that collateralised loans have a higher PD, loans granted by savings banks are riskier and, finally, that a close bank-borrower relationship increases the willingness to take more risk. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jimenez, G.; Saurina, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New evidence on the Fed's productivity in providing payments services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilbert, R. A.; Wheelock, D. C.; Wilson, P. W.
As the dominant provider of payments services, the efficiency with which the Federal Reserve provides such services is an important public policy issue. This paper examines the productivity of Federal Reserve check-process in g offices during 1980-1999 using non-parametric estimation methods and newly developed methods for non-parametric inference and hypothesis testing. The results support prior studies that found little initial improvement in the Fed's efficiency with the imposition of pricing for Federal Reserve services in 1982. However, we find that median productivity improved substantially during the 1990s, and the dispersion of productivity across Fed offices declined. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gilbert, R. A.; Wheelock, D. C.; Wilson, P. W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volume autocorrelation, information, and investor trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Covrig, V.; Ng, L.
This study investigates whether the widely documented daily correlated trading volume of stocks is driven by individual investor trading, institutional trading, or both. We find that at least 95% of NYSE and AMEX stocks exhibit statistically significant, positive serial correlation. Volume autocorrelation decreases with the level of institutional ownership of a stock. We also show that the rate of arrivals of new information to the market contributes to the clustering of trades. When there is high information flow to the market, institutional trading generates a more pronounced effect on volume autocorrelation than individual investor trading. Our results are broadly consistent with the predictions of trading volume patterns suggested by most theoretical models of stock trading and by empirical research on investor trading. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Covrig, V.; Ng, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The demise of community banks? Local economic shocks are not to blame</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yeager, T. J.
The number of US community banks is falling rapidly. Is this reduction being driven in part by banks' desire to geographically diversify to reduce their vulnerability to local economic shocks? A comparison of the performance of banks in counties that suffered economic shocks in the 1990s with similar banks in counties that did not suffer economic shocks shows that banks withstand local economic shocks quite well. This result suggests that the geographic concentration risk that community banks must bear to focus on relationship lending is small and is not an important factor contributing to the decline of community banks. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved,</description><author>Yeager, T. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate cash holdings: An empirical investigation of UK companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozkan, A.; Ozkan, N.
This paper investigates the empirical determinants of corporate cash holdings for a sample of UK firms. We focus on the importance of managerial ownership among other corporate governance characteristics including board structure and ultimate controllers of companies. We present evidence of a significant non-monotonic relation between managerial ownership and cash holdings. In addition, we observe that the way in which managerial ownership exerts influence on cash holdings does not change with board composition and, in general, the presence of ultimate controllers. The results reveal that firms' growth opportunities, cash flows, liquid assets, leverage and bank debt are important in determining cash holdings. Our analysis also suggests that firm heterogeneity and endogeneity are crucial in analysing the cash structure of firms. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ozkan, A.; Ozkan, N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-border bank mergers: What lures the rare animal?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buch, C. M.; DeLong, G.
Although domestic mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As) in the financial services industry have increased steadily over the past two decades, international M&amp;As were until recently relatively rare. Moreover, the share of cross-border mergers in the banking industry is low compared with other industries. This paper uses a novel dataset of over 3000 mergers that took place between 1985 and 2001 to analyze the determinants of international bank mergers. We test the extent to which information costs and regulations hold back merger activity. Our results suggest that information costs significantly impede cross-border bank mergers. Regulations also influence cross-border bank merger activity. Hence, policy makers can create environments that encourage cross-border activity, but information cost barriers must be overcome even in (legally) integrated markets. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buch, C. M.; DeLong, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term structure linkages surrounding the Plaza and Louvre accords: Evidence from Euro-rates and long-memory components</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patel, A.; Shoesmith, G. L.
Eurocurrency deposit rates for Germany, Japan, the UK and the US are used to investigate term structure linkages over the 1979-85 and 1986-01 periods. A single common trend drives the term structure in each country, with 1-month rates generally having little or no influence in setting the long-term trend. Cointegration and common factor analyses based on the intracurrency common factors suggest weaker integration of economic fundamentals following the Plaza Accord in 1986. However, using a 10-year moving window to examine the 1986-01 period, similar tests show that integration increased between the 1986-95 and 1988-97 periods, but declined again by 1992-01. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Patel, A.; Shoesmith, G. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The characteristics of individual analysts' forecasts in Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolliger, G.
This study investigates the determinants of financial analysts' forecasts differential accuracy in 14 different European stock markets. Using the I/B/E/S Detail History Database, I find that European financial analysts forecast accuracy is positively associated with analyst firm specific experience. Forecast accuracy is negatively associated with the number of countries followed by analysts and the age of the forecast. Surprisingly, I find no relationship between forecast accuracy and analysts' job experience and the size of the bank employing the analyst. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bolliger, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Fed and short-term rates: Is it open market operations, open mouth operations or interest rate smoothing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thornton, D. L.
It is widely believed that the Fed controls the federal funds rate by altering the degree of pressure in the reserve market through open market operations when it changes its target for the funds rate. Recently, however, several analysts have suggested that the Fed need not conduct open market operations to change the funds rate. Rather, they argue it is sufficient that the Fed indicate its desire for the funds rate. This paper notes that there is yet a third alternative. the interest-rate-smoothing hypothesis, that suggests that the Fed does not move rates per se but, rather, smooths the transition of rates to the new equilibrium required by economic shocks. This paper tests the open market and open mouth alternatives using a methodology first used by Cook and Hahn [Journal of Monetary Economics (1989a) 331]. Finding no evidence that either open market operations or open mouth operations can account for the close relationship between the funds rate and the funds rate target, a variety of evidence consistent with the interest-rate-smoothing hypothesis is considered. The results suggest that many changes in the Fed's funds rate target are an endogenous response to economic events and suggest that an alternative way to identify exogenous changes in policy is to identify exogenous changes in the Fed's funds rate target. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thornton, D. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock markets, banks, and growth: Panel evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, T.; Levine, R.
This paper investigates the impact of stock markets and banks on economic growth using a panel data set for the period 1976-1998 and applying recent generalized-method-of moments techniques developed for dynamic panels. On balance, we find that stock markets and banks positively influence economic growth and these findings are not due to potential biases induced by simultaneity, omitted variables or unobserved country-specific effects. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, T.; Levine, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are all Central Bank interventions created equal? An empirical investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sapp, S.
This study investigates the relationship between Central Bank interventions and technical trading rule profitability in the spot foreign exchange market. Because interventions are not necessarily exogenous events, we analyze the relationships between interventions by the G-3 Central Banks, financial market conditions, changes in monetary policy and technical trading profitability. By considering announced, unannounced, unilateral and coordinated interventions separately, we provide more insight into the interrelationships between these factors than previous studies. We find that the level of technical trading profits and market uncertainty increase preceding and remain high during interventions, especially announced and coordinated, but decrease afterward. A preliminary investigation of the possible role of a time-varying risk premium around interventions cannot be rejected. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sapp, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effective duration of callable corporate bonds: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkar, S.; Hong, G.
This paper computes the effective duration of callable corporate bonds, using a contingent-claims model that incorporates both default risk and call risk. The model generates empirical implications regarding the cross-sectional variation and the firm-specific determinants of duration, and demonstrates that the effect of the call feature is to shorten duration (except for low-grade bonds). The effective duration is also estimated empirically for a large sample of long-term corporate bonds, using monthly bond price and interest rate data. Cross-sectional regression analysis is used to test the empirical implications of the model regarding the determinants of effective duration, and the empirical results are quite supportive of the model's predictions. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sarkar, S.; Hong, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of positive long-term performance in strategic mergers: Corporate focus and cash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Megginson, W. L.; Morgan, A.; Nail, L.
Using a sample selection and benchmarking methodology designed to more accurately assess merger-related changes in corporate focus, we find a significantly positive relationship between corporate focus and long-term merger performance. Focus-decreasing (FD) mergers result in significantly negative long-term performance with an average 18% loss in stockholder wealth. 9% loss in firm value, and significant declines in operating cash flows three years after merger. Mergers that either preserve or increase focus (FPI) result in marginal improvements in long-term performance. These results are consistent with many corporate focus studies, suggesting that merger studies finding opposite results are the result of measurement error. A positive relationship between changes in focus and long-term performance continues to hold after controlling for other variables. A continuous measure of focus change indicates that the extent of focus changes is significant. Every 10% reduction in focus results in a 9% loss in stockholder wealth, a 4% discount in firm value, and a more than 1% decline in operating performance. Cash-financed FPI mergers exhibit the best, and stock-financed FD mergers the worst, long-term performance. Tests of subsample time periods show that the focus change measure is significant in both time periods, indicating that the extent of corporate focus changes is the more important measure of corporate focus or diversification. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Megginson, W. L.; Morgan, A.; Nail, L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The short-term effects of foreign bank entry on domestic bank behaviour: Does economic development matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lensink, R.; Hermes, N.
This paper investigates the short-term effects of foreign bank entry on the behaviour of the domestic banking sector. We hypothesise that these effects are dependent on the level of economic development of the host country. Our investigation shows that at lower levels of economic development foreign bank entry is generally associated with higher costs and margins for domestic banks. At higher levels of economic development the effects appear to be less clear: foreign bank entry is either associated with a fall of costs, profits and margins of domestic banks, or is not associated with changes in these domestic bank variables. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lensink, R.; Hermes, N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return reversals in the bond market: Evidence and causes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khang, K.; King, T. H. D.
The finance literature has shown that equity returns are predictable using past returns. This study extends that literature by examining bond return predictability. Using returns constructed from dealer bid prices, we find short- to intermediate-term reversals in investment grade corporate bond returns. These reversals are larger in the first half of the sample period and consistent with the predictions of dealer inventory cost models. This supports Jegadeesh and Titman's [J. Financ. Intermed. 4 (1995) 116] assertion that daily, weekly, and monthly reversals in equity returns come from dealer inventory considerations, not behavioral biases. Finally, unlike equity returns, we find no evidence of momentum in bond returns. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khang, K.; King, T. H. D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disequilibrium in the UK corporate loan market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanasova, C. V.; Wilson, N.
In the last decade, a debate has resurfaced about whether financial constraints stemming from asymmetric information and incentive problems play an important role in propagating monetary policy shocks. This paper investigates the monetary transmission mechanism in the UK and its impact on the availability of bank credit to small and medium size firms. The empirical specification is based on a disequilibrium model that allows for the possibility of transitory credit rationing. Sample firms are classified endogenously into 'borrowing constrained' and 'borrowing unconstrained'. The analysis of credit rationing takes into account not only firm specific variables, but also important macroeconomic factors such as the prevailing monetary conditions and the stage of the business cycle. We find that (i) firms' assets play an important role as collateral in mitigating borrowing constraints; (ii) during periods of tight monetary conditions corporate demand for bank credit increases, whereas the supply of bank loans is reduced; (iii) to avoid bank credit rationing smaller companies increase their reliance on interfirm credit; (iv) the proportion of borrowing constrained firms is significantly higher during the recession years of the early 1990s than at other times. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Atanasova, C. V.; Wilson, N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on foreigners' trading and price effects across firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahlquist, M.; Robertsson, G.
We study the investment behavior of foreign investors in association with an equity market liberalization, and find a strong link between foreigners' trading and local market returns. In the period following the liberalization, net purchases by foreign investors induced a permanent increase in stock prices, suggesting that local firms reduced their cost of equity capital. We also find a strong link between a firm's fraction of foreign ownership and the magnitude of the cost reduction. Foreign investors seem to prefer large and well-known firms. and these firms realize the largest reduction in capital cost. Furthermore, our analysis suggests that foreigners increase their net holding in firms that have recently performed well. Analyzing foreigners' performance, we find very little evidence of informed trading, suggesting that risk sharing is the most plausible explanation for the reduction of the cost of equity capital. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dahlquist, M.; Robertsson, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A model of the monetary sector with and without binding capital requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kopecky, K. J.; VanHoose, D.
Bank equity is exogenous in the standard deposit-and-loan-expansion multiplier model, so that model is inappropriate for analyzing the interaction between monetary and bank regulatory policies. This paper examines the effect of a binding capital requirement on the loan expansion process. We evaluate how the conflict between the monetary and regulatory authorities evolves when bank equity adjusts to a binding capital requirement. We find that capital requirements are not innocuous for monetary policy. Nevertheless, the monetary authority can assert control over the loan expansion process in the long run, although multiplier values will differ considerably from those in the standard multiplier model. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kopecky, K. J.; VanHoose, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-based capital requirements for mortgage loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calem, P. S.; LaCour-Little, M.
We contribute to the debate over the reform of the Basel Accord by developing risk-based capital requirements for mortgage loans held in portfolio by financial intermediaries. Our approach employs simulation of both economic variables that affect default incidence and conditional loss probability distributions. Results indicate that appropriate capital charges for credit risk vary substantially with loan characteristics and portfolio geographic diversification. Hence, rules that offer little risk differentiation, including the current Basel I regime and "standardized" approach proposed in Basel II result in significant divergence between regulatory and economic capital. These results highlight the incentive problems inherent in simplified methods of capital regulation. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calem, P. S.; LaCour-Little, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Data-conditioning biases, performance, persistence and flows: The case of Canadian equity funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deaves, R.
This study constitutes the first comprehensive examination of Canadian mutual fund performance using a dataset free of all conditioning biases. The goal is to test many of the same hypotheses which have been previously addressed using US data. The sample is carefully constructed so as to avoid not only survivorship bias but also a form of backfilling bias that exists because funds have a timing option as to when to first provide results to information vendors. The deleterious impact of both forms of bias is documented. Not unlike what has been found in the US, on average fund managers net-of-expenses underperform benchmarks, but it also seems clear that their analysis and trading contribute to portfolio performance. I also present evidence that, at least on a short-term basis, success breeds success. Investors seem aware of this since money flows to successful funds. The strategy of chasing returns looks to be a viable one. One useful byproduct of this work is that an independent dataset has allowed for the corroboration of many of the same stylized facts that have been previously observed in the US. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Deaves, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An anatomy of rating through the cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loffler, G.
Using a structural model of default, I derive rating characteristics if ratings are meant to look 'through the cycle' as opposed to being based on the borrowers' current condition. The through-the-cycle method, which is employed by most rating agencies, requires a separation of permanent and cyclical components of default risk. In a time series setting, this can be done through the Kalman filter. The analysis shows that several empirical irregularities of agency ratings could be the consequence of such a rating method. The stability of through-the-cycle ratings is relatively high, while their default prediction power is low. Though not predictable in the usual sense, rating changes exhibit properties that call for a reconsideration of the existing evidence. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loffler, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special issue - Financial services: Global perspectives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fariborz, M.
nan</description><author>Fariborz, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial services: Global perspectives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, F.
The purpose of this paper is to discuss the issues related to the deregulation of the financial services sector and the role of multilateral negotiations which has opened up opportunities for the expansion of international financial services. The paper analyses various categories of international financial services and highlights those factors that contribute to an increase in the competitiveness of financial institutions in their attempt to increase the supply of international financial services. The paper also analyses the complementary role of FDI and trade in international financial services and discusses some of the benefits of FDI in financial services that have led to a more efficient and more competitive financial services industry in the host countries. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual holding companies: Evidence of conflicts of interest through disparate dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carow, K. A.; Cox, S. R.; Roden, D. M.
The mutual holding company (MHC) structure establishes a dual-class stock that creates a unique opportunity to transfer wealth from thrift depositor-owners to new minority shareholders through the disparate payment of dividends. We show that MHCs are priced higher than comparable non-MHCs and dividend policy is a significant component of this valuation. We also show that MHC thrifts pay significantly higher dividends than non-MHC thrifts and that an Office of Thrift Supervision (OTS) ruling reducing the potential for disparate dividends between the two classes of shareholders resulted in lower dividends. These results have policy implications of special significance given that the OTS reversed its position in 2000 and because of the current controversy over the use of the MHC structure in the financial service industry. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carow, K. A.; Cox, S. R.; Roden, D. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International finance and open-economy macroeconomics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, P. R.
nan</description><author>Allen, P. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging with forwards and puts in complete and incomplete markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benninga, S. Z.; Oosterhof, C. M.
We derive general conditions for forward and/or put unbiasedness and show that restrictions on the probability distribution suffice for simultaneous unbiasedness of forwards and puts, even if consumers are assumed to be risk averse. We examine the optimal production and hedging decisions by a risk-averse producer. If the producer's state prices are derived from his marginal rates of substitution, an unbiased market forward price is perceived as overpriced and an unbiased market put price as underpriced. Even in this case the full hedging and separation theorems still hold and, contrary to previous literature, there is a hedging role for puts. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benninga, S. Z.; Oosterhof, C. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management, capital structure and lending at banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cebenoyan, A. S.; Strahan, P. E.
We test how active management of bank credit risk exposure through the loan sales market affects capital structure, lending, profits, and risk. We find that banks that rebalance their loan portfolio exposures by both buying and selling loans-that is, banks that use the loan sales market for risk management purposes rather than to alter their holdings of loans-hold less capital than other banks; they also make more risky loans (loans to businesses) as a percentage of total assets than other banks. Holding size, leverage and lending activities constant, banks active in the loan sales market have lower risk and higher profits than other banks. Our results suggest that banks that improve their ability to manage credit risk may operate with greater leverage and may lend more of their assets to risky borrowers. Thus, the benefits of advances in risk management in banking may be greater credit availability, rather than reduced risk in the banking system. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cebenoyan, A. S.; Strahan, P. E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-varying excess returns on UK government bonds: A non-linear approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lekkos, I.; Milas, C.
This paper provides an empirical examination of the behaviour of excess returns on UK government discount bonds in terms of risk factors such as the forward premium, the slope of the term structure, dividend yields and excess stock returns. We identify the existence of a time-varying term structure of expected excess returns. Further, the dynamics of the expected returns are characterised by regime-switching behaviour where the transition from one regime to the other is controlled by the slope of the term structure of interest rates. The first regime, which is characterised by flat or downward sloping term structures, occurs during periods of economic recession. The second regime, which is characterised by upward sloping term structures, occurs during periods of economic expansion. The main risk factors explaining expected returns are the slope of the term structure in the recessionary regime and the excess stock returns in the expansionary regime. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lekkos, I.; Milas, C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading costs, investor recognition and market response: An analysis of firms that move from the Amex (Nasdaq) to Nasdaq (Amex)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tse, Y.; Devos, E.
We examine 36 firms that moved from the American Stock Exchange (Amex) to Nasdaq and 70 firms that moved from Nasdaq to the Amex after the market reform of Nasdaq. Quoted, effective, and realized spreads increase (decrease) when firms switch from the Amex (Nasdaq) to Nasdaq (Amex). The trade size is smaller but volume is larger when firms are listed on Nasdaq. Quotations on both markets exhibit quote clustering. Unlike previous studies, the Amex-to-Nasdaq (Nasdaq-to-Amex) firms have an average market value higher (lower) than the average of all Amex (Nasdaq) firms. The excess returns are positive (and higher than reported by previous research) when firms announce a move from the Amex to Nasdaq, particularly for high-tech firms, but are insignificant for the reverse. Moreover, we find that institutional ownership and the number of institutional shareholders increase when firms move from the Amex to Nasdaq, but not when firms move from Nasdaq to the Amex. The overall results suggest that firms that move to Nasdaq increase investor recognition and volume at the expense of an increase in trading costs, whereas firms that move to the Amex experience lower trading costs with no apparent change in investor recognition. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tse, Y.; Devos, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Have trading rule profits in the currency markets declined over time?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Olson, D.
Previous studies have reported mixed results regarding the success of technical trading rules in currency markets. Abnormal returns were observed in many studies using data up to the mid 1980s, while more recent studies generally report less success for technical trading rules. This paper tests whether moving average trading rule profits have declined over the period from 1971 to 2000. If so, previous profits may represent a temporary inefficiency that has since been eliminated in the currency markets. The hypothesis is tested using 18 exchange rate series over a longer time period than in previous studies. Rules are optimized for successive 5-year in-sample periods from 1971 to 1995 and tested over subsequent 5-year out-of-sample periods. Results show that risk-adjusted trading rule profits have declined over time-from an average of over 3% in the late 1970s and early 1980s to about zero in the 1990s. Thus, market inefficiencies reported in previous studies may have been only temporary inefficiencies. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Olson, D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adverse selection costs, trading activity and price discovery in the NYSE: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pascual, R.; Escribano, A.; Tapia, M.
This paper studies the role that trading activity plays in the price discovery process of a NYSE-listed stock. We measure the expected information content of each trade by estimating its permanent price impact. It depends on observable trade features and market conditions. We also estimate the time required for quotes to incorporate all the information content of a particular trade. Our results show that price discovery is faster after risky trades and also at the extreme intervals of the session. The quote adjustment to trade-related shocks is progressive and this causes risk persistency and unusual short-term market conditions. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pascual, R.; Escribano, A.; Tapia, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An essay on financial innovation: The case of instalment receipts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charupat, N.; Prisman, E. Z.
We investigate the relative pricing of an innovated security called "instalment receipts" (IRs). IRs are securities that evidence the purchase of some underlying securities on an instalment basis. Theoretically, we show that investors with borrowing restrictions will be willing to pay for the leverage benefit embedded in IRs. We then provide an empirical support for our argument. The observed premium in IR price over the underlying price implies that by using IRs, the issuers benefit from both an increase in demand and a reduction in the price concessions that they have to make to ensure the success of their offerings. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Charupat, N.; Prisman, E. Z.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pricing of systematic liquidity risk: Empirical evidence from the US stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gibson, R.; Mougeot, N.
In this study, we examine whether aggregate market liquidity risk is priced in the US stock market. We define a bivariate Garch (l,1)-in-mean specification for the market portfolio excess returns and the changes in the standardized number of shares in the S&amp;P 500 Index, the aggregate market liquidity proxy. The findings, based on monthly data, suggest that systematic liquidity risk is priced in the US over the period January 1973-December 1997. The liquidity premium represents a non-negligible, negative and time-varying component of the total market risk premium whose magnitude is not influenced by the October'87 Crash. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gibson, R.; Mougeot, N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic entry and market leadership in a two-player real options game</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shackleton, M. B.; Tsekrekos, A. E.; Wojakowski, R.
We analyse the entry decisions of competing firms in a two-player stochastic real option game, when rivals earn different but correlated uncertain profitabilities from operating. In the presence of entry costs, decision thresholds exhibit hysteresis, the range of which is decreasing in the correlation between competing firms. A measure of the expected time of each firm being active in the market and the probability of both rivals entering within a finite time are explicitly calculated. The former (latter) is found to decrease (increase) with the volatility of relative firm profitabilities implying that market leadership is shorter-lived the more uncertain the industry environment. In an application of the model to the aircraft industry, we find that Boeing's optimal response to Airbus' launch of the A380 super carrier is to accommodate entry and supplement its current product line, as opposed to the riskier alternative of committing to the development of a corresponding super jumbo. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shackleton, M. B.; Tsekrekos, A. E.; Wojakowski, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical evidence on payment media costs and switch points</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>ten Raa, T.; Shestalova, V.
This paper recovers micro cost schedules of consumers' payment instruments from aggregate transaction costs. We assume that only two moments of the size distribution of payments matter: the number and volume of transactions. These variables explain the transaction costs of currency and debit card payments with much precision for a representative 1998 sample of Dutch retailers. The results imply that low fixed transaction costs favor currency for small transactions, while low variable transaction costs favor debit card payments for large transactions. The switch point is 30 Euros, but including the hidden costs of currency would lower it to 13 Euros. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>ten Raa, T.; Shestalova, V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factors affecting bank risk taking: Evidence from Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Konishi, M.; Yasuda, Y.
Using recent data from Japan, this paper examines empirically the determinants of risk taking at commercial banks. We find that the implementation of the capital adequacy requirement reduced risk taking at commercial banks. The acceptance of retired government officials on banks' boards has an insignificant effect on bank risk. The relationship between the stable shareholders' ownership and bank risk is nonlinear; the risk decreases initially with the ownership by stable shareholders, and then increases as the asset substitution effect dominates the effect of managerial entrenchment on bank risk. The decline of franchise value increases bank risk. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Konishi, M.; Yasuda, Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The national market impact of sovereign rating changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brooks, R.; Faff, R. W.; Hillier, D.; Hillier, J.
This study investigates the aggregate stock market impact of sovereign rating changes. Consistent with evidence pertaining to company credit rating changes, we report that rating downgrades have a negative wealth impact on market returns. Moreover, we find that a downgrade impacts negatively on both the domestic stock market and the dollar value of the country's currency. Interestingly, of the four credit rating agencies examined, only Standard &amp; Poors and Fitch rating downgrades result in significant market falls. Finally, we can find no evidence that emerging markets are particularly sensitive to rating changes or that markets react more severely to multiple rating changes. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brooks, R.; Faff, R. W.; Hillier, D.; Hillier, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Follow-on offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harper, J. T.; Johnston, J.; Madura, J.
Previous research has determined that lockup provisions essentially defer sell-offs of shares by insiders, and therefore cause a pronounced decline in share price at the time the lockup provisions expire. However, some IPOs involve follow-on offerings that may allow some insiders to sell their shares before the lockup provision has expired. Our objective is to determine how follow-on offerings alter firm value above and beyond the typical lockup effects, and whether the effects are conditioned by firm-specific variables. We find that follow-on offerings elicit an average market response of 3.21% over a three-day period surrounding the filing date. In addition, the offerings experience adverse effects as of lockup expiration that are about 3.75% worse than other IPOs, after considering other factors. Based on the share price response at the time of the follow-on offering along with the share price response at the time of lockup expiration, the cumulative effects for IPOs complemented by follow-on offerings are about 6.96% weaker than for IPOs not complemented by follow-on offerings. Overall, follow-on offerings may benefit some insiders who can circumvent the lockup expiration date, at the expense of other investors. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harper, J. T.; Johnston, J.; Madura, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The integration of bank syndicated loan and junk bond markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thomas, H.; Wang, Z. Q.
This paper hypothesizes that the special role of banks as corporate quasi-insiders has been changing due to developments in informational, legal and institutional infrastructures of syndicated loan markets. We investigate the integration of intermediated and disintermediated financial markets through highly leveraged transaction (HLT) syndicated loans during the 1990s. We demonstrate that, with the emergence of traded HLT syndicated loans as an alternative high-yield asset to high-yield bonds, market integration has dramatically increased. Taking the late 1980s and 1990s together, different factors explain the movement of credit spreads of the two markets. HLT loan market's spreads are strongly affected by bank liquidity. Bank liquidity's effect on HLT loan spreads disappears after 1993. From 1994-1999, junk bond market liquidity factors affect bank loan pricing. We interpret these changes as evidence of the erosion of bank specialness. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thomas, H.; Wang, Z. Q.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management strategies for banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauer, W.; Ryser, M.
We analyze optimal risk management strategies of a bank financed with deposits and equity in a one period model. The bank's motivation for risk management comes from deposits which can lead to bank runs. In the event of such a run, liquidation costs arise. The hedging strategy that maximizes the value of equity is derived. We identify conditions under which well known results such as complete hedging, maximal speculation or irrelevance of the hedging decision are obtained. The initial debt ratio, the size of the liquidation costs, regulatory restrictions, the volatility of the risky asset and the spread between the riskless interest rate and the deposit rate are shown to be the important parameters that drive the bank's hedging decision. We further extend this basic model to include counterparty risk constraints on the forward contract used for hedging. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bauer, W.; Ryser, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The propensity for local traders in futures markets to ride losses: Evidence of irrational or rational behavior?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frino, A.; Johnstone, D.; Zheng, H.
Behavioral studies of individual traders' decisions indicate that the "disposition effect" the propensity of traders to ride losses yet realize gains - is motivated by psychological rather than rational economic considerations. Consistent with previous studies by Heisler [Rev. Futures Markets 13 (1994) 793], Odean [J. Finance 53 (1998) 1775] and Locke and Mann [Do professional traders exhibit loss realization aversion? Working Paper, George Washington University, 2000], we find evidence of a disposition effect for both on-floor professional futures traders ("locals") and a matched sample of non-local traders. After controlling for potential differences in trader characteristics, comparisons reveal a stronger disposition effect among locals than non-local traders. Given that locals must trade profitably to survive, it is improbable that they are more irrational in their loss riding than non-locals. To the contrary, evidence is provided that paper losses for local traders are more likely than for non-locals to become either realized or paper gains by the time of the next transaction. This result is consistent with the hypothesis that locals, by their presence on the trading floor, have privileged albeit short-lived information on order flow that allows them to form relatively accurate probability predictions of the direction and strength of short-term market price shifts. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frino, A.; Johnstone, D.; Zheng, H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why markets should not necessarily reduce the tick size</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bourghelle, D.; Declerck, F.
This paper studies the consequences of a tick size change on the Paris Bourse thus providing a natural experiment on an order-driven market. The change raised the tick size for some stocks and lowered it for other. In contrast with US exchanges results, this generated neither a reduction in liquidity provision for large trades nor a change in the spread. Based on this paper and on US results, it appears an increasing but convex relationship between the relative tick size and the relative spread. Thus, it implies that a new pricing grid does not necessarily lead to change execution costs but it changes the level of transparency in the liquidity supply. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bourghelle, D.; Declerck, F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can bank be a source of contagion during the 1997 Asian crisis?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tai, C. S.
This paper tests whether bank can be a source of contagion during the 1997 Asian crisis using asset return data from a crisis country - Thailand. In particular, I examine whether Thai banking sector can produce contagion effects in both conditional means and volatilities of its foreign exchange and stock markets during the crisis after controlling economic fundamentals. The test results show that contagion-in-mean effects appear to be multidirectional since return shocks emanating from any one of the three markets can sweep across all markets, but contagion-in-volatility effects are mainly driven by the negative return shocks originating in the banking sector. Overall the empirical evidence indicates that the past return shocks emanating from banking sector have significant impact not only on the volatilities of foreign exchange and aggregate stock markets, but also on their prices, suggesting that bank can be a major source of contagion during the crisis. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tai, C. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information precision, transaction costs, and trading volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barron, O. E.; Karpoff, J. M.
Most theoretical models of trade (Pfleiderer, 1984; Grundy and McNichols, 1989; Holthausen and Verrecchia, 1990; Kim and Verrecchia, 1991; Blume et al., 1994) imply that the trading volume prompted by a public announcement is positively related to the announcement's precision. Relying upon this notion, empirical researchers interpret high trading volume as an indication that an announcement is highly informative. We argue that such interpretations are not, in general, correct. In a world with transaction costs, the relation between information precision and trading volume is ambiguous and can be negative. This explains why, in empirical tests using data from actual markets, the relation between announcement precision and trading volume is not monotonically positive, even though in laboratory experiments it is. Our results imply that trading volume reactions to public announcements are most sensitive to announcement precision among low-transaction cost securities and in low-cost trading regimes. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barron, O. E.; Karpoff, J. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Too much of a good incentive? The case of executive stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Y. S.
Using a utility-maximization framework, I show that the incentive to increase stock price does not always increase as more options are granted. Keeping the total cost of his compensation fixed, granting more options creates greater incentives to increase stock price only if option wealth does not exceed a certain fraction of total wealth. Beyond this critical level, granting more options actually reduces incentive effects and becomes counterproductive. In addition, stock options also create incentive to reduce (increase) idiosyncratic (systematic) risk. These incentive effects arc sensitive to the choice of exercise price. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tian, Y. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A study of the corporate governance of thrifts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cook, D. O.; Hogan, A.; Kieschnick, R.
We study corporate governance within the thrift industry during a period of industry distress and legally mandated regulatory vigilance. We find evidence consistent with the Office of Thrift Supervision displacing the disciplinary role of takeovers in the market for thrift control. Poorer prior thrift performance is associated with a greater likelihood of censure while better prior performance is associated with a greater likelihood of acquisition. For thrifts that are not censured or acquired, there is no relationship between current performance and managerial turnover. Replacement due to retirement rather than board discipline explains most of these turnovers. This result is consistent with the notion that regulation may deter board disciplinary behavior, also suggested by Kole and Lehr [Journal of Financial Economics 52 (1999) 79]. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cook, D. O.; Hogan, A.; Kieschnick, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Location of trade, ownership restrictions, and market illiquidity: Examining Chinese A- and H-shares</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, S. S.; Li, J. A.
We examine Chinese companies that issue both A-shares in mainland China and H-shares in Hong Kong. A-shares are restricted to mainland Chinese investors, while H-shares are available to Hong Kong and international investors. We find that H-shares exhibit significant exposure to Hong Kong market factors and behave more like Hong Kong stocks than mainland Chinese stocks. However, H-shares retain significant exposure to their domestic market and therefore provide foreign investors with diversification opportunities. We find a large time-varying H-share price discount relative to A-shares, and this discount is highly correlated with domestic and foreign market factors and relative market illiquidity. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, S. S.; Li, J. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional funding costs of inflation-indexed and conventional government bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reschreiter, A.
This paper employs the predictability of monthly excess returns of UK conventional and index-linked gilts to study the risk premiums of nominal and real bonds. The estimates of a single-latent-variable model suggest that indexed gilts of medium and long maturities require half the risk compensation of conventional gilts. The government can significantly reduce its long run borrowing costs through issuing inflation index-linked debt, however, the inflation indexation of bonds with maturities less than 3 years does not significantly reduce their risk compensation. Membership in the exchange rate mechanism did not significantly change the risk compensation of conventional and indexed gilts. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Reschreiter, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal liquidity management and bail-out policy in the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ringbom, S.; Shy, O.; Stenbacka, R.
We characterize the profit-maximizing reserves of a commercial bank, and the generated probability of a liquidity crisis, as a function of the penalty imposed by the Central Bank, the probability of depositors' liquidity needs, and the return on outside investment opportunities. We demonstrate that banks do not fully internalize the social cost associated with the bail-out policy if the liquidity needs of individuals are correlated, and that competitive interbank markets will induce banks to raise their reserves under reasonable conditions. The marginal benefits from an interbank market decrease as the correlation between the liquidity shocks of banks increases. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ringbom, S.; Shy, O.; Stenbacka, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading activity and price reversals in futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, C. Y.; Yu, M.
We use the standard contrarian portfolio approach to examine short-horizon return predictability in 24 US futures markets. We find strong evidence of weekly return reversals, similar to the findings from equity market studies. When interacting between past returns and lagged changes in trading activity (volume and/or open interest), we find that the profits to contrarian portfolio strategies are, on average, positively associated with lagged changes in trading volume, but negatively related to lagged changes in open interest. We also show that futures return predictability is more pronounced if interacting between past returns and lagged changes in both volume and open interest. Our results suggest that futures market overreaction exists, and both past prices and trading activity contain useful information about future market movements. These findings have implications for futures market efficiency and are useful for futures market participants, particularly commodity pool operators. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, C. Y.; Yu, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-country comparisons of efficiency: Evidence from the UK and Italian investment firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beccalli, E.
This paper compares and reconciles two new methods for cross-country comparisons of the cost efficiency of UK and Italian investment firms over the period 1995-1998. It employs four different specifications of the stochastic frontier methodology, using a translog cost function in order to measure X-efficiency. The traditional common frontier reveals that Italian investment firms are nearly as efficient as UK firms. To overcome traditional limitations, two methods are used in this paper. They provide consistent results. The first method shows differences between the efficiency of the two countries by incorporating environmental variables into the cross-country common frontier. The second method shows differences in the efficiency of the domestic versus foreign investment firms in the two countries, by testing the ability to monitor and control on a cross-border basis. Finally, to identify investment firms that are both cost and profit efficient, we undertake a profitability test. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beccalli, E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional covariances and direct central bank interventions in the foreign exchange markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beine, M.
In this paper, we investigate the effects of central bank interventions (CBIs) on the ex post correlation and covariance of exchange rates. Using a multivariate GARCH model with time-varying conditional covariances, we estimate the effects of CBIs on both the variances and covariance between the yen and the deutsche mark (the Euro) in terms of the US dollar. Our results suggest that coordinated CBIs not only tend to increase the volatility of exchange rates but also explain a significant amount of the covariance between the major currencies. We show that this result can be useful for short-run currency portfolio management. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beine, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-border acquisitions of US financial institutions: Impact of macroeconomic factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kiymaz, H.
This study investigates the impact of mergers and acquisitions on US bidders and targets involved in cross-border mergers of financial institutions. The findings indicate that while US targets experience positive significant wealth gains, US bidders encounter insignificant wealth gains during the merger announcements. There are also differences in wealth gains with respect to industry classification and to the regional location of foreign targets and bidders. The macroeconomic variables, including foreign and US economic conditions, level of economic development of target country, exchange rate volatility along with the effectiveness of foreign government, relative size of participants, and control of target largely explain the wealth gains to bidders and targets. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kiymaz, H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public information arrival and volatility of intraday stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalev, P. S.; Liu, W. M.; Pham, P. K.; Jarnecic, E.
This study employs firm-specific announcements as a proxy for information flows and investigates the information-volatility relation using high-frequency data from the Australian Stock Exchange. Our analysis reveals a positive and significant impact of the arrival rate of the selected news variable on the conditional variance of stock returns, even after controlling for the potential effects of trading volume and high opening volatility. Furthermore, the inclusion of the news variable in the conditional variance equation of the generalized autoregressive conditional heteroscedastic model also reduces volatility persistence, especially with intraday data. Combined with the evidence that news arrivals display a very strong pattern of autocorrelation, our results are consistent with the Mixture of Distribution Hypothesis, which attributes conditional heteroscedasticity of stock returns to time-dependence in the news arrival process. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kalev, P. S.; Liu, W. M.; Pham, P. K.; Jarnecic, E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cyclical behavior of optimal bank capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Estrella, A.
This paper presents a dynamic model of optimal bank capital in which the bank optimizes over costs associated with failure, holding capital, and flows of external capital. The solution to the infinite-horizon stochastic optimization problem is related to period-by-period value at risk (var) in which the optimal probability of failure is endogenously determined. Over a cycle, var is positively correlated with optimal flows of external capital, but negatively correlated with optimal net changes in capital and the optimal level of total capital. Analysis of this pattern suggests that a regulatory minimum requirement based on var, if binding, is likely to be procyclical. The model points to several ways of reducing this problem. For example, a var-based requirement makes more sense if it is applied to external capital flows than if it is applied to the total level of capital. US commercial bank data since 1984 are generally consistent with the model. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Estrella, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retail credit risk management and measurement: An introduction to the special issue</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berlin, M.; Mester, L. J.
nan</description><author>Berlin, M.; Mester, L. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Issues in the credit risk modeling of retail markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, L.; DeLong, G.; Saunders, A.
We Survey the most recent BIS proposals for the credit risk measurement of retail credits in capital regulations. We also describe the recent trend away from relationship lending toward transactional lending in the small business loan arena. These trends create the opportunity to adopt more analytical, data-based approaches to credit risk measurement. We survey proprietary credit scoring models (such as Fair Isaac), as well as options-theoretic structural models (Such as KMV and Moody's RiskCalc), and reduced-form models (such as Credit Risk Plus). These models allow lenders and regulators to develop techniques that rely oil portfolio aggregation to measure retail credit risk exposure. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allen, L.; DeLong, G.; Saunders, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default correlation: An empirical investigation of a subprime lender</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cowan, A. M.; Cowan, C. D.
In recent years, subprime lending has grown Substantially as an important sector of the credit markets. This paper is concerned with the risk management of subprime loan portfolios and the importance of default correlation in measuring that risk. Using a large portfolio of residential subprime loans from an anonymous subprime lender, we show that default correlation is substantial for this lender. In particular, the significance of default correlation increases as the internal credit rating declines. Our results suggest that lenders and regulators would be well served investing in the Understanding of default correlation in subprime portfolios. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cowan, A. M.; Cowan, C. D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should SME exposures be treated as retail or corporate exposures? A comparative analysis of default probabilities and asset correlations in French and German SMEs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dietsch, M.; Petey, J.
We use a one-factor credit risk model to provide new estimates of stationary default probabilities and asset correlations in two large samples of French and German Small and Medium-sized Enterprises. Results show that, on average, SMEs are riskier than large businesses; and the asset correlations in the SME population are very weak (1-3% on average) and decrease with size. On average, the relationship between PDs and asset correlations is not negative, as assumed by Basel II, but positive, especially at the industry level, in the two countries. It is also possible to distinguish different segments inside the SMEs' population: at least between very small and small SMEs and large SMEs. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dietsch, M.; Petey, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>