<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF18</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Economic and regulatory capital allocation for revolving retail exposures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perli, R.; Nayda, W. I.
We present two internal capital allocation models and compare the capital ratios they generate with those prescribed by the latest revision of Basel's New Capital Accord proposal for advanced retail portfolios, which allows for explicit future margin income recognition. Given a test portfolio of credit card exposures that we assemble, we find that Basel's ratios are closer to those generated by our models for low credit risk segments. We attribute the discrepancies to the different ways Basel and our models account for future margin income, to Basel's assumptions about asset correlations and to one model taking macroeconomic conditions into account. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Perli, R.; Nayda, W. I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit risk in the leasing industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmit, M.
This paper is devoted to the credit risk modeling issues of retail lease portfolios. Using a resampling method, I estimate the probability density function of, losses and VaR measures in a portfolio of 46,732 leases issued between 1990 and 2000 by a major European financial institution. My results show that physical collaterals play a major role in reducing the credit risk associated with lease portfolios. However, because of insufficient recognition of such collaterals under the new regulatory capital framework (Base II), significant differences are observed between the estimated capital requirements and those calculated in accordance with the various Basel II approaches. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schmit, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer credit scoring: Do situational circumstances matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avery, R. B.; Calem, P. S.; Canner, G. B.
Although credit history scoring offers benefits to lenders and borrowers, failure to consider situational circumstances raises important statistical issues that may affect the ability of scoring systems to accurately quantify an individual's credit risk. Evidence from a national sample of credit reporting agency records suggests that failure to consider measures of local economic circumstances and individual trigger events when developing credit history scores can diminish the potential effectiveness of such models. There are practical difficulties, however, associated with developing scoring models that incorporate situational data, arising largely because of inherent limitations of the credit reporting agency databases used to build scoring models. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avery, R. B.; Calem, P. S.; Canner, G. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does reject inference really improve the performance of application scoring models?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crook, J.; Banasik, J.
The parameters of application scorecards are Usually estimated using a sample that excludes rejected applicants which may prove biased when applied to all applicants. This paper uses a rare sample that includes those who would normally be rejected to examine the extent to which (1) the exclusion of rejected applicants undermines the predictive performance of a scorecard based only on accepted applicants, and (2) reject inference techniques can remedy the influence of this exclusion. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Crook, J.; Banasik, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What is the value of recourse to asset-backed securities? A clinical study of credit card banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Higgins, E. J.; Mason, J. R.
The present paper uses credit card securitization data to show that recourse to securitized debt may benefit short- and long-term stock returns and long-term operating performance of sponsors. Therefore, although recourse violates regulatory guidelines and FASB140, recourse may have beneficial effects for sponsors by revealing that the shocks that made recourse necessary are transitory. Sponsors providing recourse do, however, experience an abnormal delay in their normal issuance cycle around the event. Hence, it appears that the asset-backed securities market is like the commercial paper market, where a firm's ability to issue is directly correlated with credit quality. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Higgins, E. J.; Mason, J. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging behavior in small and medium-sized enterprises: The role of unobserved heterogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pennings, J. M. E.; Garcia, P.
We investigate factors that drive derivative usage in small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs). The influence of these factors on hedging behavior cannot a priori be assumed equal for all SMEs. To address this heterogeneity, a generalized mixture regression model is used which classifies firms into segments, so that the hedging response to the determinants of derivative usage is the same within each segment. Using a unique data set of 415 SMEs, containing both accounting and experimental data, we find that factors like risk exposure, risk perception, risk attitude, and the decision-making unit, among others are useful in explaining hedging behavior. However, the effects of these factors are not homogeneous across all managers, and the roots of the heterogeneity can partially be traced to differences in attitudes, Perceptions, and to differences in ownership structure. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pennings, J. M. E.; Garcia, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do spin-offs really create value? The European case</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Veld, C.; Veld-Merkoulova, Y. V.
We study wealth effects for a sample of 156 spin-offs from 15 different European countries that were announced between January 1987 and September 2000. The cumulative average abnormal return over the 3-day event window is 2.62%. This number increases, to 2.66% for the subsequently completed spin-offs. The cumulative average abnormal return is 3.57% for completed spin-offs by companies that increase their industrial focus and only 0.76% for non-focus increasing companies. The difference between these two sub-samples is significantly different from zero. These results are in line with previous studies for the US. The long-run returns in excess of matching firms are mostly insignificant for parents, subsidiaries and pro-forma combined firms. This result suggests that, unlike US spin-offs, European spin-offs are not associated with long-run superior performance. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Veld, C.; Veld-Merkoulova, Y. V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of negative cash flow and influential observations on investment-cash flow sensitivity estimates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allayannis, G.; Mozumdar, A.
Kaplan and Zingales [Quart. J. Econ. 112 (1997) 169] and Clearly [J. Finance 54 (2) (1999) 673] diverge from the large literature on investment-cash flow sensitivity by showing that investment is most sensitive to cash flow for the least financially constrained firms. We examine if this result can be explained by the fact that when firms are in sufficiently bad shape (incurring cash losses), investment cannot respond to cash flow. We find that while Cleary's results can be explained by such negative cash flow observations, the Kaplan-Zingales results are driven more by a few influential observations in a small sample. We also record a decline in investment-cash flow sensitivity over the 1977-1996 period, particularly for the most constrained firms. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allayannis, G.; Mozumdar, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The medium-term aftermarket in high-tech IPOs: Patterns and implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jaggia, S.; Thosar, S.
A number of theoretical models, loosely characterized under the rubric of behavioral finance, suggest that price convergence to value is far from instantaneous and possibly involves interplay between noise and informed traders. These models are motivated by documented anomalous patterns in equity markets and assume some form of psychological bias that affects investor behavior. With the benefit of hindsight it seems clear that the technology sector went through a bubble-like pattern in the late 1990s and that investor biases (if indeed they exist and can be inferred) may have been even more pronounced. Accordingly, our study focuses on the medium-term aftermarket in high-tech US IPOs during this period. Using both ordered logit regression and split-population hazard modeling approaches, we document momentum and reversal patterns that are consistent with the predictions of some behavioral finance models. Our findings indicate that momentum variables are important while fundamental variables have at best weak explanatory power. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jaggia, S.; Thosar, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic optimal control, international finance and debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleming, W. H.; Stein, J. L.
We use stochastic optimal control-dynamic programming (DP) to derive the optimal debt/net worth, consumption/net worth, current account/net worth, and endogenous growth rate in an economy - which could be a country, region or sector within a country. Unlike the literature that uses an intertemporal budget constraint or the Maximum Principle, the DP approach does not require perfect foresight or certainty equivalence. Our results are generalizations of the Merton model, and are explained graphically within a mean-variance context. Two examples are provided to illustrate the usefulness of our technique in predicting debt crises. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fleming, W. H.; Stein, J. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit derivatives with multiple debt issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francois, P.; Hubner, G.
We evaluate the most actively traded types of credit derivatives within a unified pricing framework that allows for multiple debt issues. Since firms default on all of their obligations, total debt is instrumental in the likelihood of default and therefore in credit derivatives valuation. We use a single factor interest rate model where the exponential default frontier is based on total debt and is made coherent with observed bond prices. Analytical formulae are derived for credit default swaps, total return swaps (both fixed-for-fixed and fixed-for-floating), and credit risk options (CROs). Price behaviors and hedging properties of all these credit derivatives are investigated. Simulations document that credit derivatives prices may be significantly affected by terms of debt other than those of the reference obligation. The analysis of CROs indicates their superior ability to fine-tune the hedging of magnitude and arrival risks of default. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Francois, P.; Hubner, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Futures trading activity and predictable foreign exchange market movements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, C. Y.
In this paper, we examine the relation between futures trading activity by trader type and returns over short horizons in five foreign currency futures markets - British pound, Canadian dollar, Deutsche mark, Japanese yen, and Swiss franc. Transforming trading activity into a sentiment measure, we find that speculator sentiment is positively related to future returns. In contrast, hedger sentiment covaries negatively with future returns. We also find that extreme sentiment by trader type is more correlated with future market movements than moderate sentiment. Our results suggest that hedgers lose to speculators in these futures markets, on average. Based on equilibrium pricing models that futures risk premiums art: determined by both market risk and hedging pressure, we show that the profits to speculators are in general compensation for bearing risk. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, C. Y.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market liquidity of DIAMONDS, Q's, and their underlying stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hegde, S. P.; McDermott, J. B.
We investigate the market liquidity effects of the introduction of index-tracking stocks for the Dow Jones Industrial Average (DIAMONDS) and the NASDAQ 100 index (Q's). Our main finding is liquidity of the underlying DJIA 30 index stocks improves after the introduction of the exchange-traded fund, largely because of a decline in the cost of informed trading. Further, we find the DIAMONDS has significantly lower liquidity costs over the first 50 days of trading as compared to the portfolio of its component stocks, again primarily because of lower adverse selection costs. Finally, we find weaker but qualitatively similar results for the Q's. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hegde, S. P.; McDermott, J. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Duration models and IRR management: A question of dimensions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Soto, G. M.
This paper compares the immunization performance of alternative single and Multiple factor duration models, using Spanish government bond data, over 1, 2 and 3-year horizons. The aim is to assess whether the success of duration-matching strategies is primarily attributable to the particular model chosen or to the number of risk factors considered. Empirical tests show that: (i) traditional immunization is easily bettered by more realistic strategies; (ii) the number of risk factors considered has a greater influence on the result than the particular model chosen; and (iii) three-factor immunization strategies offer the highest immunization benchmarks. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Soto, G. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of risk regulation on price dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danielsson, J.; Shin, H. S.; Zigrand, J. P.
Most financial risk regulations assume that asset returns are exogenous, where risk is estimated from historical data. This assumption fails to take into account the feedback effect of trading decisions on prices. We investigate the consequences of risk constrained trading by means of simulations of a general equilibrium model with a value-at-risk constraint and compare the results to the case when risk constraints are not present. Prices are lower on average in the presence of risk regulation, while volatility is higher. Risk regulation may have the perverse effect of exacerbating price fluctuations. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Danielsson, J.; Shin, H. S.; Zigrand, J. P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading intensity, volatility, and arbitrage activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, N.
The objective of this paper is to uncover the determinants of trading intensity in futures markets. In particular, the time between adjacent transactions (referred to as transaction duration) on the FTSE 100 index futures market is modeled using various augmentations of the basic autoregressive conditional duration (ACD) model introduced by Engle and Russell [Econometrica 66 (1998) 1127]. The definition of transaction duration used in this paper is an important variable as it represents the inverse of instantaneous conditional return volatility. As such, this paper can also be viewed as an investigation into the determinants of (the inverse of) instantaneous conditional return volatility. The estimated parameters from various ACD models form the basis of the hypothesis tests carried out in the paper. As predicted by various market microstructure theories, we find that bid-ask spread and transaction volume have a significant impact upon subsequent trading intensity. However, the major innovation of this paper is the finding that large (small) differences between the market price and the theoretical price of the futures contract (referred to as pricing error) lead to high (low) levels of trading intensity in the subsequent period. Moreover, the functional dependence between pricing error and transaction duration appears to be non-linear in nature. Such dependence is implied by the presence of arbitragers facing non-zero transaction costs. Finally, a comparison of the forecasting ability of the various estimated models shows that a threshold ACD model provides the best out-of-sample performance. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Taylor, N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political news and stock prices: The case of Saddam Hussein contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amihud, Y.; Wohl, A.
This paper studies the association between the market's expectations of Saddam Hussein's fall from power, as reflected in "Saddam contract" prices, and stock prices, oil prices and exchange rates. During the war, a rise in the probability of Saddam's fall, which also indicated a speedy end to the war, was positively and significantly associated with stock prices, strengthened the dollar against the Euro, and lowered oil prices. Before the war, a rise in the probability of Saddam's fall, which may also have indicated the probability of a costly war breaking out. lowered stock prices, which adjusted gradually to this information. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amihud, Y.; Wohl, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why firms use convertibles: A further test of the sequential-financing hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, S. C.; Chen, S. S.; Liu, Y. C.
The sequential-financing hypothesis advanced by Mayers [J. Financ. Econ. 47 (1998) 83] suggests that convertibles are more valuable for issuing firms with focused activities. The hypothesis also suggests that firms may design their convertibles so that there are sufficient internal funds for future investment expenditures so as to avoid the costs of accessing capital markets. This paper provides direct evidence for these two predictions. We find that the stock market responds more favorably to the announcements of convertible offerings by focused firms than to those by diversified firms. This finding holds even after controlling for other potential explanatory variables. We also find that the issuing firms' net new financing is not significantly different from zero over the life of the convertible debt. Thus, our results provide further support for the sequential-financing hypothesis that convertible debt financing is motivated by a desire to minimize security issue costs and agency costs of overinvestment for firms with promising growth opportunities to finance a sequence of potential investment options. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, S. C.; Chen, S. S.; Liu, Y. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should bank runs be prevented?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Samartin, M.
This paper extends Diamond and Dybvig's model [J. Political Economy 91 (1983) 401] to a framework in which bank assets are risky, there is aggregate uncertainty about the demand for liquidity in the population and some individuals receive a signal about bank asset quality. Others must then try to deduce from observed withdrawals whether an unfavorable signal was received by this group or whether liquidity needs happen to be high. In this environment, both information-induced and pure panic runs will occur. However, banks can prevent them by designing the deposit contract appropriately. It is shown that in some cases it is optimal for the bank to prevent runs but there are situations where the bank run allocation may be welfare superior. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Samartin, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intra-industry effects of bank privatization: A clinical analysis of the privatization of the Commonwealth Bank of Australia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Otchere, I.; Chan, J.
This paper provides a comprehensive analysis of the effects of the privatization of the Commonwealth Bank of Australia (CBA) on the Bank's performance and that of the rival banks. First, we find that the major rival banks reacted negatively to the privatization announcements although the initial (partial privatization) and the final (full) privatization announcements elicited stronger stock market reaction from the rival banks. Second, we find that the CRA's long-term stock market performance improved markedly as the proportion of government ownership decreased, with the Bank's cumulative abnormal returns being 50% more than those of its rivals three years after the Bank had been fully privatized. Also, the CBA has not only been very efficient in reducing cost and improving its profitability in the post-privatization period, it has outperformed its rivals on almost all the operating performance measures and has become the most profitable bank in Australia. A particularly noteworthy finding is that the improvements in the CBA's operating and stock market performance and the rival banks' reaction to the partial and full privatization announcements were strongest after the Bank had been fully privatized. The implication of the results for governments contemplating privatization of state-owned enterprises is that full privatization is necessary in order to achieve strong gains in efficiency, profitability and stock market performance. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Otchere, I.; Chan, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underpricing, stock allocation, ownership structure and post-listing liquidity of newly listed firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pham, P. K.; Kalev, P. S.; Steen, A. B.
This study investigates the relationship between underpricing, ownership structure and post-listing liquidity of initial public offerings (IPOs). It is argued that higher underpricing induces both broader investor participation and creates a more diffuse ownership structure. These two factors are in turn positively associated with the level of post-listing trading, and therefore offer an explanation of how underpricing can influence liquidity. Using a sample of Australian IPOs, we provide evidence of statistically significant relationship between underpricing and various proxies for shareholding distribution and liquidity. This result remains robust after controlling for a number of potential underlying factors that may drive both underpricing and ownership allocation decisions. Overall, our analysis suggests that liquidity is a partial but important benefit of underpricing an IPO. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pham, P. K.; Kalev, P. S.; Steen, A. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency in Japanese banking: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drake, L.; Hall, M. J. B.
This paper utilises the non-parametric frontier approach, data envelopment analysis, to analyse the technical and scale efficiency in Japanese banking using a recent cross-section sample. Efficiency analysis is conducted across individual banks, bank types and bank size groups. Following Berger and Humphrey [Eur. J. Oper. Res. 98 (1997) 175], problem loans are controlled for as an exogenous influence on bank efficiency. Powerful size-efficiency relationships are established with respect to both technical and scale efficiency. Furthermore, the logic of the recent large-scale merger wave in Japan is questioned as the larger (City) banks are generally found to be operating above the minimum efficient scale and to have limited opportunity to gain from eliminating X-inefficiencies. The opposite result is found for the smaller banks. Finally, the results suggest that controlling for the exogenous impact of problem loans is important in Japanese banking, especially for the smaller regional banks. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Drake, L.; Hall, M. J. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock auction bidding behavior and information asymmetries: An empirical analysis using the discriminatory auction model framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, A. S.; Liaw, G.; Leung, M. T.
This paper empirically analyzes bidding behavior and information asymmetries of stock auctions using a discriminatory auction model framework. Analyzing stock auctions using auction theory is important because it provides a logical framework for explaining observable behaviors and a solid foundation for empirical testing. Because of limited availability of stock auction data, existing empirical research based on auction theory focus mainly on treasury auctions. Away from the treasury markets, however, there is a significant paucity of literature on this subject. In this study, we make use of a detailed stock auction data set from the Taiwan Stock Exchange to empirically examine the behaviors of the Taiwan stock auction market within the framework of the auction theory. Our results show that the level of competition, the dispersion of opinion among bidders, and the bidder's risk aversion are significant in determining auction prices. Results also show that if the offering prices are set equal to the average offering prices, the first-day post-initial public offering abnormal return will be equal to zero. Additionally, we find institutional bidders possess superior bidding skills compared to small bidders and that underwriter's characteristics influence the bidding results. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, A. S.; Liaw, G.; Leung, M. T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange rate exposures of US banks: A cash flow-based methodology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martin, A. D.; Mauer, L. J.
Using a cash flow-based framework, we decompose exchange rate exposure into short-term and long-term elements for 105 individual US banks over 1988-1998. We show that significant long-term exposure is more prevalent than significant short-term exposure, reflecting the difficulty in recognizing, modeling, and managing the longer-term effects of exchange rate risk. Our analyses reveal that 72% of internationally oriented and 88% of domestically oriented banks in the sample have significant exposure to at least one of five currency pairs. This result supports the theory that domestic banks are exposed and should be concerned about the indirect impact of exchange rate risk. Furthermore, we provide some evidence that economies of scale may exist for institutions with extensive international operations. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Martin, A. D.; Mauer, L. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence of predictability in the cross-section of bank stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, M. J.; Jackson, W. E.; Patterson, G. A.
In this paper, we examine the predictability of the cross-section of bank stock returns by taking advantage of the unique set of industry characteristics that prevail in the financial services sector. We examine predictability in the cross-section of bank stock returns using information contained in individual bank fundamental variables such as income from derivative usage, previous loan commitments, loan-loss reserves, earnings, and leverage. We find that variables related to non-interest income, loan-loss reserves, earnings, leverage, and standby letters of credit are all univariately important in forecasting the cross-section of bank stock returns. Surprisingly, neither book-to-market nor firm size is important in our sample. We examine whether this cross-sectional predictability is due to increased risk, or another explanation, such as investor under or overreaction. Our results suggest that this predictability is not due to increased risk, but rather is consistent with investor underreaction to changes in banks' fundamental variables. Furthermore, out-of-sample testing demonstrates this underreaction appears to be exploitable using simple cross-sectional trading strategies. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cooper, M. J.; Jackson, W. E.; Patterson, G. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency costs, ownership structure and corporate governance mechanisms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singh, M.; Davidson, W. N.
In this paper, we extend the work of Ang et al. [J. Finance 55 (1999) 81] to large firms. We find that managerial ownership is positively related to asset utilization but does not serve as a significant deterrent to excessive discretionary expenses. Outside block ownership may only have a limited effect on reducing agency costs. Furthermore, smaller boards serve the same role, but independent outsiders on a board do not appear to protect the firm from agency costs. Thus, this paper reports complementary evidence to Ang, Cole and Lin. In large publicly traded corporations, managerial ownership significantly alleviates principal-agent conflicts even in the presence of other agency deterrent mechanisms. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Singh, M.; Davidson, W. N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regionalism in Europe geometries and strategies after 2000</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luikert, K.
nan</description><author>Luikert, K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Maestro: Greenspan's and the American boom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, J. W.
nan</description><author>Davis, J. W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Irrational exuberance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edenfield, K. A.
nan</description><author>Edenfield, K. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Challenges for central banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Steigerwalt, G. M.
nan</description><author>Steigerwalt, G. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of the manager-shareholder conflict on acquiring bank returns (vol 27, pg 103, 2003)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornett, M. M.; Hovakimian, G.; Palia, D.; Tehranian, H.
nan</description><author>Cornett, M. M.; Hovakimian, G.; Palia, D.; Tehranian, H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On trust as a commodity and on the grammar of trust (vol 26,pg 1719, 2002)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khan, M. A.
nan</description><author>Khan, M. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Federal funds market and the overnight Eurodollar market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Y. S.
This paper investigates the effect of daily management of Federal Reserve accounts by US depository institutions on the interest rate outside the US. Spindt and Hoffmeister (Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 23 (1988) 401), Griffiths and Winters (Journal of Banking and Finance 19 (1995) 1265) and Hamilton (Journal of Political Economy 104 (1996) 22) found that the Fed funds rate exhibited calendar day effects caused by Federal Reserve regulations. I find that the overnight Eurodollar rate shows similar predictable daily changes as does the Fed funds rate although the absolute magnitudes are slightly less. The empirical results support the hypothesis that the tendencies in daily changes in the two overnight interest rates are caused by the characteristics of the Fed funds market. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Y. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do investors prefer even-eighth prices? Evidence from NYSE limit orders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooney, J. W.; Van Ness, B.; Van Ness, R.
Using a large sample of limit orders on NYSE stocks, we find that investors submit more limit orders with even-eighth prices than odd-eight prices. However, even though there are a greater number of even-eighth limit orders, the proportion of executing limit orders submitted with even prices is greater than those submitted with odd prices for a large portion of our sample. We find that clustering on even prices is a positive function of stock price and various proxies for the dispersion in investors' reservation prices. The preference for even prices affects stock quotes: Investors are more likely to submit a quote improving limit order if the limit price is even and quoted depth is higher for even quotes than for odd quotes. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cooney, J. W.; Van Ness, B.; Van Ness, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposit insurance and the risk premium in bank deposit rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartholdy, J.; Boyle, G. W.; Stover, R. D.
By placing a ceiling on the amount of possible depositor loss, deposit insurance should result in a lower deposit risk premium. However, this effect may be modified if either the insurance promise has low credibility or the moral hazard incentives generated by deposit insurance result in a greater probability of bank default. Using financial and institutional panel data from thirteen countries, we find that the risk premium is over 40 basis points higher on average in uninsured countries than in countries that offer insurance up to some pre-specified maximum. However, the risk premium has a non-linear relationship with the level of maximum insurance coverage, suggesting that the market recognizes the moral hazard potential. Moreover, the effect of deposit insurance on the risk premium is weaker in countries with strong creditor rights, consistent with the view that investors view the latter as a substitute for explicit deposit insurance. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bartholdy, J.; Boyle, G. W.; Stover, R. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do US stock prices deviate from their fundamental values? Some new evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhong, M. S.; Darrat, A. F.; Anderson, D. C.
We propose a new methodology to test Fama's [J. Finance 46 (1991) 1575] contention that the present value model (PVM) should be augmented by time-varying expected inflation to more adequately account for actual stock price behavior. Unlike other methods, our testing approach can distinguish between the excess-price movement hypothesis of Shiller [Am. Econ. Rev. 71 (1981) 421] and the dividend-smoothing hypothesis of Marsh and Merton [Am. Econ. Rev. 76 (1986) 483]. We decompose the levels (as opposed to the variances) of stock prices into their fundamental and non-fundamental elements in the context of a multivariate PVM co-integrating framework and utilize the Gonzalo and Granger [J. Bus. Econ. Stat. 13 (1995) 27] procedure to formally test for the statistical significance of the non-fundamental component. Our results from monthly data for the post-WWII period do not support the inflation-augmented PVM since the non-fundamental component continues to achieve significance. This finding persists under alternative model specifications and data frequencies. The apparent failure of the traditional, rational-expectation, PVM model to adequately account for observed market behavior provides another piece of evidence supportive of Shiller's [Am. Econ. Rev. 71 (1981) 591] belief in some form of market "irrationality". (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhong, M. S.; Darrat, A. F.; Anderson, D. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long- and short-run non-parametric cost frontier efficiency: An application to Spanish savings banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prior, D.
The utilisation rate of installed capacity is a popular concept in both the performance appraisal literature and in publications on industrial organisation. However, a common consensus has yet to be reached concerning the most appropriate way to measure the capacity utilisation of physical inputs and its final effect on company results. On the one hand, there are approaches that establish capacity utilisation with reference to the maximum level of production that can be achieved. In contrast, there are other approaches more strictly related to economic analysis of operating costs. In this paper, our main objective is to define an analytical process that uses non-parametric frontier methodology to provide the distance between the total costs of a given unit and the short-run frontier costs. As a natural extension of this proposal, it is possible to compute the short-run inefficiency caused by a non-optimal dimension of the fixed inputs: we define this as capacity efficiency. The proposed evaluation process is applied to Spanish savings banks covering the period between 1986 and 1995. Throughout the period analysed, the greater part of cost inefficiency is due to capacity efficiency. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Prior, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are convertible bonds underpriced? An analysis of the French market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ammann, M.; Kind, A.; Wilde, C.
We investigate the pricing of convertible bonds on the French convertible bond market using daily market prices for a period of 18 months. Instead of a firm-value model as used in previous studies, we use a stock-based binomial-tree model with exogenous credit risk that accounts for all important convertible bond specifications and is therefore well suited for pricing convertible bonds. The empirical analysis shows that the theoretical values for the analyzed convertible bonds are on average more than 3% higher than the observed market prices. This result applies to both the standard convertibles and the exchangeable bonds in our sample. The difference between market and model prices is greater for out-of-the-money convertibles than for at- or in-the-money convertibles. A partition of the sample according to maturity indicates that there is a positive relationship between underpricing and maturity with decreasing mispricing for bonds with shorter time to maturity. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ammann, M.; Kind, A.; Wilde, C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank lending policy, credit scoring and value-at-risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobson, T.; Roszbach, K.
This paper builds on the credit-scoring literature and proposes a method to calculate portfolio credit risk. Individual. default risk estimates are used to compose a value-at-risk (VaR) measure of credit risk. In general, credit-scoring models suffer from a sample-selection bias. The starting point is therefore to estimate an unbiased scoring model using the bivariate probit approach. The paper uses a large data set with Swedish consumer credit data that contains extensive financial and personal information on both rejected and approved applicants. We study how marginal changes in a default-risk-based acceptance rule would shift the size of the bank's loan portfolio, its VaR exposure and average credit losses. Finally, we compare the risk in the sample portfolio with that in an efficiently provided portfolio of equal size. The results show that the size of a small consumer loan does not affect associated default risk, implying that the bank provides loans in a way that is not consistent with default-risk minimization. VaR calculations indicate that an efficient selection (by means of a default-risk-based rule) of loan applicants can reduce credit risk by up to 80%. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacobson, T.; Roszbach, K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are unsolicited credit ratings biased downward?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poon, W. P. H.
There has been considerable controversy over unsolicited credit ratings in recent years. Some dissatisfied issuers allege that unsolicited ratings are biased downward in contrast to solicited ratings. This is the first empirical study to analyze the controversy using pooled time-series cross-sectional data of 265 firms in 15 countries from Standard and Poor's Ratings Services (S&amp;P's) during the period of 1998-2000. The results demonstrate that unsolicited ratings are lower. On the other hand, I also find that those issuers who choose not to obtain rating services from S&amp;P's have weaker financial profiles. Although the difference in ratings can be explained by this significant self-selection bias, results of the Japanese sub-sample indicate that unsolicited ratings are still lower than solicited ratings after controlling for differences in sovereign risk and key financial characteristics. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Poon, W. P. H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Random walk versus breaking trend in stock prices: Evidence from emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaudhuri, K.; Wu, Y. R.
This paper investigates whether stock-price indexes of seventeen emerging markets can be characterized as random walk (unit root) or mean reversion processes. We implement a test that can account for structural breaks in the underlying series and is more powerful than standard tests. We find that for fourteen countries, stock prices exhibit structural breaks. Furthermore, for ten countries, the null hypothesis of a random walk can be rejected at the one or 5% significance level. Our results indicate that ignoring structural breaks that arise from the liberalization of emerging markets can lead to incorrect inference that these indices are characterized by random walks, and are consistent with the points made by Bekaert et al. [J. Int. Money Finan. 21 (2002) 295]. Our findings hold true regardless of whether stock indexes are denominated in US dollar terms, in local currencies terms, or in real terms. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chaudhuri, K.; Wu, Y. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Binary choice models and corporate takeover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Espahbodi, H.; Espahbodi, P.
This paper utilizes four different classification procedures (binary choice models) and compares their ability to predict corporate takeovers. Specifically, the paper develops logit, probit, discriminant, and recursive partitioning, models to predict which firms will be taken over. The original classification accuracy and the validation test results indicate that the recursive partitioning model outperforms the other models (although its accuracy drops significantly in the validation test). The results also indicate the difficulty in predicting corporate takeovers. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Espahbodi, H.; Espahbodi, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamic relationship between the federal funds rate and the Treasury bill rate: An empirical investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarno, L.; Thornton, D. L.
This article examines the dynamic relationship between two key US money market interest rates-the federal funds rate (FF) and the 3-month Treasury bill rate. Using daily data over the period from 1974 to 1999, we find a long-run relationship between these two rates that is remarkably stable across monetary policy regimes of interest rate and monetary aggregate targeting. Employing a nonlinear asymmetric vector equilibrium correction model, which is novel in this context, we find that most of the adjustment toward the long-run equilibrium occurs through the FF. In turn, there is strong evidence for the existence of significant asymmetries and nonlinearities in interest rate dynamics that have implications for the conventional view of interest rate behavior. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sarno, L.; Thornton, D. L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO turnover in insider-dominated boards: The Italian case</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunello, G.; Graziano, C.; Parigi, B. M.
We investigate CEO turnover in relationship to performance, ownership concentration and CEO ownership in a sample of 60 private companies listed on the Italian Stock Exchanges over the 9-year period 1988-1996. Concentrated ownership, family control, limited institutional investors activism, and lack of main bank monitoring make Italy a corporate governance environment dominated by insiders. As a result, boards of directors are dominated by insiders and/or represent the interests of the controlling shareholders. Our main finding is that CEO turnover is negatively related to firm performance also in this environment, but this relationship holds only if the controlling shareholder is not the CEO. Our findings suggest that insiders with large stakes monitor and replace under-performing outside CEOs. The paper offers positive empirical evidence that non-CEO controlling shareholders are a governance mechanism that provides a substitute for outside members on boards of directors in lowering agency costs. When the CEO is an owner, however, we have all the negative aspects of insider-dominated boards. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brunello, G.; Graziano, C.; Parigi, B. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing the risk of recovery in default with absolute priority rule violation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Unal, H.; Madan, D.; Guntay, L.
This paper proposes a simple approach to infer the risk-neutral density of recovery rates implied by the prices of the debt securities of a firm. The proposed approach is independent of modeling default arrival rates and allows for the violation of absolute priority rule. The paper demonstrates that a new statistic, the adjusted relative spread, captures risk-neutral recovery information in debt prices. Interest rates and firm tangible assets are shown to be significant determinants of the price of recovery. An application illustrates the pricing of credit derivatives written on the realized recovery rate. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Unal, H.; Madan, D.; Guntay, L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive compensation and agency costs in Germany</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elston, J. A.; Goldberg, L. G.
With the growth of international mergers like DaimlerChrysler, interest in executive compensation practices abroad, particularly in Germany, has increased. Using unique data sources for Germany, we find that similar to US firms, German firms also have agency problems caused by the separation of ownership from control, with ownership dispersion leading to higher compensation. In addition, there is evidence that bank influence has a negative impact on compensation. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elston, J. A.; Goldberg, L. G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selecting a portfolio with skewness: Recent evidence from US, European, and Latin American equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prakash, A. J.; Chang, C. H.; Pactwa, T. E.
Polynomial goal programming, in which investor preferences for skewness can be incorporated, is utilized to determine the optimal portfolio from Latin American, US and European capital markets. The empirical findings suggest that the incorporation of skewness into an investor's portfolio decision causes a major change in the resultant optimal portfolio. The empirical evidence indicates that investors do trade expected return of the portfolio for skewness. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Prakash, A. J.; Chang, C. H.; Pactwa, T. E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early and late calls of convertible bonds: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkar, S.
Many convertible bonds are called too early or too late relative to the perfect markets decision rule of Ingersoll (1977a,b). We re-examine the convertible call decision under corporate taxation and possible default prior to maturity. Our model predicts that early calls will be associated with high coupon and low call premium, dividend income, volatility, tax rate and interest rate; and late calls will be associated with high call premium, dividend income, tax rate and interest rate, and low coupon and volatility. These implications are supported by empirical tests carried out with five years of convertible call data. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sarkar, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical examination of the role of the CEO and the compensation committee in structuring executive pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, R. C.; Bizjak, J. M.
Motivated by the potential for opportunistic behavior in pay decisions, recent SEC and IRS regulations essentially preclude inside directors from serving on a firm's compensation committee (CC). We examine whether greater CC independence promotes shareholder interests and whether the CEO's presence on the CC leads to opportunistic pay structure. We find little evidence that greater committee independence affects executive pay. Moreover, committees consisting of insiders or the CEO do not award excessive pay or lower overall incentives. For example, we find no evidence that pay decreases or total incentives increase when CEOs come off the CC. Our results suggest that regulations governing committee structure,may not reduce levels of pay or achieve efficiencies in incentive contracts. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anderson, R. C.; Bizjak, J. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance, dividend payout policy, and the interrelation between dividends, R&amp;D, and capital investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gugler, K.
This paper investigates the relationship between dividends and the ownership and control structure of the firm. For a panel of Austrian firms over the 1991/99 period, we find that state-controlled firms engage in dividend smoothing, while family-controlled firms do not. The latter choose significantly lower target payout levels. Consistently, state-controlled firms are most reluctant and family-controlled firms are least reluctant to cut dividends when cuts are warranted. The dividend behavior of bank- and foreign-controlled firms lies in between state-and family-controlled firms. This is consistent with the expected "ranking" of information asymmetries and managerial agency costs. The above results hold for firms with good investment opportunities. We find that firms with low growth opportunities optimally disgorge cash irrespective of who controls the firm. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gugler, K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the performance of firms following seasoned equity issues anomalous?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bayless, M.; Jay, N. R.
The hypothesis that negative abnormal returns following an equity issue are anomalous assumes the use of the correct benchmark. The alternative hypothesis assumes that an incorrect benchmark has been used or that benchmarks change following an issue. We evaluate these assumptions by examining the performance of SEO firms during periods when there was no issue activity. Results indicate that SEO firms experience positive abnormal returns away from the issue window and that positive performance is most pronounced for small SEO firms. These and other results are inconsistent with the alternative hypothesis. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bayless, M.; Jay, N. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should you carry the load? A comprehensive analysis of load and no-load mutual fund out-of-sample performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morey, M. R.
This paper compares the out-of-sample performance of no-load and load mutual funds. Unlike previous studies, this paper provides a more comprehensive analysis as it uses methodologies to incorporate loads directly into the returns. We find two important results. First, after adjusting for loads in the returns data, no-load funds are found to perform much better than load funds, with the differences found to be significant at the 1% level across many different performance metrics. Second, we find that within load funds themselves there is little significant difference in out-of-sample performance between high-load funds and low-load funds even after adjusting for loads. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morey, M. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discretionary accounting and the behavior of Japanese banks under financial duress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shrieves, R. E.; Dahl, D.
This paper investigates utilization of discretionary accounting practices in the context of international bank regulation under the Basle Accord. Specifically, we explore implications of earnings management as a means of regulatory-capital arbitrage by Japanese banks during a period of financial duress, 1989-1996. Using a sample of 607 pooled time series and cross-sectional observations, we find evidence that Japanese banks lending was capital constrained, and that banks set gains on securities sales and loan-loss provisions in such a way as to smooth reported income and replenish regulatory capital. Our results support the hypothesis that the form of earnings management examined may have been instrumental in enabling some Japanese banks to comply with international capital regulation. We contend that this behavior is otherwise inexplicable on the basis of significant informational, tax or economic motivations. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shrieves, R. E.; Dahl, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal hedging under departures from the cost-of-carry valuation: Evidence from the Spanish stock index futures market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lafuente, J. A.; Novales, A.
We provide an analytical discussion of the optimal hedge ratio under discrepancies between the futures market price and its theoretical valuation according to the cost-of-carry model. Assuming a geometric Brownian motion for spot prices, we model mispricing as a specific noise component in the dynamics of futures market prices. Empirical evidence on the model is provided for the Spanish stock index futures. Ex-ante simulations with actual data reveal that hedge ratios that take into account the estimated, time varying, correlation between the common and specific disturbances, lead to using a lower number of futures contracts than under a systematic unit ratio, without generally losing hedging effectiveness, while reducing transaction costs and capital requirements. Besides, the reduction in the number of contracts can be substantial over some periods. Finally, a mean-variance expected utility function suggests that the economic benefits from an optimal hedge can be substantial. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lafuente, J. A.; Novales, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skewness persistence with optimal portfolio selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Q.; Yan, Y. X.
Existing studies have found that ex post stock returns are positively skewed, but such skewness is only persistent for individual stocks, not for portfolios. This implies that the ex post knowledge of skewness may not be useful in ex ante portfolio selection. However, the portfolios in these studies are not optimally formed because preferences for skewness are not taken into consideration when forming these portfolios. It is more meaningful to see if the positive skewness would persist in optimally formed mean-variance-skewness efficient portfolios. Using stocks from both Japanese and US markets and a bootstrap method, we find that the portfolios optimally formed by using a polynomial goal programming method, which considers preference for skewness, greatly enhances skewness persistence over time. Our results are robust across both Japanese and US stocks. However, the skewness persistence is stronger for portfolios formed with monthly data than that with weekly data. These findings have practical implications to investors with skewness preferences. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Q.; Yan, Y. X.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk, returns, and values in the presence of differential taxation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benninga, S.; Sarig, O.
We show that there exist separate security market lines (SMLs) for debt and equity securities in an equilibrium with differential taxation of debt and equity. We characterize the conditions under which these SMLs have the same price of risk (with different intercepts) and the conditions under which the tax effect of leverage is linear in debt value as in the adjusted present value method. We explore the implications of our results for cost of capital calculations: How to calculate the cost of capital for debt and equity and how to unlever betas correctly accounting for differential taxation. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benninga, S.; Sarig, O.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markets and institutions: Global perspectives (vol 27, pg 377, 2003)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, F.; Szego, G.
The purpose of this paper is to highlight some of the key developments of markets and institutions at the global level over the past few decades by referring to the evolution of institutions from the government-led system to a market-led system. The paper argues that innovation and deregulation in the financial sector led to acceleration of the process of globalisation in which both markets and institutions are becoming increasingly integrated and more efficient. The paper highlights the role of trade liberalisation in financial services as a way of increasing efficiency and better use of national resources. The paper also highlights the role of consolidation of financial institutions as one of the ingredients of the new developments of markets and institutions. The paper also provides brief highlights of six other papers in this special issue that analyse and discuss some of the global aspects of markets and institutions. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, F.; Szego, G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Domestic and international determinants of bank profits: Foreign banks in Australia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williams, B.
This paper develops and tests a model that integrates the existing multinational bank literature with the domestic bank profits literature. Using data for Australia, this paper demonstrates that an integrated model results in a small increase in explanatory power when compared to models drawn solely from the multinational banking literature. The paper finds that profits are a negative function of competitor market share and bank licence status, and a positive function of Australian size and home GDP growth. It is argued that there is incomplete integration between the market segments of domestic and multinational banks due to the first mover advantages of incumbent banks. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Williams, B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pricing of global and domestic initial public offerings by US companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, C. S.; Kwok, C. C. Y.
This study examines the pricing of global initial public offerings made by US companies as compared to purely domestic offerings. We find that global participation can significantly reduce underpricing by about four percentage points. Moreover, the degree of underpricing declines as larger proportions of shares are allocated to foreign investors. Our results suggest that US companies time their global offerings when foreign demand for US shares is high. There is also evidence that global offerings alleviate the downward pricing pressure associated with new share offerings. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, C. S.; Kwok, C. C. Y.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is there discrimination in mortgage pricing? The case of overages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Black, H. A.; Boehm, T. P.; DeGennaro, R. P.
Mortgage overage pricing is little understood by consumers and has received little academic scrutiny. We consider the impact of the market power of individual loan officers on overages paid by borrowers, particularly minorities. We include numerous borrower and lender characteristics unavailable previously. We find that minorities who purchase homes pay larger overages than whites, but our evidence suggests that this traces to differences in the pools of borrowers rather than to racial discrimination. We conclude that a more effective way to eliminate racial differences in overages is to increase minorities' ability to bargain rather than to enact additional anti-discrimination laws. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Black, H. A.; Boehm, T. P.; DeGennaro, R. P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value creation in corporate asset sales: The role of managerial, performance and lender monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Datta, S.; Iskandar-Datta, M.; Raman, K.
Examining stockholder and bondholder wealth of acquirers and sellers, we find that asset sales are firm value enhancing for the seller but value neutral, for the acquirer. Although divestitures are typically viewed as more synergistic and friendly transactions than takeovers, we find using a matched acquirer-seller sample, that the net wealth effect from the transaction is not significantly different from zero. However, those transactions that involve high-q bidders and low-q sellers create maximum value for acquirers and for the transaction as a whole. Further, low-q bidder/low-q seller transactions are value destroying. We find that seller gains are only related to the seller's managerial performance. We document that private lender monitoring enhances transactional value in corporate divestitures. Collectively, the analysis shows that well-managed and highly monitored firms are more likely to benefit from asset sale transactions. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Datta, S.; Iskandar-Datta, M.; Raman, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency hedging for international stock portfolios: The usefulness of mean-variance analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Roon, F. A.; Nijman, T. E.; Werker, B. J. M.
We test whether hedging currency risk improves the performance of international stock portfolios. We show that an auxiliary regression provides a wealth of information about the optimal portfolio holdings for non-mean-variance investors, analogous to the information provided by the Jensen regression about optimal portfolio holdings for the mean-variance case. We find that static hedging with currency forwards does not lead to significant improvements in portfolio performance for a US-Dollar based stock portfolio from the G5 countries, whereas dynamic hedges that are conditional on the interest rate spread do. These conclusions hold for both mean-variance and power utility investors and show up both in-sample and out-of-sample. However, the optimal forward positions can differ significantly for both types of investors. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Roon, F. A.; Nijman, T. E.; Werker, B. J. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The profit efficiency of small US commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhigbe, A.; McNulty, J. E.
This study investigates the profit efficiency (PROFEFF) of small banks (those under $500 million in total assets) for 1990-96. Assuming that small banks and large banks use the same production technology, we find, consistent with Berger and Mester [J. Bank. Finance 21 (1997) 875], that small banks are more profit efficient than large banks. Small banks in non-metropolitan statistical areas (non-MSA) areas are consistently more profit efficient than small banks in MSAs. Cross-sectional analysis of the correlates of the PROFEFF estimates suggests that structure-performance factors, relationship-development factors, and expense-preference behavior play an important role in explaining the PROFEFF of small US commercial banks. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Akhigbe, A.; McNulty, J. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Post-IPO capital expenditures and market feedback</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Bommel, J.; Vermaelen, T.
This paper presents an empirical test of the 'market feedback hypothesis', a theory suggesting that information aggregated in the IPO process is used for the firm's investment decision. We examine the relation between post-IPO unexpected capital expenditures and feedback generated during the IPO process for 1543 IPOs between 1987 and 1995. Feedback is measured by (i) the unexpected price adjustment made at the end of the waiting period and (ii) the unexpected initial return. Consistent with the hypothesis, we find that positive feedback is followed by positive abnormal capital expenditures. A long-term event study finds no significant difference in. stock returns between positive and negative feedback IPOs. This suggests that firms should not ignore market feedback as there is no evidence for a feedback related bias in post-IPO stock prices. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>van Bommel, J.; Vermaelen, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The costs (and benefits?) of diversified business groups: The case of Korean chaebols</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferris, S. P.; Kim, K. A.; Kitsabunnarat, P.
We examine Korean chaebols to determine the costs and benefits associated with the operation of a diversified business group. We find that chaebol-affiliated firms suffer a value loss relative to non-affiliated firms. We observe that this value loss holds even after controlling for the relatedness of the diversification present within the chaebol. To identify the causes of this value loss, we obtain evidence suggesting that chaebol firms: (1) pursue profit stability rather than profit maximization, (2) over-invest in low performing industries, and (3) cross-subsidize the weaker members of their group. We do find however that chaebol firms possess greater debt capacity and consequently enjoy lower tax burdens. Nevertheless, because chaebols suffer an overall loss in value, we conclude that the costs associated with chaebol membership exceed its benefits. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferris, S. P.; Kim, K. A.; Kitsabunnarat, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privatization, competition, and supercompetition in the Mexican commercial banking system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gruben, W. C.; McComb, R. P.
Much literature before and after the privatization of Mexico's commercial banking system in 1991-1992 argued that the system was collusive and noncompetitive and would likely continue to be for years. Banks would collude to underloan so that - at least in comparison with what would happen in a competitive system - they could overcharge. Because a parallel literature on lending after bank privatization suggests that the problem is often not too little, but too much, we resolved to test for competitive behavior in the Mexican banking system. Using an empirical approach developed by Shaffer (Econom. Lett. 29 (1989) 321, J. Money Credit Bank. 25 (1993) 49, Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia, Working paper no. 93-28R), we find a structural break in the middle of the privatization period that signals the start of an episode of what Shaffer calls "supercompetitive" behavior. In such a supercompetition, banks run at levels of output where marginal cost exceeds marginal revenue. This behavior is consistent with a struggle in which banks take losses now because they think the market share they get in the bargain offers a positive present value of expected future return. The behavior can also be consistent with just the sort of banking crises that ensued in Mexico. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gruben, W. C.; McComb, R. P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling the stochastic behavior of short-term interest rates: Pricing implications for discount bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, T. G.
This paper models the stochastic behavior of short-term interest rates, and determines the correct specification of the drift and diffusion functions of the spot rate process. A wide variety of one-factor diffusion and two-factor stochastic volatility models is compared in terms of their ability to capture the dynamics of interest rate volatility. The empirical evidence on the one-, three- and six-month Eurodollar deposit rates indicates that a new class of models with stochastic volatility is better than the single-factor diffusion models in forecasting the future volatility of interest rate changes. The paper extends the one-factor BDT term structure model to a two-factor setting, and presents the pricing implications for discount bonds. Monte Carlo simulation results for the implied yields of three- and six-month zero-coupon bonds imply that incorporating the so-called level and GARCH effects in volatility improves the pricing performance of the interest rate models. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, T. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-currency, cross-maturity forward exchange premiums as predictors of spot rate changes: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nucci, F.
This paper shows that, in predicting the spot rate of a currency, the term structures of forward premiums of other currencies have incremental information content in addition to the term structure of the currency's own forward premiums. The theoretical model motivating the analysis hinges on the abundant evidence on the co-movements of excess returns from investing in different currencies. The empirical results are obtained through FIML estimation of a vector error correction model for weekly data on three bilateral US dollar exchange rates. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nucci, F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of deposit rate deregulation in Hong Kong on the market value of commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kwan, S. H.
This paper examines the effects of a series of events leading up to the deregulation of deposit interest rates in Hong Kong on the market value of banks. All the evidence suggests that banks earned rents from deposit interest rate rules (IRRs) and deregulation would lower these rents and hence bank market values. On average, the total abnormal return due to interest rates deregulation was around negative 4%. There is some evidence that large banks and banks with high deposit-to-asset ratio suffered a bigger drop in value, suggesting that these banks enjoyed a bigger subsidy under the IRRs. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kwan, S. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry conditions, growth opportunities and market reactions to convertible debt financing decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewis, C. M.; Rogalski, R. J.; Seward, J. K.
Firms that issue convertible debt have high debt- and equity-related costs of external finance. Existing theories of convertible debt finance differ primarily in their identification of the specific causes of the debt- and equity-related costs of external finance. To assess the theoretical issuance motives separately, we propose a simple framework that characterizes how issuers should design convertible debt to efficiently mitigate specific debt- and equity-related costs of external finance. We provide evidence from 588 security offer announcements that supports the hypotheses that: (1) convertible debt can be designed to mitigate different combinations of debt- and equity-related costs of external finance and (2) share price reactions depend on the security design decisions. The results also illustrate that the relations between firm value, financial leverage, investment opportunities, and the rate of future growth are more complex among convertible debt issuers than situations where firms issue standard financial securities. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lewis, C. M.; Rogalski, R. J.; Seward, J. K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pre-announcement effects, news effects, and volatility: Monetary policy and the stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bomfim, A. N.
I examine pre-announcement and news effects on the stock market in the context of public disclosure of monetary policy decisions. The results suggest that the stock market tends to be relatively quiet - conditional volatility is abnormally low - on days preceding regularly scheduled policy announcements. Although this calming effect is routinely reported in anecdotal press accounts, it is statistically significant only over the past four to five years, a result that I attribute to changes in the Federal Reserve's disclosure practices in early 1994. The paper also looks at how the actual interest rate decisions of policy makers affect stock market volatility. The element of surprise in such decisions tends to boost stock market volatility significantly in the short run, and positive surprises - higher-than-expected values of the target federal funds rate - tend to have a larger effect on volatility than negative surprises. The implications of the results for broader issues in the finance and economics literatures are also discussed. Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Bomfim, A. N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of the manager-shareholder conflict on acquiring bank returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornett, M. M.; Hovakimian, G.; Palia, D.; Tehranian, H.
This paper examines whether shareholder value-maximizing corporate governance mechanisms assist in reducing the managerial incentive to enter value-destroying bank acquisitions. We find that diversifying bank acquisitions earn significantly negative announcement period abnormal returns (AR) for bidder banks whereas focusing acquisitions earn zero AR. We then find that corporate governance variables (such as CEO share and option ownership and a smaller board size) in the bidding bank are less effective in diversifying acquisitions than in focusing acquisitions. These results are robust to the inclusion of the usual control variables. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cornett, M. M.; Hovakimian, G.; Palia, D.; Tehranian, H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changes in market assessments of bank risk following the Riegle-Neal Act of 1994</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhigbe, A.; Whyte, A. M.
We examine changes in bank risk following the passage of the Riegle-Neal Act of 1994 and find a significant decline in bank risk. The extent of interstate banking activity and the status of state-level interstate banking laws are important in explaining the risk reduction. Banks with assets in multiple states experience a significant reduction in risk whereas banks with assets in one state experience no significant change in risk. Banks in states with the most restrictive interstate banking provisions experience a significant decrease in risk whereas banks in states with more liberal interstate banking provisions experience a significant increase in risk. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akhigbe, A.; Whyte, A. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider trading, abnormal return and preferential information: Supervising through a probabilistic model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Minenna, M.
The enforcement of the ban on insider trading requires an evaluation of the disgorgement, i.e. the capital gain of the insider trader who takes advantage of the exploitation of preferential information. An initial step forward on this topic has been taken by the SEC, the United States Securities and Exchange Commission, which has developed a quantitative procedure based on the event-study methodology. This paper develops an adaptation of this procedure for the Italian market and explains the limits of these methodologies in the analysis of the insider-trading phenomenon. In particular, it emerges that the econometric approach cannot be applied to all insider-trading schemes. In fact, in order to work out statistically significant results, it relies on a series of assumptions such as the existence of a robust reference market index or the availability of long time series data. For this reason, a new procedure for computing the economic value of the information exploited by the insider, based on a probabilistic approach, has also been developed. This, methodology overcomes the issues connected to the event-study procedure and can be applied by construction to all insider-trading schemes and not only to the simplest ones. In fact, the model parameters are defined by using the trading strategy of the single insider; thus, if insider trading takes place, the model is able to offer a disgorgement computation; hence, by hypotheses of its construction, it is able to detect the difference between insiders and followers. The new procedure has been adopted by CONSOB and has been presented to the Judicial System, which is in charge of inflicting the fine. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Minenna, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local bank office ownership, deposit control, market structure, and economic growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collender, R. N.; Shaffer, S.
This paper tests empirical associations between banking market structure, banking regulation, and subsequent growth rates in local real per capita personal income. Our findings suggest that out-of-market bank mergers or acquisitions need not, ceteris paribus, impair local economic growth, and may even have beneficial effects in rural markets with the possible exception of farm-dependent areas. These findings derive from empirical models that relate both short-run and long-run growth rates to geographic restrictions on bank activity, concentration in local banking markets, in-market versus out-of-market ownership of local bank offices, and in-market versus out-of-market control of local bank deposits. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Collender, R. N.; Shaffer, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Take or leave a few cents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szego, G.
nan</description><author>Szego, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comparison of yield curve estimation techniques using UK data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ioannides, M.
I compare different methods of estimating the term structure of interest rates on a daily UK treasury bill and gilt data that spans the period from January 1995 to January 1999. In-sample and out-of-sample statistics reveal the superior pricing ability of certain methods characterised by an exponential functional form. In addition to these standard goodness of fit statistics, model performance is judged in terms of two trading strategies based on model residuals. Both strategies reveal that parsimonious representations of the term structure perform better than their spline counterparts characterised by a linear functional form. This is valid even when abnormal returns are adjusted for market movements. Linear splines overfit the data and are likely to give misleading results. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ioannides, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of private sector business credit information sharing: The US case</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kallberg, J. G.; Udell, G. F.
This paper investigates the value added by private information exchanges that share information on business payment performance. We discuss how this information is collected and disseminated by the world's largest private information broker, Dun &amp; Bradstreet. We provide the first empirical examination of the importance of this information at the lending decision level. Our findings indicate that exchange-generated information provides significant explanatory power in failure prediction models controlling for other credit information that is easily available to lenders. Our study complements the work of Jappelli and Pagano [Information sharing, lending and defaults; Cross country evidence, Centre for Economic Policy Research, Discussion Paper 2184, 1999] who find in cross-country macro level tests that information exchanges add value. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kallberg, J. G.; Udell, G. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>To what extent will the banking industry be globalized? A study of bank nationality and reach in 20 European nations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, A. N.; Dai, Q. L.; Ongena, S.; Smith, D. C.
We model two dimensions of bank globalization - bank nationality (a bank from the firm's host nation, its home nation, or a third nation) and bank reach (a global, regional,or local bank) using a two-stage nested multinomial logit model. Our data set includes over 2000 foreign affiliates of multinational corporations operating in 20 European nations and over 250 banks that serve them. We find that these firms frequently use host nation banks for cash management services, and that bank reach may be strongly influenced by this choice of bank nationality. Our results suggest limits to the degree of future bank. globalization. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, A. N.; Dai, Q. L.; Ongena, S.; Smith, D. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markets and institutions: Global perspectives.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, F.; Szego, G.
nan</description><author>Moshirian, F.; Szego, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do bankers sacrifice value to build empires? Managerial incentives, industry consolidation, and financial performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hughes, J. P.; Lang, W. W.; Mester, L. J.; Moon, C. G.; Pagano, M. S.
Bank consolidation is a global phenomenon that may enhance stakeholders' value if managers do not sacrifice value to build empires. We find strong evidence of managerial entrenchment at US bank holding companies that have higher levels of managerial ownership, better growth opportunities, poorer financial performance, and smaller asset size. At banks without entrenched management, both asset acquisitions and sales are associated with improved performance. At banks with entrenched management, sales are related to smaller improvements while acquisitions are associated with worse performance. Consistent with scale economies, an increase in assets by internal growth is associated with better performance at most banks. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hughes, J. P.; Lang, W. W.; Mester, L. J.; Moon, C. G.; Pagano, M. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Operating performance of banks among Asian economies: An international and time series comparison</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kwan, S. H.
After controlling for loan quality, liquidity, capitalization, and output mix, per unit bank operating costs are found to vary significantly across Asian countries and over time. Further analysis reveals that the country rankings of per unit labor and physical capital costs are highly correlated, suggesting that there exist systematic differences in bank operating efficiency across Asian countries. However, this measure of operating efficiency is found to be unrelated to the degree of openness of the banking sector. Asian bank operating costs were found to decline from 1992 to 1997, indicating that banks were improving their operating performance over time. Since 1997, the run-up in operating costs coincided with the Asian financial crisis, suggesting that banks were incurring additional costs in dealing with their problem loans while output was declining simultaneously. Moreover, the labor cost share is found to decline significantly between 1997 and 1999, indicating that banks were able to cut their labor force after the financial crisis but were less flexible to reduce physical capital input. Furthermore, significant differences in labor cost share are detected across countries, suggesting that different countries have different bank production functions. The variations in labor cost share are significantly positively related to the country's financial services wage rate, suggesting that banks using relatively more labor in a particular country is due to the labor force productivity, rather than labor being cheap. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kwan, S. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence of a bank lending channel in the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Z. K.
Using balance sheet data for a panel of UK listed. firms, we find evidence of a bank lending channel of monetary transmission. A higher interest rate induces more bank lending to listed companies, but this effect diminishes if monetary policy becomes tight enough to impose severe constraints on bank loan lending. The dynamic behaviour of bank debt versus non-bank debt shows that the lending channel works through cutting back loan supplies to small, bank-dependent firms while restricting the bank's ability to provide financial assistance to other firms. We see cross-sectional differences between bank-dependent and non-bank-dependent listed companies, and between listed and non-listed companies: Both can contribute to the size effect of investment. Small firms bear most of the reductions in bank loan supplies, and since they do not have many alternatives to bank finance, they suffer more from monetary tightening than big firms. This is consistent with inventory behavior. Furthermore, we have found that big, non-bank-dependent firms can benefit more-from the bank-firm relationship than small, bank-dependent firms. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Z. K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A cross-country comparison of full and partial venture capital exits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, D. J.; MacIntosh, J. G.
This paper considers the issue of when venture capitalists (VC) make a partial, as opposed to a full exit, for the full range of exit vehicles. A full exit for an initial public offerings (IPO) involves a sale of all of the venture capitalist's holdings within one year of the IPO; a partial exit involves sale of only part of the venture capitalist's holdings within that period. A full acquisition exit involves the sale of the entire firm for cash; in a partial acquisition exit, the venture capitalist receives (often illiquid) shares in the acquiror firm instead of cash. In the case of a buyback exit (in which the entrepreneur buys out the venture capitalist) or a secondary sale, a partial exit entails a sale of only part of the venture capitalist's holdings. A partial write-off involves a write down of the investment. We consider the determinants of full and partial venture capital exits for all five exit vehicles. We also perform a number of comparative empirical tests on samples of full and partial exits derived from a survey of Canadian and US venture capital firms. The data offer support to the central hypothesis of the paper: that the greater the degree of information asymmetry between the selling VC and the buyer, the greater the likelihood of a partial exit to signal quality. The data also indicate differences between the US and Canadian venture capital industries, and highlight the impact of legal and institutional factors on exits across countries. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cumming, D. J.; MacIntosh, J. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading your neighbor's ETFs: Competition or fragmentation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, B.; Boehmer, E.
nan</description><author>Boehmer, B.; Boehmer, E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition among markets: The repeal of Rule 390</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kam, T. K.; Panchapagesan, V.; Weaver, D. G.
The New York Stock Exchange repealed its Rule 390 on May 8, 2000. The rule disallowed exchange members from trading stocks listed prior to April 26, 1979 outside of an exchange. We examine the implications of the rule's repeal on the competition for order flow as well as on measures of market quality such as spreads, depth and price improvement for stocks impacted by the rule. We use a second sample of stocks not subject to Rule 390 (Rule 19c-3 stocks) to control for market wide trends. We have three important findings: (1) Quoted spreads decrease by about 18% for Rule 390 stocks, three times more than the reduction for Rule 19c-3 stocks; (2) Effective spreads do not change; and (3) The NYSE lost little market share, even in smaller trades that were supposed to migrate, following the repeal. Our results indicate a paradigm shift in the way the NYSE specialists make a market. Prior to the repeal, the specialists set wider quotes but provided extensive price improvement. Following the repeal, the specialists set tighter quotes with lesser price improvement possibilities. We believe that this shift is a strategic response by the specialists to retain market share, not by improving market quality but by making order flow internalization and payment for order flow less profitable. As a result, competition improves market quality - but not in the way we would generally expect. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kam, T. K.; Panchapagesan, V.; Weaver, D. G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Competition among markets: The repeal of Rule 390" by Kam, Panchapagesan and Weaver</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edwards, A. K.
nan</description><author>Edwards, A. K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technology, automation, and productivity of stock exchanges: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, I.; Malkamaki, M.; Schmiedel, H.
This paper stresses the importance of understanding operational choices, strategies, and performances of stock exchanges as regular operating firms [J. Finance 52 (1999) 655; J. Financial Markets 2 (1999) 329]. Using unbalanced panel data on 49 stock exchanges over the period 1989-1998, the paper traces the productivity of stock exchanges over time and across different types and groups of exchanges. We find significant variability in productivity - revenue and cost efficiency - across these exchanges. On average, North American exchanges are found to be most cost and revenue efficient. However, our findings also indicate that European exchanges have improved the most, in respect of cost efficiency, while exchanges in South America and Asia-Pacific are found to be lagging as regards both cost and revenue estimations. Evidence also indicates that investment in technology-related developments effectively influenced cost and revenue efficiency. Moreover, organisational structure and market competition are found to be significantly associated with both cost and revenue efficiency for the exchanges studied, whereas market size and quality are related only to revenue efficiency. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasan, I.; Malkamaki, M.; Schmiedel, H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Technology, automation and productivity of stock exchanges: International evidence" by Hasan, Malkamaki &amp; Schmiedel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neave, E. H.
nan</description><author>Neave, E. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Development and efficiency of the banking sector in a transitional economy: Hungarian experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, I.; Marton, K.
The paper analyzes the experiences and developments of Hungarian banking sector during the transitional process from a centralized economy to a market-oriented system. The paper identifies that early reorganization initiatives, flexible approaches to privatization, and liberal policies towards foreign banks' involvement with the domestic institutions helped to build a relatively stable and increasingly efficient banking system. Foreign banks and banks with higher foreign bank ownership involvement were associated with lower inefficiency. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasan, I.; Marton, K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity trading by institutional investors: Evidence on order submission strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Naes, R.; Skjeltorp, J. A.
The trading volume channeled through off-market crossing networks is growing. Passive matching of orders outside the primary market lowers several components of execution costs compared to regular trading. On the other hand, the risk of non-execution imposes opportunity costs, and the inherent "free riding" on the price discovery process raises concerns that this eventually will lead to lower liquidity in the primary market. Using a detailed data set from a large investor in the US equity markets, we find evidence that competition from crossing networks is concentrated in the most liquid stocks in a sample of the largest companies in the US. Simulations of alternative trading strategies indicate that the investor's strategy of initially trying to cross all stocks was cost effective: in spite of their high liquidity, the crossed stocks would have been unlikely to achieve at lower execution costs in the open market. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Naes, R.; Skjeltorp, J. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Equity trading by institutional investors: Evidence on order submission strategies" by Naes and Skjeltorp</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jain, P.
nan</description><author>Jain, P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do 'thinly-traded' stocks benefit from specialist intervention?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nimalendran, M.; Petrella, G.
This paper addresses the issue of the optimal trading system for less actively traded (i.e., 'thinly-traded') stocks. We compare the performance of a pure order driven market with limit order book (POD) with that of a hybrid order driven market with specialist and limit order book (HOD). We find that the HOD system offers superior performance along several dimensions of market quality. In particular, the specialist-based system offers lower execution costs, greater depth, a significant increase in the depth-to-spread ratio, and lower adverse selection costs. Very 'thinly-traded' stocks benefit more than less inactive stocks from the adoption of a hybrid trading system both in terms of greater liquidity and in terms of lower adverse selection costs. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nimalendran, M.; Petrella, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Do 'thinly-traded' stocks benefit from specialist intervention?" by Nimalendran and Petrella</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battalio, R.
nan</description><author>Battalio, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock exchange governance and market quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnamurti, C.; Sequeira, J. M.; Fu, F. J.
We show that organization structure of a stock exchange matters by utilizing the unique setting prevailing in India. India has two major stock markets, the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) and the National Stock Exchange (NSE). These two exchanges adopt similar trading systems, trade essentially identical stocks, and follow the same trading hours. However, these exchanges have different organizational structures: BSE is mutualized whereas NSE is demutualized. Using the Hasbrouck [Review of Financial Studies 6 (1993) 191] measure of market quality we show that NSE provides a better quality market than BSE. This result is consistent with the work of Domowitz and Steil [Brookings-Wharton Papers on Financial Services, 1999], who proposed that demutualized exchanges are superior to mutualized in governance. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Krishnamurti, C.; Sequeira, J. M.; Fu, F. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Stock exchange governance and market quality" by Krishnamurti, Sequeira, and Fangjian</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angel, J. J.
nan</description><author>Angel, J. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The competitive effects of US decimalization: Evidence from the US-listed Canadian stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oppenheimer, H. R.; Sabherwal, S.
This paper analyzes the impact of US decimalization on the Canadian stocks listed on the Toronto Stock Exchange (TSE) and either the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) or National Association of Securities Dealers Automated Quotation System (Nasdaq) in the US. Using a sample of 126 firms, we find that the US trading of these stocks increases after decimalization, but this increase is not at the expense of TSE volume. Indeed, the TSE volume increases substantially for those securities that are traded on Nasdaq and increases marginally for those securities that are traded on the NYSE. Most of the increase in volume is in retail-sized trades. The bid-ask spreads and the quote depths decline on all exchanges, but by a greater amount in the US than in Canada. The depths on the NYSE decline from being above the TSE depths to well below the TSE depths. We also find that the decline in the TSE spread is directly related to the size of the firm and to the decline in the US spread, and is inversely related to the pre-decimalization ratio of spreads on the US exchange and the TSE. Overall, our results indicate that the US decimalization had the desired positive impact on trading in both the US and Canada, with a decrease in spreads and an increase in retail-sized trading. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oppenheimer, H. R.; Sabherwal, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "The competitive effects of US decimalization: Evidence from the US-listed Canadian stocks" by Oppenheimer and Sabherwal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Werner, I. M.
nan</description><author>Werner, I. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Trading your neighbor's ETFs: Competition or fragmentation?" by Boehmer and Boehmer</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peterson, M.
nan</description><author>Peterson, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Globalization and the value of US listing: Revisting Canadian evidence" by Mittoo</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heidle, H. G.
nan</description><author>Heidle, H. G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Globalization and the value of US listing: Revisiting Canadian evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mittoo, U. R.
As capital markets become integrated, the value of foreign listing and, consequently, the number of foreign listings should be expected to decline. The dramatic surge in foreign listings on US stock exchanges in recent years suggests that motivations and value of listing may also be changing as markets become increasingly globalized. We explore this issue by comparing both short- and long-run valuation effects of Canadian listings in the US in pre- and post-1990 periods. We document that the positive price and liquidity effects for Canadian stocks surrounding US listing have declined over time. The analysis of long-run performance, however, shows that Canadian firms list in the US after a strong market performance but under-perform Canadian market indexes by 13-30% over the three years after the listing in both pre- and post-1990 periods. Further, the determinants of long-run performance appear to be significantly different from that in the short-run. Our evidence suggests that valuation effects of US listing may be driven by several factors, including liquidity and industry factors, that vary cross-sectionally and over time. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mittoo, U. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An overview of the conference sessions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Halpern, P.; Jennings, R.; Gregg, T.; Summerville, J. A.
nan</description><author>Halpern, P.; Jennings, R.; Gregg, T.; Summerville, J. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation effects of seasoned global equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Errunza, V. R.; Miller, D. P.
This paper examines the shareholder wealth effects associated with global equity offerings made by foreign firms after their initial cross-listing in the United States. We document that the market reaction to seasoned global equity offerings is economically and statistically insignificant. However, it is 1.5% larger than the market reaction to offerings made on local exchanges only. In addition, we find that the adverse market reaction to local equity offerings is mitigated as more capital is raised globally. Our findings support the hypothesis that global capital raising is associated with significant benefits. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Errunza, V. R.; Miller, D. P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Valuation effects of seasoned global equity offerings" by Errunza and Miller</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foerster, S. R.
nan</description><author>Foerster, S. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of estimation error on measures of portfolio credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loffler, G.
This paper uses Monte Carlo simulations to assess the impact of noisy input parameters on the accuracy of estimated portfolio credit risk. Assumptions about input quality are derived from the distribution of historical sample statistics commonly used in default risk modelling. The resulting estimation error in the distribution of portfolio losses is considerable. Losses that are judged to occur with a probability of 0.3% may actually occur with a probability of 1%. The paper also shows that estimation error leads to biases in value at risk estimates and significance levels of backtests. The biases can be corrected by analysing predictive distributions which average over the unknown parameter values. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loffler, G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term structure estimation from on-the-run Treasuries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jordan, J. V.; Mansi, S. A.
Five methods of estimating the term structure from on-the-run Treasuries are compared with respect to error in spot rate estimation, forward rate estimation, and coupon bond pricing. The methods can all be considered variants of the bootstrapping technique. The two discrete-time bootstrapping methods are based on linear and cubic interpolation of the yield curve. Two continuous-time bootstrapping methods are based on exponential functional forms for the yield curve and a third is based on a bilinear transformation of a power function. Simulated bond samples with and without random error are employed to study the relative importance of interpolation error and random pricing error. CRSP bond data are used in assessing the accuracy of the methods in pricing liquid and illiquid bonds. Two methods stand out in terms of good interpolation properties and robustness in the face of pricing errors. These are the Nelson and Siegel and the Mansi and Phillips methods. Both are based on exponential functions. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jordan, J. V.; Mansi, S. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate use of interest rate swaps: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, H. T.; Mao, C. X.
We develop a simply theory on interest rate swaps based on the difference between bank loans and public debts. While restrictive covenants of bank loans help reduce agency costs, banks also have natural disadvantages in bearing interest rate risk due to their floating liabilities. A firm that wants a fixed-rate loan can borrow a floating-rate loan from a bank and enter an interest rate swap to hedge the interest rate risk. Consistent with our theory, we find empirically that fixed-rate swap payers generally have lower credit ratings, higher leverage ratios, higher percentages of long-term floating-rate loans, and are more likely to use bank loans than floating-rate swap payers. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, H. T.; Mao, C. X.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The fiscal cost implications of an accommodating approach to banking crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Honohan, P.; Klingebiel, D.
In recent decades, a majority of countries have experienced a systemic banking crisis requiring a major-and expensive - overhaul of their banking system. Budgetary outlays, whether immediate or deferred, have exceeded 50% of GDP in some cases. This paper uses cross-country econometric evidence to examine whether the design of crisis containment and resolution policies can systematically influence the overall magnitude of fiscal costs. We find that accommodating policies such as blanket deposit guarantees, open-ended liquidity support, repeated partial recapitalizations, debtor bail-outs and regulatory forbearance all tend to add significantly and sizably to fiscal costs. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Honohan, P.; Klingebiel, D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lender certification premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cook, D. O.; Schellhorn, C. D.; Spellman, L. J.
The announcement of a bank loan by a borrowing firm has been shown to have a positive effect on the market value of the borrower's claims. This is consistent with a lender's implied endorsement of the borrower-an endorsement that has value to the borrower. In this paper, we investigate whether the lender is able to extract a premium loan rate or certification premium in return. We find empirical evidence that in the absence of collateral reputable lenders are able to exact a certification premium. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cook, D. O.; Schellhorn, C. D.; Spellman, L. J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalized M-vector models for hedging interest rate risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nawalkha, S. K.; Soto, G. M.; Zhang, J.
This paper generalizes the M-square and M-vector models [Fong and Fabozzi, Appendix E: Derivation of Risk Immunization Measures, in: Fixed Income Portfolio Management, Dow Jones-Irwin, Homewood, IL, pp. 291-294,1985; Nawalkha and Chambers, Journal of Portfolio Management, Winter (1997) 92] by using a Taylor series expansion of the bond return function with respect to specific functions of the cash flow maturities. The classic M-vector computes the weighted averages of the distance between the maturity of each cash flow and the planning horizon, raised to integer powers (e.g., (t - H)(1), (t - H)(2) (t - H)(3), . . .). Implementation of the new approach involves computing the weighted averages of the distance between some function of the maturity of each cash flow and that of the planning horizon, raised to integer powers (e.g-, (g(t) - g(H))(1), (g(t) - g(H))(2), (g(t) - g(H))(3) , . . .). Adopting this approach, this paper explores six different generalized M-vector models corresponding to six different polynomial functions, over five different planning horizons from one year to five years. It is shown that generalized M-vector models corresponding to polynomial functions of lower power provide significantly enhanced protection from interest rate risk over short planning horizons. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nawalkha, S. K.; Soto, G. M.; Zhang, J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial deregulation and total factor productivity change: An empirical study of Turkish commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Isik, I.; Hassan, M. K.
In January 1980, a new liberal economic policy was adopted in Turkey to promote financial market development and increase the efficiency and productivity of the financial sector by fostering competition among banks. As a result of this policy, the Turkish banking system witnessed a series of legal, structural and institutional changes throughout the 1980s. To enhance their competitive viability, Turkish banks responded by streamlining their operations and investing in new technology. Utilizing a DEA-type Malmquist Total Factor Productivity Change Index, we examine productivity growth, efficiency change, and technical progress in Turkish commercial banks during the deregulation of financial markets in Turkey. We found that all forms of Turkish banks, although in different magnitudes, have recorded significant productivity gains driven mostly by efficiency increases rather than technical progress. Efficiency increases, however, were mostly owing to improved resource management practices rather than improved scales. Our results also indicate that private banks began to close their performance gap with public banks in the new environment. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Isik, I.; Hassan, M. K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading volume and location of trade: Evidence from Jardine group listings in Hong Kong and Singapore</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lau, S. T.; McInish, T. H.
The switch in primary exchange listing of members of the Jardine Group from Hong Kong to Singapore provides a unique setting in which to examine changes in exchange listings. Previous studies of listing switches from Nasdaq to AMEX/NYSE find increases in liquidity and positive abnormal returns. Clyde et al. (Journal of Finance 52 (1997) 2103) report decreased liquidity and positive abnormal returns associated with switches from AMEX to Nasdaq. In contrast, we find decreased liquidity as measured by trading volume accompanied by negative abnormal returns-demonstrating that expected liquidity increases are not the sole reason for exchange switches and that management may perceive benefits from a switch in listing even if investors do not. Moreover, evidence is accumulating that the increased liquidity observed by previous researches is only associated with switches from smaller to larger markets. In spite of the fact that trading volume declines after the switch, there are still a sufficient number of Hong Kong investors trading in Singapore to cause a statistically significant decline in trading volume in Singapore when there is a holiday in Hong Kong. Hence, order flow is segmented, but not completely. We find that individual firm trading volume is most closely associated with the market on which it is traded most. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lau, S. T.; McInish, T. H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impacts of Hong Kong's currency board reforms on the interbank market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tse, Y. K.; Yip, P. S. L.
Among the economies with a Currency Board System (CBS), Hong Kong (HK) is probably the one with the largest and most developed financial sector, as well as the highest capital mobility. Hence, studying HK's CBS is not only crucial to HK, but also important for the understanding of the modern CBS. This paper outlines the major monetary reforms in HK since the late 1980s. The impacts of these reforms and the 1997-1998 Asian Financial Crisis are then examined empirically. We focus on the differentials between the US and HK interbank interest rates. We assume the conditional-mean equation follows an autoregressive process and the conditional-variance equation follows a generalized autoregressive conditional heteroscedasticity process. This model captures the time-varying level and volatility of the differential. In light of the empirical results we provide an assessment of the reforms in HK. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tse, Y. K.; Yip, P. S. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default- and call-adjusted duration for corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacoby, G.; Roberts, G. S.
Call and default can potentially alter the timing and amounts of promised cashflows for callable, corporate bonds. While prior research has indicated the theoretical importance of adjusting Macaulay duration for the impacts of default and call, the question of their relative impact remains a matter of debate [The High Yield Debt Market, Dow Jones Irwin, New York, 1990, p. 18; J. Finan. 53 (1998) 2225]. We develop a theoretical analysis incorporating both default and call effects on duration and test its implications employing a previously unexplored data base of Canadian, investment grade, corporate bond indices containing an unusual provision making it possible to identify callable and noncallable indices. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacoby, G.; Roberts, G. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of foreign entry and ownership structure on the Philippine domestic banking market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Unite, A. A.; Sullivan, M. J.
We examine the response of domestic Philippine banks to the relaxation of foreign entry regulations that occurred in the Philippines. We find evidence that foreign bank entry is associated with a reduction in interest rate spreads and bank profits, but only for those domestic banks that are affiliated to a family business group. Foreign entry corresponds more generally with improvements in operating efficiencies, but a deterioration of loan portfolios. Overall, we conclude that foreign competition compels domestic banks to be more efficient, to focus operations due to increased risk, and to become less dependent on relationship-based banking practices. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Unite, A. A.; Sullivan, M. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common asset pricing factors in volatilities and returns in futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siddique, A. R.
Factor-based asset pricing models have been used to explain the common predictable variation in excess asset returns. This paper combines means with volatilities of returns in several futures markets to explain their common predictable variation. Using a latent variables methodology, tests do not reject a single factor model with a common time-varying factor loading. The single common factor accounts for up to 53% of the predictable variation in the volatilities and up to 14% of the predictable variation in the means. S&amp;P500 futures volatility predicted by the factor model is highly correlated with volatility implied in S&amp;P500 futures options. But both the factor and implied volatilities are significant in predicting future volatility. In derivatives pricing, both implied volatility from options and factors extracted from asset pricing models should be employed. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Siddique, A. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of foreign board membership on firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oxelheim, L.; Randoy, T.
This study examines the effect of foreign (Anglo-American) board membership on corporate performance measured in terms of firm value (Tobin's Q). Using a sample of firms with headquarters in Norway or Sweden the study indicates a significantly higher value for firms that have outsider Anglo-American board member(s), after a variety of firm-specific and corporate governance related factors have been controlled for. We argue that this superior performance reflects the fact that these companies have successfully broken away from a partly segmented domestic capital market by "importing" an Anglo-American corporate governance system. Such an "import" signals a willingness on the part of the firm to expose itself to improved corporate governance and enhances its reputation in the financial market. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oxelheim, L.; Randoy, T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common asset pricing factors in volatilies and returns in futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siddique, A. R.
nan</description><author>Siddique, A. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Acquisition premiums when investment banks invest their own money in the deals they advise and when they do not: Evidence from acquisitions of assets in the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stouraitis, A.
This paper shows that investment banks that advise acquirers of assets negotiate favourable terms when they invest their own money in the deal, but lead their clients to overpay when they do not have financial incentives. Acquirers pay the smallest premiums in divisional MBOs when advised by the investment bank that finances the deal, and the largest premiums in interfirm asset sales when advised by an investment bank remunerated contingent on deal completion. Premiums are in between the two extremes when acquirers do not use advisors. These results are attributed to investment bank incentives, which exacerbate the information asymmetry between buyers and sellers of assets. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stouraitis, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effectiveness of bank capital adequacy regulation: A theoretical and empirical approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barrios, V. E.; Blanco, J. M.
The aim of this paper is to analyse how banking firms set their capital ratios, that is, the rate of equity capital over assets. In order to study this issue, two theoretical models are developed. Both models demonstrate the existence of an optimal capital ratio; the first one for firms not affected by capital adequacy regulation, the second one for firms which are. The models have been tested by estimating a disequilibrium model using data from Spanish commercial banks. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barrios, V. E.; Blanco, J. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early warning models in real time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gunther, J. W.; Moore, R. R.
Using a unique set of banking data containing both originally reported and subsequently revised financial variables, we find adverse revisions to accounting statements are associated with downgrades in supervisory ratings. To assess the financial significance of the revisions, we compare the ability of the original and revised data to map into exam ratings. The relationship between accounting data and exam results is significantly stronger for revised data than for real-time data. Our findings document significant differences between real-time and revised banking data, highlight the auditing role of bank exams, and provide a more realistic assessment of early warning model accuracy. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gunther, J. W.; Moore, R. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on savings and loan ownership structure and expense preference: A re-examination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gropper, D. M.; Hudson, C. D.
This study extends the work of Akella and Greenbaum [Journal of Banking &amp; Finance 12 (1988) 419] through the use of a much larger, nationwide sample of US saving and loan associations and supports their original finding of significant expense-preference behavior in mutual savings and loans during their original study period (1979-80). This study also provides evidence that over the time period of substantial deregulation and changes in the competitive environment in the US financial services industry, expense-preference behavior for savings and loans decreased. The results are consistent with the idea that the removal of barriers that restrict competition should improve managerial efficiency in firms that survive. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gropper, D. M.; Hudson, C. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of venture capitalists' participation in listed companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, C. K.; Wang, K. M.; Lu, Q.
We empirically examine the effects of venture capital (VC) firms on VC-backed listed companies in Singapore. While previous studies have shown the VC value-added in lower underpricing and better post-IPO operational performance of VC-backed IPOs, we find the effects of venture capitalists' participation are very complicated. Most significantly, the post-IPO operating performance of VC-backed companies is inferior though they are less underpriced. The finding supports both the certification model and the adverse selection model. Furthermore, we find that IPOs backed by older VC firms perform better, supporting the grandstanding model that younger VC firms bring their portfolios to the market prematurely. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, C. K.; Wang, K. M.; Lu, Q.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday trading volume and return volatility of the DJIA stocks: A note</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Darrat, A. F.; Rahman, S.; Zhong, M. S.
We examine the contemporaneous correlation as well as the lead-lag relation between trading volume and return volatility in all stocks comprising the Dow Jones industrial average (DJIA). We use 5-minute intraday data and measure return volatility by the exponential generalized autoregressive conditional heteroscedasticity method. Contrary to the mixture of distribution hypothesis, the vast majority of the DJIA stock shows no contemporaneous correlation between volume and volatility. However, we find evidence of significant lead-lag relations between the two variables in a large number of the DJIA stocks in accordance with the sequential information arrival hypothesis. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Darrat, A. F.; Rahman, S.; Zhong, M. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The overnight interbank market: Evidence from the G-7 and the Euro zone</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prati, A.; Bartolini, L.; Bertola, G.
We study the interbank markets for overnight loans of the major industrial countries, linking the behavior of short-term interest rates to the operating procedures of these countries' central banks. We find that many of the key behavioral features of US federal funds rates, on which previous studies have focused, are not robust to changes in institutional details, along both cross-sectional and time-series dimensions of the data. Our results indicate that central banks' operating procedures and intervention styles play a crucial role in shaping empirical features of short-term interest rates' day to-to-day behavior in industrial countries. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Prati, A.; Bartolini, L.; Bertola, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do US stock prices deviate from their fundamental values? Some new evidence (vol 27, pg 673, 2003)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhong, M. S.; Darrat, A. F.; Anderson, D. C.
nan</description><author>Zhong, M. S.; Darrat, A. F.; Anderson, D. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-term reaction of stock markets in stressful circumstances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lasfer, M. A.; Melnik, A.; Thomas, D. C.
In this paper we document the short-term stock price behaviour following a period of stock market stress. We focus on price behaviour using daily market indexes from 39 stock exchanges over the period 1989-1998. Our results are not consistent with the overreaction hypothesis. We find positive (negative) abnormal price performance in the short-term window (up to 10 days) following positive (negative) price shocks. Our analysis also highlights differences between developed and emerging markets. We show that the post-shock abnormal performances are significantly larger for emerging markets but that this momentum behaviour is markedly less in the late 1990s. We find the size of the after-shock tremors to be related to market liquidity, with larger post-shock price changes in less-liquid markets. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lasfer, M. A.; Melnik, A.; Thomas, D. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy risk and productive efficiency in manufacturing firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becchetti, L.; Sierra, J.
The paper investigates the determinants of bankruptcy in three representative unbalanced samples of Italian firms for the periods 1989-91, 1992-94 and 1995-97. Two important results are that: (i) the degree of relative firm inefficiency measured as the distance from the efficient frontier has significant explanatory power in predicting bankruptcy (ii) qualitative regressors such as customers' concentration and strength and proximity of competitors have significant predictive power and suggest that banks should not restrict their monitoring activity to balance sheet variables. These findings remain significant after controlling for balance sheet liquidity and profitability variables usually considered in these estimates. Crown Copyright (C) 2003 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Becchetti, L.; Sierra, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of universal banks: Evidence from Switzerland</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rime, B.; Stiroh, K. J.
This paper examines the performance of Swiss banks from 1996 to 1999. Using a broad definition of bank output, we find evidence of large relative cost and profit inefficiencies in Swiss banks. A more narrow definition that focuses on only traditional activities leads to efficiency estimates that are even lower. We also find evidence of economies of scale for small and mid-size banks, but little evidence that significant scale economies remain for the very largest banks. Finally, evidence on scope economies is weak for the largest banks that are involved in a wide variety of financial activities. Taken together, these results suggest few obvious benefits from the trend toward larger, universal banks in Switzerland. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rime, B.; Stiroh, K. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The predictive power of implied volatility: Evidence from 35 futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szakmary, A.; Ors, E.; Kim, J. K.; Davidson, W. N.
Using data from 35 futures options markets from eight separate exchanges, we test how well the implied volatilities (IVs) embedded in option prices predict subsequently realized volatility (RV) in the underlying futures. We find that for this broad array of futures options, IV performs well in a relative sense. For a large majority of the commodities studied, the implieds outperform historical volatility (HV) as a predictor of the subsequently RV in the underlying futures prices over the remaining life of the option. Indeed, in most markets examined, regardless of whether it is modeled as a simple moving average or in a GARCH framework, HV contains no economically significant predictive information beyond what is already incorporated in IV. These findings add to previous research that has focused on currency and crude oil futures by extending the analysis into a very broad array of contracts and exchanges. Our results are consistent with the hypothesis that futures options markets in general, with their minimal trading frictions, are efficient. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Szakmary, A.; Ors, E.; Kim, J. K.; Davidson, W. N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inferring market information from the price and quantity of S&amp;L deposits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, L.
This paper infers market information embedded in the price and quantity of S&amp;L deposits. While previous empirical research typically treats the risk premium as the key element of deposit interest spread, subsidy-shifting theory suggests that deposit rates also contain a subsidy-shifting premium that arises from an institution's eagerness to fund loan and investment opportunities that extract deposit-insurance subsidies. This paper examines the existence and the nature of both premiums and shows how regulators can use this information to make regulatory oversight more effective. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guo, L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International asset allocation: A new perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lioui, A.; Poncet, P.
We consider an international economy where the purchasing power parity (PPP) is violated and financial asset returns and exchange rates follow, in real terms, general diffusion processes driven by K state variables. A country-specific representative individual trades on available assets to maximize the expected utility of her final consumption. Her optimal strategy is shown to contain, in addition to the usual speculative component, only two hedging components, however large is K. The first one is associated with domestic interest rate risk and the second one with the risk brought about by the co-movements of the interest rates and the market prices of risk. The implementation of the strategy thus is much easier than with the traditional Merton decomposition, as it involves estimating the characteristics of the yield curve and the market prices of risk only, rather than those of numerous (and a priori unknown) state variables. In view of the necessity for optimizing agents to account for the (partial) asset return predictability that derives from the investors' hedging demands at equilibrium, our result significantly lessens the difficulty of achieving the optimal portfolio strategy. The second hedging term turns out to depend on interest rate differentials across countries and to encompass hedging against PPP deviations. Therefore, in contrast with previous models that obtained a (direct) currency risk hedging component in a rather ad hoc manner, our decomposition leads to optimal (indirect) currency risk hedging in a natural and general way. It also provides new insights as to the pricing of foreign exchange risk at equilibrium. (C) 2002 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lioui, A.; Poncet, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on banking efficiency in Portugal, New vs. Old banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Canhoto, A.; Dermine, J.
Following entry into the European Community in 1986, Portugal transformed rapidly its repressed banking system with deregulation, the opening of borders, the granting of new banking licenses, and privatization. In a more competitive banking system, one would expect a priori an increase in operational efficiency. This paper attempts to quantify the magnitude of efficiency gains over the years 1990-1995. Moreover, the paper documents the relative efficiency performance of new domestic banks. Not hampered by a legacy of inefficiency from the past, they could operate nearer the efficiency frontier. The case of Portugal provides unique information on the joint effect of deregulation and the granting of new banking licenses on the change in operational efficiency of a previously repressed banking system. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Canhoto, A.; Dermine, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary transmission and bank competition in the EMU</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lensink, R.; Sterken, E.
The introduction of the euro has led to renewed attention for monetary transmission in the European Union. This special issue of the Journal of Banking and Finance includes papers that contribute to the development of both the theory and empirical applications of the monetary transmission channel that assumes various types of imperfections. The issue includes papers that can best be described by the credit view and studies on concentration and competition in the European banking industry. This introduction positions the papers in this active field of research. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lensink, R.; Sterken, E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment and monetary policy in the euro area</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mojon, B.; Smets, F.; Vermeulen, P.
This paper analyses the effects of a change in monetary policy on firms' investment in Germany, France, Italy and Spain using a data set which provides aggregated balance sheet and profit and loss account data for 17 different industries and three different size classes. The main findings are twofold. First, in each of the four countries a change in the user cost of capital, which in turn is affected by interest rates, has both statistically and economically significant effects on investment. Second, while the average interest rate on debt is generally higher for small firms than for large firms, there is little evidence that the effects of monetary policy on small firms are larger. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mojon, B.; Smets, F.; Vermeulen, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary policy and bank lending: Evidence from German banking groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kakes, J.; Sturm, J. E.
This paper analyses the impact of monetary shocks on bank lending in Germany. We follow a cross-sectoral approach by looking at six different banking groups. In general, smaller banks hold a larger buffer of liquid assets which they can use to offset monetary shocks. In addition, the response of bank lending after a monetary contraction is very different across banking sectors. Lending by the credit co-operatives, which are on average the smallest banks, declines most, whereas big banks are able to shield their loans portfolio against monetary shocks. Overall, our results provide support for the existence of a bank lending channel. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kakes, J.; Sturm, J. E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence on the bank lending channel in Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altunbas, Y.; Fazylov, O.; Molyneux, P.
This paper examines evidence for a bank lending channel in Europe. Following the approach suggested by Kishan and Opiela (2000) we use bank balance sheet data to estimate the response of bank lending to changes in monetary policy stance between 1991 and 1999. In particular, we classify banks according to asset size and capital strength to see if these factors have a significant impact on the lending channel. Using a panel data approach we find that across the EMU systems, undercapitalised banks (of any size) tend to respond more to change in policy. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Altunbas, Y.; Fazylov, O.; Molyneux, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modelling credit in the transmission mechanism of the United Kingdom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chrystal, A.; Mizen, P.
Studies have focused heavily on money in the transmission mechanism of monetary policy. In this article we explore the empirical importance of credit. The paper provides a framework in which to analyse the balance sheets of, and financial flows between, different sectors of the UK economy, and an econometric model of the interactions between non-financial firms, households and credit offered by banks and non-bank financial intermediaries. The paper also provides a dynamic structural model of bank and building society credit, money and decisions to consume and invest and then adds credit from non-bank financial intermediaries. Our bottom line is that credit is an important part of the transmission process of UK monetary policy. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chrystal, A.; Mizen, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank concentration and retail interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corvoisier, S.; Gropp, R.
The recent wave of mergers in the euro area raises the question whether the increase in concentration has offset the increase in competition in European banking through deregulation. We test this question by estimating a simple Cournot model of bank pricing. We construct country and product specific measures of bank concentration and find that for loans and demand deposits increasing concentration may have resulted in less competitive pricing by banks, whereas for savings and time deposits, the model is rejected, suggesting increases in contestability and/or efficiency in these markets. Finally, the paper discusses some implications for tests of the effect of concentration on monetary policy transmission. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Corvoisier, S.; Gropp, R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, concentration and their relationship: An empirical analysis of the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bikker, J. A.; Haaf, K.
This article examines competitive conditions and market structure in the banking industry, and investigates their interrelationship. Competition is measured using the Panzar-Rosse model. In order to distinguish competitive behaviour. on local, national and international markets, for each country, three subsamples are taken: small or local banks, medium-sized banks and large or international banks. For all 23 countries considered, estimations indicate monopolistic competition, competition being weaker in local markets and stronger in international markets. Subsequently, a relationship for the impact of the market structure on competition is derived and tested empirically, providing support for the conventional view that concentration impairs competitiveness. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bikker, J. A.; Haaf, K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition in the Dutch consumer credit market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Toolsema, L. A.
This paper considers the degree of competitiveness of the Dutch consumer credit market. We use the well-known Bresnahan-Lau method that estimates a structural model consisting of a demand relation and a supply relation, based on aggregate data. The level of competition is derived from the estimated conjectural variation elasticity. Our empirical results show that there is no evidence of market power. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Toolsema, L. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Boards of directors, ownership, and regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Booth, J. R.; Cornett, M. M.; Tehranian, H.
In this paper we examine whether regulation can be used to substitute for internal monitoring mechanisms (percentage of outside directors, officer and director common stock ownership, and CEO/Chair duality) to control for agency conflicts in a firm. We find that, in general, the percentage of outside directors is negatively related to insider stock ownership, but is not affected by CEO/Chair duality. CEO/Chair duality is, however, less likely when insider stock ownership increases. We find these internal monitoring mechanisms to be significantly less related with regulated firms (banks and utilities). We conclude that to the extent that regulations reduce the impact of managerial decisions on shareholder wealth, effective internal monitoring of managers becomes less important in controlling agency conflicts. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Booth, J. R.; Cornett, M. M.; Tehranian, H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of the introduction of the euro on the volatility of European stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morana, C.; Beltratti, A.
Have convergence of European economies and introduction of the euro produced some effects on European stock markets? Theory suggests that stabilization of fundamentals should decrease variance of stock returns for historically unstable stock markets. We test this proposition with daily data for the period January 1988-May 2000 and apply a three-regime Markov switching model for the variance-covariance matrix among several stock indices, including the UK and the US. The analysis shows that introduction of the euro, after an initial burst of volatility common to all European stock markets, has indeed stabilized the Spanish and Italian stock markets. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morana, C.; Beltratti, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information sharing, lending and defaults: Cross-country evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jappelli, T.; Pagano, M.
Theory predicts that information sharing among lenders attenuates adverse selection and moral hazard, and can therefore increase lending and reduce default rates. Using a new, purpose-built data set on private credit bureaus and public credit registers, we find that bank lending is higher and credit risk is lower in countries where lenders share information, regardless of the private or public nature of the information sharing mechanism. We also find that public intervention is more likely where private arrangements have not arisen spontaneously and creditor rights are poorly protected. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jappelli, T.; Pagano, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do UK financial institutions really price their banking products?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heffernan, S. A.
This paper has several objectives. The first is to explore the type (or types) of imperfect competition that prevailed in the retail banking sector in the 1990s. A general linearised pricing model is employed to test for the degree to which competition in certain markets deviated from the competitive ideal. The key finding, is that, with the exception of mortgage products, deposit and loan rate setting by UK financial institutions is best described by the Salop-Sti-glitz model of monopolistic competition, with bargain and rip-offs. Cournot type behaviour is evident in some cases. Indirectly, the presence of perfect contestability is largely ruled out. Another objective is to compare these findings with the results of a similar study conducted nearly a decade ago, when financial reforms introduced to encourage greater competition were relatively recent. Based on the results of this study, the policy lesson is that financial firms exhibit different types of price setting behaviour depending on the banking product. The policy implication is to require firms to produce comparable information for consumers, thereby helping to contain the loss of consumer surplus in imperfectly competitive markets. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heffernan, S. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining exchange rate risk in world stock markets: A panel approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patro, D. K.; Wald, J. K.; Wu, Y. R.
Using a GARCH approach, we estimate a time-varying two-factor international asset pricing model for weekly equity index returns of 16 OECD countries. A trade-weighted basket of exchange rates and the MSCI world market index are used as risk factors. We find significant currency risk exposures in country equity index returns. We then explain these currency betas using several country-specific macroeconomic variables with a panel approach. We find that imports, exports, credit ratings, and tax revenues significantly affect currency risks in a way that is consistent with some economic hypotheses. Similar conclusions are obtained by using lagged explanatory variables, and thus these macroeconomic variables may be useful as predictors of currency risk exposures. Our results are robust to a number of alternative specifications. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Patro, D. K.; Wald, J. K.; Wu, Y. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflict of interest in commercial bank security underwritings: Canadian evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hebb, G. M.; Fraser, D. R.
The recent repeal of the Glass-Steagall Act in the US has cleared the way for commercial banks to enter the securities underwriting business. Many of the concerns that resulted in the original passage of the Glass-Steagall Act, however, still exist. One of these is the possible conflict of interest a universal bank faces. This paper provides evidence on this issue from the experience of Canada following its removal of restrictions on chartered bank ownership of investment dealers. Both ex ante bond yield comparisons between commercial and investment bank underwritten issues and equity price reactions to bond issue announcements provide no evidence of a conflict of interest. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hebb, G. M.; Fraser, D. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How good is the market at assessing bank fragility? A horse race between different indicators</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bongini, P.; Laeven, L.; Majnoni, G.
We explore for individual banks, active in the East Asian countries during the years 1996 1998, the performance of three sets of indicators of bank fragility that can be computed from publicly available information: accounting data, stock market prices, and credit ratings. We find significantly different patterns among the three groups of indicators in their ability of forecasting financial distress at a specific point in time and over time. More specifically, in the East Asia crisis episode the information based on stock prices or on judgmental assessments of credit rating agencies did not outpace backward looking information contained in balance sheet data. Stock market based information, though, has responded more quickly to changing financial conditions than ratings of credit risk agencies. Overall, the evidence supports the policy conclusion that, where the information processing is quite costly, as in most developing countries, it is important to use simultaneously a plurality of indicators to assess bank fragility. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bongini, P.; Laeven, L.; Majnoni, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strengthening banks' market discipline and leveling the playing field: Are the two compatible?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sironi, A.
This paper examines whether the supervisory objective of strengthening market discipline is compatible with the one of enhancing competitive equality for internationally active banks. This issue is empirically investigated by comparing the determinants of major US and European banks' subordinated notes and debentures (SND) spreads. Three main results emerge. First, the spread/rating relationship is both statistically significant and very similar for US and European banks' bonds. Second, US banks tend to pay a higher average spread on their SND issues because of a poorer average rating. This is due to the presence of European public sector banks, i.e. banks which are either government owned or benefit from explicit government guarantees. In fact, US banks have slightly better Moody's bank financial strength and FitchIBCA individual average ratings, which omit the influence of government and other external support on risk borne by investors. Finally, controlling for the issuing banks' default risk, US banks pay a statistically significant lower average spread on their SND issues. This result is attributed to the higher liquidity of the US market for banks' bonds. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sironi, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comments on "Information about bank risk in options prices"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crouhy, M.
nan</description><author>Crouhy, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information about bank risk in options prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Swidler, S.; Wilcox, J. A.
The volatility of its share price reflects the volatility of the market value of a bank's assets. We present data for the volatilities of individual banks' shares that are implied by the prices of options on the banks' shares. We present evidence that implied volatilities (IV's) better forecast actual. future volatilities of share prices than historical volatilities do. Banks' IV's are correlated with marketwide volatility, with the levels of their own share prices, with their own subordinated debt yield spreads, and with other banks' IV's. Bank capital reduces the response of IV's to market volatility. IV's are likely to add information about bank risk that is timely, cheap, objective, and useful. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Swidler, S.; Wilcox, J. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of privatized firms in the Czech Republic</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harper, J. T.
With the growing importance of privatizations as a part of government policy, most empirical studies of these privatizations conclude that firm performance immediately improves following privatization. Privatization has been the most important part of the transition from the centrally planned economics of Central and Eastern Europe and has a larger impact on those economics than privatizations in other countries. However, few studies have looked at the performance of firms following mass privatization. This study uses 453 separate firms (101 firms privatized in both waves for a total of 554 observations), in the first and second waves of Czech voucher privatization. Using methodology from previous studies. we find that while the overall effects from privatization are positive, the effects vary by privatization wave, size, and industry. Firms privatized in the first wave performed worse (decline in performance following privatization) than firms privatized in the second wave. We also fail to find ownership concentration or debt as an important factor in restructuring the firm. I believe that the results are consistent with two hypotheses. First economic and political structure surrounding the privatization waves plays an important part in the success of privatization. Stable environments, both political and economic, help privatized firms restructure and improve operating performance as well as attract foreign investors and capital even in less developed countries, but in transitional economics undergoing mass privatization in rapidly changing and developing economic and political environments hinder firms from restructuring and improving performance following privatization. Results are also consistent with the hypothesis that firms with a longer preparation period prior to privatization, an "implicit seasoning", improve performance following privatization. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harper, J. T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory learning in failed thrift auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, A.; Misra, L.
We use a sample of failed thrift auctions to examine if regulators learn from early transactions and improve their performance in later transactions. Our findings suggest that experience at failure resolution does not by itself lead to improved regulatory performance. Evidence of regulatory learning is restricted to dealings with repeat acquirers; in cases where an acquiring firm makes abnormal gains, regulators are able to restructure the auction process and eliminate such gains in subsequent acquisitions made by the same acquirers. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gupta, A.; Misra, L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The significance of sell-off profitability in explaining the market reaction to divestiture announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clubb, C.; Stouraitis, A.
Previous research on asset sales has emphasized the divestment motivation and the use of the proceeds from the sale as determinants of selling firm value gains. In contrast, this paper explores the extent to which the relevant information necessary to evaluate sell-offs is embodied in the profitability of the sale, i.e. the price received by the seller over the value-in-use of the divested assets, where the latter is a function of past operating earnings and book value. Our empirical results show that sell-off profitability is substantially more significant in explaining the market reaction to divestiture announcements than the previous literature has suggested. We provide strong evidence of a positive relation between selling firm abnormal returns during sell-off announcements and profit on the sale, which remains significant after controlling for the motivation behind the sell-off, the use of the proceeds from the sale and the presence of agency costs of managerial discretion. We conclude that sell-off profitability explains a major portion of selling firm abnormal returns and is one of the most significant determinants of the market reaction to divestiture announcements. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Clubb, C.; Stouraitis, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt underwriting by commercial bank-affiliated firms and investment banks: More evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roten, I. C.; Mullineaux, D. J.
We compare underwriting performance by commercial bank-affiliated firms (Section 20s) and traditional investment banks over the period 1995-1998. We find that gross spreads are lower in the case of Section 20 underwritings, but that yield spreads are not. Our sample includes a substantial number of observations following changes in Federal Reserve policies that substantially eased restrictions on Section 20 activities in early 1997. Our findings differ somewhat from results in the literature that focused on periods prior to these policy changes. We find, for example, no evidence that a prior commercial bank lending relationship influences underwriting yields for ally type of issue. Our results also fail to confirm earlier evidence that collective Section 20 underwritings produce a favorable competitive effect on gross spreads and yield spreads. We find substantial evidence that both the underwriting mix and the underwriting process are relevant to the behavior of gross spreads and yield spreads over the sample period, (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roten, I. C.; Mullineaux, D. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technical, scale and allocative efficiencies of Turkish banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Isik, I.; Hassan, M. K.
This paper investigates input and output efficiency in the Turkish banking industry to understand the impact of size. international variables, ownership, control and governance on profit, cost, allocative, technical, pure technical and scale efficiency measures. Employing a non-parametric approach along with a parametric approach, we estimate the efficiency of Turkish banks over the 1988-1996 period, This period allows us to account for the changes in the macro economy and regulatory treatment of the Turkish banking industry over time. Our results suggest that the heterogeneous characteristics of banks have significant impact on their efficiency. Moreover, cost and profit efficiencies of the Turkish banks have exacerbated over time. Results also indicate that the dominant source of inefficiency in Turkish banking is due to technical inefficiency rather than allocative inefficiency, which is mainly attributed to diseconomies in scale. To the extent that they chose an inefficient level of production, bank management is responsible for scale inefficient operations. However, increasing demand for banking services in the nineties, fueled by the state's increasing demand for funds to finance chronic budget deficits and high growth policies, and the oligopolistic nature of the Turkish banking market do not justify scale adjustments. Our policy suggestions are that the government implement financial reform packages that foster competition in the banking market, and that the industry devise incentive schemes to improve managerial efficiency. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Isik, I.; Hassan, M. K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond underwriting by banks and conflicts of interest: Evidence from Japan during the pre-war period</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Konishi, M.
Article 65 of the Securities and Exchange Law of Japan, which was carried into effect in 1948, prohibited banks from underwriting corporate securities partialy because of the concern that combining the banking and securities businesses might result in a potential conflict of interest. This paper studies the pricing and long-term default performance of industrial bonds underwritten by commercial banks, the Industrial Bank of Japan (IBJ), and trust firms as compared to those underwritten by investment houses during the pre-war period in Japan when banks were allowed to underwrite industrial bonds. The evidence rejects the concern about the conflicts of interest. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Konishi, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economic and statistical significance of spread forecasts: Evidence from the London Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, N.
This paper measures the economic and statistical significance of econometric forecasts of bid-ask spreads. The economic importance of these forecasts is assessed by considering the benefits of scheduling trades based on these forecasts. The unrestricted vector autoregression (VAR) model of Huang and Masulis [Rev. Financial Studies 12 (1999) 61] and the two-equation structural model of Huang and Stoll [Rev. Financial Studies 7 (1994) 179] are used to generate intraday h-step ahead forecasts of spreads for 50 stocks listed on the London Stock Exchange (LSE). The period corresponding to the minimum expected spread is then scheduled into the trading activity of the investor. The results indicate that when the unrestricted VAR model is used, the spreads incurred are around 35% lower than the spreads incurred by investors who do not schedule their trades. By contrast, spread discounts of only 5% are obtained when the two-equation structural model is used. The heterogeneity of the economic importance of the spread forecasts generated by the models is confirmed by tests of the statistical significance of the forecasts, (D 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Taylor, N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comments on "How good is the market at assessing bank fragility? A horse race between different indicators"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shin, H. S.
nan</description><author>Shin, H. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measures of the riskiness of banking organizations: Subordinated debt yields, risk-based capital, and examination ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evanoff, D. D.; Wall, L. D.
Recently there have been a number of recommendations to increase the role of subordinated debt (SND) in satisfying bank capital requirements as a preferred means to discipline the risk-taking behavior of systemically important banks. One such proposal recommended using SND yield spreads as the triggers for mandatory supervisory action under prompt corrective action guidelines introduced in US banking legislation in the early 1990s. Currently such action is prompted by bank capital ratios. Evidence from previous research suggests that yield information may be a better predictor of bank problems. This paper empirically analyzes potential costs and benefits of using SND signals to trigger prompt corrective action. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Evanoff, D. D.; Wall, L. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market discipline and financial stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crockett, A.
nan</description><author>Crockett, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction: Banks and systemic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jackson, P.; Perraudin, W. R. M.
nan</description><author>Jackson, P.; Perraudin, W. R. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Costs of banking system instability: Some empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoggarth, G.; Reis, R.; Saporta, V.
This paper assesses the cross country 'stylised facts' on empirical measures of the losses incurred during periods of banking crises. We first consider the direct resolution costs to the government and then the broader costs to the welfare of the economy - proxied by losses in GDP. We find that the cumulative output losses incurred during crisis periods are large, roughly 15-20%, on average, of annual GDP. In contrast to previous research, we also find that output losses incurred during crises in developed countries are as high, or higher, on average, than those in emerging-market economies. Moreover, output losses during crisis periods in developed countries also appear to be significantly larger - 10-15% - than in neighbouring countries that did not at the time experience severe banking problems. In emerging-market economies, by contrast, banking crises appear to be costly only when accompanied by a currency crisis. These results seem robust to allowing for macroeconomic conditions at the outset of crisis - in particular low and declining output growth - that have also contributed to future output losses during crises episodes. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Hoggarth, G.; Reis, R.; Saporta, V.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comment on "Costs of banking system instability: Some empirical evidence"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Honohan, P.
nan</description><author>Honohan, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk and financial consolidation: Are they related?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Nicolo, G.; Kwast, M. L.
The creation of a number of very large and sometimes increasingly complex financial institutions, resulting in part from the on-going consolidation of the financial system, has raised concerns that the degree of systemic risk in the financial system may have increased. We argue that firm inter-dependencies, as measured by correlations of stock returns, provide an indicator of systemic risk potential. We analyze the dynamics of the stock return correlations of a sample of US large and complex banking organizations (LCBOs) over 1988-1999, and find a significant positive trend in stock return correlations. This finding is consistent with the view that the systemic risk potential in the financial sector appears to have increased over the last decade. In addition, we relate firms' return correlations to their consolidation activity by estimating measures of the consolidation elasticity of correlation. Consolidation at the sample LCBOs appears to have contributed to LCBOs inter-dependencies. However, consolidation elasticities of correlation exhibit substantial time variation, and likely declined in the latter part of the decade. Thus, factors other than consolidation have also been responsible for the upward trend in return correlations. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Nicolo, G.; Kwast, M. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The macroeconomic impact of bank capital requirements in emerging economies: Past evidence to assess the future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiuri, M. C.; Ferri, G.; Majnoni, G.
We test for emerging economies the hypothesis - previously verified for G-10 countries only - that the enforcement of bank capital asset requirements (CARs) curtails the supply of credit. The econometric analysis on individual bank data suggests three main results. First, CAR enforcement significantly trimmed credit supply, particularly at less-well capitalized banks. Second, the negative impact has been larger for countries enforcing CARs in the aftermath of a currency/financial crisis. Third. the adverse impact of CARs has been somewhat smaller for foreign-owned banks, suggesting that opening up to foreign investors may have partly shielded the domestic banking sector from negative shocks. Overall, CAR enforcement - inducing banks to reduce their lending - may have had both beneficial and detrimental effects. On one hand. it may have reduced ill-advised lending - possibly induced by banks' exploitation of the public safety net - and this is desirable. On the other hand. CAR enforcement may have induced an aggregate credit slowdown or contraction in the examined emerging countries, thus exacerbating liquidity constraints and negatively affecting real activity. This paper is relevant to the ongoing debate on the impact of the revision of bank CARs. as contemplated by the new Basel proposal. Our results suggest that in several emerging economies the revision of bank CARs could well induce a credit supply retrenchment, which should not be underestimated. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiuri, M. C.; Ferri, G.; Majnoni, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comments on "The macroeconomic impact of bank capital requirements in emerging economies: Past evidence to assess the future"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saunders, A.
nan</description><author>Saunders, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit ratings and the BIS capital adequacy reform agenda</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altman, E. I.; Bharath, S. T.; Saunders, A.
In this paper, we have revised and updated our earlier study in order to analyze the most recent (second) draft of the BIS's proposed reforms of bank capital requirements. We conduct Monte-Carlo experiments using data on defaults and severity rates on publicly-traded US corporate bonds over the 1981-1999 period. Analyzing the whole period and various sub-periods, it is clear that the most recent draft of the BIS proposed reforms seriously overestimates the relative riskiness of high-quality debt relative to low quality debt in the so-called standardized model. As a result, the most recent proposal still contains inherent risk-shifting (taking) incentives for banks. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Altman, E. I.; Bharath, S. T.; Saunders, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comments on "Credit ratings and the BIS capital adequacy reform agenda"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bliss, R.
nan</description><author>Bliss, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A guide to choosing absolute bank capital requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carey, M.
Resampling implementation of a stress-scenario approach to estimating portfolio default loss distributions is proposed as the basis for estimates of the appropriate absolute level of economic capital allocations for portfolio credit risk. Estimates are presented for stress scenarios of varying severity and implications of different time horizons are analyzed. Results for a numeraire portfolio are quite sensitive to such variations. Although the analysis is framed in terms of recent proposals to revise regulatory capital requirements for banks, the arguments and results are also relevant for bankers making capital structure decisions. Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Carey, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory and "economic" solvency standards for internationally active banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jackson, P.; Perraudin, W.; Saporta, V.
One of the most important policy issues for financial authorities is to decide at what level average capital charges should be set. The decision may alternatively be expressed as the choice of an appropriate survival probability for representative banks over a horizon such as a year, often termed a "solvency standard". This article sheds light on the solvency standards implied by current and possible future G10 bank regulation and on the "economic solvency standard" that banks choose themselves by their own capital setting decisions. In particular, we employ a credit risk model to show that the survival probability implied by the 1988 Basel Accord is between 99.0% and 99.9%. We then demonstrate that if a new Basel Accord were calibrated to such a standard, it would not represent a binding constraint on banks' current operations since most banks employ a solvency standard higher than 99.9%. To show this, we employ a statistical analysis of bank ratings adjusted for the impact of official or other support as well as credit risk model calculations. Lastly, we advance a possible explanation for the conservative capital choices made by banks by showing that swap volumes are highly correlated with credit quality for given bank size. This suggests that banks' access to important credit markets like the swaps markets may provide a significant discipline in the choice of solvency standard. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Jackson, P.; Perraudin, W.; Saporta, V.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor income and risky assets under market incompleteness: Evidence from Italian data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grande, G.; Ventura, L.
Theory suggests that uninsurable income risk induces individuals to accumulate assets as a precautionary reserve of value. Most assets, however, bear rate of return risk, that can be diversified only if every asset is traded by a large number of individuals and arbitrage is frictionless. Using Italian micro-data, we find evidence of income and asset risks that affect consumption. Italian households are particularly well insured against illness but not against job losses. Moreover, we detect a positive, yet weak, effect of asset holding on the variability of consumption streams across households. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grande, G.; Ventura, L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The allocation of catastrophe risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niehaus, G.
The potential losses from catastrophes have led financial researchers to address the following questions: (1) to what extent is catastrophe risk being shared (insured) and is the allocation of catastrophe risk consistent with notions of optimal risk sharing? (2) if not, what market imperfections hinder the efficient allocation of catastrophe risk? and (3) are there government policies or private market solutions that could lead to a more efficient allocation of catastrophe risk? This paper summarizes the research that has been conducted on these questions. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Niehaus, G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can insurers pay for the "big one"? Measuring the capacity of the insurance market to respond to catastrophic losses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cummins, J. D.; Doherty, N.; Lo, A.
This paper presents a theoretical and empirical analysis of the capacity of the US property liability insurance industry to finance catastrophic property losses in the $100 billion range. In our theoretical analysis, we show that the sufficient condition for capacity maximization, given a level of total resources in the industry, is for all insurers to hold a net of reinsurance underwriting portfolio which is perfectly correlated with aggregate industry losses. This result leads to a natural definition of industry capacity as the amount of industry resources that are deliverable conditional on an industry loss of a given size. Estimating capacity using insurer financial statement data, we find that the industry could adequately fund a $100 billion event. However, such an event would cause numerous insolvencies and severely destabilize insurance markets. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cummins, J. D.; Doherty, N.; Lo, A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial crises and coordination failure: A comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marshall, D. A.
The three papers of this session link financial crises (explicitly or implicitly) to coordination failure. In Bryant (Journal of Banking and Finance, 2002), the possibility of coordination failure is due to complementarity in the productive technology. In Chui et al. (Journal of Banking and Finance, 2002), foreign lenders to a small country fail to coordinate on the optimal strategy rolling over short-term loans. Finally, Amable et al. (Journal of Banking and Finance, 2002) implicitly introduce coordination failure through a production function with external increasing returns to scale. This sort of "thick markets" externality can be viewed as a reduced form that stands for coordination problems in a non-Walrasian economy. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marshall, D. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign liquidity crises: Analytics and implications for public policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chui, M.; Gai, P.; Haldane, A. G.
This paper offers an analytical framework with which to assess some recent proposals for strengthening the international financial architecture. We develop a model of sovereign liquidity crises that reflects two sources of financial stress - weak fundamentals and self-fulfilling expectations. We examine the nature of the underlying co-ordination game and investigate the properties of the unique equilibrium. In so doing, we are able to characterise the welfare costs of belief-driven crises, which we find to be potentially significant. We also evaluate some recent policy proposals including prudent debt and liquidity management, capital controls, greater information disclosure, and the efficacy of monetary policy tightening in the midst of crisis. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chui, M.; Gai, P.; Haldane, A. G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal capacity in the banking sector and economic growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amable, B.; Chatelain, J. B.; De Bandt, O.
The paper investigates, from the welfare and growth point of view, the determination of the optimal capacity of the banking system. For that purpose, we consider an overlapping generation model with endogenous growth. There is horizontal differentiation and imperfect competition in the banking sector. Macro-economic shocks affect the return on capital and, together with the expectations of depositors, condition the stability of the banking sector. We specify to what extent deposit insurance may reduce instability and increase the number of deposits, welfare and growth. We also characterise the conditions under which excess banking capacities may appear and how their reduction may improve welfare. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amable, B.; Chatelain, J. B.; De Bandt, O.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade, credit and systemic fragility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bryant, J.
This paper treats an idealized monetary framework in which merchant banks finance trade; trade which is induced by decentralized production. Indeed, merchant bank credit instruments, coupled with local bank deposits, facilitate decentralization of both production and trade. At the same time, decentralized production, exhibiting technological complementarity, induces systemic monetary fragility. However, with the decentralization of trade, the indemnification of either merchant bank credit instruments or of local bank deposits eliminates fragility. In particular, deposit insurance also stabilizes credit. The result is a stable cashless economy, a replacement of trade in specie. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bryant, J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ratings migration and the business cycle, with application to credit portfolio stress testing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bangia, A.; Diebold, F. X.; Kronimus, A.; Schagen, C.; Schuermann, T.
The turmoil in the capital markets in 1997 and 1998 has highlighted the need for systematic stress testing of banks' portfolios, including both their trading and lending books. We propose that underlying macroeconomic volatility is a key part of a useful conceptual framework for stress testing credit portfolios, and that credit migration matrices provide the specific linkages between underlying macroeconomic conditions and asset quality. Credit migration matrices, which characterize the expected changes in credit quality of obligors, are cardinal inputs to many applications, including portfolio risk assessment, modeling the term structure of credit risk premia, and pricing of credit derivatives. They are also an integral part of many of the credit portfolio models used by financial institutions. By separating the economy into two states or regimes, expansion and contraction, and conditioning the migration matrix on these states, we show that the loss distribution of credit portfolios can differ greatly, as can the concomitant level of economic capital to be assigned. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bangia, A.; Diebold, F. X.; Kronimus, A.; Schagen, C.; Schuermann, T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing rating transitions and rating drift with continuous observations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lando, D.; Skodeberg, T. M.
We consider the estimation of credit rating transitions based on continuous-time observations. Through simple examples and using a large data set from Standard and Poor's, we illustrate the difference between estimators based on discrete-time cohort methods and estimators based on continuous observations. We apply semi-parametric regression techniques to test for two types of non-Markov effects in rating transitions: Duration dependence and dependence on previous rating. We find significant non-Markov effects, especially for the downgrade movements. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lando, D.; Skodeberg, T. M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing the stability of implied probability density functions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bliss, R. R.; Panigirtzoglou, N.
This paper examines the absolute and relative robustness of two of the most common methods for estimating implied probability density functions (PDFs) - the double-lognormal approximating function and the smoothed implied volatility smile methods using short sterling futures options and the FTSE 100 index options. The changes resulting from randomly perturbing quoted prices by no more than a half tick provide a lower bound on the confidence intervals of the summary statistics derived from the estimated PDFs. Our tests show that the smoothed implied volatility smile method dominates the double lognormal as a technique for estimating implied PDFs. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bliss, R. R.; Panigirtzoglou, N.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Innovations in testing the stability of risk measures over time and across models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vlaar, P. J. G.
nan</description><author>Vlaar, P. J. G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling correlated market and credit risk in fixed income portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barnhill, T. M.; Maxwell, W. F.
Current risk assessment methodologies separate the analysis of market and credit risk and thus misestimate security and portfolio risk levels. We propose a new approach that relates financial market volatility to firm specific credit risk and integrates interest rate, interest rate spread, and foreign exchange rate risk into one overall fixed income portfolio risk assessment. Accounting for the correlation between these significant risk factors as well as portfolio diversification results in improved risk measurement and management. The methodology is shown to produce reasonable credit transition probabilities, prices for bonds with credit risk, and portfolio value-at-risk measures. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barnhill, T. M.; Maxwell, W. F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special issue - Risk management in the global economy: Measurement, management, and macroeconomic implications - Introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hunter, W. C.; Smith, S. D.
nan</description><author>Hunter, W. C.; Smith, S. D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management in the global economy: A review essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hunter, W. C.; Smith, S. D.
This paper provides a review of developments in the area of risk management at both the firm level and the macro-economy. We review rationales regarding why firms choose to manage risk, as well as new developments in measuring and managing risk in a dynamic setting. We also consider current risk sharing arrangements in light of the theory regarding optimal risk sharing. The paper concludes with some suggestions for additional research that emphasizes the importance of incorporating market incompleteness in an equilibrium setting. We also discuss the role of incompleteness at the macro-level and speculate on how derivatives markets may influence macro-economic stabilization policy. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V..</description><author>Hunter, W. C.; Smith, S. D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring off-balance-sheet leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, P.
The simultaneous unwinding of leveraged positions can trigger financial market turbulence. Although balance-sheet measures of leverage are available, it is useful to construct a measure of leverage that incorporates both on- and off-balance-sheet activities. This paper provides measures of leverage implicit in derivative contracts by decomposing the contracts into cash market equivalent components. A leverage ratio can then be calculated for this replicating portfolio, which consists of own funds (equity) and borrowed funds equivalents (debt). Methods for aggregating leverage by institution and by markets are presented. The interaction between leverage and risk is discussed, and a modified capital adequacy ratio is calculated, which captures off-balance-sheet exposure. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Breuer, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management and the credit risk premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adam, T. R.
This paper shows how the credit risk premium affects firms' optimal hedging strategies. The model predicts that if the credit risk premium is relatively small, firms use convex hedging strategies. If the credit risk premium is relatively large, firms use concave hedging strategies. Firms in between those two extremes use strategies that feature both convex and concave elements, e.g. collar strategies. Finally, firms that are unlevered, invest little and are exposed to few non-hedgeable risks are the most likely to use linear approximations of the optimal strategy. The model replicates essentially all observed hedging strategies in the gold mining industry. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adam, T. R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does executive portfolio structure affect risk management? CEO risk-taking incentives and corporate derivatives usage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rogers, D. A.
This paper extends the investigation of the effect of managerial motives on hedging policy. I utilize a proxy variable that incorporates CEO incentives to increase risk relative to incentives to increase stock price. The variable is directly measured using observed characteristics of CEO portfolios of stock and option holdings. Furthermore, CEO risk-taking incentives are modeled as a choice variable to eliminate the simultaneity bias of modeling risk-taking incentives as an exogenous variable. If modeled as a simultaneous system of equations, a strong negative link between CEO risk-taking incentives and the amount of derivative holdings exists. This result is consistent with the notion that derivatives are used for hedging purposes. Both the characteristics of stock and option holdings are important in determining cross-sectional differences in corporate derivative holdings. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rogers, D. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value and risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>MacMinn, R. D.
The corporation is often viewed as a nexus of contracts. That view is slightly altered here. The corporation is viewed as a nexus of risks. The management of the corporation may then be thought of as the selection and management of the risks in a way that creates value. This I perspective is applied in a discussion of the three articles presented in this session. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>MacMinn, R. D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The credit risk in SME loans portfolios: Modeling issues, pricing, and capital requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dietsch, M.; Petey, J.
This paper is devoted to the credit risk modeling issues of small commercial loans portfolios. We propose specific solutions dealing with the most important peculiarities of these portfolios: their large size and the limited information about the financial situation of borrowers. We then compute the probability density function of futures losses and VaR measures in a portfolio of 220.000 French SMEs. We also compute marginal risk contributions in order to discuss the loan pricing issue of small commercial loans and to compare the capital requirements derived from our model with those derived from the New Ratings-Based Basel Capital Accord. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dietsch, M.; Petey, J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>GARCH vs. stochastic volatility: Option pricing and risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lehar, A.; Scheicher, M.; Schittenkopf, C.
In this paper we compare the out-of-sample performance of two common extensions of the Black-Scholes option pricing model, namely GARCH and stochastic volatility (SV). We calibrate the three models to intraday FTSE 100 option prices and apply two sets of performance criteria, namely out-of-sample valuation errors and Value-at-Risk (VaR) oriented measures. When we analyze the fit to observed prices, GARCH clearly dominates both SV and the benchmark Black-Scholes model. However, the predictions of the market risk from hypothetical derivative positions show sizable errors. The fit to the realized profits and losses is poor and there are no notable differences between the models. Overall, we therefore observe that the more complex option pricing models can improve on the Black-Scholes methodology only for the purpose of pricing, but not for the VaR forecasts. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lehar, A.; Scheicher, M.; Schittenkopf, C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simultaneity bias in mortgage lending: A test of simultaneous equations models on bank-specific data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dawkins, M. C.
This study uses simultaneous equations models and single-equation models to test for simultaneity bias in mortgage refinance data compiled by a regional bank. The purpose of the study is to assess the claim that single-equation models of the lending decision produce biased and inconsistent parameter estimates of endogenous mortgage terms. Bank-specific data are analyzed to avoid bias resulting from uncontrolled policy, training, or underwriting differences across banks. Importantly, the data contain all variables the regional bank identified as important factors in explaining its loan disposition results. After controlling for applicants' debt, income, credit history, and requested loan term, I find that the race coefficient in single-equation models is biased upward, while the loan-to-value ratio coefficient is biased downward, although both biases are insignificant. Overall, the results suggest that simultaneous equations models are preferable to single-equation models in tests for discrimination, and can be used to determine the extent of race coefficient and loan-to-value ratio coefficient bias in single-equation models. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dawkins, M. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investigating the cost performance of UK credit unions using radial and non-radial efficiency measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McKillop, D. G.; Glass, J. C.; Ferguson, C.
This paper examines the relative efficiency of UK credit unions. Radial and non-radial measures of input cost efficiency plus associated scale efficiency measures are computed for a selection of input output specifications. Both measures highlighted that UK credit unions have considerable scope for efficiency gains. It was mooted that the documented high levels of inefficiency may be indicative of the fact that credit unions, based on clearly defined and non-overlapping common bonds, are not in competition with each other for market share. Credit unions were also highlighted as suffering from a considerable degree of scale inefficiency with the majority of scale inefficient credit unions subject to decreasing returns to scale. The latter aspect highlights that the UK Government's goal of larger credit unions must be accompanied by greater regulatory freedom if inefficiency is to be avoided. One of the advantages of computing non-radial measures is that an insight into potential over- or under-expenditure on specific inputs can be obtained through a comparison of the non-radial measure of efficiency with the associated radial measure. Two interesting findings emerged, the first that UK credit unions over-spend on dividend payments and the second that they under-spend on labour costs. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McKillop, D. G.; Glass, J. C.; Ferguson, C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamic behavior of closed-end funds and its implication for pricing, forecasting, and trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kellerhals, B. P.; Schobel, R.
Closed-end funds (CEFs) show a distinctive feature in comparison to mutual funds: The market value determined on organized exchanges dynamically differs over time from the reported net asset value by a discount. This predominant capital market anomaly motivates our valuation model to price CEFs. We derive a stochastic pricing model that captures both the price risk of the funds as well as their risk associated with altering discounts. Implementing this theoretical model on a sample of emerging market closed-end funds we are able to infer insights into two potential applications for investors. First, we test the forecasting power of the pricing model to predict CEF market prices. Second, based on information on the premia we implement portfolio trading strategies using filter rules. The results on these suggested applications indicate that our pricing model generates valuable investment information. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kellerhals, B. P.; Schobel, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global and local information asymmetries, illiquidity and SEC rule 144A/Regulation S: The case of Indian GDRs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pinegar, J. M.; Ravichandran, R.
Between 1992 and 1997, Indian firms were the most frequent issuers of equity-backed Global Depositary Receipts (GDRs) governed by the SEC's Rule 144A and Regulation S. They also accounted for the highest dollar volume. Home-market stock price responses to these issues are consistent with the hypotheses that GDRs enable firms to resolve two forms of information asymmetry: (1) an asymmetry between issuing firms and international investors that results from market segmentation and (2) an asymmetry between Indian firms and home-market investors that resembles asymmetries that help explain abnormal returns in equity private placements by US firms. Our evidence suggests that GDR issuance can increase investors' recognition of underlying shares even if there are no liquidity enhancements and even if disclosure requirements are not as demanding as those imposed on foreign firms whose depositary receipts trade in public US markets. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pinegar, J. M.; Ravichandran, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A conditional multifactor analysis of return momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, X. P.
Although the Fama-French three-factor model captures most CAPM anomalies, it still fails to explain return momentum. This paper shows that the incorporation of conditioning information into an asset-pricing model is one way to capture return momentum. Results from the conditional regression with linear exposures in the instruments show clear evidence that both small minus big (SMB) and high minus low (HML) risks are time varying and that momentum and reversal return patterns have different time-varying risk characteristics. The conditional Fama-French regression model seems, however, to remain misspecified. Conversely, when the linearity assumption is relaxed and cross-sectional restrictions are imposed, the conditional pricing model appears to capture both short-term momentum and long-term reversal. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, X. P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On trust as a commodity and on the grammar of trust</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khan, M. A.
I look at 'trust' in the light of two constructions taken from economic science: general competitive analysis and the theory of games. I draw on Baier's anti-contractarian perspective, as well as on one informed by Wittgenstein's writings. The former focuses on relations between inherently unequal and asymmetrical individuals, while the latter draws on and revolves around the imperative in the Philosophical Investigations: "Let the use teach you the meaning" [p. 212; also p. 220]. 1 try to spell out how the choice of language has epistemological implications: for an analysis of trust, for the trustworthiness of the scientific constructions I use for analyzing trust, and thereby, more generally, for defining 'ourselves' and our 'form of life.' (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khan, M. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ties that bind in business ethics: Social contracts and why they matter</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donaldson, T.; Dunfee, T. W.
How should bankers respond to challenges about whether to separate stock analysis from the other financial functions of financial services companies, or whether to maintain relationships with socially discredited customers? We wrote a book recently, Ties That Bind (Donaldson and Dunfee, 1999), out of our conviction that answering many of these questions requires a new approach to business ethics, one that exposes the implicit understandings or "contracts" that bind industries, companies, and economic systems into communities. In this article we unpack the fundamental elements of our approach called Integrative Social Contracts Theory (ISCT) and demonstrate how the theory can be applied to a particular question currently asked in the financial services industry, namely, "How should accounting firms and banking institutions deal with the increasing criticism alleging that new forms of conflict of interest impair the objectivity of auditors and security analysts." (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Donaldson, T.; Dunfee, T. W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contractors as stakeholders: Reconciling stakeholder theory with the nexus-of-contracts firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boatright, J. R.
The contractual or nexus-of-contracts theory serves as a normative foundation for both the stockholder and stakeholder conceptions of the firm. In this theory, each constituency or stakeholder group bargains with the firm over a set of rights that will protect the firm-specific assets that it makes available for production. This paper argues that the main difference between the stockholder and stakeholder conceptions lies in different assumptions about the choice of protections that each constituency would make. The value of this thesis is that it identifies the points at issue between these two conceptions in ways that facilitate a reconciliation. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boatright, J. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business ethics and organizational architecture</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brickley, J. A.; Smith, C. W.; Zimmerman, Z. L.
We suggest that economics can complement traditional ethics discussions with the respect to at least three basic points. First, economics provides a theory of how individuals make choices; including choices that have potential ethical dimensions. Second business ethics and the internal structure of the organization are inextricably linked they establish important incentives for those individuals who compose the firm. Third, a company's reputation for ethical behavior is part of its brand-name capital. As such, it is reflected in the value of its securities. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Brickley, J. A.; Smith, C. W.; Zimmerman, Z. L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>