<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF13</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Interaction between housing prices and household borrowing: The Finnish case</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oikarinen, Elias
Employing time series econometrics this study shows that there has been a significant two-way interaction between housing prices and housing loan stock in Finland since the financial liberalization in the late 1980s. Before the financial deregulation the interaction was substantially weaker. Furthermore, housing appreciation has a notable positive impact on the outstanding consumption loan stock. It appears that there is no similar relationship between stock prices and credit. Understanding the two-way interaction between housing prices and credit is of importance, since the interdependence is likely to augment boom-bust cycles in the economy and increase the fragility of the financial sector. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oikarinen, Elias</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option trading and individual investor performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauer, Rob; Cosemans, Mathijs; Eichholtz, Piet
This paper examines the impact of option trading on individual investor performance. The results show that most investors incur substantial losses on their option investments, which are much larger than the losses front equity trading. We attribute the detrimental impact of option trading on investor performance to poor market timing that results from overreaction to past stock market returns. High trading costs further contribute to the poor returns on option investments. Gambling and entertainment appear to be the most important motivations for trading options while hedging motives only play a minor role. We also provide strong evidence of performance persistence among option traders. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bauer, Rob; Cosemans, Mathijs; Eichholtz, Piet</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accounting-based versus market-based cross-sectional models of CDS spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, Sanjiv R.; Hanouna, Paul; Sarin, Atulya
Models of financial distress rely primarily on accounting-based information (e.g. [Altman, E., 1968. Financial ratios, discriminant analysis and the prediction of corporate bankruptcy. journal of Finance 23, 589609; Ohlson, J., 1980, Financial ratios and the probabilistic prediction of bankruptcy. journal of Accounting Research 19, 109-131]) or market-based information (e.g. [Merton, R.C., 1974. On the pricing of corporate debt: The risk structure of interest rates. journal of Finance 29, 449-470]). In this paper, we provide evidence on the relative performance of these two classes of models. Using a sample of 2860 quarterly CDS spreads we find that a model of distress using accounting metrics performs comparably to market-based structural models of default. Moreover, a model using both sources of information performs better than either of the two models. Overall, our results Suggest that both sources of information (accounting - and market-based) are complementary in pricing distress. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Das, Sanjiv R.; Hanouna, Paul; Sarin, Atulya</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Irreversible investment, managerial discretion and optimal capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrikopoulos, Andreas
We explore the significance of employee compensation and alternative (reservation) income on investment timing, endogenous default, Yield spreads and capital structure. In a real-options setting, a manager's incentive to under(over)invest in a project is associated to labor income lie has to forego in order to work on the project, the manager's salary, his stake on the project's equity capital and his subsequent income, should he decide to terminate operations, We find that the optimal level of coupon payments decreases with managerial salary and ownership stake while it is increasing in the manager's reservation income. Yield spreads (optimal leverage ratios) are increasing (decreasing) in the manager's salary and ownership stake, while they are decreasing (increasing) in the manager's reservation income. Exploring agency costs of debt as deviations from I value-maximizing investment policy, we document a U-shaped relationship between agency costs of debt and the managerial compensation parameters: the Manager's reservation income, salary and ownership share. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andrikopoulos, Andreas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A practical approach to validating a PD model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Medema, Lydian; Koning, Ruud H.; Lensink, Robert
The capital adequacy framework Basel II aims to promote the adoption of stronger risk management practices by the banking industry. The implementation makes validation of credit risk models more important. Lenders therefore need a validation methodology to convince their supervisors that their credit scoring models are performing well. In this paper we take tip the challenge to propose and implement a simple validation methodology that can be used by banks to validate their credit risk modelling exercise. We will contextualise the proposed methodology by applying it to a default model of mortgage loans of a commercial bank in the Netherlands. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Medema, Lydian; Koning, Ruud H.; Lensink, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt, investment, and product market competition: A note on the limited liability effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clayton, Matthew J.
This paper extends a model by Brander and Lewis [Brander, J. Lewis, T., 1986. Oligopoly and financial structure: The limited liability effect. American Economic Review 76, 956-970] on the relationship between capital structure, investment and product market competition based on the limited liability effect of debt. Empirical papers (see for example Campello [Campello, M., 2003. Capital structure and product markets interactions: Evidence from business cycles. journal of Financial Economics 68, 3533781, and Chevalier [Chevalier, J., 1995a. Capital structure and product market competition: Empirical evidence from the supermarket industry. American Economic Review 85, 415-435; Chevalier, J., 19951). Do LBO supermarkets charge more? An empirical analysis of the effect of LBOs on supermarket pricing. journal of Finance 50, 1095-1112]) generally reject the limited liability theories in favor of the predatory theories because leverage leads to less investment and weaker product market competition. This paper shows that when firms also have an investment choice, leverage can lead to weaker product market competition in a limited liability model. In addition, non-zero leverage is still optimal within this model based solely on the limited liability effect. In predatory models debt is motivated by issues outside of product market concerns, for example to solve an agency problem. Finally, this model is also consistent with the investment decisions documented empirically. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved</description><author>Clayton, Matthew J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What motivates a subprime borrower to default?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daglish, Toby
This paper uses a real options approach to analyse the exercise of the default option embedded in mortgages. In particular, it examines a subprime household who borrows at a premium, but hopes to refinance at prime rates if their house appreciates, We show how these optimal default decisions can be used to calculate probabilities of default - an important input for risk management and pricing purposes. Numerical examples are provided, calibrated to US data. In a low interest rate environment, the credit-upgrade potential may discourage subprime borrowers from defaulting. However, default probabilities are highly sensitive to changes in interest rates and house prices. This provides a rational explanation for the prevalence of adjustable rate mortgages among subprime borrowers, and the subsequent large numbers of defaults, when interest rates rose and house prices declined. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Daglish, Toby</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance and governance in microfinance institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mersland, Roy; Strom, R. Oystein
We examine the relationship between firm performance and corporate governance in microfinance institutions (MFI) using a self-constructed global dataset on MFIs collected from third-party rating agencies. Using random effects panel data estimations, we study the effects of board and CEO characteristics, firm ownership type, customer-firm relationship, and competition and regulation on an MFI's financial performance and outreach to poor clients. We find that financial performance improves with local rather than international directors, an internal board auditor, and a female CEO. The number of credit clients increase with CEO/chairman duality. Outreach is lower in the case of lending to individuals than in the case of group lending. We find no difference between non-profit organisations and shareholder firms in financial performance and outreach, and we find that bank regulation has no effect. The results underline the need for an industry specific approach to MFI governance. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mersland, Roy; Strom, R. Oystein</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying volatility risk premia from fixed income Asian options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Caio; Vicente, Jose
Fixed income options are frequently adopted by companies to hedge interest rate risk. Their payoff dependence on the cumulative short-term rate makes them particularly informative about interest rate volatility risk. Based on a joint dataset of bonds and Asian interest rate options, we study the interrelations between bond and volatility risk premia in a major emerging fixed income market. We propose a dynamic term structure model that generates an incomplete market compatible with a preliminary empirical analysis of the dataset. Approximation formulas for at-the-money Asian option prices avoid the use of computationally intensive Fourier transform methods, allowing for an efficient implementation of the model. The model generates a bond risk premium strongly correlated with a widely accepted emerging market benchmark index (EMBI-Global), and a negative volatility risk premium, consistent with the use of Asian options as insurance in this market. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Almeida, Caio; Vicente, Jose</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mitigating risks in cross-border acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mantecon, Tomas
Compared to domestic acquisitions, cross-border acquisitions present greater challenges for buyers. This article analyzes the use of contingent payments, joint ventures, and toehold investments as potential mechanisms for reducing uncertainty in cross-border acquisitions. Toehold investments and earnout payments are associated with larger gains to buyers in domestic acquisitions, but not in cross-border acquisitions. The results indicate that joint ventures can be an effective mechanism to ameliorate the uncertainty associated with cross-border acquisitions in the presence of severe valuation uncertainties and country investment risks. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mantecon, Tomas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional ownership, volatility and dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rubin, Amir; Smith, Daniel R.
We find that the sign of the correlation between institutional ownership and volatility depends on the firm's dividend policy: institutional ownership is negatively (positively) related to volatility among non-dividend (dividend) paying stocks. The empirical results are consistent with an interaction between institutional preference for low volatility and the tendency of higher levels of institutional ownership to increase volatility through their trading behavior. This result is robust to many control variables and possible endogeneity concerns. Supporting our conjecture that institutions herd on dividend signals we find that the correlation between turnover and institutional ownership is higher for dividend paying stocks, and that the positive correlation between turnover and institutional ownership is higher on dividend declaration days. Finally, we also find that the level of institutional ownership drops following an increase in volatility for both dividend payers and non-payers, and that volatility rises following increased institutional ownership for dividend paying stocks. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rubin, Amir; Smith, Daniel R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency costs, governance, and organizational forms: Evidence from the mutual fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferris, Stephen P.; Yan, Xuemin
Using a comprehensive sample Of Mutual funds and fund families for the period 1992-2004. this study examines the impact of fund management companies' organizational forms on the level of agency costs within mutual funds. We find that, all else being equal: (1) funds managed by public fund families charge higher fees than those managed by private fund families; (2) public fund families acquire more funds than private fund families: and (3) funds of public fund families significantly underperform funds of private fund families. Collectively, these findings suggest that agency costs are higher in mutual funds managed by public fund families. Our results are consistent with the idea that the agency conflict between the fund management company and fund shareholders is more acute for public management companies because of their shorter-term focus. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferris, Stephen P.; Yan, Xuemin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do investment banks charge to underwrite American Depositary Receipts?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hsuan-Chi; Fauver, Larry; Yang, Pei-Ching
We investigate how investment banks determine the gross spreads paid by American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) from 1980 to 2004. We begin by comparing the gross spreads of ADR IPOs and ADR SEOs to those of matching US IPOs and US SEOs, We document clustering at the 7% level far Our ADR 1170 sample (44%, for the ADR IPO firms without a Previous equity listing), whereas our ADR SEO sample exhibits no discernable clustering at any level. We then Find that ADR IPO gross spreads can be explained by firm and offer characteristics (similar to our matched sample of US IPOs), and by whether the ADR IPO firm has a previous equity listing. ADR SEO gross spreads can be explained more by offer characteristics (more similar to our matched sample of US SEOs). (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Hsuan-Chi; Fauver, Larry; Yang, Pei-Ching</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate changes and the timing of debt issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barry, Christopher B.; Mann, Steven C.; Mihov, Vassil; Rodriguez, Mauricio
There is much recent interest in the role of market timing in firm financial decisions. Using a large detailed sample of corporate public debt issues, private placements, Rule 144A issues and bank loans over the period 1970-2006, we investigate the relationship between interest rate changes and issues of floating and fixed-rate debt. Our results indicate that both past and future rates are associated with issuance decisions. We examine whether firms are able to lower their cost of capital by anticipating future rate changes, controlling for firm characteristics and market conditions. Our findings suggest that evidence of timing success is dependent on the time interval and type of debt examined. Over the longest time intervals available in our data, we do not find evidence of timing ability for fixed-rate or floating-rate debt issues. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barry, Christopher B.; Mann, Steven C.; Mihov, Vassil; Rodriguez, Mauricio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund volatility timing and management fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giambona, Erasmo; Golec, Joseph
This paper shows that compensation incentives partly drive fund managers' market volatility timing strategies. Larger incentive management fees lead to less counter-cyclical or more pro-cyclical volatility timing. But fund styles or aggregate fund flows could also account for this relation; therefore, we control for them and find that the relation between fees and volatility timing still holds. Results show that less aggressive fund styles are associated with pro-cyclical volatility timing, and that volatility timing and flow timing are negatively related. We also find that pro-cyclical timing mostly improves funds' average excess returns, Sharpe ratios, and alphas. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giambona, Erasmo; Golec, Joseph</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pricing of deposit insurance considering bankruptcy costs and closure policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Dar-Yeh; Shie, Fu-Shuen; Wang, Kehluh; Lin, Jung-Chu
The paper aims to study the pricing issue of deposit insurance with explicit consideration of bankruptcy costs and closure policies. Full coverage from deposit insurance is imposed by many regulators to stabilize the banking system in the current financial crisis, despite of the potential moral hazard problems. We argue that bankruptcy cost is an important factor in pricing deposit insurance, especially when the insured institution is insolvent. Applying the isomorphic relationship between deposit insurance and put option, we first derive a closed-form solution for the pricing model with bankruptcy costs and closure policies. Then, we modify the barrier option approach to price the deposit insurance in which the bankruptcy cost is set as a function of asset return volatility and more realistic closure policies considering possible forbearance can be accounted for. The properties of the models are supported by numerical simulations and are consistent with the risk-based pricing scheme. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hwang, Dar-Yeh; Shie, Fu-Shuen; Wang, Kehluh; Lin, Jung-Chu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient portfolios when housing needs change over the life cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pelizzon, Loriana; Weber, Guglielmo
We address the issue of the efficiency of household portfolios in the presence of housing risk. We treat housing stock as an asset and rents as a stochastic liability stream: over the life cycle, households can be short or long in their net-housing position. Efficient financial portfolios are the sum of a standard Markowitz portfolio and a housing risk hedge term that multiplies net housing wealth. Our empirical results show that net housing plays a key role in determining which household portfolios are inefficient. The largest proportion of inefficient portfolios obtains among those with positive net housing, who should invest more in stocks. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pelizzon, Loriana; Weber, Guglielmo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading activity, dealer concentration and foreign exchange market quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaul, Aditya; Sapp, Stephen
We study the relation between foreign exchange market quality and both trading activity and dealer concentration by considering two currency pairs with significant differences along both dimensions - the Euro-US dollar and Canadian dollar-US dollar. A variance ratio test reveals over-reaction in currency prices, but that this is smallest when trading activity is high and dealer concentration at its peak. A GARCH model shows that over-reaction declines as trading activity and dealer concentration increase, with the results being stronger for the Euro. Our results confirm that trading activity is an important determinant of market quality, but also point to a significant role for dealer concentration. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaul, Aditya; Sapp, Stephen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment, internal funds and public banking in Germany</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engel, Dirk; Middendorf, Torge
Previous studies supposed that low investment-cash flow sensitivities of German firms may be caused by a dominance of public banking. The paper addresses this assumption and applies a unique accounting dataset of German firms. Results from a dynamic version of the sales accelerator model show that the dependence of investment spending on internal funds does not significantly differ among firms attached to savings banks, cooperative banks or commercial banks. Thus, the importance of the public banking sector in Germany may not explain the rather low dependence of German firms on internal funds, and public ownership of banks does not seem to be important for reducing financing constraints. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Engel, Dirk; Middendorf, Torge</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Static hedging and pricing American options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, San-Lin; Shih, Pai-Ta
This paper utilizes the static hedge portfolio (SHP) approach of Derman et al. [Derman, E., Ergener, D., Kani, I., 1995. Static options replication. journal of Derivatives 2, 78-95] and Carr et al. [Carr, P., Ellis, K., Gupta, V., 1998. Static hedging of exotic options. journal of Finance 53, 1165-1190] to price and hedge American options under the Black-Scholes (1973) model and the constant elasticity of variance (CEV) model of Cox [Cox, J., 1975. Notes on option pricing I: Constant elasticity of variance diffusion. Working Paper, Stanford University]. The static hedge portfolio of an American option is formulated by applying the value-matching and smooth-pasting conditions on the early exercise boundary. The results indicate that the numerical efficiency of our static hedge portfolio approach is comparable to some recent advanced numerical methods such as Broadie and Detemple [Broadie, M., Detemple, J., 1996. American option valuation: New bounds, approximations, and a comparison of existing methods. Review of Financial Studies 9, 1211-1250] binomial Black-Scholes method with Richardson extrapolation (BBSR). The accuracy of the SHP method for the calculation of deltas and gammas is especially notable. Moreover, when the stock price changes, the recalculation of the prices and hedge ratios of the American options under the SHP method is quick because there is no need to solve the static hedge portfolio again. Finally, our static hedging approach also provides an intuitive derivation of the early exercise boundary near expiration. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, San-Lin; Shih, Pai-Ta</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency in housing markets: Which home buyers know how to discount?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hjalmarsson, Erik; Hjalmarsson, Randi
We test for efficiency in the Swedish co-op market by examining the negative relationship between the sales price and the present value of future monthly payments or 'rents'. If the co-op housing market is efficient, the present value of co-op rental payments due to underlying debt obligations of the cooperative should be fully reflected in the sales price. However, a one hundred kronor increase in the present value of future rents only leads to an approximately 75 kronor reduction in the sales price. These inefficiencies are larger at the lower end of the housing market and in poorer, less educated regions and appear to reflect both liquidity constraints and the existence of more 'sophisticated' buyers in higher educated areas. Overall, our findings suggest that there is some systematic failure to properly discount the future stream of rent payments relative to the up front sales price. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hjalmarsson, Erik; Hjalmarsson, Randi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic sources of foreign exchange risk in new EU members</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kocenda, Evzen; Poghosyan, Tigran
We address the issue of foreign exchange risk and its macroeconomic determinants in several new EU members. We derive the observable macroeconomic factors-consumption and inflation-using the Stochastic discount factor (SDF) approach. The joint distribution of excess returns in the foreign exchange market and the factors are modeled using a multivariate GARCH-in-mean specification. Our findings show that both real and nominal factors play important roles in explaining the variability of the foreign exchange risk premium. Both types of factors should be included in monetary general equilibrium models employed to study excess returns. To contribute to the further stability of domestic currencies, the new EU members should strive to implement stabilization policies aimed at achieving nominal as well as real convergence with the core EU members. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kocenda, Evzen; Poghosyan, Tigran</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of short-term mutual fund flows and returns: A time-series and cross-sectional investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rakowski, David; Wang, Xiaoxin
This study analyzes the dynamics of daily mutual fund flows. A Vector Auto Regression (VAR) of flows and returns shows that the behavior of fund investors is more consistent with contrarian rather than momentum characteristics. Past fund flows have a positive impact on future fund returns, with the long-term information effect dominating the transient price-pressure effect. Seasonality in daily flows, such as day-of-week and day-of-month patterns are present, and daily flows are generally mean-reverting. Probit regressions indicate that fund investment objective, marketing policy and level of active management explain cross-sectional variation in the behavioral patterns displayed in daily flows. Our results are robust to the different methods of calculating daily flows based on whether or not the day-end TNA figures include the current-day's flow. Throughout the analysis, we contrast the dynamics of daily flows with established results for monthly fund flows and find important differences between the two. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rakowski, David; Wang, Xiaoxin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How corporate governance affects payout policy under agency problems and external financing constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chae, Joon; Kim, Sungmin; Lee, Eun Jung
This paper analyzes the effect of corporate governance on the payout policy when a firm has both agency problems and external financing constraints. We empirically test whether strong corporate governance would lead to higher payout to minimize agency problems (outcome hypothesis), or to lower payout to avoid costly external financing (substitute hypothesis). We find that firms with higher (lower) external financing constraints tend to decrease (increase) payout ratio with an improvement in their corporate governance. The results are consistent with our hypothesis that the relation between payout and corporate governance is reversed depending on the relative sizes of agency and external financing costs. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chae, Joon; Kim, Sungmin; Lee, Eun Jung</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What explains the low profitability of Chinese banks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia-Herrero, Alicia; Gavila, Sergio; Santabarbara, Daniel
This paper analyzes empirically what explains the low profitability of Chinese banks for the period 1997-2004. We find that better capitalized banks tend to be more profitable. The same is true for banks with a relatively larger share of deposits and for more X-efficient banks. In addition, a less concentrated banking system increases bank profitability, which basically reflects that the four state-owned commercial banks China's largest banks - have been the main drag for system's profitability. We find the same negative influence for China's development banks (so-called Policy Banks), which are fully state-owned. Instead, more market-oriented banks, such as joint-stock commercial banks, tend to be more profitable, which again points to the influence of government intervention in explaining bank performance in China. These findings should not come as a surprise for a banking system which has long been functioning as a mechanism for transferring huge savings to meet public policy goals. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garcia-Herrero, Alicia; Gavila, Sergio; Santabarbara, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPOs, clustering, indirect learning and filing independently</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colaco, Hugh M. J.; Ghosh, Chinmoy; Knopf, John D.; Teall, John L.
IPO underpricing has been attributed to valuation uncertainty, which can be at least partially resolved by the indirect learning associated with IPO clustering [Benveniste, L.M., Ljungqvist, A., Wilhelm, W.J., Yu, X.Y., 2003. Evidence of information spillovers in the production of investment banking services. journal of Finance 58, 577-608]. We examine why firms might choose not to issue their IPOs contemporaneously with clusters of similar firms, forgoing opportunities to learn from their peers. We find that the willingness to file an IPO without the benefit of indirect learning from peer firm IPOs is directly related to insiders' needs for portfolio diversification and the firm's need to raise capital. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Colaco, Hugh M. J.; Ghosh, Chinmoy; Knopf, John D.; Teall, John L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The delegated portfolio management problem: Reputation and herding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Villatoro, Felix
We study the relationship between financial intermediaries' reputation and herding in a delegated portfolio management problem context. We identify conditions under which equilibria exist such that intermediaries with good reputation invest in private information, whereas those with poor reputation herd. The model's empirical predictions are discussed and found to be consistent with previous evidence. From a normative stand, our work points out the possible existence of a policy trade-off between protecting investors by demanding more transparency from intermediaries and encouraging herding by free-riders for whom imitating portfolio decisions would be easier under tighter regulation, such as more frequent portfolio disclosure. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Villatoro, Felix</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance and Merton-type default risk of listed banks in the EU: A panel VAR approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koutsomanoli-Filippaki, Anastasia; Mamatzakis, Emmanuel
This paper provides empirical evidence that sheds new light into the dynamic interactions between risk and efficiency, a highly debated issue. First, we estimate three alternative measures of bank performance, by employing a directional distance function framework, along with a cost frontier and a profit function. As a second step, we calculate a Merton-type bank default risk. Then, we employ a panel VAR analysis, which allows the examination of the underlying relationships between efficiency and risk without applying any a priori restrictions. Most evidence shows that the effect of a one standard deviation shock of the distance to default on inefficiency is negative and substantial. There is some evidence of a reverse causation. As part of a sensitivity analysis, we extent our study to investigate the relationship between efficiency and default risk for banks with different types of ownership structures and across financial systems with different levels of development. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koutsomanoli-Filippaki, Anastasia; Mamatzakis, Emmanuel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A framework for assessing the systemic risk of major financial institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Xin; Zhou, Hao; Zhu, Haibin
In this paper we propose a framework for measuring and stress testing the systemic risk of a group of major financial institutions. The systemic risk is measured by the price of insurance against financial distress, which is based on ex ante measures of default probabilities of individual banks and forecasted asset return correlations. Importantly, using realized correlations estimated from high-frequency equity return data can significantly improve the accuracy of forecasted correlations. Our stress testing methodology, using an integrated micro-macro model, takes into account dynamic linkages between the health of major US banks and macro-financial conditions. Our results suggest that the theoretical insurance premium that would be charged to protect against losses that equal or exceed 15% of total liabilities of 12 major US financial firms stood at $110 billion in March 2008 and had a projected upper bound of $250 billion in July 2008. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Xin; Zhou, Hao; Zhu, Haibin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining international stock correlations with CPI fluctuations and market volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Yijie; Chou, Ray Yeutien; Li, Dan
This paper investigates the dynamic correlations among six international stock market indices and their relationship to inflation fluctuation and market volatility. The current research uses a newly developed time series model, the Double Smooth Transition Conditional Correlation with Conditional Auto Regressive Range (DSTCC-CARR) model. Findings reveal that international stock correlations are significantly time-varying and the evolution among them is related to cyclical fluctuations of inflation rates and stock volatility. The higher/lower correlations emerge between countries when both countries experience a contractionary/expansionary phase or higher/lower volatilities. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cai, Yijie; Chou, Ray Yeutien; Li, Dan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit spreads: An empirical analysis on the informational content of stocks, bonds, and CDS</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Forte, Santiago; Ignacio Pena, Juan
This paper explores the dynamic relationship between stock market implied credit spreads, CDS spreads, and bond spreads. A general VECM representation is proposed for changes in the three credit spread measures which accounts for zero, one, or two independent cointegration equations, depending on the evidence provided by any particular company. Empirical analysis on price discovery, based on a proprietary sample of North American and European firms, and tailored to the specific VECM at hand, indicates that stocks lead CDS and bonds more frequently than the other way round. It likewise confirms the leading role of CDS with respect to bonds. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Forte, Santiago; Ignacio Pena, Juan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contagion as a domino effect in global stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Markwat, Thijs; Kole, Erik; van Dijk, Dick
This paper shows that stock market contagion occurs as a domino effect, where confined local crashes evolve into more widespread crashes. Using a novel framework based on ordered logit regressions we model the occurrence of local, regional and global crashes as a function of their past occurrences and financial variables. We find significant evidence that global crashes do not occur abruptly but are preceded by local and regional crashes. Besides this form of contagion, interdependence shows up by the effect of interest rates, bond returns and stock market volatility on crash probabilities. When it comes to forecasting global crashes, our model outperforms a binomial model for global crashes only. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Markwat, Thijs; Kole, Erik; van Dijk, Dick</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The ADR shadow exchange rate as an early warning indicator for currency crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eichler, Stefan; Karmann, Alexander; Maltritz, Dominik
We develop an indicator for currency crisis risk using price spreads between American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) and their underlyings. This risk measure represents the mean exchange rate ADR investors expect after a potential currency crisis or realignment. It makes crisis prediction possible on a daily basis as depreciation expectations are reflected in ADR market prices. Using daily data, we analyze the impact of several risk drivers related to standard currency crisis theories and find that ADR investors perceive higher currency crisis risk when export commodity prices fall, trading partners' currencies depreciate, sovereign yield spreads increase, or interest rate spreads widen. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eichler, Stefan; Karmann, Alexander; Maltritz, Dominik</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does multinationality matter? Implications of operational hedging for the exchange risk exposure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Jongmoo Jay; Jiang, Cao
An important issue in global corporate risk management is whether the multinationality of a firm matters in terms of its effect on exchange risk exposure. In this paper, we examine the exchange risk exposure of US firms during 1983-2006, comparing multinational and non-multinational firms and focusing on the role of operational hedging. Since MNCs and non-multinationals differ in size and other characteristics, we construct matched samples of MNCs and non-multinationals based on the propensity score method. We find that the multinationality in fact matters for a firm's exchange exposure but not in the way usually presumed - the exchange risk exposures are actually smaller and less significant for MNCs than non-multi nationals. The results are robust with respect to different samples and model specifications. There is evidence that operational hedging decreases a firm's exchange risk exposure and increases its stock returns. The effective deployment of operational risk management strategies provides one reason why MNCs may have insignificant exchange risk exposure estimates. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choi, Jongmoo Jay; Jiang, Cao</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of exchange rate variability on US shareholder wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Muller, Aline; Verschoor, Willem F. C.
We examine the relationship between financial crisis exchange rate variability and equity return volatility for US multinationals. Empirical analysis of the major financial crises of the last decades reveals that stock return variability increases significantly in the aftermath of a crisis, even relative to the increase in stock return volatility for other firms belonging to the same industry and market capitalization class. In conjunction with this increase in total volatility, there is also an increase in stock market risk (beta) for multinational firms. Moreover, trade and service oriented industries appear to be particularly sensitive to these changing exchange rate conditions. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Muller, Aline; Verschoor, Willem F. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interpreting deviations from covered interest parity during the financial market turmoil of 2007-08</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baba, Naohiko; Packer, Frank
This paper investigates the spillover effects of money market turbulence in 2007-08 on the short-term covered interest parity (CIP) condition between the US dollar and the euro through the foreign exchange (FX) swap market. Sharp and persistent deviations from the CIP condition observed during the turmoil are found to be significantly associated with differences in the counterparty risk between European and US financial institutions. Furthermore, evidence is found that US dollar term funding auctions by the ECB, supported by US dollar swap lines with the Federal Reserve, alleviated the level of dislocations, as well as the instability, of the FX swap market. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baba, Naohiko; Packer, Frank</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global financial crisis, risk analysis and risk measurement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claessens, Stijn; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Claessens, Stijn; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do financial factors affect the capital-labour ratio? Evidence from UK firm-level data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spaliara, Marina-Eliza
This paper analyses how firms' capital-labour ratio is affected by cash flow, leverage, and collateral, and how this effect differs at firms more and less likely to face financing constraints using a rich UK firm-level data set. it is common in the literature to examine the impact of financial constraints on hiring and firing decisions separately from their impact on decisions related to investment in physical capital. We argue that as long as firms use both inputs in production and there is some substitutability between them, the two decisions need to be jointly analysed. When we differentiate across firms that are more or less financially constrained, we find that the former group exhibits higher sensitivities of the capital-labour ratio to firm-specific characteristics compared to the latter. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Spaliara, Marina-Eliza</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial dollarization: Short-run determinants in transition economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neanidis, Kyriakos C.; Savva, Christos S.
This paper examines the determinants of financial dollarization in transition economies from a short-run perspective. Using aggregate monthly data of deposit and loan dollarization we study the drivers of short-term fluctuations in dollarization and test their importance at different levels of dollarization. The results provide evidence that (a) the positive (negative) short-run effects of depreciation (monetary expansion) on deposit dollarization are exacerbated in high-dollarization countries; (b) short-run loan dollarization is mainly driven by banks matching of domestic loans and deposits, currency matching of assets and liabilities. international financial integration, and institutional quality; and (c) both types of short-run dollarization are affected by interest rate differentials and deviations from desired dollarization. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Neanidis, Kyriakos C.; Savva, Christos S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An evaluation of contingent immunization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diaz, Antonio; Gonzalez, Maria de la O.; Navarro, Eliseo; Skinner, Frank S.
This paper tests the effectiveness of contingent immunization, a stop loss strategy that allows portfolio managers to take advantage of their ability to forecast interest rate movements as long as their forecasts are successful, but switches to a pure immunization strategy should the stop loss limit be encountered. This study uses actual daily transactions in the Spanish Treasury market covering the period 1993-2003 and uses performance measures that accounts for skewness and kurtosis as well as mean variance. The main result of this paper is that contingent immunization provides excellent performance despite its simplicity. Crown Copyright (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Diaz, Antonio; Gonzalez, Maria de la O.; Navarro, Eliseo; Skinner, Frank S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does competition from new equity mitigate bank rent extraction? Insights from Japanese data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Xueping; Sercu, Piet; Yao, Jun
Previous research shows that bank information production mitigates asymmetric information problems. However, this literature has ignored the concern that firms with better growth prospects are more vulnerable to bank rent extraction. This paper points out that funding competition from new equity as an effective natural mechanism solves this important concern. Using Japanese data from 1983 to 1997, we show that the relationship between loan-to-debt ratio and growth, while starting significantly negative (consistent with holdup theory), turns significantly positive towards the high end of the growth spectrum. We confirm that high-growth firms raise more new equity than do low growth firms and use more equity relative to bonds in external finance. This is consistent with a generalized Myers-Majluf framework. These results suggest that for high growth firms, when competition from public debt lessens due to increased growth-based valuations, competition from new equity steps in to restrain bank rent extraction. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Xueping; Sercu, Piet; Yao, Jun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market reaction to cross-listings: Does the destination market matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roosenboom, Peter; van Dijk, Mathijs A.
This paper examines (i) whether market reactions to cross-listings differ across destination markets and (ii) to what extent the following explanations for value creation around cross-listings can account for differences in market reactions across cross-listings on various destination markets: overcoming market segmentation, increased market liquidity, improved information disclosure, and better investor protection ("bonding"). We analyze 526 cross-listings from 44 different countries on eight major stock exchanges and document significant announcement returns of 1.3% on average for cross-listings on US exchanges, 1.1% on London Stock Exchange, 0.6% on exchanges in continental Europe, and 0.5% (not significant) on Tokyo Stock Exchange. We find evidence consistent with improved disclosure and bonding creating value for cross-listings on US exchanges, while overcoming segmentation and bonding are associated with higher announcement returns on the London Stock Exchange. The evidence is mixed for continental European exchanges and for Tokyo. Our results highlight the role of the destination market in value creation around cross-listings. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roosenboom, Peter; van Dijk, Mathijs A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of net interest income in the Mexican banking system: An integrated model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maudos, Joaquin; Solis, Liliana
This paper analyzes net interest income in the Mexican banking system over the period 1993-2005. Taking as reference the seminal work by Ho and Saunders [Ho, T., Saunders, A., 1981. The determinants of banks interest margins: theory and empirical evidence. journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis XVI (4), 581-600] and subsequent extensions by other authors, our study models the net interest margin simultaneously including operating costs and diversification and specialization as determinants of the margin. The results referring to the Mexican case show that its high margins can be explained mainly by average operating costs and by market power. Although non-interest income has increased in recent years. its economic impact is low. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maudos, Joaquin; Solis, Liliana</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring performance in a dynamic world: Conditional mean-variance fundamentals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jha, Ranjini; Korkie, Bob; Turtle, Harry J.
We develop conditional alpha performance measures that are consistent with conditional mean-variance analysis and the magnitude and sign of the implied true conditional time-varying alphas. The sequence of conditional alphas and betas is estimable from surprisingly simple unconditional regressions. Other common performance measures are derivable from the conditional investment opportunity set based on its conditional asset return moments. Our bootstrap analysis of Morningstar mutual fund returns data demonstrates that the differences between existing conditional alpha measures and our proposed alpha are substantive for typical parameterizations. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jha, Ranjini; Korkie, Bob; Turtle, Harry J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The joint estimation of bank-level market power and efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos D.; Tsionas, Efthymios G.
The aim of this study is to provide a methodology for the joint estimation of efficiency and market power of individual banks. The proposed method utilizes the separate implications of the new empirical industrial organization and the stochastic frontier literatures and suggests identification using the local maximum likelihood (LML) technique. Through LML, estimation of market power of individual banks becomes feasible, while a number of restrictive theoretical and empirical assumptions are relaxed. The empirical analysis is carried out on the basis of EMU bank data. Market power estimates indicate fairly competitive conduct in general; however, heterogeneity in market power estimates is substantial across banks. The latter result suggests that the practice of some banks deviates from the average fairly competitive behavior, a finding that has important policy implications. Finally, efficiency and market power present a negative relationship, which is in line with the so-called "quiet life hypothesis". (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Delis, Manthos D.; Tsionas, Efthymios G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Operating performance changes associated with corporate mergers and the role of corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carline, Nicholas F.; Linn, Scott C.; Yadav, Pradeep K.
We find that corporate governance characteristics of acquiring firms (board ownership, board size, and block-holder control) have an economically and statistically significant impact on operating performance changes following mergers. We also show that dispersion of intra-board ownership stakes is an important but heretofore overlooked factor when judging the influence of ownership on the outcomes of corporate choices. Finally, we present evidence that suggests the market sometimes under- or overreacts to merger news when initially revaluing merger partners but corrects any miscalculation following the consummation of the merger. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carline, Nicholas F.; Linn, Scott C.; Yadav, Pradeep K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Propping and tunneling: Empirical evidence from Japanese keiretsu</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dow, Sandra; McGuire, Jean
We examine the response of horizontal and vertical keiretsu to the changing economic and regulatory climate in Japan from 1987 to 2001. We find evidence of profit tunneling of more weakly affiliated keiretsu firms during strong economic times. We observe propping of weakly aligned firms during recession. Many horizontal keiretsu firms strengthened their degree of adhesion to the horizontal keiretsu in response to increasingly tightened credit conditions post-1991. The motivation behind strengthened affiliation appears primarily linked to the goal of overcoming financial constraints by accessing the internal capital market of the business group. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dow, Sandra; McGuire, Jean</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership changes and access to external financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana; Stiglitz, Joseph
This paper examines access to external financing in the privatization context and provides new evidence on the effects of financing constraints on performance and investment. Ownership reforms increase firms' reliance on external financing. Empirically, performance and investment changes around ownership reforms are increasing in country-level measures of access to credit. The presence of a severe prior public financing constraint contributes to stronger investment growth after privatization. Privatized enterprises do not outperform publicly owned industries, all else given. Our analyses rely on new international sector- and firm-level data and correct for potential endogeneity of ownership changes. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana; Stiglitz, Joseph</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How much intraregional exchange rate variability could a currency union remove? The case of ASEAN+3</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qin, Duo; Tan, Tao
A multilateral currency union removes intraregional exchange rates but not the union rate. The pre-union intraregional exchange rate variability is thus latent; a two-step procedure is developed to measure this. The measured variables are used to model inflation and intraregional trade growth of individual union members. Counterfactual simulations of the union impact are carried out using the resulting models. Application to ASEAN+3 shows that the intraregional variability mainly consists of short-run exchange rate shocks, that the variability significantly affects inflation and intraregional trade of major ASEAN+3 members, and that a union would reduce inflation and promote trade regionwide. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Qin, Duo; Tan, Tao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entry mode choice of multinational banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lehner, Maria
When expanding abroad, a multinational bank faces a trade-off between accessing a foreign country via cross border lending or financial foreign direct investment, i.e. greenfield or acquisition entry. We analyze the entry mode choice of multinational banks and explicitly derive the entry mode pattern in the banking industry. Moreover, we show that in less developed banking markets, a trend towards cross border lending and acquisition entry exists. Greenfield entry prevails in more developed markets. Furthermore, we identify a tendency towards acquisition entry in smaller host countries and towards greenfield entry in larger host countries. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lehner, Maria</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markets and institutions in financial intermediation: National characteristics as determinants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Raj; Goodell, John W.
Given the importance of financial intermediation and the rise of globalization, there is little prior research on how national preferences for financial intermediation (markets versus institutions) are determined by cultural, legal, and other national characteristics. Using panel analysis for data on a recent 8-year period for 30 countries, this paper documents that national preferences for market financing increase with political stability. societal openness, economic inequality, and equity market concentration, and decreases with regulatory quality and ambiguity aversion. We confirm with robustness tests that our result for regulatory quality is independent of differences in national wealth and that our result for political stability is independent of both wealth and political legitimacy. These results should be of much interest to managers, scholars, regulators, and policy makers. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, Raj; Goodell, John W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial reforms and time-varying microstructures in emerging equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lagoarde-Segot, Thomas
This paper seeks to investigate the impact of financial reforms on time-varying microstructures in emerging equity markets. We develop annual indicators of informational efficiency, market volatility and transaction costs, using daily data for a panel of 28 emerging markets over the 1996-2007 period. We then analyze the impact of insider trading regulations, trading system automation and accounting standardization on microstructures through a set of panel regressions controlling for financial development and simultaneous reforms. Our results suggest that emerging market microstructures are affected by economic and political context, are strongly related to one another and depend on specific institutional reforms. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lagoarde-Segot, Thomas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the law of one price hold in international financial markets? Evidence from tick data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akram, Q. Farooq; Rime, Dagfinn; Sarno, Lucio
This paper investigates the validity of the law of one price (LOP) in international financial markets by examining the frequency, size and duration of inter-market price differentials for borrowing and lending services ('one-way arbitrage'). Using a unique data set for three major capital and foreign exchange markets that covers a period of more than seven months at tick frequency, we find that the LOP holds on average, but numerous economically significant violations of the LOP arise. The duration of these violations is high enough to make it worthwhile searching for one-way arbitrage opportunities in order to minimize borrowing costs and/or maximize earnings on given funds. We also document that such opportunities decline with the pace of the market and increase with market volatility. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akram, Q. Farooq; Rime, Dagfinn; Sarno, Lucio</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International financial integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucey, Brian M.
nan</description><author>Lucey, Brian M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management and initial public offerings: The case of the depository industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Brian; Carow, Kenneth A.; Perry, Tod
In a typical IPO, insiders are "net sellers" of IPO shares; however, in a demutualizing thrift, insiders are "net buyers" of IPO shares. Using a sample of mutual depository IPOs, we find evidence consistent with earnings management prior to the conversion of mutual thrifts. We find on average that mutuals report lower ROA and increased loan loss provisions and loan loss reserves in the period prior to the demutualization. Using a two-stage approach, we also find that the level of discretionary loan loss provisions and discretionary reserves are positively related to both the level of insider participation in the IPO and the first-day returns to investors. Our results are consistent with management Of Mutual thrifts benefiting at the conversion from reduced pre-IPO earnings and book equity resulting from earnings management. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, Brian; Carow, Kenneth A.; Perry, Tod</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competitive and value effects of bank privatization in developed countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Otchere, Isaac
A special issue of the journal of Banking and Finance (2005) devoted to the performance of privatized banks in middle- and low-income countries shows mixed results. In this paper, we present evidence that shows that privatized banks in developed countries have experienced significant improvements in operating performance. The improvement in performance remains significant after controlling for persistence in bank performance. A comparison of the performance of privatized banks in developed and developing Countries suggests that privatization has encouraged excessive risk taking among privatized banks in developing countries, with the consequence that those banks carry large non-performing assets than their counterparts in the developed countries. We also observe that consistent with the competitive effects hypothesis, investors view privatization announcements as foreshadowing bad news for rival banks. (c) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Otchere, Isaac</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing for strict stationarity in financial variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kapetanios, George
This paper considers the stationarity properties of a variety of financial variables using statistical tests for strict stationarity. We find that there has been a gradual shift in unconditional variances for the variables examined during the 90's and 2000's and that this is the main cause of the widespread rejection of the strict stationarity null hypothesis. This is a powerful result which suggests that the consideration of conditional mean and, especially, conditional variance models which assume stationarity is problematic for the period under examination. This casts serious doubts on the usefulness of models that assume strict stationarity and model conditional second moments, such as GARCH and stochastic volatility models. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kapetanios, George</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond risk premia and realized jump risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wright, Jonathan H.; Zhou, Hao
We find that augmenting a regression of excess bond returns on the term structure of forward rates with an estimate of the mean realized jump size almost doubles the R(2), of the forecasting regression. The return predictability from augmenting with the jump mean easily dominates that offered by augmenting with options-implied volatility and realized volatility from high-frequency data. In out-of-sample forecasting exercises, inclusion of the jump mean can reduce the root mean square prediction error by up to 40%. The incremental return predictability captured by the realized jump mean largely accounts for the counter-cyclical movements in bond risk premia. This result is consistent with the setting of an incomplete market in which the conditional distribution of excess bond returns is affected by a jump risk factor that does not lie in the span of the term structure of yields. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wright, Jonathan H.; Zhou, Hao</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A re-examination of China's share issue privatization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Guohua; Yue, Heng; Zhao, Longkai
Previous studies show that in contrast to evidence that share issue privatization (SIP) in most other countries have improved firm profitability, China's SIP of the 1990s had no such effect. We argue that the main reason for the failure of China's SIP is likely to have been the weak institutional environment in place at that time. We examine China's SIP in a more recent period in which the institutional environment was greatly improved. Using a matching sample method, we find that SIP firms continued to experience negative post-SIP profitability changes in our sample period. However, their performance decline was significantly less than that of their matched non-SIP SOEs. We also find that the introduction of the independent director rule helped to improve firm performance. Our results reconcile the findings of the SIP effect in China with international evidence and illustrate the importance of a developed capital market to ensuring the success of privatization schemes. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Guohua; Yue, Heng; Zhao, Longkai</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do financial conglomerates create or destroy value? Evidence for the EU</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Lelyveld, Iman; Knot, Klaas
There is an ongoing debate about whether firm focus creates or destroys shareholder value. Earlier literature has shown significant diversification discounts: firms that engage in multiple activities are valued lower. Various factors are important in determining the size of the discount, for example cross-subsidization and agency problems. The existing literature, however, generally focuses on non-financial firms or on banks combining investment and commercial banking. Our paper focuses specifically on the valuation of bank-insurance conglomerates. We find no universal diversification discount but significant variability. The discount is explained by the size (increasing), the familiarity with the conglomerate business model (decreasing) and the risk profile (decreasing). Our results are robust to the historical origin, the merger record and the age of the conglomerate, as well as peer group specification and outlier elimination. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>van Lelyveld, Iman; Knot, Klaas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash, investments and asset returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Dayong; Wang, Fang
We use an investment-based asset pricing model to examine the effect of firms' investments relative to cash holdings on stock returns, assuming holding cash lowers transaction costs. We find that mimicking portfolios based on investments relative to non-cash capital and based on investments relative to cash capital are priced for various testing portfolios. On average, momentum stocks and growth stocks are more sensitive to the factor constructed using investment relative to cash. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Dayong; Wang, Fang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption smoothing channels in open economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asdrubali, Pierfederico; Kim, Soyoung
Many intertemporal open economy macro models imply a theory of consumption smoothing channels; thus we build an empirical model to analyze the intertemporal smoothing role of saving components (fixed investments, inventories and trade balance) through the use of VAR impulse responses to different types of shocks. We find that for the OECD countries the bulk of intertemporal smoothing has been carried out domestically, via gross fixed investments and inventories, but the trade balance has also played a relevant - albeit volatile - smoothing role. We also characterize the dynamic behavior of each component: the trade balance and inventories are mostly used as short-run smoothing tools while fixed investment provides more and more smoothing over time. We can also address some empirical puzzles, such as the "excess sensitivity of investment" anomaly (Glick, R., Rogoff, K., 1995. Global versus country-specific productivity shocks and the current account. journal of Monetary Economics, 35, 159-192) and the "saving-investment correlation puzzle" (Feldstein, M., Horioka, C., 1980. Domestic saving and international capital flows. Economic journal, 90, 314-329). (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asdrubali, Pierfederico; Kim, Soyoung</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition in banking: A disequilibrium approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goddard, John; Wilson, John O. S.
The Rosse-Panzar revenue test for competitive conditions in banking is based on observation of the impact on bank revenue of variation in factor input prices. We identify the implications for the H-statistic of misspecification bias in the revenue equation, arising when adjustment towards market equilibrium is partial and not instantaneous. In simulations, fixed effects estimation produces a measured H-statistic that is severely biased towards zero. Empirical results for the banking sectors of the Group of Seven (G7) countries corroborate our principal finding, that a dynamic formulation of the revenue equation is required for accurate identification of the H-statistic. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goddard, John; Wilson, John O. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intrinsic bubbles and Granger causality in the S&amp;P 500: Evidence from long-term data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, An-Sing; Cheng, Lee-Young; Cheng, Kuang-Fu
Results of research on whether changes in earnings can predict future stock returns are inconclusive. We add to this debate by using long-term data from 1871 to 2004 to examine the predictive power of changes in earnings in periods of intrinsic bubbles and in periods absent intrinsic bubbles. Our results show that accounting for bubbles is important in whether changes in earnings can predict future stock returns. In periods of no bubble, we find that changes in earnings Granger-cause future returns, whereas in periods of bubble, this Granger causality from changes in earnings to future returns cannot be found. We conclude that changes in earnings can predict future stock returns, but only in periods absent bubbles. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, An-Sing; Cheng, Lee-Young; Cheng, Kuang-Fu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of mergers on credit union performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauer, Keldon J.; Miles, Linda L.; Nishikawa, Takeshi
The motivation for mergers in the credit union industry differs from the commercial bank industry due to the lack of residual claimants to benefit from wealth gains. In the cooperative ownership environment of credit unions, the owners/members gain utility via the rates offered for loans and deposits. Credit union regulators also gain utility when mergers remove risky credit unions from the industry. We measure these utility gains using the event study method of Bauer [Bauer, K., 2008. Detecting abnormal credit union performance. Journal of Banking and Finance 32, 573-586] employing quadrant tests based on a multivariate test of equality of centroids. We find gains to the owners/members of the target credit union and to the regulators but not to the acquiring firm. We posit that the acquiring credit unions may encounter regulatory pressure to merge. In addition, the owners/members of the acquiring firm may avoid potential disutility in the cooperative insurance environment were the target firm allowed to fail. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bauer, Keldon J.; Miles, Linda L.; Nishikawa, Takeshi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Announcements and the effectiveness of monetary policy: A view from the</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kobayashi, Teruyoshi
Until 1994, the US prime rate was said to be sticky because of its irresponsiveness to short-term interest rates. After the Fed started the practice of announcing its intended funds rate in 1994, however. the prime rate has come to react immediately to shifts in the target rate. This paper attempts to explain how the Fed's policy announcements changed the behavior of the prime rate by using a simple menu cost model. It shows that an increase in the expected duration of funds rate targets was essential to the improvement in the target rate pass-through. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kobayashi, Teruyoshi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial instruments with sports betting components: Marketing gimmick or a domain for behavioral finance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Wolfgang; Hauten, Guido; Kreuz, Claudia
We examine theoretically and experimentally a certain class of new financial instruments which are designed as lotteries on the outcome of prominent sports events like the Soccer World Cup 2006. From a theoretical point of view, sports betting products may be superior to a fixed rate investment because of heterogeneous expectations, risk-loving behavior of investors or additional non-monetary utility components. In comparison to the direct placement of bets at bookmakers', sports betting products may be preferable in cases of hedonic framing. Our experimental section, however, reveals the limited practical relevance of these theoretical arguments for "average" decision makers. Despite this, financial instruments with sports betting components offer a certain profit potential due to the diversity of preferences across individuals. Summarizing, the issuance of sports betting products may actually be mainly driven by marketing aspects, nevertheless sports betting products may be considered to be 'viable" niche products with low cost of capital for banks. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Breuer, Wolfgang; Hauten, Guido; Kreuz, Claudia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aligning debt and equity claimant interests: Evidence from dual claim investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Xijia
This study investigates how investors that own both equity and debt in the same firm affect other shareholders in the firm. it documents that dual claim investors are quite prevalent among the industrial firms listed in the Russell 3000, with over 20% of them having a bank holding company that owns both debt and equity in the firm. The results imply that shareholders are substantially impacted by the presence of dual claim investors in firms, suggesting that relatively small ownership stakes by dual claim banks are associated with greater conflicts of interest among shareholders and debt holders; while relatively large bank equity stakes may benefit Outside shareholders when aligned with loan by dual claim banks because they improve bank monitoring incentives and reduce the agency cost of debt. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xu, Xijia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How loan portfolio diversification affects risk, efficiency and capitalization: A managerial behavior model for Austrian banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rossi, Stefania P. S.; Schwaiger, Markus S.; Winkler, Gerhard
The aim of this paper is to analyze how diversification of banks across size and industry affects risk, cost and profit efficiency, and bank capitalization for large Austrian commercial banks over the years 1997-2003. Employing a unique dataset, provided by the Austrian Central Bank, we test for several different types of managerial hypotheses, formalized according to a modified version of the Berger and DeYoung model [Berger, A.N, DeYoung, R., 1997. Problem loans and cost efficiency in commercial banks. journal of Banking and Finance 21, 849-870]. We find that, although diversification negatively affects cost efficiency, it increases profit efficiency and reduces banks' realized risk. Finally, diversification seems to have a positive impact on banks' capitalization. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rossi, Stefania P. S.; Schwaiger, Markus S.; Winkler, Gerhard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm performance and mutual fund voting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ng, Lilian; Wang, Qinghai; Zaiats, Nataliya
We employ a new comprehensive proxy voting records database to investigate whether mutual funds consider prior firm performance when they vote on a diverse range of management- and shareholder-sponsored proposals relating to governance, compensation, and director election. We argue that prior firm performance plays a role in the monitoring effort Of Mutual funds as they fulfill their fiduciary duties. Results show that voting is related to prior firm performance for selected management and shareholder proposals and that it is consistent with Institutional Shareholder Set-vices' recommendations. Mutual funds support management (shareholder) proposals less (more) when prior firm performance has been weak. Furthermore, even when mutual funds deviate from their fund family's voting policies, they attach importance to prior firm performance, and their voting is, to a certain degree, affected by business ties. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ng, Lilian; Wang, Qinghai; Zaiats, Nataliya</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Segmentation and time-of-day patterns in foreign exchange markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ranaldo, Angelo
This paper sheds light on a puzzling pattern in spot foreign exchange markets: domestic currencies appreciate (depreciate) systematically during foreign (domestic) working hours. This phenomenon spans many years and several exchange rates, and overrides calendar effects. We argue that it is mainly due to liquidity and inventory patterns that emerge from the combination of two factors: domestic agents tend to be net buyers of foreign currency and to trade mostly in their country's working hours. The prevalence of domestic (foreign) traders demanding the counterpart currency during domestic (foreign) working hours implies sell-price (buy-price) pressure on the domestic currency during domestic (foreign) working hours. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ranaldo, Angelo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank fragility, "money under the mattress", and long-run growth: US evidence from the "perfect" Panic of 1893</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ramirez, Carlos D.
This paper examines how the US financial crisis of 1893 affected state output growth between 1900 and 1930. The results indicate that a 1% increase in bank instability reduced output growth by 2-5%. A comparison of Nebraska, which had one of the highest bank failure rates, with West Virginia, which did not experience a single bank failure, reveals that disintermediation affected growth through a portfolio change among savers: people simply stopped trusting banks. Time series evidence from newspapers indicates that articles containing the words "money hidden" significantly increase after banking crises, then slowly die out. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ramirez, Carlos D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The capitalization of taxes in bond prices: Evidence from the market for Government of Canada bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Landon, Stuart
This paper provides estimates of the extent to which corporate and personal income taxes are capitalized in bond prices. The methodology yields estimates of the degree of tax capitalization, rather than an implied tax rate. This makes it straightforward to identify the marginal investor and test for changes in tax capitalization. The empirical approach also makes it unnecessary to jointly estimate the degree of tax capitalization and the entire yield curve. Corporate taxes are found to have been fully capitalized in pre-tax Government of Canada bond yields during the period 1986-1993. Since 1994, taxes have not been capitalized in yields. These results are consistent with the existence of a marginal investor, but the identity of the marginal investor changed from a financial sector firm to a non-taxed entity in the early 1990s. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Landon, Stuart</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are interest rate options important for the assessment of interest rate risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Caio; Vicente, Jose
Fixed income options contain substantial information on the price of interest rate volatility risk. In this paper, we ask if those options will also provide information related to other moments of the objective distribution of interest rates. Based on dynamic term structure models within the class of affine models, we find that interest rate options are useful for the identification of interest rate quantiles. Two three-factor models are adopted and their adequacy to estimate Value at Risk of zero-coupon bonds is tested. We find significant difference on the quantitative assessment of risk when options are (or not) included in the estimation process of each of these dynamic models. Statistical backtests indicate that bond estimated risk is clearly more adequate when options are adopted, although not yet completely satisfactory. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Almeida, Caio; Vicente, Jose</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Varying risk premia in international bond markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kessler, Stephan; Scherer, Bernd
Cochrane and Piazzesi [Cochrane, J.H., Piazzesi, M., 2005. Bond risk premia. American Economic Review 95, 138-160] use forward rates to forecast future bond returns. We extend their approach by applying their model to international bond markets. Our results indicate that the unrestricted Cochrane and Piazzesi (2005) model has a reasonable forecasting power for future bond returns. The restricted model, however, does not perform as well on an international level, Furthermore, we cannot confirm the systematic tent shape of the estimated parameters found by Cochrane and Piazzesi (2005). The forecasting models are used to implement various trading strategies. These strategies exhibit high information ratios when implemented in individual countries or on an international level and outperform alternative approaches. We introduce an alternative specification to forecast future bond returns and achieve superior risk-adjusted returns in our trading strategy. Bayesian model averaging is used to enhance the performance of the proposed trading strategy. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kessler, Stephan; Scherer, Bernd</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The wandering weekday effect in major stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doyle, John R.; Chen, Catherine Huirong
This paper reports a wandering weekday effect: the pattern of day seasonality in stock market returns is not fixed, as assumed in the Monday or weekend effects, but changes over time. Analysing daily closing prices in eleven major stock markets during 1993-2007, our results show that the wandering weekday is not conditional on average returns in the previous week (the "twist" in the Monday effect). Nor does it diminish through the period of analysis. The results have important implications for market efficiency, and help to reconcile mixed findings in previous studies, including the reported disappearance of the weekday effect in recent years. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doyle, John R.; Chen, Catherine Huirong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The long-term performance of acquiring firms: A re-examination of an anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dutta, Shantanu; Jog, Vijay
In this paper, we investigate the long-term stock return performance of Canadian acquiring firms in the post-event period by using 1300 M&amp;A events in the 1993-2002 period. We use both event-time and calendar-time approaches and conduct robustness tests for benchmarks, methodological choices, statistical techniques and other related factors such as payment methods. We also assess the role of governance variables. Contrary to stylized facts reported in US studies, neither do we find negative abnormal long-term abnormal stock market returns once we account for methodological discrepancies nor do we find negative long-term operating performance in the post-acquisition periods for the acquirer following an acquisition event. We also find that the Canadian market reacts positively to acquisition announcements but corrects for this reaction within a short period of time. Overall we find that Canadian acquisitions do not show value destruction or overpayment. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dutta, Shantanu; Jog, Vijay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The identification of technology regimes in banking: Implications for the market power-fragility nexus</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koetter, Michael; Poghosyan, Tigran
Neglecting the existence of different technologies in banking can contaminate efficiency, market power, and other performance measures. By simultaneously estimating (i) technology regimes conditional on exogenous factors, (ii) efficiency conditional on risk management, and (iii) Lerner indices of German banks, we identify three distinct technology regimes: Public &amp; Retail, Small &amp; Specialized, and Universal &amp; Relationship. System estimation at the regional level reveals that greater bank market power increases bank profitability but also fosters corporate defaults. Corporate defaults, in turn, lead to higher probabilities of bank distress, which supports the market power-fragility hypothesis. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koetter, Michael; Poghosyan, Tigran</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does concurrent management of mutual and hedge funds create conflicts of interest?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Li-Wen; Chen, Fan
This paper shows that conflicts of interest may exist in cases where a hedge fund manager starts a mutual fund but not in the opposite case. We compare performance, asset flows, and risk incentives to establish several key differences between these two scenarios: First, prior to concurrent management, hedge fund managers experience worse performance while mutual fund managers achieve better performance relative to their full-time peers. Second, hedge fund managers who choose concurrent management are disproportionately the ones with less experience. Their hedge funds tend to suffer a decline in performance after the event. By contrast, mutual fund managers who choose concurrent management tend to outperform their full-time peers, Based on our findings, we make important recommendations for policy makers and companies. The relevance of our recommendations extends beyond the small share of companies presently engaged in concurrent management. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Li-Wen; Chen, Fan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of regulation on industry structure and trade generation in the US securities industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Hyung Suk; Clarke, Jonathan; Ferris, Stephen P.; Jayaraman, Narayanan
This study investigates the effects of Regulation FD and the Global Research Analyst Settlement on market share within the US securities industry as well as the determinants of market share during 1996-2004. We find that these regulations did not cause top brokers to lose market share in spite of their reduction of information asymmetries existing within the brokerage industry. They did, however, significantly reduce the quarterly variability in market share changes. We find that Regulation FD and the Global Research Analyst Settlement reduce the importance of an all-star analyst, issuer affiliation, and analyst optimism for gaining brokerage market share. We further discover that the Global Research Analyst Settlement increases the importance of coverage as a market share determinant while reducing the value of analyst experience for non-top brokers. We find that our results remain robust even when we limit our analysis to a set of pure brokerage firms. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choi, Hyung Suk; Clarke, Jonathan; Ferris, Stephen P.; Jayaraman, Narayanan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regional growth and finance in Europe: Is there a quality effect of bank efficiency?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, Iftekhar; Koetter, Michael; Wedow, Michael
In this study, we test whether regional growth in 11 European countries depends on financial development and suggest the use of cost- and profit-efficiency estimates as quality measures of financial institutions. Contrary to the usual quantitative proxies of financial development, the quality of financial institutions is measured in this study as the relative ability of banks to intermediate funds. An improvement in bank efficiency spurs five times more regional growth then an identical increase in credit does. More credit provided by efficient banks exerts an independent growth effect in addition to direct quantity and quality channel effects. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasan, Iftekhar; Koetter, Michael; Wedow, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demutualization: Determinants and consequences of the mutual holding company choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carow, Kenneth A.; Cox, Steven R.; Roden, Dianne M.
We investigate the determinants and consequences of the mutual holding company (MHC) structure that allows mutual thrifts to issue stock to outside shareholders while maintaining the mutual form. Capital constrained firms with greater profit opportunities are more likely to choose a full demutualization; demonstrating that the MHC choice can be used to control for over- and under-investment costs. During periods of greater regulatory constraints, MHC firms have lower offer-day returns than full demutualizations. MHC firms are also less likely to be acquired, as the MHC structure provides protection from the market for corporate control. Demonstrating a clear preference by minority shareholders for the elimination of the MHC structure, the announcement of a second-stage conversion generates a 12% return. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carow, Kenneth A.; Cox, Steven R.; Roden, Dianne M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did the repeated debt ceiling controversies embed default risk in US Treasury securities?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Pu; Shao, Yingying; Yeager, Timothy J.
We examine whether the financial market charged a default risk premium to US Treasury securities when the US Federal government repeatedly reached the legally binding debt limits between 2002 and 2006. We show that for the first two of the four recurrences since the first episode in 1996, the financial market charged a small default risk premium to the Treasury securities. However, we find no significant evidence of a pricing effect in the last two recurrences. The results suggest that the financial market gradually perceived the budget standoffs as the boy who cried wolf. (c) 2009 Elsevier FIN. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Pu; Shao, Yingying; Yeager, Timothy J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The announcement impact of seasoned equity offerings on bondholder wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elliott, William B.; Prevost, Andrew K.; Rao, Ramesh P.
Previous studies document a negative return to equity on the announcement of an SEO. However, the effects of SEO announcements on bonds have received little attention. We find that bondholders experience a significant positive return on the announcement of an SEO and this effect is more pronounced for bonds with lower ratings. We examine alternate explanations for bond market reactions to SEO announcements including the leverage risk reduction, wealth transfer, and information signaling hypotheses. Overall, our results are most consistent with the leverage risk reduction hypothesis. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elliott, William B.; Prevost, Andrew K.; Rao, Ramesh P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock price reaction following large one-day price changes: UK evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mazouz, Khelifa; Joseph, Nathan L.; Joulmer, Joulmer
We examine the short-term price reaction of 424 UK stocks to large one-clay price changes. Using the GJR-GARCH(1, 1), we find no statistical difference amongst the cumulative abnormal returns (CARs) of the Single Index, the Fama-French and the Carhart-Fama-French models. Shocks &gt;= 5% are followed by a significant one-day CAR of 1% for all the models. Whilst shocks &lt;=-5% are followed by a significant one-day CAR of -0.43% for the Single Index, the CARs are around -0.34% for the other two models. Positive shocks of all sizes and negative shocks &lt;=-5% are followed by return continuations, whilst the market is efficient following larger negative shocks. The price reaction to shocks is unaffected when we estimate the CARs using the conditional covariances of the pricing variables. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mazouz, Khelifa; Joseph, Nathan L.; Joulmer, Joulmer</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The safety first expected utility model: Experimental evidence and economic implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Haim; Levy, Moshe
Roy's [Roy, A., 1952. Safety first and the holding of assets. Econometrica 20 (3), 431-449] safety first criterion advocates the minimization of the probability of outcomes below a certain "disaster" level. This paper examines safety first theoretically and experimentally. We find that safety first plays a crucial role in decision-making, inducing choices that cannot be explained by, and even contradict, risk-aversion, Prospect Theory, and loss-aversion in general. Yet, safety first alone cannot explain individual choice. Therefore, we propose an expected utility - safety first (EU-SF) model where decisions are made based on a weighted average of the safety first criterion and standard expected utility maximization. We experimentally estimate these relative weights, and discuss their economic implications. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Levy, Haim; Levy, Moshe</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endless leverage certificates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rossetto, Silvia; van Bommel, Jos
An endless leverage certificate (ELC) is a novel retail structured product that gives its holder the right to claim the difference between the value of an underlying security and an interest accruing financing level. An ELC ceases to exist if the underlying breaches a contractual knockout level, if the holder exercises, or if she/he sells it back to the issuer. We use Monte Carlo analysis to value ELCs and find that due to limited liability, a typical ELC written on a typical DAX stock can be worth 0.3% more than its intrinsic value (the difference between the value of the underlying and the financing level). Empirically, we find that in January 2007, the 5129 ELCs issued on the thirty DAX stocks traded at an average premium of 0.67% over the intrinsic Value, and that the median bid-ask spread, expressed as a percentage of the underlying, was 0.18%. For covered warrants and options this spread measure was almost twice as high. Finally, we find that upon knockout, investors received on average 3.2% less than the theoretical knockout value, which is consistent with discontinuous trading of the underyling. Overall, our findings suggest that ELCs complete the market for leverage seeking retail investors. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rossetto, Silvia; van Bommel, Jos</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dealer attention, the speed of quote adjustment to information, and net dealer revenue</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boulatov, Alex; Hatch, Brian C.; Johnson, Shane A.; Lei, Adam Y. C.
Using trade and quote data from the NYSE, we examine the relation between dealer attention, dealer revenue, and the probability of informed trade. We find that dealer revenue net of losses to better-informed traders in NYSE stocks is positively related to the speed at which quotes adjust to full information levels. The speed of quote adjustment is faster for stocks with greater dealer attention, as measured by a stock's relative prominence at its post and panel location on the NYSE floor. The level of dealer attention in turn is positively related to a stock's probability of information-based trading. The results are consistent with a theoretical model we derive in which dealers trade multiple securities and must optimally allocate their limited attention to monitoring order flow to minimize losses to better-informed traders. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boulatov, Alex; Hatch, Brian C.; Johnson, Shane A.; Lei, Adam Y. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank credit risk and structural credit models: Agency and information asymmetry perspectives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liao, Hsien-Hsing; Chen, Tsung-Kang; Lu, Chia-Wu
This work investigates the effects of agency and information asymmetry issues embedded in structural form credit models on bank credit risk evaluation, using American bank data from 2001 to 2005. Findings show that both the agency problem and information asymmetry significantly cause deviations in the credit risk evaluation of structural form models from agency ratings. Five independent factors explain a deviation of 42.6-78.3% and should be incorporated into future credit risk modeling. Additionally, both the effects of information asymmetry and debt-equity agency positively relate to the deviation while that of management-equity agency relates to it negatively. (c) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liao, Hsien-Hsing; Chen, Tsung-Kang; Lu, Chia-Wu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Compensation committee governance quality, chief executive officer stock option grants, and future firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Jerry; Cahan, Steven F.; Emanuel, David
This paper examines whether the relationship between future firm performance and chief executive officer (CEO) stock option grants is affected by the quality of the compensation committee. Compensation committee quality is measured using six committee characteristics - the proportion of directors appointed during the tenure of the incumbent CEO, the proportion of directors with at least ten years' board service, the proportion of directors who are CEOs at other companies, the aggregate shareholding of directors on the compensation committee, the proportion of directors with three or more additional board seats, and compensation committee size. We find I:hat future firm performance is more positively associated with stock option grants as compensation committee quality increases. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Jerry; Cahan, Steven F.; Emanuel, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the integrability of money-demand functions by the Sidrauski and the shopping-time models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cysne, Rubens Penha; Turchick, David
This paper investigates which properties money-demand functions must satisfy so that they are consistent with Lucas's [Lucas Jr., R.E., 2000. Inflation and welfare. Econometrica 68, 247-274] versions of the Sidrauski and the shopping-time models. We conclude that shopping-time-integrable money-demand functions are necessarily also Sidrauski-integrable, but that the converse is not necessarily true, unless a boundedness assumption on the nominal interest rate is made. Both the log-log with an interest-rate elasticity greater than or equal to one and the semi-log money demands may serve as counterexamples. All the models and results are also extended to the case in which there are several assets in the economy performing monetary functions. (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cysne, Rubens Penha; Turchick, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Catering effects in corporate dividend policy: The international evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferris, Stephen P.; Jayaraman, Narayanan; Sabherwal, Sanjiv
This study tests for the international presence of dividend catering across a sample of twenty-three countries. We find evidence of catering among firms incorporated in common law countries but not for those in civil law nations. Catering persists even after controlling for the effect of the firm's lifecycle. We conclude that when the legal regime and its accompanying set of investor protections permit, investors force dividends from managers, but they also attempt to extract such payouts indirectly by placing a high value on dividend paying firms. The relative failure of civil law firms to cater might be explained by idiosyncratic behaviors in the consumption of the private benefits of control or a lack of interest in responding to temporary market misevaluations of their equity. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferris, Stephen P.; Jayaraman, Narayanan; Sabherwal, Sanjiv</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crises, contagion and cross-listings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chandar, Nandini; Patro, Dilip K.; Yezegel, Ari
We investigate whether cross-listing shares in the form of depositary receipts in overseas markets benefits investors in emerging market countries during periods of local financial crisis from 1994 to 2002. We regress cumulative abnormal returns for three windows surrounding the crisis events oil the cross-listing status while controlling for cross-sectional differences in firm age, trading Volume, foreign exposure. disclosure quality and corporate governance. Further, we examine cross-listing effects ill Countries popularly thought to experience contagious effects of these crises. We find that cross-listed firms react significantly less negatively than non-cross-listed firms, particularly in the aftermath of the crisis. The results oil contagious cross-listing effects are however mixed. Our findings are consistent with predictions based on theories of market segmentation as well as differential disclosure/governance between developed and emerging markets. We do not find evidence that foreign investors "panic" during a Currency crisis. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chandar, Nandini; Patro, Dilip K.; Yezegel, Ari</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of default and call risk on bond duration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xie, Yan Alice; Liu, Sheen; Wu, Chunchi; Anderson, Bing
This paper examines the effects of default risk, call risk, and their interactions on bond duration. We find that call risk decreases durations of default-free bonds, while default risk alone generally decreases durations for risky bonds with only a few exceptions. The joint effect of default and call risk always results in shorter durations for corporate bonds. Controlling for the effect of default risk, call risk has a negative effect on duration, which diminishes as bond ratings decline. Finally, the effect of call risk on duration depends on bond characteristics. Empirical evidence shows that the effect of call risk is smaller for discount bonds and for deep-discount fallen angels. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xie, Yan Alice; Liu, Sheen; Wu, Chunchi; Anderson, Bing</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset allocation and location over the life cycle with investment-linked survival-contingent payouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horneff, Wolfram J.; Maurer, Raimond H.; Mitchell, Olivia S.; Stamos, Michael Z.
This paper shows how survival-contingent investment-linked payouts can enhance investor wellbeing in the context of a portfolio choice model which integrates uninsurable labor income and asymmetric mortality expectations. In exchange for illiquidity, these products provide the consumer with access to mutual-fund style portfolio choice, as well as the survival credit generated from pooling mortality risk. Our model generates optimal asset location patterns indicating how much to hold in liquid versus illiquid survival-contingent payouts over the lifetime, and also asset allocation paths, showing how to invest in stocks versus bonds. We show that the investor who moves her money out of liquid saving into survival-contingent assets gradually from middle age to retirement and beyond, will enhance her welfare by as much as 50%. The results are robust to the introduction of uninsurable consumption shocks in housing expenses, income flows during the worklife and retirement, sudden changes in health status, and medical expenses. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Horneff, Wolfram J.; Maurer, Raimond H.; Mitchell, Olivia S.; Stamos, Michael Z.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of banking sector reform in a transition economy: Evidence from Kyrgyzstan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Martin; Maurer, Maria Rueda; Pak, Tamara; Tynaev, Nurlanbek
We examine the impact of financial sector reform on interest Fate levels and spreads using Kyrgyz bank-level data from 1998 to 2005. We find that, in addition to macroeconomic stabilization, structural reforms to the banking sector significantly contributed to lower interest rates. In particular, our results suggest that foreign bank entry and regulatory efforts to increase average bank size were important in reducing deposit rates. In contrast, we find little evidence that banking sector reform or macroeconomic stabilization has impacted interest Fate Spreads. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Martin; Maurer, Maria Rueda; Pak, Tamara; Tynaev, Nurlanbek</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of coskewness in mutual fund performance evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moreno, David; Rodriguez, Rosa
Recent asset pricing studies demonstrate the relevance of incorporating coskewness in asset pricing models, and illustrate how this component helps to explain the time variation of ex-ante market risk premiums. This paper analyzes the role of coskewness in mutual fund performance evaluation and finds evidence that adding a coskewness factor is economically and statistically significant. It documents that coskewness is sometimes managed and shows persistence of the coskewness policy over time. One of the most striking results is that many negative (positive) alpha funds, measured relative to the CAPM risk adjustments, would be reclassified as positive (negative) alpha funds using a model with coskewness. Therefore, performance ranking based on risk-adjusted returns without considering coskewness could generate an erroneous classification. Moreover, some fund characteristics, such as turnover ratio or category, are related to the likelihood of managing coskewness. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moreno, David; Rodriguez, Rosa</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overvaluation and earnings management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chi, Jianxin; Gupta, Manu
Consistent with Jensen's [Jensen, M., 2005. Agency costs of overvalued equity. Financial Management 34, 5-19] agency-costs-of-overvalued-equity prediction, we find that overvaluation is statistically and economically related to subsequent income-increasing earnings management. This relation is robust to a series of tests that address potential endogeneity concerns, including omitted variable bias and reverse causality. The agency costs of overvalued equity are substantial. Overvaluation-induced income-increasing earnings management is negatively related to future abnormal stock returns and operating performance, and this negative relation becomes more pronounced as prior overvaluation intensifies. Among the most overvalued firms, those with high discretionary accruals underperform those with low discretionary accruals during the following year by 11.88% as measured by the three-factor alphas, and by 12.87% points as measured by industry-adjusted unmanaged EBITDA-to-assets ratio. (C) 2009 Elsevier B,V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chi, Jianxin; Gupta, Manu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, sophistication, and foreign versus domestic investors' performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Li-Wen; Johnson, Shane A.; Lin, Ji-Chai; Liu, Yu-Jane
Using an intraday transaction dataset with trader identity, we study foreign and domestic investors' trading activities and investment performance ahead of open-ending events of Taiwanese closed-end funds. Simply buying the funds at a discount and holding until open-ending generates large abnormal returns. All information required to execute this strategy is made public, so the events set up natural experiments to examine how investors trade, holding constant access to information. Foreign investors are net buyers ahead of the open-endings, more than doubling their positions and earning large abnormal returns. Domestic investors are net sellers while the discounts are still large, and forego large abnormal returns. The results suggest that investor sophistication in interpreting the same information is potentially an important determinant of investment performance differences across foreign and domestic investors. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Li-Wen; Johnson, Shane A.; Lin, Ji-Chai; Liu, Yu-Jane</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric effects of the business cycle on bank credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marcucci, Juri; Quagliariello, Mario
Prior empirical research on the relation between credit risk and the business cycle has failed to properly investigate the presence of asymmetric effects. To fill this gap, we examine this relation both at the aggregate and the bank level exploiting a unique dataset on Italian banks' borrowers' default rates. We employ threshold regression models that allow to endogenously establish different regimes identified by the thresholds over/below which credit risk is more/less cyclical. We find that not only are the effects of the business cycle on credit risk more pronounced during downturns but cyclicality is also higher for those banks with riskier portfolios. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marcucci, Juri; Quagliariello, Mario</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity market valuation of human capital and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pantzalis, Christos; Park, Jung Chul
We investigate whether and how well firms' stock market valuations reflect their employees' collective skills and effectiveness relative to that of their industry peers and competitors. We devise a relative stock market valuation measure of human capital intangibles (EVHC) and find that portfolios of low EVHC firms systematically outperform portfolios of high EVHC firms by an average 1.34% per month. However, this is primarily a small firms effect, because for large firms the excess returns of the arbitrage portfolio that is long on the low EVHC stocks and short on the high EVHC stocks is zero. Our results suggest that reliance on human capital intangibles may proxy for risk not fully accounted for by conventional asset pricing models, or alternatively. that the market cannot correctly price human capital intangibles for small size firms. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pantzalis, Christos; Park, Jung Chul</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The bright and dark side of staging: Investment performance and the varying motivations of private equity firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krohmer, Philipp; Lauterbach, Rainer; Calanog, Victor
Previous papers that examined investment decisions by private equity funds are divided on whether staging has a positive or negative effect on returns. We believe these opposing views can be reconciled by studying when staging is used during the life of the investment relationship: We find that staging has a positive effect on investment returns in the beginning of the investment relationship, consistent with the notion that staging helps mitigate information asymmetry. However, staging appears to be negatively associated with returns when used prior to the exit decision. Our unique dataset allows LIS to measure these intertemporal effects precisely. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Krohmer, Philipp; Lauterbach, Rainer; Calanog, Victor</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluation of linear asset pricing models by implied portfolio performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balvers, Ronald J.; Huang, Dayong
We present a theoretical perspective that motivates the use of the Generalized Least Squares R-Square, prominently advocated by Lewellen et al. [Lewellen, J., Nagel, S., Shanken, J., forthcoming. A skeptical appraisal of asset-pricing tests. Journal of Financial Economics], as an evaluation measure for multivariate linear asset pricing models. Adapting results from Shanken [Shanken, J., 1985. Multivariate tests of the zero-beta CAPM. journal of Financial Economics 14, 327-348] and Kandel and Stambaugh [Kandel, S., Stambaugh, R,F., 1995. Portfolio inefficiency and the cross-section of expected returns. journal of Finance 50, 157-184], we provide various interpretations and a graphical account in mean-variance space of this measure, facilitating a better understanding of its properties. We furthermore relate it to another leading evaluation metric, the HJ-distance of Hansen and Jagannathan [Hansen, L.P.Jagannathan, R., 1997. Assessing specification errors in stochastic discount factor models. journal of Finance 52, 557-590]. Additionally, we present a comparison between these evaluation measures using mean-variance mathematics in risk-return space, and we provide a simple formula for calculating both model evaluation measures that involves only the parameters of the mean-variance asset and factor frontiers. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balvers, Ronald J.; Huang, Dayong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A momentum trading strategy based on the low frequency component of the exchange rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, Richard D. F.; Yilmaz, Fatih
In this paper, we develop a momentum trading strategy based on the low frequency trend component of the spot exchange rate. Using kernel regression and the high-pass filter of Hodrick and Prescott [Hodrick, R., Prescott, E., 1997. Post-war US business cycles: An empirical investigation. Journal of Money, Credit and Banking 29, 1-16], we recover the non-linear trend in the monthly exchange rate and use short-term momentum in this to generate buy and sell signals. The low frequency momentum trading strategy offers greater directional accuracy, higher returns and Sharpe ratios, lower maximum drawdown and less frequent trading than traditional moving average rules. Moreover, unlike traditional moving average rules, the performance of the low frequency momentum trading strategy is relatively robust across different time periods. The low frequency momentum trading strategy is also robust to the choice of smoothing parameter (in the case of the HP filter) and the distribution and bandwidth parameter (in the case of kernel regression) over a wide range of values. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harris, Richard D. F.; Yilmaz, Fatih</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market crashes, firm characteristics, and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Jia; Meric, Gulser; Liu, Zugang; Meric, Ilhan
A number of studies have investigated the causes and effects of stock market crashes. These Studies mainly focus on the factors leading to a crash and on the volatility and co-movements of stock market indexes during and after the crash. However, how a stock market crash affects individual stocks and if stocks with different financial characteristics are affected differently in a stock market crash is an issue that has not received sufficient attention. In this paper, we study this issue by using data for eight major stock market crashes that have taken place during the December 31, 1962-December 31, 2007 period with a large sample of US firms. We use the event-study methodology and multivariate regression analysis to Study the determinants of stock returns in stock market crashes. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Jia; Meric, Gulser; Liu, Zugang; Meric, Ilhan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Financial Market in China: Issues Related to the Asia Pacific Region, the Financial Services Industry and Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can an Asia Pacific Community, similar to the European Community, emerge?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
The purpose of this paper is to analyse whether the Asia Pacific region could form a union similar to the one now established in Europe. To this end, it analyses some of the major challenge faced by the US prior to its union in the 19th century and the way countries such as France and Germany contributed to the formation of the EU, despite their past animosity. The paper proposed a two tier system for the emergence of a union in the Asia Pacific region in which all countries could become part of a regional framework for regional security and free trade and some of the more advanced countries in the region could start the process of financial integration and invite other member countries to join them over time. The paper argues that in the 2st century, unlike the claim of the "currency optimum theory," there is no need for labour mobility amongst Asian countries for the formation of a union in this region and hence Australia should not expect millions of workers from China to migrate there. The paper argues that the role of Japan and China in the process of regional integration has been underestimated, due to the claim that the former is a monoculture and the latter is too nationalistic. The paper highlights how diversity in the region could be seen as a strength in the Asia Pacific region. It also shows how the process of globalisation has already overcome differences in culture, religion and race which used to be stumbling blocks for more regional or global integration. The paper argues that a union in the Asia Pacific region would reduce "home bias" for international capital flows and hence there Would be significant financial transformation Of Countries in this region. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock returns, order imbalances, and commonality: Evidence on individual, institutional, and proprietary investors in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bailey, Warren; Cai, Jun; Cheung, Yan Leung; Wang, Fenghua
Using it unique dataset from the Shanghai Stock Exchange, we study the relation between daily open-to-close stock returns and order imbalances. and the commonality in order imbalances across individual, institutional, and proprietary investors. We find that institutional (proprietary) order imbalances have a larger price impact, but account fora sianificantly smaller proportion of daily price fluctuations. Commonality; is Much stronger for individual, rather than institutional (proprietary), order imbalances. Institutional (proprietary) investors favor large capitalization stocks. and co-movement in institutional (proprietary) order imbalances is stronger for these stocks. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bailey, Warren; Cai, Jun; Cheung, Yan Leung; Wang, Fenghua</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the type of ownership control matter? Evidence from China's listed companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Gongmeng; Firth, Michael; Xu, Liping
By tracing the identity of large shareholders, we group China's listed companies into those controlled by state asset management bureaus (SAMBs), state owned enterprises (SOEs) affiliated to the central government (SOECGs), SOEs affiliated to the local government (SOELGs), and Private investors. We argue that these distinct types of owners have different objectives and motivations and this will affect how they exercise their control rights over the firms they invest in. In particular, we contend that private ownership of listed firms in China is not necessarily superior to certain types of state ownership. To test our arguments we investigate the relative efficiency of state versus private ownership of listed firms and the efficiency of various forms of state ownership. The empirical results indicate that the operating efficiency of Chinese listed companies varies across the type of controlling shareholder. SOECG controlled firms perform best and SAMB and Private controlled firms perform worst. SOELG controlled firms are in the middle. The results are consistent with our predictions. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Gongmeng; Firth, Michael; Xu, Liping</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional development, financial deepening and economic growth: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, Iftekhar; Wachtel, Paul; Zhou, Mingming
There have been profound changes in both political and economic institutions in China over the last 20 years. Moreover, the pace of transition has led to variation across the Country in the level of development. In this paper, We use panel data for the Chinese provinces to study the role of legal institutions. financial deepening and political pluralism on growth rates. The most important institutional developments for a transition economy are the emergence and legalization of the market economy, the establishment of secure property rights, the growth of a private sector, the development of financial sector institutions and markets, and the liberalization of political institutions. We develop measures of these phenomena, which are used as explanatory variables in regression models to explain provincial GDP growth rates. Our evidence suggests that the development of financial markets, legal environment, awareness of property rights and political pluralism are associated with stronger growth. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasan, Iftekhar; Wachtel, Paul; Zhou, Mingming</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expropriation through loan guarantees to related parties: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, Henk; Cole, Rebel A.; Fu, Lawrence J.
We identify and analyze a sample of publicly traded Chinese firms that issued loan guarantees to their related Parties (usually the controlling, block holders). thereby expropriating wealth from minority shareholders. Our results show that the issuance of related guarantees is less likely at smaller firms, at more profitable firms and at firms with higher growth prospects. We also find that the identity and ownership of block holders affect the likelihood of expropriation. In addition, we use this sample to provide new evidence on the relation between tunneling and proxies for firm value and financial performance. We find that Tobin's Q, ROA and dividend yield are significantly lower, and that leverage is significantly higher at firms that issued related guarantees. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berkman, Henk; Cole, Rebel A.; Fu, Lawrence J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are New Tigers supplanting Old Mammoths in China's banking system? Evidence from a sample of city commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferri, Giovanni
"New Tigers" (including city commercial banks) outperform state-owned commercial banks burdened with non-performing loans from unprofitable state-owned enterprises. We Study whether this is solely due to superior corporate governance (multiple shareholders versus total government ownership) or also to the favorable environment (the New Tigers target affluent China, while state-owned commercial banks operate nationwide). Using a field survey on 20 city commercial banks from three provinces at different levels of economic development, we find better performance at those in the East and worse performance at those controlled by state-owned enterprises. Geography and policy do matter, and reform of state-owned commercial banks is necessary to bring better banking to China. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferri, Giovanni</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank ownership and efficiency in China: What will happen in the world's largest nation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Zhou, Mingming
China is reforming its banking system, partially privatizing and taking, on minority foreign ownership of three of its dominant "Big Four" state-owned banks. This paper helps predict the effects by analyzing the efficiency of Chinese banks over 1994-2003. Findings suggest that Big Four banks are by far the least efficient: foreign banks are most efficient and minority foreign ownership is associated with significantly improved efficiency. We present corroborating robustness checks and offer several credible mechanisms through which minority foreign owners may increase Chinese bank efficiency. These findings Suggest that minority foreign ownership of the Big Four will likely improve performance significantly. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Zhou, Mingming</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of the volatility smile on exchange settlement practices: The Hong Kong case</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Eric C.; Ren, Jinjuan; Shi, Qi
The well-documented volatility smile phenomenon in the US option,, market has affected the option settlement practices of other markets. To settle Hang Seng Index (HSI) options, the Hong Kong Stock Exchange artificially builds in a piecewise linear "smile" or "sneer" volatility function, which is determined daily by market makers rather than directly by market forces. In this study, we investigate the time-varying settlement function and find the following economic determinants of the volatility function: lag parameters, current-day HSI returns, the distribution of HSI returns, transaction costs as proxied by the bid-ask spread, and the "Monday effect". For evaluation purposes, we use as a benchmark the estimated piecewise linear volatility function as directly driven by market forces. The comparison analyses show that base volatilities set by market makers run somewhat high, while downside slopes are not steep enough. This results in the overpricing of the lion's share of traded options. An economic determinants analysis of market-force-driven parameters reveals that market makers can better align artificial volatility parameters both by reducing reliance on the function parameters of prior days and by more precisely accounting for current-day HSI returns, option time-to-maturity, bid-ask spreads and buying pressure. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Eric C.; Ren, Jinjuan; Shi, Qi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Marketability, control, and the pricing of block shares</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Zhangkai; Xu, Xingzhong
Unlike in other countries, negotiated block shares have huge discounts in China. We argue that trading restrictions help to explain this puzzle. Block shares ill China face trading restrictions in the open market and can on]), be traded in the form of block transfers at negotiated prices. Using a dataset of 233 block transfers in China between 2002 and 2003, we find that discounts oil block share prices increase with the proportion of restricted shares in the ownership. The likelihood of private benefit of control has positive impact on block prices, bill the effect diminishes when there are other large shareholders. Furthermore. private institutions offer a higher price than state-owned institutions. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Zhangkai; Xu, Xingzhong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of ownership on the prudential behavior of banks - The case of China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jia, Chunxin
Although the relationship between bank ownership and performance is the current focus Of much research, this paper investigates the relationship between ownership and the prudential behavior of banks. Using Chinese data, I show that lending by state-owned banks has been less prudent than lending by joint-equity banks, but has improved over time. This is consistent with the hypothesis that accountability to shareholders and depositors gives joint-equity banks a better incentive than state-owned banks to engage in prudent lending, and with the hypothesis that the reform of the banking system has improved the incentive for state-owned banks to behave more prudently in their lending. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jia, Chunxin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulations, earnings management, and post-IPO performance: The Chinese evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kao, Jennifer L.; Wu, Donghui; Yang, Zhifeng
In this study, we examine whether government regulatory initiatives in China involving IPO by SOEs may have contributed to opportunistic behaviors by the issuer. We focus on two sets of IPO regulations issued between January 1, 1996 and February 11, 1999: pricing regulations, which Stipulate that IPO prices be a function of accounting performance, and penalty regulations, which penalize IPO firms for overly optimistic forecasts. We find that IPO firms that report better pricing-period accounting performance have larger declines in post-IPO profitability, lower first-day stock returns and worse long-run post-IPO stock performance. Furthermore, IPO firms that make overoptimistic forecasts also have lower first-day returns and worse post-IPO stock performance. Using non-core earnings as the proxy for earnings management, we document some evidence that IPO firms that report higher pricing-period accounting performance have engaged in more income-increasing earnings management. Hence, pricing regulations may have induced I PO firms to inflate pricing-period earnings and affect the post-IPO performance negatively. On the other hand, penalty regulations have deterred IPO firms from making overoptimistic earnings forecast and therefore have a positive impact on the behavior of IPO firms. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kao, Jennifer L.; Wu, Donghui; Yang, Zhifeng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the stock market affect firm investment in China? A price informativeness perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Yaping; Wu, Liansheng; Yang, Yunhong
This paper investigates the empirical relationship between firm-level investment and the stock market in China front a price informativeness perspective. We find that firm investment does not significantly respond to the stock market valuation, because stock prices contain very little extra information about the future operating performance: of firms. This finding is further Supported by the relative investment response test and the relative price information content test based on the informativeness proxy of price non-synchronicity combined with firm information transparency. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Yaping; Wu, Liansheng; Yang, Yunhong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of reform on China's bank structure and performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fu, Xiaoqing; Heffernan, Shelagh
This paper investigates the relationship between market structure and performance in China's banking system from 1995 to 2002, a period when this sec I tor was subject to gradual but notable reform. Using panel data estimation techniques, both the market-power and efficient-structure hypotheses are tested. In addition, the model is extended to consider issues such as the impact of bank size/ownership and whether the big four banks enjoy a "quiet life". On average, X-efficiency declined significantly and most banks were operating below scale efficient levels. Estimation of the structure-performance models lends some support to the relative market-power hypothesis in the early period. The reforms had little impact on the structure of China's banking sector, though the "joint stock" banks became relatively more X-efficient. There was no evidence to support the quiet-life hypothesis, probably because strict interest rate controls prevented the state banks from earning monopoly profits. Thus the ongoing liberalisation of interest rates should be accompanied by reduced concentration. Overall. to improve competitive structure, new policies should be directed at encouraging market entry and increasing the market share of the most efficient banks. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fu, Xiaoqing; Heffernan, Shelagh</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate tax, capital structure, and the accessibility of bank loans: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Liansheng; Yue, Heng
In this paper, we investigate whether listed firms in China adjust their capital structure in response to an increase in the corporate tax rate. Although theories of capital structure suggest that corporate tax is an important determinant of capital structure, how exogenous changes of the tax rate affect firms' leverage decisions has not been fully explored. We examine a unique circumstance in which the Chinese government increased the corporate tax rate of firms that had previously received local government tax rebates. The evidence indicates that these firms increased their leverage when the corporate tax rate increased. Further investigation suggests that the adjustment of leverage was mostly driven by firms with a high level of access to bank loans. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Liansheng; Yue, Heng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank ownership reform and bank performance in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Xiaochi; Zhang, Yi
Using a panel of Chinese banks over the 1997-2004 period, we assess the effect of bank ownership on performance. Specifically, we conduct a joint analysis of the static, selection. and dynamic effects of (domestic) private, foreign and state ownership. We find that the "Big Four" state-owned commercial banks are less profitable, are less efficient, and have worse asset quality than other types of banks except the "policy" banks (static effect). Further, the banks undergoing a foreign acquisition or public listing record better pre-event performance (selection effect); however, we find little performance change in either the short or the long term. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Xiaochi; Zhang, Yi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizational distance and use of collateral for business loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jimenez, Gabriel; Salas, Vicente; Saurina, Jesus
This paper examines the effect of organizational distance (i.e. distance between the headquarters of the bank that grants a loan and the location of the borrower) on the use of collateral for business loans by Spanish banks on the basis of the recent lender-based theory of collateral [Inderst, R., Mueller, H.M., 2007. A lender-based theory of collateral. journal of Financial Economics 84, 826-859.]. We find that, for the average borrower, the use of collateral is higher for loans granted by local lenders than by distant ones. We also show that the difference in the likelihood of collateral in loans granted by local lenders, relative to distant lenders, is higher among older and larger firms, than, respectively, younger and smaller firms. We also find that banks use lending technologies that are different for near and for distant firms, in response to organizational diseconomies. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jimenez, Gabriel; Salas, Vicente; Saurina, Jesus</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting the bear stock market: Macroeconomic variables as leading indicators</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Shiu-Sheng
This paper investigates whether macroeconomic variables can predict recessions in the stock market, i.e., bear markets. Series such as interest rate spreads, inflation rates, money stocks, aggregate Output, unemployment rates, federal funds rates, federal government debt, and nominal exchange rates are evaluated. After using parametric and nonparametric approaches to identify recession periods in the stock market, we consider both in-sample and out-of-sample tests of the variables' predictive ability. Empirical evidence from monthly data on the Standard &amp; Poor's S&amp;P 500 price index suggests that among the macroeconomic variables we have evaluated, yield curve spreads and inflation rates are the most useful predictors of recessions in the US stock market, according to both in-sample and out-of-sample forecasting performance. Moreover, comparing the bear market prediction to the stock return predictability has shown that it is easier to predict bear markets using macroeconomic variables. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Shiu-Sheng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size matters: Economies of scale in European payments processing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beijnen, Christine; Bolt, Wilko
This paper investigates the existence and extent of economies of scale in the European payment processing industry. It is expected that the creation of a single European payments area (SEPA) will Spur consolidations and mergers among European payment processors to more fully realize payment economies of scale. We find evidence for the existence of significant economies of scale using data of eight European payment processors during the years 1990-2005. The analysis also reveals that ownership structure is all important factor to explain cost differences across European processing centers. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beijnen, Christine; Bolt, Wilko</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do analyst recommendations reflect shareholder rights?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Autore, Don M.; Kovacs, Tunde; Sharma, Vivek
We examine whether sell-side analyst recommendations reflect shareholder rights, Our rationale is that analysts should be influenced by external governance only if market participants do not efficiently price its value. We find that stronger shareholder rights are associated with more favorable recommendations. Further analysis reveals that analysts favor firms with strong shareholder rights only when strong rights appear to be warranted, but do not penalize firms for having strong rights when not needed. These findings Occupy middle ground in the debate on the pricing efficiency of shareholder rights. Moreover, we find that firm value is positively associated with the strength of shareholder rights regardless of the expected external governance structure. The latter result is consistent with a "one-size-fits-all" interpretation, and implies that firms across the board could increase share value by reducing their number of anti-takeover provisions. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Autore, Don M.; Kovacs, Tunde; Sharma, Vivek</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information uncertainty and auditor reputation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Autore, Don M.; Billingsley, Randall S.; Schneller, Meir I.
This paper explores the relationship between information uncertainty and auditor reputation revealed by the failure of Arthur Andersen (AA). AA's reputation deteriorated considerably when it announced on January 10, 2002. that it had shredded documents related to its audit of Enron. AA's demise was sealed on March 14, 2002, with its indictment for obstruction of justice. We find that on these dates the clients of AA and other Big Five auditors that are characterized by higher information uncertainty experience relatively larger share price declines compared to clients with lower information uncertainty. The findings suggest that the market relies more heavily on auditor reputation for higher information uncertainty firms, which implies that the value of an audit is greater when a firm is harder to value. Our results highlight the importance of information uncertainty in financial markets: where there is a shock to auditor reputation, firms with greater information uncertainty stiffer the largest losses. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Autore, Don M.; Billingsley, Randall S.; Schneller, Meir I.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do artificial income smoothing and real income smoothing contribute to firm value equivalently?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Pinghsun; Zhang, Yan; Deis, Donald R.; Moffitt, Jacquelyn S.
This paper examines the potential impacts of artificial smoothing (abnormal accruals) and real smoothing (derivatives) on firm value. We find that the value of the firm decreases with the magnitude of abnormal accruals and increases with the level of derivative use. Moreover, the accrual discount is more pronounced in firms with weak investor protection and the hedging premium is greater for poorly governed firms. These results suggest that although managers can engage in real smoothing to improve the informativeness of firms' earnings and thus reduce agency costs, they might use artificial techniques to cosmetically improve the income stream in order to expropriate minority shareholders. In further support of agency theories, we report that poor corporate governance motivates the use of abnormal accruals and discourages derivative use. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Huang, Pinghsun; Zhang, Yan; Deis, Donald R.; Moffitt, Jacquelyn S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining bank distress in Eastern European transition economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mannasoo, Kadri; Mayes, David G.
This paper considers the joint role of macroeconomic, structural and bank-specific factors in explaining the occurrence of banking problems in the nineteen Eastern European transition countries over the last decade. With data at the individual bank level we show, using a discrete time survival model, that all three factors interact in their impact and have a rich dynamic profile, which underlines the highly volatile cycles challenging the stability of banks in this region. A fragile funding basis accompanied by high exposure to market risk in an environment of reforms and macroeconomic disturbances is the typical precursor of bank distress. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mannasoo, Kadri; Mayes, David G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does better corporate governance result in higher valuations in emerging markets? Another examination using a new data set</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morey, Matthew; Gottesman, Aron; Baker, Edward; Godridge, Ben
This paper utilizes a new data set from AllianceBernstein that, unlike other corporate governance data, has monthly-updated firm-level governance ratings for 21 emerging markets countries for almost a five year period. With these unique data, we examine how changes in corporate governance ratings impact firm Valuation. Using this test we find evidence that improvements in corporate governance result in significantly higher valuations. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morey, Matthew; Gottesman, Aron; Baker, Edward; Godridge, Ben</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The changing relationship between earnings expectations and earnings for value and growth stocks during Reg FD</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Jong, Pieter J.; Apilado, Vince P.
Regulation Fair Disclosure (Reg FD) altered the Voluntary disclosure practices of firms with publicly traded securities, thereby affecting relationships between Value and growth stock expectations and actual earnings. The results show that earnings forecasts for both stock groups are biased but that bias is less after the introduction of Reg FD. In fact, the difference in pre/post FD forecast bias is larger for growth stocks, Suggesting that before Reg FD, analysts did not just misinterpret news but consciously tried to maintain relationships with growth firm managers. However, Reg FD limited these relationships severing the monetary advantage that might be gained from manipulating forecasts. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Jong, Pieter J.; Apilado, Vince P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of bank monitoring in corporate governance: Evidence from borrowers' earnings management behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, Sungyoon; Choi, Wooseok
In this paper, we examine the corporate governance role of banks by investigating the effect of bank monitoring on the borrowers' earnings management behavior. Our analyses suggest that a borrowing firm's earnings management behavior generally decreases as the strength of bank monitoring increases. The strength of bank monitoring is measured as (1) the magnitude of a bank loan, (2) the reputation (rank) of a lead bank, (3) the length of a bank loan, and (4) the number of lenders. These results imply that bank monitoring plays an important role in the corporate governance of bank-dependent firms. We further examine other bank loan characteristics (collateral. refinancing, loan types, and loan purposes) and their effects on borrowers' earnings management behavior. Our analyses show that collateral and loan types are significantly associated with borrowers' earnings management behavior while refinancing and loan put-poses have no association. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahn, Sungyoon; Choi, Wooseok</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are good or bad borrowers discouraged from applying for loans? Evidence from US small business credit markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Liang; Fraser, Stuart; Storey, David J.
This paper takes the concept of a discouraged borrower originally formulated by Kon and Storey [Kon, Y., Storey, D.J., 2003. A theory of discouraged borrowers. Small Business Economics 21, 37-49] and examines whether discouragement is an efficient self-rationing mechanism, Using US data it finds riskier borrowers have higher probabilities of discouragement, which increase with longer financial relationships, suggesting discouragement is an efficient self-rationing mechanism. It also finds low risk borrowers are less likely to be discouraged in concentrated markets than in competitive markets and that, in concentrated markets, high risk borrowers are more likely to be discouraged the longer their financial relationships. We conclude discouragement is more efficient in concentrated, than in competitive, markets. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Han, Liang; Fraser, Stuart; Storey, David J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regime switching in the relationship between equity returns and short-term interest rates in the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henry, Olan T.
This paper examines the relationship between UK equity returns and short-term interest rates using a two regime Markov-Switching EGARCH model. The results Suggest one high-return, low variance regime within which the conditional variance of equity returns responds persistently but symmetrically to equity return innovations. In the other, low-mean, high variance, regime equity volatility responds asymmetrically and Without persistence to shocks to equity returns. There is evidence of a regime dependent relationship between shorter maturity interest rate differentials and equity return volatility, Furthermore, there is evidence that events in the money markets influence the probability of transition across regimes. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Henry, Olan T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Getting PPP right: Identifying mean-reverting real exchange rates in panels</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chortareas, Georgios; Kapetanios, George
Recent advances in testing for the validity of Purchasing Power Parity (PPP) focus on the time series properties of real exchange rates in panel frameworks. One weakness of such tests, however, is that they fail to inform the researcher as to which cross-section units are stationary. As a consequence, a reservation for PPP analyses based on such tests is that a small number of real exchange rates in a given panel may drive the results. In this paper we examine the PPP hypothesis focusing on the stationarity of the real exchange rates in up to 25 OECD countries. We introduce a methodology that when applied to a set of established panel unit-root tests, allows the identification of the real exchange rates that are stationary. Our results reveal evidence of mean-reversion that is significantly stronger as compared to that obtained by the existing literature, strengthening the case for PPP. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chortareas, Georgios; Kapetanios, George</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Great expectations: Banks as equity underwriters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaplinsky, Susan; Erwin, Gayle R.
We examine the in-roads commercial banks have made into equity underwriting over 1990-2002. While banks end the period handling upwards of 25% of equity underwriting, this increase results almost exclusively from acquisitions of investment banks with an already established market share of equity underwriting. We find a significant decline in the market share of equity underwriting that banks acquired in the post-merger period, a decline that is larger than that experienced by independent investment banks of comparable reputation. Banks lose market share because they originate fewer IPOs and their IPOs have a lower incidence of follow-on SEOs compared to independent investment banks. Following the merger, banks experience a large fall off in their ability to retain follow-on SEOs and are less successful in winning SEO mandates when an issuer switches from its IPO underwriter. Overall, the findings suggest it has been difficult for banks to achieve scope economies in equity underwriting. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chaplinsky, Susan; Erwin, Gayle R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From state to private ownership: Issues from strategic industries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubakri, Narjess; Cosset, Jean-Claude; Guedhami, Omrane
This paper investigates the effects of privatization for a panel of 189 firms from strategic industries head-quartered in 39 countries, and privatized between 1984 and 2002. Strategic firms can hardly be compared to Manufacturing or competitive industries as they are generally under state monopoly, and involve specific issues Such as regulation, political and institutional constraints, We examine the change in ownership and postprivatization means of control by the government, and assess whether positive changes in performance obtain in these particular industries that include firms from the financial, mining, steel, telecommunications, transportation, utilities, and oil sectors. We document that governments continue to exert influence on former state-owned firms after three years by retaining golden shares and/or appointing politicians to key positions in the firm. Our multivariate results reveal a negative effect of state ownership on profitability and operating efficiency, which the presence of a sound institutional and political environment moderates. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubakri, Narjess; Cosset, Jean-Claude; Guedhami, Omrane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debit or credit?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zinman, Jonathan
Empirical consumer payment price sensitivity has implications for theory, optimal regulation of payment card networks, and business strategy. A critical margin is the price of a credit card charge. A revolver who did not pay her most recent balance in full pays interest; other credit card users do not. I find that revolvers are substantially less likely to incur credit card charges and substantially more likely to use a debit card, conditional on several proxies for transaction demand and tastes. Debit use also increases with credit limit constraints and decreases with credit card possession. Additional results suggest that debit is becoming a stronger substitute for credit over time. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zinman, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of banks' risk exposure to new account fraud - Evidence from Germany</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartmann-Wendels, Thomas; Maehlmann, Thomas; Versen, Tobias
This paper studies empirically the determinants of new account fraud risk within two dimensions: the probability of fraud, and the expected and unexpected (monetary) loss-per-account due to fraud. By fraud risk, we mean the risk that a bank fails to enforce a debt because the identity of the person incurring the debt cannot be ascertained. Using a unique and rich data set of account applicants, provided by a German Internet-only bank, we find that fraud risk is highly sensitive to demographic and socio-economic variables like nationality, gender, marital status, age, occupation, and urbanisation. For example, foreigners are 22.25 times more likely to commit account fraud than Germans, and men are 2.5 times more risky than women. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hartmann-Wendels, Thomas; Maehlmann, Thomas; Versen, Tobias</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of the liquidity benefits provided by secondary markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mantecon, Tomas; Poon, Percy
Listing shares in liquid secondary markets either to facilitate acquisitions or to diversify owner's personal wealth are among the most important reasons for firms to go public [Brau, J.C., Fawcett, S.E., 2006, Initial public offerings: An analysis of theory and practice. journal of Finance 61, 399-436]. We contend that the expected benefits derived from the liquidity provided by secondary markets are relevant for understanding important decisions made in preparation for an IPO. We hypothesize that the potential losses caused by an IPO failure induce firms that benefit more from going public to hire more reputable underwriters and to adopt more conservative pricing policies. We use several proxies for the benefits firms derive from post-IPO liquidity. The results indicate that firms that benefited more from liquidity were taken public by more prestigious underwriters and exhibited substantially larger levels of price revisions and underpricing. Post-IPO liquidity is also important for understanding the decision to retain the lead underwriter in subsequent SEOs. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved</description><author>Mantecon, Tomas; Poon, Percy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disappearing internal capital markets: Evidence from diversified business groups in Korea</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Sangwoo; Park, Kwangwoo; Shin, Hyun-Han
This paper examines how the onset of a financial crisis affects the operation of internal capital markets among firms within a diversified business group. We find that active internal capital markets within Korean business groups (chaebols) attenuate the financial constraints of the group-affiliated firms, allowing them to make efficient capital allocations during the early 1990s. However, these markets barely function after the financial crisis of 1997. Instead, we observe public debt markets serving as a substitute for internal capital markets. Our results suggest that chaebol firms' coordinated attempts to achieve healthier financial structures in the wake of the crisis have taken place at the expense of investment efficiency. (c) 2008 Elsevier BY. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Sangwoo; Park, Kwangwoo; Shin, Hyun-Han</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance quality and privately negotiated stock repurchases: Evidence of agency conflict</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, Oneil; Glegg, Charmaine
This study examines the impact of shareholder rights on the wealth effects of privately negotiated stock repurchases. Our results show that wealth gains are lower when shareholder rights are more suppressed. We also find that the premium paid for shares is inversely related to the strength of shareholder rights, and this suggests that managers pay higher premiums when shareholder rights are more restricted. These findings imply that managers use shareholders' funds to eliminate blockholders who are more likely to monitor them when shareholder rights are relatively weak, thereby entrench themselves. Consistent with this view, we further show that significant positive abnormal long-run returns after private stock repurchases are limited to firms with stronger shareholder protection. Overall, the evidence is consistent with the predictions of agency theory. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved,</description><author>Harris, Oneil; Glegg, Charmaine</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Block ownership and firm-specific information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, Paul; Yan, Xuemin
This study examines the impact of block ownership on the firm's information environment. Previous research shows that stock price efficiency depends on the cost of acquiring private information, as well as on the precision of this information. Blockholders have a clear advantage over diffuse, atomistic shareholders in terms of the precision and acquisition cost of their private information. We hypothesize that this informational advantage will manifest itself primarily in the firm-specific component of stock returns. Our empirical findings confirm that blockholders increase the probability of informed trading and idiosyncratic volatility, and decrease the firm's stock return synchronicity. These results hold for both inside and outside blockholders, but are insignificant for blocks controlled by employee stock ownership plans (ESOPs). Overall, our findings support the contention that ownership structure plays a significant role in shaping the firm's information environment. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brockman, Paul; Yan, Xuemin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate trade credit and inventories: New evidence of a trade-off from accounts payable and receivable</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bougheas, Spiros; Mateut, Simona; Mizen, Paul
Trade credit is an important source of finance for firms and has been well researched, but the focus has been on financial trade-offs. In this paper, we consider the trade-offs with inventories and develop a simple model that recognizes the incentives a firm faces to offer and receive trade credit. Our model identifies the response of accounts payable and accounts receivable to changes in the cost of inventories, profitability, risk and liquidity, and importantly, this influence operates through a production channel. Our results support the model and complement many existing studies focused on explaining the financial terms of trade credit. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bougheas, Spiros; Mateut, Simona; Mizen, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit risk drivers: Evaluating the contribution of firm level information and of macroeconomic dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonfim, Diana
Understanding if credit risk is driven mostly by idiosyncratic firm characteristics or by systematic factors is an important issue for the assessment of financial stability. By exploring the links between credit risk and macroeconomic developments, we observe that in periods of economic growth there may be some tendency towards excessive risk-taking. Using an extensive dataset with detailed information for more than 30000 firms, we show that default probabilities are influenced by several firm-specific characteristics. When time-effect controls or macroeconomic variables are also taken into account, the results improve substantially. Hence, though the firms' financial situation has a central role in explaining default probabilities, macroeconomic conditions are also very important when assessing default probabilities over time. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bonfim, Diana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance evaluation of portfolio insurance strategies using stochastic dominance criteria</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Annaert, Jan; Van Osselaer, Sofieke; Verstraete, Bert
This paper evaluates the performance of the stop-loss, synthetic put and constant proportion portfolio insurance techniques based on a block-bootstrap simulation. We consider not only traditional performance measures, but also some recently developed measures that capture the non-normality of the return distribution (value-at-risk, expected shortfall, and the Omega measure). We compare them to the more comprehensive stochastic dominance criteria. The impact of changing the rebalancing frequency and level of capital protection is examined. We find that, even though a buy-and-hold strategy generates higher average excess returns, it does not stochastically dominate the portfolio insurance strategies, nor vice versa. Our results indicate that a 100% floor value should be preferred to lower floor values and that daily-rebalanced synthetic put and CPPI strategies dominate their counterparts with less frequent rebalancing. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Annaert, Jan; Van Osselaer, Sofieke; Verstraete, Bert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The profitability of small single-market banks in an era of multi-market banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hannan, Timothy H.; Prager, Robin A.
This paper examines the relationship between the profitability of small single-market banks and the presence in the market of large banking organizations and banking organizations that operate primarily outside of the local banking market. We find that, in rural banking markets, the profitability of small single-market banks is significantly related to the presence of both large and small primarily-out-of-market banks. We also find that an increased presence of large or small primarily-out-of-market banks in rural banking markets reduces the positive effect of all increase in concentration on small single-market bank profits. This finding is consistent with theoretical predictions reported in the recent literature and has important implications for antitrust policy. In urban banking markets, we find little evidence of any relationship between the profitability of small single-market banks and the presence of large or primarily-out-of-market banks. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hannan, Timothy H.; Prager, Robin A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of credit cards, debit cards and ATMs: A survey and some new evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scholnick, Barry; Massoud, Nadia; Saunders, Anthony; Carbo-Valverde, Santiago; Rodriguez-Fernandez, Francisco
This paper provides a critical survey of the large and diffuse literature on credit cards, debit cards and ATMs. We argue that because there are still many outstanding issues and questions about the pricing, use and substitutability of these payment mechanisms, that there are significant further opportunities for research in these areas. A large number of questions are examined in this survey, including the pricing of credit cards, the impact of networks on the provision and pricing of ATMs, as well as the tradeoffs that consumers make between different types of payment mechanism, including debit cards, credit cards and ATMs. Importantly, this paper is also amongst the first to provide new evidence on this latter question from bank level data (from Spain). We conclude that point of sale (debit card) and ATM transactions are substitutes, and that ATM surcharges impacts point of sale volume significantly. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Scholnick, Barry; Massoud, Nadia; Saunders, Anthony; Carbo-Valverde, Santiago; Rodriguez-Fernandez, Francisco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank income structure and risk: An empirical analysis of European banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lepetit, Laetitia; Nys, Emmanuelle; Rous, Philippe; Tarazi, Amine
The purpose of this paper is to investigate the relationship between bank risk and product diversification in the changing structure of the European banking industry. Based on a broad set of European banks for the period 1996-2002, our study first shows that banks expanding into non-interest income activities present higher risk and higher insolvency risk than banks which mainly supply loans. However, considering size effects and splitting non-interest activities into both trading activities and commission and fee activities we show that the positive link with risk is mostly accurate for small banks and essentially driven by commission and fee activities. A higher share of trading activities is never associated with higher risk and for small banks it implies, in some cases, lower asset and default risks. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lepetit, Laetitia; Nys, Emmanuelle; Rous, Philippe; Tarazi, Amine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cyclical behaviour of European bank capital buffers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jokipii, Terhi; Milne, Alistair
Using an unbalanced panel of accounting data from 1997 to 2004 and controlling for individual bank costs and risk, we find capital buffers of the banks in the EU15 have a significant negative co-movement with the cycle. For banks in the accession countries there is significant positive co-movement. Capital buffers of commercial and savings banks, and of large banks, exhibit negative co-movement. Those of co-operative and smaller, banks exhibit positive co-movement. Speeds of adjustment are fairly slow. We interpret these results and discuss policy implications, noting that negative co-movement of capital buffers will exacerbate the pro-cyclical impact of Basel II. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jokipii, Terhi; Milne, Alistair</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The significance of a world government in the process of globalization in the 21st century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
This paper discusses the process of globalization and analyses those pressing global issues that have been unresolved due to the lack of an integrated global system and effective international institutions. It highlights a number of global issues that require global ethics and global action. The paper discusses how a globally integrated system, with a world government, a world parliament and a world central bank as its components, is no longer an idealistic concept. The paper highlights the dynamic gains of the transformation of nations and the future of this planet, once an integrated global system is in place. it analyses the challenges overcome during the integration of the US in the 19th century and the process of the formation of the EU in the 20th century. It argues that the creation of a globally integrated system, based on new and effective international institutions would be easier to implement than the formation of the US in the 19th Century or the EU in the 20th century, as we now have technology that did not exist in the 19th century and the process of globalization has already removed many previous financial, technological, cultural, language and other barriers to integration. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changes in the world's financial markets in the last 30 years and their implications for the future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional ownership stability and BHC performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elyaslani, Elyas; Jia, Jingyi Jane
In this study, the association between performance of BHCs and institutional ownership stability is investigated and contrasted to those found for the less regulated utility and industrial firms in Order to determine whether regulation displaces owner monitoring. We employ a simultaneous equations model treating firm performance and institutional Ownership stability as endogenous variables. Several results are obtained. First, BHC performance is positively associated with institutional ownership stability. Second. this association is weaker for BHCs than for comparable utility and industrial firms, possibly because Of the Substitution of regulation For owner monitoring in banking. Third. this association is stronger in the recent deregulated years and for BHCs with lower likelihood of regulatory intervention. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elyaslani, Elyas; Jia, Jingyi Jane</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment decisions and internal capital markets: Evidence from acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doukas, John A.; Kan, Ozgur B.
In this paper, we examine the workings of internal capital markets in diversified firms that engage in related and unrelated corporate acquisitions. Our evidence indicates that bidders invest outside their core business (diversify) when the cash flows of their core business fall behind those of their non-core lines of business. However, bidders invest inside their core business (i.e., undertake non-diversifying investments) when their core business experiences superior cash flows. We also find that bidders whose core business are in industries with low growth prospects engage in diversifying acquisitions while bidders whose core business are in high growth industries undertake non-diversifying acquisitions. The pre-acquisition evidence, then, suggests that firms tend to diversify when the cash flows and the growth opportunities of their core business are considerably lower than those of their non-core business. Subsequent to acquisitions we find that diversifying bidders continue to allocate financial resources from less profitable business segments (i.e., core business) to more profitable business segments (i.e., non-core business). Given the low profitability of diversifying bidders' core business, this capital resource allocation suggests that diversification increases do not result in capital allocation inefficiencies. The evidence for non-diversifying bidders, however, supports the existence of "corporate socialism" in the sense that there is transfer of funds from the profitable (core) to the less profitable (non-core) business segments in multi-segment bidders. We find that the capital expenditures of bidders' non-core business segments rely on both core and non-core cash flows. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doukas, John A.; Kan, Ozgur B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit to government and banking sector performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hauner, David
The impact of credit to government on three aspects of banking sector performance - its deepening over time, profitability, and efficiency - is examined for 142 countries. Country regressions suggest a sizeable negative effect of credit to government on bank deepening in developing countries, but no impact in advanced economies. Bank regressions find that credit to government raises the profitability but reduces the efficiency of banks in developing countries; in advanced economies, there appears to be no impact on profitability but a positive one on efficiency. (C) 2007 International Monetary Fund. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hauner, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial market integration and the value of global diversification: Evidence for US acquirers in cross-border mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Sun, Xian
In contrast to the previously documented cross-border discount, we find that there is positive cross-border effect for US acquirers during late 1990s and early 2000s. This is especially particular the case for those that acquire/merge with targets from segmented financial markets where acquirers experience significantly higher positive abnormal returns than those that acquire targets from integrated financial markets. Furthermore, firms acquiring segmented-market targets are also characterized by significantly higher post-merger operating performance improvement. The results indicate that the observed positive cross-border effect is mainly due to the increase in the number of transactions involving targets from segmented markets, in which the average firm experience significant financial constraints. We contend that value is created by a combination of firms with different financial market integration status, in which funds are provided to high cost firms. The finding that the value creation is even higher within the group of acquirers with a lower cost of capital provides additional support for our conjecture. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Sun, Xian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparing the performance of market-based and accounting-based bankruptcy prediction models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vineet; Taffler, Richard
Recently developed corporate bankruptcy prediction models adopt a contingent claims valuation approach. However, despite their theoretical appeal, tests of their performance compared with traditional simple accounting-ratio-based approaches are limited in the literature. We find the two approaches capture different aspects of bankruptcy risk, and while there is little difference in their predictive ability in the UK, the z-score approach leads to significantly greater bank profitability in conditions of differential decision error costs and competitive pricing regime. (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Agarwal, Vineet; Taffler, Richard</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why 'Basel II' may need a leverage ratio restriction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blum, Juerg M.
We analyze regulatory capital requirements where the amount of required capital depends on the level of risk reported by the banks. It is shown that if the supervisors have a limited ability to identify or to sanction dishonest banks, an additional, risk-independent leverage ratio restriction may be necessary to induce truthful risk reporting. The leverage ratio helps to offset the banks' potential capital savings of understating their risks by (i) reducing banks' put option value of limited liability ex ante, and by (ii) increasing the banks' net worth, which in turn enhances the supervisors' ability to sanction banks ex post. (C) Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blum, Juerg M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decomposing liquidity along the limit order book</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rakowski, David; Beardsley, Xiaoxin Wang
In this paper, we estimate the asymmetric information and order processing components of liquidity at extended depths along the limit order book. Using data from the INET ECN, we find that the asymmetric information component decreases as depth increases. Inactive stocks have more information asymmetry at the inside quotes, but it decreases more rapidly along the book than for active stocks. The order processing component of liquidity has fixed and variable constituents, consistent with a fixed cost per order as well as a variable portion based on the size of the order. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rakowski, David; Beardsley, Xiaoxin Wang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank capital regulation in a barrier option framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Episcopos, Athanasios
The barrier options theory of corporate security valuation is applied to the contingent claims of a regulated bank. The regulator/insurer of a bank owns a down-and-in call option on the bank assets which can be balanced against the expected coverage cost. Raising the regulatory barrier (critical asset level triggering bank closure) leads to a transfer of wealth from stockholders to the insurer and reduces stockholder incentives to increase asset risk. Empirical tests on a sample of 152 one-bank holding companies show that regulatory barriers are priced in the stock market and are inversely related to Tier 1 leverage ratios. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Episcopos, Athanasios</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demand estimation and consumer welfare in the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dick, Astrid A.
This paper estimates a structural demand model for commercial bank deposit services in order to measure the effects on consumers given dramatic changes in bank services throughout US branching deregulation in the 1990s. Following the discrete choice literature, consumer decisions are based on prices and bank characteristics. Consumers are found to respond to deposit rates, and to a lesser extent, to account fees, in choosing a depository institution. Moreover, consumers respond favorably to the branch staffing and geographic density, as well as to the bank's age, size, and geographic diversification. Consumers in most markets experience a slight increase in welfare throughout the period. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dick, Astrid A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Utilitarianism and fairness in portfolio positioning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Palma, Andre; Prigent, Jean-Luc
The paper introduces the theory of optimal positioning of financial products. It is illustrated in the context of long-term intertemporal portfolio allocation and can be applied for example to asset allocation funds. We embed this problem in location theory: the portfolio is optimized within the investors' risk aversion dimension. For the CRRA utility functions, we compute explicitly the distance functions. For the first (utilitarian criterion), the average utility of the investors is maximized. For the second one (fairness criterion), the choice of portfolio is optimized so that the average monetary loss due to the lack of customization is minimized. Given the distribution of investors' risk aversion, we provide a solution method and an algorithm to optimally position standardized portfolio along one of these two criteria. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Palma, Andre; Prigent, Jean-Luc</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How important is asymmetric covariance for the risk premium of international assets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mazzotta, Stefano
This paper empirically investigates the importance of asymmetric conditional covariance when computing the risk premium of international assets. Conditional second moment asymmetry of equity indices is significant and varies over time. The risk premia estimated allowing for asymmetry are statistically and economically different from risk premia estimated without allowing for asymmetry. In particular, an international investor who ignores covariance asymmetry overestimates required returns for equities of the G4 countries and for the world market, on average. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mazzotta, Stefano</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common liquidity shocks and market collapse: Lessons from the market for perps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernando, Chitru S.; Herring, Richard J.; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
We show how a high degree of commonality in investor liquidity shocks can diminish incentives for intermediaries to keep markets open and lead to market collapse, even without information asymmetry or news affecting fundamentals. We motivate our model using the perpetual floating-rate note market where two years of explosive growth - in which issues by high quality borrowers were placed with institutional investors and traded in a liquid secondary market - were followed by a precipitous collapse when market intermediaries withdrew due to large order imbalances. We shed new light on the trade-off between ownership concentration and market liquidity. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fernando, Chitru S.; Herring, Richard J.; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Split bond ratings and rating migration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Livingston, Miles; Naranjo, Andy; Zhou, Lei
This paper examines the relationships between split ratings and ratings migration. We find that bonds with split ratings are more likely to have future rating changes. A one-notch (more-than-one-notch) split rating increases the probability of rating change within one year of initial issuance by about 3% (6%). Furthermore, we find that about 30% of split rated bonds have their two ratings converge after four years of initial issuance. The rating convergence tapers off after three years, and the rating agency with a higher (lower) initial rating generally maintains a higher (lower) rating in subsequent years if the two ratings do not converge. We also show that rating transition estimation can be improved by taking into consideration split ratings. We find that one-year rating transition matrices are significantly different between non-letter-split rated bonds and letter-split rated bonds, and we show that the difference has an economically significant impact on the pricing of credit spread options and VaR-based risk management models. Overall, our results suggest that split ratings contain important information about subsequent rating changes. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Livingston, Miles; Naranjo, Andy; Zhou, Lei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank consolidation and new business formation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Bill; Hasan, Iftekhar; Wang, Haizhi
As the trend of bank consolidation activities continues to grow in the US and globally, the debate on the impact of such consolidation on small business credits and activities are still inconclusive. Building on the existing research [Berger, A.N., Saunders, A., Scalise, J.M., Udell, G.F., 1998. The effects of bank mergers and acquisitions on small business lending. Journal of Financial Economics 50, 187-229]; [Black, S.E., Strahan, P.E., 2002. Entrepreneurship and bank credit availability. Journal of Finance LVII (6), 2807-2833], this paper investigates the effects of the actual intensity of bank consolidation on the formation of new businesses in the US local markets. Evidence portrays that in the short-run, the overall intensity of bank consolidation is negatively related to the rate of new business formation, and this negative relationship is primarily driven by consolidations initiated by large acquirers. On the contrary, consolidations between small-to-medium sized banks show a positive impact on new business development and these results are consistent even when the M&amp;As are distinguished with respect to in-market or out-of-market acquirers initiating the deals. However, two years after the consolidations, the evidence reveals a positive and significant impact on the rate of new business formation in the local markets for consolidations initiated by large in-market acquirers. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Francis, Bill; Hasan, Iftekhar; Wang, Haizhi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical analysis of aggregate household portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Normandin, Michel; St-Amour, Pascal
This paper analyzes the important time variation in US aggregate household portfolios. To do so, we first use flexible descriptions of preferences and investment opportunities to derive household optimal decision rules that nest static, myopic, and non-myopic portfolio allocations. We then compare these rules to the data through formal statistical analysis. Our main results reveal that: (i) static and myopic investment behaviors are rejected, (ii) non-myopic portfolio allocations are supported, and (iii) the Fama-French factors best explain empirical portfolio shares. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Normandin, Michel; St-Amour, Pascal</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging, financing, and investment decisions: Theory and empirical tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chen-Miao; Phillips, Richard D.; Smith, Stephen D.
In this paper we theoretically and empirically examine the interaction between hedging, financing, and investment decisions. A simple equilibrium model with costly financial distress suggests that as firms become more efficient at risky investments vis a vis low risk investments, they will borrow less, invest more in risky assets, and hedge more. The model also predicts a positive relationship between hedging and leverage - a result consistent with debt capacity arguments. We test the model empirically using a simultaneous equations framework to investigate the determinants of firm-level hedging, financing and investing decisions. The results strongly support the hypothesis that the hedging, financing and investment decisions are jointly determined. In addition, we find strong support for the central hypothesis that firms more efficient investing in risky technologies more aggressively hedge and use less debt financing in order to maximize their comparative advantage. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Chen-Miao; Phillips, Richard D.; Smith, Stephen D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual funds' ownership and firm performance: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yuan, Rongli; Xiao, Jason Zezhong; Zou, Hong
Mutual funds have emerged and rapidly developed since 2000 in China. This study tests empirically the impact of mutual funds' ownership on firm performance in China, using a large sample for the period of 2001-2005. We find that equity ownership by mutual funds has a positive effect on firm performance. The result is robust to several measures of firm performance and various estimations. Our finding supports recent regulatory efforts in China to promote mutual funds as a corporate governance mechanism and suggests that pooling diffuse minority interests of individual shareholders who are prone to free-rider problems via mutual funds is beneficial. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yuan, Rongli; Xiao, Jason Zezhong; Zou, Hong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on "Inflation and Welfare"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cysne, Rubens Penha
This note provides an analytical confirmation and a refinement of [Lucas Jr., R.E., 2000. Inflation and welfare. Econometrica 68 (62) 247-274 (March)] numerical findings regarding the characterization of optimality in the shopping-time model presented in that paper. The original numerical analysis concludes that a coefficient of risk aversion (a) greater than 0.01 is sufficient for optimality. Here we use Arrow's sufficiency theorem to confirm this result and, more importantly, to show without more calculations how changes in parameters can affect it. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cysne, Rubens Penha</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Markov regime switching approach for hedging energy commodities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alizadeh, Amir H.; Nomikos, Nikos K.; Pouliasis, Panos K.
This paper estimates constant and dynamic hedge ratios in the New York Mercantile Exchange oil futures markets and examines their hedging performance. We also introduce a Markov regime switching vector error correction model with GARCH error structure. This specification links the concept of disequilibrium With that Of Uncertainty (as measured by the conditional second moments) across high and low volatility regimes. Overall. in and out-of-sample tests indicate that state dependent hedge ratios are able to provide significant reduction in portfolio risk. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alizadeh, Amir H.; Nomikos, Nikos K.; Pouliasis, Panos K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure around the world: The roles of firm- and country-specific determinants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Jong, Abe; Kabir, Rezaul; Nguyen, Thuy Thu
We analyze the importance of firm-specific and country-specific factors in the leverage choice of firms from 42 Countries around the world. Our analysis yields two new results. First, we find that firm-specific determinants of leverage differ across countries, while prior Studies implicity assume equal impact of these determinants. Second, although we concur with the conventional direct impact of country-specific factors on the capital structure of firms, we show that there is an indirect impact because country-specific factors also influence the roles of firm-specific determinants of leverage. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Jong, Abe; Kabir, Rezaul; Nguyen, Thuy Thu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market volatility around national elections</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bialkowski, Jedrzej; Gottschalk, Katrin; Wisniewski, Tomasz Piotr
This paper investigates a sample of 27 OECD countries to test whether national elections induce higher stock market volatility. It is found that the country-specific component of index return variance can easily double during the week around an election, which shows that investors are surprised by the election outcome. Several factors, such as a narrow margin of victory, lack of compulsory voting laws, change in the political orientation of the government, or the failure to form a government with parliamentary majority significantly contribute to the magnitude of the election shock. Furthermore, some evidence is found that markets with short grading history exhibit stronger reaction. Our findings have important implications for the optimal strategies of institutional and individual investors who have direct or indirect exposure to volatility risk. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bialkowski, Jedrzej; Gottschalk, Katrin; Wisniewski, Tomasz Piotr</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The decision to first enter the public bond market: The role of firm reputation, funding choices, and bank relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hale, Galina; Santos, Joao A. C.
This paper Uses survival analysis to investigate the timing of a firm's decision to issue for the first time in the public bond market. We find that firms that are more creditworthy and have higher demand for external funds issue their first public bond earlier. We also find that issuing private bonds or taking Out syndicated loans is associated with a faster entry to the public bond market. According to Our results, the relationships that firms develop with investment banks in connection with their private bond issues and syndicated loans further speed up their entry to the public bond market. Finally, we find that a firms reputation has a "U-shaped" effect on the timing of a firm's bond IPO. Consistent with Diamond's reputational theory, firms that establish a track record of high creditworthiness as well as those that establish a track record of low creditworthiness enter the public bond market earlier than firms with intermediate reputation. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hale, Galina; Santos, Joao A. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US ADR and Hong Kong H-share discounts of Shanghai-listed firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arquette, Gregory C.; Brown, William O.; Burdekin, Richard C. K.
This paper examines the differential between the share prices of Chinese securities traded on their home market of Shanghai versus prices observed offshore in New York and Hong Kong. The discounts attached to Chinese securities, whether trading as ADRs on the NYSE or as H-shares on the Hong Kong market, appear to have been significantly influenced by changes in both exchange rate expectations and investor sentiment during 1998-2006. Expected exchange rate changes alone account for approximately 40% of the total variation in each case. This is combined with large cross-sectional variation, however, reflecting additional significant market-wide and company-specific sentiment effects. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arquette, Gregory C.; Brown, William O.; Burdekin, Richard C. K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonparametric, conditional pricing of higher order multivariate contingent claims</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannopoulos, Kostas
This paper describes and applies a nonparametric model for pricing multivariate contingent claims. Multivariate contingent claims are contracts whose payoffs depend on the future prices of more than one underlying variable. The pricing however of these kinds of contracts represents a challenge. All known models are adaptations of earlier ones that have been introduced to price plain vanilla calls and They are imposing strong assumptions on the distributional properties of the underlying variables. In contrast, this study adopts a Puts. methodology that relaxes such restrictions. Following [Barone-Adesi, G., Bourgoin, F., Giannopoulos, K., 1998. Don't Look Back, Risk 11 (August), 100-104: Barone-Adesi, G., Engle, R., Mancini, L., 2004. GARCH Options in Incomplete Market:;, mimeo, University of Applied Sciences Of Southern Switzerland; Long, X., 2004. Semiparametric Multivariate GARCH Model, mimeo, University of California, Riverside] multivariate pathways for a set of underlying variables are constructed before the option payoffs are computed. This enables the covariances. in addition to the means and variances, to be modelled in a dynamic and nonparametric manner. The model is particular Suitable for options whose payoffs depend on variables that are characterised by high nonlinearities and extremes and on higher order multivariate options whose underlying variables are more unlikely to conform to a common theoretical distribution. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giannopoulos, Kostas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash flow, investment, and investment opportunities: New tests using UK panel data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carpenter, Robert E.; Guariglia, Alessandra
The interpretation of the correlation between cash flow and investment is controversial. Some argue that it is caused by financial constraints. others by the correlation between cash flow and investment opportunities that are not properly measured by Tobin's Q. This paper Uses UK firms' contracted capital expenditure to capture information about opportunities available only to insiders and thus not included in Q. When this variable is added to investment regressions, the explanatory power of cash flow falls for large firms. but remains Unchanged for small firms. This suggest that the significance of cash flow stems from its role in capturing the effects of credit frictions, (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carpenter, Robert E.; Guariglia, Alessandra</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Offsetting the implicit incentives: Benefits of benchmarking in money management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, Suleyman; Pavlova, Anna; Shapiro, Alexander
Money managers are rewarded for increasing the value of assets under management. This gives a manager an implicit incentive to exploit the well-documented positive fund-flows to relative-performance relationship by manipulating her risk exposure. The misaligned incentives create potentially significant deviations of the manager's policy from that desired by fund investors. In the context of a familiar continuous-time portfolio choice model, we demonstrate how a simple risk management practice that accounts for benchmarking can ameliorate the adverse effects of managerial incentives. Our results contrast with the conventional view that benchmarking a fund manager is not in the best interest of investors. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Basak, Suleyman; Pavlova, Anna; Shapiro, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spectral risk measures and portfolio selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adam, Alexandre; Houkari, Mohamed; Laurent, Jean-Paul
This paper deals with risk measurement and portfolio optimization under risk constraints. Firstly we give an overview of risk assessment from the viewpoint of risk theory, focusing on moment-based, distortion and spectral risk measures. We subsequently apply these ideas to an asset management framework Using a database of hedge Funds returns chosen for their non-Gaussian features. We deal with the problem of portfolio optimization Under risk constraints and lead a comparative analysis of efficient portfolios. We show sonic robustness Of optimal portfolios with respect to the choice of risk measure. Unsurprisingly, risk measures that emphasize large losses lead to slightly more diversified portfolios. However. risk measures that account primarily for worst case scenarios overweight funds with smaller tails which mitigates the relevance of diversification. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adam, Alexandre; Houkari, Mohamed; Laurent, Jean-Paul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inside shareholders' effective tax rates and dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holmen, Martin; Knopf, John D.; Peterson, Stefan
Using information collected from the Swedish tax authorities, we calculate insiders' actual effective tax rates on dividends. With this unique dataset, we find a significant negative cross-sectional relationship between insiders' effective tax rates and dividend payout. This result is consistent with a tax-induced clientele effect for dividends. We also look at the impact of large block trades on dividends. We find that when insiders with zero effective taxes sell blocks. subsequent dividend payments are significantly more likely to decrease. This provides evidence that large shareholders are adjusting dividends for their individual tax Situations. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Holmen, Martin; Knopf, John D.; Peterson, Stefan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Socially responsible investment funds: Investor reaction to current and past returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benson, Kareii L.; Humphrey, Jacquelyn E.
This paper investigates and compares the determinants of fund flows for socially responsible investment (SRI) funds and conventional funds. We consider the impact of current and past measures of monthly and annual return on fund flow. The results suggest SRI fund flows are less sensitive to returns than conventional funds. Our model also shows that flow is persistent and SRI investors are more likely to invest in a fund they already own relative to conventional investors. These results reflect the difficulty SRI investors face in finding alternative investments that meet their non-financial goals. Crown Copyright (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benson, Kareii L.; Humphrey, Jacquelyn E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The diversification and financial performance of US credit unions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goddard, John; McKillop, Donal; Wilson, John O. S.
For US credit unions, revenue from non-interest sources has increased significantly in recent years. We investigate the impact of revenue diversification oil financial performance for the period 1993-2004. The impact of a change in strategy that alters the share of non-interest income is decomposed into a direct exposure effect. reflecting the difference between interest and non-interest bearing activities, and all indirect exposure effect which reflects the effect of the institution's own degree of diversification. On both risk-adjusted and unadjusted returns measures, a positive direct exposure effect is outweighed by a negative indirect exposure effect for all but the largest credit unions. This may imply that similar diversification strategies are not appropriate for large and small credit unions. Small credit unions Should eschew diversification and continue to operate as simple savings and 10 111 institutions. while large credit unions should be encouraged to exploit new product opportunities around their core expertise. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goddard, John; McKillop, Donal; Wilson, John O. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition versus efficiency: What drives franchise values in European banking?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Jonghe, Olivier; Vennet, Rudi Vander
This paper investigates how stock market investors perceive the impact of market Structure and efficiency oil the long-run performance potential of European banks. To that end, a modified Tobin's Q ratio is introduced Lis a measure of bank franchise value. This measure is applied to discriminate between the market structure and efficient-structure hypotheses in a coherent forward-looking framework, in which differences in banks' horizontal and vertical differentiation strategies are controlled for. The results show that banks with better management or production technologies possess it long-run competitive advantage. In addition, bank market concentration does not affect all banks equally. Only the banks with a large market share in a concentrated market are able to generate non-competitive re,its. The paper further documents that the forward-looking. long-run perspective and the noise-adjustment of the performance measure overcome most of the drawbacks associated with testing these hypotheses in a multi-country Set-Up. Finally. notwithstanding the international expansion of bank activities. the harmonization of regulation and the macroeconomic convergence in the European Union (EU 15), we still find that country-specific macroeconomic variables have a significant impact on bank performance. The findings indicate that there is a trade-off between competition and stability that Should be taken into account when assessing mergers or acquisitions. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Jonghe, Olivier; Vennet, Rudi Vander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can commodity futures be profitably traded with quantitative market timing strategies?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marshall, Ben R.; Cahan, Rochester H.; Cahan, Jared M.
Quantitative market timing strategies are not consistently profitable when applied to 15 major commodity futures series. We conduct the most comprehensive study of quantitative trading rules in this market setting to date. We consider Over 7000 rules. employ two alternative bootstrapping methodologies, account for data-snooping bias. and consider different time periods. We cannot rule out the possibility that trading rules compliment some other trading strategy or that some traders may have success using a specific rule on its own, but we do conclusively show that none of these rules beat the market any more than expected given random data variation. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marshall, Ben R.; Cahan, Rochester H.; Cahan, Jared M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal financial constraints, external financial constraints, and investment choice: Evidence from a panel of UK firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guariglia, Alessandra
This paper uses a panel of 24,184 UK. firms over the period 1993-2003 to Study the extent to which the sensitivity of investment to cash flow differs at firms facing different degrees of internal and external financial constraints. Our results Suggest that When the sample is split on the basis of the level of internal funds available to the firms, the relationship between investment and cash flow is U-shaped. On the other hand. the sensitivity of investment to cash flow tends to increase monotonically with the degree of external financial constraints faced by firms. Combining the internal with the external financial constraints, we find that the dependence of investment oil cash flow is strongest for those externally financially constrained firms that have a relatively high level of internal funds. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guariglia, Alessandra</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A flight to Q? Firm investment and financing in Korea before and after the 1997 financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rousseau, Peter L.; Kim, Jong Hun
We examine investment behavior among exchange-listed Korean manufacturing firms before and after the 1997 financial crisis using firm-level panel data. Starting with the standard Q-theory of investment, we augment it by allowing for a sales accelerator and the possibility of cash constraints, categorizing firms based on their age, size and affiliation to an industrial conglomerate (i.e., chaebol). We find that Tobin's Q is a robust determinant of investment in a pooled sample for 1992-2001, but that it became more important for small firms and less important for chaebol-affiliated firms after the crisis. Investment by chaebol firms also became more sensitive to the availability of internal cash balances after the crisis. We interpret this as reflecting a shift in the Korean economy to a stronger market orientation after the crisis and to a business climate in which the quality of potential projects became more important relative to capital market imperfections in determining the destination of investment funds. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rousseau, Peter L.; Kim, Jong Hun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate clustering in UK financial services markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ashton, John K.; Hudson, Robert S.
This study forwards an explanation and empirical investigation of price clustering in retail banking markets. It is proposed that price or interest rate clustering forms in retail markets as firms wish to maximise returns from customers, some of whom have difficulties in recalling and processing price information. This theory is developed and tested using a dataset of retail interest rates from the UK which enables interest rate clustering to be viewed in both lending and investment markets, and at different levels of financial involvement. It is found that interest rate clustering occurs in a manner consistent with firms maximising returns from customers. These findings are viewed to be a key policy concern for financial regulators and firms concerned with consumer protection. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ashton, John K.; Hudson, Robert S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal portfolios when volatility can jump</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branger, Nicole; Schlag, Christian; Schneider, Eva
We consider an asset allocation problem in a continuous-time model with stochastic volatility and jumps in both the asset price and its volatility. First, we derive the optimal portfolio for an investor with constant relative risk aversion. The demand for jump risk includes a hedging component, which is not present in models without volatility jumps. We further show that the introduction of derivative contracts can have substantial economic value. We also analyze the distribution of terminal wealth for an investor who uses the wrong model, either by ignoring volatility jumps or by falsely including such jumps, or who is subject to estimation risk. Whenever a model different from the true one is used, the terminal wealth distribution exhibits fatter tails and (in some cases) significant default risk. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Branger, Nicole; Schlag, Christian; Schneider, Eva</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary policy news and exchange rate responses: Do only surprises matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fatum, Rasmus; Scholnick, Barry
We use data from the Federal Funds Futures market to show that exchange rates respond to only the surprise component of an actual US monetary policy change and we illustrate that failure to disentangle the surprise component from the actual monetary policy change can lead to an underestimation of the impact of monetary policy, or even to a false rejection of the hypothesis that monetary policy impacts exchange rates. Unlike the recent contributions to the literature on exchange rates and monetary policy news, our testing method avoids the imposition of assumptions regarding exchange rate market efficiency. We also add to the debate on how quickly exchange rates respond to news by showing that the exchange rates under study absorb monetary policy surprises within the same day as the news are announced. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fatum, Rasmus; Scholnick, Barry</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit rating dynamics and Markov mixture models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frydman, Halina; Schuermann, Til
Despite mounting evidence to the contrary, credit migration matrices, used in many credit risk and pricing applications, are typically assumed to be generated by a simple Markov process. Based on empirical evidence, we propose a parsimonious model that is a mixture of (two) Markov chains, where the mixing is on the speed of movement among credit ratings. We estimate this model using credit rating histories and show that the mixture model statistically dominates the simple Markov model and that the differences between two models can be economically meaningful. The non-Markov property of our model implies that the future distribution of a firm's ratings depends not only on its current rating but also on its past rating history. Indeed we find that two firms with identical current credit ratings can have substantially different transition probability vectors. We also find that conditioning on the state of the business cycle or industry group does not remove the heterogeneity with respect to the rate of movement. We go on to compare the performance of mixture and Markov chain using out-of-sample predictions. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frydman, Halina; Schuermann, Til</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Practical methods for measuring and managing operational risk in the financial sector: A clinical study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chapelle, Ariane; Crama, Yves; Huebner, Georges; Peters, Jean-Philippe
This paper analyzes the implications of the advanced measurement approach (AMA) for the assessment of operational risk. Through a clinical case study on a matrix of two selected business lines and two event types of a large financial institution, we develop a procedure that addresses the major issues faced by banks in the implementation of the AMA. For each cell, we calibrate two truncated distributions functions, one for "normal" losses and the other for the "extreme" losses. In addition, we propose a method to include external data in the framework. We then estimate the impact of operational risk management on bank profitability, through an adapted measure of RAROC. The results suggest that substantial savings can be achieved through active management techniques. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chapelle, Ariane; Crama, Yves; Huebner, Georges; Peters, Jean-Philippe</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry and investment-cash flow sensitivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ascioglu, Asli; Hegde, Shantaram P.; McDermott, John B.
Models of capital market imperfections predict that information asymmetry decreases firm investment and increases the sensitivity of investment expenditures to fluctuations in internal funds. Previous empirical tests of the link between investment and financing decisions have relied on indirect measures of financial constraint due to market frictions. In contrast, we use more direct measures derived from the market microstructure literature. Consistent with the theoretical predictions, our analysis shows that scaled investment expenditures are on average lower and the investment-cash flow sensitivity is greater when the probability of informed trading is high. Our results are robust to alternative measures of informed trading and liquidity, but they are not pervasive in our sample. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ascioglu, Asli; Hegde, Shantaram P.; McDermott, John B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On measuring synchronization of bulls and bears: The case of East Asia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Candelon, Bertrand; Piplack, Jan; Straetmans, Stefan
This paper implements estimation and testing procedures for comovements of stock market "cycles" or "phases" in Asia. We extend the Harding and Pagan [Harding, D., Pagan, A.P., 2006. Synchronization of cycles. Journal of Econometrics 132 (1), 59-79] test for strong multivariate nonsynchronization (SMNS) between business cycles to a test that allows for an imperfect degree of multivariate synchronization between stock market cycles. Moreover, we propose a test for endogenously determining structural change in the bivariate and multivariate synchronization indices. Upon applying the technique to five Asian stock markets we find a significant increase in the cross country comovements of Asian bullish and bearish periods in 1997. A power study of the stability test suggests that the detected increase in comovement is more of a sudden nature (i.e. contagion or "Asian Flu") instead of gradual (i.e. financial integration). It is furthermore argued that stock market cycles and their propensity toward (increased) synchronization contain useful information for both investors, policy makers and financial regulators. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Candelon, Bertrand; Piplack, Jan; Straetmans, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regime dependent determinants of credit default swap spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Carol; Kaeck, Andreas
Credit default swap (CDs) spreads display pronounced regime specific behaviour. A Markov switching model of the determinants of changes in the iTraxx Europe indices demonstrates that they are extremely sensitive to stock volatility during periods of CDs market turbulence. But in ordinary market circumstances CDs spreads are more sensitive to stock returns than they are to stock volatility. Equity hedge ratios are three or four times larger during the turbulent period, which explains why previous research on single-regime models finds stock positions to be ineffective hedges for default swaps. Interest rate movements do not affect the financial sector iTraxx indices and they only have a significant effect on the other indices when the spreads are not excessively volatile. Raising interest rates may decrease the probability of credit spreads entering a volatile period. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, Carol; Kaeck, Andreas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank stock returns and economic growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cole, Rebel A.; Moshirian, Fariborz; Wu, Qiongbing
Previous research has established (i) that a country's financial sector influence future economic growth and (ii) that stock market index returns affect future economic growth. We extend and tie together these two strands of the growth literature by analyzing the relationship between banking industry stock returns and future economic growth. Using dynamic panel techniques to analyze panel data from 18 developed and 18 emerging markets, we find a positive and significant relationship between bank stock returns and future GDP growth that is independent of the previously documented relationship between market index returns and economic growth. We also find that much of the informational content of bank stock returns is captured by country-specific and institutional characteristics, such as bank-accounting-disclosure standards, banking crises, enforcement of insider trading law and government ownership of banks. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cole, Rebel A.; Moshirian, Fariborz; Wu, Qiongbing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Haezendonck risk measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bellini, Fabio; Gianin, Emanuela Rosazza
We study the Haezendonck risk measure (introduced by Haezendonck, J., Goovaerts, M., 1982. A new premium calculation principle based on Orlicz norms. Insurance: Mathematics and Economics 1, 41-53 and by Goovaerts, M.J., Kaas, R., Dhaene, J., Tang, Q., 2003. A unified approach to generate risk measures. ASTIN Bulletin 33 (2), 173-191; Goovaerts, M.J., Kaas, R., Dhaene, J., Tang, Q., 2004. Some new classes of consistent risk measures. Insurance: Mathematics and Economics 34 (3), 505-516) and prove its subadditivity. Since the Haezendonck risk measure is defined as an infimum of Orlicz premia, we investigate when the infimum is actually attained. We determine the corresponding generalized scenarios and show how its construction can be seen as a special case of the operation of inf-convolution of convex functionals. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bellini, Fabio; Gianin, Emanuela Rosazza</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal delegated portfolio management with background risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baptista, Alexandre M.
Most investors delegate the management of a fraction of their wealth to portfolio managers who are given the task of beating a benchmark. However, in an influential paper [Roll, R., 1992. A mean/variance analysis of tracking error. Journal of Portfolio Management 18, 13-22] shows that the objective functions commonly used by these managers lead to the selection of portfolios that are suboptimal from the perspective of investors. In this paper, we provide an explanation for the use of these objective functions based on the effect of background risk on investors' optimal portfolios. Our main contribution is to provide conditions under which investors can optimally delegate the management of their wealth to portfolio managers. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baptista, Alexandre M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership structure, corporate governance and analyst following: A study of French listed firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubaker, Sabri; Labegorre, Florence
This study investigates the effects of some characteristics of the French corporate governance model - deemed to foster entrenchment and facilitate private benefits extraction - on the extent of analyst following. The results show that analysts are more likely to follow firms both with high discrepancy level between ownership and control and those controlled through pyramiding. These findings provide empirical support to the argument that minority shareholders value private information on firms with high expropriation likelihood, asking thence for more analyst services. Additional findings show that analysts are reticent to follow firms managed by controlling family members. This is, in part, explained by these firms' reliance on private communication channels rather than public disclosure, producing a poor informational environment. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubaker, Sabri; Labegorre, Florence</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A tale of two prices: Liquidity and asset prices in multiple markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Justin S. P.; Hong, Dong; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.
This paper investigates the liquidity effect in asset pricing by studying the liquidity-premium relationship of an American depositary receipt (ADR) and its underlying share. Using the [Amihud, Yakov, 2002. Illiquidity and stock returns: cross-section and time series effects. Journal of Financial Markets 5, 31-56] measure, the turnover ratio and trading infrequency as proxies for liquidity, we show that a higher ADR premium is associated with higher ADR liquidity and lower home share liquidity, in terms of changes in these variables. We find that the liquidity effects remain strong after we control for firm size and a number of country characteristics, such as the expected change in the foreign exchange rate, the stock market performance, as well as several variables measuring the openness and transparency of the home market. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Justin S. P.; Hong, Dong; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of stock split announcements: Do options matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chern, Keh-Yiing; Tandon, Kishore; Yu, Susana; Webb, Gwendolyn
We provide a new test of the informational efficiency of trading in stock options in the context of stock split announcements. These announcements tend to be associated with positive abnormal returns. Our traditional event study results show abnormal returns that are significantly lower for optioned than non-optioned stocks, whether traded on the NYSE, Amex, or Nasdaq. After controlling for market returns, capitalization, book-to-market ratio, and trading volume, we find that the abnormal returns are significantly lower for NYSE/ Amex optioned than non-optioned stocks. Although the results for Nasdaq stocks are not as clear, the overall effects tend to be lower after optioning. These findings are consistent with the hypothesis that the prices of optioned stocks embody more information, diminishing the impact of the stock split announcement. They provide new evidence of the beneficial effects of options on their underlying stocks. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chern, Keh-Yiing; Tandon, Kishore; Yu, Susana; Webb, Gwendolyn</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank incentives and suboptimal lending decisions: Evidence from the valuation effect of bank loan announcements in Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Jun-Koo; Liu, Wei-Lin
Using a sample of bank loan announcements in Japan, we examine whether or not banks have incentives to engage in suboptimal lending that results in wealth transfer from the banks to the borrowing firms. We find that abnormal returns for borrowing firms are significantly positive, but those for lending banks are sometimes significantly negative. Furthermore, the announcement returns for borrowing firms are negatively related to those for lending banks, especially when poorly performing firms borrow from financially healthy (low-risk) banks. Our results suggest that the positive valuation effect of bank loan announcements for borrowing firms is mainly due to a wealth transfer from lending banks. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kang, Jun-Koo; Liu, Wei-Lin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>