<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF20</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Evaluating credit risk models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lopez, J. A.; Saidenberg, M. R.
Over the past decade, commercial banks have devoted many resources to developing internal models to better quantify their financial risks and assign economic capital. These efforts have been recognized and encouraged by bank regulators. Recently, banks have extended these efforts into the field of credit risk modeling. However, an important question for both banks and their regulators is evaluating the accuracy of a model's forecasts of credit losses, especially given the small number of available forecasts due to their typically long planning horizons. Using a panel data approach, we propose evaluation methods for credit risk models based on cross-sectional simulation. Specifically, models are evaluated not only on their forecasts over time, but also on their forecasts at a given point in time for simulated credit portfolios. Once the forecasts corresponding to these portfolios are generated, they can be evaluated using various statistical methods. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G2; G28; C52.</description><author>Lopez, J. A.; Saidenberg, M. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit risk rating systems at large US banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Treacy, W. F.; Carey, M.
Internal credit risk rating systems are becoming an increasingly important element of large commercial banks' measurement and management of the credit risk of both individual exposures and portfolios. This article describes the internal rating systems presently in use at the 50 largest US banking organizations. We use the diversity of current practice to illuminate the relationships between uses of ratings, different options for rating system design, and the effectiveness of internal rating systems. Growing stresses on rating systems make an understanding of such relationships important for both banks and regulators. (C) 2000 Published by Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G20; G21.</description><author>Treacy, W. F.; Carey, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stability of rating transitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nickell, P.; Perraudin, W.; Varotto, S.
The distribution of ratings changes plays a crucial role in many credit risk models. As is well-known, these distributions vary across time and different issuer types. Ignoring such dependencies may lead to inaccurate assessments of credit risk. In this paper, we quantify the dependence of rating transition probabilities on the industry and domicile of the obligor, and on the stage of the business cycle. Employing ordered probit models, we identify the incremental impact of these factors. Our approach gives a clearer picture of which conditioning factors are important than comparing transition matrices estimated from different sub-samples. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. C25; G21; G33.</description><author>Nickell, P.; Perraudin, W.; Varotto, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default rates in the syndicated bank loan market: A mortality analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altman, E. I.; Suggitt, H. J.
The most fundamental aspect of credit risk models is the rating of the underlying assets and the associated expected and unexpected migration patterns. The most important migration is to default. While default rate empirical studies of corporate bonds are now commonplace, there has never been a study on the default rate in the corporate bank loan market. This paper assesses, for the first time, the default rate experience on large, syndicated bank loans. The results are stratified by original loan rating using a mortality rate framework for the 1991-1996 period. We find that the mortality rates on bank loans are remarkably similar to that of corporate bonds when measured cumulatively over the five-year period after issuance, but loan default rates appear to be considerably higher than bonds for the first two years after issuance. Since loans have an average effective maturity of under two years, this shorter maturity difference is of considerable relevance, especially if confirmed when our database will cover a longer sample period and more actual defaults. We do attempt to estimate the impact and bias on our results of the study's sample period which only covers the recent benign credit cycle in the US. Our results provide important new information for assessing the risk of corporate loans not only for bankers but also mutual fund investors and analysts of structured financial products, credit derivatives and credit insurance. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G33; G21; G3.</description><author>Altman, E. I.; Suggitt, H. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comparative study of structural models of corporate bond yields: An exploratory investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, R.; Sundaresan, S.
This paper empirically compares a variety of firm-value-based models of contingent claims. We formulate a general model which nests versions of the models introduced by Merton (1974), Leland (1994), Anderson and Sundaresan (1996), and Mella-Barral and Perraudin (1997). We estimate these using aggregate time series data for the US corporate bond market, monthly, from August 1970 through December 1996. We find that models fit reasonably well, indicating that variations of leverage and asset volatility account for much of the time-series variations of observed corporate yields. The performance of the recently developed models which incorporate endogenous bankruptcy barriers is somewhat superior to the original Merton model. We find that the models produce default probabilties which are in line with the historical experience reported by Moodys. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G3; C51; G33.</description><author>Anderson, R.; Sundaresan, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The intersection of market and credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jarrow, R. A.; Turnbull, S. M.
Economic theory tells us that market and credit risks are intrinsically related to each other and not separable. We describe the two main approaches to pricing credit risky instruments: the structural approach and the reduced form approach. It is argued that the standard approaches to credit risk management - CreditMetrics, CreditRisk+ and KMV - are of limited value when applied to portfolios of interest rate sensitive instruments and in measuring market and credit risk. Empirically returns on high yield bonds have a higher correlation with equity index returns and a lower correlation with Treasury bond index returns than do low yield bonds. Also, macro economic variables appear to influence the aggregate rate of business failures. The CreditMetrics, CreditRisk+ and KMV methodologies cannot reproduce these empirical observations given their constant interest rate assumption. However, we can incorporate these empirical observations into the reduced form of Jarrow and Turnbull (1995b). Drawing the analogy. Risk 5, 63-70 model. Here default probabilities are correlated due to their dependence on common economic factors. Default risk and recovery rate uncertainty may not be the sole determinants of the credit spread. We show how to incorporate a convenience yield as one of the determinants of the credit spread. For credit risk management, the time horizon is typically one year or longer. This has two important implications, since the standard approximations do not apply over a one year horizon. First, we must use pricing models for risk management. Some practitioners have taken a different approach than academics in the pricing of credit risky bonds. In the event of default, a bond holder is legally entitled to accrued interest plus principal. We discuss the implications of this fact for pricing. Second, it is necessary to keep track of two probability measures: the martingale probability for pricing and the natural probability for value-at-risk. We discuss the benefits of keeping track of these two measures. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G28; G33; G2.</description><author>Jarrow, R. A.; Turnbull, S. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default risk in a market model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lotz, C.; Schlogl, L.
This paper presents a theoretical model of default risk in the context of the "market" model approach to interest rate dynamics. We propose a model for finite-interval interest rates (such as LIBOR) which explicitly takes into account the possibility of default through the influence of a point process with deterministic intensity. We relate the defaultable interest rate to the non-defaultable interest rate and to the credit risk characteristics default intensity and recovery rate. We find that the spread between defaultable and non-defaultable rate depends on the non-defaultable rate even when the default intensity is deterministic. Prices of a cap on the defaultable rate and of a credit spread option are derived. We consider swaps with unilateral and bilateral default risk and derive the fair fixed swap rate in both cases. Under the condition that both counterparties are of the same risk class, we show that for a monotonously increasing term structure the swap rate for a defaultable swap will lie below the swap rate for a swap without default risk. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G30; G33; E43.</description><author>Lotz, C.; Schlogl, L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determination of the adequate capital for default protection under the one-factor Gaussian term structure model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nakazato, D.
In practice, credit risk is measured by one of the two different methodologies. One measures the prices and sensitivities of the credit linked instruments. Another measures the required collateral or capital needed to cover a potential default loss. This paper introduces a pricing methodology, which also determines the required capital. Conventionally the value-at-risk method is used to determine collateral requirements. Artzner et al. demonstrated that the resulting adequate capital measures may fail to capture the credit diversification effect, which is critical in credit risk management. (cf Artzner, P., Delbaen, F., Eber, J.-M., Heath, D. 1997. Definition of coherent measures of risk. Paper presented at the Symposium on Risk Management, European Finance Association, Vienna, August 27-30). In order to overcome this problem, this paper introduces a new approach, which combines closed form solutions and the Hull-White trinomial tree. This combined approach is computationally faster than a naively implemented Monte-Carlo-based VAR methodology. The pricing model is based on the rating-based Gaussian term structure model developed by Nakazato. This approach is applicable to a wide variety of credit derivatives and their portfolios in a coherent fashion. In this paper, however, attention is concentrated on determining the collateral requirement for the counter party risk when there is the risk of credit rating change on an issue and also risk of default on that issue or on any protection already written on the issue. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G33; G21; E43.</description><author>Nakazato, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comparative anatomy of credit risk models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gordy, M. B.
Within the past two years, important advances have been made in modeling credit risk at the portfolio level. Practitioners and policy makers have invested in implementing and exploring a variety of new models individually. Less progress has been made, however, with comparative analyses. Direct comparison often is not straightforward, because the different models may be presented within rather different mathematical frameworks. This paper offers a comparative anatomy of two especially influential benchmarks for credit risk models, the RiskMetrics Group's CreditMetrics and Credit Suisse Financial Product's CreditRisk+. We show that, despite differences on the surface, the underlying mathematical structures are similar. The structural parallels provide intuition for the relationship between the two models and allow us to describe quite precisely where the models differ in functional form, distributional assumptions, and reliance on approximation formulae. We then design simulation exercises which evaluate the effect of each of these differences individually. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G31; C15; G11.</description><author>Gordy, M. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Emerging problems with the Basel Capital Accord: Regulatory capital arbitrage and related issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, D.
In recent years, securitization and other financial innovations have provided unprecedented opportunities for banks to reduce substantially their :regulatory capital requirements with little or no corresponding reduction in their overall economic risks a process termed "regulatory capital arbitrage". These methods are used routinely to lower the effective risk-based capital requirements against certain portfolios to levels well below the Basel Capital Accord's nominal 8% total risk-based capital standard. This paper discusses the principal techniques used to undertake capital arbitrage and the difficulties faced by bank supervisors in attempting to deal with these activities under the current capital framework. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G18; G21; G28.</description><author>Jones, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy implications of the Federal Reserve study of credit risk models at major US banking institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mingo, J. J.
The current regulatory capital standard for banks - the Basle Accord - is a lose/lose proposition. Regulators cannot conclude that a bank with a nominally high regulatory capital ratio has a correspondingly low probability of insolvency. On the other hand, because the Accord often levies a capital charge out of proportion to the true economic risk of a position, banks must engage in "regulatory capital arbitrage" (or exit their low risk business lines). Since such arbitrage is costly, the capital regulations keep banks from maximizing the value of the financial firm. Regulators need to answer three questions: (1) What are the goals of prudential regulation and supervision? (2) How should bank "soundness" be defined and quantified? (3) At what level should a minimum "soundness" standard be set in order to meet the (perhaps conflicting) goals of prudential regulation and supervision? possible answers to these questions are attempted, then the paper analyzes the two leading proposals for rationalizing the Accord - a "modified-Basle" (or ratings-based) approach and a "full-models" approach. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G2; G18; G28.</description><author>Mingo, J. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory implications of credit risk modelling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jackson, P.; Perraudin, W.
This introduction places in context the papers on credit risk modelling contained in the special issue. We explain why credit risk modelling has become such a focus of interest for practitioners and financial supervisors. Even though, as we explain, the current modelling technologies have significant weaknesses, they offer the possibility of major changes in the ways banks are managed and regulated. The main impediment to greater use of these models, especially by regulators, is the difficulty involved in back-testing the risk measures they produce. We suggest some thoughts on how back-testing and other types of model assessment might be performed. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; G28.</description><author>Jackson, P.; Perraudin, W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Fed beat the foreign-exchange market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sweeney, R. J.
This paper's estimates and tests of Fed intervention profits are the first that explicitly adjust for foreign-exchange risk premia; failure to adjust may grossly affect estimated profits. Profits appear economically and statistically significant, whether risk premia are modeled as time-constant or as appreciation's market beta depending on Fed intervention. The estimates are sensitive to the method of risk adjustment and to the periods used. Because a key variable, cumulative intervention, is I(1), test statistics may have non-standard distributions, a problem affecting past tests; this paper's tests account for non-standard distributions. Possible explanations of these profits have mixed empirical support in the literature. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification:F31; F33; G15; E58.</description><author>Sweeney, R. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regionalisation versus globalisation in European financial market integration: Evidence from co-integration analyses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kleimeier, S.; Sander, H.
Motivated by recent regulatory changes, this study investigates the degree of integration in retail lending in six core European Union (EU) countries using co-integration methodology which allows to investigate the presence and effects of structural breaks. While in the pre-break period we could detect integration to a limited degree, the evidence for integration weakened in the post-1992 period. This could however reflect a convergence process, particularly with respect to spreads. This result is clearly a regional, not a global phenomenon. As European lending rates are not yet fully integrated, the still segmented financial markets pose a challenge for a unified monetary policy. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: F36; G28; G15.</description><author>Kleimeier, S.; Sander, H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, contestability and market structure in European banking sectors on the eve of EMU</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Bandt, O.; Davis, E. P.
In order to assess the effect of EMU on market conditions for banks based in countries which adopt the Single Currency, we use the H indicator suggested by Panzer and Rosse (Panzar, J.C., Rosse, J.N., 1987, Journal of Industrial Economics 35, 443-456). Our contribution is to assess results separately for large and small banks, and for interest income and total income as a dependent variable. From a panel of banks over the period 1992-1996, we provide evidence that the behavior of large banks was not fully competitive as compared to the US. Regarding small banks, the level of competition appears to be even lower, especially in France and Germany. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; L12.</description><author>De Bandt, O.; Davis, E. P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank-firm relationships and allocative efficiency in Northeastern and Central Italy and in the South</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferri, G.; Messori, M.
We make two contributions on the extent and impact of relationship banking - based on close and long-lasting bank-firm customer relationships - in the three sub-systems in which Italy may be subdivided. First, we show that relationship banking is more extensive in both sub-systems where small businesses prevail: the fast-growing Northeast and Center (NEC) and the South, the marginal area of dependent development. Second, we demonstrate that relationship banking improves the allocation of credit in the NEC but worsens it in the South. This evidence suggests that relationship banking may be beneficial or detrimental depending on the socio-economic structure. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G21; O16.</description><author>Ferri, G.; Messori, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on nonstationarity, structural breaks, and the Fisher effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malliaropulos, D.
We find empirical evidence that inflation, nominal, and real interest rates in the US are trend-stationary with a structural break in both the unconditional mean and the drift rate of a deterministic trend, which occurs shortly after the change in operating procedures of the Fed in September 1979. This finding casts some doubts on cointegration tests of the long-run Fisher effect conducted in recent studies, since the results of these tests can be affected by the existence of common structural breaks in the series. We propose an alternative test of the Fisher effect, based on a VAR representation in appropriately detrended variables. We find strong support for the Fisher effect both in the medium term and in the long term. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: E43; G12; C22.</description><author>Malliaropulos, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of bank growth choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cyree, K. B.; Wansley, J. W.; Boehm, T. P.
We study the determinants of bank growth in a two-stage logistic regression model. We first compare banks that branch, Bank Acquire, or Product Expand with banks that do not grow externally. Banks that are federally chartered, in states with higher income growth, and with higher labor prices are less likely to grow externally. Larger banks are more likely to grow externally. In the second stage, we study determinants of growth activity for banks that expand products, branch, or acquire other banks. Depending on the time period, bank structure, regulatory environment, performance, and balance sheet characteristics determine bank growth choices. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; G34.</description><author>Cyree, K. B.; Wansley, J. W.; Boehm, T. P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross- and delta-hedges: Regression- versus price-based hedge ratios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sercu, P.; Wu, X. P.
In implementing a variance-minimizing cross or delta hedge, the regression coefficient is often estimated using data from the past, but one could also use estimators that are suggested by the random-walk or unbiased-expectations models and require just a single price. We compare the performances of various hedge ratios for three-month currency exposures, and find that the price-based hedge ratios generally perform better than the regression-based ones. Specifically, all our regressions do systematically worse in the case of a delta hedge, and seem to beat the price-based hedge ratios only in the case of cross- or cross-and-delta problems where the two currencies are so distantly related - like, e.g., hedging ITL/USD using JPY/USD - that no risk manager would even consider them as hedges of each other. The poor performance of the regressions is all the more surprising as we correct the futures prices for errors-in-variables (synchronization noise, bid-ask bounce, and changing time to maturity). The results are robust to observation frequency in the regressions, sample period, percentage vs dollar returns, and OLS versus IV. One reason why price-based methods do better is that they provide immediate adjustment to breaks in the data (like EMS realignments, which get incorporated into rolling regression coefficients only very slowly, as time elapses) or other events that change the relationship between the regressor and regressand. For cross or cross-and-delta hedges between European currencies, regressions also have difficulties in capturing cross-correlations between exchange rates. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G13; G15; F31.</description><author>Sercu, P.; Wu, X. P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market risk and the concept of fundamental volatility: Measuring volatility across asset and derivative markets and testing for the impact of derivatives markets on financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, S. S.; Satchell, S. E.
This paper proposes an unobserved fundamental component of volatility as a measure of risk. This concept of fundamental volatility may be more meaningful than the usual measures of volatility for market regulators. Fundamental volatility can be obtained using a stochastic volatility model, which allows us to 'filter' out the signal in the volatility information. We decompose four FTSE100 stock index related volatilities into transitory noise and unobserved fundamental volatility. Our analysis is applied to the question as to whether derivative markets destabilise asset markets. We find that introducing European options reduces fundamental volatility, while transitory noise in the underlying and futures markets does not show significant changes. We conclude that, for the FTSE100 index, introducing a new options market has stabilised both the underlying market and existing derivative markets. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. C32; G18.</description><author>Hwang, S. S.; Satchell, S. E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does central bank independence really matter? New evidence for developing countries using a new indicator</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Haan, J.; Kooi, W. J.
This paper provides a new indicator for central bank independence (CBI) based on the turnover rate of central bank governors for 82 developing countries over the period 1980-1989. Using this new indicator it is concluded that this proxy for CBI is related to inflation, only if the high inflation countries are included in the sample. The view that both CBI and inflation are caused by effective opposition towards inflation is not supported. Using both the extreme bound analysis and Sala-i-Martin's method we do not find evidence that CBI is robustly related to economic growth. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification E42; E58.</description><author>de Haan, J.; Kooi, W. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Avoiding bank runs in transition economies: The role of risk neutral capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gangopadhyay, S.; Singh, G.
In a general equilibrium model with risk neutral and risk averse agents, we show that if banks issue both demand deposits and equity, then free banking is run-proof and efficient. In particular, we obtain the first best insurance solution if there is adequate risk neutral capital. If sufficient risk neutral capital is unavailable, then a partial suspension of convertibility is optimal. In general, therefore, policies like capital adequacy norms and deposit insurance are neither necessary nor desirable. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G28; G21.</description><author>Gangopadhyay, S.; Singh, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Winners and losers from the introduction of continuous variable price trading: Evidence from the Riga Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kairys, J. P.; Kruza, R.; Kumpins, R.
This paper examines the impact from changing the trading mechanism at the Riga Stock Exchange (RSE). All three trading lists that once traded in a daily call auction followed by fixed price trading were transferred to a mechanism where the call auction is followed by continuous variable price trading sessions. We find that for stocks with high liquidity before the transfer, trading volumes more than doubled, while for stocks with low liquidity before the transfer, trading volumes fell to less than a quarter of their pretransfer levels. The functions of a stock market in providing price discovery and a secondary market for shares were eroded for more than half of the securities listed. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G15; G12; G14; G18.</description><author>Kairys, J. P.; Kruza, R.; Kumpins, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory lessons for emerging stock markets from a century of evidence on transactions costs and share price volatility in the London Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, C. J.; Maggioni, P.; Murinde, V.
This paper draws regulatory lessons for emerging stock markets from an empirical study of the relationship between transactions costs and share price volatility in the London Stock Exchange. We concentrate our analysis on direct pecuniary costs of trading, namely transactions taxes (stamp duty) and brokerage charges, which derive directly from regulation. In a novel contribution to the transactions cost literature, we identify stock market performance with various measures of market volatility, and distinguish among market volatility, fundamental volatility and excess volatility; we also propose some simple ways of identifying the separate impact of transactions costs on these volatility measures. Our findings suggest that changes in transactions costs have a significant and dependable effect on share price volatility but the sign of this effect depends critically on the concept of volatility being measured. Among the important lessons for emerging stock markets is that transactions costs are an important factor in share market volatility and the regulatory regime therefore needs to take account of the impact of regulation on such costs. This is particularly important for those emerging stock markets that rely on stamp duty or other transactions taxes as a regulatory tool. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G18.</description><author>Green, C. J.; Maggioni, P.; Murinde, V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency tests in the French derivatives market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, C. I.; Gleason, K. C.; Mathur, I.
The French derivatives market, the Marche a Terme International de France (MATIF) or the French International Futures and Options Exchange is one of the major derivatives markets in the world. The efficiency of four financial contracts traded on the MATIF-CAC40 Index Futures, ECU Bond Futures, National Bond Futures, and PIBOR 3-Month Futures are examined in this paper. Test results from serial correlations, unit root tests, and variance ratio tests provide overwhelming evidence that the random walk hypothesis cannot be rejected for these contracts. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G15; C22; G13.</description><author>Lee, C. I.; Gleason, K. C.; Mathur, I.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic competition in retail banking under expense preference behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Purroy, P.; Salas, V.
This paper presents a theoretical analysis of strategic competition in retail banking when some of the firms show expense preference behavior. The literature on expense preference behavior by banking firms is fairly large, but to our knowledge, so far, the strategic interaction between profit maximizing banks and banks with expense preference behavior has not been investigated. The paper has also an empirical interest since it is motivated by the current situation in Spanish retail banking where commercial banks, profit maximizers, compete with savings banks, non profit maximizers. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V, All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21.</description><author>Purroy, P.; Salas, V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and financial performance: A study of German and UK initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morgan, A.
nan</description><author>Morgan, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real options: Managing strategic investment in an uncertain world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnold, T.
nan</description><author>Arnold, T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulation of the Warsaw Stock Exchange: The portfolio allocation problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charemza, W. W.; Majerowska, E.
The paper analyses the risk reduction effect of limits which are imposed on stock exchange price movements. As a result of the maximisation of traders' utility functions subject to expected price constraints, a model similar to the capital asset pricing model (CAPM) is developed, where the observed returns are corrected for the appearance of constraints. An analysis of returns from six securities traded on the Warsaw Stock Exchange has been carried out. The models have been estimated by the two-limit Tobit model and compared with the results for the corrected returns. The results show that the trade barriers increase the portfolio risk. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G12.</description><author>Charemza, W. W.; Majerowska, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial system development in transition economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hermes, N.; Lensink, R.
This paper provides an overview of the major issues with respect to financial system development in transition economies, which were discussed at a conference in Groningen, the Netherlands, December 1997. After a brief remark on the role of financial system design during economic transition, the paper focuses on the role of stock markets in the process of financial intermediation with emphasis on the role of regulations in these markets, the role of deposit insurance to improve bank system stability, and the importance of an independent central bank, measurement issues relating to central bank independence and its impact on inflation and growth. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G20; G28; G33; E58; P34.</description><author>Hermes, N.; Lensink, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial regulation and financial system architecture in Central Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scholtens, B.
At the beginning of the transition, advice to Central European countries with respect to how to set up their financial systems was based on models used in western economies. This paper analyzes the experiences to set up a financial system in Central Europe. The experience in the first transition years (1990-1996) with financial system architecture shows that changes are slow but that the Central European countries tend to catch up more quickly with the western ones in the case of their banking systems than with respect to their stock markets. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G20; G28; P34.</description><author>Scholtens, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>