<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF11</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>A Bayesian approach to detecting nonlinear risk exposures in hedge fund strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannikis, Dimitrios; Vrontos, Ioannis D.
This paper proposes a model that allows for nonlinear risk exposures of hedge funds to various risk factors. We introduce a flexible threshold regression model and develop a Bayesian approach for model selection and estimation of the thresholds and their unknown number. In particular, we present a computationally flexible Markov chain Monte Carlo stochastic search algorithm which identifies relevant risk factors and/or threshold values. Our analysis of several hedge fund returns reveals that different strategies exhibit nonlinear relations to different risk factors, and that the proposed threshold regression model improves our ability to evaluate hedge fund performance. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giannikis, Dimitrios; Vrontos, Ioannis D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit risk transfer activities and systemic risk: How banks became less risky individually but posed greater risks to the financial system at the same time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nijskens, Rob; Wagner, Wolf
A main cause of the crisis of 2007-2009 is the various ways through which banks have transferred credit risk in the financial system. We study the systematic risk of banks before the crisis, using two samples of banks respectively trading Credit Default Swaps (CDS) and issuing Collateralized Loan Obligations (CLOs). After their first usage of either risk transfer method, the share price beta of these banks increases significantly. This suggests the market anticipated the risks arising from these methods, long before the crisis. We additionally separate this beta effect into a volatility and a market correlation component. Quite strikingly, this decomposition shows that the increase in the beta is solely due to an increase in banks' correlations. Thus, while banks may have shed their individual credit risk, they actually posed greater systemic risk. This creates a challenge for financial regulation, which has typically focused on individual institutions. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nijskens, Rob; Wagner, Wolf</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital requirements under the credit risk-based framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antao, Paula; Lacerda, Ana
This work aims to study the hypothesis of lower capitalization of banks under the risk-based rules introduced in Basel II. In this sense, an assessment of the impact of these rules on the capital requirements for non-financial firms' credit risk is performed. A comparison with Basel I is presented and intervals of variation for the risk drivers such that capital requirements exceed the ones under Basel I are established. Data for a European country supports the hypothesis of a smaller capitalization of banks under the risk-based framework, as far as credit risk in concerned. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Antao, Paula; Lacerda, Ana</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor rights and debt allocation within multinationals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akbel, Basak; Schnitzer, Monika
We analyze the optimal debt structure of multinational corporations choosing between centralized or decentralized borrowing. We identify how this choice is affected by creditor rights and bankruptcy costs, taking into account managerial incentives and coinsurance considerations. We find that partially centralized borrowing structures are optimal with either weak or strong creditor rights. For intermediate levels of creditor rights fully decentralized (centralized) borrowing structures are optimal if managers have strong (weak) empire-building tendencies. Decentralized borrowing is more attractive for companies focussing on short-term profitability. Credits are rather taken in countries with better creditor rights and more efficient insolvency systems. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akbel, Basak; Schnitzer, Monika</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product market pricing power, industry concentration and analysts' earnings forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Datta, Sudip; Iskandar-Datta, Mai; Sharma, Vivek
This is the first study to establish a link between product market power and analysts' earnings forecast accuracy and bias. Relating two different dimensions of market power to earnings forecastability, we document that (a) a firm's relative pricing power and (b) its industry concentration are strong positive determinants of analysts' earnings forecast accuracy. We find that forecasting earnings of higher market power firms is less complex due to their ability to withstand cost shocks as well as greater informational-efficiency enjoyed by such firms. Further, forecast optimism increases with weakening product market pricing power and with lower industry concentration. The knowledge derived from this study will hopefully improve the accuracy of equity valuation, and thereby engender better buy-side (stock selections) and sell-side recommendations by analysts. Our analysis also suggests that brokerage firms compensating analysts based on forecast accuracy need to adjust for the differential in the information complexity of different industries. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Datta, Sudip; Iskandar-Datta, Mai; Sharma, Vivek</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A computational approach to pricing a bank credit line</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stanhouse, Bryan; Schwarzkopf, Al; Ingram, Matt
Using trended Brownian motion to characterize borrower cash needs over time, we are able to derive a probability density function for the time to depletion of a bank credit line as well as the likelihoods for the time to exhausting the sources of liquidity that fund the loan. Armed with these analytic results, we solve for the credit line mark-up rate and the configuration of stored liquidity that maximizes the bank's intertemporal expected profits from the loan. The optimality conditions produce a system of integral differential equations whose solutions we then simulate over a host of scenarios. (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Stanhouse, Bryan; Schwarzkopf, Al; Ingram, Matt</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption-based CAPM models: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Darrat, Ali F.; Li, Bin; Park, Jung Chul
We examine the performance of several types of the consumption-based CAPM (C-CAPM) models to explore if consumption factors matter for determining excess returns across 17 MSCI country indexes. While the classic world C-CAPM does exhibit some power in explaining cross-sectional variations of expected excess returns, the model seems to require an implausibly large coefficient of risk aversion. The more sophisticated models including the heterogeneous C-CAPM, the world surplus consumption and the habit-formation models provide more reasonable estimates and add substantial explanatory power for the variation in the cross section of excess stock returns. Our results suggest that country-specific consumption risk is not fully diversified thus implying that stock returns are related to idiosyncratic consumption risk. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Darrat, Ali F.; Li, Bin; Park, Jung Chul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank-specific shocks and the real economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buch, Claudia M.; Neugebauer, Katja
Governments often justify interventions into the financial system in the form of bail outs or liquidity assistance with the systemic importance of large banks for the real economy. In this paper, we analyze whether idiosyncratic shocks to loan growth at large banks have effects on real GDP growth. We employ a measure of idiosyncratic shocks which follows Gabaix (forthcoming). He shows that idiosyncratic shocks to large firms have an impact on US GDP growth. In an application to the banking sector, we find evidence that changes in lending by large banks have a significant short-run impact on GDP growth. Episodes of negative loan growth rates and the Eastern European countries in our sample drive these results. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buch, Claudia M.; Neugebauer, Katja</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do lending relationships affect access to credit and loan conditions in microlending?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Behr, Patrick; Entzian, Annekathrin; Guettler, Andre
A key problem facing microlenders is the high level of information asymmetry between them and their borrowers. In this paper, we analyze whether the relationship intensity between microlenders and borrowers helps to overcome existing information asymmetries and how this impacts access to credit and loan contract terms. Using a rich loan-level data set provided by a microlender in Mozambique for the years 2000-2006, we find that access to credit improves and that the loan approval process takes less time when relationships become more intense. Borrowers further profit from a more intense relationship through lower guarantee requirements. All effects are more pronounced the more opaque the borrowers are. These results suggest that longer lending relationships indeed help to reduce information asymmetries and that this is beneficial for microborrowers. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Behr, Patrick; Entzian, Annekathrin; Guettler, Andre</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earned/contributed capital, dividend policy, and disclosure quality: An international study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, Paul; Unlu, Emre
We examine the agency cost version of the lifecycle theory of dividends by taking advantage of cross-country variations in disclosure environments. The outcome hypothesis posits that transparent disclosure environments lead to higher dividend payouts because shareholders can more accurately measure (and therefore demand) excess cash flows. In contrast, the substitute hypothesis argues that opaque disclosure environments lead to higher payouts because managers have stronger incentives to establish their reputation for fair treatment. Our empirical results confirm both hypotheses and contribute to the literature in two primary ways. First, we confirm that the lifecycle theory of dividends explains dividend payout patterns around the world. Second, and more important, we show that the firm's disclosure environment plays a significant role in dividend payouts through its effect on agency costs; that is, we confirm an agency cost-inclusive lifecycle theory of dividends. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brockman, Paul; Unlu, Emre</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who is the more overconfident trader? Individual vs. institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chuang, Wen-I.; Susmel, Rauli
Guided by the Gervais and Odean (2001) overconfident trading hypothesis, we comprehensively investigate the trading behavior of individual vs. institutional investors in Taiwan in an attempt to identify who is the more overconfident trader. Conditional on the various states of the market, on market volatility, and on the risk level of the securities they trade, we find that both individual and institutional investors trade more aggressively following market gains in bull markets, in up-market states, in up-momentum market states, and in low-volatility market states and that only individual investors trade more in riskier securities following market gains. More importantly, we find that individual investors trade more aggressively following market gains in the three conditional states of the market and in high-volatility market states than institutional investors. Also, individual investors trade more in relatively riskier securities following gains than institutional investors. These findings provide evidence that individual investors are more overconfident traders than institutional investors. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chuang, Wen-I.; Susmel, Rauli</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm survival and financial development: Evidence from a panel of emerging Asian economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsoukas, Serafeim
Using a panel of five Asian economies - Indonesia, Korea, Malaysia, Singapore and Thailand - over the period 1995-2007 we analyze the links between firm survival and financial development. We find that traditionally used measures of financial development play an important role in influencing firm survival. When stock markets become larger or more liquid firms' survival chances improve. On the contrary, we show that higher levels of financial intermediation can increase firm failures. We also find that the beneficial effects of stock market development are more pronounced during the later years of our sample, while the adverse effects of bank intermediation have declined over time. Finally, large firms are more likely to benefit from developments in financial markets compared to small firms. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tsoukas, Serafeim</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do financial markets care about SRI? Evidence from mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Cousin, Jean-Gabriel
Mergers and acquisitions offer a framework for shedding new light on the stock market performance of socially responsible investments (SRI). We use Innovest's Intangible Value Assessment (IVA) ratings as a measure of firms' ability to cope with social and environmental risks. The IVA ratings allow us to uncover a positive relation between acquirer gains and the level of the target's social and environmental risk management practices. Our findings suggest that the stock market rewards the acquirer for making socially and environmentally responsible investments. We also document that the environmental and social performance of the acquirer increases following the acquisition of a SRI aware target. These results are consistent with acquirer learning from the target's SRI practices and experiences. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Cousin, Jean-Gabriel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does debtor protection really protect debtors? Evidence from the small business credit market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Cerqueiro, Geraldo; Penas, Maria F.
This paper analyzes how different levels of debtor protection across US states affect small firms' access to credit, as well as the price and non-price terms of their loans. We use an individual-specific measure of debtor protection that has its maximum value when the borrower's home equity is lower than the state homestead exemption (the debtor's home equity is fully protected), and is decreasing in the difference between the home equity and the homestead exemption (the amount that the creditor can seize). We find that unlimited liability small businesses have lower access to credit in states with more debtor-friendly bankruptcy laws. In addition, these businesses face tighter loan terms - they are more likely to pledge business collateral, have shorter maturities, and borrow smaller amounts. For limited liability small businesses, we also find a reduction in credit availability, but of smaller magnitude, together with an increase in the loan rate. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Cerqueiro, Geraldo; Penas, Maria F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recovering copulas from limited information and an application to asset allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chu, Ba
This paper proposes an entropy-based method to construct a new class of copulas - the most entropic canonical copulas (MECC). Our empirical study focuses on an investment problem for an investor with a constant relative risk aversion (CRRA) utility function allocating wealth between the Dow Jones Large-Cap and Small-Cap indices, of which the contemporaneous dependence can be modeled by the MECC or other commonly-used copulas. Both the theoretical analysis of the method and the empirical study indicate the potential for enormous statistical and economic gains as a result of using the MECC. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chu, Ba</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Omega performance measure and portfolio insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertrand, Philippe; Prigent, Jean-luc
We analyze the performance of the two main portfolio insurance methods, the OBPI and CPPI strategies, using downside risk measures. For this purpose, we introduce Kappa performance measures and especially the Omega measure. These measures take account of the entire return distribution. We show that the CPPI method performs better than the OBPI. As a-by-product, we determine the set of threshold values for these risk/reward performance measures. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bertrand, Philippe; Prigent, Jean-luc</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinearly weighted convex risk measure and its application</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhiping; Yang, Li
We propose a new class of risk measures which satisfy convexity and monotonicity, two well-accepted axioms a reasonable and realistic risk measure should satisfy. Through a nonlinear weight function, the new measure can flexibly reflect the investor's degree of risk aversion, and can control the fat-tail phenomenon of the loss distribution. A realistic portfolio selection model with typical market frictions taken into account is established based on the new measure. Real data from the Chinese stock markets and American stock markets are used for empirical comparison of the new risk measure with the expected shortfall risk measure. The in-sample and out-of-sample empirical results show that the new risk measure and the corresponding portfolio selection model can not only reflect the investor's risk-averse attitude and the impact of different trading constraints, but can find robust optimal portfolios, which are superior to the corresponding optimal portfolios obtained under the expected shortfall risk measure. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Zhiping; Yang, Li</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the characteristics and performance of long-short, market-neutral and bear mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Badrinath, S. G.; Gubellini, S.
We evaluate the return performance of long-short, market-neutral and bear mutual funds using multi-factor models and a conditional CAPM that allows for time-varying risk. Differences in the bearish posture of these mutual funds result in different performance characteristics. Returns to long-short mutual funds vary with the market, returns to market-neutral mutual funds are uncorrelated with the market and returns to bear mutual funds are negatively correlated. Using the conditional CAPM we document significant changes in the market-risk exposure of the most bearish of these funds during different economic climates. We then assess the flow-performance relationship for up to 60 months following up and down markets and find that investors direct flows towards market-neutral and bearish funds for several months after down markets. Market-neutral funds provide a down market hedge, but bear funds do not generate the returns that investors hope for. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Badrinath, S. G.; Gubellini, S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comprehensive analysis of the effects of risk measures on bank efficiency: Evidence from emerging Asian countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Lei; Chang, Tzu-Pu
This study investigates the role of risk in determining the cost efficiency of international banks in eight emerging Asian countries. Researchers of this paper consider three distinct risk aspects under a total of eight risk measures: credit risk, operational risk, and market risk. We apply a heteroscedastic stochastic frontier model to estimate bank cost efficiency in our analysis. Additionally, this study analyzes the marginal effects of all risk measures on the inefficiency effect in order to explore a more detailed relationship between risks and efficiency. The empirical results indicate that the risk measures represent significant effects on both the level and variability of bank efficiency. We also find that these effects vary across countries and over time. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Lei; Chang, Tzu-Pu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long memory in volatility and trading volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleming, Jeff; Kirby, Chris
We use fractionally-integrated time-series models to investigate the joint dynamics of equity trading volume and volatility. Bollerslev and Jubinski (1999) show that volume and volatility have a similar degree of fractional integration, and they argue that this evidence supports a long-run view of the mixture-of-distributions hypothesis. We examine this issue using more precise volatility estimates obtained using high-frequency returns (i.e., realized volatilities). Our results indicate that volume and volatility both display long memory, but we can reject the hypothesis that the two series share a common order of fractional integration for a fifth of the firms in our sample. Moreover, we find a strong correlation between the innovations to volume and volatility, which suggests that trading volume can be used to obtain more precise estimates of daily volatility for cases in which high-frequency returns are unavailable. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fleming, Jeff; Kirby, Chris</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A closer look at financial development and income distribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gimet, Celine; Lagoarde-Segot, Thomas
This paper analyzes the under-investigated relationship uniting financial development and income distribution. We use a novel approach taking into account for the first time the specific channels linking banks, capital markets and income inequality, the time-varying nature of the relationship, and reciprocal causality. We construct a set of annual indicators of banking and capital market size, robustness, efficiency and international integration. We then estimate the determinants of income distribution using a panel Bayesian structural vector autoregressive (SVAR) model, for a set of 49 countries over the 1994-2002 period. We uncover a significant causality running from financial sector development to income distribution. In addition, the banking sector seems to exert a stronger impact on inequality. Finally, the relationship appears to depend on the characteristics of the financial sector, rather than on its size. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gimet, Celine; Lagoarde-Segot, Thomas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio insurance and prospect theory investors: Popularity and optimal design of capital protected financial products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dichtl, Hubert; Drobetz, Wolfgang
Portfolio insurance strategies are used on both the institutional and the retail side of the asset management industry. While standard utility theory struggles to provide an explanation, this study justifies the popularity of portfolio insurance strategies in a behavioral finance context. We run Monte Carlo simulations as well as historical simulations for popular portfolio insurance strategies and benchmark strategies in order to evaluate the outcomes using cumulative prospect theory. Our simulation results indicate that most portfolio insurance strategies are the preferred investment strategy for a prospect theory investor. Moreover, the analysis provides insights into how portfolio insurance products should be designed and structured to meet the preferences of prospect theory investors as accurately as possible. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dichtl, Hubert; Drobetz, Wolfgang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Founder CEO management and the long-run investment performance of IPO firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Ning; Jain, Bharat A.
This study provides a comparative analysis of the long-run investment performance of founder and non-founder CEO led IPO firms in high and low technology environments. We find weak evidence of superior long-run investment performance on the part of founder CEO led IPO firms, since the significance of the results are sensitive to choice of benchmark, portfolio weighting method, and factor regression model. However, in the context of high technology IPO firms, we find consistent evidence to indicate that founder CEO led firms provide significantly higher long-run returns relative to non-founder CEO led firms. Our results suggest that the unique nature of founder CEO leadership is particularly beneficial to IPO firms in high technology environments. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gao, Ning; Jain, Bharat A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic behavior within families of hedge funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolokolova, Olga
The paper investigates the strategic behavior of hedge fund families. It focuses on decisions to start and liquidate family-member funds. Hedge fund families tend to liquidate funds that underperform compared to other member funds, and to replace them by new ones. By choosing a launch time after a short period of superior performance by their member funds, families extend the spillover to new funds. Hedge fund families seem to be more experienced in promoting their funds and attracting fund inflow than in generating superior performance. This results in higher dollar compensation earned by managers within multi-fund families than in stand-alone funds. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kolokolova, Olga</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm specific and macro herding by professional and amateur investors and their effects on market volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Venezia, Itzhak; Nashikkar, Amrut; Shapira, Zur
We find a herding tendency among both amateur and professional investors and conclude that the propensity to herd is lower in the professionals. These results are obtained both when we consider herding into individual stocks and herding into stocks in general. Herding depends on the firm's systematic risk and size, and the professionals are less sensitive to these variables. The differences between the amateurs and the professionals may be attributable to the latter's superior financial training. Most of the results are consistent with the theory that herding is information-based. We also find that the herding behavior of the two groups is a persistent phenomenon, and that it is positively and significantly correlated with stock market returns' volatility. Finally, herding, mainly by amateurs, causes market volatility in the Granger causality sense. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Venezia, Itzhak; Nashikkar, Amrut; Shapira, Zur</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of corporate social responsibility on the cost of bank loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goss, Allen; Roberts, Gordon S.
This study examines the link between corporate social responsibility (CSR) and bank debt. Our focus on banks exploits their specialized role as delegated monitors of the firm. Using a sample of 3996 loans to US firms, we find that firms with social responsibility concerns pay between 7 and 18 basis points more than firms that are more responsible. Lenders are more sensitive to CSR concerns in the absence of security. We document a mixed reaction to discretionary CSR investments. Low-quality borrowers that engage in discretionary CSR spending face higher loan spreads and shorter maturities, but lenders are indifferent to CSR investments by high-quality borrowers. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goss, Allen; Roberts, Gordon S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial responses to incentives: Control of firm risk, derivative pricing implications, and outside wealth management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hodder, James E.; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten
We model a firm's value process controlled by a manager maximizing expected utility from restricted shares and employee stock options. The manager also controls allocation of his outside wealth, which allows partially hedging of his exposure to firm risk. Managerial control increases the expected time to exercise for his employee stock options. It also reduces the gap between his certainty equivalent and the firm's Fair Value for his compensation, but that gap remains substantial. Managerial control also causes traded options to exhibit an implied volatility smile. With costly control the same basic patterns ;remain, but the manager's risk-taking is dampened. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hodder, James E.; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility components, leverage effects, and the return-volatility relations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Junye
This paper investigates the risk-return trade-off by taking into account the model specification problem. Market volatility is modeled to have two components, one due to the diffusion risk and the other due to the jump risk. The model implies Merton's ICAPM in the absence of leverage effects, whereas the return-volatility relations are determined by interactions between risk premia and leverage effects in the presence of leverage effects. Empirically, I find a robust negative relationship between the expected excess return and the jump volatility and a robust negative relationship between the expected excess return and the unexpected diffusion volatility. The latter provides an indirect evidence of the positive relationship between the expected excess return and the diffusion volatility. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Junye</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do ESOPs enhance firm performance? Evidence from China's reform experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Meng, Rujing; Ning, Xiangdong; Zhou, Xianming; Zhu, Hongquan
China introduced employee stock ownership plans (ESOPs) in 1992 purely as an employee incentive scheme. The government initiated the policy experiment on ESOPs as part of China's reform of its state-owned enterprises, and it was abruptly terminated 2 years after initiation. This policy experiment resulted in an exogenous sample of ESOPs that allows us to provide the first evidence from Chinese firms on the performance-ESOP relation. After examining a variety of performance measures, including ROA, ROE, Tobin's q, and productivity, we find little difference in performance between ESOP firms and non-ESOP firms. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Meng, Rujing; Ning, Xiangdong; Zhou, Xianming; Zhu, Hongquan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market discipline, financial crisis and regulatory changes: Evidence from Indonesian banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hadad, Muliaman D.; Agusman, Agusman; Monroe, Gary S.; Gasbarro, Dominic; Zumwalt, James Kenton
Following the 1997/1998 financial crisis, Indonesian banks experienced major regulatory changes, including the adoption of the blanket guarantee scheme (BGS) in 1998, a limited guarantee (LG) in 2005, and changes in capital regulation in 1998 and 2001. We examine the impact of these regulatory changes on market discipline during the period 1995-2009. The price of deposits is used to measure market discipline in a dynamic panel data methodology on a sample of 104 commercial banks. We find a weakening of market discipline following the introduction of the BGS. The result is consistent with the deposit insurance scheme being credible in the lower capital requirement environment. The adoption of LG in a recovering economy also mitigates the role of market discipline. However, market discipline is more pronounced in listed banks than unlisted banks and in foreign banks than domestic banks. These results have important implications for banking regulation and supervision, particularly during a crisis period. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hadad, Muliaman D.; Agusman, Agusman; Monroe, Gary S.; Gasbarro, Dominic; Zumwalt, James Kenton</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the sources of private information in FX markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moore, Michael J.; Payne, Richard
We investigate the source of information advantage in inter-dealer FX trading using data on trades and counter-party identities. In liquid dollar exchange rates, information is concentrated among dealers that trade most frequently and specialize their activity in a particular rate. In cross-rates, traders that engage in triangular arbitrage are best informed. Better-informed traders are also located on larger trading floors. In cross-rates, the ability to forecast flows explains all of the advantage of the triangular arbitrageurs. In liquid dollar rates, specialist traders can forecast both order-flow and the component of exchange rate changes that is uncorrelated with flow. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moore, Michael J.; Payne, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Omitted debt risk, financial distress and the cross-section of expected equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aretz, Kevin; Shackleton, Mark B.
The study of Ferguson and Shockley (2003) shows that, if the Merton (1974) model can reflect reality, the omission of debt claims from the market portfolio proxy may explain the poor pricing ability of the CAPM in empirical tests. We critically re-assess this argument by first reviewing existing, but also new avenues through which the Merton (1974) model can point to a systematic bias in market beta estimates. However, we also show that some avenues are diversifiable, and that they all rely on excessive economy-wide default risk to create a non-negligible bias. We then use the Merton (1974) model to proxy for the total debt portfolio, but find that its application in empirical tests cannot improve pricing performance. We conclude that there are (so far) no valid theoretical reasons to believe that omitted debt claims undermine CAPM tests. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aretz, Kevin; Shackleton, Mark B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership structure and risk in publicly held and privately owned banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barry, Thierno Amadou; Lepetit, Laetitia; Tarazi, Amine
Using detailed ownership data for a sample of European commercial banks, we analyze the link between ownership structure and risk in both privately owned and publicly held banks. We consider five categories of shareholders that are specific to our dataset. We find that ownership structure is significant in explaining risk differences but mainly for privately owned banks. A higher equity stake of either individuals/families or banking institutions is associated with a decrease in asset risk and default risk. In addition, institutional investors and non-financial companies impose the riskiest strategies when they hold higher stakes. For publicly held banks, changes in ownership structure do not affect risk taking. Market forces seem to align the risk-taking behavior of publicly held banks, such that ownership structure is no longer a determinant in explaining risk differences. However, higher stakes of banking institutions in publicly held banks are associated with lower credit and default risk. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barry, Thierno Amadou; Lepetit, Laetitia; Tarazi, Amine</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency and risk in European banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fiordelisi, Franco; Marques-Ibanez, David; Molyneux, Phil
We assess the inter-temporal relationship between bank efficiency, capital and risk in a sample of European commercial banks employing several definitions of efficiency, risk and capital and using the Granger-causality methodology in a panel data framework. Our results suggest that lower bank efficiency with respect to costs and revenues Granger-causes higher bank risk and that increases in bank capital precede cost efficiency improvements. We also find that more efficient banks eventually become better capitalized and that higher capital levels tend to have a positive effect on efficiency levels. These results are generally confirmed by a series of robustness tests. The results have potentially important implications for bank prudential supervision and underline the importance of attaining long-term efficiency gains to support financial stability objectives. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fiordelisi, Franco; Marques-Ibanez, David; Molyneux, Phil</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firms' debt-equity decisions when the static tradeoff theory and the pecking order theory disagree</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Jong, Abe; Verbeek, Marno; Verwijmeren, Patrick
This paper tests the static tradeoff theory against the pecking order theory. We focus on an important difference in prediction: the static tradeoff theory argues that a firm increases leverage until it reaches its target debt ratio, while the pecking order yields debt issuance until the debt capacity is reached. We find that for our sample of US firms the pecking order theory is a better descriptor of firms' issue decisions than the static tradeoff theory. In contrast, when we focus on repurchase decisions we find that the static tradeoff theory is a stronger predictor affirms' capital structure decisions. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Jong, Abe; Verbeek, Marno; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inherited or earned? Performance of foreign banks in Central and Eastern Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Havrylchyk, Olena; Jurzyk, Emilia
In this study, using a combination of propensity score matching and difference-in-difference techniques, we investigate the impact of foreign bank ownership on the performance and market power of acquired banks operating in Central and Eastern Europe. This approach allows us to control for a selection bias as larger but less profitable banks were more likely to be acquired by foreign investors. We show that during 3 years after takeover, banks become more profitable owing to cost minimization and better risk management. They also gained market share due to passing their lower cost of funds to borrowers in terms of lower lending rates. Previous studies failed to note the improvements in the performance of takeover banks because they did not account for the selection bias. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Havrylchyk, Olena; Jurzyk, Emilia</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The rise of risk-based pricing of mortgage interest rates in Italy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Magri, Silvia; Pico, Raffaella
This paper assesses how much mortgage interest rates in Italy are priced on credit risk as proxied by the probability of household mortgage delinquency estimated using the EU-Silc database. Owing to data availability, we restrict the analysis of mortgage pricing to Italian households. Consistent with the more widespread use of credit scoring, estimates indicate that Italian lenders have increasingly priced mortgage interest rates on household credit risk. For mortgages granted between 2000 and 2007, we find that a 1% point increase in the probability of default is associated with a 21 basis point rise in mortgage interest rates, lower than the 38 basis point premium Edelberg (2006) estimated for the US at the end of the 1990s. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Magri, Silvia; Pico, Raffaella</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic news, announcements, and stock market jump intensity dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gonzalo Rangel, Jose
This paper examines the effect of macroeconomic releases on stock market volatility through a Poisson-Gaussian-GARCH process with time-varying jump intensity, which is allowed to respond to such information. The day of the announcement, per se, is found to have little impact on jump intensities. Employment releases are an exception. However, when macroeconomic surprises are considered, inflation shocks show persistent effects while monetary policy and employment shocks reveal only short-lived effects. Also, the jump intensity responds asymmetrically to macroeconomic shocks. Evidence on macroeconomic variables relevance in explaining jump dynamics and improving volatility forecasts on event days is provided. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gonzalo Rangel, Jose</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The power of bad: The negativity bias in Australian consumer sentiment announcements on stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhtar, Shumi; Faff, Robert; Oliver, Barry; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
This paper examines the equity market reaction to the monthly release of Australian consumer sentiment news. Our results indicate that consumer sentiment has valuable information content. Further, we document a version of the "negativity effect" (from the psychology literature) in which, upon announcement of bad (good) sentiment news, the equity market experiences a significant negative (no) announcement day effect. Notably, we find that the market recovers from the bad news shock relatively quickly post-announcement. The results are robust to a broad range of additional tests. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akhtar, Shumi; Faff, Robert; Oliver, Barry; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial integration and emerging markets capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucey, Brian M.; Zhang, QiYu
This paper investigates the impact of country-level financial integration on corporate financing choices in emerging economies. Examining 4477 public firms from 24 countries, we find that corporate leverage is positively related to credit market integration and negatively related to equity market integration. As integration proceeds to higher levels, high-growth firms seem to obtain more debt than low-growth firms; large firms seem to obtain more debt - especially long-term debt - and issue more equity than small firms. Also, there is evidence that firms are able to borrow more funds in countries with more efficient legal systems during integration process. (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Lucey, Brian M.; Zhang, QiYu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does more information in stock price lead to greater or smaller idiosyncratic return volatility?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Dong Wook; Liu, Mark H.
We investigate the relation between price informativeness and idiosyncratic return volatility in a multi-asset, multi-period noisy rational expectations equilibrium. We show that the relation between price informativeness and idiosyncratic return volatility is either U-shaped or negative. Using several price informativeness measures, we empirically document a U-shaped relation between price informativeness and idiosyncratic return volatility. Our study therefore reconciles the opposing views in the following two strands of literature: (1) the growing body of research showing that firms with more informative stock prices have greater idiosyncratic return volatility, and (2) the studies arguing that more information in price reduces idiosyncratic return volatility. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Dong Wook; Liu, Mark H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price determinants of Aboriginal art, and its role as an alternative asset class</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Dominic; Coleman, Les
This paper analyzes auction results for over 4000 paintings by Australian Aboriginal artists to investigate determinants of prices in the Aboriginal art market. This is the first financial study of an indigenous art market, and hedonic, repeat sales and hybrid regression analyses find it shares price determinants with traditional art markets (with price premia attached to artist name, death, painting size, leading auction house, and winter sale). However, Aboriginal art's unique features significantly affect prices, particularly works that use traditional Aboriginal media and those with reputation-affirming traits. An Aboriginal Art Index provides 6.6% annual return (standard deviation 17.9%), which is comparable to traditional asset classes and superior on a risk-adjusted basis. Returns to Aboriginal art are negatively correlated with returns from other assets, and so it adds value to a diversified investment portfolio. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Taylor, Dominic; Coleman, Les</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank size and risk-taking under Basel II</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hakenes, Hendrik; Schnabel, Isabel
We analyze the relationship between bank size and risk-taking under the Basel II Capital Accord. Using a model with imperfect competition and moral hazard, we show that the introduction of an internal ratings based (IRB) approach improves upon flat capital requirements if the approach is applied uniformly across banks and if the costs of implementation are not too high. However, the banks' right to choose between the standardized and the IRB approaches under Basel II gives larger banks a competitive advantage and, due to fiercer competition, pushes smaller banks to take higher risks. This may even lead to higher aggregate risk-taking. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hakenes, Hendrik; Schnabel, Isabel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparing different explanations of the volatility trend</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rubin, Amir; Smith, Daniel R.
We analyze the puzzling behavior of the volatility of individual stock returns over the past few decades. The literature has provided many different explanations to the trend in volatility and this paper tests the viability of the different explanations. Virtually all current theoretical arguments that are provided for the trend in the average level of volatility over time lend themselves to explanations about the difference in volatility levels between firms in the cross-section. We therefore focus separately on the cross-sectional and time-series explanatory power of the different proxies. We fail to find a proxy that is able to explain both dimensions well. In particular, we find that Cao et al. [Cao, C., Simin, T.T., Zhao, J., 2008. Can growth options explain the trend in idiosyncratic risk? Review of Financial Studies 21, 2599-2633] market-to-book ratio tracks average volatility levels well, but has no cross-sectional explanatory power. On the other hand, the low-price proxy suggested by Brandt et al. [Brandt, M.W., Bray, A., Graham, J.R., Kumar, A., 2010. The idiosyncratic volatility puzzle: time trend or speculative episodes. Review of Financial Studies 23, 863-899] has much cross-sectional explanatory power, but has virtually no time-series explanatory power. We also find that the different proxies do not explain the trend in volatility in the period prior to 1995 (R-squared of virtually zero), but explain rather well the trend in volatility at the turn of the Millennium (1995-2005). (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rubin, Amir; Smith, Daniel R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting the expectations hypothesis of the term structure of interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bulkley, George; Harris, Richard D. F.; Nawosah, Vivekanand
The expectations hypothesis of the term structure has been decisively rejected in a large empirical literature that spans several decades. In this paper, using a newly constructed dataset of synthetic zero-coupon bond yields, we show that evidence against the expectations hypothesis is substantially weaker in data generated after the widespread publicity of its failure. These results are consistent with the idea that asset pricing anomalies tend to disappear once they are widely recognized. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bulkley, George; Harris, Richard D. F.; Nawosah, Vivekanand</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-parametric frontier estimates of mutual fund performance using C- and L-moments: Some specification tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kerstens, Kristiaan; Mounir, Amine; Van de Woestyne, Ignace
There is a burgeoning literature using non-parametric frontier methods to measure mutual fund performance. These articles measure the relationship between the various characteristics (mainly return information and some costs of ownership) of these specialized financial products to establish a ranking using some efficiency measure. We argue in favor of the use of the shortage function, which is compatible with general investor preferences, and question some of the often maintained hypotheses in this line of research. The empirical part employs a large database of US and European mutual funds to offer extensive tests of the underlying modeling assumptions using various frontier estimators. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kerstens, Kristiaan; Mounir, Amine; Van de Woestyne, Ignace</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The diversification effects of volatility-related assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hsuan-Chi; Chung, San-Lin; Ho, Keng-Yu
We examine whether investors can improve their investment opportunity sets through the addition of volatility-related assets into various groupings of benchmark portfolios. By first analyzing the weekly returns of three VIX-related assets over the period 1996-2008 and then applying mean-variance spanning tests, we find that adding VIX-related assets does lead to a statistically significant enlargement of the investment opportunity set for investors. Our empirical findings are robust and have two implications. First, there is scope for the further development of financial products relating to volatility indexes. Second, hedge fund managers can utilize VIX futures contracts or VIX-squared portfolios to enhance their equity portfolio performance, as measured by the Sharpe ratio. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Hsuan-Chi; Chung, San-Lin; Ho, Keng-Yu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can broker-dealer client surveys provide signals for debt investing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrade, Sandro C.; Barrett, W. Brian
We use a novel data set to study return predictability in debt markets. The data are collected from J.P. Morgan's periodic surveys on its clients' outlook for changes in US Treasury yields and corporate credit spreads. We document that simple signals constructed from such surveys predict excess returns on debt portfolios formed on the basis of duration (2-years minus zero) or credit quality (BBB minus AAA). A linear trading strategy placing equal weight on Treasury and Credit signals has an annualized Information Ratio equal to 1.18, before transaction costs. We also show that predictability is likely to stem from private information possessed by survey respondents rather than from risk premia. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andrade, Sandro C.; Barrett, W. Brian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How accurate is the square-root-of-time rule in scaling tail risk: A global study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Jying-Nan; Yeh, Jin-Huei; Cheng, Nick Ying-Pin
The square-root-of-time rule (SRTR) is popular in assessing multi-period VaR; however, it makes several unrealistic assumptions. We examine and reconcile different stylized factors in returns that contribute to the SRTR scaling distortions. In complementing the use of the variance ratio test, we propose a new intuitive subsampling-based test for the overall validity of the SRTR. The results indicate that serial dependence and heavy-tailedness may severely bias the applicability of SRTR, while jumps or volatility clustering may be less relevant. To mitigate the first-order effect from time dependence, we suggest a simple modified-SRTR for scaling tail risks. By examining 47 markets globally, we find the SRTR to be lenient, in that it generally yields downward-biased 10-day and 30-day VaRs, particularly in Eastern Europe, Central-South America, and the Asia Pacific. Nevertheless, accommodating the dependence correction is a notable improvement over the traditional SRTR. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Jying-Nan; Yeh, Jin-Huei; Cheng, Nick Ying-Pin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding seasoned equity offerings of Chinese firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bo, Hong; Huang, Zhongnan; Wang, Changyun
We examine the empirical relevance of standard theories explaining the motivation of Seasoned Equity Offerings (SEOs) in the Chinese context. Analyzing Chinese SEOs during 1994-2008 and controlling for other factors reflecting features of Chinese corporate finance, we find that Chinese SEOs are mostly motivated by timing the market. Financing for investment and growth receives weak empirical support. We do not obtain any consistent evidence supporting both the tradeoff and the agency theories. In addition, we find that the firm's SEOs behavior varies between rights issues and public offerings and across different periods along with the progress of China's market transition. Our results show that Chinese listed firms in general behave similarly as their counterparts in other countries concerning SEOs decisions in that they issue SEOs when there are opportunities to take advantage of market overvaluation. These results are consistent with the well-documented convergence trend of corporate SEOs behavior of firms around the world. In addition, our findings challenge the conventional perception on Chinese SEOs that controlling shareholders use SEOs as a means to expropriate minority shareholders. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bo, Hong; Huang, Zhongnan; Wang, Changyun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investigating sources of unanticipated exposure in industry stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bredin, Don; Hyde, Stuart
This paper investigates the sources of both foreign exchange rate and interest rate exposure of industry level portfolios in the G7, decomposing exposure into cash flow and discount rate effects. Initial examination of the degree of exposure on industry returns produces results consistent with the prior literature: that there is little evidence of exchange rate exposure in most industries - the exchange rate exposure puzzle. However, rather than relying solely on the sensitivity of industry returns, we examine the cash flow sensitivity to foreign exchange exposure, of primary interest to firm managers. Critically, decomposing the exposure into cash flow and discount rate components unlocks the exact extent and nature of exposure. Our results show industries have significant cash flow and discount rate exposures. These exposures increase with the level of trade openness and the spread between permanent cash flow exposure and transitory discount rate exposure widens. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bredin, Don; Hyde, Stuart</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing financial contagion in the interbank market: Maximum entropy versus observed interbank lending patterns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mistrulli, Paolo Emilio
Interbank markets allow banks to cope with specific liquidity shocks. At the same time, they may represent a channel for contagion as a bank default may spread to other banks through interbank linkages. This paper analyses how contagion propagates within the Italian interbank market using a unique data set including actual bilateral exposures. Based on the availability of information on actual bilateral exposures for all Italian banks, the results obtained by assuming the maximum entropy are compared with those reflecting the observed structure of interbank claims. The comparison indicates that, under certain circumstances, depending on the structure of the interbank linkages, the recovery rates of interbank exposures and banks' capitalisation, the maximum entropy approach overrates the scope for contagion. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mistrulli, Paolo Emilio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advantageous innovation and imitation in the underwriting market for corporate securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herrera, Helios; Schroth, Enrique
Investment banks that develop new corporate securities systematically lead the new underwriting market despite being imitated early by equally competitive rivals. We study how innovators and imitators set underwriting fees in order to identify empirically the source of this advantage. Using data of innovative securities since 1985, we do find that innovators set systematically higher fees than imitators. This premium decreases as more issues occur, and faster for later generation products. Imitation is also quicker for later generations. This evidence supports the hypothesis that the innovator has superior skills in structuring any given issue of the new security. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Herrera, Helios; Schroth, Enrique</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market structure and the pass-through of the federal funds rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Robert M.; Amel, Dean F.
We study the effect of local market bank concentration on business loan originations and on the pass-through of the federal funds rate to business loan originations. Economic theory on the relationship between concentration and the pass-through of input prices to quantity (or price) is ambiguous. We find that more concentrated markets have lower business loan originations and experience smaller changes in business loan originations in response to changes in the federal funds rate. Our results support the idea that market concentration dampens quantity reactions to input price changes. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Adams, Robert M.; Amel, Dean F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identification of speculative bubbles using state-space models with Markov-switching</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Al-Anaswah, Nael; Wilfling, Bernd
In this paper we use a state-space model with Markov-switching to detect speculative bubbles in stock-price data. To this end we express a present-value stock-price model in state-space form which we estimate using the Kalman filter. This procedure enables us to estimate a two-regime Markov-switching specification of the unobservable bubble process. The respective Markov-regimes represent two distinct phases in the bubble process, namely one in which the bubble survives and one in which it collapses. We ultimately identify bursting stock-price bubbles by statistically separating both Markov-regimes from each other. In an empirical analysis we apply our methodology to a plethora of artificial and real-world data sets. Our study has two major findings. First, we find significant Markov-switching structures in real-world stock-price bubbles. Second, in the stock markets considered our identification procedure correctly detects most speculative periods which have been classified as such by economic historians. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Al-Anaswah, Nael; Wilfling, Bernd</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the "Bund" dominate price discovery in Euro bond futures? Examining information shares</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fricke, Christoph; Menkhoff, Lukas
This paper examines the relative information shares of the Bund, i.e. the 10-year Euro bond future contract on German sovereign debt, versus two futures with shorter maturity. We find that the Bund is most important but does not dominate price discovery. The other contracts also have relevant - and at many days even higher - information shares. In examining determinants of information shares, we add order flow measures to market state variables and macroeconomic news. More order flow in a contract consistently increases this contract's information share. (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Fricke, Christoph; Menkhoff, Lukas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of co-managers in reducing flotation costs: Evidence from seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jeon, Jin Q.; Ligon, James A.
We examine the effect on expected flotation costs of including co-managers in the underwriting syndicate. We consider five components of SEO flotation costs: announcement returns, underpricing, the probability of withdrawals, offering delays, and underwriting spreads. The results show that the characteristics of co-managers participating in syndicates have significant effects on flotation costs, while the effect of the number of co-managers is largely insignificant. Our results are consistent with the notion that highly reputable underwriters and commercial banks serving as co-managers serve a certification role, reducing information asymmetries and, as a result, lowering SEO flotation costs. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jeon, Jin Q.; Ligon, James A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A conditional asset-pricing model with the optimal orthogonal portfolio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asgharian, Hossein
This paper employs a conditional asset-pricing model based on the optimal orthogonal portfolio approach to construct a factor portfolio that embodies all the latent factors important for pricing a given set of test assets. The advantage of this portfolio to the anomaly related mimicking portfolios is its ability to separate out the components of average return that are not related to the return covariation. The performance of this portfolio is evaluated against several conventional factors, using both cross-sectional and time-series regression approaches, as well as the Hansen and Jagannathan (1997) distance measure. Its strong out-of-sample results indicate that our suggested methodology may have important applications in risk management, portfolio selection and performance evaluation. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asgharian, Hossein</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst characteristics, timing of forecast revisions, and analyst forecasting ability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Yongtae; Lobo, Gerald J.; Song, Minsup
We first examine whether analysts with certain characteristics that prior research has identified are related to superior forecasting ability systematically time their forecast revisions later in the fiscal quarter. We then examine whether this superior ability persists after controlling for the timing advantage by using relative forecast error, a measure that largely eliminates the timing advantage of recent forecasts. Using a sample of quarterly earnings forecast revisions over the 20-year period from 1990 to 2009, we find that analysts with more firm-specific and general experience and more accurate prior-period forecasts, analysts employed by larger brokerage firms, and analysts who follow fewer industries and companies tend to revise forecasts later in the quarter. We also find that analyst characteristics that are positively correlated with revision timing are negatively related to relative forecast errors. These results are consistent with analyst characteristics being useful proxies for analyst forecasting ability and analysts with greater ability revising forecasts later in the quarter. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Yongtae; Lobo, Gerald J.; Song, Minsup</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and the balance sheet channel of monetary transmission</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aysun, Uluc; Hepp, Ralf
This paper shows that the balance sheet channel of monetary transmission is stronger for US banks that securitize their assets. This finding is different, in spirit, from the widely-found negative relationship between financial development and the strength of the lending channel of monetary transmission. Focusing on the balance sheet channel, and using bank-level observations, we find that securitizing banks are more sensitive to borrowers' balance sheets and that monetary policy has a greater impact on this sensitivity for securitizing banks. The optimality conditions from a simple partial equilibrium framework suggest that the positive effects of securitization on policy effectiveness could be due to the high sensitivity of security prices to policy rates. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aysun, Uluc; Hepp, Ralf</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining the idiosyncratic volatility puzzle using Stochastic Discount Factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni
I use Stochastic Discount Factors to examine the sources of the idiosyncratic volatility premium. I find that non-zero risk aversion and firms' non-systematic coskewness determine the premium on idiosyncratic volatility risk. The firm's non-systematic coskewness measures the comovement of the asset's volatility with the market return. When I control for the non-systematic coskewness factor, I find no significant relation between idiosyncratic volatility and stock expected returns. My results are robust across different sample periods and firm characteristics. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved,</description><author>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of leverage on the cost of capital of US buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Groh, Alexander Peter; Gottschalg, Oliver
This paper addresses the problem to assess the effect of leverage on the cost of capital for buyout performance analyses. It draws on a unique and proprietary set of data on 133 US buyouts between 1984 and 2004. For each of them, we determine a public market equivalent that matches it with respect to its timing and its systematic risk. We show that under realistic mimicking conditions, the average cost of capital is below the commonly used benchmark S&amp;P 500. Thereby, we control for two important aspects: for the risks taken by lenders in the buyout transactions (which affects the sponsors' risks), and for the corresponding cost of debt (which lowers the return of the public market equivalent). Only with borrowing and lending at the risk-free rate is the average cost of capital close to the average index return. This finding is particularly important as existing literature on that topic tends to rely on benchmarks without a proper risk-adjustment. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Groh, Alexander Peter; Gottschalg, Oliver</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider trading law enforcement and gross spreads of ADR IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hsuan-Chi; Hao
Using American Depositary Receipt (ADR) IPOs from 34 countries during 1980-2004, we find that, on average, the enforcement of insider trading laws reduces the underwriter gross spread by 49-61 basis points, which is about 10-12% of the average gross spread for ADR IPOs. This relation is present regardless of whether issuers have a prior listing or whether issuers are from developed or emerging markets. The association becomes stronger for ADRs underwritten by less prestigious underwriters and for issuers that are involved in privatization. The political institutions in the issuers' home markets also affect gross spreads. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Hsuan-Chi; Hao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stockholding: Participation, location, and spillovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christelis, Dimitris; Georgarakos, Dimitris; Haliassos, Michael
This paper provides the first joint analysis of household stockholding participation, location among stockholding modes, and participation spillovers. Our model matches observed participation, conditional and unconditional, and asset location patterns. We find that financial sophistication correlates strongly only with direct stockholding and mutual fund participation, while social interactions mainly influence stockholding through retirement accounts. Whether retirement account owners include stocks in their accounts strongly depends on owner characteristics, which is not the case with mutual fund owners and investment in stock funds. Stockholding is more common among retirement account owners, but mainly because of owner characteristics rather than of any participation spillovers from retirement account ownership. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christelis, Dimitris; Georgarakos, Dimitris; Haliassos, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cost of debt when all-equity firms raise finance: The role of investment opportunities, audit quality and debt maturity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lai, Kam-Wah
This paper investigates the effect of investment opportunities, audit quality and debt maturity on the interest paid by all-equity firms. Debt holders are likely to charge higher interest to price-protect themselves because of the under-investment and asset substitution problems. All-equity firms, however, could reduce interest charge by employing Big 4 auditors to increase the reliability of audited financial statements or using short-term debt to allow more frequent monitoring of their financial condition by lenders and re-pricing of debt. The results show that interest charge is positively related to investment opportunities of all-equity firms. This relationship is weaker when the firms have Big 4 auditors or a higher proportion of debt due in the next year over total debt. In addition, the above results do not hold for highly levered firms since the lenders are constantly monitoring the financial condition of their borrowers. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lai, Kam-Wah</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring and explaining the volatility of capital flows to emerging countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Broto, Carmen; Diaz-Cassou, Javier; Erce, Aitor
This paper analyzes the determinants of the volatility of the various types of capital inflows into emerging countries. After calculating a proxy of the volatility of FDI, portfolio and bank inflows, we use a panel data model to study their relationship with a broad set of explanatory variables. Our results highlight the difficulties policy-makers face in stabilizing capital flows. Thus, we show that since 2000 global factors beyond the control of emerging economies have become increasingly significant relative to country-specific drivers. However, we identify some domestic macroeconomic and financial factors that appear to reduce the volatility of certain capital flows without increasing that of others. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Broto, Carmen; Diaz-Cassou, Javier; Erce, Aitor</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dependence structure and extreme comovements in international equity and bond markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia, Rene; Tsafack, Georges
Common negative extreme variations in returns are prevalent in international equity markets. This has been widely documented with statistical tools such as exceedance correlation, extreme value theory, and Gaussian bivariate GARCH or regime-switching models. We point to limits of these tools to characterize extreme dependence and propose an alternative regime-switching copula model that includes one normal regime in which dependence is symmetric and a second regime characterized by asymmetric dependence. We apply this model to international equity and bond markets, to allow for inter-market movements. Empirically, we find that dependence between international assets of the same type is strong in both regimes, especially in the asymmetric one, but weak between equities and bonds, even in the same country. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garcia, Rene; Tsafack, Georges</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A reduced form model of default spreads with Markov-switching macroeconomic factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dionne, Georges; Gauthier, Genevieve; Hammami, Khemais; Maurice, Mathieu; Simonato, Jean-Guy
We examine the ability of observed macroeconomic factors and the possibility of changes in regime to explain the proportion of yield spreads caused by the risk of default in the context of a reduced form model. For this purpose, we extend the Markov-switching risk-free term structure model of Bansal and Zhou (2002) to the corporate bond setting and develop recursive formulas for default probabilities, risk-free and risky zero-coupon bond yields as well as credit default swap premia. The model is calibrated with consumption, inflation, risk-free yields and default data for Aa, A and Baa bonds from the 1987 to 2008 period. We find that our macroeconomic factors are linked with two out of three sharp increases in the spreads during this sample period, indicating that the spread variations can be related to macroeconomic undiversifiable risk. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dionne, Georges; Gauthier, Genevieve; Hammami, Khemais; Maurice, Mathieu; Simonato, Jean-Guy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downside risk and the size of credit spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gemmill, Gordon; Keswani, Aneel
We investigate why spreads on corporate bonds are so much larger than expected losses from default. Systematic factors make very little contribution to spreads, even if higher moments or downside effects are taken into account. Instead we find that sizes of spreads are strongly related to idiosyncratic-risk factors: not only to idiosyncratic equity volatility, but even more to idiosyncratic bond volatility and idiosyncratic bond value-at-risk. Idiosyncratic bond volatility helps to explain spreads because it reflects not just the distribution of firm value but is also a proxy for liquidity risk. Idiosyncratic bond value-at-risk adds to this by capturing the left-skewness of the firm-value distribution. We confirm our results both for the initial 1997-2004 sample period and also out of sample for 2005-2009, which includes the sub-prime crisis. Overall, credit spreads are large because they incorporate a large risk premium related to investors' fears of extreme losses. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gemmill, Gordon; Keswani, Aneel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A test of the different implications of the overconfidence and disposition hypotheses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chou, Robin K.; Wang, Yun-Yi
Under both the overconfidence and disposition biases, a positive relationship is predicted between prior returns and subsequent trading volume. However, theoretically the overconfidence and disposition effects have different implications on the relationships between the long- and short-position gains of traders and their subsequent buying and selling activities. We examine a unique dataset obtained from the Taiwan Futures Exchange which records all account-level trades and orders. Our data and methodology have the advantage of being able to empirically differentiate these two effects and we demonstrate that different types of traders exhibit different types and levels of behavioral biases. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chou, Robin K.; Wang, Yun-Yi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining bank market-to-book ratios: Evidence from 2006 to 2009</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jordan, Dan J.; Rice, Douglas; Sanchez, Jacques; Wort, Donald H.
This paper examines the market-price to book-value ratio for 6604 bank stock observations from December 31, 2006 through June 30, 2009. We relate each bank's market-price to book-value ratio to several fundamental ratios and whether the bank took funds from the US Treasury under the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP). The results of this study show that banks who took TARP funds have lower market-price to book-value ratios. In addition, lower relative costs, higher non-interest income, and lower assets in non-accrual or foreclosed status are associated with higher market-price to book-value ratios while controlling for size and other bank attributes. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jordan, Dan J.; Rice, Douglas; Sanchez, Jacques; Wort, Donald H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The comovement of option listed stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agyei-Ampomah, Sam; Mazouz, Khelifa
This study examines the changes in return comovement around the listing and delisting of stock option contracts. We show that newly option listed stocks experience an increase in comovement with a portfolio of option listed stocks and a decrease in comovement with the portfolio of non-optioned stocks. Similarly, stocks that undergo option delisting exhibit a decrease in comovement with option listed stocks and an increase in comovement with non-optioned stocks. We verify the reliability of our findings in several ways. A matched sample analysis suggests that our results are not driven by factors other than option listing and we find similar results using a calendar-time approach. Further analysis reveals that commonalities in option trading may induce the comovement in the option listed stocks. Overall, our evidence is consistent with the predictions of the category or habitat view of comovement. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agyei-Ampomah, Sam; Mazouz, Khelifa</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gold and the Dollar (and the Euro, Pound, and Yen)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Roll, Richard
Usually, gold and the Dollar are negatively related; when the Dollar price of gold increases. the Dollar depreciates against other currencies. This is intuitively puzzling because it seems to suggest that gold prices are associated with appreciation in other currencies. Why should the Dollar be different? We show here that there is actually no puzzle. The price of gold can be associated with currency depreciation in every country. The Dollar price of gold can be related to Dollar depreciation and the Euro (Pound, Yen) price of gold can be related to Euro (Pound, Yen) depreciation. Indeed, this is usually the case empirically. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock and option market divergence in the presence of noisy information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Carl R.; Diltz, J. David; Huang, Ying; Lung, Peter P.
We examine market behavior of the stock and option markets upon the arrival of noisy information in the form of CNBC's Mad Money recommendations. If stock and option markets are not equally efficient, they should respond differently to noisy information, with the less efficient market more susceptible to noise. We find that the stock market is less efficient than the option market. The abnormal difference between option-implied and actual stock returns is negative and significant upon exposure to noisy information. This difference may yield an economically significant monthly trading profit of up to 5%. We conclude that the stock market is more susceptible to noisy information than the option market and is therefore less efficient. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chen, Carl R.; Diltz, J. David; Huang, Ying; Lung, Peter P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor unions, bargaining power and corporate bond yield spreads: Structural credit model perspectives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Tsung-Kang; Chen, Yan-Shing; Liao, Hsien-Hsing
This study investigates labor union effects on bond yield spreads from perspectives of structural credit models by employing American bond observations from 2001 to 2007. This research finds that union strength significantly and positively relates to bond yield spreads (this effect is roughly equal to that of issuer rating for one standard deviation change when controlling for well-known variables). The empirical results also show that the positive effects become weaker when management has higher bargaining power. Additionally, union strength volatility significantly and negatively relates to bond yield spreads and capital structure (leverage). The above results are robust when controlling for credit ratings, collinearity concerns, industry effect and tax effect. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Tsung-Kang; Chen, Yan-Shing; Liao, Hsien-Hsing</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance measurement in the financial services sector: Frontier efficiency methodologies and other innovative techniques</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banker, Rajiv D.; Cummins, J. David; Klumpes, Paul J. M.
nan</description><author>Banker, Rajiv D.; Cummins, J. David; Klumpes, Paul J. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>First financial restructuring and operating efficiency: Evidence from Taiwanese commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsiao, Hsing-Chin; Chang, Hsihui; Cianci, Anna M.; Huang, Li-Hua
This paper investigates the effect of the "First Financial Restructuring" (FFR) on the operating efficiency of commercial banks in Taiwan. Applying data envelopment analysis (DEA) to operations data for 40 commercial banks over the 6-year period 2000-2005, we find that while the banks have lower operating efficiency on average during the reform period (2002-2003) compared to the pre-reform period (20002001), improved operating efficiency is reflected in the post-reform period (2004-2005). Our results remain unchanged even after controlling for the non-performing loan ratio, capital adequacy ratio, bank ownership, size, and GDP growth rate. These results suggest that the improved efficiency in the post-reform period is possibly due to enhanced banking and risk management practices and benefits obtained from compliance with the FFR. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hsiao, Hsing-Chin; Chang, Hsihui; Cianci, Anna M.; Huang, Li-Hua</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of focus versus diversification on bank performance: Evidence from Chinese banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Zhou, Mingming
This paper investigates the effects of focus versus diversification on bank performance using data on Chinese banks during the 1996-2006 period. We construct a new measure, economies of diversification, and compare the results to those of the more conventional focus indices, which are based on the sum of squares of shares in different products or regions. Diversification is captured in four dimensions: loans, deposits, assets, and geography. We find that all four dimensions of diversification are associated with reduced profits and higher costs. These results are robust regardless of alternative measures of diversification and performance. Furthermore, we observe that banks with foreign ownership (both majority and minority ownership) and banks with conglomerate affiliation are associated with fewer diseconomies of diversification, suggesting that foreign ownership and conglomerate affiliation may play important mitigating roles. This analysis may provide important implications for bank managers and regulators in China as well as in other emerging economies. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Zhou, Mingming</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of non-traditional activities on the estimation of bank efficiency: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lozano-Vivas, Ana; Pasiouras, Fotios
This paper investigates the relevance of non-traditional activities in the estimation of bank efficiency els using a sample of 752 publicly quoted commercial banks from 87 countries around the world, allowing comparison of the impact of such activities under different levels of economic development, geographical regions and other country characteristics. We estimate both cost and profit efficiency of banks using a traditional function that considers loans and other earnings assets as the only outputs, and two additional functions to account for non-traditional activities, one with off-balance sheet (OBS) items and the other with non-interest income as an additional output. Controlling for cross-country differences in regulatory and environmental conditions, we find that, on average, cost efficiency increases irrespective of whether we use OBS or non-interest income, although the results for profit efficiency are mixed. Our results also reveal that while the inclusion of non-traditional outputs does not alter the directional impact of environmental variables on bank inefficiency, regulations that restrict bank activities and enhance monitoring and supervision provisions improve both cost and profit efficiency. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lozano-Vivas, Ana; Pasiouras, Fotios</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differential impact of Korean banking system reforms on bank productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banker, Rajiv D.; Chang, Hsihui; Lee, Seok-Young
We study the impact of banking system reforms during a crisis following a period of undisciplined lending. Regulatory changes aimed at strengthening the banks' capital structure and risk management practices do not have a uniform impact on bank productivity, but rather favor financially sound or strategically privileged banks. We present evidence documenting the differential impact of regulatory reforms on Korean commercial bank productivity over the period 1995-2005. Average technical efficiency of banks decreased during the financial crisis of 1997-1998. It improved following the subsequent bank restructuring and continued to improve through 2005. The capital adequacy ratio is positively associated with banks' technical efficiency. The non-performing loans ratio is negatively associated with technical efficiency. Both relationships are accentuated during the crisis but attenuated after the reforms. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Banker, Rajiv D.; Chang, Hsihui; Lee, Seok-Young</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Malmquist-type indices in the presence of negative data: An application to bank branches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Portela, Maria C. A. S.; Thanassoulis, Emmanuel
In this paper we develop an index and an indicator of productivity change that can be used with negative data. For that purpose the range directional model (RDM), a particular case of the directional distance function, is used for computing efficiency in the presence of negative data. We use RDM efficiency measures to arrive at a Malmquist-type index, which can reflect productivity change, and we use RDM inefficiency measures to arrive at a Luenberger productivity indicator, and relate the two. The productivity index and indicator are developed relative to a fixed meta-technology and so they are referred to as a meta-Malmquist index and meta-Luenberger indicator. We also address the fact that VRS technologies are used for computing the productivity index and indicator (a requirement under negative data), which raises issues relating to the interpretability of the index. We illustrate how the meta-Malmquist index can be used, not only for comparing the performance of a unit in two time periods, but also for comparing the performance of two different units at the same or different time periods. The proposed approach is then applied to a sample of bank branches where negative data were involved. The paper shows how the approach yields information from a variety of perspectives on performance which management can use. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Portela, Maria C. A. S.; Thanassoulis, Emmanuel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Scaling models for the severity and frequency of external operational loss data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahen, Hela; Dionne, Georges
According to Basel II criteria, the use of external data is indispensable to the implementation of an advanced method for calculating operational risk capital. This article investigates how the severity and frequencies of external losses are scaled for integration with internal data. We set up an initial model designed to explain the loss severity by taking into account potential selection bias in the external data. Estimation results show that many variables have significant power in explaining the loss amount. We use them to develop a normalization formula. We develop a zero-inflated count-data model to scale the loss frequency. We compute an operational VaR and we conduct out-of-sample backtesting. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dahen, Hela; Dionne, Georges</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency in the international insurance industry: A cross-country comparison</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eling, Martin; Luhnen, Michael
The purpose of this paper is to provide new empirical evidence on frontier efficiency measurement in the international insurance industry, a topic of great interest in the academic literature during the last several years. A broad efficiency comparison of 6462 insurers from 36 countries is conducted. Different methodologies, countries, organizational forms, and company sizes are compared, considering life and non-life insurers. We find a steady technical and cost efficiency growth in international insurance markets from 2002 to 2006, with large differences across countries. Denmark and Japan have the highest average efficiency, whereas the Philippines is the least efficient. Regarding organizational form, the results are not consistent with the expense preference hypothesis, which claims that mutuals should be less efficient than stocks due to higher agency costs. Only minor variations are found when comparing different frontier efficiency methodologies (data envelopment analysis, stochastic frontier analysis). (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eling, Martin; Luhnen, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The robustness of output measures in property-liability insurance efficiency studies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leverty, J. Tyler; Grace, Martin F.
We empirically examine two methods for measuring output in property-liability insurer efficiency studies: the value-added approach and the "flow" (or financial intermediation) approach. The approaches are not mutually consistent. The value-added approach is closely related to traditional measures of firm performance, but the flow approach is not. In addition, efficient value-added approach firms are less likely to go insolvent, while firms characterized as efficient by the flow approach are generally more likely to fail. We also find that the theoretical concern regarding the value-added approach's use of losses as a measure of output is not validated empirically. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leverty, J. Tyler; Grace, Martin F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economies of scope in financial services: A DEA efficiency analysis of the US insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cummins, J. David; Weiss, Mary A.; Xie, Xiaoying; Zi, Hongmin
This paper investigates economies of scope in the US insurance industry over the period 1993-2006. We test the conglomeration hypothesis, which holds that firms can optimize by diversifying across businesses, versus the strategic focus hypothesis, which holds that firms optimize by focusing on core businesses. We analyze whether it is advantageous for insurers to offer both life-health and property-liability insurance or to specialize in one major industry segment. We estimate cost, revenue, and profit efficiency utilizing data envelopment analysis (DEA) and test for scope economies by regressing efficiency scores on control variables and an indicator for strategic focus. Property-liability insurers realize cost scope economies, but they are more than offset by revenue scope diseconomies. Life-health insurers realize both cost and revenue scope diseconomies. Hence, strategic focus is superior to conglomeration in the insurance industry. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cummins, J. David; Weiss, Mary A.; Xie, Xiaoying; Zi, Hongmin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are publicly held firms less efficient? Evidence from the US property-liability insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xie, Xiaoying
This paper studies the performance of publicly held firms in the US property-liability insurance industry by analyzing companies that issued initial public offerings (IPOs) from 1994 to 2005, using private firms as the benchmark. I investigate ex ante determinants and ex post effects of IPOs on firm efficiency, operating performance, and other financials. I also analyze stock returns and follow-on SEO and acquisition activities to provide further information on IPO motivation. The paper finds that the likelihood of an IPO significantly increases with firm size and premium growth. IPO firms experience no post-issue under-performance in efficiency, operations, or stock returns; register improvement in allocative and cost efficiency; and reduce financial leverage and reinsurance usage. Moreover, IPO firms are active in follow-on SEO issues and acquisition activities. The findings are mostly consistent with the theory that firms go public for easier access to capital and to ease capital constraints. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xie, Xiaoying</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Single Market effects on productivity in the German insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mahlberg, Bernhard; Url, Thomas
The Single Market project of the European Commission was supposed to foster productivity growth in the financial service industry. We assess its consequences on productivity development in the German insurance industry, one of the largest insurance markets within the European Union, by applying Data Envelopment Analysis to a panel of German insurance companies. We estimate standard and bootstrapped efficiency scores for the years 1991 through 2006 and apply a test on scale efficiency based on bootstrapped statistics. Furthermore, we compute a Malmquist index and test for different types of productivity convergence across firms. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mahlberg, Bernhard; Url, Thomas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenously structured boards of directors in banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pathan, Shams; Skully, Michael
This paper examines the trends and endogenous determinants of boards of directors (board size, composition, and CEO duality) for a sample of 212 US bank holding companies, from 1997 to 2004. Overall, the results show that the costs and benefits of boards' monitoring and advising roles could explain bank board structures with caveats. For example, due to the regulatory nature and comparatively intensive scrutiny of bank officers and directors, it is argued that bank managers have less control over the directors' selection processes. Thus, bank board independence should not be the outcome of negotiation with CEOs. Consistent with this view, bank CEOs are found not to affect bank board independence. The trend analysis also provides some important results. In contrast to non-bank evidence, for instance, board size was discovered to decrease over the sample period for large and medium-sized banks, while board size remained relatively stable for small banks. These results are robust with respect to different estimation specifications. Furthermore, the study's findings have important policy implications for bank regulators and investors. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pathan, Shams; Skully, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sales order backlogs and momentum profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gu, Li; Huang, Dayong
Winner stocks have higher changes in sales order backlogs and a sales order backlog factor is significant in explaining various winner minus loser returns and often reduces the as by big margins. We argue that this factor is a proxy for innovation in demand in the economy and it is likely to relate to expected growth risks and future business conditions. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gu, Li; Huang, Dayong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bought deals: The value of underwriter certification in seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pandes, J. Ari
The bought deal is the predominant method of underwriting SEOs in Canada. Offer prices are set and underwriters commit to purchase offerings several days earlier for bought deals than for firm commitment issues, implying stronger underwriter certification for bought deal issues. Consistent with the certification hypothesis, this study finds a significantly smaller negative stock price reaction around the announcement of bought deals compared to firm commitment issues. Bought deals are further shown to have smaller offer price discounts and smaller underwriting fees, implying superior pricing and thus, higher quality offerings. These findings suggest that investment banks' underwriting method of choice is informative of issue quality. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pandes, J. Ari</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivative pricing using multivariate affine generalized hyperbolic distributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fajardo, Jose; Farias, Aquiles
In this paper we use multivariate affine generalized hyperbolic (MAGH) distributions, introduced by Schmidt et al. (2006), to show how to price multidimensional derivatives when the underlying asset follows a MAGH distribution. We also illustrate the approach using market data from the BOVESPA (Sao Paulo Stock Exchange) and the exchange rate of the Brazilian Real vs. US Dollar to price some multidimensional derivatives. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fajardo, Jose; Farias, Aquiles</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are non-risk based capital requirements for insurance companies binding?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Haan, Leo; Kakes, Jan
We investigate whether insurers base their solvency margins on risk factors even when operating under a supervisory regime where minimum solvency requirements do not fully take such risk factors into account. To do this, we use a dataset of about 350 Dutch insurers from all major lines of business during the pre-Solvency II period 1995-2005. We find that the levels of insurers' actual solvency margins are related to their risk characteristics and not to regulatory solvency requirements. Consequently, the vast majority of insurers hold much more capital than required, i.e. non-risk based capital requirements generally are not binding. Requirements are found to affect solvency adjustment behaviour, though. More specifically, below-target capital ratios are raised most rapidly by those insurers whose targets are relatively close to the regulatory minimum. One implication from our results is that, because insurers already follow a risk-based approach, the transition to the new European regulatory framework, Solvency II, is likely to be smooth. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Haan, Leo; Kakes, Jan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News announcements and price discovery in foreign exchange spot and futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yu-Lun; Gau, Yin-Feng
This paper studies competition in price discovery between spot and futures rates for the EUR-USD and JPY-USD markets around scheduled macroeconomic announcements. Using both the information shares approach and the common factor component weight approach for futures prices from the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME), as well as deal prices from spot trading on the Electronic Broking Services (EBS), we gauge how foreign exchange spot and futures markets respond to news surprises. The results show that the spot rates provide more price discovery than do the CME futures rates overall: however, the contribution of the futures rates to price discovery increases in the time surrounding macroeconomic announcement releases. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Yu-Lun; Gau, Yin-Feng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relation between time-series and cross-sectional effects of idiosyncratic variance on stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Hui; Savickas, Robert
Consistent with the post-1962 US evidence by Ang et al. [Ang, A., Hodrick, R., Xing Y., Zhang, X., 2006. The cross-section of volatility and expected returns. Journal of Finance 51, 259-299], we find that stocks with high idiosyncratic variance (IV) have low CAPM-adjusted expected returns in both pre-1962 US and modern G7 data. We also test in three ways the conjecture that IV is a proxy of systematic risk. First, the return difference between low and high IV stocks - that we dub as IVF - is a priced factor in the cross-section of stock returns. Second, loadings on lagged market variance and lagged average IV account for a significant portion of variation in average returns on portfolios sorted by IV. Third, the variance of IVF correlates closely with average IV, and the two variables have similar explanatory power for the time-series and cross-sectional stock returns. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guo, Hui; Savickas, Robert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic online banking adoption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hernandez-Murillo, Ruben; Llobet, Gerard; Fuentes, Roberto
In this paper we study the determinants of banks' decisions to adopt a transactional website for their customers. Using a panel of commercial banks in the United States for the period 2003-2006, we show that although bank-specific characteristics are important determinants of banks' adoption decisions, competition also plays a prominent role. The extent of competition is related to the geographic overlap of banks in different markets and their relative market share in terms of deposits. In particular, banks adopt online banking services earlier in markets where their competitors have already adopted this technology. This paper is one of the first to construct local banking markets using the geographic market definitions delimited by the CASSIDI Database compiled at the Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hernandez-Murillo, Ruben; Llobet, Gerard; Fuentes, Roberto</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The non-7% solution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garner, Jacqueline L.; Marshall, Beverly B.
While the vast majority of underwriters charge a gross spread of exactly 7%, as documented in Chen and Ritter (2000), more than a third charge something other than 7%. Among offerings of $50 million and below where underwriters charge the firm other than 7%, two-thirds of issuers pay more than published NASD(1) compensation guidelines. When underwriters charge less than expected, they do not trade-off IPO compensation with underpricing. However, our evidence suggests a trade-off between IPO compensation and future SEO business among underwriters that charge something other than 7% and less than expected. Underwriters that overcharge may provide a signal to investors about future under performance. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garner, Jacqueline L.; Marshall, Beverly B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No-arbitrage conditions for storable commodities and the modeling of futures term structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Peng; Tang, Ke
One distinguishable feature of storable commodities is that they relate to two markets: cash market and storage market. This paper proves that, if no arbitrage exists in the storage-cash dual markets, the commodity convenience yield has to be non-negative. However, classical reduced-form models for futures term structures could allow serious arbitrages due to the high volatility of the convenience yield. To avoid negative convenience yield, this paper proposes a semi-affine arbitrage-free model, which prices futures analytically and fits futures term structures reasonably well. Importantly, our model prices commodity-related contingent claims (such as calendar spread options) quite differently with classical models. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Peng; Tang, Ke</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics and causality in industry-specific volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Zijun
This paper presents comprehensive empirical evidence on the dynamics and causality within 30 US industry-specific volatilities during July 1963 and June 2008. We find that linear trends are present in 17 of the 30 industry volatilities. Granger-causality tests reveal that the industry of business supplies and the industry of finance are the most important lead indicators of industry volatilities. To uncover contemporaneous causal relationships in the market, we implement an emerging data-driven method of directed acyclic graphs. The results suggest that volatility shocks originating from business supplies, machinery, and consumer goods industries are sources of risks that affect most other industries. By contrast, volatilities in the two traditionally important industries, oil and autos, do not appear to have a substantial influence on other large industries in the contemporaneous time. Finally, business equipment and services, both containing information technology components, are the most important driving forces of the industry volatility surge in the late 1990s. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Zijun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural models of corporate bond pricing with personal taxes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qi, Howard; Liu, Sheen; Wu, Chunchi
The structural approach offers an integrated framework to deal with yield spreads and default probability simultaneously. However, structural models perform poorly in predicting corporate bond spreads. It is unclear whether this poor performance is caused by characteristics of individual models, missing factors, or different calibration procedures. This study evaluates the performance of four structural models by incorporating two important factors, personal taxes and the liquidity factor, and calibrating these models to data. To ensure our results are not contingent on the calibration method, we further apply the maximum likelihood estimation method to a large sample of individual bonds. Results consistently show that the ability of structural models to predict spreads improves considerably when personal taxes and liquidity are taken into account. Our findings suggest that the poor performance of standard structural models is more likely due to missing factors than the characteristics of individual models or the calibration procedure. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Qi, Howard; Liu, Sheen; Wu, Chunchi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of off-balance-sheet activities on banks returns: An application of the ARCH-M to Canadian data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calmes, Christian; Theoret, Raymond
This paper revisits the impact of off-balance-sheet (OBS) activities on banks risk-return trade-off. Recent studies (e.g., Stiroh and Rumble, 2006) show that increasing OBS activities does not necessarily yield straightforward diversification benefits for banks. However, introducing a risk premium in the standard banks returns models, and resorting to an ARCH-M procedure, Canadian data suggest that banks risk-return trade-off displays a structural break around 1997. In the second subperiod of our sample (1997-2007), we find that the noninterest income generated by OBS activities no longer impacts banks returns negatively. While during the first period (1988-1996) the volatility variable is not significant in any returns equations, a risk premium eventually emerges, pricing the risk associated to OBS activities. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calmes, Christian; Theoret, Raymond</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underpricing of IPOs: Firm-, issue- and country-specific characteristics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engelen, Peter-Jan; van Essen, Marc
Using a large firm-level dataset of 2920 IPOs from 21 countries we examine the impact of country-level institutional characteristics on the underpricing of IPOs. Through hierarchical linear modeling we are able to control for firm-specific and issue-specific characteristics and test whether country-specific institutional characteristics add explanatory power to explain the level of underpricing. Our results show that about 10% of the variation in the level of underpricing is between countries. The quality of a country's legal framework, as measured by its level of investor protection, the overall quality of its legal system and its level of legal enforcement, reduces the level of underpricing significantly. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Engelen, Peter-Jan; van Essen, Marc</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of hedge funds and mutual funds in emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eling, Martin; Faust, Roger
Use of short selling and derivatives is limited in most emerging markets because such instruments are not as readily available as they are in developed capital markets. These limitations raise questions about the value added provided by hedge funds, especially compared to traditional mutual funds active in these markets. We use five existing performance measurement models plus a new asset-style factor model to identify the return sources and the alpha generated by both types of funds. We analyze subperiods, different market environments, and structural breaks. Our results indicate that some hedge funds generate significant positive alpha, whereas most mutual funds do not outperform traditional benchmarks. We find that hedge funds are more active in shifting their asset allocation. The higher degree of freedom that hedge funds enjoy in their investment style might thus be one explanation for the differences in performance. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eling, Martin; Faust, Roger</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentive and entrenchment effects in European ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennedsen, Morten; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner
In a large sample of European firms we analyze the value discount associated with disproportional ownership structures first documented by Claessens et al. (2002). Consistent with a theoretical model of incentive and entrenchment effects, we find higher value discount in family firms, in firms with low cash flow concentration, and in industries with higher amenity value. Furthermore, the discount is higher in countries with good investor protection and higher for dual class shares than for pyramids. We find no impact on operating performance, likelihood of bankruptcy, dividend policy, or growth. Finally, we discuss policy implications of these findings. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bennedsen, Morten; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convergence to market efficiency of top gainers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Su, Yong-Chern; Huang, Han-Ching; Hsu, Ming-Wei
This study investigates the convergence process toward efficiency of daily top gainers. The convergence process toward efficiency is much clearer as a result of using a GARCH(1, 1) model compared to the OLS model, and exhibits a monotonic decline as the time interval increases. The relationship between volatility and order imbalances is, however, not strong enough, suggesting that market makers do have the capability to reduce price volatility. This study develops an imbalance-based trading strategy, which earns a positive profit but fails to outperform the buy-and-hold strategy (i.e., open-to-close returns). A nested causality approach, which examines the dynamic return order imbalance relationship during the price-formation process, confirms the results. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Su, Yong-Chern; Huang, Han-Ching; Hsu, Ming-Wei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preference heterogeneity and asset prices: An exact solution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weinbaum, David
We introduce a general equilibrium model of a multi-agent, pure-exchange economy and find a set of conditions that enable us to obtain explicit closed-form solutions to the equilibrium interest rate, stock price, risk premium and stock market volatility when investors have heterogenous risk aversions. Because the market is dynamically complete, full risk sharing obtains and a representative agent can be constructed, though the risk aversion of this agent fluctuates over time with the state of the economy, as the relative wealth distribution of the individual investors changes. We show that preference heterogeneity can cause asset prices to be significantly more volatile than the underlying dividends and that it can lead to leverage-like effects in volatility, in the sense that volatility increases after stock-market declines. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Weinbaum, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence on the insurance effect of bankruptcy exemptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grant, Charles
Defaulting on one's debts when experiencing an adverse event can help insure households against unexpected income risks. But the effect of allowing default on debt levels is ambiguous, not least because lenders may restrict access to credit. Hence the optimal punishment for bankruptcy is unclear. The US states allows householders to keep a variety of assets when filing for bankruptcy - the 'bankruptcy exemptions' - and these exemptions change substantially between states and over time. By exploiting these differences this study shows that raising the exemptions (i) marginally decreases the level of unsecured debt that household's hold; (ii) makes consumption smoother. Thus, despite the effect on debt levels, the generous provisions to debtors in arrears may be helping US households to insure themselves against income risk. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grant, Charles</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank regulation, property prices and early warning systems for banking crises in OECD countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barrell, Ray; Davis, E. Philip; Karim, Dilruba; Liadze, Iana
Early warning systems (EWS) for banking crises generally omit bank capital, bank liquidity and property prices. Most work on EWS has been for global samples dominated by emerging market crises where time series data on bank capital adequacy and property prices are typically absent. We estimate logit crisis models for OECD countries, finding strong effects from capital adequacy and liquidity ratios as well as property prices, and can exclude traditional variables. Higher capital adequacy and liquidity ratios have a marked effect on the crisis probabilities, implying long-run benefits to offset some of the costs that such regulations may impose. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barrell, Ray; Davis, E. Philip; Karim, Dilruba; Liadze, Iana</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information uncertainty, information asymmetry and corporate bond yield spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Chia-Wu; Chen, Tsung-Kang; Liao, Hsien-Hsing
This study examines the effects of information uncertainty and information asymmetry on corporate bond yield spreads using American data from 2001 to 2006. Empirical results of this study show that investors charge a significant risk premium for both information uncertainty and information asymmetry when controlling for variables well known in the literature. The results are robust even when controlling for credit ratings. Finally, information uncertainty and asymmetry help structural-form credit models explain the yield spreads of bonds with short maturities. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lu, Chia-Wu; Chen, Tsung-Kang; Liao, Hsien-Hsing</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank involvement with SMEs: Beyond relationship lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de la Torre, Augusto; Peria, Maria Soledad Martinez; Schmukler, Sergio L.
The "conventional wisdom" in academic and policy circles argues that, while large and foreign banks are generally not interested in serving SMEs, small and niche banks have an advantage because they can overcome SME opaqueness through relationship lending. This paper shows that there is a gap between this view and what banks actually do. Banks perceive SMEs as a core and strategic business and seem well-positioned to expand their links with SMEs. The intensification of bank involvement with SMEs in various emerging markets is neither led by small or niche banks nor highly dependent on relationship lending. Moreover, it has not been derailed by the 2007-2009 crisis. Rather, all types of banks are catering to SMEs and large, multiple-service banks have a comparative advantage in offering a wide range of products and services on a large scale, through the use of new technologies, business models, and risk management systems. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de la Torre, Augusto; Peria, Maria Soledad Martinez; Schmukler, Sergio L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information content of IPO grading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deb, Saikat Sovan; Marisetty, Vijaya B.
In the year 2007, Indian capital market regulator-SEBI, introduced a unique certification mechanism for IPOs whereby all IPOs have to undergo mandatory quality grading by independent rating agencies. In this paper we argue that such objective, independent and exogenous certifying mechanism provides a better opportunity to test the well established certification hypothesis, especially in the context of emerging markets with institutional voids. Using a sample of 163 Indian IPOs we test the efficacy of IPO grading mechanism. We find, grading decreases IPO underpricing and positively influences demand of retail investors. Grading reduces secondary market risk and improves liquidity. However, grading does not affect long run performance of the IPOs. IPO grading successfully capture firm size, business group affiliation and firm's quality of corporate governance. Our findings imply that, in emerging markets, regulator's role to signal the quality of an IPO contributes towards the market welfare. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Deb, Saikat Sovan; Marisetty, Vijaya B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variations in sovereign credit quality assessments across rating agencies (vol 34, pg 1327, 2010)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hill, Paula; Brooks, Robert; Faff, Robert
nan</description><author>Hill, Paula; Brooks, Robert; Faff, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating financial risk measures for options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sorwar, Ghulam; Dowd, Kevin
This paper proposes a simulation-lattice procedure to estimate financial risk measures for option positions. The framework proposed can be applied to many different kinds of options, including exotic and vanilla options; it can take account of early exercise features; heavy tails in underlying processes; estimate different risk measures, including VaR, Expected Shortfall and Spectral Risk Measures; and in a limited way it can be generalized to accommodate multiple-factors. It avoids many of the limitations of existing approaches and, in particular, avoids the problems associated approaches based on delta-gamma and similar approximations. It also generates some interesting results about the risk measures of some illustrative options positions. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sorwar, Ghulam; Dowd, Kevin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Borrowing in foreign currency: Austrian households as carry traders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beer, Christian; Ongena, Steven; Peter, Marcel
Household borrowing in a foreign currency is a widespread phenomenon in Austria. Thirteen percent of Austrian households report their housing loan to be denominated in foreign currency, mostly Swiss franc. Yet, despite its importance, peculiar character, and acute policy concerns, we know little about the attitudes and characteristics of the households involved in this type of carry trade. We analyze a uniquely detailed financial wealth survey of 2556 Austrian households to sketch a comprehensive profile of the attitudes and characteristics of the households involved. We employ both univariate tests and multivariate multinomial logit models. The survey data suggest that risk seeking, affluent, and married households are more likely to take a housing loan in a foreign currency. Financially literate or high-income households are more likely to take a housing loan in general. These findings partially assuage policy concerns about household default risk on foreign-currency housing loans or household retirement security. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beer, Christian; Ongena, Steven; Peter, Marcel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active portfolio management with benchmarking: A frontier based on alpha</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Gordon J.; Baptista, Alexandre M.
Active portfolio management often involves the objective of selecting a portfolio with minimum tracking error variance (TEV) for some expected gain in return over a benchmark. However, Roll (1992) shows that such portfolios are generally suboptimal because they do not belong to the mean-variance frontier and are thus overly risky. Our paper proposes an appealing method to lessen this suboptimality that involves the objective of selecting a portfolio from the set of portfolios that have minimum TEV for various levels of ex-ante alpha, which we refer to as the alpha-TEV frontier. Since practitioners commonly use ex-post alpha to assess the performance of managers, the use of this frontier aligns the objectives of managers with how their performance is evaluated. Furthermore, sensible choices of ex-ante alpha lead to the selection of portfolios that are less risky (in variance terms) than the portfolios that active managers would otherwise select. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, Gordon J.; Baptista, Alexandre M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry and the value of cash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drobetz, Wolfgang; Grueninger, Matthias C.; Hirschvogl, Simone
This study investigates the market value of corporate cash holdings in connection with firm-specific and time-varying information asymmetry. Analyzing a large international sample, we test two opposing hypotheses. According to the pecking order theory, adverse selection problems make external financing costly and imply a higher market value of a marginal dollar of cash in states with higher information asymmetry. In contrast, the free cash flow theory predicts that excessive cash holdings bundled with higher information asymmetry generate moral hazard problems and lead to a lower market value of a marginal dollar of cash. We use the dispersion of analysts' earnings per share forecasts as our main measure of firm-specific and time-varying information asymmetry. Extending the valuation regressions of Fama and French [Fama, E.F., French, KR., 1998. Taxes, financing decisions, and firm value. Journal of Finance 53,819-843], our results support the free cash flow theory and indicate that the value of corporate cash holdings is lower in states with a higher degree of information asymmetry. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Drobetz, Wolfgang; Grueninger, Matthias C.; Hirschvogl, Simone</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The efficiency of Greek public pension fund portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angelidis, Timotheos; Tessaromatis, Nikolaos
Greek public pension funds can invest up to 23% into risky assets and are not allowed to invest outside Greece. This paper seeks to investigate the costs of investment constraints on pension fund portfolios. In particular we try to quantify the losses that portfolios suffer due to under-diversification and sub-optimal asset allocation. We find that the high concentration of Greek equity portfolios imposes a substantial return and utility loss which is further increased when the lack of international diversification is taken into account. Restricting the weight of equities to 23% of the total portfolio, leads to sub-optimal asset allocation that costs as much as 2% (3%) per annum compared to a balanced domestic (global) benchmark. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Angelidis, Timotheos; Tessaromatis, Nikolaos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple directorships and acquirer returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, Seoungpil; Jiraporn, Pornsit; Kim, Young Sang
This paper examines the impact of multiple directorships on stockholder wealth around the announcements of mergers and acquisitions. Grounded in agency theory, we argue that multiple directorships affect the quality of managerial oversight and thus influence agency conflicts in acquisition decisions. We show that acquiring firms where directors hold more outside board seats experience more negative abnormal returns. This adverse effect, nonetheless, does not extend across the entire range of multiple directorships. Rather, the detrimental impact is significant only when the number of outside board seats surpasses a certain threshold. We interpret this result as suggesting that directors serving on multiple boards allow value-destroying acquisitions when they become too busy beyond a certain point, and the effect of directors' busyness on acquisition performance appears to be nonlinear. We employ several alternative definitions of directors' busyness and obtain consistent results. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahn, Seoungpil; Jiraporn, Pornsit; Kim, Young Sang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does proximity matter in international bond underwriting?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lau, Sie Ting; Yu, Jing
In this study, we analyze a sample of 3982 international bond issues from 31 countries to examine the impact of geographic proximity on the selection of lead underwriter in the international bond market. We find that proximate banks are more likely to lead underwrite risky bonds and non-rated bonds. On average, the total issue cost is lower if the lead underwriter is a proximate bank. The overall results suggest that geographically proximate banks have better access to private information about issuing companies. We also find that the cost reduction effect of proximate underwriting only appears in developed markets. In addition, this cost reduction effect is relatively weak in countries with a legal system that provides good investor protection. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lau, Sie Ting; Yu, Jing</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market response to bank relationships: Evidence from Korean bank reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sohn, Wook
This paper examines how the forced closure of failing banks and the transfer of their loans to surviving banks affect the market value of firms that borrow from the closed banks. Pre-existing relationships between firms and the banks that acquire their loans are detrimental to the positive valuation effects of the event. Banks may have an incentive to favor pre-existing relationships to increase the value of previously extended loans. Therefore, loan renewals to firms with prior relationships do not signal borrower quality to the market, which is aware of the banks' conflicts of interest. This study highlights the importance of the specific mechanisms employed to replace failed banks without decreasing the value of their client firms. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sohn, Wook</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic European stock market convergence: Evidence from rolling cointegration analysis in the first euro-decade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mylonidis, Nikolaos; Kollias, Christos
The introduction of the euro epitomizes European economic integration. This paper assesses the dynamic process of convergence among four major European stock markets in the first euro-decade. Using tests that allow for endogenously determined breaks in cointegrating relationships and rolling cointegration analysis, we show that although some convergence has been taking place over time, it is very much an ongoing process. There is also evidence that the German and French markets appear to be the ones with a higher degree of convergence while the dominant position of Germany within the eurozone seems to be (re)affirmed by tests conducted herein. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mylonidis, Nikolaos; Kollias, Christos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring portfolio credit risk correctly: Why parameter uncertainty matters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tarashev, Nikola
Why should risk management systems account for parameter uncertainty? In addressing this question, the paper lets an investor in a credit portfolio face non-diversifiable uncertainty about two risk parameters - probability of default and asset-return correlation - and calibrates this uncertainty to a lower bound on estimation noise. In this context, a Bayesian inference procedure is essential for deriving and analyzing the main result, i.e. that parameter uncertainty raises substantially the tail risk perceived by the investor. Since a measure of tail risk that incorporates parameter uncertainty is computationally demanding, the paper also derives a closed-form approximation to such a measure. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tarashev, Nikola</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The choice of ADRs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubakri, Narjess; Cosset, Jean-Claude; Samet, Anis
We study the determinants of a firm's decision to issue one of the four available ADR programs (Level I, Level II, Level III, and Rule 144A). We find that the firm's attributes (size, income, asset growth, leverage, privatization, ownership structure, and country-of-origin) and the firm's home-country institutional variables (accounting rating and legal protection of minority shareholders) condition this choice. We also examine the issuing activity and the determinants of the ADR choice before and after the enactment of the Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) Act. Following this structural change, we provide evidence of a reallocation between ADR programs. Compared to the pre-SOX period, firms from emerging markets, and those from countries with weak legal protection of minority shareholders, are more likely after SOX to choose Rule 144A and Level III, respectively. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubakri, Narjess; Cosset, Jean-Claude; Samet, Anis</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tempered stable and tempered infinitely divisible GARCH models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Young Shin; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Bianchi, Michele Leonardo; Fabozzi, Frank J.
In this paper, we introduce a new GARCH model with an infinitely divisible distributed innovation. This model, which we refer to as the rapidly decreasing tempered stable (RDTS) GARCH model, takes into account empirical facts that have been observed for stock and index returns, such as volatility clustering, non-zero skewness, and excess kurtosis for the residual distribution. We review the classical tempered stable (CTS) GARCH model, which has similar statistical properties. By considering a proper density transformation between infinitely divisible random variables, we can find the risk-neutral price process, thereby allowing application to option-pricing. We propose algorithms to generate scenarios based on GARCH models with CTS and RDTS innovations. To investigate the performance of these GARCH models, we report parameter estimates for the Dow Jones Industrial Average index and stocks included in this index. To demonstrate the advantages of the proposed model, we calculate option prices based on the index. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Young Shin; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Bianchi, Michele Leonardo; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting insider trading: The theory and validation in Korea Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Young S.; Lee, Jaehyun
This paper provides an empirical basis for identifying insider transactions by deriving a theoretical model, which incorporates the relationship between insider transactions and time series of stock returns. Thus, this model enables us detecting insider transactions by applying stock return time series. We show that when there is an insider transaction in the market, time series can be derived as an ARMA(1,1) process having closed solution coefficients. For validation of the model, we test publicly released insider transactions and reverse takeover events using the minute-by-minute stock price data. The selected events show higher pass rate of the detection criteria than the current detection system which shows that our model produces smaller Type II error than the existing post transaction-based cumulative abnormal return model. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Park, Young S.; Lee, Jaehyun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A cultural explanation of the foreign bias in international asset allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beugelsdijk, Sjoerd; Frijns, Bart
This paper examines the foreign bias in international asset allocation. Following extant literature in behavioral finance, we argue that a society's culture and the cultural distance between two markets play an important role in explaining the foreign bias. In particular, we hypothesize that the degree of a nation's uncertainty avoidance affects the foreign bias (more uncertainty-avoiding countries allocate less to foreign markets), as does the degree of a country's individualism (in individualistic countries performance is more directly attributed to a person and less to teams, causing these individuals to be more aggressive in their foreign asset allocations). We further expect that the degree of cultural distance between two countries affects the amount of money allocated to that market. Based on extensive robustness analyses, we find support for our hypotheses on the role of culture in international asset allocation. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beugelsdijk, Sjoerd; Frijns, Bart</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analytic valuation formulas for range notes and an affine term structure model with jump risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jang, Bong-Gyu; Yoon, Ji Hee
We derive analytic valuation formulas for range accrual notes and spread range accrual notes under an affine term structure model with jump risks. We show that the value of a range accrual note can be significantly affected by the choice of interest rate model and the arrival intensity of jump risks. We also show that misuse of the correlation between reference rates of a spread range accrual note may lead traders and risk managers to mispricing of the note. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jang, Bong-Gyu; Yoon, Ji Hee</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market-making costs in Treasury bills: A benchmark for the cost of liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffiths, Mark D.; Lindley, James T.; Winters, Drew B.
We focus on market-making costs by examining the daily bid-ask spreads for off-the-run, one-month Treasury bills around two liquidity-changing events. Event one, Salomon Brothers' supply shock, results in a roughly 2.5-basis-point increase in the spread because of an increase in ask prices; and event two, the Long-Term Capital Management demand shock, results in a doubling of the spread because of a decrease in bid prices. Our results provide a benchmark for researchers examining bid-ask spreads of securities that include a liquidity premium, a risk premium, and an asymmetric information premium. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Griffiths, Mark D.; Lindley, James T.; Winters, Drew B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives at the counter: An empirical analysis of surcharging card payments and payment behaviour in the Netherlands</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolt, Wilko; Jonker, Nicole; van Renselaar, Corry
In card payment systems, no-surcharge rules prohibit merchants from charging consumers extra for card payments. However, such rules are prohibited in the Netherlands. Dutch retailers are allowed to surcharge consumers for debit card use. This setting permits an empirical analysis of the impact of surcharging card payments on merchant acceptance and consumer payment choice. Based on consumer and retailer survey data, our analysis shows that surcharging steers consumers away from using debit cards towards cash. Half of the observed difference in debit card payment shares across retailers can be explained by this surcharge effect. Removing debit card surcharges may induce cost savings of more than EUR 50 million in the long run. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bolt, Wilko; Jonker, Nicole; van Renselaar, Corry</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are (some) consumers (finally) writing fewer checks? The role of payment characteristics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schuh, Scott; Stavins, Joanna
Since the mid-1990s, the US payment system has undergone a transformation featuring a significant decline in the use of paper checks that is quite uneven across consumers and not well understood. This paper shows that characteristics of payment instruments are the most important determinants of instrument use by estimating econometric models of consumers' adoption (extensive margin) and use (intensive margin) of checks plus six other payment instruments with a comprehensive new data source. Changes in the relative convenience and cost of checks can explain directly about 34% and 11%, respectively, of the 8.4 percentage point decline in check share from 2003 to 2006. Changes in the relative characteristics of substitute payment instruments also likely contributed indirectly to the decline in check use through an increase in the number of payment instruments per consumer, but the exact magnitude of this indirect channel cannot be identified with available data. (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Schuh, Scott; Stavins, Joanna</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price incentives and consumer payment behaviour</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Simon, John; Smith, Kylie; West, Tim
In this paper we estimate the effect of particular price incentives on consumer payment patterns using transaction-level data. We find that participation in a loyalty program and access to an interest-free period tend to increase credit card use at the expense of alternative payment methods, such as debit cards and cash. Interestingly though, the pattern of substitution from cash and debit cards differs according to the price incentive. An implication of the findings is that the Reserve Bank reforms of the Australian payments system are likely to have influenced observed payment patterns. Crown Copyright (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Simon, John; Smith, Kylie; West, Tim</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payment card rewards programs and consumer payment choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ching, Andrew T.; Hayashi, Fumiko
By using a unique data set that contains detailed information about consumer payment choice and consumers' attitudes toward each payment method, we estimate the effects of payment card rewards on consumer choice of payment methods. Our approach allows us to control for consumer heterogeneity. We find the effects of rewards to be statistically significant across five retail types. Our policy experiments suggest that for the sub-population who hold both credit and debit cards, removing rewards would increase their share of paper-based payment methods (i.e., cash and checks), measured in terms of in-store transactions, by no more than 4 percentage points. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ching, Andrew T.; Hayashi, Fumiko</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit card interchange fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rochet, Jean-Charles; Wright, Julian
We build a model of credit card pricing that explicitly takes into account credit functionality. In the model a monopoly card network always selects an interchange fee that exceeds the level that maximizes consumer surplus. If regulators only care about consumer surplus, a conservative regulatory approach is to cap interchange fees based on retailers' net avoided costs from not having to provide credit themselves. This always raises consumer surplus compared to the unregulated outcome, sometimes to the point of maximizing consumer surplus. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rochet, Jean-Charles; Wright, Julian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private cards and the bypass of payment systems by merchants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bourreau, Marc; Verdier, Marianne
This paper studies the incentives of a merchant to bypass a payment platform by issuing private cards. In our model, a payment platform allocates the total cost of a card transaction between a monopolistic issuer and a monopolistic acquirer by choosing an "interchange fee". We determine how the level of the interchange fee impacts a merchant's decision to issue private cards, if there are strategic interactions between merchants. We prove that the payment platform can only deter entry by lowering the level of the interchange fee. If the payment platform chooses to accommodate entry, we find that the total user surplus increases, but that entry is beneficial to social welfare only if the entry cost is sufficiently low. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bourreau, Marc; Verdier, Marianne</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank competition efficiency in Europe: A frontier approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolt, Wilko; Humphrey, David
There are numerous ways to indicate the degree of banking competition across countries. Antitrust authorities rely on the structure-conduct-performance paradigm while academics prefer price mark-ups (Lerner index) or correlations of input costs with output prices (H-statistic). These measures are not always strongly correlated within or across countries. Frontier efficiency analysis is used to devise an alternative indicator of competition and rank European countries by their dispersion from a "competition frontier". The frontier is determined by how well payment and other costs explain variations in loan-deposit rate spread and non-interest activity revenues. Overall, differences in competition appear to be small. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bolt, Wilko; Humphrey, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A study of competing designs for a liquidity-saving mechanism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martin, Antoine; McAndrews, James
We study two designs for a liquidity-saving mechanism (LSM), a queuing arrangement used with an interbank settlement system. With a balance-reactive LSM, banks can set a balance threshold below which payments are not released from the queue, an action not possible with a receipt-reactive LSM. Payments that are costly to delay are settled earlier with a receipt reactive LSM. Payments that are not costly to delay may be queued with a balance reactive LSM but are always delayed with a receipt reactive LSM. We show that either system can provide higher welfare. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Martin, Antoine; McAndrews, James</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The coskewness puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poti, Valerio; Wang, DengLi
We propose a novel approach to testing non-linear stochastic discount factor (SDF) specifications that arise in rational representative investor models. Our approach does not require overly-restrictive assumptions about the shape of investors' preferences, typically imposed by the extant literature, and is based instead on restrictions that rule out "good deals", i.e., arbitrage opportunities as well as unduly large Sharpe ratios. We apply this framework to test the empirical admissibility of 3 and 4-moment versions of the CAPM. We find that, while coskewness and cokurtosis risk help price a number of stock strategies and portfolios, including static strategies based on a fine industry-level diversification, momentum strategies and portfolios managed on the basis of available information, the CAPM and its 3 and 4-moment versions cannot provide an exhaustive account of observed asset returns. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Poti, Valerio; Wang, DengLi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How resilient is the German banking system to macroeconomic shocks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dovern, Jonas; Meier, Carsten-Patrick; Vilsmeier, Johannes
Macroeconomic stress testing studies often rely on rather short sample periods due to the limited availability of banking data. They may fail to appropriately account for the cyclicality in the interaction between the banking system and macroeconomic developments. In this paper, we use a newly constructed data set on German banks' income and loss statements over the past 39 years to model the interaction between the banking sector and the macroeconomy. Our VAR analysis indicates that the level of stress in the banking sector is strongly affected by monetary policy shocks. The results rationalize the active behavior of central banks observed during periods of financial market crises. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dovern, Jonas; Meier, Carsten-Patrick; Vilsmeier, Johannes</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relationship between house prices and house purchase loans: The Spanish case</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gimeno, Ricardo; Martinez-Carrascal, Carmen
This paper looks at recent developments in house purchase loans and house prices in Spain and the linkages between them. It aims at identifying deviations of these variables from their equilibrium levels, and for this purpose, we estimate a vector error-correction model. The results show that both variables are interdependent in the long-run and that both variables were above their equilibrium level by the end of the sample period (2009:Q1). The paper also offers insight into how overvaluation (overindebtedness) in house prices can lead to a false sense of no overindebtedness (house prices overvaluation). (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gimeno, Ricardo; Martinez-Carrascal, Carmen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Going private transactions, bondholder returns, and wealth transfer effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baran, Lindsay C.; King, Tao-Hsien Dolly
We examine how buyout activity and deal characteristics drive bondholder returns and the wealth transfer effects between bondholders and stockholders in going private transactions from 1981 to 2006. We find that various deal characteristics are major determinants of the cross-sectional variation in bondholder returns. In particular, a single private equity acquirer mitigates bondholder losses. On the other hand, bondholders have larger losses when a reputable buyout firm is involved in the deal. Bondholders experience losses in the 1980s and 2000s, but enjoy gains in the 1990s. Our findings remain robust to consideration of deal financing, relative cost of credit, and level of market overheating. We find a negative and significant relationship between stockholder and bondholder wealth effects, which supports the wealth transfer hypothesis. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baran, Lindsay C.; King, Tao-Hsien Dolly</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limit order revisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fong, Kingsley Y. L.; Liu, Wai-Man
This paper empirically examines limit order revisions and cancellations which contribute to a significant portion of the order activity in many order-driven markets. We document that limit orders are more likely to be revised or cancelled if they are large and near the bid-ask quote. We show that order revisions generate net economic benefits to traders. Our evidence shows strong links between these activities and limit order submission risk using bid-ask spread, volatility and post-event return as proxies. We also find that these activities are less intense when the opportunity cost to monitor a stock is high, such as during lunch hours or when stock volume relative to the entire market is low. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fong, Kingsley Y. L.; Liu, Wai-Man</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is gold a safe haven? International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baur, Dirk G.; McDermott, Thomas K.
The aim of this paper is to examine the role of gold in the global financial system. We test the hypothesis that gold represents a safe haven against stocks of major emerging and developing countries. A descriptive and econometric analysis for a sample spanning a 30 year period from 1979 to 2009 shows that gold is both a hedge and a safe haven for major European stock markets and the US but not for Australia, Canada, Japan and large emerging markets such as the BRIC countries. We also distinguish between a weak and strong form of the safe haven and argue that gold may act as a stabilizing force for the financial system by reducing losses in the face of extreme negative market shocks. Looking at specific crisis periods, we find that gold was a strong safe haven for most developed markets during the peak of the recent financial crisis. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baur, Dirk G.; McDermott, Thomas K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical analysis of herd behavior in global stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiang, Thomas C.; Zheng, Dazhi
This paper examines herding behavior in global markets. By applying daily data for 18 countries from May 25, 1988, through April 24, 2009, we find evidence of herding in advanced stock markets (except the US) and in Asian markets. No evidence of herding is found in Latin American markets. Evidence suggests that stock return dispersions in the US play a significant role in explaining the non-US market's herding activity. With the exceptions of the US and Latin American markets, herding is present in both up and down markets, although herding asymmetry is more profound in Asian markets during rising markets. Evidence suggests that crisis triggers herding activity in the crisis country of origin and then produces a contagion effect, which spreads the crisis to neighboring countries. During crisis periods, we find supportive evidence for herding formation in the US and Latin American markets. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiang, Thomas C.; Zheng, Dazhi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management, market discounts and the performance of private equity placements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, An-Sing; Cheng, Lee-Young; Cheng, Kuang-Fu; Chih, Shu-Wei
Private equity placement data allow us to determine whether sophisticated investors can uncover the true value of firms. This can be done by defining sophisticated investors as those who meet the stringent participation requirements of the private equity market. Our results show private equity issuing firms overstate their earnings in the quarter preceding private equity placement announcements and that sophisticated investors do not ask for a fair discount when purchasing the shares of the private issuing firms. We also find evidence showing that the reversal of the effects of pre-issue earnings management is a significant determinant of the long-term performance of private issues. Results further show that post-issue stock performance and operating performance of firms using "aggressive" earnings management significantly underperform those using more "conservative" earnings management. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, An-Sing; Cheng, Lee-Young; Cheng, Kuang-Fu; Chih, Shu-Wei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and the dynamic pattern of asset price adjustment: A global view</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belke, Ansgar; Orth, Walter; Setzer, Ralph
Global liquidity expansion has been very dynamic since 2001. Contrary to conventional wisdom, high money growth rates have not coincided with a concurrent rise in goods prices. At the same time, however, asset prices have increased sharply, significantly outpacing the subdued development in consumer prices. We investigate the interactions between money and goods and asset prices at the global level. Using aggregated data for major OECD countries, our VAR results support the view that different price elasticities on asset and goods markets explain the observed relative price change between asset classes and consumer goods. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Belke, Ansgar; Orth, Walter; Setzer, Ralph</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are cooperatives the weakest link in European banking? A non-parametric metafrontier approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kontolaimou, Alexandra; Tsekouras, Kostas
This paper investigates the productive performance of cooperative banking firms as compared to their commercial and savings counterparts, accounting for technology heterogeneity due to different ownership in European banking. Based on the metafrontier notion, we introduce a methodology which allows the identification of technology gaps among different bank types and their decomposition into input- and output-invariant components. Our findings suggest that the type-specific frontier corresponding to cooperative banking firms lies, to its largest part, away from the European metafrontier. Furthermore, within the cooperative bank type a dichotomy seems to arise. The decomposition results suggest that the cooperatives' technology gap is attributed to output production rather than input use. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kontolaimou, Alexandra; Tsekouras, Kostas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm age and the evolution of borrowing costs: Evidence from Japanese small firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sakai, Koji; Uesugi, Iichiro; Watanabe, Tsutomu
This paper investigates how firms' borrowing costs evolve as they age. Using a new panel data set of about 100,000 bank-dependent small firms for 1997-2002 and focusing on the channel of "adaptation" (i.e., surviving firms' borrowing costs decline as they age) and that of "selection" (i.e., total borrowing costs decline as defaulting firms exit), we find that the reputation hypothesis suggested by Diamond (1989) provides a more plausible explanation of the downward sloping age profile of borrowing costs than the firm dynamics (Cooley and Quadrini, 2001) or the relationship banking (Boot and Thakor, 1994) hypothesis. In addition, we examine whether the firm selection process in Japan has been natural or unnatural. Our findings suggest that it has been natural in that firms with lower quality are separated, face higher borrowing costs, and are eventually forced to exit, which contrasts with the results of previous studies on credit allocations in Japan, including Peek and Rosengren (2005). Further, we find that the evolution of borrowing costs is partially due to selection but is mainly attributable to adaptation. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sakai, Koji; Uesugi, Iichiro; Watanabe, Tsutomu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retail payments: New contributions, empirical results, and unanswered questions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Humphrey, David B.
We offer a selected survey of retail payments and suggest areas where additional research would prove useful. After summarizing eight papers presented at a recent Norges Bank (Central Bank of Norway) payment conference and published in this volume, we show how they, and many of the other papers presented there, have contributed to the payments literature. We also illustrate how institutional and other differences across countries led to different payment arrangements historically which now, due to technological innovation affecting bank costs, have made payment arrangements across countries more homogeneous. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Humphrey, David B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio performance gauging in discrete time using a Luenberger productivity indicator</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandouy, Olivier; Briec, Walter; Kerstens, Kristiaan; Van de Woestyne, Ignace
This paper proposes a pragmatic, discrete time indicator to gauge the performance of portfolios over time. Integrating the shortage function (Luenberger, 1995) into a Luenberger portfolio productivity indicator (Chambers, 2002), this study estimates the changes in the relative positions of portfolios with respect to the traditional Markowitz mean-variance efficient frontier, as well as the eventual shifts of this frontier over time. Based on the analysis of local changes relative to these mean-variance and higher moment (in casu, mean-variance-skewness and mean-variance-skewness-kurtosis) frontiers, this methodology allows to neatly separate between on the one hand performance changes due to portfolio strategies and on the other hand performance changes due to the market evolution. This methodology is empirically illustrated using a mimicking portfolio approach (Fama and French, 1996, 1997) using US monthly data from January 1931 to August 2007. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brandouy, Olivier; Briec, Walter; Kerstens, Kristiaan; Van de Woestyne, Ignace</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Index composition changes and the cost of incumbency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gygax, Andre F.; Otchere, Isaac
This paper provides evidence of information effects and portfolio rebalancing effects that occur when stocks are added to or excluded from the S&amp;P 500 index and finds that incumbents in the index realize negative excess returns when S&amp;P revises the composition of the index. We also find that for incumbents that are in the same industry as the added firm, the price-pressure effects are mitigated by positive industry-level information and momentum effects. For index exclusions, the magnitude of the loss sustained by incumbents from the same industry as the excluded firm is larger than that realized by the non-industry incumbents, as the negative information and momentum effects reinforce the price-pressure effects. Our results suggest that changes in the composition of the index are not information-free events; however, the portfolio rebalancing effects dominate the industry information effects. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gygax, Andre F.; Otchere, Isaac</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity skewness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roll, Richard; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
Bid-ask spreads in equities have declined on average but have become increasingly right-skewed. This finding holds across exchanges as well as size, price, and volume quartiles. Higher right-skewness is consistent with more competition among market makers; which may reduce cross-subsidization across periods of high and low asymmetric information, unlike a monopolistic regime that can maintain a relatively constant spread. Confirming this intuition, proportional differences in spreads between earnings announcements and normal periods have increased considerably even as trading costs have declined on average. Skewness also is cross-sectionally related to information proxies such as institutional holdings and analyst following. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roll, Richard; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stakeholder welfare and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiao, Yawen
Using data from the independent social choice investment advisory firm Kinder, Lydenberg, Domini (KLD), we construct a stakeholder welfare score measuring the extent to which firms meet the expectation of their non-shareholder stakeholders (such as employees, customers, communities, and environment), and find it to be associated with positive valuation effects: an increase of 1 in the stakeholder welfare score leads to an increase of 0.587 in Tobin's Q. Furthermore, the valuation effects vary across stakeholders and the aforementioned positive effects are driven by firms' performance on employee relations and environmental issues. These results suggest that stakeholder welfare (in particular, employee welfare and environmental performance) represents intangibles (such as reputation or human capital) crucial for shareholder value creation rather than private benefits managers pursue for their own social or economic needs. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiao, Yawen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tactical allocation in commodity futures markets: Combining momentum and term structure signals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuertes, Ana-Maria; Miffre, Joelle; Rallis, Georgios
This paper examines the combined role of momentum and term structure signals for the design of profitable trading strategies in commodity futures markets. With significant annualized alphas of 10.14% and 12.66%, respectively, the momentum and term structure strategies appear profitable when implemented individually. With an abnormal return of 21.02%, our double-sort strategy that exploits both momentum and term structure signals clearly outperforms the single-sort strategies. This double-sort strategy can additionally be utilized as a portfolio diversification tool. The abnormal performance of the combined portfolios cannot be explained by a lack of liquidity, data mining or transaction costs. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fuertes, Ana-Maria; Miffre, Joelle; Rallis, Georgios</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do executive stock options induce excessive risk taking?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dong, Zhiyong; Wang, Cong; Xie, Fei
We examine whether executive stock options can induce excessive risk taking by managers in firms' security issue decisions. We find that CEOs whose wealth is more sensitive to stock return volatility due to their option holdings are more likely to choose debt over equity as a capital-raising vehicle. More importantly, the pattern holds not only in firms that are underlevered relative to their optimal capital structure but also in overlevered firms. This evidence is inconsistent with executive stock options aligning the interests of managers and shareholders; rather, it supports the hypothesis that stock options sometimes make managers take on too much risk and in the process pursue suboptimal capital structure policies. (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Dong, Zhiyong; Wang, Cong; Xie, Fei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting bank loans loss-given-default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bastos, Joao A.
With the advent of the new Basel Capital Accord, banking organizations are invited to estimate credit risk capital requirements using an internal ratings based approach. In order to be compliant with this approach, institutions must estimate the loss-given-default, the fraction of the credit exposure that is lost if the borrower defaults. This study evaluates the ability of a parametric fractional response regression and a nonparametric regression tree model to forecast bank loan credit losses. The out-of-sample predictive ability of these models is evaluated at several recovery horizons after the default event. The out-of-time predictive ability is also estimated for a recovery horizon of 1 year. The performance of the models is benchmarked against recovery estimates given by historical averages. The results suggest that regression trees are an interesting alternative to parametric models in modeling and forecasting loss-given-default. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bastos, Joao A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Control/ownership structure, creditor rights protection, and the cost of debt financing: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubakri, Narjess; Ghouma, Hatem
We explore the effect of governance on bond yield-spreads and ratings in a multinational sample of firms. We find strong evidence that ultimate ownership (i.e., the voting/cash-flow rights wedge) and family control have a positive and significant effect on bond yield-spreads, and a negative and significant effect on bond ratings. Control in the hands of widely held financial firms has a positive effect on bond ratings only, while State control has no effect on either bond yield-spreads or ratings. We also find that a higher protection of debtholders' rights generally reduces bond yield-spreads and increases bond ratings. Our results additionally show that, for both bondholders and rating agencies, the enforcement of debt laws is crucially important. Finally, we document a negative effect of debt covenants on debt costs when there is a high expropriation risk and poor creditor rights protection. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubakri, Narjess; Ghouma, Hatem</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The increasing default risk of US Treasury securities due to the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nippani, Srinivas; Smith, Stanley D.
This paper paper examines the impact of the current financial crisis on long-term US Treasury yields by testing the impact of a series of events from December 2007 to March 2009 on the spread between 10-year USD LIBOR swap and 10-year US Treasury (constant maturity) rates to measure risk associated with Treasuries. Controlling for the liquidity of the two markets, the default risk of the swap, and the net foreign purchases of Treasury securities, we find that 13 of the tested 20 events have significantly negative coefficients. We conclude that the lower spread is consistent with greater default risk for US Treasury securities. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nippani, Srinivas; Smith, Stanley D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are price limits really bad for equity markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deb, Saikat Sovan; Kalev, Petko S.; Marisetty, Vijaya B.
Despite widely documented criticisms, price-limit rules are present in many equity markets around the world. Using a game-theoretic model, we argue that, if the cost of monitoring a market is high, price-limit rules are beneficial. Empirical tests based on a cross section of 43 equity markets across five continents support our theoretical prediction. We find that the probability of the existence of price-limit rules is greater in markets that incur higher monitoring costs due to poorer business disclosure, more corruption and less efficiency in legal, regulatory and technological environments. (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Deb, Saikat Sovan; Kalev, Petko S.; Marisetty, Vijaya B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital-based regulation, portfolio risk and capital determination: Empirical evidence from the US property-liability insurers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shim, Jeungbo
This paper examines the impact of capital-based regulation on the insurer's risk and capital adjustments in the US property-liability insurance industry. We conduct the three-stage least squares (3SLS) procedure to estimate a simultaneous equations model. The key finding is that undercapitalized insurers increase capital to avoid regulatory costs and take more risks to generate higher returns. We also investigate firm characteristics that determine the insurer's capital structure. The results indicate that insurers appear to rely heavily on retained earnings to make up their capital shortage and insurers with greater growth opportunity may hold high levels of capital to control for agency problems. Robustness tests with an alternative risk measure and subsamples present consistent results. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shim, Jeungbo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sentiment, executive compensation, and corporate investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grundy, Bruce D.; Li, Hui
We develop a model that predicts corporate investment level increases with investors' optimism and that the relationship between investment level and executive compensation depends on investor sentiment and other parameters. The empirical test shows that optimism is significantly and positively related to the level of investment and that executive compensation is insignificantly related to the level of investment. The managerial share ownership is positively related to the level of investment, conditional on the degree of optimism. The empirical results suggest that executives make investment decisions that not only cater to investor sentiment but also reflect their own interest in the company. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grundy, Bruce D.; Li, Hui</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How loss averse are investors in financial markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Soosung; Satchell, Steve E.
We investigate loss aversion in financial markets using a typical asset allocation problem. Our theoretical and empirical results show that investors in financial markets are more loss averse than assumed in the literature. Moreover, loss aversion changes depending on market conditions; investors become far more loss averse during bull markets than during bear markets, indicating their more profound disutility for losses when others enjoy gains. Contrary to most previous results, we find that investors are more sensitive to changes in losses than changes in gains. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hwang, Soosung; Satchell, Steve E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Other January Effect: Evidence against market efficiency?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marshall, Ben R.; Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat
The Other January Effect (OJE), which suggests positive (negative) equity market returns in January predict positive (negative) returns in the following 11 months of the year, underperforms a simple buy-and-hold strategy before and after risk-adjustment. Even the best modified OJE strategy, which benefits from several ex-post adjustments, does not generate statistically or economically significant excess returns. When the OJE is tested with a method that is consistent with investor experience it is clear the OJE is no more profitable than an 11-month strategy that uses November or December as the conditioning month. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marshall, Ben R.; Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-sale inflow and stock returns: Evidence from Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Takahashi, Hidetomo
Using a 10-year panel of flow-based information on stock borrowings and constructing a flow-based measure for shorting demand, I examine the relation between shorting demand and subsequent stock price movements. I find that the least heavily shorted stocks tend to outperform the most heavily shorted stocks and that this outperformance persists up to three months. In addition, using proxies for information asymmetry derived from the market microstructure literature, I find that this outperformance is not confined to stocks with high information asymmetry. These empirical findings indicate that short sellers act not only as informed investors who gain negative news but also as skillful investors who detect stock price deviations from fundamental values. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Takahashi, Hidetomo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Operational outages and aggregate uncertainty in the federal funds market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klee, Elizabeth
This paper uses operational problems at depository institutions in sending Fedwire payments as a proxy for aggregate uncertainty in end-of-day Fed account positions and then examines funds market behavior on those days. The results suggest that increased uncertainty is associated with a deviation of the federal funds rate from the Federal Open Market Committee's (FOMC's) target rate; the magnitude depends on the severity of the difficulty, the payment volume of the affected participant, and the time of day. The intraday standard deviation of the federal funds rate is also affected by operational outages. Moreover, extensions to Fedwire are more likely on days with possible outages, and discount window borrowing picks up on these days as well. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Klee, Elizabeth</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does information drive trading in option strategies?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Sandas, Patrik
We study trading in option strategies in the FTSE-100 index market. Trades in option strategies represent around 37% of the total number of trades and over 75% of the total trading volume in our sample. We find some evidence that order flow in volatility-sensitive option strategies contains information about future realized volatility. We do not find evidence that order flow in directionally-sensitive option strategies contains information about future returns. Overall, our evidence suggests that option strategies are used both by traders who possess non-public information about future volatility and by uninformed speculators who appear to follow unprofitable trend chasing strategies. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Sandas, Patrik</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Misreaction or misspecification? A re-examination of volatility anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, George J.; Tian, Yisong S.
Existing research examines the impact of volatility shocks on the relative pricing of long-term vs. short-term options and documents patterns of "short-horizon underreaction" and "long-horizon overreaction" in the options market. These studies, however, rely on implied volatilities derived from specific option-pricing models and are thus subject to model specification errors. In this paper, we show that these anomalous patterns are the result of model misspecification as opposed to market misreaction. We provide evidence that these patterns are consistent with, in both direction and magnitude, inherent biases in the misspecified models. We also apply a model-free approach to re-examine the anomalous patterns and find no evidence of market misreaction. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, George J.; Tian, Yisong S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and market efficiency: A large sample study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Dennis; Hrazdil, Karel
Chordia et al. (2008, hereafter CRS) examine short horizon return predictability from past order flows of large, actively traded NYSE firms across three tick size regimes and conclude that higher liquidity facilitates arbitrage trading which enhances market efficiency. We extend CRS to a comprehensive sample of all NYSE firms and examine the dynamics between liquidity and market efficiency during informational periods. Our results indicate that although all NYSE firms experience an overall improvement in market efficiency across periods of different tick size regimes, this improvement varies significantly across the portfolios of sample companies formed on the basis of trading frequency, market capitalization, and trading volume. After controlling for these factors, we further document a positive association between a continuous measure of liquidity and market efficiency, and show that this effect is amplified during periods that contain new information, as reflected in high adverse selection component of the bid-ask spread. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, Dennis; Hrazdil, Karel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate bond credit spreads and forecast dispersion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guentay, Levent; Hackbarth, Dirk
Recent research establishes a negative relation between stock returns and dispersion of analysts' earnings forecasts, arguing that asset prices more reflect the views of optimistic investors because of short-sale constraints in equity markets. In this article, we examine whether a similar effect prevails in corporate bond markets. After controlling for common bond-level, firm-level, and macroeconomic variables, we find evidence that bonds of firms with higher dispersion demand significantly higher credit spreads than otherwise similar bonds and that changes in dispersion reliably predict changes in credit spreads. This evidence suggests a limited role of short-sale constraints in our corporate bond data sets. Consistent with a rational explanation, dispersion appears to proxy largely for future cash flow uncertainty in corporate bond markets. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guentay, Levent; Hackbarth, Dirk</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Parliamentary election cycles and the Turkish banking sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baum, Christopher F.; Caglayan, Mustafa; Talavera, Oleksandr
This paper analyzes the effects of parliamentary election cycles on the Turkish banking system. Using annual bank-level data representing all banks in Turkey during 1963-2007, we present evidence of meaningful differences in the structure of bank assets, liabilities and financial performance across different stages of the parliamentary election cycle. However, we find that government-owned banks' behavior does not meaningfully differ from that of either domestic and foreign-owned private-sector banks before, during or after elections. Our estimates also show that government-owned banks underperform both domestic and foreign-owned private-sector counterparts. (C) 2010 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baum, Christopher F.; Caglayan, Mustafa; Talavera, Oleksandr</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of bond rating changes on corporate bond prices: New evidence from the over-the-counter market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>May, Anthony D.
I study the information content of bond ratings changes using daily corporate bond data from TRACE. Abnormal bond returns over a two-day event window that includes the downgrade (upgrade) are negative (positive) and statistically significant, although the reaction to upgrades is economically small. Monthly abnormal bond returns around downgrades and upgrades are statistically significant but overstate the magnitude of the reaction relative to two-day abnormal returns. Unlike the bond market, the stock market reaction to upgrades is statistically insignificant. Evidence suggests that the differing inferences on the effect of upgrades in the two markets can be attributed to wealth transfer effects rather than relative market inefficiencies. In the cross-section, the bond market response is stronger for rating changes that appear more surprising, rating changes of lower rated firms, and upgrades that move the firm from speculative grade to investment grade. (C) 2010 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>May, Anthony D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Substitution between monetary assets and consumer goods: New evidence on the monetary transmission mechanism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drake, Leigh; Fleissig, Adrian R.
This paper presents important new evidence on the monetary transmission mechanism in the context of the degree of substitution across UK monetary assets and consumption goods. Specifically, our empirical results show that durable goods expenditures are a relatively powerful element of the monetary transmission mechanism with semi-durables consumption having a somewhat smaller impact. Our results also provide an explanation for the "puzzle" that the nominal expenditure share of durables has remained relatively stable in recent years while the real expenditure share has increased dramatically. In addition, this paper demonstrates that the potential bias in substitution estimates from using artificial break-adjusted monetary data can be reduced by using the relatively new non-break adjusted monetary data produced by the Bank of England. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Drake, Leigh; Fleissig, Adrian R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank profitability and taxation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albertazzi, Ugo; Gambacorta, Leonardo
This paper investigates how banks' activity is affected by the corporate income tax. For this purpose it uses aggregate data on all main components of the profit and loss account and on the interest rate applied on loans and on deposits for the banking sector of the main industrialized countries during the period 1981-2003. With such information we are able to disentangle the extent to which a bank is able to shift its tax-burden forward to its borrowers, depositors, and purchasers of fee-generating services. The main result is that the taxation of banks' profit is equivalent to a taxation on loans and as such it exerts a substantial impact on the composition of banking sector revenues. However credit intermediaries have the ability to shift a substantial part of their corporate income tax burden and therefore differences in the level of taxation cannot explain the dispersion observed in banks' net profitability across industrialized countries. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Albertazzi, Ugo; Gambacorta, Leonardo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition for small firm banking business: Bank actions versus market structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scott, Jonathan A.; Dunkelberg, William C.
This paper addresses two questions related to the ongoing consolidation of the US banking industry and its effect on small firm financing. First, are conventional measures of market structure (e.g. geographic market size and deposit concentration) related to bank competition for small firm financial business? Second, does an increase in bank competition produce an improvement in bank services irrespective of market structure? To answer these questions we use a survey of small firm owners that asks them to report on changes in bank competition for their business. Our findings show that reports of increased competition by small firm owners are negatively related to the level of and change in deposit concentration. In addition, we find a significant positive association between changes in bank competition reported by small firms and their reports of changes in banking outcomes (e.g. service quality) that is independent of deposit concentration, firm risk, and credit usage. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Scott, Jonathan A.; Dunkelberg, William C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer credit-risk models via machine-learning algorithms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khandani, Amir E.; Kim, Adlar J.; Lo, Andrew W.
We apply machine-learning techniques to construct nonlinear nonparametric forecasting models of consumer credit risk. By combining customer transactions and credit bureau data from January 2005 to April 2009 for a sample of a major commercial bank's customers, we are able to construct out-of-sample forecasts that significantly improve the classification rates of credit-card-holder delinquencies and defaults, with linear regression R-2's of forecasted/realized delinquencies of 85%. Using conservative assumptions for the costs and benefits of cutting credit lines based on machine-learning forecasts, we estimate the cost savings to range from 6% to 25% of total losses. Moreover, the time-series patterns of estimated delinquency rates from this model over the course of the recent financial crisis suggest that aggregated consumer credit-risk analytics may have important applications in forecasting systemic risk. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khandani, Amir E.; Kim, Adlar J.; Lo, Andrew W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank fund reallocation and economic growth: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Philip C.; Jia, Chunxin; Wang, Zhicheng
This paper examines bank fund reallocation and regional economic growth based on 1991-2005 provincial-level data of four state-owned commercial banks of China that practice fund reallocation nation-wide. We find no correlation between bank fund reallocation and regional economic growth or between bank loans and regional economic growth. We find, however, a positive association between bank deposits and growth. It appears economic growth leads financial development in China, not the other way around. Furthermore, as China's market-oriented reforms deepen, fund reallocation and loans start to manifest positive effects on growth even though the banks are government owned. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Philip C.; Jia, Chunxin; Wang, Zhicheng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodity derivatives valuation with autoregressive and moving average components in the price dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paschke, Raphael; Prokopczuk, Marcel
In this paper, we develop a continuous time factor model of commodity prices that allows for higher-order autoregressive and moving average components. We document the need for these components by analyzing the convenience yield's time series dynamics. The model we propose is analytically tractable and allows us to derive closed-form pricing formulas for futures and options. Empirically, we estimate a parsimonious version of the general model for the crude oil futures market and demonstrate the model's superior performance in pricing nearby futures contracts in- and out-of-sample. Most notably, the model substantially improves the pricing of long-horizon contracts with information from the short end of the futures curve. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Paschke, Raphael; Prokopczuk, Marcel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regime switching correlation hedging</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Hsiang-Tai
This paper investigates the hedging effectiveness of commodity futures when the correlations of spot and futures returns are subject to multi-state regime shifts. An independent switching dynamic conditional correlation GARCH (IS-DCC) which is free from the problems of path-dependency and recombining is applied to model multi-regime switching correlations. The results of hedging exercises indicate that state-dependent IS-DCC outperforms state-independent DCC GARCH and three-state IS-DCC exhibits superior hedging effectiveness, illustrating importance of modeling higher-state switching correlations for dynamic futures hedging. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Hsiang-Tai</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Combining mean reversion and momentum trading strategies in foreign exchange markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Serban, Alina F.
The literature on equity markets documents the existence of mean reversion and momentum phenomena. Researchers in foreign exchange markets find that foreign exchange rates also display behaviors akin to momentum and mean reversion. This paper implements a trading strategy combining mean reversion and momentum in foreign exchange markets. The strategy was originally designed for equity markets, but it also generates abnormal returns when applied to uncovered interest parity deviations for five countries. I find that the pattern for the positions thus created in the foreign exchange markets is qualitatively similar to that found in the equity markets. Quantitatively, this strategy performs better in foreign exchange markets than in equity markets. Also, it outperforms traditional foreign exchange trading strategies, such as carry trades and moving average rules. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Serban, Alina F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An advanced perspective on the predictability in hedge fund returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wegener, Christian; von Nitzsch, Ruchger; Cengiz, Cetin
This paper advances the research on the predictability in hedge fund returns, using a broad set of risk factors within a variety of different prediction models. Accounting for the fact that returns are non-normally distributed, heteroscedastic and time-varying in their exposure to pervasive economic risk factors, we advocate a non-parametric backward elimination regression approach. The interdependencies between the monthly changes of envisaged risk factors and the subsequent hedge fund returns remain remarkably stable in terms of the observed direction of impact. Thus, taking into account the specific characteristics of this asset class, we find strong evidence of its return predictability. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wegener, Christian; von Nitzsch, Ruchger; Cengiz, Cetin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Auditor reputation and earnings management: International evidence from the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lim, Chee Yeow; Lobo, Gerald J.
We examine the relation between auditor reputation and earnings management in banks using a sample of banks from 29 countries. In particular, we examine the implications of two aspects of auditor reputation, auditor type and auditor industry specialization, for earnings management in banks. We find that both auditor type and auditor industry specialization moderate benchmark-beating (loss-avoidance and just-meeting-or-beating prior year's earnings) behavior in banks. In addition, we find that once auditor type and auditor industry specialization are included in the same tests, only auditor industry specialization has a significant impact on constraining benchmark-beating behavior. In separate tests related to income-increasing abnormal loan loss provisions, we find that both auditor type and auditor expertise constrain income-increasing earnings management. Again, in joint tests, only auditor industry expertise has a significant impact on constraining income-increasing earnings management. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lim, Chee Yeow; Lobo, Gerald J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A multi-horizon comparison of density forecasts for the S&amp;P 500 using index returns and option prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shackleton, Mark B.; Taylor, Stephen J.; Yu, Peng
We compare density forecasts of the S&amp;P 500 index from 1991 to 2004, obtained from option prices and daily and 5-min index returns. Risk-neutral densities are given by using option prices to estimate diffusion and jump-diffusion processes which incorporate stochastic volatility. Three transformations are then used to obtain real-world densities. These densities are compared with historical densities defined by ARCH models. For horizons of two and four weeks the best forecasts are obtained from risk-transformations of the risk-neutral densities, while the historical forecasts are superior for the one-day horizon; our ranking criterion is the out-of-sample likelihood of observed index levels. Mixtures of the real-world and historical densities have higher likelihoods than both components for short forecast horizons. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shackleton, Mark B.; Taylor, Stephen J.; Yu, Peng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limit-order submission strategies under asymmetric information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkhoff, Lukas; Osler, Carol L.; Schmeling, Maik
This paper provides evidence that informed traders dominate the response of limit-order submissions to shocks in a pure limit-order market. In the market we study, informed traders are highly sensitive to spreads, volatility, momentum and depth. By contrast, uninformed traders are relatively insensitive to all these market conditions. The dominance of the informed over limit-order submissions is magnified by contrasts between them and the uninformed in the use of aggressively-priced limit orders. (C) 2010 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Menkhoff, Lukas; Osler, Carol L.; Schmeling, Maik</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic portfolio choice with deferred annuities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horneff, Wolfram; Maurer, Raimond; Rogalla, Ralph
We derive the optimal life-cycle portfolio choice and consumption pattern for households facing uncertain labor income, risky capital market, and mortality risk. In addition to stocks and bonds, the households have access to deferred annuities. Deferred payout life annuities are financial contracts providing life-long income to the annuitant after a specified period of time conditional on survival. We find that deferred annuities play an important role in household portfolios and generate significant welfare gains. Households with high benefits from state pensions, moderate risk aversion and moderate labor income risk purchase deferred annuities from age 40 and gradually increase their portfolio share. At retirement, deferred annuities account for 78% of total financial wealth. Households with low state pensions and high labor income risk purchase more annuities and earlier. Uncertainty with respect to future mortality rates has the same effect, i.e. household hedge against longevity risks using deferred annuities. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Horneff, Wolfram; Maurer, Raimond; Rogalla, Ralph</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives bank securitisation? The Spanish experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cardone-Riportella, Clara; Samaniego-Medina, Reyes; Trujillo-Ponce, Antonio
This paper analyses the reasons why Spanish banks securitised in the period 2000-2007 on such a large scale that Spain has become the European country with the second-largest issuance volume after the UK. The results obtained by applying a logistic regression model to a sample of 408 observations indicate that liquidity and the search for improved performance are the decisive factors in securitisation. We find no evidence to support hypotheses regarding credit risk transfer and regulatory capital arbitrage. Our study also presents a more detailed analysis that differentiates between asset and liability securitisation programmes. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cardone-Riportella, Clara; Samaniego-Medina, Reyes; Trujillo-Ponce, Antonio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International equity portfolio allocations and transaction costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thapa, Chandra; Poshakwale, Sunil S.
In spite of the critical role of transaction cost, there are not many papers that explicitly examine its influence on international equity portfolio allocation decisions. Using bilateral cross-country equity portfolio investment data and three direct measures of transaction costs for 36 countries, we provide evidence that markets where transaction costs are lower attract greater equity portfolio investments. The results imply that future research on international equity portfolio diversification cannot afford to ignore the role of transaction costs, and policy makers, especially in emerging markets, will have to reduce transaction costs to attract higher levels of foreign equity portfolio investments. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thapa, Chandra; Poshakwale, Sunil S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leads and lags in sovereign credit ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alsakka, Rasha; ap Gwilym, Owain
This paper analyses lead-lag relationships in sovereign ratings across five agencies, and finds evidence of interdependence in rating actions. Upgrade (downgrade) probabilities are much higher, and downgrade (upgrade) probabilities are much lower for a sovereign issuer with a recent upgrade (downgrade) by another agency. S&amp;P tends to demonstrate the least dependence on other agencies, and Moody's tends to be the first mover in upgrades. Rating actions by Japanese agencies tend to lag those of the larger agencies, although there is some evidence that they lead Moody's downgrades. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alsakka, Rasha; ap Gwilym, Owain</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives the performance of convertible-bond funds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ammann, Manuel; Kind, Axel; Seiz, Ralf
This paper examines the performance of US mutual funds that invest primarily in convertible bonds. Multivariate cross-sectional analyses show a significant relation between a fund's performance and its asset composition: the higher the difference in the percentage of assets invested in convertible bonds compared to the percentage invested in stocks, the higher the performance, on average. We show that this result can be explained by factors associated with investment opportunities in the convertible-bond market and trading strategies related to convertible arbitrage, as typically performed by hedge funds. Overall, convertible-bond fund performance measured by alpha is comparable to a passive investment in stocks, bonds, and convertible bonds. This performance is the result of weak selection skills and successful timing strategies related to convertible arbitrage. (C) 2010 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ammann, Manuel; Kind, Axel; Seiz, Ralf</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accelerated investment effect of risky debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lyandres, Evgeny; Zhdanov, Alexei
In this paper we examine a new effect of risky debt on a firm's investment strategy. We call this effect "accelerated investment". It stems from a potential loss of investment option in the event of default. The possibility of default reduces the value of the option to wait and provides equity holders with an incentive to speed up investment. As a result, in the absence of wealth expropriation by a levered firm's debt holders, its shareholders exercise their investment option earlier than the shareholders of an otherwise identical all-equity firm. This result is at odds with the generally accepted intuition that in the absence of potential wealth transfers and taxes the shareholders of a levered firm would follow the same investment policy as that of an unlevered firm. In addition to providing various illustrations of the accelerated investment effect, we relate its magnitude to the presence of competition for investment opportunities. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lyandres, Evgeny; Zhdanov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The use of technical analysis by fund managers: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkhoff, Lukas
The use of technical analysis by financial market professionals is not well understood. This paper thus analyzes survey evidence from 692 fund managers in five countries, the vast majority of whom rely on technical analysis. At a forecasting horizon of weeks, technical analysis is the most important form of analysis and up to this horizon it is thus more important than fundamental analysis. Technicians are as experienced, as educated, as successful in their career and largely just as overconfident in decision-making as others. However, technical analysis is somewhat more popular in smaller asset management firms. What we find most significant is the relation of technical analysis with the view that prices are heavily determined by psychological influences. Consequently, technicians apply trend-following behavior. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Menkhoff, Lukas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the diversification discount caused by the book value bias of debt?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glaser, Markus; Mueller, Sebastian
We analyze whether the diversification discount is driven by the book value bias of corporate debt. Book values of debt may be a more downward biased proxy of the market value of debt for diversified firms, relative to undiversified firms, as diversification leads to lower firm risk. Thus, measures of firm value based on book values of debt undervalue diversified firms relative to focused firms. Our paper complements recent literature which uses market values to test the risk reduction hypothesis for a subsample of firms for which debt is traded. Alternatively, we employ market value of debt estimates for the whole firm universe. Consistent with the above hypothesis, we show that the use of book values of debt underestimates the value of diversified firms. There is no discount for mainly equity financed firms and lower distress risk and equity volatility for diversified firms. More concentrated ownership increases firm valuation. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Glaser, Markus; Mueller, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probability of information-based trading and the January effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Moonsoo
We investigate the seasonality in the probability of information-based trading (PIN)-return relationship, the 'January PIN effect'. We find that on average stock returns decrease with PIN in January, in contrast to other calendar months. This pattern is more apparent for small stocks. We argue that this seasonality is related to the January effect. According to the analysis, the December selling pressure associated with the January effect decreases in PIN, especially for small stocks. This suggests that when the price bounces back in January, low-PIN stocks will exhibit a larger return within a small stock group, leading to the negative PIN-return pattern. Furthermore, this seasonality is not the same as other January anomalies associated with momentum and idiosyncratic risk. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kang, Moonsoo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using the credit spread as an option-risk factor: Size and value effects in CAPM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Young-Soon; Min, Hong-Ghi; McDonald, Judith A.; Kim, Hwagyun; Kim, Bong-Han
This paper takes an option-theoretic approach to explain why pricing anomalies are observed when traditional CAPM is used. By extending CAPM to incorporate the option-risk factor of stocks, we show that stockholders' limited liability can explain Fama and French's size and value effects. We use bonds' excess credit spread as a proxy for stocks' default risk to control for the changing non-diversifiable option-risk characteristic of stocks. Because sensitivity to the excess credit spread becomes smaller as size increases and as value decreases, excess credit spread explains the CAPM anomalies in a fashion similar to the Fama-French factors. While the excess credit spread is significant in explaining Fama and French's size and value effects, adding the Fama-French factors does not improve the performance of our model. Our revised model resembles conditional CAPM, but it offers a more intuitive explanation for the size and value effects. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hwang, Young-Soon; Min, Hong-Ghi; McDonald, Judith A.; Kim, Hwagyun; Kim, Bong-Han</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of conglomeration on the option value of equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grass, Gunnar
Using contingent claims analysis, I quantify the effect of risk-reducing corporate diversification on the value of equity as a call option on firm assets. The impact of conglomeration on firm risk is heavily conditioned on firm size. In contrast to small firms, the risk of large firms does not decline with increasing conglomeration. Accounting for this effect, the expected equity discount is much lower than commonly assumed and can even turn into a premium if the path dependency of equity is incorporated. My results stand in direct contrast to those of Mansi and Reeb (2002) and caution against using asset substitution as a qualitative argument for explaining economy-wide value phenomena. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grass, Gunnar</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A compound option approach to model the interrelation between banking crises and country defaults: The case of Hungary 2008</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maltritz, Dominik
We analyze the Hungarian financial crisis of 2008 in a stochastic framework that advances structural credit risk models for country defaults: by applying compound option theory we consider payments for bailing-out the banking sector together with debt service payments in a joint crisis model. We estimate the model parameters by applying the time series maximum-likelihood approach of Duan (1994) on yield spreads of Hungarian Bonds. We find that difficulties in acquiring funds for debt servicing in combination with high outstanding debt triggered the crisis, rather than problems in the domestic banking sector. The estimated crisis probabilities dramatically rise during 2008. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maltritz, Dominik</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economic function of credit rating agencies - What does the watchlist tell us?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bannier, Christina E.; Hirsch, Christian W.
Credit rating agencies do not only disclose simple ratings but announce watchlists (rating reviews) and outlooks as well. This paper analyzes the economic function underlying the review procedure. Using Moody's rating data between 1982 and 2004, we find that for borrowers of high creditworthiness, rating agencies employ watchlists primarily in order to improve the delivery of information. For low-quality borrowers, in contrast, the review procedure seems to have developed into an implicit contract 5 la Boot et al. (2006), inducing the companies "on watch" to abstain from risk-augmenting actions. The agencies' economic role hence appears to have been enhanced from a pure information certification towards an active monitoring function. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bannier, Christina E.; Hirsch, Christian W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of bank ownership and deposit insurance on monetary policy transmission</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andries, Natalia; Billon, Steve
In this paper we develop a theoretical model with a representative bank whose ownership is shared between state and private sector. The bank faces a risk of failure and provides private and public explicit deposit insurance. Banks owned to a larger extent by the government are more able to counteract a restrictive monetary policy because of their capacity to raise additional volume of deposits. Therefore, the greater the state's share in the bank ownership, the less the impact of a monetary tightening on the level of loan supply. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andries, Natalia; Billon, Steve</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of portfolio selection with background risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Chonghui; Ma, Yongkai; An, Yunbi
This paper investigates the impact of background risk on an investor's portfolio choice in a mean-variance framework, and analyzes the properties of efficient portfolios as well as the investor's hedging behaviour in the presence of background risk. Our model implies that the efficient portfolio with background risk can be separated into two independent components: the traditional mean-variance efficient portfolio, and a self-financing component constructed to hedge against background risk. Our analysis also shows that the presence of background risk shifts the efficient frontier of financial assets to the right with no changes in its shape. Moreover, both the composition of the hedge portfolio and the location of the efficient frontier are greatly affected by a number of background risk factors, including the proportion of background assets in total wealth and the correlation between background risk and financial risk. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Chonghui; Ma, Yongkai; An, Yunbi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and systematic risk in European banking: Empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uhde, Andre; Michalak, Tobias C.
Using a unique dataset of 592 cash and synthetic securitizations issued by 54 banks from the EU-15 plus Switzerland over the period from 1997 to 2007 this paper provides empirical evidence that credit risk securitization has a positive impact on the increase of European banks systematic risk. Baseline results hold when comparing estimated beta coefficients with a control group of similar non-securitizing banks. Building several sub-samples we additionally find that (a) the increase in systematic risk is more relevant for larger banks that repeatedly engage in securitization, (b) securitization is more important for small and medium financial institutions, (c) banks have a higher incentive to retain the larger part of credit risk as a quality signal at the beginning of the securitization business in Europe, and (d) the overall risk-shifting effect due to securitization is more distinct when the pre-event systematic risk is low. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Uhde, Andre; Michalak, Tobias C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multi-country event-study methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, Cynthia J.; Cowan, Arnold R.; Salotti, Valentina
We provide the first simulation evidence of event-study test performance in multi-country non-US samples. The nonparametric rank and generalized sign tests are more powerful than two common parametric tests, especially in multi-day windows. The two nonparametric tests are mostly well specified, but neither is perfectly specified in all situations. The parametric standardized cross-sectional test can provide a useful robustness check but is less powerful than the nonparametric tests and rejects too often in single-market samples and when firm-specific events affect the market index. Local-currency market-model abnormal returns using national market indexes are sufficient. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campbell, Cynthia J.; Cowan, Arnold R.; Salotti, Valentina</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does gender matter in bank-firm relationships? Evidence from small business lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bellucci, Andrea; Borisov, Alexander; Zazzaro, Alberto
In this paper we study the relevance of the gender of the contracting parties involved in lending. We show that female entrepreneurs face tighter credit availability, even though they do not pay higher interest rates. The effect is independent of the information available about the borrower and holds if we control for unobservable individual effects. The gender of the loan officer is also important: we find that female officers are more risk-averse or less self-confident than male officers as they tend to restrict credit availability to new, un-established borrowers more than their male counterparts. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bellucci, Andrea; Borisov, Alexander; Zazzaro, Alberto</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavior of liquidity and returns around Canadian seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kryzanowski, Lawrence; Lazrak, Skander; Rakita, Ian
Spread costs and their adverse selection and temporary components for Canadian SEOs follow an approximate V-shaped pattern with a trough at the closing window. Enhanced ownership diffusion partly explains the decrease in these spread costs post-SEO completion versus pre-SEO announcement. SE spread costs decrease after the April 1996 TSX decimalization. The adverse selection cost of privately-placed Canadian SEOs decreases after Multilateral Instrument 45-102 reduced the lock-up period to four months in 2001. Consistent with results for non-US SEOs, negative abnormal returns (ARs) occur in announcement windows for undifferentiated SEOs. ARs are significantly different for public (significantly negative) versus private (insignificantly positive) SEOs consistent with their associated differential reductions in information asymmetry. Conditional residual volatilities decrease post-announcement, consistent with a diminished temporary spread cost and expected behavior following an unanticipated event. (C) 2010 Elsevier BAT. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kryzanowski, Lawrence; Lazrak, Skander; Rakita, Ian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>