<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JBF10</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Inventories, sales uncertainty, and financial strength</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caglayan, Mustafa; Maioli, Sara; Mateut, Simona
We investigate the empirical linkages between sales uncertainty and firms' inventory investment behavior while controlling for firms' financial strength. Using large panels of manufacturing firms from several European countries we find that higher sales uncertainty leads to larger stocks of inventories. We also identify an indirect effect of sales uncertainty on inventory accumulation through the financial strength of firms. Our results provide evidence that financial strength mitigates the adverse effects of uncertainty. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caglayan, Mustafa; Maioli, Sara; Mateut, Simona</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The nature of the foreign listing premium: A cross-country examination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkissian, Sergei; Schill, Michael J.
An expanding literature asserts that non-US firms achieve a unique valuation premium for listing on US equity markets. In this paper we test the uniqueness of the US foreign listing premium by examining the premium achieved by foreign listings across a global set of stock exchanges. We highlight that the documented valuation premium for listing on US exchanges is not unique but common to many home and host markets including US firms that list abroad. The cross-sectional variation in the valuation premium appears to have little association with such cross-country institutional features as investor protection rules, law enforcement practice, or accounting disclosure standards. Rather the premium appears most related to variation in pre-listing valuation ratios. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sarkissian, Sergei; Schill, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variable annuities and the option to seek risk: Why should you diversify?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mahayni, Antje; Schneider, Judith C.
We analyze the impacts of an additional rider incorporated in recent retirement products. The payoff is linked to the performance of a multi asset investment strategy and includes a minimum interest rate guarantee. In addition, the buyer receives the option to decide on the investments dynamically. Prominent examples are so called variable annuities. Due to the embedded guarantee, these products are interesting for risk averse investors who benefit from diversification. However, the price setting of the provider takes into account the most risky strategy. This implies that the investor mitigates optimally between the diversification and the worst case strategy. We analyze the distortion and utility effects caused by the additional rider in the presence of background risk and borrowing constraints. A simulation analysis sheds light on the question if the additional rider is worth its costs. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mahayni, Antje; Schneider, Judith C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relationship between net interest margin and noninterest income using a system estimation approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, James
This paper examines the determinants of bank net interest margin (NIM) and non-traditional banking activities (NII). A system estimation approach is employed to control for the simultaneity between NIM and NII for commercial banks in a group of 28 financially liberalized countries during the period between 1997 and 2004. We find a statistically significant negative relationship between NIM and Nil for the period between 1997 and 2002. A generally positive but statistically insignificant association between NIM and NII is found for the subsequent period (2003-2004). Banks' increasing involvement in non-traditional activities is negatively correlated with risk-adjusted profitability measures in the former subperiod, suggesting no obvious diversification benefits. However, the share of noninterest income is positively related to the return on assets (ROA) and the return on equity (ROE) for the latter subsample. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nguyen, James</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivatives traders' reaction to mispricing in the underlying equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hayunga, Darren K.; Holowczak, Richard D.; Lung, Peter P.; Nishikawa, Takeshi
This article examines trading behavior in the options market conditioned on mispricing in the underlying stock. We investigate the price equilibrium between the observed equity asset and the options-implied synthetic share as well as the relative divergence between the two prices. We find a consistently positive relation between the level of stock mispricing and violations of the upper-boundary condition using derivatives, along with an increase in price divergence. To control for the effect of shorting limitations on mispricing, we further examine prices during the short-sale ban in 2008. The results hold and in many instances are more significant during the ban period. Given the persistent disequilibria between the synthetic and observed stock prices, we argue the results are evidence of informed trading in the derivatives market. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hayunga, Darren K.; Holowczak, Richard D.; Lung, Peter P.; Nishikawa, Takeshi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the diversification benefits of commodities from the perspective of euro investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belousova, Julia; Dorfleitner, Gregor
This paper investigates the diversification contribution of several commodities to a portfolio of traditional assets from the perspective of a euro investor. The approach applied in our analysis has high informational content as it differentiates between the sources of the diversification benefits in a statistically significant way. The results indicate that the diversification contribution varies greatly amongst the different commodities. Industrial metals, agriculturals and livestock contribute to the reduction of risk, while energy and precious metals contribute to both the reduction of the level of risk and to the improvement of return. The differentiation between bull and bear markets reveals that investors can enhance the portfolio performance by changing exposure into individual commodities. Investors can benefit from the diversification gains through financial instruments as the diversification gains hold both in the sample of physical commodity and commodity futures. Overall, the results confirm that commodities are valuable investments from the perspective of diversification. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Belousova, Julia; Dorfleitner, Gregor</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional ownership, analyst following, and share prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernando, Chitru S.; Gatchev, Vladimir A.; Spindt, Paul A.
We study the mutual relationships between institutional ownership, analyst following and share prices. We show that the pressure on firms to set lower share prices to attract analysts is attenuated by institutional monitoring. Our theory refutes the assumed causal relation between share price and institutional ownership, attributed to the share price-liquidity relation, and we show empirically that share prices and institutional ownership are positively related after controlling for liquidity. Our study provides a rationale for why better firms generally maintain higher share price levels, and offers new insights into the puzzling empirical linkages observed between nominal share price levels and firm fundamentals. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fernando, Chitru S.; Gatchev, Vladimir A.; Spindt, Paul A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pitfalls in backtesting Historical Simulation VaR models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Escanciano, Juan Carlos; Pei, Pei
Historical Simulation (HS) and its variant, the Filtered Historical Simulation (FHS), are the most popular Value-at-Risk forecast methods at commercial banks. These forecast methods are traditionally evaluated by means of the unconditional backtest. This paper formally shows that the unconditional backtest is always inconsistent for backtesting HS and FHS models, with a power function that can be even smaller than the nominal level in large samples. Our findings have fundamental implications in the determination of market risk capital requirements, and also explain Monte Carlo and empirical findings in previous studies. We also propose a data-driven weighted backtest with good power properties to evaluate HS and MS forecasts. A Monte Carlo study and an empirical application with three US stocks confirm our theoretical findings. The empirical application shows that multiplication factors computed under the current regulatory framework are downward biased, as they inherit the inconsistency of the unconditional backtest. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Escanciano, Juan Carlos; Pei, Pei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking crises and market discipline: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cubillas, Elena; Rosa Fonseca, Ana; Gonzalez, Francisco
This paper analyzes the effect of banking crises on market discipline in an international sample of banks. We also evaluate how bank regulation, supervision, institutions, and crisis intervention policies shape the effect of banking crises on market discipline. We control for unobservable bank, country, and time specific effects using a panel data set of banks from 66 countries around 79 banking crises. The results suggest that on average market discipline weakens after a banking crisis. This weakening is higher in countries where bank regulation, supervision, and institutions promoted market discipline before the banking crisis, and where a more accommodative approach is adopted to resolve it. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cubillas, Elena; Rosa Fonseca, Ana; Gonzalez, Francisco</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are banks using hidden reserves to beat earnings benchmarks? Evidence from Germany</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bornemann, Sven; Kick, Thomas; Memmel, Christoph; Pfingsten, Andreas
Section 340f of the German Commercial Code allows banks to provision against the special risks inherent to the banking business by building hidden reserves. Beyond risk provisioning, these reserves are implicitly accepted as an earnings management device. By analyzing financial statements of German banks for the period 1997-2009, we see these hidden reserves being used to (1) avoid a negative net income, (2) avoid a drop in net income compared to the previous year, (3) avoid a shortfall in net income compared to a peer group, and (4) reduce the variability of banks' net income over time. Our analysis also shows that if bank managers are unable to reach the targets as set out in (1)-(3), they are more inclined to keep the hidden reserves for use in future periods. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bornemann, Sven; Kick, Thomas; Memmel, Christoph; Pfingsten, Andreas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political connection and leverage: Some Malaysian evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bliss, Mark A.; Gul, Ferdinand A.
This paper extends prior work on the linkage between politically connected (PCON) firms and capital structure in developing countries. Specifically, this paper focuses on the association between Malaysian PCON firms and leverage, and is motivated by the results of Fraser et al. (2006) who report a positive association between leverage and political patronage. Controlling for a potential misspecification in that paper, this study documents that a significant proportion (almost 12%) of the Malaysian PCON firms have negative equity, and builds on the previous paper by providing fresh evidence that market to book ratio is positively associated with leverage, and that borrowing PCON firms have significantly lower ROA compared to non-PCON firms. (C) 2012 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bliss, Mark A.; Gul, Ferdinand A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global equity fund performance, portfolio concentration, and the fundamental law of active management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huij, Joop; Derwall, Jeroen
This paper investigates the relation between portfolio concentration and the performance of global equity funds. Concentrated funds with higher levels of tracking error display better performance than their more broadly diversified counterparts. We show that the observed relation between portfolio concentration and performance is mostly driven by the breadth of the underlying fund strategies; not just by fund managers' willingness to take big bets. Our results indicate that when investors strive to select the best-performing funds, they should not only consider fund managers' tracking-error levels. More important is that they take into account the extent to which fund managers carefully allocate their risk budget across multiple investment strategies and have concentrated holdings in multiple market segments simultaneously. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huij, Joop; Derwall, Jeroen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Specialists as risk managers: The competition between intermediated and non-intermediated markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mao, Wen; Pagano, Michael S.
We develop a model that analyzes competition between a non-intermediated market (such as an electronic communications network) and an intermediated market (such as via the market specialist's structure within the NYSE) when both markets are allowed to trade the same securities. Specialists are viewed as providers of a "volatility dampening" service, a mechanism for reducing round-trip trading costs, as well as an "order execution risk management" service. The economic value of these three specialist services is determined by five key factors (the difference in spreads between the two financial market types, investors' holding periods, the specialist's quoted spread in relation to the asset's price, the relative probability of executing an order in the intermediated market, and the short-term risk-free rate). (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mao, Wen; Pagano, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A framework for journal assessment: The case of the Journal of Banking &amp; Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borokhovich, Kenneth A.; Lee, Allissa A.; Simkins, Betty J.
We propose a citation-based framework for the assessment of journal influence and demonstrate its application with the Journal of Banking and Finance. The framework assesses the current position of the journal, its trends and the reasons behind the trends. The Journal of Banking and Finance is found to be one of the leading journals in the field of finance and its influence is increasing. In fact, it appears to be part of a group of leading journals that is separating itself from the other journals that are generally regarded as peers. Finally, the Journal of Banking and Finance is found to be the only leading finance journal with a high concentration of banking articles, making it a primary outlet for influential articles in this area. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Borokhovich, Kenneth A.; Lee, Allissa A.; Simkins, Betty J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance journal rankings and tiers: An Active Scholar Assessment methodology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Currie, Russell R.; Pandher, Gurupdesh S.
This study uses respondent data from a web-based survey of active finance scholars (45% response rate from 37 countries) to endogenously rank 83 finance journals by quality and importance. journals are further tiered into four groups (A, B, C and D) and stratified into "upper", "middle" and "lower" tier categories (e.g. A+, A and A-) by estimating a nested regression with random journal-within-tier effects. The comprehensive and endogenous ranking of finance journals based on the Active Scholar Assessment (ASA) methodology can help authors evaluate the strategic aspects of placing their research, facilitate assessment of research achievement by tenure and promotion committees: and assist university libraries in better managing their journal resources. Study findings from active researchers in the field also provide useful guidance to editorial boards for enhancing their journal standing. Crown Copyright (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Currie, Russell R.; Pandher, Gurupdesh S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market discipline of banks: Why are yield spreads on bank-issued subordinated notes and debentures not sensitive to bank risks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balasubrarnnian, Bhanu; Cyree, Ken B.
The default risk sensitivity of yield spreads on bank-issued subordinated notes and debentures (SNDs) decreased after banks started issuing trust-preferred securities (TPS). The too-big-to-fail (TBTF) discount on yield spreads is absent prior to the LTCM bailout, but the size discount doubles after the LTCM bailout. Prior to TPS issuance and the LTCM bailout, SND yield spreads are sensitive to conventional firm-specific default risk measures, but not after the bailout. We find paradigm shift in determinants of yield spreads after the LTCM bailout. Yield spreads on TPS are sensitive to default risks and can provide an additional source of market discipline. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balasubrarnnian, Bhanu; Cyree, Ken B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial entrenchment, equity payout and capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Hao
I develop a contingent claims model to examine the impacts of managerial entrenchment on capital structure and security valuation. The analysis shows that managers' self-interested leverage choices deviate significantly from the optimal leverages that maximize firm values, partially explaining the suboptimal leverage ratios observed empirically (Graham, 2000). Both the extent and sensitivity of the deviations are affected by firm characteristics, debt features and default solutions. The shareholder-manager conflicts over risk level and cash payout vary dynamically with a firm's financial health. Managerial entrenchment does not mitigate the agency problems of debt since managers' discretionary decisions on milking properties or asset substitution could be driven by incentives to increase their own utility. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Hao</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Future labor income growth and the cross-section of equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Dongcheol; Kim, Tong Suk; Min, Byoung-Kyu
This paper examines the equilibrium relation between future labor income growth and expected asset returns; it proposes revisions in the expectation of future labor income growth as a macroeconomic state variable and suggests a three-factor model, including a factor related to this variable, along with the consumption growth factor and the market factor. The proposed future labor income growth factor is positively associated with the Fama-French factors and subsumes their explanatory power in explaining the cross-section of stock returns. These results provide a possible economic explanation for the roles of the Fama-French factors: they are compensation for higher exposure to the risk related to changes in the value of human capital. This paper also compares the performance of the proposed three-factor model with other competing models and finds that the proposed model specification better captures cross-sectional variation in average returns than any of the competing asset pricing models considered. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Dongcheol; Kim, Tong Suk; Min, Byoung-Kyu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of CD rates and monetary policy transmission</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nishiyama, Yasuo
The paper investigates the term structure of CD rates and its relationship with the federal funds rate or monetary policy. The term structure derived in this paper is governed primarily by the federal funds rate and secondarily by banks' income smoothing behavior. It is consistent with the estimation results and differs significantly from the standard term structure of interest rates. The downturn phase of business cycles appears to be accompanied by more aggressive income smoothing by banks (compared with the upturn phase) due to their pessimistic expectations of future profits. The compositional shift in banks' liabilities during the downturn phase away from CDs toward transaction deposits may pose a greater withdrawal risk for banks. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nishiyama, Yasuo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting time-variation in corporate bond index returns: A smooth transition regression model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, XiaoHua; Maringer, Dietmar
This paper investigates the time-varying corporate bond index returns in a multi-factor smooth transition regression model. We find that expected index returns vary between weak and strong economic regimes, where the transition from one regime to the other is governed by the 3-quartered growth of industrial production. Weak economic regimes are characterized by low growth of industrial production, vice versa for strong economic regimes. Further, risk factor sensitivities are generally more negative in strong economic regimes than in weak regimes, implying that index returns are low when economic conditions are good and high when economic conditions are poor. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, XiaoHua; Maringer, Dietmar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, interlisting and market structure in options trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khoury, Nabil; Perrakis, Stylianos; Savor, Marko
This paper applies a game theory approach to examine the effects of a market structure change in options trading from a monopoly to a Cournot-type oligopoly that occurred in two successive periods on the Montreal exchange. We analyze the intra-day behaviour of option bid-ask spreads and find that cross-listing has a differential impact on spreads, affecting quoted but not effective spreads under oligopoly. We also find that the impact of the change in structure on effective spreads comes mostly from an increase in limit orders and is consistent with a switch from Cournot to Bertrand-type strategic behaviour for such orders. We conclude that market structure effects within an options exchange are enough to realize most of the benefits of inter-market competition even in the context of market thinness. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khoury, Nabil; Perrakis, Stylianos; Savor, Marko</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dominant institutional owners and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Victoria Ruiz-Mallorqui, Maria; Santana-Martin, Domingo J.
This research analyzes the impact of control by dominant institutional owners (banking institutions and investment funds) on firm value. The analysis considers the level of voting rights in the hands of the dominant institutional owner and other large shareholders. The results reveal a different effect on value depending on whether the dominant institutional investor is a banking institution or an investment fund. Moreover, the results show that the presence of other large shareholders affects firm value when a dominant institutional owner controls the firm. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Victoria Ruiz-Mallorqui, Maria; Santana-Martin, Domingo J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global financial crisis, extreme interdependences, and contagion effects: The role of economic structure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aloui, Riadh; Ben Aiessa, Mohamed Safouane; Nguyen, Duc Khuong
The paper examines the extent of the current global crisis and the contagion effects it induces by conducting an empirical investigation of the extreme financial interdependences of some selected emerging markets with the US. Several copula functions that provide the necessary flexibility to capture the dynamic patterns of fat tail as well as linear and nonlinear interdependences are used to model the degree of cross-market linkages. Using daily return data from Brazil, Russia, India, China (BRIC) and the US, our empirical results show strong evidence of time-varying dependence between each of the BRIC markets and the US markets, but the dependency is stronger for commodity-price dependent markets than for finished-product export-oriented markets. We also observe high levels of dependence persistence for all market pairs during both bullish and bearish markets. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aloui, Riadh; Ben Aiessa, Mohamed Safouane; Nguyen, Duc Khuong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics of international integration of government securities' markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Manmohan S.; Okimoto, Tatsuyoshi
This paper investigates the dynamics of international government bond market integration in six of the G7 economies over two decades leading up to the global crisis. It examines whether such integration had been significant; the extent to which integration at the short and long end of the yield curve differed; the nature of such integration; and the extent of the decoupling of the long rates from short rates. These issues are investigated using the rigorous smooth-transition copula-GARCH model framework. The results show that integration at the long end of the yield curve had been increasing, had become pronounced, and was significantly greater than at the short end. Decoupling between the short and long end of the yield curve was notable, with important implications for the efficacy of monetary policy in the period before the crisis. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kumar, Manmohan S.; Okimoto, Tatsuyoshi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International evidence on bond risk premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sekkel, Rodrigo
This paper revisits the study of time-varying excess bond returns in international bond markets. Using newly available yield curve data from 10 different countries with independent monetary policy, I test the robustness of Cochrane and Piazzesi (2005). For most countries in my sample, I find more modest predictive power for forward rates than originally found by Cochrane and Piazzesi (2005) for the US. Their single-factor model captures well the predictability in international data, and this factor also tends to have a tent-shape in most countries of my sample. CP factors are more idiosyncratic across countries than yields or forward rates. Finally, I show that the recent financial crisis has significantly affected the predictability of excess bond returns. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sekkel, Rodrigo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The high-frequency response of exchange rates to monetary policy actions and statements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosa, Carlo
This paper investigates the impact of US monetary policy on the level and volatility of exchange rates using an event study with intraday data for five currencies (the US dollar exchange rate versus the euro, the Canadian dollar, the British pound, the Swiss franc, and the Japanese yen). I construct two indicators of news about monetary policy stemming separately from policy decisions and from balance of risk statements. Estimation results show that both policy decisions and communication have economically large and highly significant effects on the exchange rates, with the surprise component of statements accounting for most of the explainable variation in exchange rate returns in response to monetary policy. This paper also shows that exchange rates tend to absorb FOMC monetary surprises within 30-40 min from the announcement release. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rosa, Carlo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value and capacity of tax shields: An analysis of the slicing approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qi, Howard
Correctly valuing tax shields has been a challenge in corporate valuation. A recent study by Liu (2009) introduces the slicing approach to separating the tax shield into the earned and unearned parts. Liu also shows that the MM results are wrong, and claims that the slicing approach has finally resolved the issue of pricing tax shields, thereby bringing closure to the topic. However, through careful analysis, we refute Liu's main claims and restore the MM results. There are still open questions and the topic is not completely resolved as claimed in Liu (2009). (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Qi, Howard</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset-liability management under time-varying investment opportunities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferstl, Robert; Weissensteiner, Alex
Stochastic linear programming is a suitable numerical approach for solving practical asset-liability management problems. In this paper, we consider a multi-stage setting under time-varying investment opportunities and propose a decomposition of the benefits in dynamic re-allocation and predictability effects. We use a first-order unrestricted vector autoregressive process to model asset returns and state variables and include, in addition to equity returns and dividend-price ratios, Nelson/Siegel parameters to account for the evolution of the yield curve. The objective is to minimize the Conditional Value at Risk of shareholder value, i.e., the difference between the mark-to-market value of (financial) assets and the present value of future liabilities. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferstl, Robert; Weissensteiner, Alex</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does ownership matter in mergers? A comparative study of the causes and consequences of mergers by family and non-family firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shim, Jungwook; Okamuro, Hiroyuki
Although the family firm is the dominant type among listed corporations worldwide, few papers investigate the behavioral differences between family and non-family firms. We analyze the differences in merger decisions and the consequences between them by using a unique Japanese dataset from a period of high economic growth. Empirical results suggest that family firms are less likely to merge than non-family firms are. Moreover, we find a positive relationship between pre-merger family ownership and the probability of mergers. Thus, ownership structure is an important determinant of mergers. Finally, we find that non-family firms benefit more from mergers than family firms do. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shim, Jungwook; Okamuro, Hiroyuki</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does deposit insurance improve financial intermediation? Evidence from the Russian experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernykh, Lucy; Cole, Rebel A.
This study examines how the introduction of deposit insurance affects depositors and banks, using the deposit-insurance scheme introduced into the Russian banking system as a natural experiment. The fundamental research question is whether the introduction of deposit insurance leads to a more effective banking system as evidenced by increased deposit-taking and decreased reliance upon State-owned banks as custodians of retail deposits. We find that banks entering the new deposit-insurance system increase both their level of retail deposits and their ratios of retail deposits to total assets relative to banks that do not enter the new deposit insurance system. These results hold up in a multivariate panel-data analysis that controls for bank- and time-random effects. The longer a bank has been entered into the deposit insurance system, the greater is its level of deposits and its ratio of deposits to assets. Moreover, this effect is stronger for regional banks and for smaller banks. We also find that implementation of the new deposit-insurance system has the effect of "leveling the playing field" between State-owned banks and privately owned banks. Finally, we find strong evidence of moral hazard following implementation of deposit insurance in the form of increased bank risk-taking. Financial risk and, to a lesser degree, operating risk increase following implementation. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chernykh, Lucy; Cole, Rebel A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regime-switching analysis of ADR home market pass-through</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Hui; Yang, Jiawen
We model and estimate ADRs' home market pass-through and pricing-to-market using a regime-switching approach, which nests the two regimes in a conditional capital asset pricing model and treats any changes in these two regimes probabilistically. Our results from the 1998 to 2006 data show that the pricing-to-market regime dominates ADRs from China and Japan, whereas the home market pass-through regime dominates ADRs from Argentina and Germany when their respective home markets are volatile. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Hui; Yang, Jiawen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected returns, risk premia, and volatility surfaces implicit in option market prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Camara, Antonio; Krehbiel, Tim; Li, Weiping
This article presents a pure exchange economy that extends Rubinstein (1976) to show how the jump-diffusion option pricing model of Merton (1976) is altered when jumps are correlated with diffusive risks. A non-zero correlation between jumps and diffusive risks is necessary in order to resolve the positively sloped implied volatility term structure inherent in traditional jump diffusion models. Our evidence is consistent with a negative covariance, producing a non-monotonic term structure. For the proposed market structure, we present a closed form asset pricing model that depends on the factors of the traditional jump-diffusion models, and on both the covariance of the diffusive pricing kernel with price jumps and the covariance of the jumps of the pricing kernel with the diffusive price. We present statistical evidence that these covariances are positive. For our model the expected stock return, jump and diffusive risk premiums are non-linear functions of time. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Camara, Antonio; Krehbiel, Tim; Li, Weiping</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fiscal policy and financial market movements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tagkalakis, Athanasios
This paper estimates fiscal policy reaction function in order to investigate the links between financial market movements and fiscal policy outcomes. An increase in asset prices affects in a positive and significant manner primary balances, with the response reflecting both an increase in government revenues and a fall in government spending. The most important impact on fiscal balances is due to changes in residential property prices. Changes in equity and commercial property prices are also important determinants of fiscal balances. Our findings suggest that the steepening of the slope of the yield curve contributes to expenditure based fiscal discipline. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tagkalakis, Athanasios</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Options, short-sale constraints and market efficiency: A new perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phillips, Blake
This paper undertakes a new investigation of the potential for options to mitigate short-sale constraints. I find that option introduction alleviates 79% of the price adjustment efficiency disparity between short-sale constrained and unconstrained stocks in relation to negative news. No significant improvement in adjustment efficiency is found in response to positive information. These results are robust to controls for endogeneity biases associated with the option introduction selection process. Further, I find evidence that post-option improvement in efficiency is similar in relation to private and public information. This suggests that short-sale constraint effects stem, at least in part, from an irrational, optimism bias or another behavioral source as suggested theoretically by Miller (1977). Collectively, these results suggest that options act as an effective substitute to short-sales, significantly contributing to the informational efficiency of the market. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Phillips, Blake</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment intensity of currencies and the random walk hypothesis: Cross-currency evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chuluun, Tuugi; Eun, Cheol S.; Kilic, Rehim
This paper studies the cross-currency and temporal variations in the random walk behavior in exchange rates. We characterize currencies with relatively large investment flows as investment intensive and conjecture that the more investment intensive a currency is, the closer its exchange rate adheres to random walk. Using 29 floating bilateral USD exchange rates, we find that the higher the investment intensity, the less likely it is to reject random walk and the smaller the deviation from random walk is. However, the effect of investment intensity is non-monotonic. Application of threshold models shows that after investment intensity reaches the estimated thresholds, the level of investment intensity has no further effect on the deviation from random walk. These findings help reconcile the previous conflicting results on the random walk in exchange rates by focusing on the effect of cross-currency and temporal variations in investment intensity. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chuluun, Tuugi; Eun, Cheol S.; Kilic, Rehim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International fund investment and local market returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jinjarak, Yothin; Wongswan, Jon; Zheng, Huanhuan
International fund investment in bonds and equities is characterized by a positive association between current net inflows and contemporaneous and past market returns: positive-feedback trading, while being possibly profitable for international fund investors, could be destabilizing for the underlying markets. Allowing for interactions between equity investment and bond investment, our panel vector autoregression shows that past equity returns contain useful information in forecasting equity and bond flows and that bond flows impact future equity returns positively. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jinjarak, Yothin; Wongswan, Jon; Zheng, Huanhuan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global financial crisis, international financial architecture and regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder governance, bondholder governance, and managerial risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>King, Tao-Hsien Dolly; Wen, Min-Ming
We examine the relation between the overall corporate governance structure and managerial risk-taking behavior. We find that the overall governance structure has a significant impact on how managers make decisions on investment policy: strong bondholder governance motivates more low-risk investments such as capital expenditure and lower high-risk investments such as R&amp;D expenditures, whereas weak shareholder governance (entrenched managers) leads to more R&amp;D expenditures. Moreover, we find that the effects of governance on investment policy differ significantly between speculative and investment-grade firms. For speculative firms, strong bondholder or shareholder governance leads to more capital expenditures and low R&amp;D investments. For investment-grade firms, strong bondholder or shareholder governance leads to low capital expenditures and an insignificant impact on R&amp;D investments. Furthermore, financing and investment covenants exhibit strong binding power to deter risky investments. Finally, a more dependent (or a less independent) board is associated with low capital expenditures and high R&amp;D investments. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>King, Tao-Hsien Dolly; Wen, Min-Ming</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fire sale acquisitions: Myth vs. reality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, James; Mauck, Nathan
We provide empirical evidence on the conjecture that in economic crises, firms could be forced to sell at deep discounts, or fire sale prices. Using the conventional stock price near the announcement date, we find instead distressed firms in crisis periods receive a 30% higher offer premium than distressed firms in normal periods: they also receive a 34% higher premium than non-distressed firms in crisis periods. Acquirers also do not gain, at announcement and over the long-term. Acquirers, however, may perceive they realize fire sale discounts if the reference is the targets' highest price in the previous 52 weeks. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, James; Mauck, Nathan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interbank market integration, loan rates, and firm leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Popov, Alexander; Ongena, Steven
This paper investigates the effect of interbank market integration on small firm finance in the build-up to the 2007-2008 financial crisis. We use a comprehensive data set that contains contract terms on individual loans to 6047 firms across 14 European countries between 1998:01 and 2005:12. We account for the selection that arises in the loan request and approval process. Our findings imply that integration of interbank markets resulted in less stringent borrowing constraints and in substantially lower loan rates. The decrease was strongest in markets with competitive banking sectors. We also find that in the most rapidly integrating markets, firms became substantially overleveraged during the build-up to the crisis. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Popov, Alexander; Ongena, Steven</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rethinking the liquidity puzzle: Application of a new measure of the economic money stock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, Logan J.; Barnett, William A.; Keating, John W.
Historically, attempts to solve the liquidity puzzle focus on narrowly defined monetary aggregates, such as non-borrowed reserves, the monetary base, or M1. Many of these efforts fail to find a short-term negative correlation between interest rates and monetary policy innovations. More recent research uses sophisticated macroeconomic and econometric modeling. However, little research has investigated the role measurement error plays in the liquidity puzzle. since in nearly every case, work investigating the liquidity puzzle has used one of the official monetary aggregates, which have been shown to exhibit significant measurement error. In this paper, we examine the role that measurement error plays in the liquidity puzzle by (i) providing a theoretical framework explaining how the official simple-sum methodology can lead to a liquidity puzzle, and (ii) testing for the liquidity effect by estimating an unrestricted VAR. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kelly, Logan J.; Barnett, William A.; Keating, John W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The use of bank lines of credit in corporate liquidity management: A review of empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher
This paper reviews empirical evidence on the use of bank lines of credit as a source of corporate liquidity. Traditional explanation for lines of credit is that they provide insurance against liquidity shocks, in much the same as way hoarding cash does. However, recent empirical research suggests that access to lines of credit is contingent on the credit quality of the borrower as well as the financial condition of the lender. These findings suggest that lines of credit are an imperfect substitute for cash as a source of corporate liquidity. (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can pure play internet banking survive the credit crisis?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnold, Ivo J. M.; van Ewijk, Saskia E.
This paper positions the pure-play internet banking model (PPI) as a hybrid business model that combines features of both relationship and transaction banking. Although in terms of customer orientation PPI banks may partly resemble relationship banks, they lack their comparative advantage in generating borrower-specific information. Instead, the characteristic features of PPI banks are low costs and easy scalability. While the latter may enable PPI banks to quickly capture market share, it may also generate overexposure in risky markets. We present a case study on ING Direct, one of the leading global PPI banks and address the sustainability of the PPI business model by comparing the ING Direct foreign operations. The findings for ING Direct are validated using data for E-Trade Bank. We conclude that managing growth appears to be the prime challenge to PPI banks. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arnold, Ivo J. M.; van Ewijk, Saskia E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial dollarization: The role of foreign-owned banks and interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basso, Henrique S.; Calvo-Gonzalez, Oscar; Jurgilas, Marius
Why in many economies households and firms borrow and make deposits in foreign currency? Expanding on the existing literature, our framework addresses this question allowing for interest rate differentials and access to foreign funds to play a role in explaining this process of asset substitution or financial dollarization. Using a newly compiled data set on transition economies and employing a standard panel as well as a panel-VAR methodology we find that increasing access to foreign funds leads to higher credit dollarization, while it decreases deposit dollarization. Interest rate differentials matter for the dollarization of both loans and deposits. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Basso, Henrique S.; Calvo-Gonzalez, Oscar; Jurgilas, Marius</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting the fragility of the banking and insurance sectors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernoth, Kerstin; Pick, Andreas
Linkages between banks and insurance companies are important when forecasting the fragility of the banking and insurance sectors. We propose a novel empirical framework that allows us to estimate unobserved linkages in panel data sets that contain observed regressors. We find that taking unobserved common factors into account reduces the root mean square forecasts error of firm specific forecasts by up to 9%, of system forecasts by up to 14%, and by up to 39% for systemic forecasts of more distressed firms relative to a model based on observed variables only. Estimates of the factor loadings suggest that the correlation of financial institutions has been relatively stable over the forecast period. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bernoth, Kerstin; Pick, Andreas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are foreign banks more profitable than domestic banks? Home- and host-country effects of banking market structure, governance, and supervision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Hung; Liao, Chien-Chang
Using both bank- and country-level data on banking sectors from 70 countries over the period 1992-2006, this paper empirically investigates the joint home- and host-country effects of banking market structure, macroeconomic condition, governance, and changes in bank supervision on foreign bank margins. We find that foreign banks are more profitable than domestic banks when they operate in a host country whose banking sector is less competitive and when the parent bank in the home country is highly profitable. Moreover, when foreign banks operate in a host country with lower growth rates of GDP, higher interest and inflation rates, and more stringent regulatory compliance with Basel risk weights, their margins increase. Specifically, changes in bank supervision of a parent bank's ownership restrictiveness in the home country significantly increases foreign bank margins, while supervisory changes in regulatory compliance with Basel risk weights in the host country enhances foreign bank margins. Crown Copyright (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Hung; Liao, Chien-Chang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rates and bank risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos D.; Kouretas, Georgios P.
A recent line of research views the low interest-rate environment of the early to mid 2000s as an element that triggered increased risk-taking appetite of banks in search for yield. This paper uses approximately 18000 annual observations on euro area banks over the period 2001-2008 and presents strong empirical evidence that low-interest rates indeed increase bank risk-taking substantially. This result is robust across a number of different specifications that account, inter alia, for the potential endogeneity of interest rates and/or the dynamics of bank risk. Notably, among the banks of the large euro area countries this effect is less pronounced for French institutions, which held on average a relatively low level of risk assets. Finally, the distributional effects of interest rates on bank risk-taking due to individual bank characteristics reveal that the impact of interest rates on risk assets is diminished for banks with higher equity capital and is amplified for banks with higher off-balance sheet items. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Delis, Manthos D.; Kouretas, Georgios P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of banking crisis risk in the United States: A market data based compound option approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eichler, Stefan; Karmann, Alexander; Maltritz, Dominik
We use a compound option-based structural credit risk model to estimate banking crisis risk for the United States based on market data on bank stocks on a daily frequency. We contribute to the literature by providing separate information on short-term, long-term and total crisis risk instead of a single-maturity risk measure usually inferred by Merton-type models or barrier models. We estimate the model by applying the Duan (1994) maximum-likelihood approach. A strongly increasing total crisis risk estimated from early July 2007 onwards is driven mainly by short-term crisis risk. Banks that defaulted or were overtaken during the crisis have a considerably higher crisis risk (especially higher long-term risk) than banks that survived the crisis. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eichler, Stefan; Karmann, Alexander; Maltritz, Dominik</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of European bank mergers on bidder default risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vallascas, Francesco; Hagendorff, Jens
We analyze the implications of European bank consolidation on the default risk of acquiring banks. For a sample of 134 bidding banks, we employ the Merton distance to default model to show that, on average, bank mergers are risk neutral. However, for relatively safe banks, mergers generate a significant increase in default risk. This result is particularly pronounced for cross-border and activity-diversifying deals as well as for deals completed under weak bank regulatory regimes. Also, large deals, which pose organizational and procedural hurdles, experience a merger-related increase in default risk. Our results cast doubt on the ability of bank merger activity to exert a risk-reducing and stabilizing effect on the European banking industry. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vallascas, Francesco; Hagendorff, Jens</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information verifiability, bank organization, bank competition and bank-borrower relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kano, Masaji; Uchida, Hirofumi; Udell, Gregory F.; Watanabe, Wako
This paper investigates whether the benefits of bank-borrower relationships differ depending on three factors identified in the theoretical literature: verifiability of information, bank size and complexity, and bank competition. We extend the current literature by analyzing how relationship lending affects loan contract terms and credit availability in an empirical model that simultaneously accounts for all three of these factors. Based on Japanese survey data we find evidence that the benefits from stronger bank-borrower relationships in terms of credit availability are limited to smaller banks. However, when the benefits are measured as improved credit terms, we find little additional benefit, and in some cases increased cost, from stronger relationships for opaque borrowers and for borrowers who get funding from small banks. These latter findings suggest the possibility that relationship borrowers may suffer from capture effects. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kano, Masaji; Uchida, Hirofumi; Udell, Gregory F.; Watanabe, Wako</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of optimal expropriation, mergers and industry competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brisley, Neil; Bris, Arturo; Cabolis, Christos
We model a competitive industry where managers choose quantities and costs to maximize a combination of firm profits and benefits from expropriation. Expropriation is possible because of corporate governance 'slack' permitted by the government. We show that corporate governance slack induces managers to choose levels of output and costs that are higher than would otherwise be optimal. This, in turn, benefits consumers - the equilibrium price is lower - and other stakeholders such as suppliers and employees. Depending on the government's social welfare objective, less-than-perfect investor protection can be optimal. We show why some mechanisms suggested by the literature as improving investor protection - legal change, cross-listing, domestic mergers - may not be effective. We provide a theoretical argument showing the efficacy of cross-border mergers. The stronger corporate governance of a foreign acquirer, imposed on the domestic target firm, benefits merging shareholders and those of competing unmerged domestic firms. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brisley, Neil; Bris, Arturo; Cabolis, Christos</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pricing and performance of leveraged exchange-traded funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charupat, Narat; Miu, Peter
Leveraged ETFs are a recent and very successful financial innovation. They provide daily returns that are in a multiple or a negative multiple of the daily returns on a market benchmark. In this paper, we examine the characteristics, trading statistics, pricing efficiency and tracking errors of a sample of leveraged ETFs. We find that these ETFs are traded mainly by retail traders with very short holding periods. Price deviations (from NAV) are small on average, but large premiums and discounts are prone to occur. More interestingly, the behavior of premiums is different between bull (i.e., those with a positive multiple) and bear ETFs (i.e., those with a negative multiple). Our findings are consistent with the argument that the end-of-day rebalancing of the funds exposures increases market volatility at the close of a trading day. As for tracking errors, they are small for holding periods of up to a week, but become increasingly larger for longer horizons. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Charupat, Narat; Miu, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal liquidity risk in corporate bond yield spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Tsung-Kang; Liao, Hsien-Hsing; Tsai, Pei-Ling
The recent global financial crisis reveals the important role of internal liquidity risk in corporate credit risk. However, few existing studies investigate its effects on bond yield spreads. Panel data for the period from year 1993 through 2008 show that corporate internal liquidity risk significantly impacts bond yield spreads (and changes) when controlling for well-known bond yield determinant variables, traditional accounting measures of corporate debt servicing ability, cash flow volatility, credit ratings, and state variables. This finding indicates that internal liquidity risk should therefore be incorporated into bond yield spread modeling. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Tsung-Kang; Liao, Hsien-Hsing; Tsai, Pei-Ling</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An FFT-network for Levy option pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wong, Hoi Ying; Guan, Peiqiu
This paper develops a simple network approach to American exotic option valuation under Levy processes using the fast Fourier transform (FFT). The forward shooting grid (FSG) technique of the lattice approach is then generalized to expand the FFT-network to accommodate path-dependent variables. This network pricing approach is applicable to all Levy processes for which the characteristic function is readily available. In other words, the log-value of the underlying asset can follow finite-activity or infinite-activity Levy processes. With the powerful computation of FFT, the proposed network has a negligible additional computational burden compared to the binomial tree approach. The early exercise policy and option values in the continuation region are determined in a way very similar to that of the lattice approach. Numerical examples using American-style barrier, lookback, and Asian options demonstrate that the FFT-network is accurate and efficient. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wong, Hoi Ying; Guan, Peiqiu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A factor analysis approach to measuring European loan and bond market integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wagenvoort, Rien J. L. M.; Ebner, Andre; Borys, Magdalena Morgese
By using an existing and a new convergence measure, this paper assesses whether bank loan and bond interest rates are converging for the non-financial corporate sector across the euro area. Whilst we find evidence for complete bond market integration, the market for bank loans remains segmented, albeit to various degrees depending on the type and size of the loan. Factor analysis reveals that rates on large loans and small loans with long rate fixation periods have weakly converged in the sense that, up to a fixed effect, their evolution is driven by common factors only. In contrast, the price evolution of small loans with short rate fixation periods is still affected by country-specific dynamic factors. There are few signs that bank loan rates are becoming more uniform with time. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wagenvoort, Rien J. L. M.; Ebner, Andre; Borys, Magdalena Morgese</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do foreign banks increase competition? Evidence from emerging Asian and Latin American banking markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jeon, Bang Nam; Olivero, Maria Pia; Wu, Ji
In this paper we examine the impact of foreign bank penetration on the competitive structure of domestic banking sectors in host emerging economies. We focus our analysis on Asia and Latin America during the period 1997-2008. Using bank-level panel data to identify foreign banks and to estimate measures of banking competition, we are able to provide robust empirical evidence that an increase in foreign bank penetration enhances competition in these host countries' banking sectors. We find that this positive foreign bank penetration and banking competition link is associated with a spillover effect from foreign banks to their domestic counterparts. This spillover effect becomes stronger when more efficient and less risky foreign banks enter into less concentrated host country markets. We also find that the spillover effect is greater when foreign banks enter in the form of 'de novo penetration' than through mergers or acquisitions of domestic banks ('M&amp;A penetration'). (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jeon, Bang Nam; Olivero, Maria Pia; Wu, Ji</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Towards a more accurate measure of foreign bank entry and its impact on domestic banking performance: The case of China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Ying
This paper examines the impact of foreign bank entry on China's banking performance. An innovation in this study is that it constructs a spatially disaggregated measure of foreign bank presence, employing location data of foreign bank branches. Using this measure, the study examines the relationship between foreign bank presence and domestic banking performance in China. The results show that the spatially disaggregated measure not only improves the assessment of the impact of foreign bank presence but also resolves unexplained discrepancies found in existing empirical studies contingent on aggregate measures. Importantly, the study provides strong empirical evidence that foreign bank entry is supportive of a more competitive and efficient banking industry in China. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xu, Ying</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cultural influences on home bias and international diversification by institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Christopher W.; Fedenia, Mark; Hirschey, Mark; Skiba, Hilla
We investigate determinants of international diversification in institutionally managed portfolios from more than 60 countries. Survey-based country-specific variables on cross-cultural behaviors help to explain both home bias and diversification among foreign equities. In particular, investment funds from countries characterized by higher uncertainty avoidance behavior display greater home bias and are less diversified in their foreign holdings. Portfolios from countries with higher levels of masculinity and long-term orientation display lower levels of home bias, and portfolios from countries with higher levels of masculinity are more diversified abroad. Portfolios from culturally distant countries invest less abroad and underweight culturally distant target markets. The economic significance of cultural variables is high and comparable in magnitude to geographical distance, a consistent influence on foreign diversification in prior studies. Culture impacts investor behavior directly and not merely though indirect channels such as legal and regulatory framework. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anderson, Christopher W.; Fedenia, Mark; Hirschey, Mark; Skiba, Hilla</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign bank entry and firms' access to bank credit: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Huidan
This paper studies the impact of foreign bank entry on domestic firms' access to bank credit using a within-country staggered geographic variation in the policy of foreign bank lending in China. The paper finds that after foreign bank entry profitable firms use more long-term bank loans; whereas firms with higher value of potential collateral do not. It also finds that non-state-owned firms become able to substitute some trade credit with long-term bank loans. The findings suggest that less opaque firms and non-state-owned firms benefit more from foreign bank entry and that collateral may only play a limited role in mitigating the problem of information asymmetry when creditors' rights are not well protected in a host country. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Huidan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition in banking and the lending channel: Evidence from bank-level data in Asia and Latin America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Olivero, Maria Pia; Li, Yuan; Jeon, Bang Nam
This paper examines how banking competition affects the transmission of monetary policy through the bank lending channel. We apply a two-step estimation procedure using bank-level panel data for commercial banks in 10 Asian and 10 Latin American countries during the period from 1996 to 2006. In the first step we measure the degree of banking competition by applying the methodology proposed by Panzar and Rosse (1987). In the second step we estimate a loan growth equation where the explanatory variables include the Panzar-Rosse measure of banking competition. The estimation results provide consistent evidence that increased competition in the banking sector weakens the transmission of monetary policy through the bank lending channel. This is especially true for banks in Latin American countries and banks of small size, low liquidity, and low capitalization. We also discuss the policy implications of the main findings of this paper. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Olivero, Maria Pia; Li, Yuan; Jeon, Bang Nam</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives foreign expansion of the top 100 multinational banks? The role of the credit reporting system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsai, Hsiangping; Chang, Yuanchen; Hsiao, Pei-Hsin
This study explores how information costs, proxied by characteristics of credit reporting systems, affect the foreign expansion of the top 100 multinational banks. We find that banks prefer to expand operations in countries where private credit bureaus exist or where the credit reporting system is of better quality. This preference is particularly strong for banks' branch decisions. Furthermore, banks prefer subsidiary entry only in countries where private credit bureaus exist with better credit information quality. Overall, our results indicate that banks are attracted to countries where the credit reporting system helps reduce banks' information costs. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tsai, Hsiangping; Chang, Yuanchen; Hsiao, Pei-Hsin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price dispersion in OTC markets: A new measure of liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jankowitsch, Rainei; Nashikkar, Amrut; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.
In this paper, we model price dispersion effects in over-the-counter (OTC) markets to show that, in the presence of inventory risk for dealers and search costs for investors, traded prices may deviate from the expected market valuation of an asset. We interpret this deviation as a liquidity effect and develop a new liquidity measure quantifying the price dispersion in the context of the US corporate bond market. This market offers a unique opportunity to study liquidity effects since, from October 2004 onwards, all OTC transactions in this market have to be reported to a common database known as the Trade Reporting and Compliance Engine (TRACE). Furthermore, market-wide average price quotes are available from Markit Group Limited, a financial information provider. Thus, it is possible, for the first time, to directly observe deviations between transaction prices and the expected market valuation of securities. We quantify and analyze our new liquidity measure for this market and find significant price dispersion effects that cannot be simply captured by bid-ask spreads. We show that our new measure is indeed related to liquidity by regressing it on commonly-used liquidity proxies and find a strong relation between our proposed liquidity measure and bond characteristics, as well as trading activity variables. Furthermore, we evaluate the reliability of end-of-day marks that traders use to value their positions. Our evidence suggests that the price deviations from expected market valuations are significantly larger and more volatile than previously assumed. Overall, the results presented here improve our understanding of the drivers of liquidity and are important for many applications in OTC markets, in general. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jankowitsch, Rainei; Nashikkar, Amrut; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of terrorism on financial markets: An empirical study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chesney, Marc; Reshetar, Ganna; Karaman, Mustafa
The main focus of this paper is to study empirically the impact of terrorism on the behavior of stock, bond and commodity markets. We consider terrorist events that took place in 25 countries over an 11-year time period and implement our analysis using different methods: an event-study approach, a non-parametric methodology, and a filtered GARCH-EVT approach. In addition, we compare the effect of terrorist attacks on financial markets with the impact of other extreme events such as financial crashes and natural catastrophes. The results of our analysis show that a non-parametric approach is the most appropriate method among the three for analyzing the impact of terrorism on financial markets. We demonstrate the robustness of this method when interest rates, equity market integration, spillover and contemporaneous effects are controlled. We show how the results of this approach can be used for investors' portfolio diversification strategies against terrorism risk. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chesney, Marc; Reshetar, Ganna; Karaman, Mustafa</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of cash dividend announcements in a unique environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Al-Yahyaee, Khamis H.; Pham, Toan M.; Walter, Terry S.
Due to its distinctive institutional background, Oman offers a valuable opportunity to examine stock price reactions to dividend announcements. In Oman, (1) there are no taxes on dividends and capital gains, (2) there is a high concentration of share ownership, (3) there is low corporate transparency, and (4) firms frequently change their dividends. Our results show that announcements of dividend increases are associated with increased stock prices, while announcements of dividend decreases cause decreases in stock prices. Firms that do not change their dividends experience insignificant negative returns. These results contradict tax-based signaling models, which argue that higher taxes on dividends relative to capital gains are a necessary condition for dividends to be informative. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Al-Yahyaee, Khamis H.; Pham, Toan M.; Walter, Terry S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage-free credit pricing using default probabilities and risk sensitivities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloechlinger, Andreas
The relation between physical probabilities (rating) and risk-neutral probabilities (pricing) is derived in a large market with a quasi-factor structure. Factor sensitivities and default probabilities are obtainable for all kinds of credits on historical rating data. Since factor prices can be backed out from market data, the model allows the pricing of non-marketable credits and structured products thereof. The model explains various empirical observations: credit spreads of equally rated borrowers differ, spreads are wider than implied by expected losses, and expected returns on CDOs must be greater than their rating matched, single-obligor securities due to the inherent systematic risk. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bloechlinger, Andreas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On syndicate composition, corporate structure and the certification effect of credit ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bosch, Oliver; Steffen, Sascha
We assess the relative importance of ratings versus stock exchange listings in reducing information asymmetry using a dataset of syndicated loans to public and private firms in the UK. We find that the certification effect of ratings is largest for private firms and that syndicates are smallest if firms are privately held or unrated. Moreover, we find that the marginal effect of being stock exchange listed is insignificant once these firms are rated. Exploiting the heterogeneity among lenders, we find that especially foreign bank and non-bank investors do not provide capital if firms are unrated. Our paper highlights the information produced by rating agencies as an important mechanism by which ratings improve access to capital. Our results also emphasize the importance of syndicate moral hazard on the supply of uninformed capital: bank-borrower relationships significantly increase the loan share syndicated to investors particularly if firms are not listed and unrated. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bosch, Oliver; Steffen, Sascha</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effect of collateral characteristics on bank performance: Evidence from collateralized stocks in Taiwan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Anlin; Kao, Lanfeng
Taiwanese law requires directors of listed firms to disclose their stocks collateralized at banks creating the possibility of examining the characteristics of collateralized stocks and their influence on bank performance. This study demonstrates that the risk (value) attributes of collateralized stocks increase (reduce) bank efficiency yet reduce (increase) bank profits. Government-owned banks but not private banks require sufficiently high margins to prevent stock loans from non-performing. Furthermore, banks charge higher interest to cover the non-performing risk. Directors who lack funds, hold high turnover stocks, and/or have weak relationships with their banks prefer to collateralize their stocks at private banks. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Anlin; Kao, Lanfeng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hierarchical determinants of capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kayo, Eduardo K.; Kimura, Herbert
We analyze the influence of time-, firm-, industry- and country-level determinants of capital structure. First, we apply hierarchical linear modeling in order to assess the relative importance of those levels. We find that time and firm levels explain 78% of firm leverage. Second, we include random intercepts and random coefficients in order to analyze the direct and indirect influences of firm/industry/country characteristics on firm leverage. We document several important indirect influences of variables at industry and country-levels on firm determinants of leverage, as well as several structural differences in the financial behavior between firms of developed and emerging countries. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kayo, Eduardo K.; Kimura, Herbert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International diversification: A copula approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chollete, Loran; de la Pena, Victor; Lu, Ching-Chih
The viability of international diversification involves balancing benefits and costs. This balance hinges on the degree of asset dependence. In light of theoretical research linking diversification and dependence, we examine international diversification using two measures of dependence: correlations and copulas. We document several findings. First, dependence has increased over time. Second, we find evidence of asymmetric dependence or downside risk in Latin America, but less in the G5. The results indicate very little downside risk in East Asia. Third, East Asian and Latin American returns exhibit some correlation complexity. Interestingly, the regions with maximal dependence or worst diversification do not command large returns. Our results suggest international limits to diversification. They are also consistent with a possible tradeoff between international diversification and systemic risk. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chollete, Loran; de la Pena, Victor; Lu, Ching-Chih</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do exchange rates co-move? A study on the currencies of five inflation-targeting countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xiao-Ming
This paper does three things. First, it explores the type of asymmetry in exchange rate correlation for five inflation-targeting countries. We show their currencies co-move more closely with the currencies of some influential foreign countries during joint appreciations than joint depreciations against a world currency. Second, it establishes empirically the linkage between interest rate differentials and exchange rate correlation. We find evidence that both widening and narrowing interest rate differentials will reduce the correlation. Third, it proposes a new version of the asymmetric dynamic conditional correlation model. The model proves to be capable of providing great insight into the two issues investigated. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Xiao-Ming</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange rate expectations and the pricing of Chinese cross-listed stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eichler, Stefan
I show that the price discounts of Chinese cross-listed stocks (American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) and H-shares) to their underlying A-shares indicate the expected yuan/US dollar exchange rate. The forecasting models reveal that ADR and H-share discounts predict exchange rate changes more accurately than the random walk and forward exchange rates, particularly at long forecast horizons. Using panel estimations, I find that ADR and H-share investors form their exchange rate expectations according to standard exchange rate theories such as the Harrod-Balassa-Samuelson effect, the risk of competitive devaluations, relative purchasing power parity, uncovered interest rate parity, and the risk of currency crisis. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eichler, Stefan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax avoidance, cost of debt and shareholder activism: Evidence from Korea</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Youngdeok
This paper examines the impact of tax avoidance on the cost of debt and its interaction effect with shareholder activism. Using Korean firms, I find a negative relationship between tax avoidance and the cost of debt, supporting the trade-off theory. Further tests reveal that the negative relationship becomes stronger when the level of institutional ownership is high. It becomes even stronger after 1998, when the shareholder rights of institutional investors were strengthened. It suggests that the managerial opportunism theory has an additional explanation for tax avoidance activities. My findings indicate that tax avoidance reduces the cost of debt through trade-offs and creates a managerial rent diversion, which is mitigated in firms with larger institutional holdings. Crown Copyright (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lim, Youngdeok</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetrical return on equity mean reversion and catering</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, An-Sing; Lin, Shih-Chieh
Using a momentum threshold autoregression model, we find evidence showing that there is an asymmetrical mean reversion behavior in return on equity (ROE). Results show that the speed of adjustment of ROE towards the long-term mean is slower in the ROE increasing regimes than in the ROE decreasing regimes. Additional results indicate that investor earnings optimism is significantly related to change in abnormal ROE. These results are consistent with predictions from catering theory. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, An-Sing; Lin, Shih-Chieh</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information disclosure in credit markets when banks' costs are endogenous</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Tassel, Eric
In this paper we develop a model of information disclosure among banks based on an endogenous interest rate for externally placed debt. Banks with private credit information are given an opportunity to disclose information prior to competing for borrowers. While disclosure eliminates a bank's information advantage over its competitors, disclosing information creates a new advantage for the bank in terms of a lower cost of external funds. We find that the incentive for a bank to disclose information is inversely related to the bank's capital ratio and positively related to the number of other banks that disclose information. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Van Tassel, Eric</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks' exposure to interest rate risk, their earnings from term transformation, and the dynamics of the term structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Memmel, Christoph
We use a unique dataset of German banks' exposure to interest rate risk to derive the following statements about their exposure to this risk and their earnings from term transformation. The systematic factor for the exposure to interest rate risk moves in sync with the shape of the term structure. At bank level, however, the time variation of the exposure is largely determined by idiosyncratic effects. Over time, changes in earnings from term transformation have a large impact on interest income. Across banks, however, the earnings from term transformation do not seem to be a decisive factor for the interest margin. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Memmel, Christoph</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The macroeconomic sources of systemic risk in the banking sectors of five new EU member states</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Festic, Mejra; Kavkler, Alenka; Repina, Sebastijan
Rapid credit growth has been one of the most pervasive developments in recent years in Central and Eastern Europe. Our estimates support the hypothesis that the growth of credit and the amount of available finance might harm banking performance and deteriorate non-performing loans (NPL) dynamics, most probably due to the overheating of economies in the five NMSs. The procyclicality of banking sector performance and high economic activities growth is a signal of an economy overheating and therefore a slowdown in economic activity is likely to accelerate the growth of the NPL ratio. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Festic, Mejra; Kavkler, Alenka; Repina, Sebastijan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank capital regulation and credit supply</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hyun, Jung-Soon; Rhee, Byung-Kun
Banks can meet the need to increase their capital ratio either by issuing new equity or by reducing loans. It is generally known that banks prefer to reduce assets due to the high cost of equity. With a simple banking model we show that, if incumbent shareholders are to benefit, banks may prefer to reduce loans, even though they can recapitalize by issuing new equity without any cost. The result holds when banks hold relatively small amounts of long-term loans, or when the economy is in downturn. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hyun, Jung-Soon; Rhee, Byung-Kun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Productivity and efficiency analysis of Shinkin banks: Evidence from bootstrap and Bayesian approaches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Assaf, A. George; Barros, Carlos P.; Matousek, Roman
This paper analyzes the productivity and efficiency of Shinkin banks and the various prefectures in Japan, over the period from 2000 to 2006. We obtain estimates of efficiency growth and productivity growth, using the bootstrapped Malmquist index, and estimates of efficiency using the Bayesian distance frontier approach. We confirm that the efficiency growth and productivity growth of Shinkin banks did not improve significantly over the period of this study. In addition, we show that the efficiency of Shinkin banks is homogenous, with little variation across the banks analyzed. Methodologically, we also prove that a failure to impose theoretical regularity on the distance function could lead to false conclusions about the average efficiency or efficiency ranking of Shinkin banks. The study also includes an analysis of the correlates of productivity and efficiency growth, and provides efficiency and productivity estimates of the prefectures in which the banks are located. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Assaf, A. George; Barros, Carlos P.; Matousek, Roman</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Small business groups enhance performance and promote stability, not expropriation. Evidence from French SMEs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hamelin, Anais
This paper investigates the influence that a firm's distance from control has on its performance, using balance sheet information and a unique data set on small business ownership. This study fills a gap in the empirical governance literature by investigating whether there is expropriation of minority shareholders in small business groups. Contrary to observations for large business groups, results show a positive relationship between the separation of control from ownership and firm performance. Results also underline that tunneling promotes controlling shareholders' profit stability rather than profit maximization in small business groups. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hamelin, Anais</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing liquidity: Optimal degree of centralization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pokutta, Sebastian; Schmaltz, Christian
Large banking groups face the question of how to optimally allocate and generate liquidity: in a central liquidity hub or in many decentralized branches. We translate this question into a facility location problem under uncertainty. We show that volatility is the key driver behind (de-)centralization. We provide an analytical solution for the 2-branch model and show that a liquidity center can be interpreted as an option on immediate liquidity. Therefore, its value can be interpreted as the price of information, i.e., the price of knowing the exact demand. Furthermore, we derive the threshold above which it is advantageous to open a liquidity center and show that it is a function of the volatility and the characteristic of the bank network. Finally, we discuss the n-branch model for real-world banking groups (10-60 branches) and show that it can be solved with high granularity (100 scenarios) within less than 30s. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pokutta, Sebastian; Schmaltz, Christian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating exponential affine models with correlated measurement errors: Applications to fixed income and commodities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dempster, M. A. H.; Tang, Ke
Exponential affine models (EAMs) are factor models popular in financial asset pricing requiring a dynamic term structure, such as for interest rates and commodity futures. When implementing EAMs it is usual to first specify the model in state-space form (SSF) and then to estimate it using the Kalman filter. To specify the SSF, a structure of the measurement error must be provided which is not specified in the EAM itself. Different specifications of the measurement errors will result in different SSFs, leading to different parameter estimates. In this paper we investigate the influence of the measurement error specification on the parameter estimates. Using market data for both fixed income and commodities we provide evidence that measurement errors are cross-sectionally and serially correlated, which is not consistent with the independent identically distributed (iid) assumptions commonly adopted in the literature. Using simulated data we show that measurement error assumptions affect parameter estimates, especially in the presence of serial correlation. We provide a new specification, the augmented state-space form (ASSF), as a solution to these biases and show that the ASSF gives much better estimates than the basic SSF. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dempster, M. A. H.; Tang, Ke</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>House prices, non-fundamental components and interstate spillovers: The Australian experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Costello, Greg; Fraser, Patricia; Groenewold, Nicolaas
Using Australian capital city data from 1984Q3-2008Q2, this paper utilizes a dynamic present value model within a VAR framework to construct time series of house prices depicting what aggregate house prices should be given expectations of future real disposable income - the "fundamental price" - and continues by comparing capital city fundamental prices with actual prices. The extent to which revealed capital city "non-fundamental" components spillover from state to state, as well as their long-term impact is also investigated. Results provide evidence of periods of sustained deviations of house prices from values warranted by income for all state capitals with the greatest deviations arising in the NSW market and starting around 2000. In general NSW is relatively more susceptible to spillovers transmitted from other states while ACT and WA are most isolated from the rest of the country. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Costello, Greg; Fraser, Patricia; Groenewold, Nicolaas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relationship between asset growth and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gray, Philip; Johnson, Jessica
There is a large body of literature examining the association between stock characteristics and the cross-section of stock returns in international markets. Recently, Cooper et al. (2008) reported a strong association between total asset growth and stock returns in the US. In this paper, we show that an asset-growth effect also exists in the Australian equity market. Of particular interest, it is present amongst the largest Australian stocks. Over the 1983-2007 period, an equally-weighted portfolio of low-growth Big stocks outperforms a portfolio of high-growth Big stocks by an average 1% per month, equating to nearly 13% per annum. At an individual stock level of analysis, the asset-growth effect remains even after controlling for other variables whose association with the cross-section of returns is well known. Finally, we explicitly test whether asset growth is a priced risk factor using the common two-stage cross-sectional regression methodology. We find no evidence to support a risk-based explanation, thereby lending credence to Cooper et al.'s (2008) suggestion that the asset-growth effect is attributable to mispricing. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gray, Philip; Johnson, Jessica</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contagion risk in the Australian banking and property sectors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pais, Amelia; Stork, Philip A.
The Australian banking system emerged from the global crisis virtually unhurt, with most banks still profitable, adequately capitalized, and with AA credit ratings. Are there any risks or vulnerabilities in this success story? This paper analyzes Australia's systemic banking risk and attempts to determine if this risk increased with the recent global crisis and whether this risk is related to the downturn experienced in the real estate market. We use extreme value theory to measure banks' and property firms' univariate Value at Risk, as well as multivariate intra-sector and inter-sector contagion risks. Of the 13 sectors analyzed, we find that the property sector exhibits the highest level of extremal dependence with the banking sector. The credit crisis significantly increased the probability of a bank or property firm crashing. Moreover, contagion risks significantly increased not only within the banking and property sectors, but also between those sectors. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pais, Amelia; Stork, Philip A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pitfalls and remedies in testing the calibration quality of rating systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aussenegg, Wolfgang; Resch, Florian; Winkler, Gerhard
Testing calibration quality by means of backtesting is an integral part in the validation of credit rating systems. Against this background this paper provides a comprehensive overview of existing testing procedures. We study the procedures' deficiencies theoretically and illustrate their impact empirically. Based on the insights gained therefrom, we develop enhanced hybrid testing procedures which turn out to be superior to the commonly applied methods. We also propose computationally efficient algorithms for our calibration tests. Finally, we are able to demonstrate empirically that our method outperforms existing tests in a scenario analysis using rating data of Moody's. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aussenegg, Wolfgang; Resch, Florian; Winkler, Gerhard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Access to financing and firm growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rahaman, Mohammad M.
Why do some firms grow faster than others? Although various observed and unobserved aspects of firms have been suggested as potential drivers of firm heterogeneity, economists disagree sharply on the role of financial structure in influencing firm growth. In this paper. I use a sample of quoted and unquoted firms to show that the effect of financial structure on firm growth is statistically significant and quantitatively important. In the presence of external financing constraints, firms rely more on internal funds to finance growth, but the effect of internal financing on firm growth decreases with an increase in the firm's access to an external bank credit facility. As the external financing constraint is alleviated, the firm relies less on internal funds and switches to external financing as the primary source of financing for its growth. This pattern of transition between internal and external financing is particularly pronounced in small unquoted firms (conditional on their survival). These results suggest a real effect of financial structure on growth via the channel of an external financing constraint. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rahaman, Mohammad M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does regulation substitute or complement governance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becher, David A.; Frye, Melissa B.
We examine whether firms utilize governance systems and increased monitoring mechanisms when information asymmetry and managerial discretion are limited. Given that such monitoring is costly, we expect regulated firms to use less monitoring if regulation substitutes for governance. Using data from initial public offerings, we document that regulated firms have greater proportions of monitoring directors and larger boards as well as use similar amounts of equity-based compensation as non-regulated firms. Further, regulated and unregulated firms are analogous in terms of observed trade-offs between traditional monitoring mechanisms and insider ownership. Finally, regulated firms appear to decrease monitoring following a period of deregulation. These findings support the hypothesis that regulation and governance are complements and are consistent with the notion that regulators pressure firms to adopt effective monitoring structures. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Becher, David A.; Frye, Melissa B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The global financial crisis and the evolution of markets, institutions and regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
This paper analyses the recent global financial crisis in the context of the dual processes of market development and regulation. It discusses how, in the absence of a globally integrated financial framework, past and present regulations and interventions in reaction to national and global financial crises did not resolve the cross border regulatory arbitrage. The paper discusses how crises often lead to the emergence of new national and international institutions. It also analyses the proposed "new global framework" that needs to be in place if the policy recommendations contained in the G20 communique are going to be effectively implemented. The paper argues that unless international agreements are ratified by all nations and become part of national rules and laws, the presence of regulatory arbitrage and the lack of adequate cross border information and data may prevent the global economy from addressing the underlying causes of the recent global financial crisis. The paper also discusses the evolution of central banks and their new role in contributing to global financial stability. The paper argues that the recent global financial crisis has provided a unique opportunity to go beyond economic data and attempt to capture cross border financial data and other information that could assist international and national institutions to measure and manage financial risk more effectively. Finally, the paper discusses "too big to fail" and argues that only an internationally integrated financial system will make large banks global, both when operational and in the event of insolvency. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank size, lending technologies, and small business finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Black, Lamont K.
Under the current paradigm in small business lending research, large banks tend to specialize in lending to relatively large, informationally transparent firms using "hard" information, while small banks have advantages in lending to smaller, less transparent firms using "soft" information. We go beyond this paradigm to analyze the comparative advantages of large and small banks in specific lending technologies. Our analysis begins with the identification of fixed-asset lending technologies used to make small business loans. Our results suggest that large banks do not have equal advantages in all of these hard lending technologies and these advantages are not all increasing monotonically in firm size, contrary to the predictions of the current paradigm. We also analyze lines of credit without fixed-asset collateral to focus on relationship lending. We confirm that small banks have a comparative advantage in relationship lending, but this appears to be strongest for lending to the largest firms. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Black, Lamont K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simultaneous monetary policy announcements and international stock markets response: An intraday analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hussain, Syed Mujahid
This paper investigates the return and volatility response of major European and US equity indices to monetary policy surprises by utilizing extensive intraday data on 5-min price quotes along with a comprehensive dataset on monetary policy decisions and macroeconomic news announcements. The results indicate that the monetary policy decisions generally exert immediate and significant influence on stock index returns and volatilities in both European and the US markets. The findings also show that press conferences held by the European Central Bank (ECB) that follow monetary policy decisions on the same day have a clear impact on European index return volatilities. This implies that they convey additional important information to market participants. Overall, our analysis suggests that the use of high frequency data is critical to separate the effect of monetary policy actions from those of macroeconomic news announcements on stock index returns and volatilities. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hussain, Syed Mujahid</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The future of universal banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kouretas, Georgios P.; Papadopoulos, Athanasios P.
nan</description><author>Kouretas, Georgios P.; Papadopoulos, Athanasios P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial intermediation in the theory of the risk-free rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marini, Francois
This paper constructs a general equilibrium model of the interaction between financial intermediaries and financial markets that sheds some light on the short-term volatility of real interest rates. The main findings of the paper are as follows. When financial intermediaries issue contingent (non-contingent) liabilities, an increase in the consumers' relative risk aversion coefficient decreases (increases) the interest rate. Also, the interest rate rises when capitalists are less risk-averse and financial intermediaries are hit by a liquidity shock. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marini, Francois</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nominal and true cost of loan collateral</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niinimaki, J.-P.
This paper explores costs and proceeds from loan collateral in the credit market with ex-ante asymmetric information when collateral value and the probability of project success fluctuate. A borrower is willing to pledge collateral if (i) its future value is correlated with the probability of project success, or (ii) its value fluctuates strongly, or (iii) it is funded with loan capital. When one of the conditions is satisfied, in contrast to Bester (1985), a high-risk borrower may be more willing to pledge collateral than a low-risk borrower. The paper is related to topical subprime crises and real estate collateral. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Niinimaki, J.-P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government, taxes and banking crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasman, Augusto; Lopez, Angel L.; Samartin, Margarita
This paper analyzes the effectiveness of different government policies to prevent the emergence of banking crises. In particular, we study the impact on welfare of using taxpayers money to recapitalize banks, government injection of money into the banking system through credit lines, the creation of a buffer and taxes on financial transactions (the Tobin tax). We illustrate the trade-off between these policies and derive policy implications. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasman, Augusto; Lopez, Angel L.; Samartin, Margarita</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing for rational bubbles in the presence of structural breaks: Evidence from nonstationary panels</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cerqueti, Roy; Costantini, Mauro
This paper presents new results on the rational bubbles hypothesis for a panel of 18 OECD countries using the model developed by Campbell (2000). We provide an analysis of international data that exploits increased power deriving from the panel unit root and cointegration methodology, together with the flexibility of allowing explicitly for multiple endogenous structural breaks in the individual series. Differently from the time series methodology, the panel data approach allows for a global analysis of the financial crashes that are related to rational bubbles. We find strong evidence in favor of bubbles phenomena. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cerqueti, Roy; Costantini, Mauro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of macroeconomic news on quote adjustments, noise, and informational volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hautsch, Nikolaus; Hess, Dieter; Veredas, David
We study the impact of the arrival of macroeconomic news on the informational and noise-driven components in high-frequency quote processes and their conditional variances. We decompose bid and ask returns into a common ("efficient return") factor and two market-side-specific components capturing market microstructure effects. The corresponding variance components reflect information-driven and noise-induced volatilities. We find that all volatility components reveal distinct dynamics and are positively influenced by news. The proportion of noise-induced variances is highest before announcements and significantly declines thereafter. Moreover, news-affected responses in all volatility components are influenced by order flow imbalances. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hautsch, Nikolaus; Hess, Dieter; Veredas, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disentangling demand and supply in credit developments: A survey-based analysis for Italy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Del Giovane, Paolo; Eramo, Ginette; Nobili, Andrea
This paper combines qualitative information from the Eurosystem Bank Lending Survey with micro-data on loans for the participating Italian banks to assess the role of supply and demand factors in lending to enterprises developments, with a focus on the 2007-2009 financial crisis. Both demand and supply have played a relevant role, in the whole sample period and during the crisis. A counterfactual exercise shows that the effect of supply factors on the growth of lending was strongest after the Lehman collapse. On average, over the crisis period the negative effect on the annualized quarter-on-quarter growth rate of the panel banks' lending to enterprises can be estimated in a range of 2.3-3.1 percentage points, depending on the specification. About one fourth of the total supply effect can be attributed to costs related to the banks' balance sheet position, the rest to their perception of credit risk. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Del Giovane, Paolo; Eramo, Ginette; Nobili, Andrea</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading volume and exchange rate volatility: Evidence for the sequential arrival of information hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mougoue, Mbodja; Aggarwal, Raj
The relationship between trading volume and volatility in foreign exchange markets continues to be of much interest, especially given the higher than expected volatility of returns. Allowing for nonlinearities, this paper tests competing hypotheses on the possible relationship between volatility and trading volume using data for three major currency futures contracts denominated in US dollars, namely the British pound, the Canadian dollar and the Japanese yen. We find that trading volumes and return volatility are negatively correlated, implying a lack of support for the mixture of distributions hypothesis (MOH). Using linear and nonlinear Granger causality tests, we document significant lead-lag relations between trading volumes and return volatility consistent with the sequential arrival of information (SAI) hypothesis. These findings are robust and nor sample-dependent or due to heterogeneity of beliefs as proxied by open interest. Furthermore, our results are insensitive to the modeling approach used to recover volatility measures. Overall, our findings support the contention that short- to medium-term currency relationships may be dominated by trading dynamics and not by fundamentals. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mougoue, Mbodja; Aggarwal, Raj</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign banks in syndicated loan markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haselmann, Rainer; Wachtel, Paul
Foreign banks play a prominent role in syndicated loan markets. In this paper we examine foreign banks' motives in participating in cross-border deals in 25 European countries. We find that usual explanations of foreign banking activities can only account partly for the high rate of foreign involvement in syndicated loan markets. The usual argument is that foreign banks are at a disadvantage because they lack soft information and thus they tend to lend to more transparent firms compared to their domestic counterparts. We find that this relationship only holds in relatively small financial systems. We illustrate different motivations for the large amount of cross border lending in large developed markets. In these markets foreign banks tend to lend to especially risky borrowers and projects. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Haselmann, Rainer; Wachtel, Paul</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership structure, market discipline, and banks' risk-taking incentives under deposit insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Forssbaeck, Jens
The paper studies the effects of market discipline by creditors and ownership structure on banks' risk taking in the presence of partial deposit insurance. An agency-cost model explains how the effects of creditor discipline and shareholder control arc interdependent, the non-monotonic effect of shareholder control, and the role of leverage. Panel regressions on several hundred banks worldwide 1995-2005 confirm a negative individual risk effect of creditor discipline and the expected convex effect of shareholder control. Increased shareholder control significantly strengthens the negative effect of market discipline on asset risk, but joint effects on overall default risk are limited. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Forssbaeck, Jens</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric herding as a source of asymmetric return volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Beum-Jo
As a considerable source of asymmetry in return volatility, this paper introduces asymmetric herding and extends the continuous beliefs system to account for its asymmetry and derive the asymmetric herding parameters that are easily estimated by using a maximum likelihood method based on the GARCH-type econometric model. This paper presents new empirical evidence for asymmetry in the exchange rates volatility of major currencies against the US dollar, which have bilateral nature. Interestingly, the asymmetry of Japanese yen is the opposite of that of others and the global financial crisis highlights the opposite asymmetry. Some of traditional hypotheses, such as the leverage effect and the volatility feedback effect, do not adequately explain these findings; however, a significant asymmetric herding effect is observed and appears to be time-varying. Further, the clear link between asymmetric herding and volatility strongly supports the hypothesis of the asymmetric herding effect. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Park, Beum-Jo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic incompatibility in ATM markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knittel, Christopher R.; Stango, Victor
We test whether Firms use incompatibility strategically, using data from Ani markets. High ATM fees degrade the value of competitors' deposit accounts, and can in principle serve as a mechanism for siphoning depositors away from competitors or for creating deposit account differentiation. Our empirical framework can empirically distinguish surcharging motivated by this strategic concern from surcharging that simply maximizes ATM profit considered as a stand-alone operation. The results are consistent with such behavior by large banks, but not by small banks. For large banks, the effect of incompatibility seems to operate through higher deposit account fees rather than increased deposit account base. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Knittel, Christopher R.; Stango, Victor</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of start-up firm external financing worldwide</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nofsinger, John R.; Wang, Weicheng
The typical new start-up firm acquires external financing in stages through its development. Researchers have frequently examined the later stages of financing; however, they have rarely analyzed the early stages of financing. This study examines the determinants of the initial start-up financing of entrepreneurial firms in 27 countries. There are information asymmetries and moral hazard problems inherent in the funding of an initial start-up firm. Empirical results show that institutional investors rely on the experience of entrepreneurs in managing start-ups and the quality of investor protection to reduce moral hazard. On the other hand, informal investors are also common in initial start-up funding. They tend to be attracted to the type of products in the new firm. In comparison, informal investors are likely to have a social relationship with the entrepreneur, and thus have information about that person's skill and character, which renders entrepreneurial experience less important. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nofsinger, John R.; Wang, Weicheng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should investors include commodities in their portfolios after all? New evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daskalaki, Charoula; Skiadopoulos, George
This paper investigates whether an investor is made better off by including commodities in a portfolio that consists of traditional asset classes. First, we revisit the posed question within an in-sample setting by employing mean-variance and non-mean-variance spanning tests. Then, we form optimal portfolios by taking into account the higher order moments of the portfolio returns distribution and evaluate their out-of-sample performance. Under the in-sample setting, we find that commodities are beneficial only to non-mean-variance investors. However, these benefits are not preserved out-of-sample. Our findings challenge the alleged diversification benefits of commodities and are robust across a number of performance evaluation measures, utility functions and datasets. The results hold even when transaction costs are considered and across various sub-periods. Not surprisingly, the only exception appears over the 2005-2008 unprecedented commodity boom period. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Daskalaki, Charoula; Skiadopoulos, George</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic fundamentals, price discovery, and volatility dynamics in emerging bond markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nowak, Sylwia; Andritzky, Jochen; Jobst, Andreas; Tamirisa, Natalia
This study characterizes volatility dynamics in external emerging bond markets and examines how prices and volatility respond to macroeconomic news. As in mature bond markets, surprises about macroeconomic conditions in emerging markets are found to affect both conditional returns and volatility of external bonds, with the effects on volatility being more pronounced and longer lasting than those on prices. Yet the process of information absorption tends to be more drawn-out than in mature bond markets. Global and regional macroeconomic news is at least as important as local news for both price and volatility dynamics. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nowak, Sylwia; Andritzky, Jochen; Jobst, Andreas; Tamirisa, Natalia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership structure and tax-friendly dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henry, Darren
The paper examines the existence of tax-based dividend clienteles using the novel environment of Australia. which has operated a full dividend imputation system since 1987. The analysis jointly focuses on the tax-based preferences of five categories of shareholders, including both domestic and foreign-domiciled shareholder classes. Incorporating the dividend franking percentage as a direct measure of the degree of tax benefit associated with dividends, strong evidence supporting the existence of tax-based dividend clienteles is present for both domestic and foreign shareholder categories. This includes domestic corporate blockholders and company directors, and local institutional investors following tax reforms in 2000. and foreign institutional shareholders which, alternatively, demand lower dividends and dividend franking. These findings persist after considering the effect of share repurchases. and under various model specifications controlling for unobserved firm heterogeneity and potential endogeneity between ownership structure and dividend payout policy. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Henry, Darren</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do market capitalization and stocks traded converge? New global evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayan, Paresh Kumar; Mishra, Sagarika; Narayan, Seema
In this paper, we examine convergence of stock markets. Our empirical exercise is based on 11 different panels, which together consist of 120 countries. The richness of the dataset allows us to disaggregate countries into panels, such as high income, middle income, low income, OECD, CSI. and developing country panels. In addition. we construct regional panels, such as those representing the Arab States, East Asia and the Pacific. South Asia, Latin America and the Caribbean. and Sub-Saharan Africa. Our main finding is that, based on the conditional convergence model, convergence of stock market capitalization and stocks traded is found for four panels, namely the high and low-income panels, the OECD panel, and the Sub-Saharan African panel. The speed of convergence is high, in most cases between 20% and 30%. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Narayan, Paresh Kumar; Mishra, Sagarika; Narayan, Seema</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selling winners, holding losers: Effect on fund flows and survival of disposition-prone mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singal, Vijay; Xu, Zhaojin
Recent studies suggest that presence of a disposition effect in a large subset of investors can create stock mispricings, which has serious implications for market efficiency. We examine whether US equity mutual funds are disposition-prone, how that effect influences performance, investor flows and fund survival. and whether the disposition orientation of mutual funds affects stock prices in a sustained manner. We find that about 30% of all funds exhibit some degree of disposition behavior and that such funds underperform funds that are not disposition-prone by 4-6% per year. Moreover, after controlling for performance, tax overhang and other factors that potentially affect flows, disposition-prone funds attract significantly smaller flows than other funds. The results suggest that mutual fund investors are smart enough to minimize investment in disposition-prone funds. Consequently, disposition-prone funds have significantly higher rates of failure than other funds, thereby reducing the impact of such trading behavior on security prices. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Singal, Vijay; Xu, Zhaojin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pernicious effects of contaminated data in risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fresard, Laurent; Perignon, Christophe; Wilhelmsson, Anders
Banks hold capital to guard against unexpected surges in losses and long freezes in financial markets. The minimum level of capital is set by banking regulators as a function of the banks' own estimates of their risk exposures. As a result, a great challenge for both banks and regulators is to validate internal risk models. We show that a large fraction of US and international banks uses contaminated data when testing their models. In particular, most banks validate their market risk model using profit-and-loss (P/L) data that include fees and commissions and intraday trading revenues. This practice is inconsistent with the definition of the employed market risk measure. Using both bank data and simulations, we find that data contamination has dramatic implications for model validation and can lead to the acceptance of misspecified risk models. Moreover, our estimates suggest that the use of contaminated data can significantly reduce (market-risk induced) regulatory capital. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fresard, Laurent; Perignon, Christophe; Wilhelmsson, Anders</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio selection with mental accounts and delegation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Gordon J.; Baptista, Alexandre M.
Das et al. (2010) develop an elegant framework where an investor selects portfolios within mental accounts but ends up holding an aggregate portfolio on the mean-variance frontier. This investor directly allocates the wealth in each account among available assets. In practice, however, investors often delegate the task of allocating wealth among assets to portfolio managers who seek to beat certain benchmarks. Accordingly, we extend their framework to the case where the investor allocates the wealth in each account among portfolio managers. Our contribution is threefold. First, we provide an analytical characterization of the existence and composition of the optimal portfolios within accounts and the aggregate portfolio. Second, we present conditions under which such portfolios are not on the mean-variance frontier, and conditions under which they are. Third. we show that the aforementioned analytical characterization is also applicable within the framework of Das et al. and thus improves upon their numerical approach. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, Gordon J.; Baptista, Alexandre M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The asymmetric behavior and procyclical impact of asset correlations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Shih-Cheng; Lin, Chien-Ting; Yang, Chih-Kai
This paper examines the behavior of asset correlations with the market returns in the asymptotic single risk factor (ASRF) approach of the Basel II accord on regulatory capital requirement. Over a sample period from 1988 to 2007, we find that asset correlations are positively related to firm size, but negatively related to firm default probability. Asset correlations are also industry specific, as firms in media, transportation, pharmaceutical, and semiconductor industries exhibit higher asset correlations than those in retail and consumer staples. Most importantly, asset correlations are asymmetric and have a procyclical impact on the real economy after controlling for these effects. They tend to rise during economic downturns, but decline during economic upturns. The average magnitude of the rise is larger than that of the decline. These findings suggest that asset correlations may be underestimated during economic downturns, and may provide policy implications for the capital requirement framework. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Shih-Cheng; Lin, Chien-Ting; Yang, Chih-Kai</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The return impact of realized and expected idiosyncratic volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peterson, David R.; Smedema, Adam R.
We show that the negative relation between realized idiosyncratic volatility, measured over the prior month, and returns is robust in non-January months. Controlling for realized idiosyncratic volatility, we show that the relation between returns and expected idiosyncratic volatility is positive and robust. Realized and expected idiosyncratic volatility are separate and important effects describing the cross-section of returns. We find the negative return on a zero-investment portfolio that is long high realized idiosyncratic volatility stocks and short low realized idiosyncratic volatility stocks is dependent on aggregate investor sentiment. In cross-sectional tests, we find the negative relation is weaker for stocks with a large analyst following and stronger for stocks with high dispersion of analyst forecasts. The positive relation between expected idiosyncratic volatility and returns is not due to mispricing. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Peterson, David R.; Smedema, Adam R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Perfect surcharging and the tourist test interchange fee</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zenger, Hans
Two widely discussed pricing benchmarks in the literature on payment card markets are the "tourist test" interchange fee (Rochet and Tirole, forthcoming), which internalizes usage externalities in payment card markets. and "perfect surcharging" by merchants (Rochet and Tirole, 2002). This paper shows that these benchmarks are allocatively equivalent. Implications for the regulatory treatment of interchange fees and no-surcharge rules are discussed. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zenger, Hans</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of changes in bank ownership structure on the allocation of capital: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taboada, Alvaro G.
A new wave of bank privatizations in the past decade has significantly changed the ownership structure of banking systems around the world. This paper explores how these changes affect the allocation of capital within countries. Increases in domestic blockholder ownership of banks adversely affect the allocation of capital through increased lending activity to less productive industries and to those with less dependence on external finance. This result is more pronounced in countries with higher levels of corruption. I find some evidence that foreign presence improves capital allocation efficiency by increasing lending to more productive industries, primarily in common law countries. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Taboada, Alvaro G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday jumps and US macroeconomic news announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evans, Kevin P.
This paper applies recent non-parametric intraday jump detection procedures to investigate the presence and importance of intraday jumps in US futures markets. More importantly. the paper investigates the extent to which statistically significant intraday jumps are associated with US macroeconomic news announcements. Jumps are prevalent, large and contribute heavily to total daily price variation. Approximately one third of jumps correspond to US macroeconomic news announcements, with pure announcement effects causing large increases in the absolute sizes of jumps and the informational surprise of the announcement explaining large proportions of the jumps. The statistical and economic significance of news-related jumps is confirmed by results that show higher volatility persistence. predictability of lower frequency returns, larger effects on microstructure variables, jump clustering and co-jumps from these jumps versus non-news-related jumps, although there are some interesting variations across asset classes. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Evans, Kevin P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging the black swan: Conditional heteroskedasticity and tail dependence in S&amp;P500 and VIX</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hilal, Sawsan; Poon, Ser-Huang; Tawn, Jonathan
The recent financial crisis has accentuated the fact that extreme outcomes have been overlooked and not dealt with adequately. While extreme value theories have existed for a long time, the multivariate variant is difficult to handle in the financial markets due to the prevalent heteroskedasticity embedded in most financial time series, and the complex extremal dependence that cannot be conveniently captured by a single structure. Moreover, most of the existing approaches are based on a limiting argument in which all variables become large at the same rate. In this paper, we show how the conditional approach of Heffernan and lawn (2004) can be implemented to model extremal dependence between financial time series. We use a hedging example based on VIX futures to demonstrate the flexibility and superiority of the conditional approach against the conventional OLS regression approach. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hilal, Sawsan; Poon, Ser-Huang; Tawn, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does corporate social responsibility affect the cost of capital?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.; Mishra, Dev R.
We examine the effect of corporate social responsibility (CSR) on the cost of equity capital for a large sample of US firms. Using several approaches to estimate firms' ex ante cost of equity, we find that firms with better CSR scores exhibit cheaper equity financing. In particular, our findings suggest that investment in improving responsible employee relations, environmental policies, and product strategies contributes substantially to reducing firms' cost of equity. Our results also show that participation in two "sin" industries, namely, tobacco and nuclear power, increases firms' cost of equity. These findings support arguments in the literature that firms with socially responsible practices have higher valuation and lower risk. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.; Mishra, Dev R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial ownership and the disposition effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fu, Richard; Wedge, Lei
This paper examines the relationship between mutual fund managers' ownership and the disposition effect. Using recently disclosed managerial ownership data required by new SEC rules, we document that a significant number of mutual funds exhibit the disposition effect. Funds with managerial ownership exhibit significantly less disposition effect than those without, and the disposition measure decreases with managers' percentage ownership. We also find that the disposition effect is negatively related to the degree of board independence and fund performance. Our findings suggest that the disposition effect is significantly affected by fund governance and higher managerial ownership may help mitigate the problem. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fu, Richard; Wedge, Lei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A tale of values-driven and profit-seeking social investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Derwall, Jeroen; Koedijk, Kees; Ter Horst, Jenke
The segmentation of the socially responsible investing (SRI) movement with a values-versus-profit orientation solves the puzzling evidence that both socially responsible and controversial stocks produce superior returns. We derive that the segment of values-driven investors primarily uses "negative" screens to avoid controversial stocks, while the profit-driven segment uses "positive" screens. As the result of an empirical analysis over the period 1992-2008, we base our segmentation on investment screens that help us to examine whether values affect prices. We find that, although the profit-driven segment earns abnormal returns in the short run, these profit-generating opportunities do not persist in the long run for SRI stocks. However, our conclusions highlight the observation that different views on SRI can be complementary in the short run. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Derwall, Jeroen; Koedijk, Kees; Ter Horst, Jenke</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pricing dynamics of cross-listed securities: The case of Chinese A- and H-shares</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Charlie X.; McGuinness, Paul B.; Zhang, Qi
We develop a non-linear Markov error correction approach to examine the general co-integration relation between the H- and A-prices of cross-listed Chinese stock issuers across the period January 1999 to March 2009. We unravel three important dimensions of this relation. These pertain to (i) the long-run expectation of the H- (to A-price) discount; (ii) the level of short-run co-movement in prices; and (iii) the magnitude of error corrections. Findings point to significant improvements in all three areas. Policy and corporate governance change appears to be the principal force driving the efficiency gains. Weakening informational asymmetries underlie much of the change in the markets' relative pricing. In contrast, sentiment effects strongly underpin the contemporaneous response and error correction adjustments. Finally, the escalating Global Financial Crisis of 2008 appears to have not only bolstered the A- and H-markets' short-term pricing dynamic but also temporarily increased the long-term H-share discount. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cai, Charlie X.; McGuinness, Paul B.; Zhang, Qi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Counter-cyclical substitution between trade credit and bank credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Hui; Shi, Xiaojun; Zhang, Shunming
This paper explores the substitution relationship between trade credit and bank credit, and its counter-cyclic dynamic pattern through economic cycles. We propose a new theoretical model, using a mechanism design method, which predicts the substitution between the two credits and its counter-cyclic behavior, subject to the condition of technological efficiency not less than one. This model also helps explain the somewhat contradictory evidence in the literature, on the relationship between the two credits. We present empirical evidence on the substitution effect and its counter-cyclic behavior, by using a balanced panel data set of 284 listed Chinese companies for the period 1998-2006. We further find that the substitution behaves counter-cyclically with respect to the coincident macroeconomic indicator, namely, GDP. Our empirical analysis also has some new features such as treating endogeneity carefully and incorporating the lag-effect of trade credit coherently. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved,</description><author>Huang, Hui; Shi, Xiaojun; Zhang, Shunming</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home country bias: Does domestic experience help investors enter foreign markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abreu, Margarida; Mendes, Victor; Santos, Joao A. C.
This paper investigates the dynamics of individuals' investments leading up to their decision to make the first investment abroad. We show that investors first invest in domestic securities and only some time later they invest abroad in foreign securities. We also show that investors who trade more often in the domestic market start to invest abroad earlier. Our findings suggest that the experience investors acquire while they trade in the domestic market is a key reason why active investors enter the foreign market earlier. A reason is that highly educated investors as well as investors with more financial knowledge, arguably those for whom learning by trading is the least important, do not need to trade as much in the domestic market before they start investing in foreign securities. Another reason is that investors who start investing in foreign securities are able to improve on their performance afterwards. This improvement in performance constitutes further evidence that the home country bias is costly. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abreu, Margarida; Mendes, Victor; Santos, Joao A. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sufficient conditions for expected utility to imply drawdown-based performance rankings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schuhmacher, Frank; Eling, Martin
The least restrictive sufficient condition for expected utility to imply Sharpe ratio rankings is the location and scale (LS) property (see Sinn, 1983; Meyer, 1987). The normal, the extreme value, and many other distributions commonly used in finance satisfy this property. We argue that the LS property is also sufficient for expected utility to imply drawdown-based performance measure rankings, because for investment funds satisfying the LS condition, the Sharpe ratio and drawdown-based performance measures result in identical rankings. Hence, the same conditions that provide an expected utility foundation for the Sharpe ratio also provide a foundation for drawdown-based performance measures. We conclude that from a decision-theoretic perspective, drawdown-based performance measures are as good as the Sharpe ratio. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schuhmacher, Frank; Eling, Martin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign exchange risk pricing and equity market segmentation in Africa</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kodongo, Odongo; Ojah, Kalu
This work is the first to investigate simultaneously the occurrence of unconditional currency risk pricing and equity market segmentation in Africa's major stock markets. The multi-factor asset pricing theory provides the theoretical framework for our model. We find strong evidence suggesting that Africa's equity markets are partially segmented. However, we find insufficient evidence to reject the hypothesis that foreign exchange risk is not unconditionally priced in Africa's stock markets. This result is robust to alternative foreign exchange rate-adjusted return measures. These findings suggest that international investors can diversify into Africa's equity markets without worrying about unconditional risks associated with foreign exchange rate fluctuations. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kodongo, Odongo; Ojah, Kalu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multivariate option pricing with time varying volatility and correlations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rombouts, Jeroen V. K.; Stentoft, Lars
In this paper we consider option pricing using multivariate models for asset returns. Specifically, we demonstrate the existence of an equivalent martingale measure, we characterize the risk neutral dynamics, and we provide a feasible way for pricing options in this framework. Our application confirms the importance of allowing for dynamic correlation, and it shows that accommodating correlation risk and modeling non-Gaussian features with multivariate mixtures of normals substantially changes the estimated option prices. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rombouts, Jeroen V. K.; Stentoft, Lars</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The 2008 short sale ban: Liquidity, dispersion of opinion, and the cross-section of returns of US financial stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Autore, Don M.; Billingsley, Randall S.; Kovacs, Tunde
This study examines the cross-sectional impact of the 2008 short sale ban on the returns of US financial stocks. Motivated by the large cross-sectional variation in the extent to which banned stocks suffer an illiquidity shock, we hypothesize that stocks with larger liquidity declines are associated with poorer contemporaneous stock returns. The evidence supports this hypothesis and suggests that this effect is stronger for more liquid stocks, as predicted by Amihud and Mendelson (1986). Moreover, consistent with Miller's (1977) model, we report a valuation reversal whereby stocks with higher abnormal returns at the onset of the ban have lower abnormal returns at its removal. Our findings are robust when we control for firms most affected by TARP, include non-banned matched firms, and compare banned firms' stock returns with their bond returns. From a policy standpoint, the ban reduced valuations, ceteris paribus, of the stocks that were hardest hit by illiquidity. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Autore, Don M.; Billingsley, Randall S.; Kovacs, Tunde</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum or contrarian investment strategies: Evidence from Dutch institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Haan, Leo; Kakes, Jan
This paper analyses investment strategies of three types of Dutch institutional investors - pension funds, life insurers and non-life insurers - over the period 1999-2005. We use balance sheet and cash flow data, including purchases and sales of equity, fixed income and real estate. We trace asset reallocations back to both active trading and revaluations and link investment decisions to firm-specific characteristics and macroeconomic variables. Overall, our results indicate that all three investor types tend to be contrarian traders, i.e. they buy past losers and sell past winners. Especially pension funds showed this behaviour in the most turbulent part of the sample - the crash of 2002 and early 2003 - implying that these institutions have a stabilising impact on financial markets when this is needed most. Life insurers tend to be contrarian traders when they have a high proportion of unit-linked policies, while non-life insurers are contrarian when they have a more risky business model. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Haan, Leo; Kakes, Jan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bidders' strategic timing of acquisition announcements and the effects of payment method on target returns and competing bids</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chou, Robin K.; Lee, Yun-Chi
Using a sample of acquisition announcements released during trading versus nontrading hours, this study examines how the strategic timing of acquisition announcements determines the impact of the method of payment on target stock returns and competition among bidders. For overnight acquisition announcements, we find that cash payment offers positively and significantly affect acquisition premiums and target returns, yet these results do not hold for daytime announcements. Cash payment offers made during nontrading hours are more likely to deter potential bidders and complete proposed transactions. However, we find no such relationship for daytime announcements. These findings suggest that the timing of acquisition announcements by bidders is important for assessing the effects of payment method as a signal of target valuation and a preemption of competing bids. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chou, Robin K.; Lee, Yun-Chi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and asset pricing: Evidence from the Hong Kong stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lam, Keith S. K.; Tam, Lewis H. K.
This study investigates the role of liquidity in pricing stock returns in the Hong Kong stock market. Our results show that liquidity is an important factor for pricing returns in Hong Kong after taking well-documented asset pricing factors into consideration. The results are robust to adding portfolio residuals and higher moment factor in the factor models. The results are also robust to seasonality, and conditional-market tests. We also compare alternative factor models and find that the liquidity four-factor model (market excess return, size, book-to-market ratio, and liquidity) is the best model to explain stock returns in the Hong Kong stock market, while the momentum factor is not found to be priced. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lam, Keith S. K.; Tam, Lewis H. K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The volatility of consumption-based stochastic discount factors and economic cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nieto, Belen; Rubio, Gonzalo
This paper aims to assess the macroeconomic and financial impact of economic uncertainty using information contained in the second moments of financial risk factors employed in the asset pricing literature. Specifically, we propose the volatility of consumption-based stochastic discount factors (SDFs) as a predictor of future economic and stock market cycles. We employ both contemporaneous and ultimate consumption risk specifications with durable and non-durable consumption. Alternative empirical tests show that this volatility has significant forecasting ability from 1985 to 2006. The degree of predictability tends to dominate that shown by standard predictor variables. We argue that the significant predictability of the volatility of consumption-based SDFs reported in this paper relies mainly on the joint effect of their components. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nieto, Belen; Rubio, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric information and price competition in small business lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Ming-Hua; Margaritis, Dimitris; Tourani-Rad, Alireza
This paper examines the relationship between bank lending rates and their cost of funds in New Zealand. Our results show that on average mortgage rates respond more quickly to changes in the cost of funds than base business lending rates. We also find an asymmetry in the initial (short-run) response of banks to changes in funding costs: in particular, our results show banks adjust mortgage rates downwards faster than upwards. The speed to which lending rates revert back to their equilibrium relationship with funding costs varies across the lending markets. We find the adjustment speed is faster when mortgage rates are below equilibrium, whereas it is slower when business lending rates are above long-run levels in relation to funding costs. Our analysis suggests that banks prefer the plain-vanilla type of lending such as mortgages in comparison to small business lending consistent with asymmetric information associated with business loans. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Ming-Hua; Margaritis, Dimitris; Tourani-Rad, Alireza</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal VWAP trading under noisy conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Humphery-Jenner, Mark L.
This article proposes an empirically tractable way to incorporate intra-day noise into a VWAP trading rule. In volatile markets, news arrives unexpectedly and rapidly. This should influence a trader's trading decisions. However, the literature has not incorporated such information into an algorithmic trading framework. Subsequently, this paper presents a Dynamic VWAP (DVWAP) framework that allows informed traders to utilize random news; and thus, improve trade-execution. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Humphery-Jenner, Mark L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank M&amp;A: A market power story?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hankir, Yassin; Rauch, Christian; Umber, Marc P.
This paper analyzes capital market reactions to international bank M&amp;A. We investigate the combined stock return patterns of targets, bidders, and their peers upon takeover announcement, and closing or withdrawal. We distinguish five common M&amp;A hypotheses and relate characteristic and mutually exclusive abnormal stock return patterns to each hypothesis. The findings show that there are more investors who believe in gains through the exploitation of market power by the post-merger entity than investors who believe in any of the other motives tested in the paper. In a multinomial logistic model we show that patterns related to market power significantly concur with large relative target size, intra-industry mergers, and increasing market concentration, suggesting a substantial lessening of competition through M&amp;A. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hankir, Yassin; Rauch, Christian; Umber, Marc P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition among stock exchanges for equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amira, Khaled; Muzere, Mark L.
We consider cross-border competition by stock exchanges for listings from firms that have controlling shareholders who have private benefits. We examine exchanges' choices of their listing standards and firms' choices of the exchanges where they cross-list their shares. We show that the share price compensates controlling shareholders for giving up some private benefits and enables firms with growth opportunities to obtain listings on exchanges with different listing standards. In particular, firms with high-growth opportunities tend to obtain listings on stock exchanges with high listing standards. We empirically examine these predictions and find that they are consistent with evidence. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amira, Khaled; Muzere, Mark L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Have community banks reduced home foreclosure rates?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fogel, Kathy; Kali, Raja; Yeager, Tim
Compared with mortgage brokers and universal banks, community banks have stronger incentives to originate high-quality residential home loans. Using the RealtyTrac database on residential foreclosures between 2005 and 2008, we show that county-level foreclosure rates are lower in counties with greater community bank presence. This finding is robust to a host of county-level economic and demographic control variables and after controlling for possible endogeneity of community bank presence. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fogel, Kathy; Kali, Raja; Yeager, Tim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest on bank reserves and optimal sweeping</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dutkowsky, Donald H.; VanHoose, David D.
A key rationale offered by the Federal Reserve for the payment of interest on reserves was to remove the incentive for banks to operate sweep accounts. Sweeping shifts funds from transactions deposits subject to reserve requirements to non-reservable deposits. This paper extends a conventional banking model to analyze sweeping behavior. Sweeping responds positively to increases in bank loan rates and reserve ratios and negatively to increases in the interest rate on reserves or exogenous increases in bank equity. Sweeping generates greater responsiveness in lending to changes in loan rates or the interest rate on reserves and lower responsiveness to changes in reserve ratios or equity than in its absence. Empirical analysis of an explicit condition that we derive suggests that, with an unchanged reserve requirement, the Fed could eliminate sweeping by setting the interest rate on reserves to no less than approximately 4% points below the market loan rate. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dutkowsky, Donald H.; VanHoose, David D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the evidence for PPP reliable? A sustainability examination of the stationarity of real exchange rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhou, Su; Kutan, Ali M.
Some recent time series studies testing the stationarity of real exchange rates (RERs) produce conflicting results. Using nonlinear unit root tests and recursive analysis, this paper tests whether the evidence on the stationarity of RERs is sensitive to different numeraire currencies, different sample periods covering regional and global crises, and the inclusion of countries with different levels of economic or regional integration. The results indicate that evidence for a stationary RER could be substantially sensitive to sample period changes, but not so for the currencies of the countries involved in forming the euro area. We also find that financial crises have a notable impact on testing the stationarity of RERs, depending on the numeraire currency used. We discuss the policy implications of the findings. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhou, Su; Kutan, Ali M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convergent synergies in the global market for corporate control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madura, Jeff; Ngo, Thanh; Viale, Ariel M.
We investigate the informational role of the takeover premium as a forward looking price to expected synergies in the global market for corporate control. We find that premiums paid in the global market for corporate control are clustered in waves and driven to some extent by the US premium. International takeover premiums have become more responsive to US premiums as the globalization process evolved over time. Short-run divergent dynamics due to idiosyncratic or country-specific factors have become less severe, which suggests that expected synergies have become increasingly integrated in the global market for corporate control. Furthermore, we find that the region's takeover premiums typically become more responsive to US takeover premiums when US economic conditions are relatively weak, when the US monetary policy is restrictive, when US credit risk is high, and when the region's corporate governance (as measured by legal system quality and accounting quality) is high. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Madura, Jeff; Ngo, Thanh; Viale, Ariel M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of stock splits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Honghui; Nguyen, Hoang Huy; Singal, Vijay
We develop a new methodology that controls for both the timing of annual earnings news (Asquith et al., 1989) and the performance prior to split announcements (Barber and Lyon, 1996) to evaluate the information content of stock splits. In contrast to existing evidence, we find that stock splits in aggregate are followed by positive abnormal future earnings growth, suggesting that stock splits contain information about future, rather than past, operating performance. When we use changes in breadth of institutional ownership as a new metric of information content to corroborate our findings, we find that splits with the greatest increase in breadth experience positive post-split abnormal returns and positive abnormal earnings growth. Together, our results suggest that some splits contain positive information about future performance, and that sophisticated market participants such as institutional investors are able to select these splits. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Honghui; Nguyen, Hoang Huy; Singal, Vijay</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-sale constraints and price bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Bryan Y.
Miller (1977) demonstrated that if investors have heterogeneous beliefs and short sales are restricted, trade of a security will disproportionately reflect positive information, generating a price bubble. As this intuition applies most relevantly to short intervals of trade, a question arises as to the longevity of such a bubble. In this paper, I argue that a bubble effected by short-sale constraints persists only if agents cannot distinguish between order flow caused by positive information or order flow caused by the constraints. If the constraint is common knowledge, it should have no effect on the long-term pricing of the stock. If, however, the constraint is random and unknown, a price bubble may form. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lim, Bryan Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lending behavior and real estate prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hott, C.
The willingness of banks to provide funding for real estate purchases depends on the creditworthiness of borrowers. Besides other factors, this creditworthiness depends on the development of real estate prices. Real estate prices, in turn, depend on the demand for homes which is influenced by the supply of mortgages. I develop a theoretical model which explains this circular relationship. I show how different kinds of expectation formations can lead to fluctuations in real estate prices. Furthermore, I show that banks make above-average profits in the upswing phase of the real estate cycle but stiffer high losses when the market turns. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hott, C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implications of bank ownership for the credit channel of monetary policy transmission: Evidence from India</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhaumik, Sumon Kumar; Dang, Vinh; Kutan, Ali M.
Using bank-level data from India, we examine the impact of ownership on the reaction of banks to monetary policy, and also test whether the reaction of different types of banks to monetary policy changes is different in easy and tight policy regimes. Our results suggest that there are considerable differences in the reactions of different types of banks to monetary policy initiatives of the central bank, and that the bank lending channel of monetary policy is likely to be much more effective in a tight money period than in an easy money period. We also find differences in impact of monetary policy changes on less risky short-term and more risky medium-term lending. We discuss the policy implications of the findings. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhaumik, Sumon Kumar; Dang, Vinh; Kutan, Ali M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An investigation of customer order flow in the foreign exchange market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cerrato, Mario; Sarantis, Nicholas; Saunders, Alex
This paper examines the effect that heterogeneous customer orders flows have on exchange rates by using a new, and the largest, proprietary dataset of weekly net order flow segmented by customer type across nine of the most liquid currency pairs. We make several contributions. Firstly, we investigate the extent to which customer order flow can help to explain exchange rate movements over and above the influence of macro-economic variables. Secondly, we address the issue of whether order flows contain (private) information which explain exchange rates changes. Thirdly, we look at the usefulness of order flow in forecasting exchange rate movements at longer horizons than those generally considered in the micro-structure literature. Finally we address the question of whether the out-of-sample exchange rate forecasts generated by order flows can be employed profitably in the foreign exchange markets. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cerrato, Mario; Sarantis, Nicholas; Saunders, Alex</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of taxation on bank profits: Evidence from EU banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiorazzo, Vincenzo; Milani, Carlo
Using bank-level data for the period 1990-2005, we investigate to what extent European banks are able to shift their tax-burden forward. We examine the effects of corporate income tax (CIT) and value added tax (VAT) on pre-tax profits and their components, and find that both are shifted forward. The pass-through mainly involves total operating income, but as far as CIT is concerned it also affects loss provisions, with negative implications on stability of the banking systems. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiorazzo, Vincenzo; Milani, Carlo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of management and board ownership on profitability in banks with different strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Westman, Hanna
In this study I combine the ownership and diversification literature and show that the agency problem varies across traditional, diversified and non-traditional banks. In a sample of European banks, I find that management ownership has a positive impact on profitability in non-traditional banks, whereas board ownership has a positive impact on profitability in traditional banks. These findings indicate that management ownership is important in opaque banks, which are difficult to monitor, whereas board ownership is important in banks where the government guaranteed safety-net reduces the monitoring incentive of depositors, but which are not too complex or opaque for the board to monitor. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Westman, Hanna</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The liquidity effect for open market operations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kopchak, Seth J.
The liquidity effect is the negative relationship between the supply of federal funds and the overnight federal funds rate. Deviations of the federal funds rate from its target can be interpreted as demand innovations for federal funds. Permanent adjustments to demand are modeled as an unobserved component and estimated using the Kalman filter to identify liquidity effects. The demand-based approach for identifying the liquidity effect contrasts previous work which concentrates on errors forecasting the supply of federal funds. This paper finds a liquidity effect several times larger than that from previous studies, indicating the market for federal funds is less liquid than previously thought. The effect of a $1 billion increase in open market operations over a 1-week period is a decrease of the federal funds rate by about 12 basis points. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kopchak, Seth J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How effective are rewards programs in promoting payment card usage? Empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carbo-Valverde, Santiago; Linares-Zegarra, Jose M.
Card issuers have mainly relied on rewards programs as their main strategy to increase usage. However, there is scarce evidence on the effectiveness of these programs. This paper is addressing two topics which could have important managerial and public policy implications: (i) it estimates the impact of rewards on the use of cards and (ii) it quantifies their economic effects in terms of the cash substitution. We find that rewards may significantly modify choice for card payments. Their economic impact also varies significantly across types of rewards and merchant activities. Additionally, rewards seem to be more effective for debit cards. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carbo-Valverde, Santiago; Linares-Zegarra, Jose M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is size dead? A review of the size effect in equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Dijk, Mathijs A.
Beginning with Banz (1981), I review 30 years of research on the size effect in equity returns. Since Fama and French (1992), there has been a vigorous, ongoing debate on whether the size premium is a compensation for systematic risk. Since the late 1990s, research on the size effect has been characterized by two developments that are seemingly contradictory. At last, theoretical models have emerged in which the size effect arises endogenously as a result of systematic risk. However, recent empirical studies assert that the size effect has disappeared after the early 1980s. In this review, I address this disconnect between recent theoretical and empirical research. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>van Dijk, Mathijs A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term structure modelling with observable state variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huse, Cristian
This paper proposes and implements a parsimonious three-factor model of the term structure whose dynamics is driven uniquely by observable state variables. This approach allows comparing alternative views on the way state variables - macroeconomic variables, in particular - influence the yield curve dynamics, avoids curse of dimensionality problems, and provides more reliable inference by using both the cross-sectional and the time series dimension of the data. I simulate the small-sample properties of the procedure and conduct in- and out-of-sample studies using a comprehensive set of US data. I show that even a parsimonious model where the level, slope and curvature factors of the term structure are driven by, respectively, inflation, monetary policy and economic activity consistently outperforms the (latent-variable) benchmark model in an out-of-sample study. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huse, Cristian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial asset demand is elastic: Evidence from new issues of Federal Home Loan Bank debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanasov, Vladimir; Merrick, John
We estimate the slope of the demand curve for newly auctioned FHLB discount notes and investigate the impacts of arbitrage risk and heterogeneity of investor beliefs on demand elasticity. Our unique dataset of roughly 2900 observations of two price-quantity pairs-the first from a pre-auction dealer survey, the second from actual auction results-provides the quantity shift necessary to identify demand. In contrast to previous findings of downward-sloping demand curves for equities, we show that demand for newly issued FHLB notes is nearly perfectly elastic during normal market conditions. We find, however, that frictions like arbitrage risk and, to a lesser extent, heterogeneity of investor beliefs negatively affect elasticity and explain the nearly 50% drop in elasticity observed during the recent financial crisis. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Atanasov, Vladimir; Merrick, John</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which firms engage small, foreign, or state banks? And who goes Islamic? Evidence from Turkey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ongena, Steven; Sendeniz-Yuencue, Ilkay
We study a representative dataset from Turkey that identifies firm-bank connections. Banks in Turkey differ not only in size and nationality, but also in ownership and orientation (non-Islamic versus Islamic)-resulting in at least six distinct bank types. We estimate a multinomial logit of the choice by the firm of bank type. We document a strong correspondence between bank type and firm characteristics that is not always the same as has been documented so far for US datasets. For example, small firms engage large rather than small banks. Young, large, multiple-bank, and industry-diversified firms, that are located in or close to Istanbul, team up with foreign banks. Islamic banks mainly deal with young, multiple-bank, industry-focused and transparent firms. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ongena, Steven; Sendeniz-Yuencue, Ilkay</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimizing international portfolios with options and forwards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Topaloglou, Nikolas; Vladimirou, Hercules; Zenios, Stavros A.
We develop a stochastic programming model to address in a unified manner a number of interrelated decisions in international portfolio management: optimal portfolio diversification and mitigation of market and currency risks. The goal is to control the portfolio's total risk exposure and attain an effective balance between risk and expected return. By incorporating options and forward contracts in the portfolio optimization model we are able to numerically assess the performance of alternative tactics for mitigating exposure to the primary risks. We find that control of market risk with options has more significant impact on portfolio performance than currency hedging. We demonstrate through extensive empirical tests that incremental benefits, in terms of reducing risk and generating profits, are gained when both the market and currency risks are jointly controlled through appropriate means. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Topaloglou, Nikolas; Vladimirou, Hercules; Zenios, Stavros A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock repurchases: How firms choose between a self tender offer and an open-market program</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oded, Jacob
In practice, open-market stock repurchase programs outnumber self tender offers by approximately 10-1. This evidence is puzzling given that tender offers are more efficient in disbursing free cash and in signaling undervaluation - the two main motivations suggested in the literature for repurchasing shares. We provide a theoretical model to explore this puzzle. In the model, tender offers disburse free cash quickly but induce information asymmetry and hence require a price premium. Open-market programs disburse free cash slowly, and hence do not require a price premium, but because they are slow, result in partial free cash waste. The model predicts that the likelihood that a tender offer will be chosen over an open-market program increases with the agency costs of free cash and decreases with uncertainty (risk), information asymmetry, ownership concentration, and liquidity. These predictions are generally consistent with the empirical evidence. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oded, Jacob</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing the impact of credit migration in a portfolio setting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsaig, Yaakov; Levy, Amnon; Wang, Yashan
Credit migration is an essential component of credit portfolio modeling. In this paper, we outline a framework for gauging the effects of credit migration on portfolio risk measurements. For a typical loan portfolio, we find credit migration can explain as much as 51% of volatility and 35% of economic capital. We compare through-the-cycle migration effects, implied by agency rating transitions, with point-in-time migration, implied by EDF (TM) (Expected Default Frequency) transitions, and find that migration of point-in-time credit quality accounts for a greater fraction of total portfolio risk when compared with through-the-cycle dynamics. In a stylized analytic setting, we show that, when controlling for PD term structure effects, higher likelihood of moving away from the current credit state does not necessarily imply greater risk. Finally, we review methods for generating high-frequency transition matrices, needed for analyzing instruments with cash flows or contingencies whose frequencies are asynchronous to an available transition matrix. We further demonstrate that the naive application of such methods can result in material deviations to portfolio analytics. (C) 2011 Moody's Investors Service Inc. and/or its affiliates. Reprinted with permission. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tsaig, Yaakov; Levy, Amnon; Wang, Yashan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility and covariation of financial assets: A high-frequency analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cartea, Alvaro; Karyampas, Dimitrios
Using high frequency data for the price dynamics of equities we measure the impact that market microstructure noise has on estimates of the: (i) volatility of returns; and (ii) variance-covariance matrix of n assets. We propose a Kalman-filter-based methodology that allows us to deconstruct price series into the true efficient price and the microstructure noise. This approach allows us to employ volatility estimators that achieve very low Root Mean Squared Errors (RMSEs) compared to other estimators that have been proposed to deal with market microstructure noise at high frequencies. Furthermore, this price series decomposition allows us to estimate the variance covariance matrix of n assets in a more efficient way than the methods so far proposed in the literature. We illustrate our results by calculating how microstructure noise affects portfolio decisions and calculations of the equity beta in a CAPM setting. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cartea, Alvaro; Karyampas, Dimitrios</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading frequency and asset pricing on the London Stock Exchange: Evidence from a new price impact ratio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Florackis, Chris; Gregoriou, Andros; Kostakis, Alexandros
This study proposes a new price impact ratio as an alternative to the widely used Amihud's (2002) Return-to-Volume ratio. We demonstrate that the new price impact ratio, which is deemed Return-to-Turnover ratio, has a number of appealing features. Using daily data from all stocks listed on the London Stock Exchange over the period 1991-2008, we provide overwhelming evidence that this ratio, while being unequivocal to construct and interpret, is also free of a size bias. More importantly, it encapsulates the stocks' cross-sectional variability in trading frequency, a relatively neglected but possibly important determinant of stock returns given the recently observed trends in financial markets. Overall, our findings argue against the conventional wisdom that there is a simple direct link between trading costs and stock returns by strongly suggesting that it is the compound effect of trading frequency and transaction costs that matters for asset pricing, not each aspect in isolation. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Florackis, Chris; Gregoriou, Andros; Kostakis, Alexandros</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incorporating the dynamics of leverage into default prediction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loeffler, Gunter; Maurer, Alina
A firm's current leverage ratio is one of the core characteristics of credit quality used in statistical default prediction models. Based on the capital structure literature, which shows that leverage is mean-reverting to a target leverage, we forecast future leverage ratios and include them in the set of default risk drivers. An out-of-sample analysis of default predictions from a hazard model reveals that the discriminative power increases substantially when leverage forecasts are included. We further document that credit ratings contain information beyond the one contained in standard variables but that this information is unrelated to forecasts of leverage ratios. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loeffler, Gunter; Maurer, Alina</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional beta pricing models: A nonparametric approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Eva; Gil-Bazo, Javier; Orbe, Susan
We propose a two-stage procedure to estimate conditional beta pricing models that allows for flexibility in the dynamics of asset betas and market prices of risk (MPR). First, conditional betas are estimated nonparametrically for each asset and period using the time-series of previous data. Then, time-varying MPR are estimated from the cross-section of returns and betas. We prove the consistency and asymptotic normality of the estimators. We also perform Monte Carlo simulations for the conditional version of the three-factor model of Fama and French (1993) and show that nonparametrically estimated betas outperform rolling betas under different specifications of beta dynamics. Using return data on the 25 size and book-to-market sorted portfolios, we find that the nonparametric procedure produces a better fit of the three-factor model to the data, less biased estimates of MPR and lower pricing errors than the Fama-MacBeth procedure with betas estimated under several alternative parametric specifications. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferreira, Eva; Gil-Bazo, Javier; Orbe, Susan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the acquisition of equity carve-outs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, Chintal A.; Klock, Mark S.; Mansi, Sattar A.
We examine the role played by the parent's motive in undertaking a carve-out; the parent's post-IPO influence over the carved-out subsidiary; and anti-takeover provisions and industry structure of a carve-out on its acquisition likelihood and its acquisition premium. We find that the probability and hazard of a carve-out acquisition increase when the parent's objective is to unlock the value of a subsidiary and when the parent and the subsidiary are tied with a product-market relationship. We also find that the post-IPO parent ownership significantly affects the acquisition likelihood and the level of acquisition premium. Additional analyses examining the post-IPO carve-out status suggest that the product-market relationship and post-IPO parent ownership increase the probability of re-acquisition. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Desai, Chintal A.; Klock, Mark S.; Mansi, Sattar A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring via staging: Evidence from Private investments in public equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Na
I study the causes and consequences of staging in the setting of private investments in public equities (PIPEs). I find that, in PIPE investments, as in venture capital staging, the staging strategy is used by investors as a monitoring mechanism to mitigate information asymmetry and agency problems. Moreover, strategic investors and investors investing alone are more likely to utilize staging. I show also that staging reduces the cost of financing and has positive implications for PIPE issuers' long-run stock performance. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dai, Na</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposit insurance and subsidized recapitalizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morrison, Alan D.; White, Lucy
The 2007-2009 financial crisis saw a vast expansion in deposit insurance guarantees around the world and yet our understanding of the design and consequences of deposit insurance schemes is in its infancy. We provide a new rationale for the provision of deposit insurance. In our model the banking sector exhibits both adverse selection and moral hazard, which implies that the social benefits of bank monitoring must for incentive reasons be shared between depositors and banks. Consequently, socially too few deposits are made in equilibrium. Deposit insurance - or, equivalently, bank recapitalization - corrects this market failure. We find that deposit insurance should be funded not by banks or depositors but out of general taxation. The optimal level of deposit insurance varies inversely with the quality of the banking system. Hence, when the soundness of the financial sector is uncertain, governments should consider supporting deposit insurance schemes and undertaking subsidized recapitalizations. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morrison, Alan D.; White, Lucy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional trading and share returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foster, F. Douglas; Gallagher, David R.; Looi, Adrian
Using a unique database of daily transactions from Australian equity managers, we investigate the relation between institutional trading and share returns. The 34 institutional investors included in our sample exhibit a statistically and economically significant ability to predict large capitalization share returns for the ten days following their trades. Detailed analysis indicates that investment manager style is important in understanding the link between institutional trading and stock returns. The contemporaneous relation between institutional trading and returns depends on trade size, broker use, and investment style. We find growth-oriented managers are momentum traders, while style-neutral and value managers are contrarian. (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Foster, F. Douglas; Gallagher, David R.; Looi, Adrian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New evidence on oil price and firm returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayan, Paresh Kumar; Sharma, Susan Sunila
In this paper, we examine the relationship between oil price and firm returns for 560 US firms listed on the NYSE. First, we find that oil price affects returns of firms differently depending on their sectoral location. Second, we find strong evidence of lagged effect of oil price on firm returns. Third, we test whether oil price affects firm returns based on different regimes and find that in five out of the 14 sectors this is indeed the case. Finally, we unravel that oil price affects firm returns differently based on firm size, implying strong evidence of size effects. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Narayan, Paresh Kumar; Sharma, Susan Sunila</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic risk and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Jangkoo; Kim, Tong Suk; Lee, Changjun; Min, Byoung-Kyu
We develop a conditional version of the consumption capital asset pricing model (CCAPM) using the conditioning variable from the cointegrating relation among macroeconomic variables (dividend yield, term spread, default spread, and short-term interest rate). Our conditioning variable has a strong power to predict market excess returns in the presence of competing predictive variables. In addition, our conditional CCAPM performs approximately as well as Fama and French's (1993) three-factor model in explaining the cross-section of the Fama and French 25 size and book-to-market sorted portfolios. Our specification shows that value stocks are riskier than growth stocks in bad times, supporting the risk-based story. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kang, Jangkoo; Kim, Tong Suk; Lee, Changjun; Min, Byoung-Kyu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Participating mortgages and the efficiency of financial intermediation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ebrahim, M. Shahid; Shackleton, Mark B.; Wojakowski, Rafal M.
This paper establishes a basic framework to study three different variants of Participating Mortgages (PMs). We obtain results for Shared Appreciation Mortgages (SAMs), Shared Income Mortgages (SIMs) and Shared Equity Mortgages (SEMs) in closed-form. We illustrate our findings with examples that show PMs are also attractive in an environment where prepayment can occur. Finally we conclude with the public policy implications of employing PMs as workout loans, especially post sub-prime crisis. We argue that by facilitating better risk sharing, PMs offer a means to enhance the efficiency and resiliency of the financial system. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ebrahim, M. Shahid; Shackleton, Mark B.; Wojakowski, Rafal M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Control-ownership wedge and investment sensitivity to stock price</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Li; Kim, Jeong-Bon; Pang, Lei
This study examines whether insiders' incentives for private control benefits affect investment sensitivity to stock price. While Chen et al. (2007) link stock price informativeness to firms' learning from the stock market, we offer an alternative agency-cost based explanation. Using a total of 2822 firms from 22 countries in East Asia and Western Europe, we document a strong negative association between control-ownership wedge and investment-q sensitivity, suggesting that insiders' incentives for private control benefit reduce their propensity to listen to the market. Furthermore, the negative impact of wedge on investment-q sensitivity is primarily driven by sub-optimal investments. Overall, we provide evidence that agency problem is an important factor that determines the learning from the stock market in capital allocation. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Li; Kim, Jeong-Bon; Pang, Lei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility transmission in emerging European foreign exchange markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bubak, Vit; Kocenda, Evzen; Zikes, Filip
This paper studies the dynamics of volatility transmission between Central European (CE) currencies and the EUR/USD foreign exchange using model-free estimates of daily exchange rate volatility based on intraday data. We formulate a flexible yet parsimonious parametric model in which the daily realized volatility of a given exchange rate depends both on its own lags as well as on the lagged realized volatilities of the other exchange rates. We find evidence of statistically significant intra-regional volatility spillovers among the CE foreign exchange markets. With the exception of the Czech and, prior to the recent turbulent economic events, Polish currencies, we find no significant spillovers running from the EUR/USD to the CE foreign exchange markets. To measure the overall magnitude and evolution of volatility transmission over time, we construct a dynamic version of the Diebold-Yilmaz volatility spillover index and Keywords: show that volatility spillovers tend to increase in periods characterized by market uncertainty. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bubak, Vit; Kocenda, Evzen; Zikes, Filip</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resolving the deposit dilemma: A new DEA bank efficiency model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holod, Dmytro; Lewis, Herbert F.
One of the weaknesses of current bank efficiency models is a disagreement as to the role of deposits in the bank production process. Some models view deposits as an input, while others view them as an output. Such disparity of approaches results in inconsistent efficiency estimates. In this study we propose an alternative Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA) bank efficiency model that treats deposits as an intermediate product, thus emphasizing the dual role of deposits in the bank production process. Consequently, the effect of the amount of deposits on bank efficiency depends on the efficiency at both stages of the bank production process. The main advantage of our model is that it does not require a researcher to make a judgment call as to whether having more (production approach) or less (intermediation approach) deposits is "better" for bank efficiency. Our unified framework has the potential to produce more consistent efficiency estimates. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Holod, Dmytro; Lewis, Herbert F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are small family firms financially sophisticated?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Di Giuli, Alberta; Caselli, Stefano; Gatti, Stefano
We study the drivers of financial sophistication in small family firms. Sophistication is defined as the use of non-basic financial products such as options, swaps, debt restructuring, and mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;A) advisory services. Our analysis is based on a unique dataset with detailed information on 187 Italian family firms. We find that the main drivers of financial sophistication are: (1) the generation that currently owns the firm; (2) the presence of a non-family CFO; and (3) the existence of a non-family shareholder. We analyze the impact of these factors on the following four classes of non-basic financial products: corporate finance, cash management, corporate lending and risk management. Our results can be used to determine the characteristics of financially sophisticated family firms and whether their corporate governance and ownership structure increase the use of non-basic financial products. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Di Giuli, Alberta; Caselli, Stefano; Gatti, Stefano</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Marriage and other risky assets: A portfolio approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertocchi, Graziella; Brunetti, Marianna; Torricelli, Costanza
We study the joint impact of gender and marital status on financial investments by testing the hypothesis that marriage represents - in a portfolio framework - a sort of safe asset and that this attribute may change over time. We show that married individuals have a higher propensity to invest in risky assets than single ones, that this marital status gap is stronger for women and that, for women only, it evolves and declines at the end of the sample period. Next we explore a number of possible explanations of the observed gender differences by controlling for background factors that capture the evolution of family and society. We find that both the higher female marital status gap and its time variability vanish for those women who are employed. Our empirical investigation is based on a dataset drawn from the 1993-2006 Bank of Italy Survey of Household Income and Wealth. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bertocchi, Graziella; Brunetti, Marianna; Torricelli, Costanza</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Habit-based asset pricing with limited participation consumption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bach, Christian; Moller, Stig V.
We calibrate and estimate a consumption-based asset pricing model with habit formation using limited participation consumption data. Based on survey data of a representative sample of American households, we distinguish between assetholder and non-assetholder consumption, as well as the standard aggregate consumption series commonly used in the CCAPM literature. We show that assetholder consumption outperforms non-assetholder and aggregate consumption data in explaining bond returns, bond yields, and the volatility of bond yields. We further show that the high volatility of assetholder consumption enables the model to explain the equity premium puzzle and the risk-free rate puzzle simultaneously for a reasonable value of relative risk aversion. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bach, Christian; Moller, Stig V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The persistence of bank profit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goddard, John; Liu, Hong; Molyneux, Philip; Wilson, John U. S.
This paper examines the intensity of competition in 65 national banking industries. Country-level dynamic panel estimates of the persistence of bank profit are reported and compared. Persistence of bank profit is interpreted as an indicator of the intensity of competition, and as such is found to be consistent with traditional structure-based and conduct-based competition indicators. Persistence is negatively related to the rate of growth in GDP per capita, and positively related to the size of entry barriers. Persistence tends to be weaker, and competition stronger, in countries where institutional development is more advanced and external governance mechanisms are strong. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goddard, John; Liu, Hong; Molyneux, Philip; Wilson, John U. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme returns: The case of currencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Osler, Carol; Savaser, Tanseli
Financial market crashes can occur even in the absence of news. This paper highlights four properties of price-contingent trading that increase the frequency of such events. Price-contingent trading is common across financial market, since it includes algorithmic trading, technical trading, and dynamic option hedging. The four properties we consider are: (1) high kurtosis in the distribution of order sizes; (2) clustering of trades within the day; (3) clustering of trades at certain prices; and (4) feedback between trading and returns. The paper estimates the relative importance of these factors using data from the foreign exchange market. Calibrated simulations indicate that interactions among these factors are at least as important as any single one. Among individual factors, the orders' size distribution and feedback effects have the strongest influence. Overall, price-contingent trading could account for half of realized excess kurtosis. The paper suggests that extreme returns unaccompanied by news are statistically inevitable in the presence of price-contingent trading. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Osler, Carol; Savaser, Tanseli</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparison of modeling methods for Loss Given Default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qi, Min; Zhao, Xinlei
We compare six modeling methods for Loss Given Default (LGD). We find that non-parametric methods (regression tree and neural network) perform better than parametric methods both in and out of sample when over-fitting is properly controlled. Among the parametric methods, fractional response regression has a slight edge over OLS regression. Performance of the transformation methods (inverse Gaussian and beta transformation) is very sensitive to epsilon, a small adjustment made to LGDs of 0 or 1 prior to transformation. Model fit is poor when epsilon is too small or too large, although the fitted LGDs have strong bi-modal distribution with very small epsilon. Therefore, models that produce strong bi-model pattern do not necessarily have good model fit and accurate LGD predictions. Even with an optimal epsilon, the performance of the transformation methods can only match that of the OLS. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Qi, Min; Zhao, Xinlei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting the presence of insider trading via structural break tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Olmo, Jose; Pilbeam, Keith; Pouliot, William
The occurrence of abnormal returns before the unscheduled announcement of price sensitive information is a potential indicator of insider trading. We identify insider trading with a structural change in the intercept of an extended capital asset pricing model. To detect such a change we introduce a consistent timing structural break test (CTSB) based upon a U-statistic type process. Unlike the traditional CUSUM test, the CTSB test provides a consistent estimator of the timing of a break in the intercept that occurs across the whole evaluation period. We apply our test to a rich data set covering 370 price sensitive announcements relating to FTSE 350 companies. Our test is able to detect potential insider trading far more reliably than the standard CUSUM test. We also show that the majority of suspected insider trading takes place in the 25 days prior to the release of market sensitive information. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Olmo, Jose; Pilbeam, Keith; Pouliot, William</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ability of accounting and audit quality variables to predict bank failure during the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Justin Yiqiang; Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lobo, Gerald J.
We examine the ability of selected accounting and audit quality variables measured in a period prior to the financial crisis (i.e., the four quarters of 2006), to predict banks that subsequently failed during the financial crisis. We employ two sets of samples from the US: a troubled banks sample that includes banks that failed in or after 2007 as well as banks classified as being troubled based on profitability, loan quality, and balance sheet position in 2007, and a full sample that includes all banks with available required data. Using the troubled banks sample, we identify six reliable predictors of bank failure: auditor type, auditor industry specialization, Tier 1 capital ratio, proportion of securitized loans, growth in loans, and loan mix. For the larger full sample of banks, we identify the following ten predictors of bank failure: auditor type, Tier 1 capital ratio, proportion of securitized loans, nonperforming loans, loan loss provisions, growth in commercial loans, growth in real estate loans, growth in overall loans, loan mix, and whether the bank is a public bank. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jin, Justin Yiqiang; Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lobo, Gerald J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of macroeconomic news on stock returns: New evidence from newspaper coverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Birz, Gene; Lott, John R.
Previous literature has produced weak evidence to support the hypothesis that real economic news affects stock returns. This is, in part, attributed to the difficulty of measuring how investors interpret macroeconomic announcements in different economic environments. In this paper, we choose a different approach of measuring macroeconomic news to better estimate its effect on stock returns. Since newspaper stories provide an interpretation of the statistical releases, we choose newspaper stories as our measure of news. Our findings indicate that news about GDP and unemployment does affect stock returns. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Birz, Gene; Lott, John R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme dependence with asymmetric thresholds: Evidence for the European Monetary Union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herrera, R.; Eichler, S.
Existing papers on extreme dependence use symmetrical thresholds to define simultaneous stock market booms or crashes such as the joint occurrence of the upper or lower one percent return quantile in both stock markets. We show that the probability of the joint occurrence of extreme stock returns may be higher for asymmetric thresholds than for symmetric thresholds. We propose a non-parametric measure of extreme dependence which allows capturing extreme events for different thresholds and can be used to compute different types of extreme dependence. We find that extreme dependence among the stock markets of ten initial EMU member countries, the United Kingdom, and the United States is largely asymmetrical in the pre-EMU period (1989-1998) and largely symmetrical in the EMU period (1999-2010). Our findings suggest that ignoring the possibility of asymmetric extreme dependence may lead to an underestimation of the probability of co-booms and co-crashes. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Herrera, R.; Eichler, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crash risk of the euro in the sovereign debt crisis of 2009-2010</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hui, Cho-Hoi; Chung, Tsz-Kin
The economic-political instability of a country, which is tied to its credit risk, often leads to sharp depreciation and heightened volatility in its currency. This paper shows that not only the creditworthiness of the euro-area countries with weaker fiscal positions but also that of the member countries with more sound fiscal positions are important determinants of the deep out-of-the-money euro put option prices, which embedded information on the euro crash risk during the sovereign debt crisis of 2009-2010. We also find evidence of information flow from the sovereign credit default swap market to the currency option market during the crisis. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hui, Cho-Hoi; Chung, Tsz-Kin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross hedging under multiplicative basis risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mueller, Axel F. A. Adam; Nolte, Ingmar
Cross hedging price risk in an incomplete financial market creates basis risk. We propose a new way of modeling basis risk where price risk and basis risk are combined in a multiplicative way. Under this specification, positive prudence is a necessary and sufficient condition for underhedging in an unbiased market. Using the example of cross hedging jet fuel price risk with crude oil futures, we show that the new specification is superior in describing the price series and that optimal cross hedges differ significantly from those derived under the traditional additive cross hedging model. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mueller, Axel F. A. Adam; Nolte, Ingmar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Joint effect of financial fragility and macroeconomic shocks on bank loan losses: Evidence from Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pesola, Jarmo
A reduced-form model including nonlinearities is estimated from pooled data from nine European countries during 1982-2004 to show the effects of macroeconomic shocks and financial fragility on bank loan losses. The main ingredients of the model are unanticipated-output and interest-rate shocks estimated from published macroeconomic and naive forecasts. The model fits the data well, capturing the extremely high levels of loan losses witnessed in different financial crises. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pesola, Jarmo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The order flow of discount certificates and issuer pricing behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baule, Rainer
We analyze the order flow of discount certificates, its dependence on product age, and the implications for issuer pricing behavior. Based on a unique data set of exchange trades and issuer quotes, we find that for tax reasons investors prefer to buy products that mature in just over 1 year from the date of purchase. Furthermore, they tend to sell products back preferably close to maturity. These patterns in the trade direction allow us to separate the issuer pricing behavior from (i) the life cycle and (ii) the order flow. We find evidence that 7 out of 11 issuers anticipate the order flow and price in an additional margin in phases of positive expected net sales. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baule, Rainer</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good news, bad news and rating announcements: An empirical investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galil, Koresh; Soffer, Gil
In this paper we employ a new approach to test the contribution of information in rating announcements. This is the first study to test and corroborate how the CDS market responds to rating actions after controlling for the presence of concurrent public and private information. We show that since the clustering of rating announcements characterizes economically significant developments, the common practice of using "uncontaminated" samples underestimates market response. As in previous studies, we find that the market response to bad news is stronger than to good news. Nevertheless, bad news and negative rating announcements tend to cluster. Therefore, the residual contribution of negative rating announcements is small and in some cases insignificant. Positive rating announcements are less frequent and less clustered, though their residual contribution is still significant. (C) 2011 Elsevier By. All rights reserved.</description><author>Galil, Koresh; Soffer, Gil</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International variations in expected equity premia: Role of financial architecture and governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Raj; Goodell, John W.
Estimates of ex-ante equity premia are important in planning investments in pension funds, life insurance pools, and for other long-term financial obligations or goals. However, while global cross-border investment positions and flows have been rising, there is little research on non-US ex-ante equity premia or on their determinants in a global setting. This paper uses data on a recent 8-year period from 33 countries and models simultaneously our estimate of the ex-ante equity premium as a dependent variable and our measure of financial architecture as an instrumental variable. We document that ex-ante equity premia are larger in countries that have a more bank-oriented financial architecture, are wealthier, and have better governance. These results are robust to alternative model specifications and estimation techniques. Given the importance of equity premia and financial architecture, these results should be of much interest to scholars, managers, regulators, and policy makers. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, Raj; Goodell, John W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed momentum trading versus uninformed "naive" investors strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Anurag; Hung, Chi-Hsiou
We construct a zero net-worth uninformed "naive investor" who uses a random portfolio allocation strategy. We then compare the returns of the momentum strategist to the return distribution of naive investors. For this purpose we reward momentum profits relative to the return percentiles of the naive investors with scores that are symmetric around the median. The score function thus constructed is invariant and robust to risk factor models. We find that the average scores of the momentum strategies are close to zero (the score of the median) and statistically insignificant over the sample period between 1926 and 2005, various sub-sample periods including the periods examined in Jegadeesh and Titman (1993, 2001). The findings are robust with respect to sampling or period-specific effects, tightened score intervals, and the imposition of maximum-weight restrictions on the naive strategies to mitigate market friction considerations. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Banerjee, Anurag; Hung, Chi-Hsiou</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of loan portfolio concentration on Brazilian banks' return and risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tabak, Benjamin M.; Fazio, Dimas M.; Cajueiro, Daniel O.
This paper tests whether diversification of the credit portfolio at the bank level leads to better performance and lower risk. We employ a new high frequency (monthly) panel data for the Brazilian banking system with information at the bank level for loans by economic sector. We find that loan portfolio concentration increases returns and also reduces default risk; the impact of concentration on bank's return is decreasing on bank's risk; there are significant size effects; foreign and state-owned banks seem to be less affected by the degree of diversification. An important additional finding is that there is an increasing concentration trend after the breakout of the recent international financial crisis, specially after the failure of Lehman Brothers. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tabak, Benjamin M.; Fazio, Dimas M.; Cajueiro, Daniel O.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A cyclical model of exchange rate volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, Richard D. F.; Stoja, Evarist; Yilmaz, Fatih
In this paper, we investigate the long run dynamics of the intraday range of the GBP/USD, JPY/USD and CHF/USD exchange rates. We use a non-parametric filter to extract the low frequency component of the intraday range, and model the cyclical deviation of the range from the long run trend as a stationary autoregressive process. We use the cyclical volatility model to generate out-of-sample forecasts of exchange rate volatility for horizons of up to 1 year under the assumption that the long run trend is fully persistent. As a benchmark, we compare the forecasts of the cyclical volatility model with those of the range-based EGARCH and FIEGARCH models of Brandt and Jones (2006). Not only does the cyclical volatility model provide a very substantial computational advantage over the EGARCH and FIEGARCH models, but it also offers an improvement in out-of-sample forecast performance. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harris, Richard D. F.; Stoja, Evarist; Yilmaz, Fatih</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing, consumption and monetary policy: How different are the US and the euro area?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Musso, Alberto; Neri, Stefano; Stracca, Livio
This paper provides a systematic empirical analysis of the role of the housing market in the macroeconomy in the US and the euro area. First, it establishes some stylised facts concerning key variables in the housing market on the two sides of the Atlantic, such as real house prices, residential investment and mortgage debt. It then presents evidence from Structural Vector Autoregressions (SVAR) by focusing on the effects of monetary policy, credit supply and housing demand shocks on the housing market and the broader economy. The analysis shows that similarities outweigh differences as far as the housing market is concerned. The empirical evidence suggests a stronger role for housing in the transmission of monetary policy shocks in the US. The evidence is less clear-cut for housing demand shocks. Finally, credit supply shocks seem to matter more in the euro area. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Musso, Alberto; Neri, Stefano; Stracca, Livio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange rate volatility across financial crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coudert, Virginie; Couharde, Cecile; Mignon, Valerie
This paper studies the impact of global financial turmoil on the exchange rate policies in emerging countries. Spillovers from advanced financial markets to currencies in emerging countries are likely to be exacerbated during crisis periods. To test this hypothesis, we assess the exchange rate policies by currencies' volatility and investigate their relationship to a global financial stress indicator, measured by the volatility on global markets. We introduce the possibility of nonlinearities by running smooth transition regressions over a sample of 21 emerging countries from January 1994 to September 2009. The results confirm that exchange rate volatility does increase more than proportionally with the global financial stress, for most countries in the sample. We also evidence regional contagion effects spreading from one emerging currency to other currencies in the neighboring area. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coudert, Virginie; Couharde, Cecile; Mignon, Valerie</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk capital allocation for RORAC optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buch, Arne; Dorfleitner, Gregor; Wimmer, Maximilian
This paper considers the financial optimization problem of a firm with several sub-businesses striving for its optimal RORAC. An insightful example shows that the implementation of classical gradient capital allocation can be suboptimal if division managers are allowed to venture into all business whose marginal RORAC exceeds the firm's RORAC. The marginal RORAC requirements are refined by adding a risk correction term that takes into account the interdependencies of the risks of different lines of business. It is shown that under certain stationarity conditions this approach can guarantee that the optimal RORAC will eventually be achieved. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buch, Arne; Dorfleitner, Gregor; Wimmer, Maximilian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alternative models for hedging yield curve risk: An empirical comparison</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carcano, Nicola; Dall'O, Hakim
We test alternative models of yield curve risk by hedging US Treasury bond portfolios through note/bond futures. We show that traditional implementations of models based on principal component analysis, duration vectors and key rate duration lead to high exposure to model errors and to sizable transaction costs, thus lowering the hedging quality. Also, this quality randomly varies from one model and hedging problem to the other. We show that accounting for the variance of modeling errors substantially reduces both hedging errors and transaction costs for all considered models. Additionally, it leads to much more stable weights in the hedging portfolios and - as a result - to more homogeneous hedging quality. On this basis, error-adjusted principal component analysis is found to systematically and significantly outperform alternative models. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carcano, Nicola; Dall'O, Hakim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal asset allocation under linear loss aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fortin, Ines; Hlouskova, Jaroslava
We study the asset allocation of a linear loss-averse (LA) investor and compare it to the more traditional mean-variance (MV) and conditional value-at-risk (CVaR) investors. First we derive conditions under which the LA problem is equivalent to the MV and CVaR problems and solve analytically the two-asset problem of the LA investor for a risk-free and a risky asset. Then we run simulation experiments to study properties of the optimal LA and MV portfolios under more realistic assumptions. We find that under asymmetric dependence LA portfolios outperform MV portfolios, provided investors are sufficiently loss-averse and dependence is large. Finally, using 13 EU and US assets, we implement the trading strategy of a linear LA investor who reallocates his/her portfolio on a monthly basis. We find that LA portfolios clearly outperform MV and CVaR portfolios and that incorporating a dynamic update of the LA parameters significantly improves the performance of LA portfolios. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fortin, Ines; Hlouskova, Jaroslava</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does FOMC news increase global FX trading?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischer, Andreas M.; Ranaldo, Angelo
Does global currency volume increase on Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) days? To test hypotheses of abnormal currency volume on FOMC days, a new data set from the Continuous Linked Settlement (CLS) Bank is used. The CLS measure captures more than half of the global trading volume in foreign exchange (FX) markets. The evidence shows that FX trading volume increases about 5% in the spot and the spot-next market following FOMC deliberations. The novelty of this result is that the aggregated CLS data controls for responses in various derivatives markets: a feature that existing studies based on intradaily data for specific trading platforms do not consider. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fischer, Andreas M.; Ranaldo, Angelo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time series analysis for financial market meltdowns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Young Shin; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Bianchi, Michele Leonardo; Mitov, Ivan; Fabozzi, Frank J.
There appears to be a consensus that the recent instability in global financial markets may be attributable in part to the failure of financial modeling. More specifically, it is alleged that current risk models have failed to properly assess the risks associated with large adverse stock price behavior. In this paper, we first discuss the limitations of classical time series models for forecasting financial market meltdowns. Then we set forth a framework capable of forecasting both extreme events and highly volatile markets. Based on the empirical evidence presented in this paper, our framework offers an improvement over prevailing models for evaluating stock market risk exposure during distressed market periods. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Young Shin; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Bianchi, Michele Leonardo; Mitov, Ivan; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset market linkages: Evidence from financial, commodity and real estate assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Kam Fong; Treepongkaruna, Sirimon; Brooks, Robert; Gray, Stephen
We use a general Markov switching model to examine the relationships between returns over three different asset classes: financial assets (US stocks and Treasury bonds), commodities (oil and gold) and real estate assets (US Case-Shiller index). We confirm the existence of two distinct regimes: a "tranquil" regime with periods of economic expansion and a "crisis" regime with periods of economic decline. The tranquil regime is characterized by lower volatility and significantly positive stock returns. During these periods, there is also evidence of a flight from quality - from gold to stocks. By contrast, the crisis regime is characterized by higher volatility and sharply negative stock returns, along with evidence of contagion between stocks, oil and real estate. Furthermore, during these periods, there is strong evidence of a flight to quality - from stocks to Treasury bonds. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Kam Fong; Treepongkaruna, Sirimon; Brooks, Robert; Gray, Stephen</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate derivatives use and the cost of equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gay, Gerald D.; Lin, Chen-Miao; Smith, Stephen D.
We investigate the relation between derivatives use and corporations' cost of equity capital. Using a large sample of non-financial firms, we compute and analyze (i) the relative cost of equity of firms that use derivatives and those that do not; and (ii) the change in cost of equity experienced by firms initiating derivatives programs. We find that the cost of equity of derivatives users is lower than non-users by 24-78 basis points. Our results are robust to specifications that account for potential endogeneity related to a firm's derivatives use and capital structure decisions. We further find that the reduction in the cost of equity is attributable to both lower market beta and SMB beta, suggesting that firms use derivatives to reduce their financial distress risk and that this distress risk has a systematic component that is priced in the market. Finally, the observed reductions in the cost of equity tend to be largest for smaller firms and for firms utilizing currency and interest rate derivatives. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gay, Gerald D.; Lin, Chen-Miao; Smith, Stephen D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Patterns in payout policy and payout channel choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Renneboog, Luc; Trojanowski, Grzegorz
We study the decision to distribute funds as well as the choice of the payout channel (i.e. dividends, repurchases, or both). Our analysis of the payout policy of UK firms demonstrates that the importance of share repurchases is increasing, but dividends still constitute a vast proportion of the total payout. We document that there is a relation between the presence of blockholders and the choice of the payout channel. We find that payout decisions are influenced by directors' liquidity needs but are not consistent with the agency theory of payout. We also reject the tax-clientele explanation for payout choices. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Renneboog, Luc; Trojanowski, Grzegorz</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership, control, and pyramids in Spanish commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Azofra, Valentin; Santamaria, Marcos
Using the law and finance approach we analyze how the ultimate ownership and control structure influences the performance of Spanish commercial banks during the period 1996-2004. Our evidence shows that 96% of Spanish commercial banks have an ultimate controlling owner. Also, we observe that whenever there is a gap between the ultimate controlling owner's cash flow and control rights, than the bigger the gap, the poorer the bank's performance. We find that whenever there is no difference between the ultimate controlling owner's cash flow and control rights, there is a non-monotonic relation between ownership concentration and the bank's performance. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Azofra, Valentin; Santamaria, Marcos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When and how US dollar shortages evolved into the full crisis? Evidence from the cross-currency swap market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baba, Naohiko; Sakurai, Yuji
This paper investigates when and how the US dollar shortages evolved into the full crisis in the cross-currency swap market between major European currencies and the US dollar during the turmoil of 20072009, using the dynamic factor model with regime-switching beta coefficients of each swap price with respect to the latent common factor. The 1-year market entered the high-beta crisis regime soon after the onset of the subprime problem in August 2007. The 10-year market entered that regime following the collapse of Bear Sterns in mid-March 2008. Financial credit spreads have significant predictive power for switches between high and low-beta regimes. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baba, Naohiko; Sakurai, Yuji</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk adjustment and momentum sources</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Jun; Wu, Yangru
We show that the conventional procedure of risk adjustment by running full-sample time-series Fama-French three-factor regressions is not appropriate for momentum portfolios because the procedure fails to allow for the systematic dynamics of momentum portfolio factor loadings. We propose a simple procedure to adjust risks associated with the Fama-French three factors for momentum portfolios. Using our proposed method, the Fama-French three factors can explain approximately 40% of momentum profits generated by individual stocks and nearly all of momentum returns from style portfolios. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Jun; Wu, Yangru</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>