<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JEL0</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Sports Economics Uncut</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradbury, John Charles
nan</description><author>Bradbury, John Charles</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Game Theory and Climate Change</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wagner, Gernot
nan</description><author>Wagner, Gernot</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Internet Trap: How the Digital Economy Builds Monopolies and Undermines Democracy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faulhaber, Gerald R.
nan</description><author>Faulhaber, Gerald R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>World Scientific Reference on Handbook of the Economics of Wine</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ugaglia, A. Alonso
nan</description><author>Ugaglia, A. Alonso</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Gift of Global Talent: How Migration Shapes Business, Economy &amp; Society</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fairlie, Robert
nan</description><author>Fairlie, Robert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Waiting on Retirement: Aging and Economic Insecurity in Low-Wage Work</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Button, Patrick
nan</description><author>Button, Patrick</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring and Modeling Health Care Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kleiner, Samuel A.
nan</description><author>Kleiner, Samuel A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The National Debt: A Short History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lennard, Jason
nan</description><author>Lennard, Jason</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Review of Books on Student Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avery, Christopher
This essay reviews three recent books on the causes and consequences of student debt. In addition to increases in college tuition and fees, supply and resource constraints both contribute to the growing phenomenon of default: degree completion rates are relatively low, especially at two-year colleges. Default rates actually decrease with the amount of debt incurred, as students who incur more debt are more likely to complete degrees that bolster their earning power. These books suggest some promising policy options, but there are no quick fixes given that the net cost of attending both private and public colleges continues to rise.</description><author>Avery, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unhappiness and Pain in Modern America: A Review Essay, and Further Evidence, on Carol Graham's Happiness for All?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blanchflower, David G.; Oswald, Andrew J.
In Happiness for All? Unequal Hopes and Lives in the Pursuit of the American Dream, Carol Graham raises disquieting ideas about today's United States. The challenge she puts forward is an important one. Here we review the intellectual case and offer additional evidence. We conclude broadly on the author's side. Strikingly, Americans appear to be in greater pain than citizens of other countries, and most subgroups of citizens have downwardly trended happiness levels. There is, however, one bright side to an otherwise dark story. The happiness of black Americans has risen strongly since the 1970s. It is now almost equal to that of white Americans.</description><author>Blanchflower, David G.; Oswald, Andrew J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weyl, E. Glen
I argue that there exists a coherent and relevant tradition in economic thought that I label "price theory." I define it as neoclassical microeconomic analysis that reduces rich and often incompletely specified models into "prices" (approximately) sufficient to characterize solutions to simple allocative problems. I illustrate this definition by highlighting distinctively price theoretic approaches to prominent research practices (diagrams and problems sets) and substantive research topics (e.g. selection markets and media slant). I trace the origins of price theory from the early nineteenth century through its segregation into the Chicago School in the last quarter of the twentieth. I argue that price theory plays a valuable complementary role to two traditions, "reductionism" and "empiricism," with which I contrast it and show how this contribution of price theory has fueled a resurgence in this style of research in fields ranging from market design to international trade. Approximations critical to price theory are less formally developed than tools used in other methodological traditions, suggesting a research agenda to clarify the accuracy and range of validity of these methods.</description><author>Weyl, E. Glen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What We Have Learned about Terrorism since 9/11</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaibulloev, Khusrav; Sandler, Todd
This overview examines critically the post-9/11 empirical literature on terrorism. Major contributions by both economists and political scientists are included. We focus on five main themes: the changing nature of terrorism, the organization of terrorist groups, the effectiveness of counterterrorism policies, modern drivers or causes of terrorism, and the economic consequences of terrorism. In so doing, we investigate a host of questions that include: How do terrorist groups attract and retain members? What determines the survival of terrorist groups? Is poverty a root cause of terrorism? What counterterrorism measures work best? In the latter regard, we find that many counterterrorism policies have unintended negative consequences owing to attack transference and terrorist backlash. This suggests the need f or novel policies such as service provision to counter some terrorist groups' efforts to provide such services. Despite terrorists' concerted efforts to damage targeted countries' economies, the empirical literature shows that terrorism has had little or no effect on economic growth or GDP except in small terrorism-plagued countries. At the sectoral level, terrorism can adversely affect tourism and foreign direct investment, but these effects are rather transient and create transference of activities to other sectors, thus cushioning the consequences.</description><author>Gaibulloev, Khusrav; Sandler, Todd</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Design: A Unified Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergemann, Dirk; Morris, Stephen
Given a game with uncertain payoffs, information design analyzes the extent to which the provision of information alone can influence the behavior of the players. Information design has a literal interpretation, under which there is a real information designer who can commit to the choice of the best information structure (from her perspective) for a set of participants in a game. We emphasize a metaphorical interpretation, under which the information design problem is used by the analyst to characterize play in the game under many different information structures. We provide an introduction to the basic issues and insights of a rapidly growing literature in information design. We show how the literal and metaphorical interpretations of information design unify a large body of existing work, including that on communication in games (Myerson 1991), Bayesian persuasion (Kamenica and Gentzkow 2011), and some of our own recent work on robust predictions in games of incomplete information.</description><author>Bergemann, Dirk; Morris, Stephen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Mechanism Design: An Introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergemann, Dirk; Valimaki, Juuso
We provide an introduction to the recent developments of dynamic mechanism design, with a primary focus on the quasilinear case. First, we describe socially optimal (or efficient) dynamic mechanisms. These mechanisms extend the well-known Vickrey-Clark-Groves and D'Aspremont-Gerard-Varet mechanisms to a dynamic environment. Second, we discuss revenue optimal mechanisms. We cover models of sequential screening and revenue-maximizing auctions with dynamically changing bidder types. We also discuss models of information management where the mechanism designer can control (at least partially) the stochastic process governing the agents' types. Third, we consider models with changing populations of agents over time. After discussing related models with risk-averse agents and limited liability, we conclude with a number of open questions and challenges that remain for the theory of dynamic mechanism design.</description><author>Bergemann, Dirk; Valimaki, Juuso</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Progress: A Review Essay on The Pricing of Progress: Economic Indicators and the Capitalization of American Life by Eli Cook</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coyle, Diane
There is growing interest in the history of economic statistics, and Eli Cook has provided in The Pricing of Progress: Economic Indicators and the Capitalization of American Life a fascinating account of the era of economic measurement prior to the creation of the modern System of National Accounts. The story illustrates the dual character of statistics, which is the product of political contestation and social structures, as well as the data by which we can interpret the economy. Appreciating this duality through the history of economic measurement helps explain why political polarization today often seems to play out as competing interpretations of the "facts." In this context, the idea that GDP growth is a good measure of economic progress is increasingly being challenged, as both the "beyond GDP" agenda and digital disruption point to a growing wedge between what GDP is measuring and economic welfare. Economists should be engaging with the history of the statistics we use even,' day in order to be able to shape their future.</description><author>Coyle, Diane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review on Basic Income: A Radical Proposal for a Free Society and a Sane Economy by Philippe Van Parijs and Yannick Vanderborght</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calsamiglia, Caterina; Flamand, Sabine
In order to clarify the potential impact of a basic income, we argue that any discussion on whether to adopt a basic income policy should be framed within the greater context of the transfer system as a whole. In particular, such discussion should consider separately the issues of (i) the desired income distribution to be achieved and (ii) the most efficient way of achieving it through a transfer system. Further, we stress the importance of the non-take-up phenomenon in current transfer systems and discuss the potential necessity of a basic income policy in the age of automation.</description><author>Calsamiglia, Caterina; Flamand, Sabine</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Can Be Learned from Spatial Economics?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Proost, Stef; Thisse, Jacques-Francois
Spatial economics aims to explain why there are peaks and troughs in the spatial distribution of wealth and people, from the international and regional to the urban and local. The main task is to identify the microeconomic underpinnings of centripetal forces, which lead to the concentration of economic activities, and centrifugal forces, which bring about the dispersion of economic activities at the regional and urban levels. Transportation matters at both scales, but in a different way. The emphasis is on the interregional flows of goods and passenger trips at the regional level and on individual commuting at the urban level.</description><author>Proost, Stef; Thisse, Jacques-Francois</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Text as Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gentzkow, Matthew; Kelly, Bryan; Taddy, Matt
An ever-increasing share of human interaction, communication, and culture is recorded as digital text. We provide an introduction to the use of text as an input to economic research. We discuss the features that make text different from other forms of data, offer a practical overview of relevant statistical methods, and survey a variety of applications.</description><author>Gentzkow, Matthew; Kelly, Bryan; Taddy, Matt</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Market for Lemons</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyal, Sanjeev
Mark Granovetter has written a deep and wide-ranging book on economy and society entitled Society and Economy: Frameworks and Principles. Economists, in particular, will find his discussion on the role of social networks in understanding the problem of aggregation-from micro foundations to large-scale institutional phenomena-especially relevant. And they will find much to ponder over the ways in which overlapping structures-of networks and institutions-shape human behavior and determine aggregate economic outcomes. The high-level and parsimonious style of this book is distinctive and sets it apart from much of contemporary social science. This style and the apparent unwillingness to engage closely with research developments over the past two decades may, however, mean that the book will have limited influence on ongoing and future research.</description><author>Goyal, Sanjeev</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Utility: From the Marginal Revolution to Behavioral Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Read, Daniel
nan</description><author>Read, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Handbook of Computational Economics, vol 4. Heterogeneous Agent Modeling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Georges, Christophre
nan</description><author>Georges, Christophre</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coping with Financial Crises: Some Lessons from Economic History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruner, Robert F.
nan</description><author>Bruner, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankers and Bolsheviks: International Finance and the Russian Revolution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dempster, Gregory
nan</description><author>Dempster, Gregory</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Elites and European Banking: Historical Perspectives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oosterlinck, Kim
nan</description><author>Oosterlinck, Kim</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Research Universities and the Public Good: Discovery for an Uncertain Future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Valero, Anna
nan</description><author>Valero, Anna</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, Incentives, and Education Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Epple, Dennis
nan</description><author>Epple, Dennis</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Frontiers of the Capability Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sugden, Robert
nan</description><author>Sugden, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Digital Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldfarb, Avi; Tucker, Catherine
Digital technology is the representation of information in bits. This technology has reduced the cost of storage, computation, and transmission of data. Research on digital economics examines whether and how digital technology changes economic activity. In this review, we emphasize the reduction in five distinct economic costs associated with digital economic activity: search costs, replication costs, transportation costs, tracking costs, and verification costs.</description><author>Goldfarb, Avi; Tucker, Catherine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Review Essay on Why Muslim Integration Fails in Christian-Heritage Societies by Claire Adida, David Laitin and Marie-Anne Valfort</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Verdier, Thierry
This paper reviews the book Why Muslim Integration Fails in Christian-Heritage Societies by Claire Adida, David Laitin and Marie-Anne Valfort (hereafter, ALV), providing an analytical perspective on the issues related to minority discrimination and integration in a host society. Building upon the sociological and recent economic approaches to cultural integration, we highlight the different mechanisms behind the existence of a discriminatory equilibrium between a majority group and a minority group in a given social context. The paper then discusses the specific case of the Muslim minority groups in the French context and outlines the strengths and limitations of the research approach expanded by ALV. We finally consider the policy proposals provided by ALV, assessing their viability, as well as the dynamic political economy constraints they might face in a Christian-heritage society.</description><author>Verdier, Thierry</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gorbachev versus Deng: A Review of Chris Miller's The Struggle to Save the Soviet Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guriev, Sergei
Chris Miller's book is a historian's account of Mikhail Gorbachev's efforts to save the Soviet economy. Miller focuses on the question of why Gorbachev did not follow Deng Xiaoping and did not manage to reform the economy. Miller argues that it was not for the lack of understanding (Gorbachev did invest in learning China's approach to reform and did understand it well), nor for the lack of trying. In fact, Gorbachev did try to implement Deng's agricultural and industrial enterprise reforms. However, Gorbachev's reforms were blocked by powerful vested interests. An inability to tackle the agricultural and industrial lobbies eventually resulted in the bankruptcy and collapse of the Soviet Union. While I generally agree with the political economy argument, I discuss a number of alternative explanations. I also discuss sources of Gorbachev's weak state capacity and offer an evaluation of Gorbachev's and post-Gorbachev reform efforts and mistakes based on the political economy research carried out in the last twenty-five years.</description><author>Guriev, Sergei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing Lives: Guideposts for a Safer Society</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schulze, William
nan</description><author>Schulze, William</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Last Resort: The Financial Crisis and the Future of Bailouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit
nan</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Worst-Case Economics: Extreme Events in Climate and Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rezai, Armon
nan</description><author>Rezai, Armon</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blockchain and the Law: The Rule of Code</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gandal, Neil
nan</description><author>Gandal, Neil</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Structural Foundations of Monetary Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bundick, Brent
nan</description><author>Bundick, Brent</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agent-Based Models in Economics: A Toolkit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dawid, Herbert
nan</description><author>Dawid, Herbert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Environmentalism with Chinese Characteristics-A Review of Matthew E. Kahn and Siqi Zheng's Blue Skies over Beijing: Economic Growth and the Environment in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coxhead, Ian
China's dramatic rise from poverty to global economic prominence has been accompanied by an equally dramatic increase in environmental damages. The book under review presents an exploration of economic and political economy factors that might bring about a reversal in emissions that contribute to high pollution loadings in large urban areas. The authors highlight preference shifts associated with rapid growth of per capita income and express optimism about government responses to demands for a cleaner environment. There are some indications that China's largest cities are indeed getting cleaner air. However, total emissions (largely from heavy industry and coal-fired energy generators) continue to rise, and the mechanisms by which preference shifts turn into policy changes remain opaque. It may be that China's most polluting industries are sorting into localities where either preferences for clean air are less pronounced or local governments are less responsive. This may match a positively selected counterflow of individuals seeking better environmental amenities and more responsive government.</description><author>Coxhead, Ian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Devil Is in the Details: Implications of Samuel Bowles's The Moral Economy for Economics and Policy Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kranton, Rachel
All economists should buy and read The Moral Economy by Samuel Bowles. The book challenges basic premises of economic theory and questions policies based on monetary incentives. Incentives not only crowd out intrinsic motivations, they erode the ethical and moral codes necessary for the workings of markets. Bowles boldly suggests that successfull policies must combine incentives and moral messages, exploiting complementarities between the two. This essay argues that to achieve this objective, economists must study the local institutions and social context and engage untraditional data to uncover the interplay of incentives and identity.</description><author>Kranton, Rachel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A History of American State and Local Economic Development: As Two Ships Pass in the Night</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, Benjamin
nan</description><author>Harris, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regression Discontinuity Designs: Theory and Applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lovenheim, Michael
nan</description><author>Lovenheim, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The First Serious Optimist: A. C. Pigou and the Birth of Welfare Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McDonald, John F.
nan</description><author>McDonald, John F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The End of Alchemy by Mervyn King: A Review Essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farmer, Roger E. A.
I review The End of Alchemy by Mervyn King, published by W. W. Norton and Company in 2016. I discuss King's proposed regulatory reform, the "pawnbroker for all seasons" (PFAS), and I compare it to an alternative solution developed in my own work. I argue that unregulated trade in the financial markets will not, in general, lead to Pareto-optimal allocations. As a consequence, solutions like the PFAS that correct problems with existing institutions are likely to be circumvented by the development of new ones.</description><author>Farmer, Roger E. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mind the Gap: A Review of The Health Gap: The Challenge of an Unequal World by Sir Michael Marmot</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lleras-Muney, Adriana
The Health Gap documents the large and persistent health gaps that exist across and within relatively rich countries today. Marmot argues that in developed countries, poor health does not cause low incomes; rather, low socioeconomic status leads to poor health, but not because of proximate factors like differential health care access, which can explain only a small portion of these gaps. Therefore, to eliminate health gaps, policy should focus on the deep causes of disease: poverty, education, and occupational mobility, among others. While Marmot's ethical arguments are quite compelling, his recommendations are too strong given the current evidence. Policies need to be based on a clearer understanding of why things work, when, and for whom.</description><author>Lleras-Muney, Adriana</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Income Taxation Theory and Principles of Fairness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleurbaey, Marc; Maniquet, Francois
The achievements and limitations of the classical theory of optimal labor-income taxation based on social welfare functions are now well known. Even though utilitarianism still dominates public economics, recent interest has arisen for broadening the normative approach and making room for fairness principles such as desert or responsibility. Fairness principles sometimes provide immediate recommendations about the relative weights to assign to various income ranges, but in general require a careful choice of utility representations embodying the relevant interpersonal comparisons. The main message of this paper is that the traditional tool of welfare economics, the social welfare function framework, is flexible enough to incorporate many approaches, from egalitarianism to libertarianism.</description><author>Fleurbaey, Marc; Maniquet, Francois</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Offshoring and Labor Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hummels, David; Munch, Jakob R.; Xiang, Chong
In this paper, we survey the recent empirical literature on the effects of offshoring on wage, employment, and displacement. We start with an overview of the measurement of offshoring, organizing our discussion around the three key elements of offshoring: that it involves intermediate inputs for production (versus final goods for consumption); that it involves imported inputs (versus domestically produced ones); and that the inputs involved could have been produced internally within the same firm. We then briefly discuss the theories of offshoring and survey the literature that examines the wage effects of offshoring: the wave of studies using industry-level data; the wave using firm-level data; the wave using worker-level data; and the wave using matched worker-firm data. For each wave, we highlight the identification strategies used, critically assess its strengths and weaknesses, discuss its connections with theory, and draw out potential policy implications of its findings. Finally, we survey the literature that examines how offshoring affects employment and displacement. We highlight the recent development of a novel cohort-based approach that is specifically designed to address selection with displacement, and capable of identifying the overall effects of offshoring, including wage, displacement, and all other types of transitions.</description><author>Hummels, David; Munch, Jakob R.; Xiang, Chong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Central Banks and Gold: How Tokyo, London, and New York Shaped the Modern World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wilkins, Mira
nan</description><author>Wilkins, Mira</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inequality and Globalization: A Review Essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ravallion, Martin
As normally measured, "global inequality" is the relative inequality of incomes found among all people in the world no matter where they live. Francois Bourguignon and Branko Milanovic have written insightful and timely books on global inequality, emphasizing the role of globalization. The books are complementary: Milanovic provides an ambitious broad-brush picture, with some intriguing hypotheses on the processes at work; Bourguignon provides a deep and suitably qualified economic analysis. This paper questions the thesis of both books-that globalization has been a major driving force of inequality between or within countries. The paper also questions the robustness of the evidence for declining global inequality, and notes some conceptual limitations of standard measures in capturing the concerns of many observers in the ongoing debates about globalization and the policy responses.</description><author>Ravallion, Martin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying and Estimating Neighborhood Effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, Bryan S.
Residential segregation by race and income are enduring features of urban America. Understanding the effects of residential segregation on educational attainment, labor market outcomes, criminal activity, and other outcomes has been a leading project of the social sciences for over half a century. This paper describes techniques for measuring the effects of neighborhood of residence on long-run life outcomes.</description><author>Graham, Bryan S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Islam Instrumentalized: Religion and Politics in Historical Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rubin, Jared
nan</description><author>Rubin, Jared</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Innovation in the Asia Pacific: From Manufacturing to the Knowledge Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenhalgh, Christine
nan</description><author>Greenhalgh, Christine</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Poverty Reduction in the Course of African Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Devarajan, Shantayanan
nan</description><author>Devarajan, Shantayanan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Theory of Externalities and Public Goods: Essays in Memory of Richard C. Cornes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allouch, Nizar
nan</description><author>Allouch, Nizar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency Conflict and Trade Policy: A New Strategy for the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dominguez, Kathryn M. E.
nan</description><author>Dominguez, Kathryn M. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macro-Econophysics: New Studies on Economic Networks and Synchronization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jovanovic, Franck
nan</description><author>Jovanovic, Franck</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Case for Imposing Cashlessness: A Review Article</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wallace, Neil
In The Curse of Cash, Rogoff (2016) makes two arguments. (i) Large denominations of currency are primarily used for illegal activity. Therefore, eliminating them would have benefits that far outweigh the costs in terms of lost seigniorage. (ii) The zero lower bound (ZLB) on the interest rate implied by the possibility of holding large amounts of currency is a costly constraint on central-bank policy. The best way to eliminate the ZLB is to eliminate all but small denominations of currency, ten dollars and lower, and to have those be in the form of coins. The style of the book, no models and no symbols, works fairly well for (i), but not so well for (ii). For (ii), the author is unclear about a crucial matter: what fiscal policy accompanies alternative interest-rate settings chosen by the central bank?</description><author>Wallace, Neil</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and Economic Development in the Very Long Run: A Review Essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shin, Yongseok
I review William N. Goetzmann's Money Changes Everything: How Finance Made Civilization Possible. This magnificent book offers insightful coverage of more than 5,000 years of human history under the theme of "how finance made civilization possible." I reinterpret its main hypotheses in the context of recent economic research on finance and development, and also compare them with other economic historians' views. I suggest that further examinations of the historical facts in the book could guide us in rethinking financial regulation.</description><author>Shin, Yongseok</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Riddles and Models: A Review Essay on Michel De Vroey's A History of Macroeconomics from Keynes to Lucas and Beyond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Azariadis, Costas
This essay reviews Michel De Vroey's important new book on the history of macroeconomics, which extends to business cycles an earlier book by the same author on the history of involuntary unemployment. The review also offers a broader nontechnical survey of the issues and models that make up modern macroeconomics, including a reckoning of what we have learned since John Maynard Keynes and of the discoveries that still lie ahead.</description><author>Azariadis, Costas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Sound of Silence: A Review Essay of Nancy MacLean's Democracy in Chains: The Deep History of the Radical Right's Stealth Plan for America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleury, Jean-Baptiste; Marciano, Alain
This essay reviews Nancy MacLean's Democracy in Chains: The Deep History of the Radical Right's Stealth Plan for America, which triggered a huge controversy that virally spread on the Internet and in various journals. We will evaluate MacLean's almost biographical account of James Buchanan, which portrays the 1986 Nobel Prize laureate as the mastermind behind today's attacks, by the foot soldiers of the radical right, on American democracy. This essay develops three main points. One, MacLean's general narrative puts too much emphasis on Buchanan and largely neglects the many other important characters who contributed to the intellectual criticism of government intervention. Two, MacLean's account is marred by many misunderstandings about public choice theory, for instance about the role that simple majority rule plays in constitutional economics. Third, in the midst of abundant archival material, her historical narrative is, at best, sketchy, and is replete with significantly flawed arguments, misplaced citations, and dubious conjectures. Overall, MacLean tends to-overinterpret certain aspects in Buchanan's life and thought, while she overlooks others that are equally important in understanding his work and influence. In particular, we stress that Buchanan was, first and foremost, a scholar, not a political activist, who gave significant attention to ethical considerations in his analysis of markets.</description><author>Fleury, Jean-Baptiste; Marciano, Alain</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Formation of Expectations, Inflation, and the Phillips Curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coibion, Olivier; Gorodnichenko, Yuriy; Kamdar, Rupal
This paper argues for a careful (re) consideration of the expectations formation process and a more systematic inclusion of real-time expectations through survey data in macroeconomic analyses. While the rational expectations revolution has allowed for great leaps in macroeconomic modeling, the surveyed empirical microevidence appears increasingly at odds with the full-information rational expectation assumption. We explore models of expectation formation that can potentially explain why and how survey data deviate from full-information rational expectations. Using the New Keynesian Phillips curve as an extensive case study, we demonstrate how incorporating survey data on inflation expectations can address a number of otherwise puzzling shortcomings that arise under the assumption of full-information rational expectations.</description><author>Coibion, Olivier; Gorodnichenko, Yuriy; Kamdar, Rupal</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Childhood Circumstances and Adult Outcomes: Act II</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almond, Douglas; Currie, Janet; Duque, Valentina
That prenatal events can have life-long consequences is now well established. Nevertheless, research on the fetal origins hypothesis is flourishing and has expanded to include the early childhood (postnatal) environment. Why does this literature have a "second act?" We summarize the major themes and contributions driving the empirical literature since our 2011 reviews, and try to interpret the literature in light of an overarching conceptual framework about how human capital is produced early in life. One major finding is that relatively mild shocks in early life can have substantial negative impacts, but that the effects are often heterogeneous reflecting differences in child endowments, budget constraints, and production technologies. Moreover, shocks, investments, and interventions can interact in complex ways that are only beginning to be understood. Many advances in our knowledge are due to increasing accessibility of comprehensive administrative data that allow events in early life to be linked to long-term outcomes. Yet, we still know relatively little about the interval between, and thus about whether it would be feasible to identify and intervene with affected individuals at some point between early life and adulthood. We do know enough, however, to be able to identify some interventions that hold promise for improving child outcomes in early life and throughout the life course.</description><author>Almond, Douglas; Currie, Janet; Duque, Valentina</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Islam and Economic Performance: Historical and Contemporary Links</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuran, Timur
This essay critically evaluates the analytic literature concerned with causal connections between Islam and economic performance. It focuses on works since 1997, when this literature was last surveyed comprehensively. Among the findings are the following: Ramadan fasting by pregnant women harms prenatal development; Islamic charities mainly benefit the middle class; Islam affects educational outcomes less through Islamic schooling than through structural factors that handicap learning as a whole; Islamic finance has a negligible effect on Muslim financial behavior; and low generalized trust depresses Muslim trade. The last feature reflects the Muslim world's delay in transitioning from personal to impersonal exchange. The delay resulted from the persistent simplicity of the private enterprises formed under Islamic law. Weak property rights reinforced the private sector's stagnation by driving capital from commerce to rigid waqfs. Waqfs limited economic development through their inflexibility and democratization by keeping civil society embryonic. Parts of the Muslim world conquered by Arab armies are especially undemocratic, which suggests that early Islamic institutions were particularly critical to the persistence of authoritarian patterns of governance. States have contributed to the persistence of authoritarianism by treating Islam as an instrument of governance. As the world started to industrialize, -non-Muslim subjects of Muslim-governed states pulled ahead of their Muslim neighbors, partly by exercising the choice of law they enjoyed under Islamic law in favor of a Western legal system.</description><author>Kuran, Timur</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skewed Wealth Distributions: Theory and Empirics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benhabib, Jess; Bisin, Alberto
Invariably, across a cross-section of countries and time periods, wealth distributions are skewed to the right displaying thick upper tails, that is, large and slowly declining top wealth shares. In this survey, we categorize the theoretical studies on the distribution of wealth in terms of the underlying economic mechanisms generating skewness and thick tails. Further, we show how these mechanisms can be micro-founded by the consumption-savings decisions of rational agents in specific economic and demographic environments. Finally we map the large empirical work on the wealth distribution to its theoretical underpinnings.</description><author>Benhabib, Jess; Bisin, Alberto</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Macrogenoeconomics of Comparative Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ashraf, Quamrul H.; Galor, Oded
The importance of evolutionary forces for comparative economic performance across societies has been the focus of a vibrant literature, highlighting the roles played by the Neolithic Revolution as well as the prehistoric "out of Africa" migration of anatomically modern humans in generating worldwide variations in the composition of human traits. This essay provides an overview of the literature on the macrogenoeconomics of comparative development, underscoring the significance of evolutionary processes and human population diversity in generating differential paths of economic development across societies. Furthermore, it examines the contribution of Nicholas Wade's recent hypothesis, regarding the evolutionary origins of comparative development, to this important line of research.</description><author>Ashraf, Quamrul H.; Galor, Oded</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transparency, Reproducibility, and the Credibility of Economics Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christensen, Garret; Miguel, Edward
There is growing interest in enhancing research transparency and reproducibility in economics and other scientific fields. We survey existing work on these topics within economics and discuss the evidence suggesting that publication bias, inability to replicate, and specification searching remain widespread in the discipline. We next discuss recent progress in this area, including through improved research design, study registration and pre-analysis plans, disclosure standards, and open sharing of data and materials, drawing on experiences in both economics and other social sciences. We discuss areas where consensus is emerging on new practices, as well as approaches that remain controversial, and speculate about the most effective ways to make economics research more credible in the future.</description><author>Christensen, Garret; Miguel, Edward</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Production and Welfare: Progress in Economic Measurement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jorgenson, Dale W.
While the GDP was intended by its originators as a measure of production, the absence of a measure of welfare in the national accounts has led to widespread misuse of the GDP to proxy welfare. Measures of welfare are needed to appraise the outcomes of changes in economic policies and evaluate the results. Concepts that describe the income distribution, such as poverty and inequality, fall within the scope of welfare rather than production. This paper reviews recent advances in the measurement of production and welfare within the national accounts, primarily in the United States and international organizations. Expanding the framework beyond the national accounts has led to important innovations in the measurement of both production and welfare.</description><author>Jorgenson, Dale W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Experimental Research on Labor Market Discrimination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neumark, David
Understanding whether labor market discrimination explains inferior labor market outcomes for many groups has drawn the attention of labor economists for decades-at least since the publication of Gary Becker's The Economics of Discrimination in 1957. The decades of research on discrimination in labor markets began with a regression-based "decomposition" approach, asking whether raw wage or earnings differences between groups-which might constitute prima facie evidence of discrimination-were in fact attributable to other productivity-related factors. Subsequent research-responding in large part to limitations of the regression-based approach-moved on to other approaches, such as using firm-level data to estimate both marginal productivity and wage differentials. In recent years, however, there has been substantial growth in experimental research on labor market discrimination-although the earliest experiments were done decades ago. Some experimental research on labor market discrimination takes place in the lab. But far more of it is done in the field, which makes this particular area of experimental research unique relative to the explosion of experimental economic research more generally. This paper surveys the full range of experimental literature on labor market discrimination, places it in the context of the broader research literature on labor market discrimination, discusses the experimental literature from many different perspectives (empirical, theoretical, and policy), and reviews both what this literature has taught us thus far, and what remains to be done.</description><author>Neumark, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Road Ahead for America's Colleges and Universities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Toutkoushian, Robert K.
nan</description><author>Toutkoushian, Robert K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking's Final Exam: Stress Testing and Bank-Capital Reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Resti, Andrea
nan</description><author>Resti, Andrea</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditworthy: A History of Consumer Surveillance and Financial Identity in America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flynn, David
nan</description><author>Flynn, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Directions in Productivity Measurement and Efficiency Analysis: Counting the Environment and Natural Resources</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Surender
nan</description><author>Kumar, Surender</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The End Game: How Inequality Shapes Our-Final Years</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, Inas
nan</description><author>Kelly, Inas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review Essay on Social Neuroscience: Can Research on the Social Brain and Economics Inform Each Other?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alos-Ferrer, Carlos
Social neuroscience studies the "socialbrain," conceived as the set of brain structures and functions supporting the perception and evaluation of the social environment. This article provides an overview of the field, using the book Social Neuroscience: Brain, Mind, and Society (Russell K. Schutt, Larry J. Seidman, and Matcheri S. Keshavan, editors) as a starting point. Topics include the evolution of the social brain, the concept of " theory of mind," the relevant brain networks, and documented failures of the social brain. I argue that social neuroscience and economics can greatly benefit from each other because the social brain underlies interpersonal decision making, as studied in economics.</description><author>Alos-Ferrer, Carlos</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Morality, Policy, and the Brain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rustichini, Aldo
The book Moral Tribes: Emotion, Reason, and the Gap between Us and Them, by Joshua Greene, invites the reader to give a new look at the foundation of ethics and, by implication, to policy. Its specific strength is the systematic integration of new methods from neuroscience into a very old debate. Having something new and substantial to add in an investigation that has been at the center of the philosophical debate in Western civilization for twenty-five centuries is remarkable. While I invite everyone to read and enjoy this wonderful book, I take here the opportunity to invite economists to take the challenge. We are particularly interested in the question, "Is there a specific contribution that economics can give to this debate?" I believe there is and this insight is now in danger of being lost. This is my attempt to indicate where the research should look now. Maybe it is not too late.</description><author>Rustichini, Aldo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review Essay on Howard Bodenhorn's The Color Factor: The Economics of African-American Well-Being in the Nineteenth-Century South</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shertzer, Allison
In The Color Factor: The Economics of African-American Well-Being in the Nineteenth-Century South, Howard Bodenhorn investigates the origins, health, and socioeconomic performance of mixed-race people in the antebellum Southern United States. The central conclusion of the book is that mixed-race people fared better than darker-skinned blacks on nearly every dimension; however, they were still disadvantaged relative to whites. This review essay discusses the book's valuable data contributions and relates Bodenhorn's conclusions to the broader literature on colorism. I close with implications for future research on the economics of skin color.</description><author>Shertzer, Allison</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markets and Manipulation: Time for a Paradigm Shift?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basu, Kaushik
There is a growing appreciation in economics that people have emotional vulnerabilities, commitments to social norms, and systematic irrationalities that impact their decision making and choice in the market place. The flip side of this is that human beings are susceptible to being manipulated by unscrupulous agents single-minded about marketing their services and wares. This paper reviews George Akerlof and Robert Shiller's Phishing for Phools: The Economics of Manipulation and Deception, alongside other writings in the field, and discusses how this research agenda can be taken forward. The paper shows how this new research can shed light on the ubiquity of corruption in so many societies, and proposes ideas for controlling corruption.</description><author>Basu, Kaushik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Work on Auctions of Multiple Objects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hortacsu, Ali; McAdams, David
Abundant data has led to new opportunities for empirical auctions research in recent years, with much of the newest work on auctions of multiple objects, including: (1) auctions of ranked objects (such as sponsored search ads), (2) auctions of identical objects (such as Treasury bonds), and (3) auctions of dissimilar objects (such as FCC spectrum licenses). This paper surveys recent developments in the empirical analysis of such auctions.</description><author>Hortacsu, Ali; McAdams, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Citations In Economics: Measurement, Uses, and Impacts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hamermesh, Daniel S.
I describe and compare sources of data on citations in economics and the statistics derived from them. Constructing data sets of the post-publication citation histories of articles published in the "top five" journals in the 1970s and 2000s, I examine distributions and life cycles of citations, compare citation histories of articles in different subspecialties in economics, and present evidence on the history and heterogeneity of those journals' impacts and the marginal citation productivity of additional coauthors. I use a new data set of the lifetime citation histories of over 1,000 economists from thirty universities to rank economics departments by various measures and demonstrate the importance of intra- and interdepartmental heterogeneity in productivity. Throughout, the discussion summarizes earlier work, including the impacts of citations on salaries and nonmonetary rewards, and how citations reflect judgments about research quality in economics and the importance of economic ideas.</description><author>Hamermesh, Daniel S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oxford Handbook of Professional Economic Ethics (vol 55, pg 1, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, Anne
nan</description><author>Krueger, Anne</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of American Art: Issues, Artists and Market Institutions.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pownall, Rachel A. J.
nan</description><author>Pownall, Rachel A. J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liberalism and the Welfare State: Economists and Arguments for the Welfare State.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boettke, Peter
nan</description><author>Boettke, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inequality and Growth: Patterns and Policy, vol2, Regions and Regularities.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>FitzGerald, Valpy
nan</description><author>FitzGerald, Valpy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economy of Ghana Sixty Years after Independence.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nyarko, Yaw
nan</description><author>Nyarko, Yaw</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creativity without Law: Challenging the Assumptions of Intellectual Property.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenhalgh, Christine
nan</description><author>Greenhalgh, Christine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gaining Currency: The Rise of the Renminbi.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schnabl, Gunther
nan</description><author>Schnabl, Gunther</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Myth of Independence: How Congress Governs the Federal Reserve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Waller, Christopher J.
nan</description><author>Waller, Christopher J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Review of Global Tax Fairness, Thomas Pogge and Krishen Mehta, Editors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weinzierl, Matthew
This timely volume (Global Tax Fairness, edited by Thomas Pogge and Krishen Mehta) on the proper taxation of multinational enterprises argues that several feasible, near-term reforms could substantially narrow the scope for tax avoidance by closing information gaps, and it proposes more ambitious, long-term reforms that pursue coordination on the design, not just the enforcement, of tax policy. The editors construct an impassioned normative case that (legal) avoidance violates fairness because its negative effects fall especially hard on the world's poor, but their case could be bolstered by an appeal to the classical benefit-based logic behind the central aim of the reforms they recommend.</description><author>Weinzierl, Matthew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Measuring Multidimensional Deprivation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pattanaik, Prasanta K.; Xu, Yongsheng
This essay presents a critical review of the recent book by Alkire et al. entitled Multidimensional Poverty Measurement and Analysis, and, in the course of doing so, it also discusses some general issues that come up in this context. We outline the basic structure of the problem of measuring multidimensional deprivation and critically evaluate the methodology adopted by Alkire et al. (2015). In particular, we discuss some problems associated with the methods used by them to identify the deprived and to aggregate individual deprivations so as to derive an index of social deprivation. We examine the interpretation in terms of unfreedoms of individuals, which Alkire et al. put on one of their measures of social deprivation. We also suggest a variant of their methodology for measuring multidimensional deprivation.</description><author>Pattanaik, Prasanta K.; Xu, Yongsheng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Medieval Origins: A Review Essay on Campbell's The Great Transition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaney, Eric
Bruce M. S. Campbell's The Great Transition: Climate, Disease and Society in the Late-Medieval World is a significant contribution to the growing literature that traces the roots of Europe's economic rise to the climatic and population shocks of the late medieval period. This review essay discusses the empirical, historical, and theoretical support for Campbell's view while highlighting that it struggles to explain why these positive effects were limited to Europe. It then hypothesizes that Europe's differential response to this shock reflected prior institutional advantages and provides some preliminary empirical evidence in support of this hypothesis. The essay concludes by examining Campbell's claim that these shocks contributed to Atlantic Europe's rise prior to the colonial period.</description><author>Chaney, Eric</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernard, Andrew B.; Jensen, J. Bradford; Redding, Stephen J.; Schott, Peter K.
Research in international trade has changed dramatically over the last twenty years, as attention has shifted from countries and industries towards the firms actually engaged in international trade. The now-standard heterogeneous firm model posits measurezero firms that compete under monopolistic competition and decide whether to export to foreign markets. However, much of international trade is dominated by a few "global firms," which participate in the international economy along multiple margins and account for substantial shares of aggregate trade. We develop a new theoretical framework that allows firms to have large market shares and decide simultaneously on the set of production locations, export markets, input sources, products to export, and inputs to import. Using US firm and trade transactions data, we provide strong evidence in support of this framework's main predictions of interdependencies and complementarities between these margins of firm international participation. Global firms participate more intensively along each margin, magnifying the impact of underlying differences in firm characteristics and increasing their shares of aggregate trade.</description><author>Bernard, Andrew B.; Jensen, J. Bradford; Redding, Stephen J.; Schott, Peter K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating Risk Preferences in the Field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barseghyan, Levon; Molinari, Francesca; O'Donoghue, Ted; Teitelbaum, Joshua C.
We survey the literature on estimating risk preferences using field data. We concentrate our attention on studies in which risk preferences are the focal object and estimating their structure is the core enterprise. We review a number of models of risk preferences-including both expected utility (EU) theory and non-EU models-that have been estimated using field data, and we highlight issues related to identification and estimation of such models using field data. We then survey the literature, giving separate treatment to research that uses individual-level data (e.g., property-insurance data) and research that uses aggregate data (e.g., betting-market data). We conclude by discussing directions for future research.</description><author>Barseghyan, Levon; Molinari, Francesca; O'Donoghue, Ted; Teitelbaum, Joshua C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economics of the Pharmaceutical Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lakdawalla, Darius N.
The pharmaceutical industry accounts for a substantial chunk of the US economy's research and development investments, which have resulted in significant medical breakthroughs. At the same time, the costs of pharmaceutical products continue to rise, as does pressure to adopt direct or indirect controls on pharmaceutical prices. We review the economics literature on the pharmaceutical industry, focusing particularly on its positive and normative implications for the innovation, pricing, and marketing decisions of pharmaceutical firms. We discuss the major achievements of, and persistent gaps in, the literature, along with lessons for policy.</description><author>Lakdawalla, Darius N.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Places in Need: The Changing Geography of Poverty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wozniak, Abigail
nan</description><author>Wozniak, Abigail</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Determinants of Cooperation in Infinitely Repeated Games: A Survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dal Bo, Pedro; Frechette, Guillaume R.
A growing experimental literature studies the determinants of cooperation in infinitely repeated games, tests different predictions of the theory, and suggests an empirical solution to the problem of multiple equilibria. To provide a robust description of the literature's findings, we gather and analyze a metadata set of experiments on infinitely repeated prisoner's dilemma games. The experimental data show that cooperation is affected by infinite repetition and is more likely to arise when it can be supported in equilibrium. However, the fact that cooperation can be supported in equilibrium does not imply that most subjects will cooperate. High cooperation rates will emerge only when the parameters of the repeated game are such that cooperation is very robust to strategic uncertainty. We also review the results regarding the effect of imperfect monitoring, changing partners, and personal characteristics on cooperation and the strategies used to support it.</description><author>Dal Bo, Pedro; Frechette, Guillaume R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Science of Monetary Policy: An Imperfect Knowledge Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eusepi, Stefano; Preston, Bruce
This paper reevaluates the basic prescriptions of monetary policy design in the new Keynesian paradigm through the lens of imperfect knowledge. We show that while the basic logic of monetary policy design under rational expectations continues to obtain, perfect knowledge and learning can limit the set of policies available to central banks, rendering expectations management in general more difficult. Nonetheless, the desirability of some form of price-level targeting, inducing inertia in interest-rate policy, paramount under rational expectations, is robust to the assumption of imperfect knowledge.</description><author>Eusepi, Stefano; Preston, Bruce</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Tax Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weber, Caroline
nan</description><author>Weber, Caroline</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Immigration in American Economic History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abramitzky, Ran; Boustan, Leah
The United States has long been perceived as a land of opportunity for immigrants. Yet, both in the past and today, US natives have expressed concern that immigrants fail to integrate into US society and lower wages for existing workers. This paper reviews the literatures on historical and contemporary migrant flows, yielding new insights on migrant selection, assimilation of immigrants into US economy and society, and the effect of immigration on the labor market.</description><author>Abramitzky, Ran; Boustan, Leah</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Family Economics Writ Large</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Jeremy; Guner, Nezih; Vandenbroucke, Guillaume
Powerful currents have reshaped the structure of families over the last century. There has been (1) a dramatic drop in fertility and greater parental investment in children; (2) a rise in married female labor-force participation; (3) a significant decline in marriage; (4) a higher degree of positive assortative mating; (5) more children living with a single mother; and (6) shifts in social norms governing premarital sex and married women's roles in the workplace. Macroeconomic models explaining these aggregate trends are surveyed. The relentless flow of technological progress and its role in shaping family life are stressed.</description><author>Greenwood, Jeremy; Guner, Nezih; Vandenbroucke, Guillaume</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Parties or Problem Sets: Review Article on How College Works and Paying for the Party</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, William R.
The potential of Internet-enabled distance learning to transform higher education focuses attention on exactly what residential higher-education institutions do for and to their students. Two recent books marshal detailed quantitative and subjective data on individual student outcomes to document the effects of two institutions and how these outcomes might be improved. Paying for the Party concludes that a Midwestern state university reinforces existing economic inequalities rather than fostering upward mobility. How College Works finds that a northeastern liberal-arts college generally serves its students well and suggests low-cost improvements. These claims are evaluated.</description><author>Johnson, William R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Game Theory and Cold War Rationality: A Review Essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weintraub, E. Roy
This essay reviews new histories of the role of game theory and rational decision making in shaping the social sciences, economics among them, in the postwar period. The recent books The World the Game Theorists Made by Paul Erickson and How Reason Almost Lost Its Mind: The Strange Career of Cold War Rationality by Paul Erickson, Judy Klein, Lorraine Daston, Rebecca Lemov, Thomas Sturm, and Michael Gordin raise a number of complex historical questions about the interconnections among game theory, utility theory, decision theory, optimization theory, information theory, and theories of rational choice. Moreover, the contingencies of time, place, and person call into question the usefulness of economists' linear narratives about the autonomous and progressive development of modern economics. The essay finally reflects on the challenges that these issues present for historians of recent economics.</description><author>Weintraub, E. Roy</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comments on Economic Models, Economics, and Economists: Remarks on Economics Rules by Dani Rodrik</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rubinstein, Ariel
This essay reviews Dani Rodrik's superb book Economics Rules and argues that it can serve as an ideal platform for discussing what economists can and should accomplish. The essay comments on some of the major issues in contemporary economics examined in the book: whether economics is a science, the meaning of economic models, the nature of "facts" in economics, and others. It also touches on issues that the book overlooks, such as the sociology of the profession, the teaching curriculum in economics, and the dismal situation of publishing in economics.</description><author>Rubinstein, Ariel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hansen and Sargent's Recursive Models of Dynamic Linear Economies: A Review Essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>West, Kenneth D.
Lars Peter Hansen and Thomas J. Sargent's book, Recursive Models of Dynamic Linear Economies, exposits, extends, and applies methods for solution and analysis of dynamic stochastic linear quadratic models. The book, which can be used as a monograph or in a graduate course, integrates theory, econometrics, and computation. This essay provides a summary and offers some mild complaints about material not included in what is already a remarkably comprehensive book.</description><author>West, Kenneth D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Geoffrey M. Hodgson, Conceptualizing Capitalism: Institutions, Evolution, Future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rose-Ackerman, Susan
Capitalism and law go together in Geoffrey M. Hodgson's comprehensive analysis of the intellectual history and practical development of the capitalist system in Western Europe and North America. Given the breadth and depth of Professor Hodgson's reading in political economy and his reflections on its implications for the present and future of global capitalism, his book deserves to be widely read. Labeling his approach legal institutionalism, he argues that a legal system that supports capitalism and the market is necessary but not sufficient to sustain a fair and efficient economic system. The state makes efficient markets possible, but it must also deal with the inevitable tensions and the fundamental asymmetry between labor and capital. Tensions arise because labor cannot be used as collateral for the loans that are needed for largescale capitalist enterprise. Hodgson has not developed the political implications of his conclusions in any detail, but his work ought to inspire research that explores the implications of his arguments for ongoing projects of nation building.</description><author>Rose-Ackerman, Susan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capitalism and Socialism: A Review of Kornai's Dynamism, Rivalry, and the Surplus Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Chenggang
Understanding the nature of capitalism has been a central theme of economics. The collapse of the Eastern Bloc and the global financial crisis spurred the reemergence of the political economy as a new frontier and the revival of interest in the nature of capitalism. Janos Kornai's book Dynamism, Rivalry, and the Surplus Economy: Two Essays on the Nature of Capitalism fills an important intellectual gap in understanding the dynamic nature of capitalism by comparing it with its mirror image, socialism. To further develop the themes contained in the book, serious challenges are posed theoretically and empirically, as well as in subjects, such as hybrid capitalism.</description><author>Xu, Chenggang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Oxford Handbook of Professional Economic Ethics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, Anne O.
nan</description><author>Krueger, Anne O.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Theory of Extensive Form Games</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perea, Andres
nan</description><author>Perea, Andres</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finding Time: The Economics of Work-Life Conflict</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sevilla, Almudena
nan</description><author>Sevilla, Almudena</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Voting: Studies of Self-Interest, Bargaining, Duty and Rights, vol 203</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van der Straeten, Karine
nan</description><author>Van der Straeten, Karine</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economics with Heterogeneous Interacting Agents: A Practical Guide to Agent-Based Modeling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Georges, Christophre
nan</description><author>Georges, Christophre</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>You have to really stretch your imagination to infer what the intrinsic value of Bitcoin is. I haven't been able to do it. Maybe somebody else can</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolt, Wilko
nan</description><author>Bolt, Wilko</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies: A Comprehensive Introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolt, Wilko
nan</description><author>Bolt, Wilko</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Milton Friedman: Contributions to Economics and Public Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diamond, Arthur M.
nan</description><author>Diamond, Arthur M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Econometric Analysis of Recurrent Events in Macroeconomics and Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yoldas, Emre
nan</description><author>Yoldas, Emre</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Oxford Handbook of the Economics of Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reich, Bryony
nan</description><author>Reich, Bryony</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Central Bank Governance and Oversight Reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kirsanova, Tatiana
nan</description><author>Kirsanova, Tatiana</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prosperity for All: How to Prevent Financial Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eden, Benjamin
nan</description><author>Eden, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Virtual Competition: The Promise and Perils of the Algorithm-Driven Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peitz, Martin
nan</description><author>Peitz, Martin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Federal Trade Commission Privacy Law and Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hui, Kai-Lung
nan</description><author>Hui, Kai-Lung</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money in the Western Legal Tradition: Middle Ages to Bretton Woods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tymoigne, Eric
nan</description><author>Tymoigne, Eric</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity: A New Monetarist Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lagos, Ricardo; Rocheteau, Guillaume; Wright, Randall
This essay surveys the new monetarist approach to liquidity. Work in this literature strives for empirical and policy relevance, plus rigorous foundations. Questions include: What is liquidity? Is money essential in achieving desirable outcomes? Which objects can or should serve in this capacity? When can asset prices differ from fundamentals? What are the functions of commitment and collateral in credit markets? How does money interact with credit and intermediation? What can and should monetary policy do? The research summarized emphasizes the micro structure of frictional transactions, and studies how institutions like monetary exchange, credit arrangements, or intermediation facilitate the exchange process. (JEL E24, E31, E42, E44, E52, G10, G21)</description><author>Lagos, Ricardo; Rocheteau, Guillaume; Wright, Randall</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary Analysis at Central Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neyapti, Bilin
nan</description><author>Neyapti, Bilin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Aspects of Genocides, Other Mass Atrocities, and Their Prevention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferrero, Mario
nan</description><author>Ferrero, Mario</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Europe Isn't Working</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zymek, Robert
nan</description><author>Zymek, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Oxford Handbook of Economics and Human Biology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kinge, Jonas Minet
nan</description><author>Kinge, Jonas Minet</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing the Macroeconomy: Monetary and Exchange Rate Issues in India</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pattnaik, R. K.
nan</description><author>Pattnaik, R. K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Politics of Innovation: Why Some Countries Are Better Than Others at Science and Technology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fagerberg, Jan
nan</description><author>Fagerberg, Jan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Criminal Deterrence: A Review of the Literature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chalfin, Aaron; McCrary, Justin
We review economics research regarding the effect of police, punishments, and work on crime, with a particular focus on papers from the last twenty years. Evidence in favor of deterrence effects is mixed. While there is considerable evidence that crime is responsive to police and to the existence of attractive legitimate labor-market opportunities, there is far less evidence that crime responds to the severity of criminal sanctions. We discuss fruitful directions for future work and implications for public policy.</description><author>Chalfin, Aaron; McCrary, Justin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Consequences of Social-Network Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jackson, Matthew O.; Rogers, Brian W.; Zenou, Yves
We survey the literature on the economic consequences of the structure of social networks. We develop a taxonomy of "macro" and "micro" characteristics of - social-interaction networks and discuss both the theoretical and empirical findings concerning the role of those characteristics in determining learning, diffusion, decisions, and resulting behaviors. We also discuss the challenges of accounting for the endogeneity of networks in assessing the relationship between the patterns of interactions and behaviors.</description><author>Jackson, Matthew O.; Rogers, Brian W.; Zenou, Yves</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Avoidance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golman, Russell; Hagmann, David; Loewenstein, George
We commonly think of information as a means to an end. However, a growing theoretical and experimental literature suggests that information may directly enter the agent's utility function. This can create an incentive to avoid information, even when it is useful, free, and independent of strategic considerations. We review research documenting the occurrence of information avoidance, as well as theoretical and empirical research on reasons why people avoid information, drawing from economics, psychology, and other disciplines. The review concludes with a discussion of some of the diverse (and often costly) individual and societal consequences of information avoidance.</description><author>Golman, Russell; Hagmann, David; Loewenstein, George</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Review of The Business of Slavery and the Rise of American Capitalism, 1815-1860 by Calvin Schermerhorn and The Half Has Never Been Told: Slavery and the Making of American Capitalism by Edward E. Baptist</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engerman, Stanley L.
The two books being reviewed are concerned with the importance of slavery in the antebellum US South for the economic development of the Northern states. One (Schermerhorn) deals primarily with Southern financial arrangements facilitating the sales of slaves and cotton. The other (Baptist) presents a broader picture of masters' treatment of slaves, as well as how the incomes of slaveowners spurred the demand for Northern industrial production. The review argues that both books overstate the importance of slavery and cotton production for US economic growth.</description><author>Engerman, Stanley L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Power and Independence of the Federal Reserve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kocherlakota, Narayana R.
nan</description><author>Kocherlakota, Narayana R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Climbing Mount Laurel: The Struggle for Affordable Housing and Social Mobility in an American Suburb</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ioannides, Yannis M.
Climbing Mount Laurel, authored by a group of sociologists led by Douglas S. Massey, is about the efforts by Mount Laurel Township, NJ, residents to have affordable housing built in their community. From when it was first proposed in 1969 and until the first units were completed in 2000, the project faced extraordinary political opposition, caused a number of landmark court decisions, and motivated affordable-housing legislation by other US states. This review evaluates, from an economics perspective, the lessons learned, as argued by Massey et al., about the impact of affordable housing within the host community and on surrounding communities.</description><author>Ioannides, Yannis M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Successful Was the New Deal? The Microeconomic Impact of New Deal Spending and Lending Policies in the 1930s</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fishback, Price
The New Deal during the 1930s was arguably the largest peace-time expansion in federal government activity in American history. Until recently, there had been very little quantitative testing of the microeconomic impact of the wide variety of New Deal programs. Over the past decade scholars have developed new panel databases for counties, cities, and states and then used panel data methods on them to examine the impact of New Deal spending and lending policies for the major New Deal programs. In most cases, the identification of the effect comes from changes across time within the same geographic location after controlling for national shocks to the economy. Many of the studies also use instrumental variable methods to control for endogeneity. The studies find that public works and relief spending had state income multipliers of around one, increased consumption activity, attracted internal migration, reduced crime rates, and lowered several types of mortality. The farm programs typically aided large farm owners but eliminated opportunities for share croppers, tenants, and farm workers. The Home Owners' Loan Corporation's purchases and refinancing of troubled mortgages staved off drops in housing prices and home ownership rates at relatively low ex post cost to taxpayers. The Reconstruction Finance Corporation's loans to banks and railroads appear to have had little positive impact, although the banks were aided when the RFC took ownership stakes.</description><author>Fishback, Price</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the Energy-Efficiency Gap</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gerarden, Todd D.; Newell, Richard G.; Stavins, Robert N.
Energy-efficient technologies offer considerable promise for reducing the financial costs and environmental damages associated with energy use, but it has long been observed that these technologies may not be adopted by individuals and firms to the degree that might be justified, even on a purely financial basis. We survey the relevant literature on this "energy-efficiency gap" by presenting two complementary frameworks. First, we divide potential explanations for the energy-efficiency gap into three categories: market failures, behavioral explanations, and model and measurement errors. Second, we organize previous research in terms of the fundamental elements of cost-minimizing energy-efficiency decisions. This provides a decomposition that organizes thinking around four questions. First, are product offerings and pricing economically efficient? Second, are energy operating costs inefficiently priced and/or understood? Third, are product choices cost minimizing in present value terms? Fourth, do other costs inhibit more energy-efficient decisions? We synthesize academic research on these questions, with an emphasis on recent empirical findings, and offer suggestions for future research.</description><author>Gerarden, Todd D.; Newell, Richard G.; Stavins, Robert N.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ideology, Economic Policy, and Economic History: Cohen and DeLong's Concrete Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Field, Alexander J.
Stephen S. Cohen and J. Bradford DeLong view US economic policy extending up to 1980 as pragmatically fostering growth. This they interpret as the Hamiltonian tradition, and their intent is to rescue policy debate from the data- and logic-free quagmire into which they believe it has fallen. Following an introduction, section 2 of this essay describes methods and evidence that permit statements about the historical influence of ideological thinking more empirically grounded than those essayed by the authors. Section 3 examines specific aspects of their narrative. Section 4 considers what we mean by ideological thinking, and why it might be deleterious.</description><author>Field, Alexander J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public Economics and History: A Review of Fiscal Regimes and the Political Economy of Premodern States, Edited by Andrew Monson and Walter Scheidel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoffman, Philip T.
Fiscal Regimes and the Political Economy of Premodern States greatly expands our knowledge of the history of premodern fiscal systems and raises important questions about the political economy of premodern states. Answering those questions can help explain how states developed the capacity to tax; why tax levels and government-spending patterns varied greatly in the past, even though per capita incomes were similar; how government debt and representative institutions arose; and, last but not least, why some premodern states expanded and others collapsed. But firm answers to those questions will have to combine the history outlined in Fiscal Regimes and the Political Economy of Premodern States with systematic data and formal models of political economy.</description><author>Hoffman, Philip T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Group Selection: A Review Essay on Does Altruism Exist? by David Sloan Wilson</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robson, Arthur J.
In response to the question in the title, Does Altruism Exist?, David Sloan Wilson argues forcefully that altruism exists and that the biological mechanism of group selection is responsible. He argues that group selection should be taken especially seriously for humans, since cultural evolution is especially important for us. Economists' view of basic human motivations should then include altruism. Wilson promotes a strong form of pervasive altruism, which seems bound to be inconsistent with many economic phenomena. Although a moderate version of the position he advocates is not easily dismissed, it is unclear what such an extended theory would look like.</description><author>Robson, Arthur J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Great Recession in the Shadow of the Great Depression: A Review Essay on Hall of Mirrors: The Great Depression, the Great Recession, and the Uses and Misuses of History, by Barry Eichengreen</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ohanian, Lee E.
This essay compares the Great Depression to the Great Recession in light of Barry Eichengreen's new book Hall of Mirrors. Eichengreen discusses these two episodes from a historical, Keynesian perspective, and concludes that policies that increase aggregate demand, such as larger fiscal deficits, would have promoted a much stronger and faster recovery from the Great Recession. I review these episodes from a neoclassical approach, which provides a very different perspective on why recoveries from these episodes were so slow and incomplete. I also argue that supply-side policies, rather than demand-side policies, are more likely to restore prosperity today.</description><author>Ohanian, Lee E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review Essay on Alvin Roth's Who Gets What-and Why</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glaeser, Edward L.
Alvin Roth's Who Gets What-And Why provides a richly accessible introduction to his pioneering work on market design. Much of economics ignores the institutions that allocate goods, blithely assuming that the mythical Walrasian auctioneer will handle everything perfectly. But markets do fail and Roth details those failures, like the market for law clerks that unravels because clerks and judges commit to each other too quickly. Roth combines theory and pragmatic experience to show how the economist can engineer successful markets. He has even enabled welfare-improving trades in kidney exchanges, where law and social repugnance forbids cash payments.</description><author>Glaeser, Edward L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convolution Copula Econometrics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beare, Brendan K.
nan</description><author>Beare, Brendan K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan Sharks: The Birth of Predatory Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caskey, John P.
nan</description><author>Caskey, John P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Engines of Anxiety: Academic Rankings, Reputation, and Accountability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffith, Amanda
nan</description><author>Griffith, Amanda</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The World Economy: Growth or Stagnation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poschke, Markus
nan</description><author>Poschke, Markus</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Feeling Smart: Why Our Emotions Are More Rational Than We Think</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kirman, Alan
nan</description><author>Kirman, Alan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generation Unbound: Drifting into Sex and Parenting without Marriage and Laurence Steinberg's Age of Opportunity: Lessons from the New Science of Adolescence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aizer, Anna
Sawhill and Steinberg approach risky behavior among youth from two different angles: Steinberg argues for intervention during the adolescent years to alter behavior in ways that prioritize patience and self-regulation, while Sawhill advocates interventions that mitigate the negative effects of risky behavior. Both argue that disadvantaged youth suffer worse consequences as a result of risky behavior and therefore stand to gain the most from interventions. While the authors develop strong arguments for adolescent interventions, the existing evidence on their effectiveness is less compelling. To reconcile the promise with the reality, I argue that growing up in environments of significant uncertainty reduces the returns to forward-thinking behavior in the daily lives of disadvantaged youths. Interventions to develop adolescent decision-making skills so as to reduce risky behavior will not be effective if they are inconsistent with the incentives generated by a local environment that is often characterized by uncertainty.</description><author>Aizer, Anna</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>School Vouchers: A Survey of the Economics Literature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Epple, Dennis; Romano, Richard E.; Urquiola, Miguel
We review the theoretical, computational, and empirical research on school vouchers, with a focus on the latter. Our assessment is that the evidence to date is not sufficient to warrant recommending that vouchers be adopted on a widespread basis; however, multiple positive findings support continued exploration. Specifically, the empirical research on small-scale programs does not suggest that awarding students a voucher is a systematically reliable way to improve educational outcomes, and some detrimental effects have been found. Nevertheless, in some settings, or for some subgroups or outcomes, vouchers can have a substantial positive effect on those who use them. Studies of large-scale voucher programs find student sorting as a result of their implementation, although of varying magnitude. Evidence on both small-scale and large-scale programs suggests that competition induced by vouchers leads public schools to improve. Moreover, research is making progress on understanding how vouchers may be designed to limit adverse effects from sorting, while preserving positive effects related to competition. Finally, our sense is that work originating in a single case (e.g., a given country) or in a single research approach (e.g., experimental designs) will not provide a full understanding of voucher effects; fairly wide-ranging empirical and theoretical work will be necessary to make progress. (JEL H52, H75, I21, I22, I28, O15)</description><author>Epple, Dennis; Romano, Richard E.; Urquiola, Miguel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sorting through Search and Matching Models in Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chade, Hector; Eeckhout, Jan; Smith, Lones
Toward understanding assortative matching, this is a self-contained introduction to research on search and matching. We first explore the nontransferable and perfectly transferable utility matching paradigms, and then a unifying imperfectly transferable utility matching model. Motivated by some unrealistic predictions of frictionless matching, we flesh out the foundational economics of search theory. We then revisit the original matching paradigms with search frictions. We finally allow informational frictions that often arise, such as in college-student sorting. (JEL C78, D82, D83, I23, J12)</description><author>Chade, Hector; Eeckhout, Jan; Smith, Lones</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Classifying Economics: A History of the JEL Codes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cherrier, Beatrice
In this paper, I suggest that the history of the classification system used by the American Economic Association (AEA) to list economic literature and scholars is a relevant proxy to understand the transformation of economics science throughout the twentieth century. Successive classifications were fashioned through heated discussions on the status of theoretical and empirical work, data and measurement, and proper objects of analysis. They also reflected the contradictory demands of users, including economists but also civil servants, journalists, publishers, librarians, and the military, and reflected rapidly changing institutional and technological constraints. Until the late 1940s, disagreements on the general structure of the classification dominated AEA discussions. As the subject matters, methods, and definition of economics rapidly evolved after the war, methodological debates raged on the status of theoretical and empirical work and the degree of unification of the discipline. It was therefore the ordering and content of major categories that was closely discussed during the 1956 revision. The 1966 revision, in contrast, was fueled by institutional and technical transformations rather than intellectual ones. Classifiers essentially reacted to changes in the way economists' work was evaluated, the nature and size of the literature they produced, the publishing industry, and the use of computer facilities. The final 1988-90 revision was an attempt by the Journal of Economic Literature (JEL) editors to translate the mature core fields structure of their science into a set of codes and accommodate the new types of applied work economists identified themselves with. The 1990 classification system was only incrementally transformed in the next twenty years, but that the AEA is currently considering a new revision may signal more profound changes in the structure of economics. (JEL A14)</description><author>Cherrier, Beatrice</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Opportunities, Welfare, and Social Justice: A Review of Fishkin's Bottlenecks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maniquet, Francois
In his Bottlenecks: A New Theory of Equal Opportunity, Joseph Fishkin claims he presents an entirely new way of thinking about equality of opportunity. The core of the new theory is the call for opportunity pluralism, which consists in enlarging the range of opportunities available to people at every stage in life. In this essay, we discuss how successful Fishkin is at shaking the way economists think about equality of opportunity. We identify two aspects of Fishkin's theory that deeply conflict with economic theories of equality of opportunity. Those aspects have to do with the way economists interpret the ethical values of respect for preferences and responsibility. We also argue that the way Fishkin suggests to look at opportunities can help economists fill gaps in the way they define well-being and social justice. (JEL A13, D63, I31).</description><author>Maniquet, Francois</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Evolution of Value Systems: A Review Essay on Ian Morris's Foragers, Farmers, and Fossil Fuels</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bisin, Alberto
Foragers, Farmers, and Fossil Fuels: How Human Values Evolve is a large-scale history of the world through the different modes of production humanity has adopted over time and their implications in terms of moral values. Morris argues that the predominant value systems of human societies are cultural adaptations to the organizational structures of the societies themselves, their institutions, and ultimately to their modes of production. In particular, the book contains a careful analysis of how the hunting-gathering mode of production induces egalitarian values and relatively favorable attitudes toward violent resolution of conflicts, while farming induces hierarchical values and less favorable attitudes toward violence, and in turn the fossil fuel (that is, industrial) mode of production induces egalitarian values and nonviolent attitudes. The narrative in the book is rich, diverse, and ultimately entertaining. Morris's analysis is very knowledgeable and informative: arguments and evidence are rooted in history, anthropology, archeology, and social sciences in general. Nonetheless, the analysis falls short of being convincing about the causal nature of the existing relationship between modes of production and moral value systems.</description><author>Bisin, Alberto</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional Cash Transfers: The Case of Progresa/Oportunidades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parker, Susan W.; Todd, Petra E.
Conditional cash transfer (CCT) programs innovate by conditioning transfers to poor families on investments in the human capital of children and other family members. The Mexican CCT program Progresa/Oportunidades began in 1997 and has served as a model for many of the now over sixty countries with CCTs around the world, in large part due to its initial evaluation with an experimental design and numerous follow-up studies. This article reviews the literature on the development, evaluation, and findings of Progresa/Oportunidades, summarizing what is known about program effects, taking into account corrections for multiple-hypothesis testing.</description><author>Parker, Susan W.; Todd, Petra E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Political Economy of Dynamic Elections: Accountability, Commitment, and Responsiveness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duggan, John; Martinelli, Cesar
We survey the literature on dynamic elections in the traditional settings of spatial preferences and rent seeking under perfect and imperfect monitoring of politicians. We define stationary electoral equilibrium, which encompasses notions used by Barro (1973), Ferejohn (1986), Banks and Sundaram (1998), and others. We show that repeated elections mitigate the commitment problems of politicians and voters, and that a responsive democracy result holds under general conditions. Term limits, however, attenuate the responsiveness finding. We also touch on related applied work, and we point to areas for fruitful future research, including the connection between dynamic models of politics and economics.</description><author>Duggan, John; Martinelli, Cesar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Static and Intertemporal Household Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiappori, Pierre-Andre; Mazzocco, Maurizio
We discuss the most popular static and dynamic models of household behavior. Our main objective is to explain which aspects of household decisions different models can account for. Using this insight, we describe testable implications, identification results, and estimation findings obtained in the literature. Particular attention is given to the ability of different models to answer various types of policy questions.</description><author>Chiappori, Pierre-Andre; Mazzocco, Maurizio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of the Climate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heal, Geoffrey
I review the economic characteristics of the climate problem, focusing on the choice of discount rates in the presence of a stock externality, risk and uncertainty/ambiguity, and the role of integrated assessment models (IAMs) in analyzing policy choices. I suggest that IAMs can play a role in providing qualitative understanding of how complex systems behave, but are not accurate enough to provide quantitative insights. Arguments in favor of action on climate issues have to be based on aversion to risk and ambiguity and the need to avoid a small but positive risk of a disastrous outcome.</description><author>Heal, Geoffrey</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Intellectual Legacy of Progressive Economics: A Review Essay of Thomas C. Leonard's Illiberal Reformers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Steinbaum, Marshall I.; Weisberger, Bernard A.
Thomas Leonard's 2016 book Illiberal Reformers: Race, Eugenics, and American Economics in the Progressive Era argues that exclusionary views on eugenics, race, immigration, and gender taint the intellectual legacy of progressive economics and economists. This review essay reconsiders that legacy and places it in the context within which it developed. While the early generations of scholars who founded the economics profession in the United States and trained in its departments did indeed hold and express retrograde views on those subjects, those views were common to a broad swath of the intellectual elite of that era, including the progressives' staunchest opponents inside and outside academia. Moreover, Leonard anachronistically intermingles a contemporary critique of early-twentieth-century progressive economics and the progressive movement writ large, serving to decontextualize those disputes-a flaw that is amplified by the book's unsystematic approach to reconstructing the views and writing it attacks. Notwithstanding the history Leonard presents, economists working now nonetheless owe their progressive forebears for contributions that have become newly relevant: the "credibility revolution," the influence of economic research on policy and program design, the prestige of economists working in and providing advice to government agencies and policy makers, and the academic freedom economists enjoy in modern research-oriented universities are all a part of that legacy.</description><author>Steinbaum, Marshall I.; Weisberger, Bernard A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Economic Interdependence and War</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morelli, Massimo; Sonno, Tommaso
In this article, we review the book Economic Interdependence and War by Dale C. Copeland, and take this opportunity to describe and discuss the current debate on the topic from an interdisciplinary perspective. We also provide novel insights on the measurability of dependence expectations' effects on conflict, using the interaction with geography and endowment asymmetries.</description><author>Morelli, Massimo; Sonno, Tommaso</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Law, Coercion, and Expression: A Review Essay on Frederick Schauer's The Force of Law and Richard McAdams's The Expressive Powers of Law</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rasmusen, Eric
What is law and why do people obey it? This question from jurisprudence has recently been tackled using the tools of economics. The field of law and economics has long studied how fines and imprisonment affect behavior. Nobody believes, however, that all compliance is motivated by penalties, and it is questionable whether that is even the typical motivation. Two books published in 2015, Frederick Schauer's The Force of Law and Richard McAdams's The Expressive Powers of Law: Theories and Limits, consider alternative motivations-Schauer skeptically and McAdams more sympathetically. While coercion, either directly or in support of internalized norms, seems to dominate law qua law (and not as a mere expression of morality), a considerable portion of law serves other uses such as coordination, information provision, expression, and reduction of transaction costs.</description><author>Rasmusen, Eric</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Ideas You Should Forget</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colander, David
nan</description><author>Colander, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>British Banking: Continuity and Change from 1694 to the Present.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Quinn, Stephen
nan</description><author>Quinn, Stephen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Politics and Perils of Space Exploration: Who Will Compete, Who Will Dominate?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gibson, Bill
nan</description><author>Gibson, Bill</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Invisible Hand? How Market Economies Have Emerged and Declined since</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drelichman, Mauricio
nan</description><author>Drelichman, Mauricio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How China Escaped the Poverty Trap</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkowitz, Daniel
nan</description><author>Berkowitz, Daniel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endangered Economies: How the Neglect of Nature Threatens Our Prosperity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ackerman, Frank
nan</description><author>Ackerman, Frank</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Gender Wage Gap: Extent, Trends, and Explanations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blau, Francine D.; Kahn, Lawrence M.
Using Panel Study of Income Dynamics (PSID) microdata over the 1980-2010 period, we provide new empirical evidence on the extent of and trends in the gender wage gap, which declined considerably during this time. By 2010, conventional human capital variables taken together explained little of the gender wage gap, while gender differences in occupation and industry continued to be important. Moreover, the gender pay gap declined much more slowly at the top of the wage distribution than at the middle or bottom and by 2010 was noticeably higher at the top. We then survey the literature to identify what has been learned about the explanations for the gap. We conclude that many of the traditional explanations continue to have salience. Although human-capital factors are now relatively unimportant in the aggregate, women's work force interruptions and shorter hours remain significant in high-skilled occupations, possibly due to compensating differentials. Gender differences in occupations and industries, as well as differences in gender roles and the gender division of labor remain important, and research based on experimental evidence strongly suggests that discrimination cannot be discounted. Psychological attributes or noncognitive skills comprise one of the newer explanations for gender differences in outcomes. Our effort to assess the quantitative evidence on the importance of these factors suggests that they account for a small to moderate portion of the gender pay gap, considerably smaller than, say, occupation and industry effects, though they appear to modestly contribute to these differences.</description><author>Blau, Francine D.; Kahn, Lawrence M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Affirmative Action and the Quality-Fit Trade-off</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arcidiacono, Peter; Lovenheim, Michael
This paper reviews the literature on affirmative action in undergraduate education and law schools, focusing especially on the trade-off between institutional quality and the fit between a school and a student. We discuss the conditions under which affirmative action for underrepresented minorities (URM) could help or harm their educational outcomes. We provide descriptive evidence on the extent of affirmative action in law schools, as well as a critical review of the contentious literature on how affirmative action affects URM law-school student performance. Our review then discusses affirmative action in undergraduate admissions, focusing on the effects such admissions preferences have on college quality, graduation rates, college major, and earnings. We conclude by examining the evidence on "percent plans" as a replacement for affirmative action.</description><author>Arcidiacono, Peter; Lovenheim, Michael</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory Races: The Effects of Jurisdictional Competition on Regulatory Standards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carruthers, Bruce G.; Lamoreaux, Naomi R.
This article surveys the literature on regulatory arbitrage in four settings: labor regulation, environmental protection, corporate governance, and banking and finance. For a regulatory race to occur, firms must migrate across state or country borders in response to geographic differences in the costs and benefits of regulation, and governments must shape their regulatory policies with the aim of affecting those migration flows. We find that both these conditions hold only in rare circumstances. Instead, the much more common outcome is for political pressures within jurisdictions to produce a heterogeneous pattern resembling Tiebout sorting. Such regulatory convergence as occurs is more often the result of deliberate harmonization or imitation.</description><author>Carruthers, Bruce G.; Lamoreaux, Naomi R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Temporary Migrations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dustmann, Christian; Goerlach, Joseph-Simon
Many migrations are temporary-a fact that has often been ignored in the economic literature on migration. Such omission may be serious in that expected migration temporariness can impart a distinct dynamic element to immigrants' economic behavior, generating possible consequences for nonmigrants in both home and host countries. In this paper, we provide a thorough examination of the various aspects of temporary migrations that matter for the analysis of economic phenomena. We demonstrate the extent of temporary migrations in population movements. We show how temporariness can affect the various economic choices and how better data have improved both the measurement of nonpermanent migrations and the analyses of various aspects of migrant behavior. We propose a general theoretical framework for modeling temporary migration decisions, based on which we outline the various motives for temporariness while simultaneously reviewing related literature and available data sources. We discuss the possible consequences of migration temporariness for nonmigrants in both home and host countries.</description><author>Dustmann, Christian; Goerlach, Joseph-Simon</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Quantitative Review of Marriage Markets: How Inequality is Remaking the American Family by Carbone and Cahn</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornelson, Kirsten; Siow, Aloysius
June Carbone and Naomi Cahn argue that growing earnings inequality and the increased educational attainment of women, relative to men, have led to declining marriage rates for less-educated women and an increase in positive assortative matching since the 1970s. These trends have negatively affected the welfare of children, as they increase the proportion of poor, single-female-headed households. Using data on marriage markets defined by state, race and time, and the Choo-Siow marriage matching function, this review provides a quantitative assessment of these claims. We show that changes in earnings inequality had a qualitatively consistent but modest quantitative impact on marriage rates and positive assortative matching. Neither changes in the wage distributions nor educational attainments can explain the large decline in marriage rates over this period.</description><author>Cornelson, Kirsten; Siow, Aloysius</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Organizations Fail: Models and Cases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garicano, Luis; Rayo, Luis
Organizations fail due to incentive problems (agents do not want to act in the organization's interests) and bounded rationality problems (agents do not have the necessary information to do so). This survey uses recent advances in organizational economics to illuminate organizational failures along these two dimensions. We combine reviews of the literature with simple models and case discussions. Specifically, we consider failures related to short-termism and the allocation of authority, both of which are instances of "multitasking problems"; communication failures in the presence of both soft and hard information due to incentive misalignments; resistance to change due to vested interests and rigid cultures; and failures related to the allocation of talent and miscommunication due to bounded rationality. We find that the organizational economics literature provides parsimonious explanations for a large range of economically significant failures.</description><author>Garicano, Luis; Rayo, Luis</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Would You Like to Pay? How Technology Is Changing the Future of Money</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angel, James J.
nan</description><author>Angel, James J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Review Essay on British Economic Growth, 1270-1870 by Stephen Broadberry, Bruce M. S. Campbell, Alexander Klein, Mark Overton, and Bas van Leeuwen</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williamson, Jeffrey G.
British Economic Growth, 1270-1870 makes a big leap forward in our understanding of the long-run performance of what became the leading nineteenth-century economy and the workshop of the world. It does so by implementing a giant quantitative enterprise, one that will make it the standard data source for studying the evolution of the British economy for decades to come.</description><author>Williamson, Jeffrey G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did Science Cause the Industrial Revolution?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grada, Cormac O.
The role of science and technology in the First Industrial Revolution is still contested. Some scholars, focusing on the textiles sector, argue that skilled and talented artisans with no scientific training were mainly responsible for the key inventions; others, with steam power in mind, hold that the links between science and the crucial inventions of the period were fundamental. Margaret Jacob has been a leading contributor to the debate for nearly four decades. The publication of her The First Knowledge Economy offers an opportunity to review the issues.</description><author>Grada, Cormac O.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Review of Cultural Evolution: Society, Technology, Language, and Religion Edited by Peter J. Richerson and Morten H. Christiansen</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giuliano, Paola
Peter J. Richerson and Morten H. Christiansen have assembled a compelling picture of the evolution of societies, technology, language, and religion-with culture at the epicenter. The book is a must-have for economists and any other social scientists interested in the evolution of behavior. Using the book as a starting point, this article sums up what cultural evolution can teach us about these four major aspects of human behavior. Each topic is also linked to the relevant empirical research in economics. Directions for future research integrating cultural evolution into an economic framework are also explored.</description><author>Giuliano, Paola</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Complexity and Economic Policy: A Paradigm Shift or a Change in Perspective? A Review Essay on David Colander and Roland Kupers's Complexity and the Art of Public Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kirman, Alan
In their recent book, Colander and Kupers (2014) argue that viewing the economy as a complex adaptive system should change the way in which we make economic policy. This would necessitate a paradigm shift. Economics has, over time, tried to produce a coherent model to underpin the dominant laissez-faire liberal approach. But we have never proved, in that model, that left to their own devices, the participants in an economy will self-organize into a satisfactory state. This is an assumption. Complex interactive systems with direct interaction between heterogeneous agents may show no tendency to self-equilibrate and will undergo endogenous crises. Economists should concentrate on the emergence of certain patterns. Colander and Kupers suggest that we may be able to nudge the system into "good" basins of attraction. A more radical view is that there are no fixed basins of attraction; these change with the evolution of the system and it is illusory to believe that we can choose good basins. We may be able to recognize and influence the emergence of certain states of the economy, but we are far from Leon Walras's dream of economics as a science like astrophysics.</description><author>Kirman, Alan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review Essay on GDP: A Brief but Affectionate History by Diane Coyle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Syrquin, Moshe
GDP, the most fundamental concept of aggregate economics, is often misunderstood and misused. In a brief book, Diane Coyle attempts to demystify and clarify the concept by providing what she calls "an affectionate history." The product is a lucid and clear presentation that however must come with a caution sign. The story is often incomplete, and what it does contain is not always accurate. Among the salient and controversial topics discussed are the adequacy of GDP for the twenty-first century, the deficiencies of GDP as a measure of welfare, and the strange way in which banking services are calculated.</description><author>Syrquin, Moshe</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Introduction to the Theory of Mechanism Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diamantaras, Dimitrios
nan</description><author>Diamantaras, Dimitrios</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Economist in the Real World: The Art of Policymaking in India</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jayaraman, Rajshri
nan</description><author>Jayaraman, Rajshri</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Production: Firms, Contracts, and Trade Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rauch, James
nan</description><author>Rauch, James</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Guild-Ridden Labor Markets: The Curious Case of Occupational Licensing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allensworth, Rebecca
nan</description><author>Allensworth, Rebecca</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Future of Law and Economics: Essays in Reform and Recollection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Posner, Eric
nan</description><author>Posner, Eric</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Routledge Handbook of Major Events in Economic History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jaremski, Matthew
nan</description><author>Jaremski, Matthew</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond the Tragedy in Global Fisheries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hannesson, Rognvaldur
nan</description><author>Hannesson, Rognvaldur</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The New Economics of Religion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iyer, Sriya
The economics of religion is a relatively new field of research in economics. This survey serves two purposes-it is backward-looking in that it traces the historical and sociological origins of this field, and it is forward-looking in that it examines the insights and research themes that are offered by economists to investigate religion globally in the modern world. Several factors have influenced the economics of religion: (1) new developments in theoretical models including spatial models of religious markets and evolutionary models of religious traits; (2) empirical work that addresses innovatively econometric identification in examining causal influences on religious behavior; (3) new research in the economic history of religion that considers religion as an independent, rather than a dependent, variable; and (4) more studies of religion outside the Western world. Based on these developments, this paper discusses four themes-first, secularization, pluralism, regulation, and economic growth; second, religious markets, club goods, differentiated products, and networks; third, identification including secular competition and charitable giving; and fourth, conflict and cooperation in developing societies. In reviewing this paradoxically ancient yet burgeoning field, this paper puts forward unanswered questions for scholars of the economics of religion to reflect upon in years to come.</description><author>Iyer, Sriya</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Privacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acquisti, Alessandro; Taylor, Curtis; Wagman, Liad
This article summarizes and draws connections among diverse streams of theoretical and empirical research on the economics of privacy. We focus on the economic value and consequences of protecting and disclosing personal information, and on consumers' understanding and decisions regarding the trade-offs associated with the privacy and the sharing of personal data. We highlight how the economic analysis of privacy evolved over time, as advancements in information technology raised increasingly nuanced and complex issues. We find and highlight three themes that connect diverse insights from the literature. First, characterizing a single unifying economic theory of privacy is hard, because privacy issues of economic relevance arise in widely diverse contexts. Second, there are theoretical and empirical situations where the protection of privacy can both enhance and detract from individual and societal welfare. Third, in digital economies, consumers' ability to make informed decisions about their privacy is severely hindered because consumers are often in a position of imperfect or asymmetric information regarding when their data is collected, for what purposes, and with what consequences. We conclude the article by highlighting some of the ongoing issues in the privacy debate of interest to economists.</description><author>Acquisti, Alessandro; Taylor, Curtis; Wagman, Liad</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Politics of Financial Development: A Review of Calomiris and Haber's Fragile by Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rousseau, Peter L.
Fragile by Design by Charles W. Calomiris and Stephen H. Haber introduces a framework for understanding financial crises and credit abundance with politics at its center. Using the historical experiences of five nations to illustrate, the authors propose that democracies such as the United States and Canada can have stable banks and ample credit so long as populist forces do not dominate the policy agenda, and that strong autocratic states such as Mexico can also achieve stability at the cost of restricting credit. Weak autocracies, such as Brazil over much of its history, often require inflationary finance and suffer from the banking fragility that comes with it. The authors identify populist ideologies and related policy decisions (such as unit banking, deposit insurance, and the Community Reinvestment Act) as underlying causes of banking instability in the United States as typified by the recent subprime crisis. Canada, in contrast, by holding populist forces in check through calculated political choices, remains crisis-free.</description><author>Rousseau, Peter L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arthur Cecil Pigou</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Takami, Norikazu
nan</description><author>Takami, Norikazu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Minsky Matters: An Introduction to the Work of a Maverick Economist</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sawyer, Malcolm
nan</description><author>Sawyer, Malcolm</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Rise of the Value-Added Tax</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gordon, Roger H.
nan</description><author>Gordon, Roger H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Japan's Industrious Revolution: Economic and Social Transformations in the Early Modern Period</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mosk, Carl
nan</description><author>Mosk, Carl</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Characterological Imperative: On Heckman, Humphries, and Kautz's The Myth of Achievement Tests: The GED and the Role of Character in American Life</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sampson, Robert J.
James J. Heckman, John Eric Humphries, and Tim Kautz make a powerful case for noncognitive skills-or what they conceptualize as character-as an explanation of educational achievement and other important outcomes in life. They do so while exposing the myth of the GED, arguing that the GED harms its intended beneficiaries by failing to instill the character skills that predict adult success. Childhood interventions to build personal character, especially self-control, are emphasized. The Myth of Achievement Tests is a major contribution, but I integrate relevant research on crime and social control across the life course that motivates a more dynamic conceptualization of character. I also review evidence on the environment as a source of both cognitive and noncognitive skills, including exposure to concentrated deprivation, violence, and lead toxicity. Moreover, I review evidence suggesting that social reactions to character shape life chances in ways not reducible to individual propensities, such as changes in criminal-justice policy that created large cohort differentials in incarceration for the same underlying behaviors. Social context and the character of American society itself are thus central to fostering individual character-not just skills but the desire to conform. It follows that self-control and social control need to be better unified theoretically and in designing interventions.</description><author>Sampson, Robert J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coming of Age in the Other America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cano-Urbina, Javier
nan</description><author>Cano-Urbina, Javier</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the WTO Passe?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bagwell, Kyle; Bown, Chad P.; Staiger, Robert W.
The WTO has delivered policy outcomes that are very different from those likely to emerge out of the recent wave of preferential trade agreements (PTAs). Should economists see this as an efficient institutional hand-off, where the WTO has carried trade liberalization as far as it can manage, and is now passing the baton to PTAs to finish the job? We survey a growing economics literature on international trade agreements and argue on this basis that the WTO is not passe. Rather, and subject to some caveats, our survey of research to date suggests that the WTO warrants strong support while a more cautious view of PTAs seems appropriate.</description><author>Bagwell, Kyle; Bown, Chad P.; Staiger, Robert W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive Compensation: A Modern Primer</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Gabaix, Xavier
This article studies traditional and modern theories of executive compensation, bringing them together under a simple unifying framework accessible to the general-interest reader. We analyze assignment models of the level of pay, and static and dynamic moral-hazard models of incentives, and compare their predictions to empirical findings. We make two broad points. First, traditional theories find it difficult to explain the data, suggesting that compensation results from "rent extraction" by CEOs. However, more modern "shareholder value" theories, that arguably better capture the CEO setting, do deliver predictions consistent with observed practices, suggesting that these practices need not be inefficient. Second, seemingly innocuous features of the modeling setup, often made for tractability or convenience, can lead to significant differences in the model's implications and conclusions on the efficiency of observed practices. We close by highlighting apparent inefficiencies in executive compensation and additional directions for future research.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Gabaix, Xavier</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equality of Opportunity: Theory and Measurement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roemer, John E.; Trannoy, Alain
During the last third of the twentieth century, political philosophers actively debated about the content of distributive justice; the ruling ethical view of utilitarianism was challenged by various versions of equality of opportunities. Economists formulated several ways of modeling these ideas, focusing upon how individuals are placed with respect to opportunities for achieving various outcomes, and what compensation is due to individuals with truncated opportunities. After presenting a review of the main philosophical ideas (section 2), we turn to economic models (sections 3 and 4). We propose a reformulation of the definition of economic development, replacing the utilitarian measure of GDP per capita with a measure of the degree to which opportunities for income acquisition in a nation have been equalized. Finally, we discuss issues that the econometrician faces in measuring inequality of opportunity, briefly review the empirical literature (section 6), and conclude (section 7).</description><author>Roemer, John E.; Trannoy, Alain</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Immigration Economics by George J. Borjas: A Review Essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Card, David; Peri, Giovanni
We review Immigration Economics by George J. Borjas, published in 2014 by Harvard University Press. The book is written as a graduate-level textbook, and summarizes and updates many of Borjas's important contributions to the field over the past thirty years. A key message of the book is that immigration poses significant costs to many members of the host-country labor market. Though the theoretical and econometric approaches presented in the book will be very useful for students and specialists in the field, we argue that the book presents a one-sided view of immigration, with little or no attention to the growing body of work that offers a more nuanced picture of how immigrants fit into the host-country market and affect native workers.</description><author>Card, David; Peri, Giovanni</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Crisis in Economic Theory: A Review Essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoover, Kevin D.
The Great Recession and the financial crisis of 2007-09 prompted calls for fundamental reforms of economic theory. The role of theory in economics and in recent economic events is considered in light of two recent books: the sociologist Richard Swedberg's The Art of Social Theory and the economist Andre Orlean's The Empire of Value: A New Foundation for Economics.</description><author>Hoover, Kevin D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Male Is a Gender, Too: A Review of Why Gender Matters in Economics by Mukesh Eswaran</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nelson, Julie A.
Mukesh Eswaran's Why Gender Matters in Economics presents a generally well-researched review of the literature on women and economics, and admirably attempts take a global perspective. Eswaran's analysis is compromised, however, by an unreflective use of perspectives and methods that themselves, when seen in a broader perspective, reflect gendered biases. With particular reference to Eswaran's discussions of gender differences in preferences, the preferential treatment of groups, and work/family issues, this essay outlines how these biases arise, and how economic analysis must change if it is to become more rigorous.</description><author>Nelson, Julie A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The German Historical School and European Economic Thought</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schefold, Bertram
nan</description><author>Schefold, Bertram</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editor's Note: Guidelines for Selecting Books to Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prisoners of Reason: Game Theory and Neoliberal Political Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heap, Shaun Hargreaves
nan</description><author>Heap, Shaun Hargreaves</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agent-Based Computational Economics: How the Idea Originated and Where It Is Going</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tesfatsion, Leigh
nan</description><author>Tesfatsion, Leigh</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>