<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JEL2</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>The Quest for Prosperity: How Developing Economies Can Take Off</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ranis, Gustav
nan</description><author>Ranis, Gustav</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Capitalism for the People: Recapturing the Lost Genius of American Prosperity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>MacCulloch, Robert J.
nan</description><author>MacCulloch, Robert J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US High School Graduation Rates: Patterns and Explanations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murnane, Richard J.
I survey the evidence on patterns in U. S. high school graduation rates over the period 1970-2010 and report the results of new research conducted to fill in holes in the evidence. I begin by pointing out the strengths and limitations of existing data sources. I then describe six striking patterns in graduation rates. They include stagnation over the last three decades of the twentieth century, significant race-, income-, and gender-based gaps, and significant increases in graduation rates over the first decade of the twenty-first century, especially among blacks and Hispanics. I then describe the models economists use to explain the decisions of individuals to invest in schooling, and examine the extent to which the parameters of the models explain recent patterns in graduation rates. I find that increases in the nonmonetary costs of completing high school and the increasing availability of the GED credential help to explain stagnation in the face of substantial gaps between the wages of high school graduates and school dropouts. I point out that there are several hypotheses, but to date, very little evidence to explain the increases in high school graduation rates over the first decade of the twenty-first century. I conclude by reviewing the evidence on effective strategies to increase high school graduation rates, and explaining why the causal evidence is quite modest.</description><author>Murnane, Richard J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Chosen Few: How Education Shaped Jewish History, 70-1492</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Temin, Peter
nan</description><author>Temin, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Patenting of Pharmaceuticals and Development in Sub-Saharan Africa: Laws, Institutions, Practices, and Politics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nattrass, Nicoli
nan</description><author>Nattrass, Nicoli</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Producing Prosperity: Why America Needs a Manufacturing Renaissance.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branstetter, Lee G.
nan</description><author>Branstetter, Lee G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demystifying the Chinese Economy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleisher, Belton M.
nan</description><author>Fleisher, Belton M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capitalizing on Nature: Ecosystems as Natural Assets.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fenichel, Eli P.
nan</description><author>Fenichel, Eli P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using Marginal Damages in Environmental Policy: A Study of Air Pollution in the United States.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fraas, Art; Lutter, Randall
nan</description><author>Fraas, Art; Lutter, Randall</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Climate Change and Common Sense: Essays in Honour of Tom Schelling.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Auffhammer, Maximilian
nan</description><author>Auffhammer, Maximilian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Golf by the Numbers.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moore, Michael J.
nan</description><author>Moore, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Building Resilience: Social Capital in Post-Disaster Recovery.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Torgler, Benno
nan</description><author>Torgler, Benno</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Deep Are the Roots of Economic Development?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spolaore, Enrico; Wacziarg, Romain
The empirical literature on economic growth and development has moved from the study of proximate determinants to the analysis of ever deeper, more fundamental factors, rooted in long-term history. A growing body of new empirical work focuses on the measurement and estimation of the effects of historical variables on contemporary income by explicitly taking into account the ancestral composition of current populations. The evidence suggests that economic development is affected by traits that have been transmitted across generations over the very long run. This article surveys this new literature and provides a framework to discuss different channels through which intergenerationally transmitted characteristics may impact economic development, biologically (via genetic or epigenetic transmission) and culturally (via behavioral or symbolic transmission). An important issue is whether historically transmitted traits have affected development through their direct impact on productivity, or have operated indirectly as barriers to the diffusion of productivity-enhancing innovations across populations.</description><author>Spolaore, Enrico; Wacziarg, Romain</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seeds, Science, and Struggle: The Global Politics of Transgenic Crops</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parthasarathy, Shobita
nan</description><author>Parthasarathy, Shobita</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Minimum Wage and Labor Market Outcomes.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wasmer, Etienne
nan</description><author>Wasmer, Etienne</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural Models of Nonequilibrium Strategic Thinking: Theory, Evidence, and Applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crawford, Vincent P.; Costa-Gomes, Miguel A.; Iriberri, Nagore
Most applications of game theory assume equilibrium, justified by presuming either that learning will have converged to one, or that equilibrium approximates people's strategic thinking even when a learning justification is implausible. Yet several recent experimental and empirical studies suggest that people's initial responses to games often deviate systematically from equilibrium, and that structural nonequilibrium "level-k" or "cognitive hierarchy" models often out-predict equilibrium. Even when learning is possible and converges to equilibrium, such models allow better predictions of history-dependent limiting outcomes. This paper surveys recent theory and evidence on strategic thinking and illustrates the applications of level-k models in economics. (JEL C70, D03, D82, D83)</description><author>Crawford, Vincent P.; Costa-Gomes, Miguel A.; Iriberri, Nagore</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home Bias in Open Economy Financial Macroeconomics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coeurdacier, Nicolas; Rey, Helene
Home bias is a perennial feature of international capital markets. We review various explanations of this puzzling phenomenon highlighting recent developments in macroeconomic modeling that incorporate international portfolio choices in standard two-country general equilibrium models. We refer to this new literature as Open Economy Financial Macroeconomics. We focus on three broad classes of explanations: (i) hedging motives in frictionless financial markets (real exchange rate and nontradable income risk), (ii) asset trade costs in international financial markets (such as transaction costs or differences in tax treatments between national and foreign assets), and (iii) informational frictions and behavioral biases. Recent theories call for new portfolio facts beyond equity home bias. We present new evidence on cross-border asset holdings across different types of assets: equities, bonds and bank lending and new micro data on institutional holdings of equity at the fund level. These data should inform macroeconomic modeling of the open economy and a growing literature of models of delegated investment. (JEL E13, F41, G11, G12, G15)</description><author>Coeurdacier, Nicolas; Rey, Helene</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Economics: A Review of Why Nations Fail by D. Acemoglu and J. Robinson and Pillars of Prosperity by T. Besley and T. Persson</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>MacLeod, W. Bentley
The purpose of this essay is to review the books Why Nations Fail by Daron Acemoglu and James Robinson, and Pillars of Prosperity by Timothy Besley and Torsten Persson. The essay briefly discusses the main contributions of the books and the role of politics for economic performance. The review then discusses these contributions in the light of recent research on organizational economics, particularly the modern theory of the firm. (JEL D23, D72, O10, O47, O57)</description><author>MacLeod, W. Bentley</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Odd Couple: International Trade and Labor Standards in History.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Drusilla
nan</description><author>Brown, Drusilla</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>America's Economic Way of War: War and the US Economy from the Spanish-American War to the Persian Gulf War.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Janssen, Volker
nan</description><author>Janssen, Volker</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The New Economics of Equilibrium Sorting and Policy Evaluation Using Housing Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuminoff, Nicolai V.; Smith, V. Kerry; Timmins, Christopher
Households "sort" across neighborhoods according to their wealth and their preferences for public goods, social characteristics, and commuting opportunities. The aggregation of these individual choices in markets and in other institutions influences the supply of amenities and local public goods. Pollution, congestion, and the quality of public education are examples. Over the past decade, advances in economic models of this sorting process have led to a new framework that promises to alter the ways we conceptualize the policy evaluation process in the future. These "equilibrium sorting" models use the properties of market equilibria, together with information on household behavior, to infer structural parameters that characterize preference heterogeneity. The results can be used to develop theoretically consistent predictions for the welfare implications of future policy changes. Analysis is not confined to marginal effects or a partial equilibrium setting. Nor is it limited to prices and quantities. Sorting models can integrate descriptions of how nonmarket goods are generated, estimate how they affect decision making, and, in turn, predict how they will be affected by future policies targeting prices or quantities. Conversely, sorting models can predict how equilibrium prices and quantities will be affected by policies that target product quality, information, or amenities generated by the sorting process. These capabilities are just beginning to be understood and used in applied research. This survey article aims to synthesize the state of knowledge on equilibrium sorting, the new possibilities for policy analysis, and the conceptual and empirical challenges that define the frontiers of the literature.</description><author>Kuminoff, Nicolai V.; Smith, V. Kerry; Timmins, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Facts and Challenges from the Great Recession for Forecasting and Macroeconomic Modeling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ng, Serena; Wright, Jonathan H.
This paper provides a survey of business cycle facts, updated to take account of recent data. Emphasis is given to the Great Recession, which was unlike most other postwar recessions in the United States in being driven by deleveraging and financial market factors. We document how recessions with financial market origins are different from those driven by supply or monetary policy shocks. This helps explain why economic models and predictors that work well at some times do poorly at other times. We discuss challenges for forecasters and empirical researchers in light of the updated business cycle facts.</description><author>Ng, Serena; Wright, Jonathan H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Is Wrong with Islamic Economics? Analysing the Present State and Future Agenda.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>El-Gamal, Mahmoud
nan</description><author>El-Gamal, Mahmoud</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Worldly Philosopher: The Odyssey of Albert O. Hirschman.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McPherson, Michael
nan</description><author>McPherson, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jane Austen, Game Theorist.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Terasvirta, Timo
nan</description><author>Terasvirta, Timo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavioural Economics and Finance.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shogren, Jason F.
nan</description><author>Shogren, Jason F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Redistribution Recession: How Labor Market Distortions Contracted the Economy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foote, Christopher L.
nan</description><author>Foote, Christopher L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Islamic Finance in Europe: Towards a Plural Financial System.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wilson, Rodney
nan</description><author>Wilson, Rodney</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes in America: What Everyone Needs to Know.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cullen, Julie Berry
nan</description><author>Cullen, Julie Berry</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining Long-Term Trends in Health and Longevity.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Costa, Dora L.
nan</description><author>Costa, Dora L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Fracturing of the American Corporate Elite.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Palmer, Donald
nan</description><author>Palmer, Donald</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reforms and Economic Transformation in India.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dhingra, Swati
nan</description><author>Dhingra, Swati</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Growth Spiral: Money, Energy, and Imagination in the Dynamics of the Market Process.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perla, Jesse
nan</description><author>Perla, Jesse</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Rights and Public Problems: The Global Economics of Intellectual Property in the 21st Century.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Albert G.
nan</description><author>Hu, Albert G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange Rate Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rossi, Barbara
The main goal of this article is to provide an answer to the question: does anything forecast exchange rates, and if so, which variables? It is well known that exchange rate fluctuations are very difficult to predict using economic models, and that a random walk forecasts exchange rates better than any economic model (the Meese and Rogoff puzzle). However, the recent literature has identified a series of fundamentals/methodologies that claim to have resolved the puzzle. This article provides a critical review of the recent literature on exchange rate forecasting and illustrates the new methodologies and fundamentals that have been recently proposed in an up-to-date, thorough empirical analysis. Overall, our analysis of the literature and the data suggests that the answer to the question: "Are exchange rates predictable?" is, "It depends"-on the choice of predictor, forecast horizon, sample period, model, and forecast evaluation method. Predictability is most apparent when one or more of the following hold: the predictors are Taylor rule or net foreign assets, the model is linear, and a small number of parameters are estimated. The toughest benchmark is the random walk without drift.</description><author>Rossi, Barbara</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review Essay about Foundations of Neuroeconomic Analysis by Paul Glimcher</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Camerer, Colin F.
Neuroeconomics aims to discover mechanisms of economic decision, and express them mathematically, to predict observed choice. While the contents of neuroeconomic models and evidence are obviously different than in traditional economics, (some of the) goals are identical: to explain and predict choice, the effects of comparative statics, and perhaps make interesting new welfare judgments that are defensible. To this end, Paul Glimcher's important book carefully describes how economics, psychological, and neural levels of explanation can be linked (a structure which has been successful in visual neuroscience). As Glimcher shows, the neural evidence is quite strong for a process of learning valuations through prediction error, and a simple model of neural valuation and comparison that corresponds to random utility (though subject to normalization, which produces menu effects). There is also rapidly growing evidence for more complicated constructs in behavioral economics, including prospect theory's account of risky choice, hyperbolic time discounting, level-k models of games, and social preferences corresponding to internal reward based on what happens to other agents.</description><author>Camerer, Colin F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Enrico Moretti's The New Geography of Jobs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glaeser, Edward
Why is prosperity distributed so unevenly across America's metropolitan areas? While population growth has gone disproportionately towards the Sunbelt, high-skill areas have experienced the strongest income growth since 1970. Gaps between more and less educated areas were modest forty years ago, but they have become quite large, and far larger than would be predicted solely by the general rise in the returns to skill. Unemployment rates during the recent recession were also strongly correlated with area level education. This essay reviews Enrico Moretti's The New Geography of Jobs, which both describes and explains these significant regional trends.</description><author>Glaeser, Edward</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and the Good Society.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bronchetti, Erin Todd
nan</description><author>Bronchetti, Erin Todd</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tail-Hedge Discounting and the Social Cost of Carbon</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weitzman, Martin L.
The choice of an overall discount rate for climate change investments depends critically on how different components of investment payoffs are discounted at differing rates reflecting their underlying risk characteristics. Such underlying rates can vary enormously, from. approximate to 1 percent for idiosyncratic diversifiable risk to. approximate to 7 percent for systematic nondiversifiable risk. Which risk-adjusted rate is chosen can have a huge impact on cost-benefit analysis. In this expository paper, I attempt to set forth in accessible language with a simple linear model what I think are some of the basic issues involved in discounting climate risks. The paper introduces a new concept that may be relevant for climate-change discounting: the degree to which an investment hedges against the bad tail of catastrophic damages by insuring positive expected payoffs even under the worst circumstances. The prototype application is calculating the social cost of carbon.</description><author>Weitzman, Martin L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Economy of Public Policies: Insights from Distortions to Agricultural and Food Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Kym; Rausser, Gordon; Swinnen, Johan
The agricultural and food sector is an ideal case for investigating the political economy of public policies. Many of the policy developments in this sector since the 1950s have been sudden and transformational, while others have been gradual but persistent. This article reviews and synthesizes the literature on trends and fluctuations in market distortions and the political-economy explanations that have been advanced. Based on a rich global data set covering a half-century of evidence on commodities, countries, and policy instruments, we identify hypotheses that have been explored in the literature on the extent of market distortions and the conditions under which reform may be feasible.</description><author>Anderson, Kym; Rausser, Gordon; Swinnen, Johan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's the Good of the Market? An Essay on Michael Sandel's What Money Can't Buy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Besley, Timothy
This essay will discuss the criticisms of the economic approach to markets offered by Michael Sandel's What Money Can't Buy. After reviewing the main arguments, the essay looks at these from three main angles. First, it relates them to different traditions of thinking about markets and their achievements that have been developed by economists. Second, it discusses the idea that markets can change values as argued by Sandel in light of recent related literature in economics. Third, it discusses some of the literature on alternatives to using the market to allocate resources and the pros and cons of these.</description><author>Besley, Timothy</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bounded-Rationality Models: Tasks to Become Intellectually Competitive</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harstad, Ronald M.; Selten, Reinhard
Research in experimental economics has cogently challenged the fundamental precept of neoclassical economics that economic agents optimize. The last two decades have seen elaboration of boundedly rational models that try to move away from the optimization approach, in ways consistent with experimental findings. Nonetheless, the collection of alternative models has made little headway supplanting the dominant paradigm. We delineate key ways in which neoclassical microeconomics holds continuing and compelling advantages over bounded-rationality models, and suggest, via a few examples, the sorts of further, difficult pushes that would be needed to redress this state of affairs. Closer collaboration between theoretic modeling and experiments is clearly seen to be necessary.</description><author>Harstad, Ronald M.; Selten, Reinhard</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Boundedly Rational versus Optimization-Based Models of Strategic Thinking and Learning in Games</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crawford, Vincent P.
Harstad and Selten's article in this forum performs a valuable service by highlighting the dominance of optimization-based models over boundedly rational models in modern microeconomics, and questioning whether optimization-based models are a better way forward than boundedly rational models. This article complements Rabin's response to Harstad and Selten, focusing on modeling strategic behavior. I consider Harstad and Selten's examples and proposed boundedly rational models in the light of modern behavioral economics and behavioral game theory, commenting on the challenges that remain and the most promising ways forward.</description><author>Crawford, Vincent P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incorporating Limited Rationality into Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rabin, Matthew
Harstad and Selten (this forum) raise interesting questions about the relative promise of optimization models and bounded-rationality models in making progress in economics. This article builds from their analysis by indicating the potential for using neoclassical (broadly defined) optimization models to integrate insights from psychology on the limits to rationality into economics. I lay out an approach to making (imperfect and incremental) improvements over previous economic theory by incorporating greater realism while attempting to maintain the breadth of application, the precision of predictions, and the insights of neoclassical theory. I then discuss how many human limits to full rationality are, in fact, well understood in terms of optimization.</description><author>Rabin, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No Slack: The Financial Lives of Low-Income Americans.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elliehausen, Gregory
nan</description><author>Elliehausen, Gregory</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Japan's Great Stagnation: Forging Ahead, Falling Behind.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoshi, Takeo
nan</description><author>Hoshi, Takeo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making the European Monetary Union: The Role of the Committee of Central Bank Governors and the Origins of the European Central Bank.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gros, Daniel
nan</description><author>Gros, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Votes, Vetoes, and the Political Economy of International Trade Agreements.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishna, Pravin
nan</description><author>Krishna, Pravin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Macroeconomic Theory of Exchange Rate Crises.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaminsky, Graciela Laura
nan</description><author>Kaminsky, Graciela Laura</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Great Persuasion: Reinventing Free Markets since the Depression.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Telser, Lester G.
nan</description><author>Telser, Lester G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Arithmetic: Simon Kuznets and the Empirical Tradition in Economics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Backhouse, Roger E.
nan</description><author>Backhouse, Roger E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Information Theoretic Approach to Econometrics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Byoung Gun
nan</description><author>Park, Byoung Gun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lectures on Behavioral Macroeconomics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gatti, Domenico Delli
nan</description><author>Gatti, Domenico Delli</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Devaluing to Prosperity: Misaligned Currencies and Their Growth Consequences.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dooley, Michael P.
nan</description><author>Dooley, Michael P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public Capital, Growth and Welfare: Analytical Foundations for Public Policy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kessides, Ioannis N.
nan</description><author>Kessides, Ioannis N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing the Planet's Future: The Economics of Discounting in an Uncertain World.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Groom, Ben
nan</description><author>Groom, Ben</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Foundations of International Law.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hadfield, Gillian K.
nan</description><author>Hadfield, Gillian K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Russia: A Long View.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsyvinski, Aleh
nan</description><author>Tsyvinski, Aleh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wall Street: A History.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kirshner, Jonathan
nan</description><author>Kirshner, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Founders and Finance: How Hamilton, Gallatin, and Other Immigrants Forged a New Economy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vietor, Richard H. K.
nan</description><author>Vietor, Richard H. K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Australia Prospered: The Shifting Sources of Economic Growth.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leigh, Andrew
nan</description><author>Leigh, Andrew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sharing the Prize: The Economics of the Civil Rights Revolution in the American South.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collins, William J.
nan</description><author>Collins, William J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From Miracle to Maturity: The Growth of the Korean Economy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rhee, Changyong
nan</description><author>Rhee, Changyong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good Green Jobs in a Global Economy: Making and Keeping New Industries in the United States.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levinson, Marc
nan</description><author>Levinson, Marc</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Environment, Health, and Human Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zivin, Joshua Graff; Neidell, Matthew
In this review, we discuss three major contributions economists have made to our understanding of the relationship between the environment and individual well-being. First, in explicitly recognizing how optimizing behavior, particularly in the form of residential sorting, can lead to nonrandom assignment of pollution, economists have employed a wide range of quasi-experimental techniques to develop causal estimates of the effect of pollution. Second, economic research has placed a considerable focus on the role of avoidance behavior, which is an important component for understanding the difference between biological and behavioral effects of pollution and for proper welfare calculations. Lastly, economic research has expanded the focus of analysis beyond traditional health outcomes to include measures of human capital, including labor supply, productivity, and cognition. Our review of the quasi-experimental evidence on this topic suggests that pollution does indeed have a wide range of effects on individual well-being, even at levels well below current regulatory standards. Given the importance of health and human capital as an engine for economic growth, these findings underscore the role of environmental conditions as an important factor of production.</description><author>Zivin, Joshua Graff; Neidell, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding China's Urban Pollution Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zheng, Siqi; Kahn, Matthew E.
China's ongoing urban economic growth has sharply increased the population's per capita income, lowered the count of people living below the poverty line, and caused major environmental problems. We survey the growing literature investigating the causes and consequences of China's urban pollution challenges. We begin by studying how urban population and industrial growth impacts local pollution levels and greenhouse gas production. As the urban population grows richer, its demand for private transportation and electricity sharply increases. Such privately beneficial activity exacerbates urban pollution externalities. Facing these severe environmental challenges, China's urbanites increasingly demand quality of life progress. We survey the emerging literature investigating the demand for environmental progress in China. Progress in mitigating externalities hinges on whether the powerful central and local governments choose to address these issues. We analyze the political economy of whether government officials have strong incentives to tackle lingering urban externalities. We conclude by discussing future research opportunities at the intersection of environmental and urban economics.</description><author>Zheng, Siqi; Kahn, Matthew E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Performance of the US Transportation System: Caution Ahead</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Winston, Clifford
Transportation is a vital sector of the U.S. economy based on consumers', firms', and government's enormous expenditures in money and time and on its effect on virtually all other sectors in the economy. I assess the performance of the transportation system and consider how it could be improved by analyzing whether the United States has the optimal mix of public and private provision. The empirical evidence indicates that our hugely important transportation system has been compromised by various government policies and the significant welfare costs motivate either vastly improving public provision or expanding the role of the private sector.</description><author>Winston, Clifford</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Structure of Economic Modeling of the Potential Impacts of Climate Change: Grafting Gross Underestimation of Risk onto Already Narrow Science Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stern, Nicholas
Scientists describe the scale of the risks from unmanaged climate change as potentially immense. However, the scientific models, because they omit key factors that are hard to capture precisely, appear to substantially underestimate these risks. Many economic models add further gross underassessment of risk because the assumptions built into the economic modeling on growth, damages and risks, come close to assuming directly that the impacts and costs will be modest and close to excluding the possibility of catastrophic outcomes. A new generation of models is needed in all three of climate science, impact and economics with a still stronger focus on lives and livelihoods, including the risks of large-scale migration and conflicts.</description><author>Stern, Nicholas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Climate Change Policy: What Do the Models Tell Us?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pindyck, Robert S.
Very little. A plethora of integrated assessment models (IAMs) have been constructed and used to estimate the social cost of carbon (SCC) and evaluate alternative abatement policies. These models have crucial flaws that make them close to useless as tools for policy analysis: certain inputs (e. g., the discount rate) are arbitrary, but have huge effects on the SCC estimates the models produce; the models' descriptions of the impact of climate change are completely ad hoc, with no theoretical or empirical foundation; and the models can tell us nothing about the most important driver of the SCC, the possibility of a catastrophic climate outcome. IAM-based analyses of climate policy create a perception of knowledge and precision, but that perception is illusory and misleading.</description><author>Pindyck, Robert S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange-Rate Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lyons, Richard K.
nan</description><author>Lyons, Richard K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectations, Employment and Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pintus, Patrick
nan</description><author>Pintus, Patrick</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Keynes: The Return of the Master</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Lance
nan</description><author>Taylor, Lance</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding Global Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feenstra, Robert C.
nan</description><author>Feenstra, Robert C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adapt: Why Success Always Starts with Failure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Audretsch, David
nan</description><author>Audretsch, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review Essay on The Enlightened Economy: An Economic History of Britain 1700-1850 by Joel Mokyr</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clark, Gregory
The British Industrial Revolution is the key break in world history. Yet the timing, location, and cause of this Revolution are unsolved puzzles. Joel Mokyr's book is one of a number of recent attempted solutions. He explains the Industrial Revolution through the arrival of a particular ideology in Britain, associated with the earlier European intellectual movement of the Enlightenment. This review considers how Mokyr's "idealist" approach fares as an account of the Industrial Revolution, compared to the spate of recent proposed "materialist" explanations. (JEL N13, N63)</description><author>Clark, Gregory</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Thinking Small: A Review of Poor Economics: A Radical Rethinking of the Way to Fight Global Poverty by Abhijit Banerjee and Esther Duflo</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosenzweig, Mark R.
In Poor Economics, Abhijit Banerjee and Esther Duflo eschew grand theorizing about poverty reduction in favor of an approach in which intelligently designed and tested small interventions, based on a scientific understanding of the lives of the poor, marginally improve their welfare. In so doing, they describe the findings from the recent large literature describing the behavior and institutions of the poor and the consequences of policy and experimental interventions targeted to poverty populations. In this review, I assess whether "thinking small" with its associated policy regime of transfers, subsidies, and nudges, is both a practical and effective policy prescription for "fighting" poverty and whether the set of studies that have focused on populations that have not escaped poverty has improved our fundamental understanding of both the consequences and causes of poverty. (JEL I32, I38, O15)</description><author>Rosenzweig, Mark R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fighting Poverty One Experiment at a Time: A Review of Abhijit Banerjee and Esther Duflo's Poor Economics: A Radical Rethinking of the Way to Fight Global Poverty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ravallion, Martin
Abhijit Banerjee and Esther Duflo offer a coherent vision for an economics of poverty and antipoverty policy. Their economics is grounded in an effort to understand the economic and psychological complexities in the lives of poor people, informed by social experiments and field observations. Their preferred policies entail small reforms at the margin, also informed by experiments-specifically randomized control trials. While the book provides some interesting insights, I question how far its approach will get us in fighting global poverty. (JEL I32, I38, O15, P36)</description><author>Ravallion, Martin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic History or History of Economics? A Review Essay on Sylvia Nasar's Grand Pursuit: The Story of Economic Genius</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ashenfelter, Orley
In this essay, I review Sylvia Nasar's long awaited new history of economics, Grand Pursuit: The Story of Economic Genius. I describe how the book is an economic history of the period 1850-1950, with distinguished economists' stories inserted in appropriate places. Nasar's goal is to show how economists work, but also to show that they are people too-with more than enough warts and foibles to show they are human! I contrast the general view of the role of economics in Grand Pursuit with Robert Heilbroner's remarkably different conception in The Worldly Philosophers: The Lives, Times, and Ideas of the Great Economic Thinkers. I also discuss more generally the question of why economists might be interested in their history at all. (JEL B10, B20, B30, N00)</description><author>Ashenfelter, Orley</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pandora's Risk: Uncertainty at the Core of Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roussanov, Nikolai
nan</description><author>Roussanov, Nikolai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Next Convergence: The Future of Economic Growth in a Multispeed World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Subramanian, Arvind
nan</description><author>Subramanian, Arvind</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Long Divergence: How Islamic Law Held Back the Middle East</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanna, Nelly
nan</description><author>Hanna, Nelly</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reconsidering Retirement: How Losses and Layoffs Affect Older Workers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stock, Wendy A.
nan</description><author>Stock, Wendy A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unified Growth Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dinopoulos, Elias
nan</description><author>Dinopoulos, Elias</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Climate Change: Adaptations Past and Present</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Swoboda, Aaron
nan</description><author>Swoboda, Aaron</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Political Economy of Agricultural Price Distortions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalambokidis, Laura
nan</description><author>Kalambokidis, Laura</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Decision to Patent</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Putnam, Jonathan D.
nan</description><author>Putnam, Jonathan D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade and Poverty: When the Third World Fell Behind</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitchener, Kris James
nan</description><author>Mitchener, Kris James</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where Are All the Good Jobs Going? What National and Local Job Quality and Dynamics Mean for U.S. Workers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Houseman, Susan
nan</description><author>Houseman, Susan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Evolution and Revolution in Historical Time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Steckel, Richard
nan</description><author>Steckel, Richard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Wall Street Met Main Street: The Quest for an Investors' Democracy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hausman, William J.
nan</description><author>Hausman, William J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Comingled Code: Open Source and Economic Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Krogh, Georg
nan</description><author>von Krogh, Georg</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hot Stove Economics: Understanding Baseball's Second Season</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sauer, Raymond D.
nan</description><author>Sauer, Raymond D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporations in Evolving Diversity: Cognition, Governance, and Institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, Martijn
nan</description><author>Cremers, Martijn</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unnatural Selection: Choosing Boys over Girls, and the Consequences of a World Full of Men</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edlund, Lena
nan</description><author>Edlund, Lena</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Advice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, Roman; Ottaviani, Marco
Financial advice could play an essential role in well-functioning markets for retail financial products, given that many consumers find it difficult to evaluate the complex products on offer. However, conflicts of interest, which are pervasive in some parts of the industry, can turn advice into a curse rather than a blessing for consumers, especially when consumers are not sufficiently wary. Through a simple model of financial advice, we overview the pros and cons of various policy interventions, such as imposing mandatory disclosure, banning commissions, and regulating contract cancellation terms.</description><author>Inderst, Roman; Ottaviani, Marco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Micro and Macro Labor Supply Elasticities: A Reassessment of Conventional Wisdom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keane, Michael; Rogerson, Richard
The response of aggregate labor supply to various changes in the economic environment is central to many economic issues, especially the optimal design of tax policies. Conventional wisdom based on studies in the 1980s and 1990s has long held that the analysis of micro data leads one to conclude that aggregate labor supply elasticities are quite small. In this paper we argue that this conventional wisdom does not hold up to empirically reasonable and relevant extensions of simple life cycle models that served as the basis for these conclusions. In particular, we show that several pieces of conventional wisdom fail in the presence of human capital accumulation or labor supply decisions that allow for adjustment along both the extensive and intensive margin. We conclude that previous estimates of small labor supply elasticities based on micro data are fully consistent with large aggregate labor supply elasticities.</description><author>Keane, Michael; Rogerson, Richard</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Does Human Capital Do? A Review of Goldin and Katz's The Race between Education and Technology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acemoglu, Daron; Autor, David
Goldin and Katz's The Race between Education and Technology is a monumental achievement that supplies a unified framework for interpreting how the demand and supply of human capital have shaped the distribution of earnings in the U.S. labor market over the twentieth century. This essay reviews the theoretical and conceptual underpinnings of this work and documents the success of Goldin and Katz's framework in accounting for numerous broad labor market trends. The essay also considers areas where the framework falls short in explaining several key labor market puzzles of recent decades and argues that these shortcomings can potentially be overcome by relaxing the implicit equivalence drawn between workers' skills and their job tasks in the conceptual framework on which Goldin and Katz build. The essay argues that allowing for a richer set of interactions between skills and technologies in accomplishing job tasks both augments and refines the predictions of Goldin and Katz's approach and suggests an even more important role for human capital in economic growth than indicated by their analysis.</description><author>Acemoglu, Daron; Autor, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Incentives and Social Preferences: Substitutes or Complements?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bowles, Samuel; Polania-Reyes, Sandra
Explicit economic incentives designed to increase contributions to public goods and to promote other pro-social behavior sometimes are counterproductive or less effective than would be predicted among entirely self-interested individuals. This may occur when incentives adversely affect individuals' altruism, ethical norms, intrinsic motives to serve the public, and other social preferences. The opposite also occurs-crowding in-though it appears less commonly. In the fifty experiments that we survey, these effects are common, so that incentives and social preferences may be either substitutes (crowding out) or complements (crowding in). We provide evidence for four mechanisms that may account for these incentive effects on preferences: namely that incentives may (i) provide information about the person who implemented the incentive, (ii) frame the decision situation so as to suggest appropriate behavior, (iii) compromise a control averse individual's sense of autonomy, and (iv) affect the process by which people learn new preferences. An implication is that the evaluation of public policy must be restricted to allocations that are supportable as Nash equilibria when account is taken of these crowding effects. We show that well designed fines, subsidies, and the like minimize crowding out and may even do the opposite, making incentives and social preferences complements rather than substitutes.</description><author>Bowles, Samuel; Polania-Reyes, Sandra</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reading About the Financial Crisis: A Twenty-One-Book Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lo, Andrew W.
The recent financial crisis has generated many distinct perspectives from various quarters. In this article, I review a diverse set of twenty-one books on the crisis, eleven written by academics, and ten written by journalists and one former Treasury Secretary. No single narrative emerges from this broad and often contradictory collection of interpretations, but the sheer variety of conclusions is informative, and underscores the desperate need for the economics profession to establish a single set of facts from which more accurate inferences and narratives can be constructed. (JEL E32, E44, E52, G01, G21, G28)</description><author>Lo, Andrew W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Getting Up to Speed on the Financial Crisis: A One-Weekend-Reader's Guide</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, Gary; Metrick, Andrew
All economists should be conversant with "what happened?" during the financial crisis of 2007-09. We select and summarize sixteen documents, including academic papers and reports from regulatory and international agencies. This reading list covers the key facts and mechanisms in the build-up of risk, the panics in short-term-debt markets, the policy reactions, and the real effects of the financial crisis. (JEL E32, E44, E52, G01, G21, G28)</description><author>Gorton, Gary; Metrick, Andrew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Perspectives on Corporate Social Responsibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kitzmueller, Markus; Shimshack, Jay
This paper synthesizes the expanding corporate social responsibility (CSR) literature. We define CSR from an economic perspective and develop a CSR taxonomy that connects disparate approaches to the subject. We explore whether CSR should exist and investigate conditions when CSR may produce higher welfare than other public good provision channels. We also explore why CSR does exist. Here, we integrate theoretical predictions with empirical findings from economic and noneconomic sources. We find limited systematic empirical evidence in favor of CSR mechanisms related to induced innovation, moral hazard, shareholder preferences, or labor markets. In contrast, we uncover consistent empirical evidence in favor of CSR mechanisms related to consumer markets, private politics, and public politics. (JEL D21, L21, M14)</description><author>Kitzmueller, Markus; Shimshack, Jay</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Elasticity of Taxable Income with Respect to Marginal Tax Rates: A Critical Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saez, Emmanuel; Slemrod, Joel; Giertz, Seth H.
This paper critically surveys the large and growing literature estimating the elasticity of taxable income with respect to marginal tax rates using tax return data. First, we provide a theoretical framework showing under what assumptions this elasticity can be used as a sufficient statistic for efficiency and optimal tax analysis. We discuss what other parameters should be estimated when the elasticity is not a sufficient statistic. Second, we discuss conceptually the key issues that arise in the empirical estimation of the elasticity of taxable income using the example of the 1993 top individual income tax rate increase in the United States to illustrate those issues. Third, we provide a critical discussion of selected empirical analyses of the elasticity of taxable income in light of the theoretical and empirical framework we laid out. Finally, we discuss avenues for future research. (JEL H24, H31, J22)</description><author>Saez, Emmanuel; Slemrod, Joel; Giertz, Seth H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heredity, Family, and Inequality: A Critique of Social Sciences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mazumder, Bhash
nan</description><author>Mazumder, Bhash</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technology Growth and Expenditure Growth in Health Care</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chandra, Amitabh; Skinner, Jonathan
In the United States, health care technology has contributed to rising survival rates, yet health care spending relative to GDP has also grown more rapidly than in any other country. We develop a model of patient demand and supplier behavior to explain these parallel trends in technology growth and cost growth. We show that health care productivity depends on the heterogeneity of treatment effects across patients, the shape of the health production function, and the cost structure of procedures such as MRIs with high fixed costs and low marginal costs. The model implies a typology of medical technology productivity: (I) highly cost-effective "home run" innovations with little chance of overuse, such as anti-retroviral therapy for HIV, (II) treatments highly effective for some but not for all (e.g., stents), and (III) "gray area" treatments with uncertain clinical value such as ICU days among chronically ill patients. Not surprisingly, countries adopting Category I and effective Category II treatments gain the greatest health improvements, while countries adopting ineffective Category II and Category III treatments experience the most rapid cost growth. Ultimately, economic and political resistance in the United States to ever-rising tax rates will likely slow cost growth, with uncertain effects on technology growth. (JEL H51, I11, I18, O31)</description><author>Chandra, Amitabh; Skinner, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flexible Exchange Rates for a Stable World Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Papell, David H.
nan</description><author>Papell, David H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industrial Policy and Development: The Political Economy of Capabilities Accumulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harrison, Ann
nan</description><author>Harrison, Ann</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good Jobs America: Making Work Better for Everyone</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Charles C.
nan</description><author>Brown, Charles C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Causes and Consequences of Income Tax Noncompliance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erard, Brian
nan</description><author>Erard, Brian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From Optimal Tax Theory to Tax Policy: Retrospective and Prospective Views</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rothschild, Casey
nan</description><author>Rothschild, Casey</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Benefit and the Burden: Tax Reform-Why We Need It and What It Will Take</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Viard, Alan D.
nan</description><author>Viard, Alan D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Guardians of Finance: Making Regulators Work for Us</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Truman, Edwin M.
nan</description><author>Truman, Edwin M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Peter, Goetz
nan</description><author>von Peter, Goetz</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Milton Friedman: A Concise Guide to the Ideas and Influence of the Free-Market Economist</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nelson, Edward
nan</description><author>Nelson, Edward</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Milton Friedman</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nelson, Edward
nan</description><author>Nelson, Edward</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Financial Stability and the Lessons of History: A Review of Carmen M. Reinhart and Kenneth S. Rogoff's This Time Is Different: Eight Centuries of Financial Folly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Alan M.
In Reinhart and Rogoff's economic history This Time is Different, the authors provide a panoramic view of crises from the Middle Ages to the modern era. Published just as the current global financial storm arrived, the book quickly showed how history could provide not just useful perspective but also, as we can now see, very prescient guidance in the aftermath. In the longer run, the book serves to inspire ongoing work in long-run macro-financial history.</description><author>Taylor, Alan M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Psychologists at the Gate: A Review of Daniel Kahneman's Thinking, Fast and Slow</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shleifer, Andrei
The publication of Daniel Kahneman's book, Thinking, Fast and Slow, is a major intellectual event. The book summarizes, but also integrates, the research that Kahneman has done over the past forty years, beginning with his path-breaking work with the late Amos Tversky. The broad theme of this research is that human beings are intuitive thinkers and that human intuition is imperfect, with the result that judgments and choices often deviate substantially from the predictions of normative statistical and economic models. In this review, I discuss some broad ideas and themes of the book, describe some economic applications, and suggest future directions for research that the book points to, especially in decision theory.</description><author>Shleifer, Andrei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing the Spectrum of Asset Returns: Jump and Volatility Components in High Frequency Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ait-Sahalia, Yacine; Jacod, Jean
This paper reports some of the recent developments in the econometric analysis of semimartingales estimated using high frequency financial returns. It describes a simple yet powerful methodology to decompose asset returns sampled at high frequency into their base components (continuous, small jumps, large jumps), determine the relative magnitude of the components, and analyze the finer characteristics of these components such as the degree of activity of the jumps. We incorporate to effect of market microstructure noise on the test statistics, apply the methodology to high frequency individual stock returns, transactions and quotes, stock index returns and compare the qualitative features of the estimated process for these different data and discuss the economic implications of the results.</description><author>Ait-Sahalia, Yacine; Jacod, Jean</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Racial Discrimination in the Labor Market: Theory and Empirics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lang, Kevin; Lehmann, Jee-Yeon K.
We review theories of race discrimination in the labor market. Taste-based models can generate wage and unemployment duration differentials when combined with either random or directed search even when strong prejudice is not widespread, but no existing model explains the unemployment rate differential. Models of statistical discrimination based on differential observability of productivity across races can explain the pattern and magnitudes of wage differentials but do not address employment and unemployment. At their current state of development, models of statistical discrimination based on rational stereotypes have little empirical content. It is plausible that models combining elements of the search models with statistical discrimination could fit the data. We suggest possible avenues to be pursued and comment briefly on the implication of existing theory for public policy.</description><author>Lang, Kevin; Lehmann, Jee-Yeon K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Collusion: Cartels and Bidding Rings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siegfried, John J.
nan</description><author>Siegfried, John J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business Ethics: A Critical Approach: Integrating Ethics across the Business World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sergi, Bruno S.
nan</description><author>Sergi, Bruno S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Prosperity of Vice: A Worried View of Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mokyr, Joel
nan</description><author>Mokyr, Joel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Greek Economy and the Crisis: Challenges and Responses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vettas, Nikolaos
nan</description><author>Vettas, Nikolaos</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Carbon Coalitions: Business, Climate Politics, and the Rise of Emissions Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rabe, Barry G.
nan</description><author>Rabe, Barry G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Green Paradox: A Supply-Side Approach to Global Warming</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Tao
nan</description><author>Wang, Tao</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Poker: The Parody of Capitalism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baron, James N.
nan</description><author>Baron, James N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jewish Economies: Development and Migration in America and Beyond, vol 2, Comparative Perspectives on Jewish Migration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiswick, Barry R.
nan</description><author>Chiswick, Barry R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jewish Economies: Development and Migration in America and Beyond, vol 1, The Economic Life of American Jewry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiswick, Barry R.
nan</description><author>Chiswick, Barry R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Women Empowerment and Economic Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duflo, Esther
Women empowerment and economic development are closely related: in one direction, development alone can play a major role in driving down inequality between men and women; in the other direction, empowering women may benefit development. Does this imply that pushing just one of these two levers would set a virtuous circle in motion? This paper reviews the literature on both sides of the empowerment-development nexus, and argues that the interrelationships are probably too weak to be self-sustaining, and that continuous policy commitment to equality for its own sake may be needed to bring about equality between men and women.</description><author>Duflo, Esther</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyse the Budget and Financial Question Resolved - Economic Systems and Reforms through extinguishing the deficit being equaled revenue and budget for the economic year 1869 to 1870 with little sacrifice for all with remarkable improvement of many services and without prejudice to any</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mourao, Paulo Reis
nan</description><author>Mourao, Paulo Reis</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forensic Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zitzewitz, Eric
A new meta-field of "forensic economics" has begun to emerge, uncovering evidence of hidden behavior in a variety of domains. Examples include teachers cheating on exams, road builders skimping on materials, violations of U.N. sanctions, unnecessary heart surgeries, and racial biases in employment decisions, traffic stops, auto retailing, and even sports judging. In each case, part of the contribution of economic analysis is in uncovering evidence of wrongdoing. Although research questions differ, forensic economic work shares commonalities in approaches and limitations. This article seeks to draw out the common threads, with the hope of stimulating further research across fields. (JEL K13)</description><author>Zitzewitz, Eric</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Mirrlees Review and the State of Public Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atkinson, Anthony B.
The Mirrlees Review of taxation in the United Kingdom is a landmark in the analysis of U.K. fiscal policy, and of wide interest to public finance economists around the world. This review concentrates on what we can learn from the Review about the current state of public economics and directions for future research. (JEL E62, H20, H50)</description><author>Atkinson, Anthony B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Mirrlees Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldstein, Martin
The Mirrlees Review is an ambitious and comprehensive analysis of the British tax system with detailed recommendations for reform. This review essay focuses on those issues that are also likely to be of interest to an American reader. The Review has the technical sophistication that readers would expect from a team of ten economists, chaired by James Mirrlees, the distinguished theorist who received the Nobel Prize for his contributions to the theory of optimal taxation. But it is written for a broader audience, explaining concepts like deadweight loss and the elasticity of tax revenue with respect to tax rates and doing so without any mathematics. (JEL D64, E21, E62, H24, H25)</description><author>Feldstein, Martin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomics and the Term Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guerkaynak, Refet S.; Wright, Jonathan H.
This paper provides an overview of the analysis of the term structure of interest rates with a special emphasis on recent developments at the intersection of macroeconomics and finance. The topic is important to investors and also to policymakers, who wish to extract macroeconomic expectations from longer-term interest rates, and take actions to influence those rates. The simplest model of the term structure is the expectations hypothesis, which posits that long-term interest rates are expectations of future average short-term rates. In this paper, we show that many features of the configuration of interest rates are puzzling from the perspective of the expectations hypothesis. We review models that explain these anomalies using time-varying risk premia. Although the quest for the fundamental macroeconomic explanations of these risk premia is ongoing, inflation uncertainty seems to play a large role. Finally, while modern finance theory prices bonds and other assets in a single unified framework, we also consider an earlier approach based on segmented markets. Market segmentation seems important to understand the term structure of interest rates during the recent financial crisis.</description><author>Guerkaynak, Refet S.; Wright, Jonathan H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Protection and Contingent Charges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armstrong, Mark; Vickers, John
Contingent charges for financial services, such as fees for unauthorized overdrafts, are often controversial. We study the economics of contingent charges in a stylized setting with naive and sophisticated consumers. We contrast situations where the naive benefit from the presence of sophisticated consumers with situations where competition works to subsidize the sophisticated at the expense of the naive, arguably unfairly. The case for regulatory intervention in these situations depends in good part, but not only, on the weight placed on distributional concerns. The economic and legal issues at stake are well illustrated by a case on bank charges recently decided by the U.K. Supreme Court.</description><author>Armstrong, Mark; Vickers, John</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Something for Nothing: A Novel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauman, Yoram
nan</description><author>Bauman, Yoram</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changing Inequality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burkhauser, Richard V.
nan</description><author>Burkhauser, Richard V.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dictator's Handbook: Why Bad Behavior Is Almost Always Good Politics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Russett, Bruce
nan</description><author>Russett, Bruce</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Fairness and Social Welfare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boadway, Robin
nan</description><author>Boadway, Robin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beauty Pays: Why Attractive People Are More Successful</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamenica, Emir
nan</description><author>Kamenica, Emir</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomics beyond the NAIRU</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pflueger, Carolin
nan</description><author>Pflueger, Carolin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Trade in Services: Fear, Facts, and Offshoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lincoln, William F.
nan</description><author>Lincoln, William F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Decade of Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chinn, Menzie D.
nan</description><author>Chinn, Menzie D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From Financial Crisis to Global Recovery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuttner, Kenneth
nan</description><author>Kuttner, Kenneth</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inside and Outside Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnamurthy, Arvind
nan</description><author>Krishnamurthy, Arvind</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Maynard's Revenge: The Collapse of Free Market Macroeconomics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Epstein, Gerald
nan</description><author>Epstein, Gerald</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Changing Body: Health, Nutrition, and Human Development in the Western World since 1700</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Margo, Robert A.
nan</description><author>Margo, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Age of Equality: The Twentieth Century in Economic Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Temin, Peter
nan</description><author>Temin, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pollution Limits and Polluters' Efforts to Comply: The Role of Government Monitoring and Enforcement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Judge, Rebecca P.
nan</description><author>Judge, Rebecca P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Origins of Roman Christianity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Douglas W.
nan</description><author>Allen, Douglas W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lectures on Urban Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mills, Edwin S.
nan</description><author>Mills, Edwin S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Development in the Americas since 1500: Endowments and Institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williamson, Jeffrey G.
nan</description><author>Williamson, Jeffrey G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Perilous Life of Symphony Orchestras: Artistic Triumphs and Economic Challenges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosett, Joshua
nan</description><author>Rosett, Joshua</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interpreting China's Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tao, Zhigang
nan</description><author>Tao, Zhigang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth with Financial Stability: Central Banking in an Emerging Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mody, Ashoka
nan</description><author>Mody, Ashoka</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Parasites, Pathogens, and Progress: Diseases and Economic Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weil, David N.
nan</description><author>Weil, David N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Great A&amp;P and the Struggle for Small Business in America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hamilton, Shane
nan</description><author>Hamilton, Shane</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Moving Boxes by Air: The Economics of International Air Cargo</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hummels, David
nan</description><author>Hummels, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Transformation of the American Pension System: Was It Beneficial for Workers?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Turner, John A.
nan</description><author>Turner, John A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Migration and the Welfare State: Political-Economy Policy Formation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mukand, Sharun W.
nan</description><author>Mukand, Sharun W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Pursuit of Happiness: An Economy of Well-Being</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clark, Andrew
nan</description><author>Clark, Andrew</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Cooperative Species: Human Reciprocity and Its Evolution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Veelen, Matthijs
nan</description><author>van Veelen, Matthijs</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Moral Foundation of Economic Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Janice Boucher
nan</description><author>Breuer, Janice Boucher</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Darwin Economy: Liberty, Competition, and the Common Good</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergstrom, Ted
nan</description><author>Bergstrom, Ted</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Globalization, Brain Drain, and Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Docquier, Frederic; Rapoport, Hillel
This paper reviews four decades of economics research on the brain drain, with a focus on recent contributions and on development issues. We first assess the magnitude, intensity, and determinants of the brain drain, showing that brain drain (or high-skill) migration is becoming a dominant pattern of international migration and a major aspect of globalization. We then use a stylized growth model to analyze the various channels through which a brain drain affects the sending countries and review the evidence on these channels. The recent empirical literature shows that high-skill emigration need not deplete a country's human capital stock and can generate positive network externalities. Three case studies are also considered: the African medical brain drain, the exodus of European scientists to the United States, and the role of the Indian diaspora in the development of India's information technology sector. We conclude with a discussion of the implications of the analysis for education, immigration, and international taxation policies in a global context. (JEL F02, F22, J24, J61, O15)</description><author>Docquier, Frederic; Rapoport, Hillel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking on the Future: The Fall and Rise of Central Banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mohan, Rakesh
nan</description><author>Mohan, Rakesh</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economist's Oath: On the Need for and Content of Professional Economic Ethics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oster, Sharon
nan</description><author>Oster, Sharon</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding Chinese Families: A Comparative Study of Taiwan and Southeast China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siow, Aloysius
nan</description><author>Siow, Aloysius</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Big-Time Sports in American Universities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siegfried, John J.
nan</description><author>Siegfried, John J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debates on the Measurement of Global Poverty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thorbecke, Erik
nan</description><author>Thorbecke, Erik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Big Banks Fail and What to Do about It</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Macey, Jonathan
nan</description><author>Macey, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Brink of Deglobalization: An Alternative Perspective on the Causes of the World Trade Collapse</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rappoport, Veronica
nan</description><author>Rappoport, Veronica</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Globalization at Risk: Challenges to Finance and Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Javorcik, Beata S.
nan</description><author>Javorcik, Beata S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Variety and the Gains from International Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weinstein, David E.
nan</description><author>Weinstein, David E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seeds of Destruction: Why the Path to Economic Ruin Runs through Washington, and How to Reclaim American Prosperity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barr, Michael S.
nan</description><author>Barr, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How the Economy Works: Confidence, Crashes and Self-Fulfilling Prophecies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cole, Harold L.
nan</description><author>Cole, Harold L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economics Evolving: A History of Economic Thought</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baumol, William J.
nan</description><author>Baumol, William J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Redeeming Economics: Rediscovering the Missing Element</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colander, David
nan</description><author>Colander, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Famous Figures and Diagrams in Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Appleyard, Dennis R.
nan</description><author>Appleyard, Dennis R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact Evaluation in Practice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanna, Rema
nan</description><author>Hanna, Rema</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Greed, Lust and Gender: A History of Economic Ideas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergmann, Barbara R.
nan</description><author>Bergmann, Barbara R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Measuring the Effects of Fiscal Policy in Recessions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parker, Jonathan A.
We do not have a good measure of the effects of fiscal policy in a recession because the methods that we use to estimate the effects of fiscal policy-both those using the observed outcomes following different policies in aggregate data and those studying counterfactuals in fitted model economies-almost entirely ignore the state of the economy and estimate "the" government multiplier, which is presumably a weighted average of the one we care about-the multiplier in a recession-and one we care less about-the multiplier in an expansion. Notable exceptions to this general claim suggest this difference is potentially large. Our lack of knowledge stems significantly from the focus on linear dynamics: vector autoregressions and linearized (or close-to-linear) dynamic stochastic general equilibrium (DSGE) models. Our lack of knowledge also reflects a lack of data: deep recessions are few and nonlinearities hard to measure. The lack of statistical power in the estimation of nonlinear models using aggregate data can be addressed by exploiting estimates of partial-equilibrium responses in disaggregated data. Microeconomic estimates of the partial-equilibrium causal effects of a policy can discipline the causal channels inherent in any DSGE model of the general equilibrium effects of policy. Microeconomic studies can also provide measures of the dependence of the effects of a policy on the states of different agents, which is a key component of the dependence of the general-equilibrium effects of fiscal policy on the state of the economy.</description><author>Parker, Jonathan A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Analysis of the Revival of Fiscal Activism in the 2000s</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, John B.
An empirical review of the three fiscal stimulus packages of the 2000s shows that they had little if any direct impact on consumption or government purchases. Households largely saved the transfers and tax rebates. The federal government only increased purchases by a small amount. State and local governments saved their stimulus grants and shifted spending away from purchases to transfers. Counterfactual simulations show that the stimulus-induced decrease in state and local government purchases was larger than the increase in federal purchases. Simulations also show that a larger stimulus package with the same design as the 2009 stimulus would not have increased government purchases or consumption by a larger amount. These results raise doubts about the efficacy of such packages adding weight to similar assessments reached more than thirty years ago.</description><author>Taylor, John B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange Rate Regimes in the Modern Era: Fixed, Floating, and Flaky</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rose, Andrew K.
This paper provides a selective survey of the incidence, causes, and consequences of a country's choice of its exchange rate regime. I begin with a critical review of Michael Klein and Jay C. Shambaugh's (2010) book Exchange Rate Regimes in the Modern Era, and then proceed to provide an alternative overview of what the economics profession knows and needs to know about exchange rate regimes. While a fixed exchange rate with capital mobility is a well-defined monetary regime, floating is not; thus, it is unclear whether it is theoretically sensible to compare countries across exchange rate regimes. This comparison is quite difficult to make empirically. It is often hard to figure out what the exchange rate regime of a country is in practice, since there are multiple conflicting regime classifications. More importantly, similar countries choose radically different exchange rate regimes without substantive consequences for macroeconomic outcomes like output growth and inflation. That is, the profession knows surprisingly little about either the causes or consequences of national choices of exchange rate regimes. But since the consequences of these choices are small, understanding their causes is of only academic interest.</description><author>Rose, Andrew K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wage Structures, Employment Adjustments and Globalization: Evidence from Linked and Firm-Level Panel Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dunne, Timothy
nan</description><author>Dunne, Timothy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minimum Wages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dube, Arindrajit
nan</description><author>Dube, Arindrajit</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From Immigrants to Americans: The Rise and Fall of Fitting In</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanson, Gordon
nan</description><author>Hanson, Gordon</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Gangsters: Corruption, Violence, and the Poverty of Nations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Dean
nan</description><author>Yang, Dean</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Government Purchases Stimulate the Economy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ramey, Valerie A.
This essay briefly reviews the state of knowledge about the government spending multiplier. Drawing on theoretical work, aggregate empirical estimates from the United States, as well as cross-locality estimates, I assess the likely range of multiplier values for the experiment most relevant to the stimulus package debate: a temporary, deficit-financed increase in government purchases. I conclude that the multiplier for this type of spending is probably between 0.8 and 1.5.</description><author>Ramey, Valerie A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Causal Effect of Parents' Schooling on Children's Schooling: A Comparison of Estimation Methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holmlund, Helena; Lindahl, Mikael; Plug, Erik
We review the empirical literature that estimates the causal effect of parent's schooling on child's schooling, and conclude that estimates differ across studies. We then consider three explanations for why this is: (a) idiosyncratic differences in data sets, (b) differences in remaining biases between different identification strategies, and (c) differences across identification strategies in their ability to make out-of-sample predictions. We conclude that discrepancies in past studies can be explained by violations of identifying assumptions. Our reading of past evidence, together with an application to Swedish register data, suggests that intergenerational schooling associations are largely driven by selection. Parental schooling constitutes a large part of the parental nurture effect, but as a whole does not play a large role.</description><author>Holmlund, Helena; Lindahl, Mikael; Plug, Erik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Historical Fertility Transition: A Guide for Economists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guinnane, Timothy W.
The historical fertility transition is the process by which much of Europe and North America went from high to low fertility in the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. This transformation is central to recent accounts of long-run economic growth. Prior to the transition, women bore as many as eight children each, and the elasticity of fertility with respect to incomes was positive. Today, many women have no children at all, and the elasticity of fertility with respect to incomes is zero or even negative. This paper discusses the large literature on the historical fertility transition, focusing on what we do and do not know about the process. I stress some possible misunderstandings of the demographic literature, and discuss an agenda for future work.</description><author>Guinnane, Timothy W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Climatopolis: How Our Cities Will Thrive in the Hotter Future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kotchen, Matthew J.
nan</description><author>Kotchen, Matthew J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Choices in a Warming World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tietenberg, Tom
nan</description><author>Tietenberg, Tom</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wealth and Welfare States: Is America a Laggard or Leader?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stevens, Ann Huff
nan</description><author>Stevens, Ann Huff</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity and Growth in a Globalizing World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kharas, Homi
nan</description><author>Kharas, Homi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blind Spots: Why We Fail to Do What's Right and What to Do about It</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Markovits, Daniel
nan</description><author>Markovits, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Balancing the Banks: Global Lessons from the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Richardson, Matthew
nan</description><author>Richardson, Matthew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Triumph of the City: How Our Greatest Invention Makes Us Richer, Smarter, Greener, Healthier, and Happier</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Strange, William C.
nan</description><author>Strange, William C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The End of Energy: The Unmaking of America's Environment, Security, and Independence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobsen, Mark
nan</description><author>Jacobsen, Mark</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No Precedent, No Plan: Inside Russia's 1998 Default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aslund, Anders
nan</description><author>Aslund, Anders</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taking Economics Seriously</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Folbre, Nancy
nan</description><author>Folbre, Nancy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>