<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JEL3</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Understanding Growth and Poverty: Theory, Policy, and Empirics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mestieri, Marti
nan</description><author>Mestieri, Marti</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Big Ditch: How America Took, Built, Ran, and Ultimately Gave Away the Panama Canal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ramey, Valerie A.
nan</description><author>Ramey, Valerie A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peddling Protectionism: Smoot-Hawley and the Great Depression</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crucini, Mario J.
nan</description><author>Crucini, Mario J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Football Economics and Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Orsogna, Paola; Ottaviano, Gianmarco I. P.
nan</description><author>D'Orsogna, Paola; Ottaviano, Gianmarco I. P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Knowledge Intensive Entrepreneurship: The Birth, Growth and Demise of Entrepreneurial Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taussig, Markus
nan</description><author>Taussig, Markus</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monopsony in Law and Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremieux, Pierre Y.
nan</description><author>Cremieux, Pierre Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Time Use of Mothers in the United States at the Beginning of the 21st Century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danziger, Sandra K.
nan</description><author>Danziger, Sandra K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inequality in Living Standards since 1980: Income Tells Only a Small Part of the Story</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flinn, Christopher J.
nan</description><author>Flinn, Christopher J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Running the World's Markets: The Governance of Financial Infrastructure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisenbach, Thomas M.
nan</description><author>Eisenbach, Thomas M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reforming US Financial Markets: Reflections before and beyond Dodd-Frank</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hubbard, Glenn
nan</description><author>Hubbard, Glenn</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Guaranteed to Fail: Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac and the Debacle of Mortgage Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fetter, Daniel K.
nan</description><author>Fetter, Daniel K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Globalization Paradox: Democracy and the Future of the World Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zedillo, Ernesto
nan</description><author>Zedillo, Ernesto</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Emerging Markets: Resilience and Growth amid Global Turmoil</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Jing
nan</description><author>Zhang, Jing</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diaspora, Development, and Democracy: The Domestic Impact of International Migration from India</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singh, Nirvikar
nan</description><author>Singh, Nirvikar</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exorbitant Privilege: The Rise and Fall of the Dollar and the Future of the International Monetary System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giovannini, Alberto
nan</description><author>Giovannini, Alberto</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Enough: How to Run the Economy As If the Future Matters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Frank
nan</description><author>Levy, Frank</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Idea of Justice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shapiro, Ian
nan</description><author>Shapiro, Ian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individuals and Identity in Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sprenger, Charles
nan</description><author>Sprenger, Charles</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy and Choice: Public Finance through the Lens of Behavioral Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kroft, Kory
nan</description><author>Kroft, Kory</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Zombie Economics: How Dead Ideas Still Walk among Us</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williamson, Stephen D.
nan</description><author>Williamson, Stephen D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bourgeois Dignity: Why Economics Can't Explain the Modern World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parente, Stephen L.
nan</description><author>Parente, Stephen L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond the Invisible Hand: Groundwork for a New Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoff, Karla
nan</description><author>Hoff, Karla</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Liberalization and Indian Economic Growth: What's the Evidence?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kotwal, Ashok; Ramaswami, Bharat; Wadhwa, Wilima
India's growth and poverty performance over the last three decades has been a subject of great curiosity. Unlike the East Asian countries, India's growth spurt is not associated with exceptionally high domestic savings or foreign capital inflows or manufacturing exports. So what triggered the change in the growth trajectory? Did the market liberalization policies of the 1990s help? How have the initial conditions shaped the process? And how has the "Indian model" impinged on India's central problem of mass poverty? This paper surveys the literature and offers its own assessment of the drivers of change.</description><author>Kotwal, Ashok; Ramaswami, Bharat; Wadhwa, Wilima</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear Models of Measurement Errors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Xiaohong; Hong, Han; Nekipelov, Denis
Measurement errors in economic data are pervasive and nontrivial in size. The presence of measurement errors causes biased and inconsistent parameter estimates and leads to erroneous conclusions to various degrees in economic analysis. While linear errors-in-variables models are usually handled with well-known instrumental variable methods, this article provides an overview of recent research papers that derive estimation methods that provide consistent estimates for nonlinear models with measurement errors. We review models with both classical and nonclassical measurement errors, and with misclassification of discrete variables. For each of the methods surveyed, we describe the key ideas for identification and estimation, and discuss its application whenever it is currently available.</description><author>Chen, Xiaohong; Hong, Han; Nekipelov, Denis</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Many Languages Do We Need? The Economics of Linguistic Diversity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Melitz, Jacques
nan</description><author>Melitz, Jacques</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Plenitude: The New Economics of True Wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milberg, William
nan</description><author>Milberg, William</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collaborative Governance: Private Roles for Public Goals in Turbulent Times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischer, Ronald
nan</description><author>Fischer, Ronald</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>European Integration at the Crossroads: A Review Essay on the 50th Anniversary of Bela Balassa's Theory of Economic Integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sapir, Andre
Bela Balassa's Theory of Economic Integration, published fifty years ago, is a remarkable, yet little known book. This essay reviews developments in the economic literature and in the process of European integration since the book's publication, showing that it was incredibly prescient. It anticipated by more than twenty years the modern literature on economic integration that emphasizes scale economies, imperfect competition, and economic geography. It also predicted that monetary union cannot function properly without political unification, a condition well illustrated by the recent euro-debt crisis that is likely to be a watershed in the history of European integration.</description><author>Sapir, Andre</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Fundamental Institutions of China's Reforms and Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Chenggang
China's economic reforms have resulted in spectacular growth and poverty reduction. However, China's institutions look ill-suited to achieve such a result, and they indeed suffer from serious shortcomings. To solve the "China puzzle," this paper analyzes China's institution-a regionally decentralized authoritarian system. The central government has control over personnel, whereas subnational governments run the bulk of the economy; and they initiate, negotiate, implement, divert, and resist reforms, policies, rules, and laws. China's reform trajectories have been shaped by regional decentralization. Spectacular performance on the one hand and grave problems on the other hand are all determined by this governance structure.</description><author>Xu, Chenggang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor Supply and Taxes: A Survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keane, Michael P.
I survey the male and female labor supply literatures, focusing on implications for effects of wages and taxes. For males, I describe and contrast results from three basic types of model: static models (especially those that account for nonlinear taxes), life-cycle models with savings, and life-cycle models with both savings and human capital. For women, more important distinctions are whether models include fixed costs of work, and whether they treat demographics like fertility and marriage (and human capital) as exogenous or endogenous. The literature is characterized by considerable controversy over the responsiveness of labor supply to changes in wages and taxes. At least for males, it is fair to say that most economists believe labor supply elasticities are small. But a sizable minority of studies that I examine obtain large values. Hence, there is no clear consensus on this point. In fact, a simple average of Hicks elasticities across all the studies I examine is 0.31. Several simulation studies have shown that such a value is large enough to generate large efficiency costs of income taxation. For males, I conclude that two factors drive many of the differences in results across studies. One factor is use of direct versus ratio wage measures, with studies that use the former tending to find larger elasticities. Another factor is the failure of most studies to account for human capital returns to work experience. I argue that this may lead to downward bias in elasticity estimates. In a model that includes human capital, I show how even modest elasticities-as conventionally measured-can be consistent with large efficiency costs of taxation. For women, in contrast, it is fair to say that most studies find large labor supply elasticities, especially on the participation margin. In particular, I find that estimates of "long-run" labor supply elasticities-by which I mean estimates that allow for dynamic effects of wages on fertility, marriage, education and work experience-are generally quite large.</description><author>Keane, Michael P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sign Restrictions in Structural Vector Autoregressions: A Critical Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fry, Renee; Pagan, Adrian
The paper provides a review of the estimation of structural vector autoregressions with sign restrictions. It is shown how sign restrictions solve the parametric identification problem present in structural systems but leaves the model identification problem unresolved. A market and a macro model are used to illustrate these points. Suggestions have been made on how to find a unique model. These are reviewed. An analysis is provided of whether one can recover the true impulse responses and what difficulties might arise when one wishes to use the impulse responses found with sign restrictions.</description><author>Fry, Renee; Pagan, Adrian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Regulation: Lessons from the Recent Financial Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoshi, Takeo
The experiences of the financial crises in the United States recently and in Japan in the 1990s suggest two lessons for future financial regulations. First, the lack of an orderly resolution mechanism for large and complex financial institutions created serious problems. Second, it is important to distinguish between individual financial institutions' health and stability of the whole financial system. Policy recommendations in the Squam Lake Report address these issues well. The Dodd-Frank Act could provide an effective regulatory framework to implement these recommendations, but the success depends on the details of the regulations that have not been specified. (JEL E44, E52, G01, G21, G28, L51)</description><author>Hoshi, Takeo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Misadventures of the Most Favored Nations: Clashing Egos, Inflated Ambitions, and the Great Shambles of the World Trade System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, Anne
nan</description><author>Krueger, Anne</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Europe and the Euro</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wyplosz, Charles
nan</description><author>Wyplosz, Charles</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Top Incomes: A Global Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Margo, Robert A.
nan</description><author>Margo, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Bounds of Reason: Game Theory and the Unification of the Behavioral Sciences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robson, Arthur J.
nan</description><author>Robson, Arthur J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Better Living through Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Watts, Michael
nan</description><author>Watts, Michael</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Frontiers of Real-Time Data Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Croushore, Dean
In the past ten years, researchers have explored the impact of data revisions in many different contexts. Researchers have examined the properties of data revisions, how structural modeling is affected by data revisions, how data revisions affect forecasting, the impact of data revisions on monetary policy analysis, and the use of real-time data in current analysis. This paper summarizes many of the questions for which real-time data analysis has provided answers. In addition, researchers and institutions have developed better real-time data sets around the world. Still, additional research is needed in key areas and research to date has uncovered even more fruitful areas worth exploring. (JEL C52, C53, C80, E01)</description><author>Croushore, Dean</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Top Incomes in the Long Run of History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atkinson, Anthony B.; Piketty, Thomas; Saez, Emmanuel
A recent literature has constructed top income shares time series over the long run for more than twenty countries using income tax statistics. Top incomes represent a small share of the population but a very significant share of total income and total taxes paid. Hence, aggregate economic growth per capita and Gini inequality indexes are sensitive to excluding or including top incomes. We discuss the estimation methods and issues that arise when constructing top income share series, including income definition and comparability over time and across countries, tax avoidance, and tax evasion. We provide a summary of the key empirical findings. Most countries experience a dramatic drop in top income shares in the first part of the twentieth century in general due to shocks to top capital incomes during the wars and depression shocks. Top income shares do not recover in the immediate postwar decades. However, over the last thirty years, top income shares have increased substantially in English speaking countries and in India and China but not in continental European countries or Japan. This increase is due in part to an unprecedented surge in top wage incomes. As a result, wage income comprises a larger fraction of top incomes than in the past. Finally, we discuss the theoretical and empirical models that have been proposed to account for the facts and the main questions that remain open. (JEL D31, D63, H26, N30)</description><author>Atkinson, Anthony B.; Piketty, Thomas; Saez, Emmanuel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Squam Lake Report: Commentary</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goodhart, Charles A. E.
The idea of the Squam Lake Report was to bring together some fifteen leading U. S. financial economists to see what regulatory changes they could jointly agree and thereby influence policy discussions. Seeking to find a consensus, however, meant that many issues were not mentioned in the Report, e.g., structural limitations, Pigovian taxes, procyclicality, and boundary problems between banks and nonbanks. But what is presented is generally, though not invariably, admirable, and the book is beautifully written in good, easily accessible English. (JEL E44, E52, G01, G21, G28, L51)</description><author>Goodhart, Charles A. E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Thinking about the Firm: A Review of Daniel Spulber's The Theory of the Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hart, Oliver
In this review, I describe how economists have moved beyond the firm as a black box to incorporate incentives, internal organization, and firm boundaries. I then turn to the way that the theory of the firm is treated in Daniel Spulber's book The Theory of the Firm: Microeconomics with Endogenous Entrepreneurs, Firms, Markets, and Organizations. Spulber's goal is to explain why firms exist, how they are established, and what they contribute to the economy. To accomplish this, Spulber defines a firm to be a transaction institution whose objectives differ from those of its owners. For Spulber, this separation is the key difference between the firm and direct exchange between consumers. I raise questions about whether this is a useful basis for a theory of the firm. (JEL D21)</description><author>Hart, Oliver</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Trade with Equilibrium Unemployment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xiang, Chong
nan</description><author>Xiang, Chong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unequal Partners: The United States and Mexico</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robertson, Raymond
nan</description><author>Robertson, Raymond</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticipating Correlations: A New Paradigm for Risk Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Binsbergen, Jules H.
nan</description><author>van Binsbergen, Jules H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nordics in Global Crisis: Vulnerability and Resilience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergh, Andreas
nan</description><author>Bergh, Andreas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reforming the Welfare State: Recovery and Beyond in Sweden</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Skedinger, Per
nan</description><author>Skedinger, Per</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Invention of Enterprise: Entrepreneurship from Ancient Mesopotamia to Modern Times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bikard, Michael; Stern, Scott
nan</description><author>Bikard, Michael; Stern, Scott</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Emergent Economies, Divergent Paths: Economic Organization and International Trade in South Korea and Taiwan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rauch, James E.
nan</description><author>Rauch, James E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Offshoring in the Global Economy: Microeconomic Structure and Macroeconomic Implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branstetter, Lee
nan</description><author>Branstetter, Lee</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Higher Education Worldwide: Who Pays? Who Should Pay?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hall, Martin
nan</description><author>Hall, Martin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Saving Alma Mater: A Rescue Plan for America's Public Universities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sullivan, Teresa A.
nan</description><author>Sullivan, Teresa A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Humans Cooperate: A Cultural and Evolutionary Explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Page, Scott E.
nan</description><author>Page, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Von Neumann, Morgenstern, and the Creation of Game Theory: From Chess to Social Science, 1900-1960</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shubik, Martin
nan</description><author>Shubik, Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Modeling and Inference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sauer, Robert M.
nan</description><author>Sauer, Robert M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A World without Intellectual Property? A Review of Michele Boldrin and David Levine's Against Intellectual Monopoly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilbert, Richard
In their recent book, Against Intellectual Monopoly, Michele Boldrin and David Levine conclude that patents and copyrights are not necessary to provide protection for either innovation or creative expression and should be eliminated. The authors note the many flaws of the U.S. system of intellectual property protection and argue that other means are available to appropriate the benefits of invention and creative expression. While the authors overlook important functions of intellectual property, they provide support for further reforms of intellectual property law. (JEL K11, O31, O34)</description><author>Gilbert, Richard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Natural Resources: Curse or Blessing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van der Ploeg, Frederick
Are natural resources a "curse" or a "blessing"? The empirical evidence suggests that either outcome is possible. This paper surveys a variety of hypotheses and supporting evidence for why some countries benefit and others lose from the presence of natural resources. These include that a resource bonanza induces appreciation of the real exchange rate, deindustrialization, and bad growth prospects, and that these adverse effects are more severe in volatile countries with bad institutions and lack of rule of law, corruption, presidential democracies, and underdeveloped financial systems. Another hypothesis is that a resource boom reinforces rent grabbing and civil conflict especially if institutions are bad, induces corruption especially in nondemocratic countries, and keeps in place bad policies. Finally, resource rich developing economies seem unable to successfully convert their depleting exhaustible resources into other productive assets. The survey also offers some welfare-based fiscal rules for harnessing resource windfalls in developed and developing economies. (JEL O47, Q32, Q33)</description><author>van der Ploeg, Frederick</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Determines Productivity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Syverson, Chad
Economists have shown that large and persistent differences in productivity levels across businesses are ubiquitous. This finding has shaped research agendas in a number of fields, including (but not limited to) macroeconomics, industrial organization, labor, and trade. This paper surveys and evaluates recent empirical work addressing the question of why businesses differ in their measured productivity levels. The causes are manifold, and differ depending on the particular setting. They include elements sourced in production practices-and therefore over which producers have some direct control, at least in theory-as well as from producers' external operating environments. After evaluating the current state of knowledge, I lay out what I see are the major questions that research in the area should address going forward. (JEL D24, G31, L11, M10, O30, O47)</description><author>Syverson, Chad</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Illiquidity and All Its Friends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tirole, Jean
The recent crisis was characterized by massive illiquidity. This paper reviews what we know and don't know about illiquidity and all its friends: market freezes, fire sales, contagion, and ultimately insolvencies and bailouts. It first explains why liquidity cannot easily be apprehended through a single statistic, and asks whether liquidity should be regulated given that a capital adequacy requirement is already in place. The paper then analyzes market breakdowns due to either adverse selection or shortages of financial muscle, and explains why such breakdowns are endogenous to balance sheet choices and to information acquisition. It then looks at what economics can contribute to the debate on systemic risk and its containment. Finally, the paper takes a macroeconomic perspective, discusses shortages of aggregate liquidity, and analyzes how market value accounting and capital adequacy should react to asset prices. It concludes with a topical form of liquidity provision, monetary bailouts and recapitalizations, and analyzes optimal combinations thereof; it stresses the need for macro-prudential policies. (JEL E44, G01, G21, G28, G32, L51)</description><author>Tirole, Jean</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Experimental Economics: Rethinking the Rules</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Gary E.
nan</description><author>Bolton, Gary E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common Wealth: Economics for a Crowded Planet</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Srinivasan, T. N.
nan</description><author>Srinivasan, T. N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Globalization, Economic Growth, and the Crisis of 2007-09</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levchenko, Andrei A.
nan</description><author>Levchenko, Andrei A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heroes and Cowards: The Social Face of War</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Munshi, Kaivan
nan</description><author>Munshi, Kaivan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>India: The Emerging Giant</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mohan, Rakesh
nan</description><author>Mohan, Rakesh</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Famine and Foreigners: Ethiopia Since Live Aid</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Broussard, Nzinga H.
nan</description><author>Broussard, Nzinga H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Achieving Anew: How New Immigrants Do in American Schools, Jobs, and Neighborhoods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bohn, Sarah E.
nan</description><author>Bohn, Sarah E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Migration in the Age of Crisis and Globalization: Historical and Recent Experiences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zavodny, Madeline
nan</description><author>Zavodny, Madeline</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beside the Golden Door: US Immigration Reform in a New Era of Globalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hunt, Jennifer
nan</description><author>Hunt, Jennifer</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Britain's War on Poverty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ziliak, James P.
nan</description><author>Ziliak, James P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Big Short: Inside the Doomsday Machine</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, Gary
nan</description><author>Gorton, Gary</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Greatest Trade Ever: The Behind-the-Scenes Story of How John Paulson Defied Wall Street and Made Financial History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, Gary
nan</description><author>Gorton, Gary</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Theory of Decision under Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lipman, Barton L.
nan</description><author>Lipman, Barton L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Development and Testing of Heckscher-Ohlin Trade Models: A Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bowen, Harry P.
nan</description><author>Bowen, Harry P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Money Myth: School Resources, Outcomes, and Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ladd, Helen F.
nan</description><author>Ladd, Helen F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Against the Tide: Household Structure, Opportunities, and Outcomes among White and Minority Youth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korenman, Sanders
nan</description><author>Korenman, Sanders</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Brute Force Fails: How to Have Less Crime and Less Punishment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donohue, John J.
nan</description><author>Donohue, John J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulating Vice: Misguided Prohibitions and Realistic Controls</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guryan, Jonathan
nan</description><author>Guryan, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Playbooks and Checkbooks: An Introduction to the Economics of Modern Sports</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baumann, Robert
nan</description><author>Baumann, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economy of Renaissance Florence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Federico, Giovanni
nan</description><author>Federico, Giovanni</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Invisible Hook: The Hidden Economics of Pirates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clark, Gregory
nan</description><author>Clark, Gregory</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economics of Forest Resources</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lopez, Ramon
nan</description><author>Lopez, Ramon</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making Cities Work: Prospects and Policies for Urban America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Roger
nan</description><author>Bolton, Roger</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutions and Economic Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giavazzi, Francesco
nan</description><author>Giavazzi, Francesco</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boergers, Tilman
nan</description><author>Boergers, Tilman</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unequal Democracy: The Political Economy of the New Gilded Age</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pollin, Robert
nan</description><author>Pollin, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Civil War</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blattman, Christopher; Miguel, Edward
Most nations have experienced an internal armed conflict since 1960. Yet while civil war is central to many nations' development, it has stood at the periphery of economics research and teaching. The past decade has witnessed a long overdue explosion of research into war's causes and consequences. We summarize progress, identify weaknesses, and chart a path forward. Why war? Existing theory is provocative but incomplete, omitting advances in behavioral economics and making little progress in key areas, like why armed groups form and cohere, or how more than two armed sides compete. Empirical work finds that low per capita incomes and slow economic growth are both robustly linked to civil war. Yet there is little consensus on the most effective policies to avert conflicts or promote postwar recovery. Cross-country analysis of war will benefit from more attention to causal identification and stronger links to theory. We argue that micro-level analysis and case studies are also crucial to decipher war's causes, conduct, and consequences. We bring a growth theoretic approach to the study of conflict consequences to highlight areas for research, most of all the study of war's impact on institutions. We conclude with a plea for new and better data. (JEL D72, D74, O17)</description><author>Blattman, Christopher; Miguel, Edward</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Boards of Directors in Corporate Governance: A Conceptual Framework and Survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Renee B.; Hermalin, Benjamin E.; Weisbach, Michael S.
This paper is a survey of the literature on boards of directors, with an emphasis on research done subsequent to the Benjamin. E. Hermalin and Michael S. Weisbach (2003) survey. The two questions most asked about boards are what determines their makeup and what determines their actions? These questions are fundamentally intertwined, which complicates the study of boards because makeup and actions are jointly endogenous. A focus of this survey is how the literature, theoretical as well as empirical, deals or on occasions fails to deal with this complication. We suggest that many studies of boards can best be interpreted as joint statements about both the director-selection process and the effect of board composition on board actions and firm performance. ( JEL G34, L25)</description><author>Adams, Renee B.; Hermalin, Benjamin E.; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Scott E. Page's The Difference: How the Power of Diversity Creates Better Groups, Firms, Schools, and Societies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ioannides, Yannis M.
This assessment of Scott Page's The Difference (Princeton University Press, 2007) emphasizes the depth and breadth of the book's coverage and arguments and checks them against existing empirical evidence, when available. It argues that the book navigates artfully between being a "manifesto" for diversity and rigorous science writing while at the same time marketing economic science in new ways. The review welcomes the book's popularization of richer aspects of everyday decision making, individual and collective, and its making an excellent case for the social significance of abstract economic theorizing, especially about problem solving. It praises the book's lively interpretations of statistical tools of decision making by means of enticing narratives. The book's rhetoric urges us to move beyond accepting diversity as a matter of taste, or even because of its beneficial effects on the "production function,and ultimately adopts its powerful logic. It speculates that the book's true impact will likely come after thorough empirical research. In empirical endeavors, issues of definition, especially of identity and of measurement, and evaluation of policies that would enhance diversity would be decisive. In democratic societies, policies may pose new dilemmas as they benefit from public interest in. overcoming the accumulation of past disadvantages. (JEL D23, Z13)</description><author>Ioannides, Yannis M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Central Should the Central Bank Be?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blinder, Alan S.
The nature and scope of the Federal Reserve's authority and the structure of its decision making are now "on the table" to an extent that has not been seen since 1935, and the Fed's vaunted independence is under some attack. This essay asks what the Federal Reserve should and shouldn't do, leaning heavily on the concept of economies of scope. In particular; I conclude that the central bank should monitor and regulate systemic risk because preserving financial stability is (a) closely aligned with the standard objectives of monetary policy and (b) likely to require lender of last resort powers. I also conclude that the Fed should supervise large financial institutions because that function is so closely to regulating systemic risk. However, several other functions now performed by the Fed could easily be done elsewhere. (JEL E52, E58, G21, G28)</description><author>Blinder, Alan S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Powers for the Federal Reserve?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldstein, Martin
In this essay, I explain my reasons for the following policy recommendations: (1) The Fed should continue to manage monetary policy as it has in the past, should act as the nation's lender of last resort, should fully supervise the large hank holding companies and their subsidiary banks, and should be given resolution authority over the institutions that it supervises. (2) While a council of supervisors and regulators can play a useful role in dealing with macro prudential risks, it should not replace the central role of the Federal Reserve. (3) The virtually unlimited lending powers that the Fed has recently exercised in creating credit and helping individual institutions should he restricted in duration and subjected to formal Treasury approval backed by Congressional preauthorization of funds. (4) The Fed's capital rules for commercial banks need to he strengthened by replacing the existing risk-based capital approach with a broader definition of risk and the introduction of contingent capital. (5) Subjecting mortgage lending to a broader range of Federal Reserve regulations and allowing the Fed to deal with nonbank creators of mortgage products would be better than the creation of a new consumer financial protection organization. (JEL E52, E58, G21, G28)</description><author>Feldstein, Martin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncommon Sense: Economic Insights, from Marriage to Terrorism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levinson, Marc
nan</description><author>Levinson, Marc</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Life and Times of Raul Prebisch, 1901-1986</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fishlow, Albert
nan</description><author>Fishlow, Albert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Networks in Telecommunications: Economics and Law.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crandall, Robert W.
nan</description><author>Crandall, Robert W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Nature of Demography.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lam, David
nan</description><author>Lam, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Has the Cure? Hamilton Project Ideas on Health Care.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Helen
nan</description><author>Levy, Helen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption and Saving: Models of Intertemporal Allocation and Their Implications for Public Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Attanasio, Orazio P.; Weber, Guglielmo
This paper provides a critical survey of the large literature on the life cycle model of consumption, both from an empirical and a theoretical point of view. It discusses several approaches that have been taken in the literature to bring the model to the data, their empirical successes, and their failures. Finally, the paper reviews a number of changes to the standard life cycle model that could help solve the remaining empirical puzzles.</description><author>Attanasio, Orazio P.; Weber, Guglielmo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Offshoring of American Jobs: What Response from US Economic Policy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antras, Pol
nan</description><author>Antras, Pol</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oil, Dollars, Debt, and Crises: The Global Curse of Black Gold.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kilian, Lutz
nan</description><author>Kilian, Lutz</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>This Time Is Different: Eight Centuries of Financial Folly.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boskin, Michael J.
nan</description><author>Boskin, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fiscal Federalism: Principles and Practices of Multiorder Governance.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McMillan, Melville L.
nan</description><author>McMillan, Melville L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Microtheory of Innovative Entrepreneurship.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henrekson, Magnus; Sanandaji, Tino
nan</description><author>Henrekson, Magnus; Sanandaji, Tino</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Smart Energy Policy: An Economist's Rx for Balancing Cheap, Clean, and Secure Energy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Walls, Margaret
nan</description><author>Walls, Margaret</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Warming and the World Trading System.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischer, Carolyn; Mavroidis, Petros C.
nan</description><author>Fischer, Carolyn; Mavroidis, Petros C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Climate Change and Agriculture: An Economic Analysis of Global Impacts, Adaptation and Distributional Effects.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Runge, Carlisle Ford
nan</description><author>Runge, Carlisle Ford</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Global Deal: Climate Change and the Creation of a New Era of Progress and Prosperity.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yohe, Gary
nan</description><author>Yohe, Gary</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>World Development Report 2010: Development and Climate Change.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mendelsohn, Robert
nan</description><author>Mendelsohn, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Douglass C. North, John Joseph Wallis, and Barry R. Weingast's Violence and Social Orders: A Conceptual Framework for Interpreting Recorded Human History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, Robert
In Violence and Social Orders: A Conceptual Framework for Interpreting Recorded Human History, Douglass C. North, John Joseph Wallis, and Barry R. Weingast probe the organizational foundations of development. Outlining the properties of the "natural" and "open entry" societies, they highlight as well the conditions under which societies can move from one to the other, thereby achieving political order and economic prosperity.</description><author>Bates, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Services Trade and Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francois, Joseph; Hoekman, Bernard
A substantial body of research has taken shape on trade in services since the mid-1980s. Much of this is inspired by the WTO and regional trade agreements. However, an increasing number of papers focus on the impacts of unilateral services sector liberalization. The literature touches on important linkages between trade and FDI in services and the general pattern of productivity growth and economic development. This paper surveys the literature on services trade, focusing on contributions that investigate the determinants of international trade and investment in services, the potential gains from greater trade, and efforts to cooperate to achieve such liberalization through trade agreements. There is increasing evidence that services liberalization is a major potential source of gains in economic performance, including productivity in manufacturing and the coordination of activities both between and within firms. The performance of service sectors, and thus services policies, may also be an important determinant of trade volumes, the distributional effects of trade, and overall patterns of economic growth and development. At the same time, services trade is also a source of increasing political unease about the impacts of globalization on labor markets, linked to worries about offshoring and the potential pressure this places on wages in high income countries.</description><author>Francois, Joseph; Hoekman, Bernard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Macroeconomic Costs and Benefits of the EMU and Other Monetary Unions: An Overview of Recent Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beetsma, Roel; Giuliodori, Massimo
This article provides an overview of recent research into the macroeconomic costs and benefits of monetary unification. We are primarily interested in Europe's monetary union. Given that unification entails the loss of a policy instrument, its potential benefits have to be found elsewhere. Unification may serve as a vehicle for beneficial institutional changes. In particular, it may be a route toward an independent monetary policy, which alleviates the scope for political pressure to relax monetary policy. Unification also eliminates harmful monetary policy spillovers and competitive devaluations. We explore how disagreement between the monetary and fiscal authorities about their policy objectives can lead to extreme macroeconomic outcomes. Further, we pay considerable attention to the desirability ( or not) of fiscal constraints and fiscal coordination in a monetary union. Monetary commitment and fiscal free riding play a key role in this regard. Similar free-riding issues also feature prominently in the analysis of how unification influences structural reforms. We end with a brief discussion of monetary unification outside Europe. The cost-benefit trade-off of unification may differ substantially between industrialized and less-developed countries, where differences in fiscal needs and, hence, the reliance on seigniorage revenues may dominate the scope for unification.</description><author>Beetsma, Roel; Giuliodori, Massimo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regression Discontinuity Designs in Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, David S.; Lemieux, Thomas
This paper provides an introduction and "user guide" to Regression Discontinuity (RD) designs for empirical researchers. It presents the basic theory behind the research design, details when RD is likely to be valid or invalid given economic incentives, explains why it is considered a "quasi-experimental" design, and summarizes different ways (with their advantages and disadvantages) of estimating RD designs and the limitations of interpreting these estimates. Concepts are discussed using examples drawn from the growing body of empirical research using RD. (JEL C21, C31)</description><author>Lee, David S.; Lemieux, Thomas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Building Bridges Between Structural and Program Evaluation Approaches to Evaluating Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heckman, James J.
This paper compares the structural approach to economic policy analysis with the program evaluation approach. It offers a third way to do policy analysis that combines the best features of both approaches. I illustrate the value of this alternative approach by making the implicit economics of LATE explicit, thereby extending the interpretability and range of policy questions that LATE can answer. (JEL C21, E61)</description><author>Heckman, James J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Better LATE Than Nothing: Some Comments on Deaton (2009) and Heckman and Urzua (2009)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Imbens, Guido W.
Two recent papers, Deaton (2009) and Heckman and Urzua (2009), argue against what they see as an excessive and inappropriate use of experimental and quasi-experimental methods in empirical work in economics in the last decade. They specifically question the increased use of instrumental variables and natural experiments in labor economics and of randomized experiments in development economics. In these comments, I will make the case that this move toward shoring up the internal validity of estimates, and toward clarifying the description of the population these estimates are relevant for, has been important and beneficial in increasing the credibility of empirical work in economics. I also address some other concerns raised by the Deaton and Heckman-Urzua papers. (JEL C21, C31)</description><author>Imbens, Guido W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Instruments, Randomization, and Learning about Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deaton, Angus
There is currently much debate about the effectiveness of foreign aid and about what kind of projects can engender economic development. There is skepticism about the ability of econometric analysis to resolve these issues or of development agencies to learn from their own experience. In response, there is increasing use in development economics of randomized controlled trials (RCTs) to accumulate credible knowledge of what works, without overreliance on questionable theory or statistical methods. When RCTs are not possible, the proponents of these methods advocate quasi-randomization through instrumental variable (IV) techniques or natural experiments. I argue that many of these applications are unlikely to recover quantities that are useful for policy or understanding: two key issues are the misunderstanding of exogeneity and the handling of heterogeneity. I illustrate from the literature on aid and growth. Actual randomization faces similar problems as does quasi-randomization, notwithstanding rhetoric to the contrary. I argue that experiments have no special ability to produce more credible knowledge than other methods, and that actual experiments are frequently subject to practical problems that undermine any claims to statistical or epistemic superiority. I illustrate using prominent experiments in development and elsewhere. As with IV methods, RCT-based evaluation of projects, without guidance from an understanding of underlying mechanisms, is unlikely to lead to scientific progress in the understanding of economic development. I welcome recent trends in development experimentation away from the evaluation of projects and toward the evaluation of theoretical mechanisms. (JEL C21, F35, O19)</description><author>Deaton, Angus</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Provocative Joan Robinson: The Making of a Cambridge Economist.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marcuzzo, Maria Cristina
nan</description><author>Marcuzzo, Maria Cristina</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tournament Approaches to Policy Reform: Making Development Assistance More Effective.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tarp, Finn
nan</description><author>Tarp, Finn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Experiments in Economics: Playing Fair with Money.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, David J.
nan</description><author>Cooper, David J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency and Redistribution: An Evaluative Review of Louis Kaplow's The Theory of Taxation and Public Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boadway, Robin
Louis Kaplow proposes a two-step methodology for normative policy analysis and illustrates it using various policy reforms. The first step is to identify efficiency gains when hypothetical lump-sum taxes can undo redistributive consequences. The second step evaluates the redistributive effects using a strictly welfaristic social welfare function. I critically review the foundations for Kaplow's procedure and its reliance on strict welfarism. I argue that basing efficiency gains on hypothetical lump- sum tax adjustments can lead to social welfare reducing policies if such tax adjustments are not carried out. I also indicate some conceptual problems with translating welfarism into policy evaluation when individuals have different utility function, and review one promising alternative approach.(JEL H20, H41, H50)</description><author>Boadway, Robin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Have Economic Reforms in Mexico Not Generated Growth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kehoe, Timothy J.; Ruhl, Kim J.
Following its opening to trade and foreign investment in the mid-1980s, Mexico's economic growth has been modest at best, particularly in comparison with that of China. Comparing these countries and reviewing the literature, we conclude that the relation between openness and growth is not a simple one. Using standard trade theory, we find that Mexico has gained from trade, and by some measures, more so than China. We sketch out a theory in which developing countries can grow faster than the United States by reforming. As a country becomes richer, this sort of catch-up becomes more difficult. Absent continuing reforms, Chinese growth is likely to slow down sharply, perhaps leaving China at a level less than Mexico's real GDP per working-age person. (JEL E23, E65, F14, O10, O20, O47)</description><author>Kehoe, Timothy J.; Ruhl, Kim J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Designing Climate Mitigation Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aldy, Joseph E.; Krupnick, Alan J.; Newell, Richard G.; Parry, Ian W. H.; Pizer, William A.
This paper provides (for the nonspecialist) a highly streamlined discussion of the main issues, and controversies, in the design of climate mitigation policy. The first part of the paper discusses how much action to reduce greenhouse gas emissions at the global level is efficient under both the cost-effectiveness and welfare-maximizing paradigms. We then discuss various issues in the implementation of domestic emissions control policy, instrument choice, and incentives for technological innovation. Finally, we discuss alternative policy architectures at the international level. (JEL Q54, Q58)</description><author>Aldy, Joseph E.; Krupnick, Alan J.; Newell, Richard G.; Parry, Ian W. H.; Pizer, William A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Network Theory Connect to the Rest of Us? A Review of Matthew O. Jackson's Social and Economic Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rauch, James E.
The ubiquity of networks in our social lives has long been recognized, and their importance in our economic lives is increasingly recognized as well. Yet the literature synthesized in Matthew O. Jackson's Social and Economic Networks, which covers the theory of how networks form, decay, and shape behavior at a general level, has had little influence on either applied theory or empirical work in this area. This is partly because of limitations of network theory as it has evolved in this literature. After describing the network theory presented in the book, I discuss these limitations and make some tentative suggestions as to how they might be overcome. (JEL D85, L14, Z13)</description><author>Rauch, James E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quality Disclosure and Certification: Theory and Practice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dranove, David; Jin, Ginger Zhe
This essay reviews the theoretical and empirical literature on quality disclosure and certification. After comparing quality disclosure with other quality assurance mechanisms and describing a brief history of quality disclosure, we address two sets of theoretical issues. First, why don't sellers voluntarily disclose through a process of "unraveling" and, given the lack of unraveling, is it desirable to mandate seller disclosure? Second, when we rely on certifiers to act as the intermediary of quality disclosure, do certifiers necessarily report unbiased and accurate information? We further review empirical evidence on these issues, with a particular focus on healthcare, education, and finance. The empirical review covers quality measurement, the effect of third-party disclosure on consumer choice and seller behavior, as well as the economics of certifiers. (JEL D18, K32, L15, M31)</description><author>Dranove, David; Jin, Ginger Zhe</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Isn't Mexico Rich?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanson, Gordon H.
Over the last three decades, Mexico has aggressively reformed its economy, opening to foreign trade and investment, achieving fiscal discipline, and privatizing state owned enterprises. Despite these efforts, the country's economic growth has been lackluster, trailing that of many other developing nations. In this paper, I review arguments for why Mexico hasn't sustained higher rates of economic growth. The most prominent suggest that some combination of poorly functioning credit markets, distortions in the supply of nontraded inputs, and perverse incentives for informality creates a drag on productivity growth. These are factors internal to Mexico. One possible external factor is that the country has the bad luck of exporting goods that China sells, rather than goods that China buys. I assess evidence from recent literature on these arguments and suggest directions for future research. (JEL E23, E65, F14, O10, O20, O47)</description><author>Hanson, Gordon H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Immigration: Theory and Policy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewis, Ethan G.
nan</description><author>Lewis, Ethan G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Technology and Productivity Growth: German Trends and OECD Comparisons.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saunders, Adam
nan</description><author>Saunders, Adam</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Accumulation and Economic Growth in a Small Open Economy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kimbrough, Kent P.
nan</description><author>Kimbrough, Kent P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Patterns and Stories.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conley, Tim
nan</description><author>Conley, Tim</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Against Injustice: The New Economics of Amartya Sen</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Landemore, Helene
nan</description><author>Landemore, Helene</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Natural Experiments of History.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boustan, Leah
nan</description><author>Boustan, Leah</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Statistical Models and Causal Inference: A Dialogue with the Social Sciences.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chalak, Karim
nan</description><author>Chalak, Karim</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Scroogenomics: Why You Shouldn't Buy Presents for the Holidays.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Price, Joseph
nan</description><author>Price, Joseph</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Automatic: Changing the Way America Saves.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, James J.
nan</description><author>Choi, James J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A History of the Federal Reserve, vol 2</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cowen, Tyler
nan</description><author>Cowen, Tyler</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A History of the Federal Reserve, vol 2</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cowen, Tyler
nan</description><author>Cowen, Tyler</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Problems of Disadvantaged Youth: An Economic Perspective.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heinrich, Carolyn J.
nan</description><author>Heinrich, Carolyn J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ending Government Bailouts: As We Know Them.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stein, Jeremy C.
nan</description><author>Stein, Jeremy C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mother's Work and Children's Lives: Low-Income Families after Welfare Reform.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, Cecilia
nan</description><author>Conrad, Cecilia</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mission and Money: Understanding the University.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scott-Clayton, Judith
nan</description><author>Scott-Clayton, Judith</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Boulevard of Broken Dreams: Why Public Efforts to Boost Entrepreneurship and Venture Capital Have Failed-And What to Do About It.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Audretsch, David
nan</description><author>Audretsch, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Antitrust and Regulation in the EU and US: Legal and Economic Perspectives.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Persson, Lars; Tag, Joacim
nan</description><author>Persson, Lars; Tag, Joacim</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Land in Transition: Reform and Poverty in Rural Vietnam.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glewwe, Paul
nan</description><author>Glewwe, Paul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring the Value of Culture: Methods and Examples in Cultural Economics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klamer, Arjo
nan</description><author>Klamer, Arjo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Marketplace of Christianity.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiswick, Barry R.
nan</description><author>Chiswick, Barry R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Decline of Latin American Economies: Growth, Institutions, and Crises.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hallak, Juan Carlos
nan</description><author>Hallak, Juan Carlos</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Things Fell Apart: State Failure ill Late-Century Africa.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanna, Rema
nan</description><author>Hanna, Rema</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Job Creation and Poverty Reduction in India: Towards Rapid and Sustained Growth.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Senses, Mine Zeynep
nan</description><author>Senses, Mine Zeynep</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Price Fixing, 2nd edition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Suslow, Valerie Y.
nan</description><author>Suslow, Valerie Y.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Structure of International Law</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keohane, Robert O.
nan</description><author>Keohane, Robert O.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Color and Money: How Rich White Kids Are Winning the War over College Affirmative Action</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krislov, Marvin
nan</description><author>Krislov, Marvin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving School-to-Work Transitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clark, Damon
nan</description><author>Clark, Damon</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spin Cycle: How Research Is Used in Policy Debates: The Case of Charter Schools</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bifulco, Robert
nan</description><author>Bifulco, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Gender Impact of Social Security Reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stahlberg, Ann-Charlotte
nan</description><author>Stahlberg, Ann-Charlotte</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Banking Crises? The Politics and Policy of Bank Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Sudipto
nan</description><author>Bhattacharya, Sudipto</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Plight of the Fortune Tellers: Why We Need to Manage Financial Risk Differently</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jorion, Philippe
nan</description><author>Jorion, Philippe</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pop Finance: Investment Clubs and the New Investor Populism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajan, Uday
nan</description><author>Rajan, Uday</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regional Monetary Integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wyplosz, Charles
nan</description><author>Wyplosz, Charles</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary Policy Strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gali, Jordi
nan</description><author>Gali, Jordi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Evolution of Monetary Policy and Banking in the US</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlson, Mark A.
nan</description><author>Carlson, Mark A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cult of Statistical Significance: How the Standard Error Costs Us Jobs, Justice, and Lives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hymans, Saul R.
nan</description><author>Hymans, Saul R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Augustin Cournot: Modelling Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feiler, Lauren E.
nan</description><author>Feiler, Lauren E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Harry Johnson: A Life in Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corden, W. Max
nan</description><author>Corden, W. Max</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Milton Friedman: A Biography</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwartz, Anna Jacobson
nan</description><author>Schwartz, Anna Jacobson</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hunting Causes and Using Them: Approaches in Philosophy and Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoover, Kevin D.
nan</description><author>Hoover, Kevin D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>EconoPower: How a New Generation of Economists Is Transforming the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oster, Emily
nan</description><author>Oster, Emily</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dismal Science: How Thinking Like an Economist Undermines Community</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leonard, Thomas C.
nan</description><author>Leonard, Thomas C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Intercollegiate Sports</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Netz, Janet S.
nan</description><author>Netz, Janet S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crunch: Why Do I Feel So Squeezed? (And Other Unsolved Economic Mysteries)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frank, Robert H.
nan</description><author>Frank, Robert H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Michael Tomz's Reputation and International Cooperation: Sovereign Debt across Three Centuries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gersovitz, Mark
Repudiation and expropriation pose obstacles to the international mobility Of capital and thereby to efficient international allocation of resources. Tomz discusses the determinants of lending in the face of the threat of repudiation. Using history, he argues that debtor countries have sought a reputation for compliance with loan agreements to access future loans and that military or trade sanctions have been unimportant in sustaining lending. He discusses when and why banks have been more active as lenders relative to bondholders. This article situates Tomz's concerns in the broad themes of thought on obstacles to capital mobility and evaluates his arguments.</description><author>Gersovitz, Mark</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender Differences in Preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Croson, Rachel; Gneezy, Uri
This paper reviews the literature on gender differences in economic experiments. In the three main sections, we identify robust differences in risk preferences, social (other-regarding) preferences, and competitive preferences. We also speculate on. the source of these differences, as well as on their implications. Our hope is that this article will serve as a resource for those seeking to understand gender differences and to use as a starting point to illuminate the debate on gender-specific outcomes in. the labor and goods markets.</description><author>Croson, Rachel; Gneezy, Uri</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can the West Save Africa?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easterly, William
In the new millennium, the Western aid effort toward Africa has surged due to writings by well-known economists, a celebrity mass advocacy campaign, and decisions by Western leaders to make Africa a major foreign policy priority. This survey contrasts the predominant "transformational" approach (West comprehensively saves Africa) to occasional swings to a "marginal" approach (West takes one small step at a time to help individual Africans). Evaluation of "one step at a time" initiatives is generally easier than that of transformational ones either through controlled experiments (although these have been oversold) or simple case studies where it is easier to attribute outcomes to actions. We see two themes emerge from the literature survey: (1) escalation-as each successive Western transformational effort. has yielded disappointing results (as judged at least by stylized facts, since again, the econometrics are shaky), the response has been to try an, even more, ambitious effort and (2) the cycle of ideas-rather than a progressive testing and discarding of failed ideas, we see a cycle in aid ideas in many areas in Africa, with ideas going out of fashion, only to come back again later after some lapse long enough to forget the previous disappointing experience. Both escalation and cyclicality of ideas are symptomatic of the lack of learning that seems to be characteristic of the "transformational" approach. In, contrast, the "marginal" approach has had sonic successes in improving the well-being of individual Africans, such as the dramatic fall in mortality.</description><author>Easterly, William</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Psychology and Economics: Evidence from the Field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DellaVigna, Stefano
The research in Psychology and Economics (a.k.a. Behavioral Economics) suggests that individuals deviate from the standard model in three respects: (1) nonstandard preferences, (2) nonstandard beliefs, and (3) nonstandard decision making. In, this paper, I survey the empirical evidence from the field on these three classes of deviations. The evidence covers a number of applications, from consumption to finance, from crime to voting, from charitable giving to labor supply. In the class of nonstandard preferences, I discuss time preferences (self-control problems), risk preferences (reference dependence), and social preferences. On nonstandard beliefs, I present evidence on over-confidence, on the law of small numbers, and on projection bias. Regarding nonstandard decision, making, I cover framing, limited attention, menu effects, persuasion and social pressure, and emotions. I also present evidence on how rational actors-firms, employers, CEOs, investors, and politicians-respond to the nonstandard behavior described in, the survey. Finally, I briefly discuss under what conditions experience and,market interactions limit the impact of the nonstandard features.</description><author>DellaVigna, Stefano</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Korean Economy: The Challenges of FDI-led Globalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Noavook
nan</description><author>Park, Noavook</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Washington Shut Down Wall Street: The Great Financial Crisis of 1914 and the Origins of America's Monetary Supremacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bordo, Michael D.
nan</description><author>Bordo, Michael D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contours of the World Economy, 1-2030 AD: Essays in Macro-Economic History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guinnane, Timothy W.
nan</description><author>Guinnane, Timothy W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, Innovation, and Antitrust: A Theory of Market Leaders and Its Policy Implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acs, Zoltan J.
nan</description><author>Acs, Zoltan J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Staircases or Treadmills? Labor Market Intermediaries and Economic Opportunity in a Changing Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gottschalk, Peter
nan</description><author>Gottschalk, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Great Depressions of the Twentieth Century (vol 46, pg 669, 2008)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Temin, Peter
nan</description><author>Temin, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Developments in the Econometrics of Program Evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Imbens, Guido W.; Wooldridge, Jeffrey M.
Many empirical questions in economics and other social sciences depend on causal effects of programs or policies. In the last two decades, much research has been done on, the econometric and statistical analysis of such causal effects. This recent theoretical literature has built on, and combined features of earlier work in both the statistics and econometrics literatures. It has by now reached a level of maturity that makes it an important tool in many areas of empirical research in economics, including labor economies, public finance, development economics, industrial organization, and other areas of empirical microeconomics. In, this review, we discuss some of the recent developments. We focus primarily on practical issues for empirical researchers, as well as provide a historical overview of the area and give references to more technical research.</description><author>Imbens, Guido W.; Wooldridge, Jeffrey M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Healthy, Wealthy, and Wise: Socioeconomic Status, Poor Health in Childhood, and Human Capital Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Currie, Janet
There are many possible pathways between parental education, income, and health, and between child health and education, but only some of them, have been explored in the literature. This essay focuses on links between. parental socioeconomic status (as measured by education, income, occupation, or in, some cases area of residence) and, child health, and between child health and adult education. or income. Specifically, I ask two questions: What is the evidence regarding whether parental socioeconomic status affects child health? And, what, is the evidence relating child health to future educational and labor market outcomes? I show that there is now strong evidence of both links, suggesting that health could play a role in. the intergenerational transmission of economic status.</description><author>Currie, Janet</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Age of Milton Friedman</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shleifer, Andrei
Between 1980 and 2005, as the world embraced free market policies, living Standards rose sharply, while life, expectancy, educational attainment, and democracy improved and absolute poverty declined. Is this a coincidence? A collection of essays edited by Balcerowicz and Fischer argues that indeed reliance on free market forces is key to economic growth. A book by Stiglitz and others disagrees. I review and compare the two arguments.</description><author>Shleifer, Andrei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Globalization and the Welfare State: A Review of Hans-Werner Sinn's Can Germany Be Saved?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Snower, Dennis J.; Brown, Alessio J. G.; Merkl, Christian
What are the challenge that globalization makes on welfare states and how should welfare states respond? How should welfare states be designed to enable countries to reap the benefits of globalization? These are the main themes of Hans-Werner Sinn's book, Can Germany Be Saved? We view Germany as a case study of how a welfare state can go wrong in reacting the pressures of globalization. We present two views of globalization-the "specialization view" (of Sinn) and the "Great Reorganization view" (ours)-and examine the policy implications of each for the welfare state design.</description><author>Snower, Dennis J.; Brown, Alessio J. G.; Merkl, Christian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Do (and Don't) We Know about the Value Added Tax? A Review of Richard M. Bird and Pierre-Pascal Gendron's The VAT in Developing and Transitional Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keen, Michael
The VAT has taken. the tax world by storm over the last fifty years, but left little trace in the academic literature. Bird. and Gendron provide an impressively informed and informative account of the VAT experience in lower income countries, largely vindicating the tax and standard advice for its design. But they rightly stress too that dominant "expert opinion" on the VAT remains troublingly uninformed by serious analysis and evidence. This article focuses on some of these gaps and recent attempts to start filling them.</description><author>Keen, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Elements of Multinational Strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crowley, Meredith A.
nan</description><author>Crowley, Meredith A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The General Theory of Economic Evolution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ormerod, Paul
nan</description><author>Ormerod, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Philosophy of Economics: An Anthology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ross, Don
nan</description><author>Ross, Don</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictocracy: Market Mechanisms for Public and Private Decision Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zitzewitz, Eric
nan</description><author>Zitzewitz, Eric</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Termites in the Trading System: How Preferential Agreements Undermine Free Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baldwin, Richard
nan</description><author>Baldwin, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Do We Know About Globalization? Issues of Poverty and Income Distribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lipsey, Robert E.
nan</description><author>Lipsey, Robert E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debating China's Exchange Rate Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alfaro, Laura
nan</description><author>Alfaro, Laura</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Cooperate? The Incentive to Supply Global Public Goods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cline, William R.
nan</description><author>Cline, William R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxing Reforms: The Politics of the Consumption Tax in Japan, the United States, Canada and Australia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martin, Isaac W.
nan</description><author>Martin, Isaac W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US Taxation of Foreign Income</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grubert, Harry
nan</description><author>Grubert, Harry</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax Compliance and Tax Morale: A Theoretical and Empirical Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erard, Brian
nan</description><author>Erard, Brian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Happiness, Economics and Public Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rousseau, Jean-Benoit G.
nan</description><author>Rousseau, Jean-Benoit G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Happiness: Building Genuine Wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rousseau, Jean-Benoit G.
nan</description><author>Rousseau, Jean-Benoit G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Inequality and Higher Education: Access, Persistence, and Success</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breneman, David W.
nan</description><author>Breneman, David W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Happiness Quantified: A Satisfaction Calculus Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Powdthavee, Nattavudh
nan</description><author>Powdthavee, Nattavudh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Privatization and Ownership in Transition Economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Estrin, Saul; Hanousek, Jan; Kocenda, Evzen; Svejnar, Jan
In this paper, we evaluate what we have learned to date about the effects of privatization from the experiences during the last fifteen to twenty years in. the postcommunist (transition) economies and, where relevant, China. We distinguish separately the impact of privatization on efficiency, profitability, revenues, and other indicators and distinguish between studies on the basis of their econometric methodology in, order to focus attention on more credible results. The effect of privatization, is mostly positive in. Central Europe, but quantitatively smaller than that to foreign owners and greater in the later than earlier transition period. In. the Commonwealth of Independent States, privatization to foreign owners yields a positive or insignificant effect while privatization to domestic owners generates a negative or insignificant effect. The available papers on China find diverse results, with the effect of nonstate ownership on, total factor productivity being mostly positive but sometimes insignificant or negative.</description><author>Estrin, Saul; Hanousek, Jan; Kocenda, Evzen; Svejnar, Jan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics and Law of Sovereign Debt and Default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Panizza, Ugo; Sturzenegger, Federico; Zettelmeyer, Jeromin
This paper surveys the recent literature on sovereign debt and relates it to the evolution of the legal principles underlying the sovereign debt market and the experience of the most recent debt crises and defaults. It finds limited support for theories that explain the feasibility of sovereign debt based on either external sanctions or exclusion from the international capital market and more support for explanations that emphasize domestic costs of default. The paper concludes that there remains a case for establishing institutions that reduce the cost of default but the design of such institutions is not a trivial task.</description><author>Panizza, Ugo; Sturzenegger, Federico; Zettelmeyer, Jeromin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toward a Theory of Regulation for Developing Countries: Following Jean-Jacques Laffont's Lead</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Estache, Antonio; Wren-Lewis, Liam
The efficient operation and expansion, of infrastructures in developing countries is crucial for growth and poverty reduction. However, recent reforms aimed at improving the performance of these sectors have had limited success. Evidence suggests that, in many instances, this was because the traditional regulatory theory relied on, by policymakers was not suitable for the institutional context in developing countries. This article surveys more, recent theoretical work focusing on problems with regulation in these countries. At the heart of the survey is the work of Jean-Jacques Laffont, who, in the last decade of his life, set about developing a theoretical framework for regulation in developing countries. We consider the implications of his work, which, focused on the key institutional limitations faced in developing countries. We then discuss where experience suggests that there, are important omissions from this modeling, bringing in extensions and alternative approaches pursued by other authors. We conclude by summarizing the key ways in which regulatory policy will be different when institutions are weak. Overall, we find that an understanding of the institutional context and its implications arc, crucial when designing a regulatory framework for developing countries.</description><author>Estache, Antonio; Wren-Lewis, Liam</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Edward Luce's In Spite of the Gods: The Strange Rise of Modern India</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pritchett, Lant
India poses a development puzzle on a grand scale. Sixty years of electoral democracy, thirty years of rapid growth, and a number of world class institutions (such as the Institutes of Technology or Election Commission) have led to talk of India as a superpower in a league with the United States and China. Yet, on many fronts, India's indicators of human well-being (e.g., malnutrition, immunization) are at, or below, those of much poorer sub-Saharan African countries. Measures of the administrative capacity of the state on, basics like attendance, performance, and corruption reveal a potentially "flailing state" whose brilliantly formulated policies are disconnected from realities on the ground. This review essay of Ed Luce's In Spite of the Gods attempts to articulate the puzzle that is modern India and pose questions about the development trajectory of a country whose fortunes will shape our century.</description><author>Pritchett, Lant</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and Politics: A Review Essay Based on Kenneth Dam's Analysis of Legal Traditions in The Law-Growth Nexus</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roe, Mark J.; Siegel, Jordan I.
Strong financial markets arc widely thought to propel economic development, with many in finance seeing legal tradition, as fundamental to protecting investors sufficiently for finance to flourish. Kenneth Dam finds that the legal tradition view inaccurately portrays how legal systems work, how laws developed historically, and how government power is allocated in the various legal traditions. Yet, after probing the legal origins' literature for inaccuracies, Dam, does not deeply develop an alternative hypothesis to explain the world's differences in financial development. Nor does he challenge the origins core data, which could be origins' trump card. Hence, his analysis will not convince many economists, despite that his legal learning suggests conceptual and factual difficulties for the legal origins explanations. Yet, a dense political. economy explanation is already out there and the origins-based data has unexplored weaknesses consistent with, Dam's contentions. Knowing if the origins view is truly fundamental, flawed, or secondary is vital for financial development policy making because policymakers who believe it will pick policies that imitate what they think to be the core institutions of the preferred legal tradition. But if they have mistaken views, as Dam indicates they might, as to what the legal traditions' institutions really are and which types of laws are effective, or what is really most important to financial development, they will make policy mistakes-potentially serious ones.</description><author>Roe, Mark J.; Siegel, Jordan I.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>