<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JEP3</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Human resources from an organizational behavior perspective: Some paradoxes explained</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pfeffer, Jeffrey
Workplaces in America and elsewhere show pervasive job dissatisfaction, distrust, and disengagement, with the evidence suggesting that these problems are getting worse and have a number of negative consequences for employers as well as employees. What follows is a necessarily selective exploration of human resource management in organizations, covering why it is often done so badly, what theory suggests about how to do it better, and why so little of what is known is actually implemented.</description><author>Pfeffer, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Paying respect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellingsen, Tore; Johannesson, Magnus
Why do people work? Economic theory generally, and the principal-agent model specifically, emphasize the role of material incentives. But many academics, for example, work diligently year after year for a nearly fixed real salary, continuing to work hard as they approach retirement, although financial incentives are usually absent. We will argue that while economists have been right to focus on incentives, they have been wrong to focus so exclusively on material incentives. While workers appreciate monetary rewards, they also get utility from what (they believe that) others think about them. We lay out a body of evidence that, taken as a whole, makes a strong case that respect matters in the workplace, above and beyond material rewards. We discuss evidence that workers respond to attention, symbolic rewards, and trust - and even that material incentives in some cases lead to less effort. Finally, we argue that many of these observations can be captured in a standard principal-agent model, once the principals and the agents are assumed to care about respect or esteem as well as money.</description><author>Ellingsen, Tore; Johannesson, Magnus</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of dowry and brideprice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Siwan
Payments between families at the time of marriage have existed throughout the history of most developed countries and are currently pervasive in many areas of the developing world. These payments can be substantial enough to affect the welfare of women and a society's distribution of wealth. Recent estimates document transfers per marriage amounting to four to six times annual household income. This paper first establishes some basic facts about the prevalence and magnitude of marriage payments. It then discusses how such patterns vary across countries depending upon economic conditions, societal structures, institutions, and family characteristics. Marriage payments have evolved within societies over time: in some periods, payments have risen sharply; in some cases, payments have shifted from the grooms' side to the brides', and vice versa; sometimes, property rights over such payments shift between marrying partners and parental generations. The second part of this paper discusses the economic literature devoted to explaining these facts.</description><author>Anderson, Siwan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy reform and credit cards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>White, Michelle J.
From 1980 to 2004, the number of personal bankruptcy filings in the United States increased more than five-fold, from 288,000 to 1.5 million per year. By 2004, more Americans were filing for bankruptcy each year than were graduating from college, getting divorced, or being diagnosed with cancer. In 2005, the Bankruptcy Abuse Prevention and Consumer Protection Act (BAPCPA) became law. It made bankruptcy law much less debtor-friendly. Personal bankruptcy filings fell to 600,000 in 2006. This paper explores why personal bankruptcy rates rose, and will argue that the main reason is the growth of "revolving debt" - mainly credit card debt. It explains how the Bankruptcy Abuse Prevention and Consumer Protection Act (BAPCPA) of 2005 altered the conditions of bankruptcy. Finally, this essay considers the balances that need to be struck in a bankruptcy system and how the U.S. bankruptcy system strikes these balances in comparison with other countries. I argue that a less debtor-friendly bankruptcy policy should be accompanied by changes in bank regulation and truth-in-lending rules, so that lenders have a greater chance of facing losses when they supply too much credit or charge excessively high interest rates and fees.</description><author>White, Michelle J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markets - Preserving funeral markets with ready-to-embalm laws</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harrington, David E.
Thirty-nine states currently have ready-to-embalm laws, which typically require that all firms selling any type of funeral service (even those specializing in cremations) have embalming preparation rooms and all funeral directors be trained as embalmers. Ready-to-embalm laws are designed to preserve the status-quo in funeral markets, thereby protecting currently licensed funeral directors from the ravages of competition. These laws attempt to preserve funeral markets as they existed in the mid-twentieth century, markets that centered on traditional funerals sold by small, full-service funeral homes. The economic chemicals needed to preserve the status quo are harsh, leading to higher funeral prices and often poorer-quality services. The empirical evidence suggests that these laws reduce the cremation rate, the market share of Internet casket retailers, the penetration of national chains, and the number of funeral directors who are immigrants. They also appear to substantially increase the retail price of direct cremations and the cost of traditional funerals. Commissions in several states have recently recommended repealing ready-to-embalm laws, arguing that they are anticompetitive. The evidence presented in this paper should make their recommendations harder to ignore.</description><author>Harrington, David E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retrospectives Leon Walras and the Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sandmo, Agnar
This feature addresses the history of economic terms and ideas. The hope is to deepen the workaday dialogue of economists, while perhaps also casting new light on ongoing questions. If you have suggestions for future topics or authors, please write to Joseph Persky, c/o journal of Economic Perspectives, Department of Economics (M/C 144), University of Illinois at Chicago, 601 South Morgan Street, Room 2103, Chicago, Illinois 60607-7121.</description><author>Sandmo, Agnar</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recommendations for further reading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Timothy
This section will list readings that may be especially useful to teachers of undergraduate economics, as well as other articles that are of broader cultural interest. In general, the articles chosen will be expository or integrative and not focus on original research. If you write or read an appropriate article, please send a copy of the article (and possibly a few sentences describing it) to Timothy Taylor, c/o journal of Economic Perspectives, Macalester College, 1600 Grand Ave., Saint Paul, Minnesota, 55105.</description><author>Taylor, Timothy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How wages change: Micro evidence from the international wage flexibility project (vol 21, pg 195, 2007)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dickens, William T.; Goette, Lorenz; Groshen, Erica L.; Holden, Steinar; Messina, Julian; Schweitzer, Mark E.; Turunen, Jarkko; Ward, Melanie E.
nan</description><author>Dickens, William T.; Goette, Lorenz; Groshen, Erica L.; Holden, Steinar; Messina, Julian; Schweitzer, Mark E.; Turunen, Jarkko; Ward, Melanie E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transportation costs and international trade in the second era of globalization (vol 21, pg 131, 2007)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hummels, David
nan</description><author>Hummels, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The case for forecast targeting as a monetary policy strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Woodford, Michael
At central banks around the world, including the Bank of England, Sweden's Riksbank, Norway's Norges Bank, and the Reserve Bank of New Zealand, policy is conducted on the basis of "inflation-forecast targeting": the central bank constructs quantitative projections of the economy's expected future evolution based on the way in which it intends to control short-term interest rates, and public discussion of those projections plays a critical role in justifying the banks' conduct of monetary policy to the public. What accounts for the appeal of this approach? Should it be adopted more widely or more explicitly? I review the long-running debate between proponents of monetary rules and proponents of discretionary monetary policy and argue that inflation-forecast targeting represents a powerful synthesis of the two approaches. I explore some common questions that arise about inflation-forecast targeting and consider how the U.S. Federal Reserve might move toward an explicit policy of inflation-forecast targeting.</description><author>Woodford, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Some uses of happiness data in economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Di Tella, R.; MacCulloch, R.
Happiness research is based on the idea that it is fruitful to study empirical measures of individual welfare. The most common is the answer to a simple well-being question such as "Are you Happy?" Hundreds of thousands of individuals have been asked this question, in many countries and over many years. Researchers have begun to use these data to tackle a variety of important questions in economics. Some require strong assumptions concerning interpersonal comparisons of utility, but others make only mild assumptions in this regard. They range from microeconomic questions, such as the way income and utility are connected, to macroeconomic questions such as the tradeoff between inflation and unemployment, including large areas in political economy. Public policy is another area where progress using happiness data is taking place. Given the central role of utility notions in economic theory, we argue that the use of happiness data in empirical research should be given serious consideration.</description><author>Di Tella, R.; MacCulloch, R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Developments in the measurement of subjective well-being</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahneman, D.; Krueger, A. B.
Direct reports of subjective well-being may have a useful role in the measurement of consumer preferences and social welfare, if they can be done in a credible way. Can well-being be measured by a subjective survey, even approximately? In this paper, we discuss research on how individuals' responses to subjective well-being questions vary with their circumstances and other factors. We will argue that it is fruitful to distinguish among different conceptions of utility rather than presume to measure a single, unifying concept that motivates all human choices and registers all relevant feelings and experiences. While various measures of well-being are useful for some purposes, it is important to recognize that subjective well-being measures features of individuals' perceptions of their experiences, not their utility as economists typically conceive of it. Those perceptions are a more accurate gauge of actual feelings if they are reported closer to the time of, and in direct reference to, the actual experience. We conclude by proposing the U-index, a misery index of sorts, which measures the proportion of time that people spend in an unpleasant state, and has the virtue of not requiring a cardinal conception of individuals' feelings.</description><author>Kahneman, D.; Krueger, A. B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Poverty in America: Trends and explanations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoynes, H. W.; Page, M. E.; Stevens, A. H.
Despite robust growth in real GDP per capita in the last three decades, U.S. poverty rates have changed very little. We summarize some basic facts about poverty in the United States, relying on a combination of previously published data from the Census Bureau and our own tabulations based on Current Population Survey data. We then discuss and evaluate four determinants of changes in the poverty rate that have been advanced in the literature: the impact of labor market opportunities; the role of changes in family structure; the role played by government antipoverty programs; and the role of immigration.</description><author>Hoynes, H. W.; Page, M. E.; Stevens, A. H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Poor people in rich nations: The United States in comparative perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smeeding, T.
Cross-national comparisons can teach lessons about antipoverty policy. While all nations value low poverty, high levels of economic self-reliance and equality of opportunity for younger persons, they differ dramatically in the extent to which they reach these goals. Nations also exhibit differences in the extent to which working age adults mix economic self-reliance (earned incomes), family support and government support to avoid poverty. We begin by reviewing international concepts and measures of poverty. The Luxembourg Income Study (LIS) database contains the information needed to construct comparable poverty measures for more than 30 nations. It allows comparisons of the level and trend of poverty and inequality across several nations, along with considerable detail on the sources of market incomes and public policies that shape these outcomes. We will highlight the different relationships between antipoverty policy and outcomes among several countries, and consider the implications of our analysis for research and for antipoverty policy in the United States. In doing so, we will draw on a growing body of evidence that evaluates antipoverty programs in a cross-national context.</description><author>Smeeding, T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anomalies - Utility maximization and experienced utility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahneman, D.; Thaler, R. H.
In this column, we discuss a version of the utility maximization hypothesis that can be tested-and we find that it is false. We review empirical challenges to utility maximization, which return to the old question of whether preferences optimize the experience of outcomes. Much of this work has focused on a necessary condition for utility-maximizing choices: an ability of economic agents to make accurate, or at least unbiased, forecasts of the hedonic outcomes of potential choices. The research we review shows that this condition is not satisfied: people do not always know what they will like; they often make systematic errors in predicting their future experience of outcomes and, as a result, fail to maximize their experienced utility. We discuss four areas in which errors of hedonic forecasting and choice have been documented: 1) where the emotional or motivational state of the agent is very different at t0 and at t1; 2) where the nature of the decision focuses attention on aspects of the outcome that will not be salient when it is actually experienced; 3) when choices are made on the basis of flawed evaluations of past experiences; and 4) when people forecast their future adjustment to new life circumstances.</description><author>Kahneman, D.; Thaler, R. H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - Debt relief</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arslanalp, S.; Henry, P. B.
At the Gleneagles summit in July 2005, the heads of state from the G-8 countries-the United States, Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, Russia and the United Kingdom-called on the International Monetary Fund (IMF), the World Bank and the African Development Bank to cancel 100 percent of their debt claims on the world's poorest countries. The world's richest countries have agreed in principle to forgive roughly $55 billion dollars owed by the world's poorest nations. This article considers the wisdom of the proposal for debt forgiveness, from the standpoint of stimulating economic growth in highly indebted countries. In the 1980s, debt relief under the "Brady Plan" helped to restore investment and growth in a number of middle-income developing countries. However, the debt relief plan for the Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) launched by the World Bank and the International Monetary Fund in 1996 has had little impact on either investment or growth in the recipient countries. We will explore the key differences between the countries targeted by these two debt relief schemes and argue that the Gleneagles proposal for debt relief is, at best, likely to have little effect at all. Debt relief is unlikely to help the world's poorest countries because, unlike the middle-income Brady countries, their main economic difficulty is not debt overhang, but an absence of functional economic institutions that provide the foundation for profitable investment and growth. We will show that debt relief may be more valuable for Brady-like middle-income countries than for low-income ones because of how it leverages the private sector.</description><author>Arslanalp, S.; Henry, P. B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markets - Beer in Germany and the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, W. J.
Between 1950 and 2000, the four-firm producer-concentration ratio for beer increased from 22 to 95 in the United States; and Anheuser-Busch's share of domestic output ballooned from 6 to 54 percent. In Germany, concentration has risen, but it remains low. In 2000, the four-firm producer-concentration ratio was just 29; and the eight-firm ratio in Germany was smaller than the one-firm ratio in the United States. In 2005, after five years of important mergers involving big brewers, the German beer industry was still much less concentrated than its American counterpart. In this article, I discuss several candidate explanations for the failure of beer-producer-concentration to rise as much in Germany as in the United States: the relevance of the new technologies to German brewers, the preferences of German consumers, the rules for advertising on German television and other factors, largely absent from the consensus interpretation of American experience. I find that market structure depends on a remarkably broad range of factors, extending well beyond technological opportunity and market size.</description><author>Adams, W. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's in a surname? The effects of surname initials on academic success</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Einav, L.; Yariv, L.
In this paper, we focus on the effects of surname initials on professional outcomes in the academic labor market for economists. We begin our analysis with data on faculty in all top 35 U.S. economics departments. Faculty with earlier surname initials are significantly more likely to receive tenure at top ten economics departments, are significantly more likely to become fellows of the Econometric Society, and, to a lesser extent, are more likely to receive the Clark Medal and the Nobel Prize. These statistically significant differences remain the same even after we control for country of origin, ethnicity, religion or departmental fixed effects. As a test, we replicate our analysis for faculty in the top 35 U.S. psychology departments, for which coauthorships are not normatively ordered alphabetically. We find no relationship between alphabetical placement and tenure status in psychology. We suspect the "alphabetical discrimination" reported in this paper is linked to the norm in the economics profession prescribing alphabetical ordering of credits on coauthored publications. We also investigate the extent to which the effects of alphabetical placement are internalized by potential authors in their choices to work with different numbers of coauthors as well as in their willingness to follow the alphabetical ordering norm.</description><author>Einav, L.; Yariv, L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Electronic trading in stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoll, H. R.
Modern trading technology clashes with the traditional organization of a stock exchange, where transactions were consummated via face-to-face negotiation. The modern trading facility is no longer a place. Rather, it is a computer system over which transactions are entered, routed, executed and cleared electronically with little or no human intervention. In this article, I examine how electronic trading has altered stock markets. I begin with an overview of how the stock trading process works and then address a number of questions. How have the jobs of traditional stock market dealers on the NYSE and on Nasdaq been affected by electronic trading? How do electronic communications networks differ from traditional markets? How has electronic trading affected bid-ask spreads and commission costs? What subtle issues arise in electronic trading when dealer and customer interests diverge? Will computer programs replace human judgment? What is the effect of electronic trading on the number and types of securities markets? What is the role of regulation in electronic markets?</description><author>Stoll, H. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economy of the early Roman Empire</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Temin, P.
Many inhabitants of ancient Rome lived well. Tourists marvel at the temples, baths, roads and aqueducts that they built. Economists also want to understand the existence of a flourishing and apparently prosperous economy two millennia ago. Market institutions and a stable government appear to have been the combination that produced this remarkable result. This essay provides an economist's view of the Roman economy that emphasizes the role of markets. I focus on the early Roman Empire, from 27 BCE to around 200 CE. I begin with some indications suggesting that the standard of living in ancient Rome was similar to that of early modern period of seventeenth- and eighteenth-century Europe, an extraordinary achievement for any economy in the ancient world. I then argue that ancient Rome managed to achieve this high standard of living through the combined operation of moderately stable political conditions and markets for goods, labor and capital, which allowed specialization and efficiency. After surveying the labor and financial markets in turn, I return to the broad questions of how the Romans prospered and the economy appears to have grown.</description><author>Temin, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Addressing absence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, A.; Duflo, E.
Absent providers are a major problem both for public health facilities and primary schools in many developing countries. For example, in India, absence rates for teachers are over 24 percent, and for health providers they are over 40 percent. This paper presents evidence on a number of innovative strategies to reduce absenteeism in government- and nongovernmental organization-run schools and health facilities. These strategies were implemented in Kenya and India over the past few years and have been evaluated using the randomized evaluation methodology. The strategies involved alternative levers to fight absence. Some tried to improve incentives for providers, either through rewards and punishments implemented by external monitors, or through facilitating a more active involvement of those who expect to benefit from the service. Others are based on the idea that the providers are discouraged by the lack of interest among the potential beneficiaries in what they are being offered; these strategies aim at increasing the demand for the services as a way of putting more pressure on the providers. The results of these efforts, taken together, shed light not only on ways to address the problem of absence in the public sector, but also on the underlying reasons for this phenomenon.</description><author>Banerjee, A.; Duflo, E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Missing in action: Teacher and health worker absence in developing countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaudhury, N.; Hammer, J.; Kremer, M.; Muralidharan, K.; Rogers, F. H.
In this paper, we report results from surveys in which enumerators made unannounced visits to primary schools and health clinics in Bangladesh, Ecuador, India, Indonesia, Peru and Uganda and recorded whether they found teachers and health workers in the facilities. Averaging across the countries, about 19 percent of teachers and 35 percent of health workers were absent. The survey focused on whether providers were present in their facilities, but since many providers who were at their facilities were not working, even these figures may present too favorable a picture. For example, in India, one-quarter of government primary school teachers were absent from school, but only about one-half of the teachers were actually teaching when enumerators arrived at the schools. We will provide background on education and health care systems in developing; analyze the high absence rates across sectors and countries; investigate the correlates, efficiency, and political economy of teacher and health worker absence; and consider implications for policy.</description><author>Chaudhury, N.; Hammer, J.; Kremer, M.; Muralidharan, K.; Rogers, F. H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Europe and the west? Why not China?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Landes, D. S.
nan</description><author>Landes, D. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Religion and economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McCleary, R. M.; Barro, R. J.
nan</description><author>McCleary, R. M.; Barro, R. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of family in family firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertrand, M.; Schoar, A.
nan</description><author>Bertrand, M.; Schoar, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Purple America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ansolabehere, S.; Rodden, J.; Snyder, J. M.
nan</description><author>Ansolabehere, S.; Rodden, J.; Snyder, J. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Myths and realities of American political geography</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glaeser, E. L.; Ward, B. A.
nan</description><author>Glaeser, E. L.; Ward, B. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>People flows in globalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Freeman, Richard B.
nan</description><author>Freeman, Richard B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price changes in the Euro area and the United States: Some facts from individual consumer price data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dhyne, E.; Alvarez, L. J.; Le Bihan, H.; Veronese, G.; Dias, D.; Hoffmann, J.; Jonker, N.; Lunnemann, P.; Rumler, F.; Vilmunen, J.
nan</description><author>Dhyne, E.; Alvarez, L. J.; Le Bihan, H.; Veronese, G.; Dias, D.; Hoffmann, J.; Jonker, N.; Lunnemann, P.; Rumler, F.; Vilmunen, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assassinations: Evaluating the effectiveness of an Israeli counterterrorism policy using stock market data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zussman, Asaf; Zussman, Noam
nan</description><author>Zussman, Asaf; Zussman, Noam</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markets - The Fulton fish market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graddy, K.
nan</description><author>Graddy, K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>History lessons - The birth of impersonal exchange: The community responsibility system and impartial justice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greif, Avner
nan</description><author>Greif, Avner</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does culture affect economic outcomes?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guiso, L.; Sapienza, P.; Zingales, L.
nan</description><author>Guiso, L.; Sapienza, P.; Zingales, L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The coining of "privatization" and Germany's national socialist party</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bel, Germa
The concept of privatization attracted much attention in the late 1970s and early 1980s, as Margaret Thatcher's privatization policies were implemented in the United Kingdom. My goal here is not to comment on the merits of privatization as a policy, but rather to investigate the history of the term "privatization" in economics and to shed some light on the context in which the word was coined. Although the origin of the term is often attributed to a 1969 book by Peter Drucker, I will show that this attribution is incorrect, and that the terminology of privatization played an evolving role in German economic policy from the 1930s through the 1950s.</description><author>Bel, Germa</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An economic evaluation of the moneyball hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hakes, Jahn K.; Sauer, Raymond D.
Michael Lewis's book, Moneyball, describes how an innovative manager working for the Oakland Athletics successfully exploited an inefficiency in baseball's labor market over a prolonged period of time. We evaluate Lewis's claims by applying standard econometric procedures to data on player productivity and compensation from 1999 to 2004. These methods support Lewis's argument that certain baseball skills were valued inefficiently in the early part of this period, and that this inefficiency was profitably exploited by managers with the ability to generate and interpret statistical knowledge. Consistent with Lewis's story and economic reasoning, as knowledge of the inefficiency became increasingly dispersed across baseball teams the market corrected the original mispricing.</description><author>Hakes, Jahn K.; Sauer, Raymond D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the academic labor market initially allocate new graduates efficiently?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smeets, Valerie; Warzynski, Frederic; Coupe, Tom
It is not surprising that economics graduate students from elite and very good schools find better jobs after completion of their Ph.D. degree, on average, than do candidates from less prestigious universities. Yet the job market outcome for candidates from the same university varies quite a lot. While the top candidates from the elite schools are often able to find jobs in other elite universities, it is unclear how "average" candidates from elite schools fare compared to the top students from relatively less prestigious schools and how the relative job market outcome relates to future success as a researcher. The objective of this paper is to investigate these issues. In this paper, we compare the career trajectories of candidates coming from three different types of schools: elite universities, very good universities, and good universities. We define three types of graduates within each group: those who placed best; those who had an average placement; and those who found jobs at lower levels. Then, for each of these nine groups, we look at initial and current affiliations and we compare publication patterns of the graduates more than a decade into their academic careers. Can we say that the initial allocation was efficient, in the sense that those who placed higher were also more productive in research terms? And to what extent does the labor market for economists adapt and allow economists to move between schools as the ability of individuals to publish their work manifests itself over time?</description><author>Smeets, Valerie; Warzynski, Frederic; Coupe, Tom</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Initial labor market conditions and long-term outcomes for economists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oyer, Paul
Each year, graduate students entering the academic job market worry that they will suffer due to uncontrollable macroeconomic risk. Given the importance of general human capital and the relative ease of publicly observing productivity in academia, one might expect that long-term labor market outcomes for students graduating in unfavorable climates will resemble long-term outcomes for those graduating in favorable climates. In this paper, I analyze the relationship between macroeconomic conditions at graduation, initial job placement, and long-term outcomes for Ph.D. economists from seven programs. Using macroeconomic conditions as an instrument for initial placement, I show that a quality and type of initial job have a causal effect on long-term job characteristics. I also show that better initial placement increases research productivity, which helps to limit the set of economic models that can explain the effect of initial placement on long-term jobs.</description><author>Oyer, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of HIV/AIDS in low-income countries: The case for prevention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Canning, David
nan</description><author>Canning, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of mortality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cutler, David; Deaton, Angus; Lleras-Muney, Adriana
nan</description><author>Cutler, David; Deaton, Angus; Lleras-Muney, Adriana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The growth in the social security disability rolls: A fiscal crisis unfolding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Autor, David H.; Duggan, Mark G.
nan</description><author>Autor, David H.; Duggan, Mark G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment insurance: Strengthening the relationship between theory and policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nicholson, Walter; Needels, Karen
nan</description><author>Nicholson, Walter; Needels, Karen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changes in labor force participation in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Juhn, Chinhui; Potter, Simon
nan</description><author>Juhn, Chinhui; Potter, Simon</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The flow approach to labor markets: New data sources and micro-macro links</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, Steven J.; Faberman, R. Jason; Haltiwanger, John
nan</description><author>Davis, Steven J.; Faberman, R. Jason; Haltiwanger, John</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Continuity and change in the international diamond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spar, Debora L.
The international diamond cartel, which presides over the production side of the industry, may be the most successful and longest-lasting cartel in the world. The dominant company in the industry, DeBeers, has been around since 1880 and has been controlled by a single South African family, the Oppenheimers, since 1925. Eight countries produce the bulk of the world's gem diamonds, and most of the producing entities within these countries conform to a set of rules. This conformity is the product of over a century of careful planning and negotiation, in which DeBeers has undertaken largely successful efforts to control the diamond trade and maximize its long-term prospects. The past decade has seen the end of apartheid in South Africa, the fall of communism in Russia, the opening of major mines in Canada, and the emergence of a worldwide movement against so-called "blood" or "conflict" diamonds. While, these developments have pummeled the diamond industry and forced its central players - most notably DeBeers - to change the nature of their trade, these changes have not affected the core dynamic of the global diamond market. It remains an industry dominated by a single firm and an industry in which, perhaps uniquely, all of the major players understand the extent to which their long-term livelihood depends on the fate and actions of the others.</description><author>Spar, Debora L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The London congestion charge</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leape, Jonathan
nan</description><author>Leape, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Avoiding invalid instruments and coping with weak instruments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murray, Michael P.
nan</description><author>Murray, Michael P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interview with Robert A. Mundell</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vane, Howard R.; Mulhearn, Chris
nan</description><author>Vane, Howard R.; Mulhearn, Chris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The European Central Bank, the euro, and global financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dominguez, Kathryn M. E.
nan</description><author>Dominguez, Kathryn M. E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The real effects of European monetary union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lane, Philip R.
nan</description><author>Lane, Philip R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The macroeconomist as scientist and engineer</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mankiw, N. Gregory
nan</description><author>Mankiw, N. Gregory</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modern macroeconomics in practice: How theory is shaping policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chari, V. V.; Kehoe, Patrick J.
nan</description><author>Chari, V. V.; Kehoe, Patrick J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The homecoming of American college women: The reversal of the college gender gap</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldin, Claudia; Katz, Lawrence F.; Kuziemko, Ilyana
nan</description><author>Goldin, Claudia; Katz, Lawrence F.; Kuziemko, Ilyana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Richard Nixon pressured Arthur Bums: Evidence from the Nixon tapes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abrams, Burton A.
nan</description><author>Abrams, Burton A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markets - The US lodging industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalnins, Arturs
nan</description><author>Kalnins, Arturs</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cognitive reflection and decision making (vol 19, pg 39, 2005)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frederick, Shane
nan</description><author>Frederick, Shane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - Examining the justification for residential recycling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kinnaman, Thomas C.
nan</description><author>Kinnaman, Thomas C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What has mattered to economics since 1970</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, E. Han; Morse, Adair; Zingales, Luigi
nan</description><author>Kim, E. Han; Morse, Adair; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Irreversibility - Response</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arrow, K. J.; Dasgupta, P.; Goulder, L.
nan</description><author>Arrow, K. J.; Dasgupta, P.; Goulder, L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Irreversibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wasow, B.
nan</description><author>Wasow, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Data watch - Tort-uring the data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helland, E.; Klick, J.; Tabarrok, A.
This article discusses data available for researchers interested in the U.S. civil justice system and illustrates the uses of the various datasets with some interesting findings. Our focus is on torts, defined as an injury to person or property that is not covered by contract and for which civil liability may be imposed. The most common tort is the result of an auto accident. We discuss data useful for analyzing trends, data that are useful for cross-sectional research and finally data covering only a specific type of civil litigation such as medical malpractice. We conclude by discussing the limitations of all civil litigation data.</description><author>Helland, E.; Klick, J.; Tabarrok, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Direct democracy works</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Matsusaka, J. G.
The purpose of this essay is to describe the practice and theory of the increasingly important political phenomenon of direct democracy and the main lessons from the scholarly literature. Many questions remain to be answered, but the emerging view is that direct democracy works-allowing the general public to participate in lawmaking often seems to improve the performance of government.</description><author>Matsusaka, J. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The original management incentive schemes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holden, R. T.
During the 1990s, the structure of pay for top corporate executives shifted markedly as the use of stock options greatly expanded. By the early 2000s, as the dot-com boom ended and the Nasdaq stock index melted down, these modern executive incentive schemes were being sharply questioned on many grounds-for encouraging excessive risk-taking and a short-run orientation, for being an overly costly and inefficient method of providing incentives, and even for tempting managers of firms like Enron, WorldCom and Tyco to commit fraud in order to ensure a high stock price at the time of exercise. This article examines executive incentive schemes developed by Du Pont and General Motors in the 1920s-the original incentive schemes linking executive compensation to stock prices. The author argues that these plans were well-designed to pre-empt and address many of the criticisms of modern-day executive stock option plans.</description><author>Holden, R. T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accounting for stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bulow, J.; Shoven, J. B.
As public companies begin their new fiscal years, they are implementing a new and controversial Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB, 2004) proposal for expensing stock options. Applied to 2003 and 2004, this rule would have slashed reported earnings of the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 by 8.6 and 7.4 percent; the effect in the bubble years would have been more than twice as large. We describe the history of how these options have been expensed for financial statement purposes. We assess the new FASB approach and find that it is deeply flawed. The main purpose of the paper is to describe an alternative options expense valuation method, the Bulow-Shoven approach, that addresses these problems. Our approach is simpler than the new FASB methodology, less prone to earnings manipulation and more consistent with the way the rest of compensation is treated in financial statements.</description><author>Bulow, J.; Shoven, J. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The American mortgage in historical and international context</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, R. K.; Wachter, S. M.
The U.S. mortgage before the 1930s would be nearly unrecognizable today: it featured variable interest rates, high down payments and short maturities. The authors compare the form of U.S. home mortgages today with those in other countries. The U.S. mortgage provides many more options to borrowers than are commonly provided elsewhere: American homebuyers can choose whether to pay a fixed or floating rate of interest; they can lock in their interest rate in between the time they apply for the mortgage and the time they purchase their house; they can choose the time at which the mortgage rate resets; they can choose the term and the amortization period; they can prepay freely; and they can generally borrow against home equity freely. They can also obtain home mortgages at attractive terms with very low down payments. The authors discuss the nature of the U.S. government intervention in home mortgage markets that has led to the specific choices available to American homebuyers. They believe that the unique characteristics of the U.S. mortgage provide substantial benefits for American homeowners and the overall stability of the economy.</description><author>Green, R. K.; Wachter, S. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing high house prices: Bubbles, fundamentals and misperceptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Himmelberg, C.; Mayer, C.; Sinai, T.
How does one tell when rapid growth in house prices is caused by fundamental factors of supply and demand and when it is an unsustainable bubble? In this paper, we explain how to assess the state of house prices-both whether there is a bubble and what underlying factors support housing demand-in a way that is grounded in economic theory. In doing so, we correct four common fallacies about the costliness of the housing market. For a number of reasons, conventional metrics for assessing pricing in the housing market such as price-to-rent ratios or price-to-income ratios generally fail to reflect accurately the state of housing costs. To the eyes of analysts employing such measures, housing markets can appear "exuberant" even when houses are in fact reasonably priced. We construct a measure for evaluating the cost of home owning that is standard for economists-the imputed annual rental cost of owning a home, a variant of the user cost of housing-and apply it to 25 years of history across a wide variety of housing markets. This calculation enables us to estimate the time pattern of housing costs within a market. As of the end of 2004, our analysis reveals little evidence of a housing bubble.</description><author>Himmelberg, C.; Mayer, C.; Sinai, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual irrationality and aggregate outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fehr, E.; Tyran, J. R.
In their personal lives, many economists recognize that they are surrounded by individuals who are less than fully rational. In their professional lives, however, economists often use models that examine the interactions of fully rational agents. To reduce the cognitive dissonance of this situation, many economists believe that interactions in markets will correct or offset individually anomalous behaviors-although the reasons for this belief are often not clearly spelled out. This paper presents evidence indicating that "strategic complementarity" and "strategic substitutability" are important determinants of aggregate outcomes. Under strategic complementarity, a small amount of individual irrationality may lead to large deviations from the aggregate predictions of rational models; under strategic substitutability, a minority of rational agents may suffice to generate aggregate outcomes consistent with the predictions of rational models. Thus, the presence of strategic substitutability or complementarity seems to be a key condition in determining when a population that is heterogeneous with regard to rationality reaches either a "rational" or an "irrational" outcome.</description><author>Fehr, E.; Tyran, J. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cognitive reflection and decision making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frederick, S.
This paper introduces a three-item "Cognitive Reflection Test" (CRT) as a simple measure of one type of cognitive ability-the ability or disposition to reflect on a question and resist reporting the first response that comes to mind. The author will show that CRT scores are predictive of the types of choices that feature prominently in tests of decision-making theories, like expected utility theory and prospect theory. Indeed, the relation is sometimes so strong that the preferences themselves effectively function as expressions of cognitive ability-an empirical fact begging for a theoretical explanation. The author examines the relation between CRT scores and two important decision-making characteristics: time preference and risk preference. The CRT scores are then compared with other measures of cognitive ability or cognitive "style." The CRT scores exhibit considerable difference between men and women and the article explores how this relates to sex differences in time and risk preferences. The final section addresses the interpretation of correlations between cognitive abilities and decision-making characteristics.</description><author>Frederick, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The vulcanization of the human brain: A neural perspective on interactions between cognition and emotion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, J. D.
Emotions may explain inconsistencies in human behavior and forms of behavior that some have deemed irrational, though such behavior may seem more sensible after a discussion of the functions that emotions serve-or may have once served in our evolutionary past. People do have the capacity to override emotional responses. This capacity relies in large measure on the most recently evolved parts of our brains that support forms of behavior that are more recognizably rational. Neuroscientists are beginning to make headway in identifying the neural mechanisms involved in both emotional responses and higher cognitive processes. Among the most recent and exciting developments in neuroscience has been the introduction of methods for imaging the function of the intact human brain. This effort offers the promise of a deeper understanding of how and why emotions impact decision making, how this may contribute to behavior that appears to deviate from optimality, and how and when we are able to overcome such emotional responses.</description><author>Cohen, J. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A natural experiment in monetary policy covering three episodes of growth and decline in the economy and the stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friedman, M.
The third of three episodes in a major natural experiment in monetary policy that started more than 80 years ago is just now coming to an end. The experiment consists in observing the effect on the economy and the stock market of the monetary policies followed during and after three very similar periods of rapid economic growth in response to rapid technological change: the booms of the 1920s in the United States, the 1980s in Japan and the 1990s in the United States. In this experiment, the quantity of money is the counterpart of the experimenter's input. The performance of the economy and the level of the stock market are the counterpart of the experimenter's output. The results of this natural experiment are clear, at least for major ups and downs: what happens to the quantity of money has a determinative effect on what happens to national income and to stock prices. The results strongly support Anna Schwartz's and my 1963 conjecture about the role of monetary policy in the Great Contraction. They also support the view that monetary policy deserves much credit for the mildness of the recession that followed the collapse of the U.S. boom in late 2000.</description><author>Friedman, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intelligence failures: An organizational economics perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garicano, L.; Posner, R. A.
Two recent failures of the U.S. intelligence system have led to the creation of high-level investigative commissions. The failure to prevent the terrorist attacks of 9/11 prompted the creation of the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States (2004), or 9/11 Commission.The mistaken belief that Saddam Hussein had retained weapons of mass destruction prompted the creation of the Commission on the Intelligence Capabilities of the United States Regarding Weapons of Mass Destruction (2005), or the WMD Commission. In this paper, we use insights from organizational economics to analyze the principal organizational issues these commissions have raised in the ongoing discussion about how to prevent intelligence failures.</description><author>Garicano, L.; Posner, R. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The degradation of reported corporate profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, M. A.
Recent corporate scandals have highlighted abuses by firms overstating profits to capital markets. In a related but less noticed vein, the reporting of profits to tax authorities has come under increased scrutiny with heightened concerns over the spread of tax avoidance activities. How could firms simultaneously be inflating profits reported to the capital markets and understating profits reported to tax authorities? The practical answer is that American firms keep two sets of financial statements: a financial statement that reports "book profits" to the capital markets and a separate financial statement that reports "tax profits" to the government. These two profit reports can bear little resemblance to each other and follow distinct rules. This paper argues that the latitude afforded managers by the dual nature of corporate profit reporting has contributed to the simultaneous degradation of profit reporting to capital markets and tax authorities. The distinction between book and tax profits allows managers the ability to mischaracterize tax savings to capital markets and to mischaracterize profits to tax authorities. Examination of three high-profile cases of managerial misreporting of profits and tax avoidance-at Enron, Tyco and Xeroxreveals how the drive to improve reported book profits fosters tax avoidance and how the drive to limit taxes gives rise to the manipulation of accounting profits and managerial malfeasance.</description><author>Desai, M. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oil for what? - Illicit Iraqi oil contracts and the UN Security Council</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heaton, P.
The Oil-For-Food program was established by United Nations Security Council Resolution 986 in 1995 as a means of providing humanitarian relief to Iraq, which had been under U.N. economic sanctions since the Persian Gulf War in 1991. After the invasion of Iraq, considerable evidence emerged suggesting that Saddam Hussein was able to subvert the Oil-For-Food program to obtain hard currency as well as items on the United Nation's prohibited transfer list. In this paper, I use recently available data to examine how the Iraqi government used illicit contracts for underpriced oil to reward supporters. Although it may never be possible to prove conclusively that the Iraqi government used oil contracts as a mechanism to trade bribes for votes in the U.N. Security Council, I demonstrate that nations with seats on the Security Council received a greater number and a greater value of these contracts and that receipt of the contracts was positively associated with pro-Iraqi votes. I also find that Iraq was more likely to give contracts to countries on the Council that had exhibited prior support for the Iraqi regime.</description><author>Heaton, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating public goods and regulations - Response</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplow, L.
nan</description><author>Kaplow, L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating public goods and regulations - Comments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goulder, L. H.; Parry, I. W. H.; Williams, R. C.
nan</description><author>Goulder, L. H.; Parry, I. W. H.; Williams, R. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retrospectives - Eugenics and economics in the progressive era</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leonard, T. C.
During the Progressive Era, eugenic approaches to social and economic reform were popular, respectable and widespread. This essay documents the influence of eugenic ideas upon American economic reform, especially in the areas of immigration and labor reform, and tries to illuminate something of its causes and consequences.</description><author>Leonard, T. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Russian retrospectives on reforms from Yeltsin to Putin</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, P.
The kamikaze crew of liberal reformers, picked by former President Boris Yeltsin in the early 1990s, succeeded in overturning the planned economy and the authoritarian political arrangements of seven decades of Soviet Communism. However, the resulting breakdown of political cohesion and the urgency of restoring stability prompted Yeltsin to select Vladimir Putin as his successor. The consolidating impetus under Putin, who was elected president in early 2000, has raised concerns about the continuation of economic and political reforms under his leadership. In this essay, nine Russian interviewees look back on the reform issues under Yeltsin and look ahead on the unfolding political economy scenario under Putin. They include three principle economic reformers under Yeltsin, three economic policy analysts, and three banking professionals.</description><author>Desai, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A sociological perspective on gender and career outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reskin, B. F.; Bielby, D. D.
nan</description><author>Reskin, B. F.; Bielby, D. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ecologies of organizations: Diversity and identity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hannan, M. T.
nan</description><author>Hannan, M. T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of social structure on economic outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Granovetter, M.
nan</description><author>Granovetter, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identity and the economics of organizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akerlof, G. A.; Kranton, R. E.
The economics of organizations is replete with the pitfalls of monetary rewards and punishments to motivate workers. If economic incentives do not work, what does? This paper proposes that workers' self-image as jobholders, coupled with their ideal as to how their job should be done, can be a major work incentive. It shows how such identities can flatten reward schedules, as they solve "principal-agent" problem. The paper also identifies and explores a new tradeoff: supervisors may provide information to principals, but create rifts within the workforce and reduce employees' intrinsic work incentives. We motivate the theory with examples from the classic sociology of military and civilian organizations.</description><author>Akerlof, G. A.; Kranton, R. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What is economic sociology and should any economists care?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gibbons, R.
nan</description><author>Gibbons, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of oligarchs in Russian capitalism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guriev, S.; Rachinsky, A.
Using a unique dataset, we describe the degree of ownership concentration in Russian economy and its role in shaping economic and political institutions in Russia. In particular, we find that Russian "oligarchs" do control a substantial part of the economy. While the relative weight of their firms in Russian economy is huge, they do not seem to be excessively large by the standards of the global economy where most of them are operating. The oligarchs seem to run their firms more efficiently than other Russian owners controlling for industry, region and size.</description><author>Guriev, S.; Rachinsky, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Autopsy on an empire: Understanding mortality in Russia and the former soviet union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brainerd, E.; Cutler, D. M.
Male life expectancy at birth fell by over six years in Russia between 1989 and 1994. Many other countries of the former Soviet Union saw similar declines, and female life expectancy fell as well. Using cross-country and Russian household survey data, we assess six possible explanations for this upsurge in mortality. Most find little support in the data: the deterioration of the health care system, changes in diet and obesity, and material deprivation fail to explain the increase in mortality rates. The two factors that do appear to be important are alcohol consumption, especially as it relates to external causes of death (homicide, suicide, and accidents) and stress associated with a poor outlook for the future. However, a large residual remains to be explained.</description><author>Brainerd, E.; Cutler, D. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A normal country: Russia after communism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shleifer, A.; Treisman, D.
During the 1990s, Russia underwent an extraordinary transformation from a communist dictatorship to a multi-party democracy, from a centrally planned economy to a market economy, and from a belligerent adversary of the West to a cooperative partner. Yet a consensus in the US circa 2000 viewed Russia as a disastrous and threatening failure, and the 1990s as a decade of catastrophe for its citizens. Analyzing a variety of economic and political data, we demonstrate a large gap between this perception and the facts. In contrast to the common image, by the late 1990s Russia had become a typical middle-income capitalist democracy.</description><author>Shleifer, A.; Treisman, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The making of an economist redux</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colander, D.
This paper reports the findings of a survey and interviews with graduate students at seven top-ranking graduate economics programs. It finds that over the last 15 years graduate economics programs have become more empirical, less mathematical and less theoretically oriented, and that the students are generally positive about the profession. It also finds fewer differences among school. Despite the improvements, and greater student satisfaction, the paper suggests that there are serious pedagogical questions about the focus of the core on mathematical techniques rather than on creativity and economic reasoning, which students see as the true core of economics.</description><author>Colander, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Antitrust enforcement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, J. B.
nan</description><author>Baker, J. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rationality and voting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, P.; Hudson, J.
nan</description><author>Jones, P.; Hudson, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Weather and the Salem witch trials</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mixon, F. G.
nan</description><author>Mixon, F. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Data watch - The American time use survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hamermesh, D. S.; Frazis, H.; Stewart, J.
We discuss the new American Time Use Survey (ATUS), an on-going household survey of roughly 1,200 Americans per month (1,800 per month in the first year, 2003) that collects time diaries as well as demographic interview information from respondents who had recently been in the Current Population Survey. The characteristics of the data are presented, as are caveats and concerns that one might have about them. A number of novel uses of the ATUS in economic research, including in the areas of macroeconomics, national income accounting, labor economics, and others, are proposed to illustrate the magnitude of this new survey's possible applications.</description><author>Hamermesh, D. S.; Frazis, H.; Stewart, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Child labor in the global economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmonds, E. V.; Pavcnik, N.
Few issues in developing countries draw as much popular attention as child labor. This paper begins by quantifying the extent and main characteristics of child labor. It then considers the evidence on a range of issues about child labor. Fundamentally, child labor is a symptom of poverty. Low income and poor institutions are driving forces behind the prevalence of child labor worldwide. This study concludes by assessing the policy options to reduce worldwide child labor.</description><author>Edmonds, E. V.; Pavcnik, N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fussing and fuming over Fannie and Freddie: How much smoke, how much fire?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frame, W. S.; White, L. J.
The roles of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac have become increasingly controversial in the modern world of residential mortgage finance. We describe the special features of these two companies and their roles in the mortgage markets. We then discuss the controversies that surround them and offer recommendations for improvements in public policy.</description><author>Frame, W. S.; White, L. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lessons about markets from the Internet</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellison, G.; Ellison, S. F.
Many of us have grown used to, tired of, and finally downright skeptical of claims of the transformative powers of the Internet. It was to usher in the New Economy, but we seem mostly to have the Old. It would transform retail, but Toys "R" Us has outlasted EToys. Frictionless commerce would be the norm, but plenty of friction still exists. The Internet was also claimed to require a whole new economics with all new laws. While this, too, was very far from the truth-existing theories have mostly done quite well-the Internet has had a substantial effect on economic thought. In this paper, we discuss some ways in which the Internet has affected how economists think about markets.</description><author>Ellison, G.; Ellison, S. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Copying and copyright</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Varian, H. R.
Today most newly created textual, photographic, audio, and video content is available in digital form. Even older content that was not "born digital" can relatively easily converted to machine-readable formats. At same time, the world has become more networked, making it easy to transfer digital content from one person to another. The combination of technological progress in both digitization and computer networking has been a challenge for traditional ways of managing intellectual property. Some observers have even questioned whether current models for intellectual property can or should survive in a digital world. For example, there is widespread concern about piracy of popular music and film, both via the network and via bootleg CDs and DVDs. There is also concern about the economic viability of the current model for scholarly publication, or, for that matter traditional forms of publishing such as newspapers and TV network news. These developments have led to a revival of interest in the economics of copying and copyright. In this brief review we examine some of the economic issues in this area, and describe some of the insights that have emerged from this work. We end with some reflections on alternative business models for provision of creative works.</description><author>Varian, H. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of technology sharing: Open source and beyond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lerner, J.; Tirole, J.
This paper reviews our understanding of the growing open source movement. We highlight how many aspects of open source software appear initially puzzling to an economist. As we have acknowledged, our ability to answer confidently many of the issues raised here questions is likely to increase as the open source movement itself grows and evolves. At the same time, it is heartening to us how much of open source activities can be understood within existing economic frameworks, despite the presence of claims to the contrary. The labor and industrial organization literatures provide lenses through which the structure of open source projects, the role of contributors, and the movement's ongoing evolution can be viewed.</description><author>Lerner, J.; Tirole, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probabilistic patents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lemley, M. A.; Shapiro, C.
Economists often assume that a patent gives its owner a well-defined legal right to exclude others from practicing the invention described in the patent. In practice, however, the rights afforded to patent holders are highly uncertain. Under patent law, a patent is no guarantee of exclusion but more precisely a legal right to try to exclude. Since only 0.1% of all patents are litigated to trial, and since nearly half of fully litigated patents are declared invalid, this distinction is critical to understanding the economic impact of patents. The growing recognition among economists and legal scholars that patents are probabilistic property rights has significant implications for our understanding of patents in four important areas: (1) reform of the system by which patents are granted; (2) the legal treatment of patents in litigation; (3) the incentives of patent holders and alleged infringers to settle their disputes through licensing or cross-licensing agreements rather than litigate them to completion; and (4) the antitrust limits on agreements between rivals that settle actual or threatened patent litigation.</description><author>Lemley, M. A.; Shapiro, C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intellectual property: The law and economics approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Posner, R. A.
With the rise of the law and economics movement, the focus of economic analysis of intellectual property has begun to shift to more concrete and manageable issues concerning the structure and texture of the complicated pattern of common law and statutory doctrines, legal institutions and business practices relating to intellectual property. Among the issues discussed in this paper are the length of protection for intellectual property, the rules that allow considerable copying of intellectual property without permission of the originator, the rules governing derivative works, and alternative methods of providing incentives for the creation of intellectual property. The emphasis is on copyright law, which, perhaps because of its complex legal structure and the relative neglect by economists of the arts and entertainment, has tended to be slighted in the conventional economic analysis of intellectual property, relative to patent law, where economic analysis can draw on an extensive literature concerning the economics of innovation. The article also touches on trademarks and trade secrets, and explores some parallels and contrasts between the legal treatment of physical and intellectual property.</description><author>Posner, R. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural reform of social security</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldstein, M.
Governments around the world have enacted or are currently considering fundamental structural reforms of their Social Security pension programs. The key feature in these reforms is a shift from a pure pay-as-you-go tax-financed system, in which taxes on current workers are primarily distributed to current retirees, to a mixed system that combines pay-as-you-go benefits with investment-based personal retirement accounts. This paper discusses how such a mixed system could work in practice and how the transition to such a change could be achieved. It then analyzes the economic gains that would result from shifting to a mixed system. I turn next to the three problems that critics raise about any investment-based plan: administrative costs, risk, and income distribution. Finally, I comment on some of the ad hoc proposals for dealing with the financial problem of Social Security without shifting to an investment-based system.</description><author>Feldstein, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Saving social security</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diamond, P. A.; Orszag, P. R.
Social Security is one of America's most successful government programs. It has helped millions of Americans avoid poverty in old age. To be sure, the program faces a long-term deficit and is in need of updating. But Social Security's long-term financial health can be restored: the projected deficit is small enough that it can be eliminated through a progressive reform that combines modest benefit reductions and revenue increases.</description><author>Diamond, P. A.; Orszag, P. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shortfalls in the long run: Predictions about the social security trust fund</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hines, J. R.; Taylor, T.
Many proposals for addressing the long-term issues of Social Security involve benefit reductions both in Disability Insurance and in Old Age and Survivors Insurance. However, the proposals in the papers that follow in this symposium do not alter the long-term financial balance of Disability Insurance, and instead focus on the Old Age and Survivors Insurance program. Thus, the discussion in this introduction will also focus on the OASI trust fund.</description><author>Hines, J. R.; Taylor, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adam Smith, behavioral economist</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ashraf, N.; Camerer, C. F.; Loewenstein, G.
Adam Smith's psychological perspective in The Theory of Moral Sentiments is remarkably similar to "dual-process" frameworks advanced by psychologists, neuroscientists, and more recently by behavioral economists, based on behavioral data and detailed observations of brain functioning. It also anticipates a wide range of insights regarding phenomena such as loss aversion, willpower, and fairness that have been the focus of modern behavioral economics. This essay draws attention to some of these connections.</description><author>Ashraf, N.; Camerer, C. F.; Loewenstein, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adam Smith's Theory of Moral Sentiments: On morals and why they matter to a liberal society of free people and free markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evensky, J.
This essay describes Smith's analysis of ethics in his Theory of Moral Sentiments: the interaction of our nature and our nurturing that makes common civic ethics possible and the dynamic interaction of individuals and extant societal constructions that can lead to ever more mature systems of civic ethics and thus toward those conditions necessary for a constructive, sustainable liberal system.</description><author>Evensky, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The constitutional dilemma of economic liberty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weingast, B. R.
This paper studies the problem of self-enforcing constitutions, addressing the question, how do some constitutions provide incentives for political officials to abide by the constraints announced in the constitution? To understand the mechanisms underlying successful constitutions, the paper begins by exploring a simple society facing the dilemma of policing the government: a sovereign, who controls the government, and two citizens. It then moves to a discussion of how constitutions are often formed out of crises, with some more detailed discussion of two main examples: England's Glorious Revolution of 1688 and the U.S. Constitution.</description><author>Weingast, B. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Law, endowments and property rights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levine, R.
While scholars have hypothesized about the sources of variation in property rights for over 2500 years, it is only very recently that researchers have begun to test these theories empirically. This paper reviews both the theory and empirical evidence supporting and refuting the law and endowment views of property rights. The law view holds that historically determined differences in national legal traditions continue to shape cross-country differences in property rights. The endowment view argues that during European colonization, differences in climate, crops, the indigenous population, and the disease environment influenced long-run property rights.</description><author>Levine, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Besley, T.
Almost every major episode of economic change over the past 200 years of political history has been associated with key personalities coming to power with a commitment to these changes. But if such dynamic leaders are so important, then we need to understand how they come to hold the reins of power. This outcome could be viewed as largely the product of random events colored by idiosyncratic personalities and chance encounters. However, at least some role must be given to the underlying institutional structure, which has a more systematic influence on who rises to the top. Thus, it is essential to understand how political selection works.</description><author>Besley, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Eight questions about corruption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Svensson, J.
This paper will discuss eight frequently asked questions about public corruption: (1) What is corruption? (2) Which countries are the most corrupt? (3) What are the common characteristics of countries with high corruption? (4) What is the magnitude of corruption? (5) Do higher wages for bureaucrats reduce corruption? (6) Can competition reduce corruption? (7) Why have there been so few (recent) successful attempts to fight corruption? (8) Does corruption adversely affect growth?</description><author>Svensson, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distinguished lecture on economics in government - What we don't know could hurt us: Some reflections on the measurement of economic activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abraham, K. G.
The routine production of U.S. economic statistics dates back to the early part of the twentieth century. But in recent decades, as services output has continued to expand a system of economic statistics that had been designed during the manufacturing era began to seem increasingly outdated. Over the past decade, the statistical agencies have done yeoman work to expand the availability and quality of service sector statistics, but the task is far from completed. Moreover, the traditional accounting framework for economic statistics has focused almost exclusively on market transactions. Looking ahead, more comprehensive measurement of productive activities, however they may be organized, must be a priority.</description><author>Abraham, K. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend taxation and corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morck, R.; Yeung, B.
In 2003, the United States enacted a tax reform that reduced, but did not eliminate, individual dividend income taxes. Cutting the dividend tax deprives corporate insiders of a justification for retaining earnings to build unprofitable corporate empires. But not eliminating it entirely preserves an advantage for institutional investors, who can put pressure on underperforming managers. This balance is broadly appropriate in the United States-whose large companies are freestanding and widely held. In addition, preserving the existing tax on intercorporate dividends, in place since the Roosevelt era, discourages the pyramidal corporate groups commonplace in other countries, and preserves America's large corporate sector of free-standing widely held firms.</description><author>Morck, R.; Yeung, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Affirimative action and its mythology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fryer, R. G.; Loury, G. C.
For more than three decades, critics and supporters of affirmative action have fought for the moral high ground through ballot initiatives and lawsuits, in state legislatures, and in varied courts of public opinion. The goal of this paper is to show the clarifying power of economic reasoning to dispel some myths and misconceptions in the racial affirmative action debates. We enumerate seven commonly held (but mistaken) views one often encounters in the folklore about affirmative action (affirmative action may involve goals and timelines, but definitely not quotas, e.g.). Simple economic arguments reveal these seven views to be more myth than fact.</description><author>Fryer, R. G.; Loury, G. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Steven D Levitt: 2003 John Bates Clark medalist</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poterba, J. M.
Steve's Clark Medal citation mentions his path-breaking contributions to the economics of crime and to the political economy of campaign finance. This paper describes Steve's research in each of these areas, as well as his contributions on a range of other topics. It identifies the substantive themes as well as the methodological patterns that run through Steve's research, and it describes the economic issues that have been informed by his analysis.</description><author>Poterba, J. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>History lessons - The end of American exceptionalism? Mobility in the United States since 1850</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferrie, J. P.
New longitudinal data on individuals linked across nineteenth century U.S. censuses document the geographic and occupational mobility of more than 75,000 Americans from the 1850s to the 1920s. Together with longitudinal data for more recent years, these data make possible for the first time systematic comparisons of mobility over the last 150 years of American economic development, as well as cross-national comparisons for the nineteenth century. The U.S. was a substantially more mobile economy than Britain between 1850 and 1880. But both intergenerational occupational mobility and geographic mobility have declined in the U.S. since the beginning of the twentieth century, leaving much less apparent two aspects of the "American Exceptionalism" noted by nineteenth century observers.</description><author>Ferrie, J. P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Chairing the federal reserve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sunshine, J. H.
nan</description><author>Sunshine, J. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational choice theory and the paradox of not voting (vol 18, pg 99, 2004)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feddersen, T. J.
nan</description><author>Feddersen, T. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Chairing the federal reserve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimand, R. W.
nan</description><author>Dimand, R. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The limits of free trade - Response from Paul A Samuelson</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Samuelson, P. A.
nan</description><author>Samuelson, P. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The limits of free trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dixit, A.; Grossman, G.
nan</description><author>Dixit, A.; Grossman, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - Reform of the US Postal Service</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geddes, R. R.
The author first reviews the current structure and regulation of the U.S. Postal Service. He then discusses the changing size and composition of the U.S. mail stream. Many other countries have already undertaken comprehensive postal reform, including both privatization and demonopolization, and the author discusses what lessons their experience can provide. He concludes by evaluating current reform proposals in the United States.</description><author>Geddes, R. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why the Middle East is economically underdeveloped: Historical mechanisms of institutional stagnation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuran, T.
Although a millennium ago the Middle East was not an economic laggard, by the 18th century it exhibited clear signs of economic backwardness. The reason for this transformation is that certain components of the region's legal infrastructure stagnated as their Western counterparts gave way to the modern economy. Among the institutions that generated evolutionary bottlenecks are the Islamic law of inheritance, which inhibited capital accumulation; the absence in Islamic law of the concept of a corporation and the consequent weaknesses of civil society; and the waqf, which locked vast resources into unproductive organizations for the delivery of social services. All of these obstacles to economic development were largely overcome through radical reforms initiated in the nineteenth century. Nevertheless, traditional Islamic law remains a factor in the Middle East's ongoing economic disappointments. The weakness of the region's private economic sectors and its human capital deficiency stand among the lasting consequences of traditional Islamic law.</description><author>Kuran, T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The capital asset pricing model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perold, A. F.
The Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM) revolutionized modern finance. Developed in the early 1960s by William Sharpe, Jack Treynor, John Lintner and Jan Mossin, the model provided the first coherent framework for relating the required return on an investment to the risk of that investment. This paper lays out the key ideas of the model, places its development in a historical context, and discusses its applications and enduring importance to the field of finance.</description><author>Perold, A. F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The capital asset pricing model: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.
The capital asset pricing model (CAPM) of William Sharpe (1964) and John Lintner (1965) marks the birth of asset pricing theory (resulting in a Nobel Prize for Sharpe in 1990). Before their breakthrough, there were no asset pricing models built from first principles about the nature of tastes and investment opportunities and with clear testable predictions about risk and return. Four decades later, the CAPM is still widely used in applications, such as estimating the cost of equity capital for firms and evaluating the performance of managed portfolios. And it is the centerpiece, indeed often the only asset pricing model taught in MBA level investment courses. The attraction of the CAPM is its powerfully simple logic and intuitively pleasing predictions about how to measure risk and about the relation between expected return and risk. Unfortunately, perhaps because of its simplicity, the empirical record of the model is poor-poor enough to invalidate the way it is used in applications. The model's empirical problems may reflect true failings. (It is, after all, just a model.) But they may also be due to shortcomings of the empirical tests, most notably, poor proxies for the market portfolio of invested wealth, which plays a central role in the model's predictions. We argue, however, that if the market proxy problem invalidates tests of the model, it also invalidates most applications, which typically borrow the market proxies used in empirical tests. For perspective on the CAPM's predictions about risk and expected return, we begin with a brief summary of its logic. We then review the history of empirical work on the model and what it says about shortcomings of the CAPM that pose challenges to be explained by more complicated models.</description><author>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic policy and prospects in Iraq</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foote, C.; Block, W.; Crane, K.; Gray, S.
This paper describes the Coalition Provisional Authority's attempts to stabilize and reform Iraq's economy along market lines. It argues that while security concerns remain serious, Iraq's economy has not been crippled by violence. However, sustained economic growth will depend on whether Iraq's future leaders pursue the pro-market approaches the Coalition has advocated. If the Iraqi economy is to reach its potential, it will need to go even farther than the Coalition did, implementing reforms the Coalition did not pursue because of security concerns.</description><author>Foote, C.; Block, W.; Crane, K.; Gray, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Development, growth and policy reform in the Middle East and North Africa since 1950</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yousef, T. M.
The September 11 terrorist attacks ignited global interest in the Middle East. Observers in the region and abroad were quick to highlight the development "deficits" in Middle Eastern countries which have been linked to everything from structural economic imbalances to deficient political systems, the curse of natural resources, and even culture and religion. This paper reviews the development history of the Middle East and North Africa region in the post-World War II era, providing a framework for understanding past outcomes, current challenges and the potential for economic and political reform.</description><author>Yousef, T. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Media, education and anti-Americanism in the Muslim world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gentzkow, M. A.; Shapiro, J. A.
Recent surveys in the United States and the Muslim world show widespread misinformation about the events of September 11, 2001. Using data from 9 predominantly Muslim countries, we study how such beliefs depend on exposure to news media and levels of education. Standard economic theory would predict that increased access to information should cause beliefs to converge. More recent models of biased belief formation suggest that this result might hinge critically on who is providing the information. Consistent with the latter, we find that overall intensity of media use and level of education have at best a weak correlation with beliefs, while particular information sources have strong and divergent effects. Compared to those with little media exposure or schooling, individuals watching Arab news channels or educated in schools with little Western influence are less likely to agree that the September 11 attacks were carried out by Arab terrorists. Those exposed to media or education from Western sources are more likely to agree. Belief that the attacks were morally justified and general attitudes toward the US are also strongly correlated with source of information. These findings survive controls for demographic characteristics and are robust to identifying media effects using cross-country variation in language.</description><author>Gentzkow, M. A.; Shapiro, J. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Activist antitrust? Response from Robert W. Crandall and Clifford Winston</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Activist antitrust?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Werden, G. J.
nan</description><author>Werden, G. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Activist antitrust?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kouliavtsev, M. S.
nan</description><author>Kouliavtsev, M. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Women in economics: Moving up or falling off the academic career ladder?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ginther, D. K.; Kahn, S.
The percentage of economics doctorates awarded to women has increased over the past twenty years. This article considers whether women Ph.D. economists have increased their representation in academia, particularly at higher tenured ranks. Our study draws upon several empirical approaches and multiple data sets for the 1990s. We find that when compared with other academic disciplines, women in economics are less likely to get tenure and take longer to achieve it. Although gender differences in productivity and the effect of children on promotion partly explain women's lesser chances of receiving tenure in economics, a significant portion of the gender promotion gap remains unexplained by observable characteristics.</description><author>Ginther, D. K.; Kahn, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should we fear derivatives?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stulz, R. M.
This paper discusses the extent to which derivatives pose threats to firms and to the economy. After reviewing the derivatives markets and putting in perspective the various measures of the size of these markets, the paper shows who uses derivatives and why. The difficulties firms face in valuing derivatives portfolios are evaluated. Although academics pay much attention to no-arbitrage pricing results, the paper points out that there can be considerable subjectivity in the pricing of derivatives that do not have highly liquid markets. It is shown that the known risks of derivatives portfolios can generally be measured and managed well at the firm level. However, derivatives can create systemic risks when a market participant becomes excessively large relative to particular derivatives markets. Overall, the benefits of derivatives outweigh the potential threats.</description><author>Stulz, R. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are we consuming too much?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arrow, K.; Dasgupta, P.; Goulder, L.; Daily, G.; Ehrlich, P.; Heal, G.; Levin, S.; Maler, K. G.; Schneider, S.; Starrett, D.; Walker, B.
This paper articulates and applies frameworks for examining whether consumption is excessive. We consider two criteria for the possible excessiveness (or insufficiency) of current consumption. One is an intertemporal utility-maximization criterion: actual current consumption is deemed excessive if it is higher than the level of current consumption on the consumption path that maximizes the present discounted value of utility. The other is a sustainability criterion, which requires that current consumption be consistent with non-declining living standards over time. We extend previous theoretical approaches by offering a formula for the sustainability criterion that accounts for population growth and technological change. In applying this formula, we find that some poor regions of the world are failing to meet the sustainability criterion: in these regions, genuine wealth per capita is falling as investments in human and manufactured capital are not sufficient to offset the depletion of natural capital.</description><author>Arrow, K.; Dasgupta, P.; Goulder, L.; Daily, G.; Ehrlich, P.; Heal, G.; Levin, S.; Maler, K. G.; Schneider, S.; Starrett, D.; Walker, B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where Ricardo and mill rebut and confirm arguments of mainstream economists supporting globalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Samuelson, P. A.
Autarky real per capita well being, does not deny that new technical Chinese progress in goods that America previously had competitive advantage in can, ceteris paribus, lower permanently measurable per capita U.S. real income. Nor does it deny that technical progress in China's export goods can, ceteris paribus, hurt permanently her own net measurable per capita real income itself when demand inelasticity prevails. Ergo, the winds of dynamic comparative advantage cannot be counted on to create in each region new net gains of the gainers assuredly greater than the new net losses of the losers. However, correct Ricardian theory does imply that worldwide real income per capita does gain net, so that winners' winnings will suffice worldwide to more than compensate losers' losings-some cold comfort in a scenario of many semi-autonomous nations.</description><author>Samuelson, P. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reply from Paul Portney, Ian Parry and Winston Harrington</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange rate regimes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schuler, K.
nan</description><author>Schuler, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>School accountability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Hippel, P. T.
nan</description><author>von Hippel, P. T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fuel economy standards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Howarth, R. B.
nan</description><author>Howarth, R. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inequality and poverty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Honohan, P.
nan</description><author>Honohan, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Joan Robinson and B. L. Hallward named monopsony</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thornton, R. J.
The term "monopsony" was introduced by Joan Robinson in her 1932 classic The Economics of Imperfect Competition, although she gives credit to classics scholar B.L. Hallward of Cambridge for the actual coining of the term. Even though the term has become widely accepted by economists, its literal meaning is more idiosyncratic than simply "one buyer" of a commodity or service. In this paper I discuss the etymology of the term monopsony and suggest several other words that would seem to be more appropriate for describing this market phenomenon.</description><author>Thornton, R. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - Trade adjustment assistance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baicker, K.; Rehavi, M. M.
nan</description><author>Baicker, K.; Rehavi, M. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prospects in the academic Labor market for economists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ehrenberg, R. G.
This paper discussed what the academic labor market for economists is likely to look like in the years ahead. After tracing out trends in PhD production of new economists, including the increasing share of new PhDs who are foreign residents, it presents new evidence on the growing use of part-time and full-time non tenure-track faculty in U.S. economics departments, the growing salary differentials between economists employed at private and public doctoral universities, and how economists' salaries have changed relative to those of faculty in other disciplines.</description><author>Ehrenberg, R. G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State budget deficit dynamics and the california debacle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sheffrin, S. M.
This paper analyzes the recent experience with state budget deficits in the United States, with an in-depth analysis of the California experience. Compared to prior recessions, states were slower to make adjustments in taxes and spending this time. The paper explores a variety of reasons for this difference including changes in the legal, political, and institutional environments, the unusual increase in capital gains revenue during the boom preceding the recession, and the inherent difficulties in forecasting revenues, particularly those derived from capital income. As the case study from California illustrates, states made long term commitments from temporary revenue sources and were required to make budgetary decisions in the face of very incomplete information about current and projected tax receipts.</description><author>Sheffrin, S. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos and the future of mass torts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>White, M. J.
nan</description><author>White, M. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Manager-investor conflicts in mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mahoney, P. G.
Half of all of U.S. households own shares in one or more mutual funds, either directly or through personal or employer-sponsored retirement accounts. This article describes the structure and regulation of mutual funds and the resulting incentives facing those who make decisions for the funds. After providing some basic institutional details, it focuses on the cash flows from mutual fund investors to fund managers, brokers, and other third parties and the associated conflicts of interest. The article concludes with a summary of recent legal proceedings against mutual fund managers and brokers based on improper trading practices and regulatory proposals to curb those practices.</description><author>Mahoney, P. G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making a name: Women's surnames at marriage and beyond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldin, C.; Shim, M.
This paper tracks the fraction of college graduate women who kept their surnames upon marriage and after childbirth and explores some of the correlates of surname retention. Data from the New York Times, Harvard College alumni books, and Massachusetts birth records are used. Surname retention at marriage greatly increased from 1975 to about 1985 although Massachusetts birth records and the Harvard data show a decrease in the fraction keeping their surnames beginning around the early 1990s. The observable characteristics of importance in surname retention are those revealing that the bride has already "made a name" for herself.</description><author>Goldin, C.; Shim, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Historical presidential betting markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rhode, P. W.; Strumpf, K. S.
This paper analyzes the large and often well-organized markets for betting on U.S. presidential elections that operated between 1868 and 1940. Four main points are addressed. First, we show that the market did a remarkable job forecasting elections in an era before scientific polling. Second, the market was fairly efficient, despite the limited information of participants and active attempts to manipulate the odds. Third, we argue political betting markets disappeared largely because of the rise of scientific polls and the increasing availability of other forms of gambling. Finally, we discuss lessons this experience provides for the present.</description><author>Rhode, P. W.; Strumpf, K. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prediction markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wolfers, J.; Zitzewitz, E.
We analyze the extent to which simple markets can be used to aggregate disperse information into efficient forecasts of uncertain future events. Drawing together data from a range of prediction contexts, we show that market-generated forecasts are typically fairly accurate, and that they outperform most moderately sophisticated benchmarks. Carefully designed contracts can yield insight into the market's expectations about probabilities, means and medians, and also uncertainty about these parameters. Moreover, conditional markets can effectively reveal the market's beliefs about regression coefficients, although we still have the usual problem of disentangling correlation from causation. We discuss a number of market design issues and highlight domains in which prediction markets are most likely to be useful.</description><author>Wolfers, J.; Zitzewitz, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Latin America since the 1990s: Rising from the sickbed?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fraga, A.
nan</description><author>Fraga, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Latin America's growth and equity frustrations during structural reforms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ocampo, J. A.
This paper argues that Latin America's market-oriented reforms, together with increased monetary and fiscal discipline, were successful in bringing down inflation, inducing export growth and diversification, and attracting foreign direct investment. Nonetheless, economic growth was frustratingly slow. Pro-cyclical macroeconomic policies generated, in turn, strong business cycles in the face of unstable access to international capital markets. Higher productivity in leading firms and sectors failed to spread throughout the economy and led to increasing productive sector dualism. Furthermore, despite the democratic dividend reflected in increased social spending and coverage of social services, weak economic performance and additional distributive tensions led to disappointing results in terms of employment generation and poverty reduction. Overcoming these frustrating outcomes would require counter-cyclical macroeconomic policies, open-economy productive development strategies and mainstreaming social objectives into economic policies.</description><author>Ocampo, J. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How should we measure consumer confidence?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dominitz, J.; Manski, C. F.
Research on consumer confidence has mainly sought to evaluate the power of available data to predict economic outcomes. In contrast, this article considers how best to measure consumer confidence. We analyze the responses to eight questions that have appeared recently on the Michigan Survey of Consumers; four elicit expectations in the traditional qualitative manner and four use a newer "percent chance" format. Examination of the responses suggests three implications. It makes more sense to ask for expectations of events directly relevant to individual economic decisions than for predictions of general business conditions. Surveys should shift away from qualitative questions in favor of ones eliciting subjective probability judgments. While aggregating responses into an index of consumer confidence may provide simple summary statistics, results should also be presented on a question-by-question basis for different subgroups of the population.</description><author>Dominitz, J.; Manski, C. F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer confidence and consumer spending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ludvigson, S. C.
Despite the widespread attention given to surveys of consumer confidence, the mechanisms by which household attitudes influence the real economy are less well understood. This paper begins with an overview of how consumer confidence is measured and reported. It then evaluates the relationship between consumer attitudes and the real economy. The evidence suggests that popular survey measures contain some information about future aggregate consumer expenditure growth. However, much of that information is found in other economic and financial indicators, and the independent information provided by consumer confidence predicts a relatively modest amount of additional variation in future consumer spending.</description><author>Ludvigson, S. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distinguished lecture on economics in government: Lessons from past productivity booms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferguson, R. W.; Wascher, W. L.
nan</description><author>Ferguson, R. W.; Wascher, W. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is housing unaffordable? why isn't it more affordable?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Quigley, J. A.; Raphael, S.
This paper reviews trends in housing affordability in the U.S. over the past four decades. There is little evidence that owner-occupied housing has become less affordable. In contrast, there have been modest increases in the fraction of income that the median renter household devotes to housing. We find pronounced increases in the rent burdens for poor households. We explore the low-income rental market in more detail, analyzing the relative importance of changes in the income distribution, in housing quality, land use regulation, and zoning in affecting rent burdens. We also sketch out some policies that might improve housing affordability.</description><author>Quigley, J. A.; Raphael, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Constitutions and economic policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Persson, T.; Tabellini, G.
nan</description><author>Persson, T.; Tabellini, G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do democracies have different public policies than nondemocracies?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mulligan, C. B.; Gil, R.; Sala-i-Martin, X.
Estimates of democracy's effect on the public sector are obtained from comparisons of 142 countries over the years 1960-90. Based on three tenets of voting theory-that voting mutes policy preference intensity, political power is equally distributed in democracies, and the form of voting processes is important-we expect democracy to affect policies that redistribute, or economically favor the political leadership, or enhance efficiency. We do not find such differences. Instead democracy is correlated with policies that limit competition for public office. Alternative modeling approaches emphasize the degree of competition, and deemphasize the form or even existence of voting processes.</description><author>Mulligan, C. B.; Gil, R.; Sala-i-Martin, X.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition in Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Porter, M. E.; Sakakibara, M.
This article examines competition in Japan and its link to postwar economic prosperity. While Japan's industrial structure and competition policy seem to indicate that competition in Japan has been less intense, the empirical evidence does not support this conclusion. The sectors in which competition was restricted prove to be those where Japan was not internationally successful. In the internationally successful sectors, internal competition in Japan was invariably fierce. While the level of competition in Japan is currently rising, economic recovery is still hindered by distortions in the competition in many industries.</description><author>Porter, M. E.; Sakakibara, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Japan's financial crisis mid economic stagnation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoshi, T.; Kashyap, A. K.
We survey the macroeconomic stagnation and financial problems in Japan. The financial sector assessment includes separate analyses of the commercial banks, the life insurance companies and the government's fiscal investment and loan program (FILP). We estimate that the Japanese taxpayer will have to pay at least another 100 trillion yen (20% of GDP) to cover financial system losses. We explain how the current dysfunctional Japanese banking system misallocates funds by keeping many insolvent firms in business. These inefficient firms crowd out potentially profitable ones and worsen macroeconomic stagnation. A sustained macroeconomic recovery requires serious restructuring aimed at stopping this cycle.</description><author>Hoshi, T.; Kashyap, A. K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational choice theory and the paradox of not voting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feddersen, T. J.
nan</description><author>Feddersen, T. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Legislative organization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krehbiel, K.
With an emphasis on the U.S. Congress, this essay addresses political economy approaches to the study of legislative organization. Simple models provide a foundation for more sophisticated studies of one of two problems: how coalitions of intense minorities pass policies that reflect gains from trade (efficiency in distributive policies) and how the legislature obtains gains from specialization (efficiency in information acquisition and dissemination). The recurring impediment to solutions to these problems is that legislatures are self-organizing and, therefore, have difficulty in committing to potentially effective institutional solutions.</description><author>Krehbiel, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choosing the federal reserve chair: Lessons from history</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Romer, C. D.; Romer, D. H.
nan</description><author>Romer, C. D.; Romer, D. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding why crime fell in the 1990s: Four factors that explain the decline and six that do not</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levitt, S. D.
Crime dropped sharply and unexpectedly in the United States in the 1990s. I conclude that four factors collectively explain the entire drop in crime: increases in the number of police, increases in the size of the prison population, the waning of the crack epidemic, and the legalization of abortion in the 1970s. Other common explanations for declining crime appear far less important. The factors identified are much less successful in explaining fluctuations in crime in the preceding two decades. The real puzzle is not why crime fell in the 1990s, but rather, why crime did not begin falling earlier.</description><author>Levitt, S. D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Witchcraft, weather and economic growth in renaissance Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oster, E.
nan</description><author>Oster, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retrospectives - Gender in classical economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimand, R. W.; Forget, E. L.; Nyland, C.
nan</description><author>Dimand, R. W.; Forget, E. L.; Nyland, C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How to subvert democracy: Montesinos in Peru</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McMillan, J.; Zoido, P.
Which of the democratic checks and balances-opposition parties, the judiciary, a free press-is the most forceful? Peru has the full set of democratic institutions. In the 1990s, the secret-police chief Montesinos systematically undermined them all with bribes. We quantify the checks using the bribe prices. Montesinos paid a televisionchannel owner about 100 times what he paid a judge or a politician. One single television channel's bribe was five times larger than the total of the opposition politicians' bribes. By revealed preference, the strongest check on the government's power was the news media.</description><author>McMillan, J.; Zoido, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Challenges for terrorism risk insurance in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kunreuther, H.; Michel-Kerjan, E.
nan</description><author>Kunreuther, H.; Michel-Kerjan, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Urban sprawl</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nechyba, T. J.; Walsh, R. P.
This paper examines the role that insurance has played in dealing with terrorism before and after September 11, 2001, by focusing on the distinctive challenges associated with terrorism as a catastrophic risk. The Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 (TRIA) was passed by the U.S. Congress in November 2002, establishing a national terrorism insurance program that provides up to $100 billion commercial coverage with a specific but temporary risk-sharing arrangement between the federal government and insurers. TRIA's three-year term ends December 31, 2005, so Congress soon has to determine whether it should be renewed, whether an alternative terrorism insurance program should be substituted for it, or whether insurance coverage is left solely in the hands of the private sector. As input into this process, the paper examines several alternatives and scenarios, and discusses their potential to create a sustainable terrorism insurance program in the Unites States.</description><author>Nechyba, T. J.; Walsh, R. P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the (Ir)relevance of distribution and labor supply distortion to government policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplow, L.
Should the assessment of government policies, such as the provision of public goods and the control of externalities, deviate from first-best principles to account for distributive effects and the distortionary cost of labor income taxation? For example, is the optimal extent of public goods provision smaller than indicated by the Samuelson rule because finance is distortionary? Or should environmental regulations fail to internalize externalities fully if the incidence of the regulations is regressive? It is suggested that these questions are best addressed by considering distribution-neutral implementation, in which budget balance is achieved by choosing an adjustment to the income tax that offsets the distributive impact of the policy in question. In basic cases, both distribution and labor supply distortion are moot because the target policy and the tax adjustment produce offsetting effects on each. Thus, traditional first-best principles provide good benchmarks for policy analysis after all. Moreover, even when actual implementation will not be distribution neutral in aggregate, distribution-neutral policy analysis has many conceptual and practical virtues that render it quite useful to investigators.</description><author>Kaplow, L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The purchasing power parity debate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, A. M.; Taylor, M. P.
Originally propounded by the sixteenth-century scholars of the University of Salamanca, the concept of purchasing power parity (PPP) was revived in the interwar period in the context of the debate concerning the appropriate level at which to reestablish international exchange rate parities. Broadly accepted as a long-run equilibrium condition in the post-war period, it was first advocated as a short-run equilibrium by many international economists in the first few years following the breakdown of the Bretton Woods system in the early 1970s and then increasingly came under attack on both theoretical and empirical grounds from the late 1970s to the mid 1990s. Accordingly, over the last three decades, a large literature has built up that examines how much the data deviated from theory, and the fruits of this research have provided a deeper understanding of how well PPP applies in both the short run and the long run. Since the mid 1990s, larger datasets and nonlinear econometric methods, in particular, have improved estimation. As deviations narrowed between real exchange rates and PPP, so did the gap narrow between theory and data, and some degree of confidence in long-run PPP began to emerge again. In this respect, the idea of long-run PPP now enjoys perhaps its strongest support in more than thirty years, a distinct reversion in economic thought.</description><author>Taylor, A. M.; Taylor, M. P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oil and the macroeconomy since the 1970s</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barsky, R. B.; Kilian, L.
Increases in oil prices have been held responsible for recessions, periods of excessive inflation, reduced productivity and lower economic growth. In this paper, we review the arguments supporting such views. First, we highlight some of the conceptual difficulties in assigning a central role to oil price shocks in explaining macroeconomic fluctuations, and we trace how the arguments of proponents of the oil view have evolved in response to these difficulties. Second, we challenge the notion that at least the major oil price movements can be viewed as exogenous with respect to the US macroeconomy. We examine critically the evidence that has led many economists to ascribe a central role to exogenous political events in modeling the oil market, and we provide arguments in favor of "reverse causality" from macroeconomic variables to oil prices. Third, although none of the more recent oil price shocks has been associated with stagflation in the US economy, a major reason for the continued popularity of the oil shock hypothesis has been the perception that only oil price shocks are able to explain the US stagflation of the 1970s. We show that this is not the case.</description><author>Barsky, R. B.; Kilian, L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The muddles over outsourcing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhagwati, J.; Panagariya, A.; Srinivasan, T. N.
Critics have muddled the public debate over offshore outsourcing by using the term interchangeably to refer to altogether different phenomena such as on-line purchase of services, direct foreign investment and, sometimes, all imports. We argue that clarity requires distinguishing among these various phenomena and define outsourcing explicitly as the services trade at arm's length that does not require geographical proximity of the buyer and the seller-the so-called Mode 1 services in the WTO terminology-conducted principally via the electronic mediums such as the telephone, fax and Internet. The definition is appropriate because this is the phenomenon that is relatively new and scary in public consciousness and has fueled the recent "outsourcing" debate. Under this definition, the total number of the U.S. jobs outsourced annually is minuscule and is expected to remain so over the next decade, even on a gross basis (i.e., without adjusting for the jobs in-sourced from the U.S.). The fears that offshore outsourcing will lead to high-value jobs being replaced by low-value jobs down the road are also argued here to be implausible in view of several qualitative arguments to the contrary. We also demonstrate that offshore outsourcing of Mode 1 services raises no new analytical issues, contrary to what many fear. Thus, it leads to gains from trade (with the standard caveats applicable to conventional trade in goods) and, in specific cases, to income-distribution effects.</description><author>Bhagwati, J.; Panagariya, A.; Srinivasan, T. N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are European countries diverging in their unemployment experience?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saint-Paul, G.
nan</description><author>Saint-Paul, G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The European Union: A politically incorrect view</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alesina, A.; Perotti, R.
In this paper, we present our view of the recent evolution of European integration. We first briefly describe the main features of the institution and decision making process in the European Union, with particular attention to the debate between federalists and super nationalists. We then identify two key issues in the process of European integration: 1) an emphasis on "institutional balance" based on a complex web of institutions with overlapping jurisdiction; 2) A conflict between a dirigiste versus a more laissez faire approach to government. We argue that the first problem leads to a lack of clarity in the allocation of powers between European institutions, confusion in the allocation of prerogatives between national governments and EU institutions, and lack of transparency and accountability. The dirigiste culture also manifests itself in an abundant production of verbose rhetoric, which in our view is far from innocuous and direct set the European policy debate in the wrong direction. We then study how these problems play out in 4 important areas: employment policies, culture and scientific research, foreign and defense policies, and fiscal policy. Finally, we study the implications of the recently proposed European Constitution a potential solution of these two problems.</description><author>Alesina, A.; Perotti, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economic future of Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blanchard, O.
After three years of near stagnation, the mood in Europe is definitely gloomy. Many doubt that the European model has a future. In this paper, I argue that things are not so bad, and there is room for optimism. Over the last thirty years, productivity growth has been much faster in Europe than in the United States. Productivity levels are roughly similar today in the European Union and in the United States. The main difference is that Europe has used some of the increase in productivity to increase leisure rather than income, while the United States has done the opposite. Still not everything is well. Unemployment is still high, and Europe suffers from inefficient regulation. Here also however, there is more action than often perceived, and a wide ranging reform process is taking place. This process is driven by reforms in financial and product markets. Reforms in those markets are in turn putting pressure for reform in the labor market. Reform in the labor market is slowly taking place, but not without political tensions. These tensions dominate the news; but they are a symptom of change, not a reflection of immobility.</description><author>Blanchard, O.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Halving global poverty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Besley, T.; Burgess, R.
The Millennium Development Goals-global targets that the world's leaders set at the Millennium Summit in September 2000-are an ambitious agenda for reducing poverty. As a central plank, these goals include halving the proportion of people living below a dollar a day from around 30 percent of the developing world's population in 1990 to 15 percent by 2015-a reduction in the absolute number of poor of around one billion. This paper examines what economic research can tell us about how to fulfill these goals. It begins by discussing poverty trends on a global scale-where the poor are located in the world and how their numbers have been changing over time. It then discusses the relationship of economic growth and income distribution to poverty reduction. Finally, it suggests an evidence-based agenda for poverty reduction in the developing world.</description><author>Besley, T.; Burgess, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The trouble with stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hall, B. J.; Murphy, K. J.
The benefits of stock options are often not large enough to offset the inefficiency implied by the large divergence between the cost of options to companies and the value of options to risk-averse, undiversified executives and employees. Moreover, the benefits of options can often be achieved more effectively and economically through other means. Why are options so prevalent? Several explanations include changes in corporate governance, reporting requirements, taxes, the bull market and managerial rent-seeking. We offer an alternative hypothesis: boards and managers incorrectly perceive stock options to be inexpensive because options create no accounting charge and require no cash outlay.</description><author>Hall, B. J.; Murphy, K. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can foreign aid buy growth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easterly, W.
The widely publicized finding that "aid promotes growth in a good policy environment" is not robust to the inclusion of new data or alternative definitions of "aid," "policy" or "growth." The idea that "aid buys growth" is on shaky ground theoretically and empirically. It doesn't help that aid agencies face poor incentives to deliver results and underinvest in enforcing aid conditions and performing scientific evaluations. Aid should set more modest goals, like helping some of the people some of the time, rather than trying to be the catalyst for society-wide transformation.</description><author>Easterly, W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive compensation as an agency problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bebchuk, L. A.; Fried, J. A.
Executive compensation has long attracted a great deal of attention from financial economists. Indeed, the increase in academic papers on the subject of CEO compensation during the 1990s seems to have outpaced even the remarkable increase in CEO pay itself during this period (Murphy, 1999). Much research has focused on how executive compensation schemes can help alleviate the agency problem in publicly traded companies. To understand adequately the landscape of executive compensation, however, one must recognize that the design of compensation arrangements is also partly a product of this same agency problem.</description><author>Bebchuk, L. A.; Fried, J. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why have Americans become more obese?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cutler, D. M.; Glaeser, E. L.; Shapiro, J. M.
Americans have become considerably more obese over the past 25 years. This increase is primarily the result of consuming more calories. The increase in food consumption is itself the result of technological innovations which made it possible for food to be mass prepared far from the point of consumption, and consumed with lower time costs of preparation and cleaning. Price changes are normally beneficial, but may not be if people have self-control problems. This applies to some, but not most, of the population.</description><author>Cutler, D. M.; Glaeser, E. L.; Shapiro, J. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The negative income tax and the evolution of US welfare policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moffitt, R. A.
The negative income tax proposed by Milton Friedman represents one of the fundamental ideas of modern welfare policy. However, the academic literature has raised two difficulties with it, one challenging its purported work incentives and the other suggesting the possible superiority of work requirements. In addition, work requirement approaches have gained ground in actual U.S. welfare policy over the last 30 years and the number of different programs has proliferated, another development counter to the negative income tax. On the other hand, the Earned Income Tax Credit has produced a negative-income-tax-like program on a vast scale.</description><author>Moffitt, R. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics and law of sexual harassment in the workplace</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basu, K.
Suppose a firm has a widespread reputation for sexually harassing its employees. When a person signs up to work for such a firm, it would appear that both the firm and the worker are better off by virtue of the "exchange". Is there a case then for government to ban sexual harassment in the workplace? Starting from this question, this paper constructs an argument for legislative intervention. This "economic approach" is applied to other labor market practices and is used to evaluate and critique the current law concerning sexual harassment in the U.S. and other nations.</description><author>Basu, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In honor of Matthew Rabin: Winner of the John Bates Clark Medal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thaler, R. H.
Although there is some evidence that Matthew Rabin existed before 1990, we had the pleasure of discovering him for ourselves when, in the early 1990s, he sent each of us a copy of his manuscript "Incorporating Fairness into Game Theory and Economics" [2]. Matthew was, at this time, an assistant professor in Berkeley's economics department, having recently finished his graduate training at MIT. The paper was remarkable in many ways, and it induced us both to call around and ask: "Who is this guy Rabin?" Now, just a decade later, we find ourselves writing an article in honor of his winning the John Bates Clark award. So, who is this guy?</description><author>Thaler, R. H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retrospectives - Who invented instrumental variable regression?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stock, J. H.; Trebbi, F.
This feature addresses the history of economic words and ideas. The hope is to deepen the workaday dialogue of economists, while perhaps also casting new light on ongoing questions.</description><author>Stock, J. H.; Trebbi, F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The global inheritance of inequality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tullock, G.
nan</description><author>Tullock, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The global inheritance of inequality - Reply from Samuel Bowles and Herbert Gintis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global warming policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michaelowa, A.
nan</description><author>Michaelowa, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global warming policy - Reply from Warwick J. McKibbin and Peter Wilcoxen</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indirect liability for copyright infringement: Napster and beyond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Landes, W.; Lichtman, D.
When individuals infringe copyright, they often use tools, services, and venues provided by other parties. An enduring legal question asks to what extent those other parties should be held liable for the resulting infringement. For example, should a firm that produces photocopiers be required to compensate authors for any unauthorized copies made on that firm's machines? What about firms that manufacture personal computers or offer Internet access; should they be held liable, at least in part, for online music piracy? In this essay, we examine how modern copyright law addresses these questions and we evaluate the resulting system on economic grounds.</description><author>Landes, W.; Lichtman, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Awards, success and aesthetic quality in the arts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ginsburgh, V.
The role of experts is dramatically increasing in our societies, where sorting information about quality is becoming more and more difficult. This paper looks at expertise in the arts (movies, novels and musical interpretation) and shows that expert opinion given shortly after the work has been produced (Oscars, prizes, rankings in musical competitions) may influence success, though it does not always recognize talent and does often not survive the "test of time," considered by many art philosophers, since Hume, as one of the possible measures of fundamental aesthetic quality.</description><author>Ginsburgh, V.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Some economics of ticket resale</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Courty, P.
A large number of brokers and scalpers resell a significant fraction of event tickets at substantial markups and they manage to do so despite the fact that promoters and ticketing agencies do not support resell for profits and often attempt to block secondary market. Why can't promoters capture the profits from secondary markets or at least deter brokers from doing so? I present a simple explanation that borrows from the literature on airline ticket pricing and draw parallels with that literature. I review some evidence consistent with this explanation.</description><author>Courty, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contracts between art and commerce</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caves, R. E.
Contract structures used in the arts and entertainment industries are central to understanding their economic organization. The structures spring from common bedrock traits of these industries-pervasive product differentiation, all costs sunk, consumers' valuations unpredictable, artists having tastes for how creative work is done. Joint-venture structures are common, with revenue (not profit) shared. Advances to artists help bring incentive and distributive goals into consistency, as do long-term contracts covering successive cycles of the artist's output. Real option contracts allow the efficient allocation of decision rights in a project on which collaborators work successively.</description><author>Caves, R. E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate conflicts of interest</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demski, J. S.
This paper surveys conflicts of interest in the corporate governance arena, with emphasis on auditors, boards of directors, analysts and investment bankers, regulators, management, attorneys and investors. Enron provides a host of examples as well. I stress the multifaceted nature of these conflicts, and the fact most research looks at some conflicts, such as auditor independence, absent the larger setting and potential interactions among various players. I further speculate herding behavior is an important explanatory device in understanding periodic failures.</description><author>Demski, J. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate earnings: Facts and fiction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lev, B.
Manipulated earnings played a central role in the slew of corporate scandals which surfaced during the last three years. This article focuses on the vulnerability of earnings to manipulation by managers: it surveys the empirical record of manipulation, their major objectives, and the means of manipulation. It then focuses on the major source of earnings manipulation-the multitude of estimates and subjective judgments underlying the comutation of earnings. The article accordingly concludes with a proposal to curb manipulation by requiring managers to routinely compare key estimates with ex post realizations, and revise earnings in case of large deviations.</description><author>Lev, B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The fall of Enron</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Healy, P. M.; Palepu, K. G.
nan</description><author>Healy, P. M.; Palepu, K. G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Health care costs: On the rise again</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glied, S.
Since 1999, health care costs have been growing faster than national income. This rapid growth has occurred as the ability of private and public purchasers to reduce service utilization and bargain for lower prices has fallen, insurers have recouped lost profits through higher premiums, and new technologies have driven up costs throughout the sector. Private insurance market responses to these rising costs may lead to reductions in the number of people with insurance and to increased fragmentation of the insurance market. Over time, technological change in medicine both increases costs and improves the quality of care. The challenge for public policy is to maintain insurance and some degree of equity in the face of these rising costs.</description><author>Glied, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Perspectives from the president's commission on social security reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cogan, J. F.; Mitchell, O. S.
Recently we were asked to serve on the President's Commission to Strengthen Social Security (CSSS) along with 14 other members drawn equally from both major political parties. The Commission's charge was to provide recommendations to modernize the Social Security system, restore its fiscal soundness, and develop a workable system of Personal Retirement Accounts. This paper explains how the Commission arrived at some of its recommendations and the role that economics played in contributing to these recommendations. We describe the key institutional constraints confronting efforts to reform Social Security and how these constraints influenced Commission decisions. We also illustrate how economics research influenced the Commission's analysis of how to structure personal accounts, ways to enhance traditional Social Security program finances, and means of measuring the extent of financial progress achieved through reform.</description><author>Cogan, J. F.; Mitchell, O. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - The expanding reach of the individual alternative minimum tax</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burman, L. E.; Gale, W. G.; Rohaly, J.
The individual alternative minimum tax (AMT) was designed in 1970 to apply reduce aggressive tax sheltering, but under current law will grow to cover tens of millions of households in the next decade. The growth occurs because the AMT is not indexed for inflation and the 2001 tax cut reduced regular income taxes but not the AMT. AMT growth is troubling because the tax has questionable effects on equity and efficiency and is inordinately complex. This paper describes the AMT, discusses economic issues related to the alternative minimum tax, and examines options for reform.</description><author>Burman, L. E.; Gale, W. G.; Rohaly, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>History lessons - Sanctions: Neither war nor peace</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, L.; Engerman, S.
This paper surveys the increasing international use of sanctions over the past century. Sanctions are a form of action taken by one state or by collective action to influence another state to change its behavior, as a substitute for welfare. They generally involve restrictions on foreign trade, either of all goods or of specific commodities. Sanctions have generally been imposed by larger countries on smaller countries. Sanctions have had a mixed success rate, depending on the costs imposed on the targeted nation, their response to these costs, and the impact on the economy and public opinion in other nations.</description><author>Davis, L.; Engerman, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Group selection and randomness - Reply from Theodore Bergstrom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>History lessons - Sanctions: Neither war nor peace - Response from Arthur Robson</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robson, A. J.
nan</description><author>Robson, A. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Group selection and randomness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Field, A. J.
nan</description><author>Field, A. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolution and human nature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hayford, J. D.
nan</description><author>Hayford, J. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolution and human nature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neu, W.
nan</description><author>Neu, W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sources of bias and solutions to bias in the Consumer Price Index</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hausman, J.
Four sources of bias in the Consumer Prices Index (CPI) have been identified. The most discussed is substitution bias, which creates a second order bias in the CPI. Three other changes besides prices changes create first order effects on a correctly measured cost of living index (COLI). I explain in this paper that a "pure price" based approach of surveying prices to estimate a COLI cannot succeed in solving the 3 problems of first order bias. I discuss economic and econometric approaches to measuring the first order bias effects as well as the availability of scanner data that would permit implementation of the techniques.</description><author>Hausman, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Consumer Price Index: Conceptual issues and practical suggestions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultze, C. L.
A National Academy of Sciences Panel recently made a number of recommendations to the BLS for improving the Consumer Price Index, while also suggesting some cautions to be observed when considering the adoption of new concepts and techniques. This paper discusses the Panel's analyses in four areas: Should a cost-of-living index be the measurement objective of the CPI? Should the index attempt to capture the effect on living costs from changes in "environmental" conditions? How can hedonic techniques be best applied for measuring quality changes? Should the BLS attempt to measure the consumer surpluses accompanying the introduction of new goods?</description><author>Schultze, C. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>