<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JEP4</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>The efficient market hypothesis and its critics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malkiel, B. G.
Revolutions often spawn counterrevolutions and the efficient market hypothesis in finance is no exception. The intellectual dominance of the efficient-market revolution has more been challenged by economists who stress psychological and behaviorial elements of stock-price determination and by econometricians who argue that stock returns are, to a considerable extent, predictable. This survey examines the attacks on the efficient market hypothesis and the relationship between predictability and efficiency. I conclude that our stock markets are more efficient and less predictable than many recent academic papers would have us believe.</description><author>Malkiel, B. G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toward a cost-of-living index: Progress and prospects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abraham, K. G.
nan</description><author>Abraham, K. G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From efficient markets theory to behavioral finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shiller, R. J.
The efficient markets theory reached the height of its dominance in academic circles around the 1970s. Faith in this theory was eroded by a succession of discoveries of anomalies, many in the 1980s, and of evidence of excess volatility of returns. Finance literature in this decade and after suggests a more nuanced view of the value of the efficient markets theory, and, starting in the 1990s, a blossoming of research on behavioral finance. Some important developments since 1990 include feedback theories, models of the interaction of smart money with ordinary investors, and evidence on obstacles to smart money.</description><author>Shiller, R. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The environmental Kuznets curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, D.
nan</description><author>Baker, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Instrumental variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buse, A.
nan</description><author>Buse, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why is there so little money in US politics?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ansolabehere, S.; de Figueiredo, J. M.; Snyder, J. M.
nan</description><author>Ansolabehere, S.; de Figueiredo, J. M.; Snyder, J. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recommendations for further reading - Comments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McCullough, B. D.; Vinod, H. D.
nan</description><author>McCullough, B. D.; Vinod, H. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recommendations for further reading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saffran, B.
nan</description><author>Saffran, B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retrospectives - Whatever happened to the Cambridge capital theory controversies?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, A. J.; Harcourt, G. C.
We argue that the Cambridge capital theory controversies of the 1950s to 1970s were the latest in a series of still-unresolved controversies over three deep issues: explaining and justifying the return to capital; Joan Robinson's complaint that, due to path dependence, equilibrium is not an outcome of an economic process and therefore an inadequate tool for analyzing accumulation and growth; and the role of ideology and vision in fuelling controversy when results of simple models are not robust. We predict these important and relevant issues, latent in endogenous growth and real business cycle theories, will erupt in future controversy.</description><author>Cohen, A. J.; Harcourt, G. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An interview with Edmond Malinvaud</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, A. B.; Malinvaud, E.
This article contains an interview with Edmond Malinvaud. Professor Malinvaud describes the origins of his interest in economics, teachers who had a major influence on his development as an economist, his visit to the Cowles Commission in 1950, the substance of his research, and the contributions he made as a policy maker. Among the interesting tidbits in the interview is that Professor Malinvaud's popular textbooks in microeconomic theory, macroeconomics and econometrics were a direct outgrowth of courses he taught at INSEE. "I am not good at speaking," he said, "when not constrained by a written text."</description><author>Krueger, A. B.; Malinvaud, E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond incentive pay: Insiders' estimates of the value of complementary human resource management practices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ichniowski, C.; Shaw, K.
Do human resource management (HRM) practices, such as incentive pay, teamwork, training, and careful screening practices, raise productivity, and if so, under what conditions does productivity rise? Recently, this question has been a central focus in organizational and personnel economics. We emphasize the value of a new research approach-an approach we label "insider econometrics"-that is aimed going deep inside businesses to obtain data and insights into the ways in which HRM practices affect specific production processes. We conclude that sets of complementary HRM practices appear to raise performance, but that some firms, such as those that make complex products or those that are starting up brand new facilities, benefit more from these practices.</description><author>Ichniowski, C.; Shaw, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Durable goods theory for real world markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Waldman, M.
The early 1970s witnessed three major advances in durable-goods theory-Swan (1970, 1971) and Sieper and Swan (1973) on optimal durability, Coase (1972) on time inconsistency, and Akerlof (1970) on adverse selection. This paper surveys durable goods theory starting with these three contributions, where much of the focus is on recent literature and on models that explain real-world phenomena. In addition to the ideas found in the contributions of Swan, Coase, and Akerlof, topics covered include why producers sometimes practice "planned obsolescence," the role of adverse selection in new-car leasing, and reasons for aftermarket monopolization.</description><author>Waldman, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The mirage of exchange rate regimes for emerging market countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calvo, G. A.; Mishkin, F. S.
This paper argues that much of the debate on choosing an exchange rate regime misses the boat. It begins by discussing the standard theory of choice between exchange rate regimes, and then explores the weaknesses in this theory, especially when it is applied to emerging market economies. It then discusses a range of institutional traits that might predispose a country to favor either fixed or floating rates, and then turns to the converse question of whether the choice of exchange rate regime may favor the development of certain desirable institutional traits. The conclusion from the analysis is that the choice of exchange rate regime is likely to be of second order importance to the development of good fiscal, financial, and monetary institutions in producing macroeconomic success in emerging market countries. This suggests that less attention should be focused on the general question whether a floating or a fixed exchange rate is preferable, and more on these deeper institutional arrangements. A focus on institutional reforms rather than on the exchange rate regime may encourage emerging market countries to be healthier and less prone to the crises that we have seen in recent years.</description><author>Calvo, G. A.; Mishkin, F. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Restructuring sovereign debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eichengreen, B.
This paper provides new empirical evidence relevant to the debate over the desirability of reforms to the way that financial markets and the international community deal with sovereign debt crises. In particular, given the ongoing opposition of investors and some sovereigns to greater use of collective action clauses (CACs) in emerging market bonds, we present new evidence on the way that financial markets have priced the use or non-use of CACs.</description><author>Eichengreen, B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The unholy trinity of financial contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaminsky, G. L.; Reinhart, C. M.; Vegh, C. A.
Over the last 20 years, some financial events, such as devaluations or defaults, have triggered an immediate adverse chain reaction in other countries-which we call fast and furious contagion. Yet, on other occasions, similar events have failed to trigger any immediate international reaction. We argue that fast and furious contagion episodes are characterized by "the unholy trinity": (i) they follow a large surge in capital flows; (ii) they come as a surprise; and (iii) they involve a leveraged common creditor. In contrast, when similar events have elicited little international reaction, they were widely anticipated and took place at a time when capital flows had already subsided.</description><author>Kaminsky, G. L.; Reinhart, C. M.; Vegh, C. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The case for antitrust enforcement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, J. B.
This paper provides evidence of the necessity and success of antitrust enforcement. It begins with examples of socially beneficial antitrust challenges by the federal antitrust agencies to price-fixing and other forms of collusion; to mergers that appear likely to harm competition; and to monopolists that use anticompetitive exclusionary practices to obtain or maintain their market power. It then reviews systematic empirical evidence on the value of antitrust derived from informal experiments involving the behavior of U.S. firms during periods without effective antitrust enforcement, and the behavior of firms across different national antitrust regimes. Overall, it concludes, the benefits of antitrust enforcement to consumers and social welfare-particularly in deterring the harms from anticompetitive conduct across the economy-appear to be far larger than what the government spends on antitrust enforcement and firms spend directly or indirectly on antitrust compliance.</description><author>Baker, J. B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does antitrust policy improve consumer welfare? Assessing the evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crandall, R. W.; Winston, C.
This paper reviews the literature and assesses the effects of antitrust policy and enforcement on consumer welfare. We find no evidence that antitrust policy in the areas of monopolization, collusion, and mergers has provided much benefit to consumers and, in some instances, we find evidence that it may have lowered consumer welfare. We also do not find any evidence that antitrust policy has deterred firms from engaging in actions that could harm consumers. We identify various reasons for the apparent ineffectiveness of antitrust policy, offer preliminary policy recommendations, and suggest ways in which economists could more fully assess antitrust policy.</description><author>Crandall, R. W.; Winston, C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Escaping from a liquidity trap and deflation: The foolproof way and others</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Svensson, L. E. O.
Existing proposals to escape from a liquidity trap and deflation, including my "Foolproof Way," are discussed in the light of the optimal way to escape. The optimal way involves three elements: (1) an explicit central-bank commitment to a higher future price level; (2) a concrete action that demonstrates the central bank's commitment, induces expectations of a higher future price level and jump-starts the economy; and (3) an exit strategy that specifies when and how to get back to normal. A currency depreciation is a direct consequence of expectations of a higher future price level and hence an excellent indicator of those expectations. Furthermore, an intentional currency depreciation and a crawling peg, as in the Foolproof Way, can implement the optimal way and, in particular, induce the desired expectations of a higher future price level. I conclude that the Foolproof Way is likely to work well for Japan, which is in a liquidity trap now, as well as for the euro area and the United States, in case either would fall into a liquidity trap in the future.</description><author>Svensson, L. E. O.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Education, poverty and terrorism: Is there a causal connection?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, A. B.; Maleckova, J.
The paper investigates whether there is a connection between poverty or low education and terrorism. We review evidence on hate crimes, which are closely related to terrorism; the occurrence of hate crimes is largely independent of economic conditions. We analyze data on support for attacks against Israeli targets from public opinion polls conducted in the West Bank and Gaza Strip; support for violent attacks does not decrease among those with higher education and higher living standards. The core contribution of the paper is a statistical analysis of the determinants of participation in Hezbollah militant activities; having a living standard above the poverty line or a secondary or higher education is positively associated with participation in Hezbollah. We also find that Israeli Jewish settlers who attacked Palestinians in the West Bank in the early 1980s were overwhelmingly from high-paying occupations. Although our results are tentative and exploratory, they suggest that neither poverty nor education has a direct, causal impact on terrorism.</description><author>Krueger, A. B.; Maleckova, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The demographic transition: Three centuries of fundamental change</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, R.
The global demographic transition began around 1800 in Europe with declining mortality followed by declining fertility, trends which spread around the world and continue in this century. At the aggregate level, population size greatly increased, growth accelerated and declined with many countries now shrinking, and age distributions inevitably moved from young to old. Population aging has not yet run its course, Its effects exacerbated by declining retirement ages, straining pensions systems and prompting their reform. These aggregate demographic trends reflect profound changes in risks and behavior for individuals and families, and in the shape of the economic life cycle.</description><author>Lee, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International sanctions - Response from Lance E. Davis and Stanley Engerman</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International sanctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaempfer, W. H.; Lowenberg, A. D.
nan</description><author>Kaempfer, W. H.; Lowenberg, A. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anomalies - The law of one price in financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lamont, O. A.; Thaler, R. H.
The Law of One price states that identical goods (or securities) should sell for identical prices. In financial markets the law of one price is thought to hold almost exactly, and is the basis for much of financial economic theory. We present evidence on several examples of violations of this law, including closed-end country funds, twin shares, dual class shares, and corporate spinoffs. We analyze the causes of these violations, and show they all stem from some limits on the extent to which rational arbitrageurs can intervene.</description><author>Lamont, O. A.; Thaler, R. H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cambridge capital controversies - Response from Avi J. Cohen and G. C. Harcourt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cambridge capital controversies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenfield, R. L.
nan</description><author>Greenfield, R. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cambridge capital controversies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Felipe, J.; McCombie, J. S. L.
nan</description><author>Felipe, J.; McCombie, J. S. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cambridge capital controversies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fisher, F. M.
nan</description><author>Fisher, F. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cambridge capital controversies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pasinetti, L. L.
nan</description><author>Pasinetti, L. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - The economics standards of fuel economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Portney, P. R.; Parry, I. W. H.; Gruenspecht, H. K.; Harrington, W.
One of the most hotly contested of all energy policy issues involves Corporate Average Fuel Economy (or CAFE) standards for new cars and light-duty trucks. Tighter standards would reduce gasoline consumption, and hence both greenhouse gas emissions as well as this country's vulnerability to oil price shocks. But they would also increase the price of new vehicles, worsen traffic congestion and-depending on how they are phased in-possibly even reduce occupant safety. These effects are amenable to economic analysis, and we review the evidence to date bearing on this interesting and important question.</description><author>Portney, P. R.; Parry, I. W. H.; Gruenspecht, H. K.; Harrington, W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comments - Pricing and cost of electronics journals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dirkmaat, J.
nan</description><author>Dirkmaat, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comments - Pricing and cost of electronics journals - Response from Theodore Bergstrom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergstrom, T.
nan</description><author>Bergstrom, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comments - Pricing and cost of electronics journals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kohn, R. E.
nan</description><author>Kohn, R. E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retrospectives - Economists and the fed: Beginnings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mehrling, P.
As usually understood, the significant debate over the founding of the Fed was between advocates of the real bills doctrine and advocates of the quantity theory of money. This understanding however conflates two different distinctions: one between the banking principle and the currency principle, and one between self-regulation and active management. It also fails to take seriously both the context of practical experience with the national banking system and the developing practical experience inside the Fed. I propose a new interpretation focused mainly on the contributions of four economists: J. Laurence Laughlin, Irving Fisher, Paul Warburg and Benjamin Strong.</description><author>Mehrling, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decentralization of governance and development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bardhan, P.
In this paper we note that the institutional context (and therefore the structure of incentives and organization) in developing and transition economies is quite different from those in advanced industrial economies, and this necessitates the literature on decentralization in the context of development to go beyond the traditional fiscal federalism literature. We review some of the existing theoretical work and empirical case studies of decentralization from the point of view of delivery of public services and of conditions for local business development, and point to ways of going forward in research.</description><author>Bardhan, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Productivity growth in world agriculture: Sources and constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ruttan, V. W.
During the last half-century, advances in crop production came from expansion in areas irrigated from more intensive application of fertilizers and crop protection chemicals, and from crop varieties that were more responsive to technical inputs and management. Advances in animal production came from genetic improvements and advances in animal nutrition. Differences among developed and developing countries in output per hectare and per worker have widened. If these gaps are to be narrowed agricultural research capacity in developing countries will have to be substantially strengthened.</description><author>Ruttan, V. W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trends in aggregate concentration in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>White, L. J.
I assemble two rarely used data sets to measure aggregate concentration in the U.S. in the 1980s and 1990s. Despite the merger waves of those decades, aggregate concentration declined in the 1980s and the early 1990s, but rose modestly in the late 1990s. The levels at the end of the decade were at or below the levels of the late 1980s or early 1990s. The average size of firm and the relative importance of larger size classes of firms increased, however. Gini coefficients for employment and payroll shares of companies showed moderate but steady increases from 1988 through 1999.</description><author>White, L. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The NAIRU in theory and practice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ball, L.; Mankiw, N. G.
This paper discusses the NAIRU-the non-accelerating inflation rate of unemployment. It first considers the role of the NAIRU concept in business cycle theory, arguing that this concept is implicit in any model in which monetary policy influences both inflation and unemployment. The exact value of the NAIRU is hard to measure, however, in part because it changes over time. The paper then discusses why the NAIRU changes and, in particular, why it fell in the United States during the 1990s. The most promising hypothesis is that the decline in the NAIRU is attributable to the acceleration in productivity growth.</description><author>Ball, L.; Mankiw, N. G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The promise and pitfalls of using imprecise school accountability measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kane, T. J.; Staiger, D. O.
In recent years, most states have constructed elaborate accountability systems using school-level test scores. However, because the median elementary school contains only 69 children per grade level, such measures are quite imprecise. We evaluate the implications for school accountability systems. For instance, rewards or sanctions for schools with scores at either extreme primarily affect small schools and provide weak incentives to large ones. Nevertheless, we conclude that accountability systems may be worthwhile. Even in states with aggressive financial incentives, the marginal reward to schools for raising student performance is a small fraction of the potential labor market value for students.</description><author>Kane, T. J.; Staiger, D. O.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pharmaceuticals and the developing world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kremer, M.
Pharmaceuticals have greatly improved health in developing countries, but many people in developing countries do not obtain even inexpensive pharmaceuticals and little pharmaceutical R&amp;D is oriented toward products needed by developing countries, such as a malaria vaccine. Access to existing products could be improved by facilitating differential pricing, for example by subsidizing donation programs, and reforming health care delivery. R&amp;D incentives could be improved if rich countries or international organization committed to purchase needed products when they are developed and make them available to the poor.</description><author>Kremer, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pharmaceuticals in US health care: Determinants of quantity and price</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berndt, E. R.
The U.S. pharmaceutical industry has again become the focus of considerable controversy. In understanding the economics underlying this industry, distinctions between short, medium and long-run costs are critical, as is that between economic and accounting costs. Consumers' heterogeneous valuations create strong incentives for non-uniform pricing and targeted marketing. The conflict between static efficiency (price new drugs low, near short-run marginal cost) and dynamic efficiency (price new drugs high, maintain incentives for innovation) is deep and enduring. This trade-off is becoming more severe as the relative costs of bringing new drugs to market have increased sharply.</description><author>Berndt, E. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How vouchers could change the market for education</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neal, D.
nan</description><author>Neal, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>School vouchers: A critical view</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ladd, H. F.
This paper marshals available evidence from both the U.S. and other countries on the effects of private schools, peer effects, and competition to demonstrate that that any gains in overall student achievement from a large scale voucher program are at best likely to be small. Moreover, given the tendency of parents to judge schools in part by the characteristics of a school's students, a universal voucher system would undoubtedly harm large numbers of disadvantaged students. Although the case for a small means tested voucher program is somewhat stronger, it will do little to improve education for low-performing students.</description><author>Ladd, H. F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic reforms in India since 1991: Has gradualism worked?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahluwalia, M. S.
Opinions on the causes of India's growth deceleration vary. World economic growth was slower in the second half of the 1990s, and that would have had some dampening effect, but India's dependence on the world economy is not large enough for this to account for the slowdown. Critics of liberalization have blamed the slowdown on the effect of trade policy reforms on domestic industry. However, the opposite view is that the slowdown is due not to the effects of reforms, but rather to the failure to implement the reforms effectively. This in turn is often attributed to India's gradualist approach to reform, which has meant a frustratingly slow pace of implementation. However, even a gradualist pace should be able to achieve significant policy changes over ten years. This paper examines India's experience with gradualist reforms from this perspective.</description><author>Ahluwalia, M. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic interpretations of intergenerational correlations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grawe, N. D.; Mulligan, C. B.
Since accurate prediction ultimately determines the usefulness of theory, our paper gives the reader a taste of some predictions derived from economic theory and some empirical successes and failures. We provide only a taste, because there are a great many economic models relevant to intergenerational correlations - such as models of educational attainment, neighborhood effects in schooling, family formation and fertility choice, occupational choice and discrimination - and quite a variety of predictions that might be derived from these models. However, a simple model of investment and intergenerational decision making can be interpreted as a conceptual aggregation of many more detailed economic models. We present such a model and from it derive one class of predictions that has received substantial attention in the empirical literature - the role of endowments and credit markets in determining intergenerational correlations.</description><author>Grawe, N. D.; Mulligan, C. B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intergenerational inequality: A sociological perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erikson, R.; Goldthorpe, J. H.
When economists are concerned with the inheritance of inequality, they typically focus on the intergenerational transmission of income or wealth. In contrast, sociologists are more likely to analyze intergenerational mobility between (and immobility in) different class positions.</description><author>Erikson, R.; Goldthorpe, J. H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The inheritance of inequality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bowles, S.; Gintis, H.
How level is the intergenerational playing field? What are the causal mechanisms that underlie the intergenerational transmission of economic status? Are these mechanisms amenable to public policies in a way that would make the attainment of economic success more fair? These are the questions we will try to answer.</description><author>Bowles, S.; Gintis, H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-country differences in intergenerational earnings mobility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Solon, G.
International studies of the extent to which economic status is passed from one generation to the next are important for at least two reasons. First, each study of a particular country characterizes an important feature of that country's income inequality. Second, comparisons of intergenerational mobility across countries may yield valuable clues about how income status is transmitted across generations and why the strength of that intergenerational transmission varies across countries. The first section of this paper explains a benchmark measure of intergenerational mobility commonly used in U.S. studies. The second section summarizes comparable empirical findings that have accumulated so far for countries other than the United States. The third section sketches a theoretical framework for interpreting cross-country differences in intergenerational mobility.</description><author>Solon, G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is India's economic growth leaving the poor behind?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Datt, G.; Ravallion, M.
Has poverty continued to fall with growth in India in the 1990s, or has the nature of the growth process changed, such that the poor have been left behind? This paper tries to answer those questions. We do not attempt to assess the impact of India's macroeconomic reforms of the 1990s on poverty, since this would require identification of the counterfactual of what would have been experienced in the 1990s without the reforms. Rather, our aim is to describe what has happened to poverty in India in the 1990s. In the course of the discussion, we will learn about the proximate causes of changes in India's poverty rate. Moreover, although this discussion is India-specific, it illustrates themes that are often encountered in the analysis of poverty in low-income economies, including difficult issues of survey design and comparability and the proximate factors underlying the responsiveness of poverty to economic growth.</description><author>Datt, G.; Ravallion, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic history and modern India: Redefining the link</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roy, T.
This paper argues that to restore the link between economic history and modern India, a different narrative of Indian economic history is needed. An exclusive focus on colonialism as the driver of India's economic history misses those continuities that arise from economic structure or local conditions. In fact, market-oriented British imperial policies did initiate a process of economic growth based on the production of goods intensive in labor and natural resources. However, productive capacity per worker was constrained by low rates of private and public investment in infrastructure, excessively low rates of schooling, social inequalities based on caste and gender and a delayed demographic transition to lower birthrates and the resultant heavy demographic burden placed on physical capital and natural resources.</description><author>Roy, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Meta-analysis - Response from T.D. Stanley</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stanley, T. D.
nan</description><author>Stanley, T. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Meta-analysis - Comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neumark, D.; Wascher, W.
nan</description><author>Neumark, D.; Wascher, W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Meta-analysis - Comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldfarb, R. S.; Stekler, H. O.
nan</description><author>Goldfarb, R. S.; Stekler, H. O.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recommendations for further reading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saffran, B.
nan</description><author>Saffran, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retrospectives - The origins of neoclassical microeconomics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ekelund, R. B.; Hebert, R. F.
Until recently, the standard story line in history of thought textbooks was that a triumvirate of British and Continental writers established demarcation between classical economics and neoclassical economics in the early 1870s. The authors raise two objections to this potted history. The first is that the tools of neoclassical economics were invented earlier. Recent work has demonstrated that the tools of neoclassical analysis were widely available across Europe well before 1870. The notion that neoclassical economics experienced a tripartite immaculate conception around 1870 cannot stand. The second objection is that the method of neoclassical economics was invented later. As it stands, the legend undervalues the key contribution of Alfred Marshall, who put an indelible stamp on neoclassical economics by defining the appropriate method of economic inquiry. When we refer to neoclassical economics today, we usually mean the collection of tools of economic knowledge available to (and invented by) Marshall, channeled and directed into uses dictated by Marshall's view of economic science. Yet as we shall see, Marshall had an eminent predecessor in method as well, in the person of Jules Dupuit.</description><author>Ekelund, R. B.; Hebert, R. F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The theory of the firm as governance structure: From choice to contract</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williamson, O. E.
The propositions that organization matters and that it is susceptible to analysis were long greeted by skepticism by economists. One reason why this message took a long time to register is that it is much easier to say that organization matters than it is to show how and why. The prevalence of the science of choice approach to economics has also been an obstacle. As developed herein, the lessons of organization theory for economics are both different and more consequential when examined through the lens of contract. This paper examines economic organization from a science of contract perspective, with special emphasis on the theory of the firm.</description><author>Williamson, O. E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The central role of entrepreneurs in transition economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McMillan, J.; Woodruff, C.
The authors summarize entrepreneurial patterns in the transition economies, particularly Russia, China, Poland and Vietnam. Markets developed spontaneously in every transition country, but they were built at varying speeds. Some governments impeded the entrepreneurs' self-help by creating conditions that made it hard for informal contracting to work; others created an environment that was conducive to self-help. The spontaneous emergence of markets, furthermore, has its limits. As firms' activities became more complex, they came to need formal institutions. Some governments fostered entrepreneurship by building market-supporting infrastructure; others did not. The authors argue that the success or failure of a transition economy can be traced in large part to the performance of its entrepreneurs.</description><author>McMillan, J.; Woodruff, C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Perspectives on the US current account deficit and sustainability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mann, C. L.
This essay considers the underpinnings of the large U.S. current account deficit. It then tackles the question of whether the U.S. current account deficit is sustainable. A current account deficit is "sustainable" at a point in time if neither it, nor the associated foreign capital inflows, nor the negative net international investment position are large enough to induce significant changes in economic variables, such as consumption or investment or interest rates or exchange rates. Even if the current account deficit is sustainable by this definition today, its trajectory could still be creating future risks for the U.S. and global economy.</description><author>Mann, C. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolutionary theorizing in economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nelson, R. R.; Winter, S. G.
This paper reviews the case for an evolutionary approach to problems of economic analysis, ranging from the details of individual firm behavior in the short run through industrial dynamics to the historical evolution of institutions and technologies. We draw upon a substantial body of recent research contributions. We characterize micro behavior as governed by skills and routines that are shaped by learning and selection. We then consider major areas of application of evolutionary thinking, including the analysis of competitive processes in technologically dynamic industries and the evolution of institutions and technologies.</description><author>Nelson, R. R.; Winter, S. G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolution of social behavior: Individual and group selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergstrom, T. C.
How selfish does our evolutionary history suggest that humans will be? We explore models in which groups are formed and dissolved and where reproduction of individuals is determined by their payoffs in a game played within groups. If groups are formed "randomly" and reproductive success of group founders is determined by a multiperson prisoners' dilemma game, then selfish behavior will prevail over maximization of group payoffs. However, interesting models exist in which "group selection "sustains cooperative behavior. Forces that support cooperative behavior include assortative matching in groups, group longevity and punishment-based group norms.</description><author>Bergstrom, T. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolution and human nature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robson, A. J.
This paper considers how biological evolution shaped the elements of a simple but complete model of economic decision making. These elements are preferences, beliefs and rationality. Whereas Nature might impose preferences over consumption on the individual, Nature might optimally allow beliefs to be influenced by local knowledge and final choice to be flexible. This reinforces the usual approach. On the one hand, evolution also suggests that some extensions of this model are implausible; on the other, it suggests unexpected directions of generalization. In any case, evolution provides a basis for an overarching economic theory and maintains restrictions on this theory.</description><author>Robson, A. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of economics in climate change policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McKibbin, W. J.; Wilcoxen, P. J.
The most important characteristic of climate change as a policy problem is uncertainty. From climatology to economics, uncertainties are pervasive, large and difficult to resolve. However, the economic theory of environmental policy under uncertainty provides a clear guide to the design of an appropriate policy. An efficient and practical approach would be a hybrid that incorporates the best features of tradable permits and emissions taxes. Unfortunately, international negotiations have taken a different approach, focusing on rigid targets and timetables for emissions reductions. The result has been the Kyoto Protocol, an agreement with no real chance of reducing greenhouse gas emissions.</description><author>McKibbin, W. J.; Wilcoxen, P. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of patents: Lessons from recent US patent reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallini, N. T.
U.S. patent reform over the past two decades has strengthened the legal enforcement of patent rights and has extended protection to new subject matter, such as genetically engineered life forms and business methods. This paper highlights these and other policy changes and the debate that this apparent increase in protection has sparked. While the case for stronger patents as a spur to innovation is a weak one, as revealed by recent theoretical and empirical research, evidence that they encourage disclosure and technology transfer is persuasive. The paper discusses the social costs and benefits of these effects from the policy changes and proposals for alleviating the costs through further patent reform.</description><author>Gallini, N. T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oligopsony and monopsonistic competition in labor markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhaskar, V.; Manning, A.; To, T.
We argue that models of oligopsony or monopsonistic competition provide insights and explanation for many empirical phenomena in labor markets. Using a simple model with job differentiation and preference heterogeneity, we illustrate how such models can be employed to explain the existence of wage dispersion, the persistence of labor market discrimination, market failures in the provision of training and the anomalous employment effects of minimum wages.</description><author>Bhaskar, V.; Manning, A.; To, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposit insurance around the globe: Where does it work?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Kane, E. J.
Explicit deposit insurance has been spreading rapidly in recent years, even to countries with low levels of financial and institutional development. This paper documents the extent of cross-country differences in deposit insurance design and reviews empirical evidence on how particular design features affect private market discipline, banking stability, financial development and the effectiveness of crisis resolution. This evidence challenges the wisdom of encouraging countries to adopt explicit deposit insurance without first stopping to assess and remedy weaknesses in their informational and supervisory environments.</description><author>Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Kane, E. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retrospectives - Captains of industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dixon, R.
This paper traces the origin and use of the term "captains of industry." Introduced by the Scottish historian and essayist Thomas Carlyle in the mid-nineteenth century, its meanings and associations were very different from today. For Carlyle, they were ferocious instruments of social control who would force the unemployed and idle to work and, if necessary, discipline them. The term, if not the meaning, rapidly entered the popular lexicon. It was brought into economics by Francis Walker, the first president of the AEA, who argued that the captain of industry was a fourth factor of production and the engine of industrial progress. While many other writers shared this view, Veblen did not.</description><author>Dixon, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - The federal employees health benefits plan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldman, R.; Thorpe, K. E.; Gray, B.
This short feature describes the Federal Employees Health Benefits Plan (FEHBP), which provides health insurance benefits to active and retired federal employees and their dependents. The article discusses the FEHBP as a touchstone for research on employment-based health insurance and as a touchstone for health policy reform.</description><author>Feldman, R.; Thorpe, K. E.; Gray, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recommendations for further reading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saffran, B.
nan</description><author>Saffran, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Defending expected utility theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Watt, R.
nan</description><author>Watt, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Defending expected utility theory - Response</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rabin, M.; Thaler, R. H.
nan</description><author>Rabin, M.; Thaler, R. H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolution and game theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Samuelson, L.
Research in noncooperative game theory has focused attention on two questions: Should we expect equilibrium play? If so, which of the multiple equilibria that arise in many games should we expect? This paper summarizes recent approaches to these questions that have been based on evolutionary models.</description><author>Samuelson, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distinguished lecture on economics in government - The new economy: Post mortem or second wind?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baily, M. N.
There was an acceleration of U.S. productivity after 1995. Investment in information technology hardware and software contributed importantly to this, but was not its sole cause. In part, heavy IT investment, perhaps overinvestment, was the result of the booming economy and cheap capital. Besides IT, the expansion of productive firms boosted productivity, together with the competitive pressure this put on other firms to innovate and improve. Productivity growth has been surprisingly strong in 2001, and the likely trend for the future is in the range of 2.2 to 2.7 percent a year. The economy should get a second wind.</description><author>Baily, M. N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional determinants of labor reallocation in transition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boeri, T.; Terrell, K.
The transition process differed in the countries of the Former Soviet Union (FSU) and those of Central and Eastern Europe (CEE) in terms of reallocation of labor real wage, employment and output adjustment. We sift through the theoretical and empirical literature to find an explanation for these diverging adjustment trajectories and conclude that they can be explained by the fact that the CEE countries adopted social policies that upheld wages at the bottom of the distribution forcing the old sector to restructure or collapse while the FSU countries allowed wages to free-fall not forcing the hand of the old sector.</description><author>Boeri, T.; Terrell, K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Data watch - Research data from transition economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Filer, R. K.; Hanousek, J.
Ten years into the transition from communism in the countries of the former Soviet Union and central and eastern Europe, a cursory search of the EconLit database turns up hundreds of empirical studies published in refereed journals that deal with various issues in transition economies. Even so, we suspect that many economists are prevented from making full use of the possibilities offered by the transition by the difficulties of obtaining and interpreting data from the region. The purpose of this brief essay is to indicate some possible sources for data that can be used for economic analysis, as well as some cautions regarding the use of these data.</description><author>Filer, R. K.; Hanousek, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - US disability policy in a changing environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burkhauser, R. V.; Daly, M. C.
In this paper we provide a context for evaluating the goals and effectiveness of current disability policy. We review the Social Security Disability Insurance and Supplemental Security Income programs and examine trends in disability benefit receipt and employment among working-age people with disabilities. We discuss the difficulties in crafting efficient and equitable programs for this difficult to target, heterogeneous population. We conclude that changes in policy rather than in underlying health are most likely behind the increases in disability benefit receipt and the declines in employment of working-age people with disabilities over the 1990s business cycle.</description><author>Burkhauser, R. V.; Daly, M. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The trouble with electricity markets: Understanding California's restructuring disaster</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borenstein, S.
In June 2000, after two years of fairly smooth operation, California's deregulated wholesale electricity market began producing extremely high prices and threats of supply shortages. The upheaval demonstrated dramatically why most current electricity markets are extremely volatile: demand is difficult to forecast and exhibits virtually no price responsiveness, while supply faces strict production constraints and prohibitive storage costs. This structure leads to periods of surplus and of shortage, the latter exacerbated by sellers' ability to exercise market power. Electricity markets can function much more smoothly, however, if they are designed to support price-responsive demand and long-term wholesale contracts for electricity.</description><author>Borenstein, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What really matters in auction design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klemperer, P.
The most important issues in auction design are the traditional concerns of competition policy-preventing collusive, predatory, and entry-deterring behavior. Ascending and uniform-price auctions are particularly vulnerable to these problems. The Anglo-Dutch auction - a hybrid of the sealed-bid and ascending auctions - may perform better. Effective antitrust is also critical. Notable fiascoes in auctioning mobile-phone licenses, television franchises, companies, eletricty, etc., and especially the European "third-generation" (UMTS) spectrum auctions, show that everything depends on the details of the context. Auction design is not "one size fits all."</description><author>Klemperer, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Confronting the environmental Kuznets curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dasgupta, S.; Laplante, B.; Wang, H.; Wheeler, D.
The environmental Kuznets curve posits an inverted-U relationship between pollution and economic development. Pessimistic critics of empirically estimated curves have argued that their declining portions are illusory, either because they are cross-sectional snapshots that mask a long-run "race to the bottom" in environmental standards, or because industrial societies will continually produce new pollutants as the old ones are controlled. However, recent evidence has fostered an optimistic view by suggesting that the curve is actually flattening and shifting to the left. The driving forces appear to be economic liberalization, clean technology diffusion, and new approaches to pollution regulation in developing countries.</description><author>Dasgupta, S.; Laplante, B.; Wang, H.; Wheeler, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Environmental policy since earth day I: What have we gained?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Freeman, A. M.
I review the data on costs and benefits of the major environmental laws passed during the 1970s. The winners in terms of benefit-cost analysis include: getting lead out of gasoline; controlling particulate air pollution; reducing the concentration of lead in drinking water; and the cleanup of hazardous waste sites with the lowest cost per cancer case avoided under Superfund The losers include: mobile source air pollution control; water pollution control; and many of the regulations and cleanup decisions taken under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, the Toxic Substances Control Act, the Safe Drinking Water Act, and Superfund.</description><author>Freeman, A. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and corporate governance in transition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Estrin, S.
This paper examines the elements of institutional development critical to the enhancement of company performance in transition economies. This includes initial conditions, forms of privatization, institutional frameworks and the competitiveness of markets. Comparing empirical evidence, the paper concludes that there is a clear distinction in effectiveness of policies followed and their impact between Central Europe and CIS countries. This divergence is attributed to fundamentally different political attitudes toward reform, the need of CIS governments to gain political support for reform and as a consequence of the desire of Central European countries to join European Union.</description><author>Estrin, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The great divide and beyond: Financial architecture in transition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berglof, E.; Bolton, P.
The Great Divide in economic and financial development and the convergence in financial architecture among the successful countries raise fundamental questions about how financial development interacts with economic growth. Is it possible to engineer a development takeoff by creating a modern financial architecture from scratch? Or are financial institutions and markets a reflection of underlying conditions in the real sector? Or are both financial development and economic growth driven by some other underlying variables? Is it possible to leapfrog certain stages of financial development or must all countries go through a phase of bank-oriented financial architecture? The experience of the transition economies represents a unique opportunity to shed new light on these issues.</description><author>Berglof, E.; Bolton, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The political economy of transition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roland, G.
The overriding importance of political constraints in the transition process has led to developments of the theory of the political economy of reform. What are the main insights from that theory? How does it reflect the transition reality? What have we learned, and what do we still need to learn? The present article will attempt to answer those questions.</description><author>Roland, G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transition economies: Performance and challenges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Svejnar, J.
I present data and assess the first twelve years of the transition from plan to market. Transformations have taken place, but the income gap between the transition and advanced economies has widened. Transition countries further east have performed worse than those further west, but policies matter. All countries carried out quickly Type I reforms, such as macroeconomic stabilization, price liberalization, small-scale privatization, and breakup of state-owned enterprises. They differed in Type II reforms, such as large-scale privatization and development of banking and legal systems. Countries that developed a functioning legal framework and corporate governance have performed better than others.</description><author>Svejnar, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Microsoft case: What can a dominant firm do to defend its market position?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klein, B.
This paper examines the competitive actions taken by Microsoft in its "browser war" with Netscape, most importantly Microsoft's decisions to give away Explorer free of charge, integrate Explorer into its dominant Windows operating system and pay online service providers for exclusive distribution. Consumers benefited significantly from these actions, but the fundamental economic question is whether Microsoft abused its existing market power when competing in this way. A detailed analysis of Microsoft's conduct and the economics of competition for distribution suggests that severe limits placed on Microsoft's behavior would not be welfare.</description><author>Klein, B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and merger activity in the United States: Making sense of the 1980s and 1990s</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holmstrom, B.; Kaplan, S. N.
This paper describes and considers explanations for changes in corporate governance and merger activity in the United States since 1980. Corporate governance in the 1980s was dominated by intense merger activity distinguished by the prevalence of leveraged buyouts (LBOs) and hostility. After a brief decline in the early 1990s, substantial merger activity resumed in the second half of the decade, while LBOs and hostility did not. Instead, internal corporate governance mechanisms appear to have played a larger role in the 1990s. We conclude by considering whether these changes and the movement toward shareholder value are likely to be permanent.</description><author>Holmstrom, B.; Kaplan, S. N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New evidence and perspectives on mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrade, G.; Mitchell, M.; Stafford, E.
As in previous decades, merger activity clusters by industry during the 1990s. One particular kind of industry shock, deregulation, becomes a dominant factor, accountings for nearly half of the merger activity since the late 1980s. In contrast to the 1980s, mergers in the 1990s are mostly stock swaps, and hostile takeovers virtually disappear. Over our 1973 to 1998 sample period, the announcement-period stock market response to mergers is positive for the combined merging parties, suggesting that mergers create value on behalf of shareholders. Consistent with that, we find evidence of improved operating performance following mergers, relative to industry peers.</description><author>Andrade, G.; Mitchell, M.; Stafford, E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Myers, S. C.
nan</description><author>Myers, S. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exclusivity and tying in US v. Microsoft: What we know, and don't know</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Whinston, M. D.
Research on capital structure attempts to explain how corporations finance real investment, with particular emphasis on the proportions of debt vs. equity financing. There is no universal theory of the debt-equity choice, and no reason to expect one. But three useful conditional theories are reviewed in this paper. The tradeoff theory says that firms seek debt levels that balance the tax advantages of additional debt against the costs of possible financial distress. The pecking order theory says that the firm will borrow, rather than issuing equity, when internal cash flow is not sufficient to fund capital expenditures. Thus, the amount of debt will reflect the firm's cumulative need for external funds. The free cash flow theory says that dangerously high debt levels will increase value, despite the threat of financial distress. Each of these theories "works" for some firms in some circumstances. More general theories will require a deeper understanding of the financial objectives of corporate managers.</description><author>Whinston, M. D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An economist's guide to US v. Microsoft</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilbert, R. J.; Katz, M. L.
We analyze the central economic issues raised by U.S. v Microsoft. Network effects and economies of scale in applications programs created a barrier to entry for new operating system competitors, which the combination of Netscape Navigator and the Java programming language potentially could have lowered. Microsoft took actions to eliminate this threat to its operating system monopoly, and some of Microsoft's conduct very likely harmed consumers. While we recognize the risks of the government's proposed structural remedy of splitting Microsoft in two, we are pessimistic that a limited conduct remedy would be effective in this case.</description><author>Gilbert, R. J.; Katz, M. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distinguished lecture on economics in government - Exchange rate regimes: Is the bipolar view correct?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischer, S.
The bipolar or two-corner solution view of exchange rates is that intermediate policy regimes between hard pegs and floating are not sustainable. This paper argues that the proponents of the bipolar view have probably exaggerated their point. The right statement is that for countries open to international capital flows, softly pegged exchange rates are crisis-prone and not sustainable over long periods. However, a wide variety of flexible rate arrangements remains possible. Monetary and exchange rate policy in most countries should not and will not be indifferent to exchange rate movements.</description><author>Fischer, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An interview with William J. Baumol</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, A. B.
nan</description><author>Krueger, A. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional economics: Then and now</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rutherford, M.
This article gives a history of American institutionalism, and a brief comparison with the more recent "new" institutional economics. Institutionalism was a significant element in American economics between the Wars, but declined rapidly thereafter. The article outlines the movement's initial appeal, its contributions, and the reasons for its decline. Although the "new" institutionalism has few direct ties to the older tradition, some interesting commonalities are found and discussed. Links to the "new institutionalism" in sociology and political science, and to historical work on other "institutional" traditions are also mentioned.</description><author>Rutherford, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International productivity comparisons built from the firm level</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baily, M. N.; Solow, R. M.
International productivity comparisons can be built up with micro and macro data. Studies of firms or groups of firms producing similar outputs reveal the deeper causes of differences in productivity across countries. The studies find that such differences often depend on patterns of organization within firms, the motivations of managers and the like. The intensity of domestic and international competition can have a large impact on productivity. The case of retailing illustrates the importance of industry evolution. High productivity retailing formats drive out traditional retailers, unless restrained by land-use restrictions or regulations.</description><author>Baily, M. N.; Solow, R. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wheat from chaff: Meta-analysis as quantitative literature review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stanley, T. D.
This paper presents and develops a quantitative method of literature reviewing and evaluating empirical research, meta-regression analysis or MRA. Economics is theory-driven. Yet, we must learn empirically if economics is to advance. MRA offers a more objective statistical method to summarize our empirical knowledge and to explain the wide study-to-study variation in economic research. MRA is used to assess the evidence for Ricardian equivalence, and its findings are contrasted to those of conventional narrative review. Furthermore, MRA establishes a platform from which to distinguish genuine empirical effect from the exploitable specification error that infests applied econometrics.</description><author>Stanley, T. D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bridging the trade-environment divide</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Esty, D. C.
Perceived conflict between trade liberalization and environmental protection can be traced to a number of issues. Some tensions relate to the environmental Kuznets curve and whether economic growth yields environmental benefits. Other concerns arise from efforts to address transboundary externalities and disputes over the role of trade measures as an environmental enforcement tool. Another set of issues centers on the risk of a race-toward-the-bottom regulatory dynamic and the limits of legitimate comparative advantage. This paper argues that, in an ecologically and economically interdependent world, trade and environmental policies are inescapably linked as a matter of descriptive reality and normative necessity.</description><author>Esty, D. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor standards: Where do they belong on the international trade agenda?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, D. K.
During the past decade, universal labor standards have become the focus of intense debate. Advocates argue from humanitarian concerns and the interests of industrialized-country labor, seeking enforcement with WTO sanctions. Opponents regard labor regulation as a matter of national sovereignty, challenge the effectiveness of trade sanctions, and prefer the ILO emphasis on dialogue, monitoring and technical advice. This paper analyzes the labor standards debate, with specific attention to the analytical underpinnings of universal rules; evidence linking weak labor protections in developing countries to industrialized country wages; and the role of labor standards in WTO negotiations.</description><author>Brown, D. K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The WTO as a mechanism for securing market access property rights: Implications for global labor and environmental issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bagwell, K.; Staiger, R. W.
Can the World Trade Organization (WTO) contribute to the attainment of sound labor and environmental policies? An answer requires an understanding of WTO rules. We argue that the purpose of WTO rules is to create a negotiating forum where governments can exchange secure market access commitments. From this perspective, we argue that supporters of sound trade, labor and environmental policies can benefit from a well-functioning WTO, because facilitating trade liberalization and preventing race-to-the-bottom/regulatory-chill problems go hand in hand, and each is accomplished by maintaining secure property rights over negotiated market access commitments.</description><author>Bagwell, K.; Staiger, R. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The hyperbolic consumption model: Calibration, simulation, and empirical evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angeletos, G. M.; Laibson, D.; Repetto, A.; Tobacman, J.; Weinberg, S.
Laboratory and field studies of time preference find that discount rates are much greater in the short run than in the long run. Hyperbolic discount functions capture this property. This paper presents simulations of the savings and asset allocation choices of households with hyperbolic preferences. The behavior of the hyperbolic households is compared to the behavior of exponential households. The hyperbolic households borrow much more frequently in the revolving credit market. The hyperbolic households exhibit greater consumption income comovement and experience a greater drop in consumption around retirement. The hyperbolic simulations match observed consumption and balance sheet data much better than the exponential simulations.</description><author>Angeletos, G. M.; Laibson, D.; Repetto, A.; Tobacman, J.; Weinberg, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of the consumption function, with and without liquidity constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carroll, C. D.
This paper argues that the modern stochastic consumption model, in which impatient consumers face uninsurable labor income risk, matches Milton Friedman's (1957) original description of the Permanent Income Hypothesis much better than the perfect foresight or certainty equivalent models did. The model can explain the high marginal propensity to consume, the high discount rate on future income, and the important role for precautionary behavior that were all part of Friedman's original framework. The paper also explains the relationship of these questions to the Euler equation literature, and argues that the effects of precautionary saving and liquidity constraints are often virtually indistinguishable.</description><author>Carroll, C. D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The life-cycle model of consumption and saving</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Browning, M.; Crossley, T. F.
A central implication of life-cycle models is that agents smooth consumption. We review the empirical evidence on smoothing at frequencies from within the year up to across a lifetime. We find that life-cycle models-particular those which incorporate realistic features of markets and goods-have more empirical successes than failures. We also show that some apparent deviations from theoretical predictions imply very small welfare losses for agents. Finally, we emphasize that the coherence of life-cycle models imposes an important discipline when incorporating new features into models.</description><author>Browning, M.; Crossley, T. F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The record and prospects of the all-volunteer military in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Warner, J. T.; Asch, B. J.
From the onset of World War II until July 1973, the draft was a fact of life for male youth in the United States. Since then, America's armed forces have been staffed by volunteers. Recent recruiting difficulties have precipitated calls from some quarters for a return to conscription. This paper reviews the economic issues involved in the choice over conscription versus volunteerism and it reviews the volunteer force record in the U. S. Despite recent recruiting difficulties, the case for the volunteer force is more compelling today than it was in 1973.</description><author>Warner, J. T.; Asch, B. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic education in US high schools</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Walstad, W. B.
The teaching of economics at the high school level is vital for increasing basic economic literacy. This assessment of high school economics in the United States covers seven topics: enrollments in courses; course content; the testing of students; achievement in economics courses; economics instruction in related courses; teacher preparation for economics instruction; and the contributions from organizations and economists. Significant improvements are found in the teaching, content, and testing of high school economics over the past two decades, but more work is needed because a formal course in economics is taken by less than half of high school graduates.</description><author>Walstad, W. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>History lessons - The early development of intellectual property institutions in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khan, B. Z.; Sokoloff, K. L.
The U.S. was a pioneer in establishing the world's first modern intellectual property system. That system was distinguished by the provision of broad access to, and strict enforcement of, property rights in new inventions, coupled with the requirement of public disclosure, and it was effective at stimulating the growth of a market for technology and technical change more generally. Far from being static, fundamental modifications were introduced over time in response to changing circumstances. That such adjustments so often proved to be constructive owes partly to a private market being a central feature of the system, and partly to the democratic structure of U.S. institutions.</description><author>Khan, B. Z.; Sokoloff, K. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The production function and productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foley, D. K.; Michl, T. R.
nan</description><author>Foley, D. K.; Michl, T. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The production function and productivity - Response from Stephen E. Oliner and Daniel E. Sichel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oliner, S. D.; Sichel, D. E.
nan</description><author>Oliner, S. D.; Sichel, D. E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sociology and social interactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mote, J. E.
nan</description><author>Mote, J. E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The production function and productivity - Response from Robert J. Gordon</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gordon, R. J.
nan</description><author>Gordon, R. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The venture capital revolution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gompers, P.; Lerner, J.
Venture capital has emerged as an important intermediary in financial markets, providing capital to young high-technology firms that might have otherwise gone unfunded. Venture capitalists have developed a variety of mechanisms to overcome the problems that emerge at each stage of the investment process. At the same time, the venture capital process is also subject to various pathologies from time to time, which can create problems for investors or entrepreneurs. This article reviews the recent empirical literature on these organizations and points out area where further research is needed.</description><author>Gompers, P.; Lerner, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tobacco at the crossroads: The past and future of smoking regulation in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gruber, J.
The past five years have seen a dramatic turn of events against the tobacco industry, raising the question of the appropriate future path for smoking policy in the U.S. This paper discusses the theory and evidence on regulation of smoking. I begin by reviewing the background on this industry. I then turn to a discussion of the motivations for regulating smoking, both external and internal to the smoker. I review the evidence on the effects of existing regulations. And I conclude with a discussion of future policy directions.</description><author>Gruber, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early childhood education programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Currie, J.
This paper discusses early childhood education programs: their goals; effectiveness; optimal timing, targeting, and content; and costs and benefits. Early intervention has significant short- and medium-term benefits: most notably it reduces grade repetition and special education costs, and provides quality child care. The effects are greatest for more disadvantaged children. Some model programs have produced exciting improvements in educational attainment and earnings and have reduced welfare dependency and crime. The jury is still out on the long-term effects of Head Start, but Head Start would pay for itself if it produced a quarter of the long-term gains of model programs.</description><author>Currie, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A public choice explanation for the budget surplus - Response from Alberto Alesina</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alesina, A.
nan</description><author>Alesina, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Data watch - The national longitudinal surveys</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pergamit, M. R.; Pierret, C. R.; Rothstein, D. S.; Veum, J. R.
This article describes the design features and topical coverage of the National Longitudinal Surveys (NLS). The NLS are perhaps the oldest and most widely used panel surveys of individuals in the United States. These surveys were started in the mid-1960s to exam employment issues faced by different cohorts of the U.S. population. Since then, the NLS surveys have expanded to include two new cohorts of youth. Survey topic areas include employment, education, training, family relationships, financial well-being, and health. Information on data access is also provided.</description><author>Pergamit, M. R.; Pierret, C. R.; Rothstein, D. S.; Veum, J. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economics and electronic commerce</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borenstein, S.; Saloner, G.
nan</description><author>Borenstein, S.; Saloner, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The implications of electronic commerce for fiscal policy (and vice versa)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goolsbee, A.
nan</description><author>Goolsbee, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wiring the labor market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Autor, D. H.
Workers and jobs are naturally heterogeneous and the quality of their interaction when paired is difficult to forecast. The Internet promises to open new channels for worker-firm communications. What are the consequences of this opening? I discuss three labor market features that may be altered: how worker-firm matches are made; how labor services are delivered; and how local markets shape labor demand. Theory predicts these developments will produce social benefits. But the gains are unlikely to be uniform and realizing them will generate novel problems. One result may be the formation of new institutions to address issues accompanying these opportunities.</description><author>Autor, D. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Internet and the investor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, B. M.; Odean, T.
nan</description><author>Barber, B. M.; Odean, T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business-to-business electronic commerce</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucking-Reiley, D.; Spulber, D. F.
Just as the industrial revolution mechanized the manufacturing functions of firms, the information revolution is automating their merchant functions. Four types of potential productivity gains are expected from business-to-business (B2B) electronic commerce: cost efficiencies from automation of transactions, potential advantages of new market intermediaries, consolidation of demand and supply through organized exchanges, and changes in the extent of vertical integration of firms. The article examines the characteristics of B2B online intermediaries, including categories of goods traded, market mechanisms employed, and ownership arrangements, and considers the market structure of B2B e-commerce.</description><author>Lucking-Reiley, D.; Spulber, D. F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The emerging landscape for retail E-commerce</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakos, Y.
nan</description><author>Bakos, Y.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A symposium on the North American economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Long, J. B.
nan</description><author>De Long, J. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Life is not easy: Mexico's quest for stability and growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lustig, N.
In the wake of the debt crisis in 1982, Mexico adopted far reaching reforms but growth and stability remained elusive for many years. At present, the reforms and NAFTA seem to be finally paying off: inflation for 2000 is close to 10 percent and output per capita grew at an average of 5.4 percent during the last five years. However, altogether output per capita was only 9 percent higher in 1999 than in 1980, a great disappointment for particularly the 20 million Mexicans that live on less than $ 2 a day.</description><author>Lustig, N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Canada: Life beyond the looking glass</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helliwell, J. F.
Canada's population, a tenth that of the United States, is perched close to the U.S. northern border, tightly but asymmetrically tied to U.S. information networks. However, trade, capital and population mobility remains an order of magnitude tighter among provinces than between provinces and states. This separating effect of the national border is not primarily due to barriers, but to networks of contacts, trust and institutions that make it efficient to concentrate economic activity within national borders. This separation combines with quite different histories to explain why Canadian economic, social, education and health care policies remain distinct from U.S. policies, often closer to those in Northern Europe.</description><author>Helliwell, J. F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of NAFTA on the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burfisher, M. E.; Robinson, S.; Thierfelder, K.
We describe the main economic arguments posed for and against the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) during the U.S. policy debate. To evaluate these arguments, we analyze recent trade data and survey post-NAFTA studies. We find that both the U.S. and Mexico benefit from NAFTA, with much larger relative benefits for Mexico. NAFTA also has had little effect on the U.S. labor market. These results confirm the consensus opinion of economists at the time of the debate. Finally, studies find that trade creation greatly exceeds trade diversion in the region under NAFTA, especially in intermediate goods.</description><author>Burfisher, M. E.; Robinson, S.; Thierfelder, K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No history of ideas, please, we're economists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blaug, M.
nan</description><author>Blaug, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insiders versus outsiders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lindbeck, A.; Snower, D. J.
nan</description><author>Lindbeck, A.; Snower, D. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In honor of Andrei Shleifer: Winner of the John Bates Clark medal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blanchard, O.
nan</description><author>Blanchard, O.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - Death watch for the estate tax?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gale, W. G.; Slemrod, J. B.
nan</description><author>Gale, W. G.; Slemrod, J. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anomalies - Risk aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rabin, M.; Thaler, R. H.
Economists ubiquitously employ a simple and elegant explanation for risk aversion: It derives from the concavity of the utility-of-wealth function within the expected-utility framework. We show that this explanation is not plausible in most applications, since anything more than economically negligible risk aversion over moderate stakes requires a utility-of-wealth function that is so concave that it predicts absurdly severe risk aversion over very large stakes. We present examples of how the expected-utility framework has misled economists, and why we believe a better explanation for risk aversion must incorporate loss aversion and mental accounting.</description><author>Rabin, M.; Thaler, R. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recommendations for further reading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saffran, B.
nan</description><author>Saffran, B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Symposium on econometric tools</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, A. B.
nan</description><author>Krueger, A. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonparametric density and regression estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DiNardo, J.; Tobias, J. L.
We provide a nontechnical review of recent nonparametric methods for estimating density and regression functions. The methods we describe make it possible for a researcher to estimate a regression function or density without having to specify in advance a particular-and hence potentially misspecified functional form. We compare these methods to more popular parametric alternatives (such as OLS), illustrate their use in several applications, and demonstrate their flexibility with actual data and generated-data experiments. We show that these methods are intuitive and easily implemented, and in the appropriate context may provide an attractive alternative to "simpler" parametric methods.</description><author>DiNardo, J.; Tobias, J. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Semiparametric censored regression models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chay, K. Y.; Powell, J. L.
When data are censored, ordinary least squares regression can provide biased coefficient estimates. Maximum likelihood approaches to this problem are valid only if the error distribution is correctly specified, which can be problematic in practice. We review several semiparametric estimators for the censored regression model that do not require parameterization of the error distribution. These estimators are used to examine changes in black-white earnings inequality during the 1960s based on censored tax records. The results show that there was significant earnings convergence among black and white men in the American South after the passage of the 1964 Civil Rights Act.</description><author>Chay, K. Y.; Powell, J. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Binary response models: Logits, probits and semiparametrics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horowitz, J. L.; Savin, N. E.
A binary-response model is a mean-regression model in which the dependent variable takes only the values zero and one. This paper describes and illustrates the estimation of logit and probit binary-response models. The linear probability model is also discussed. Reasons for not using this model in applied research are explained and illustrated with data. Semiparametric and nonparametric models are also described. In contrast to logit and probit models, semi- and nonparametric models avoid the restrictive and unrealistic assumption that the analyst knows the functional form of the relation between the dependent variable and the explanatory variables.</description><author>Horowitz, J. L.; Savin, N. E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mismeasured variables in econometric analysis: Problems from the right and problems from the left</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hausman, J.
The effect of mismeasured variables in the most straightforward regression analysis with a single regressor variable leads to a least squares estimate that is downward biased in magnitude toward zero. I begin by reviewing classical issues involving mismeasured variables. I then consider three recent developments for mismeasurement econometric models. The first issue involves difficulties in using instrumental variables. A second involves the consistent estimators that have recently been developed for mismeasured nonlinear regression models. Finally, I return to mismeasured left hand side variables, where I will focus on issues in binary choice models and duration models.</description><author>Hausman, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Instrumental variables and the search for identification: From supply and demand to natural experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angrist, J. D.; Krueger, A. B.
Instrumental variables was first used in the 1920s to estimate supply and demand elasticities and later to correct for measurement error in single equation models. Recently, instrumental variables have been widely used to reduce bias from omitted variables in estimates of causal relationships. Intuitively, instrumental variables methods use only a portion of the variability in key variables to estimate the relationships of interest; if the instruments are valid, that portion is unrelated to the omitted variables. We discuss the mechanics of instrumental variables and the qualities that make for a good instrument, devoting particular attention to instruments derived from "natural experiments."</description><author>Angrist, J. D.; Krueger, A. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Applications of generalized method of moments estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wooldridge, J. M.
I describe how the method of moments approach to estimation, including the more recent generalized method of moments (GMM) theory, can be applied to problems using cross section, time series, and panel data. Method of moments estimators can be attractive because in many circumstances they are robust to failures of auxiliary distributional assumptions that are not needed to identify key parameters. I conclude that while sophisticated GMM estimators are indispensable for complicated estimation problems, it seems unlikely that GMM will provide convincing improvements over ordinary least squares and two-stage least squares-by far the most common method of moments estimators used in econometrics-in settings faced most often by empirical researchers.</description><author>Wooldridge, J. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vector autoregressions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stock, J. H.; Watson, M. W.
This paper critically reviews the use of vector autoregressions (VARs) for four tasks: data description, forecasting, structural inference, and policy analysis. The paper begins with a review of VAR analysis, highlighting the differences between reduced-form VARs, recursive VARs and structural VARs. A three variable VAR that includes the unemployment rate, price inflation and the short term interest rate is used to show how VAR methods are used for the four tasks. The paper concludes that VARs have proven to be powerful and reliable tools for data description and forecasting, but have been less useful for structural inference and policy analysis.</description><author>Stock, J. H.; Watson, M. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The new econometrics of structural change: Dating breaks in US labor productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hansen, B. E.
We have seen the emergence of three major innovations in the econometrics of structural change in the past fifteen years: (1) tests for a structural break of unknown timing; (2) estimation of the timing of a structural break; and (3) tests to distinguish unit roots from broken time trends. These three innovations have dramatically altered the face of applied time series econometrics. In this paper, we review these three innovations, and illustrate their application through an empirical assessment of U.S. labor productivity in the manufacturing/durables sector.</description><author>Hansen, B. E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The bootstrain and multiple imputations: Harnessing increased computing power for improved statistical tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brownstone, D.; Valletta, R.
The bootstrap and multiple imputations are two techniques that can enhance the accuracy of estimated confidence bands and critical values. Although they are computationally intensive, relying on repeated sampling from empirical data sets and associated estimates, modern computing power enables their application in a wide and growing number of econometric settings. We provide an intuitive overview of how to apply these techniques, referring to existing theoretical literature and various applied examples to illustrate both their possibilities and their pitfalls.</description><author>Brownstone, D.; Valletta, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantile regression</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koenker, R.; Hallock, K. F.
Quantile regression, as introduced by Koenker and Bassett (1978), may be viewed as an extension of classical least squares estimation of conditional mean models to the estimation of an ensemble of models for several conditional quantile functions. The central special case is the median regression estimator which minimizes a sum of absolute errors. Other conditional quantile functions are estimated by minimizing an asymmetrically weighted sum of absolute errors. Quantile regression methods are illustrated with applications to models for CEO pay, food expenditure, and infant birthweight.</description><author>Koenker, R.; Hallock, K. F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>GARCH 101: The use of ARCH/GARCH models in applied econometrics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engle, R.
ARCH and GARCH models have become important tools in the analysis of time series data, particularly in financial applications. These models are especially useful when the goal of the study is to analyze and forecast volatility. This paper gives the motivation behind the simplest GARCH model and illustrates its usefulness in examining portfolio risk. Extensions are briefly discussed.</description><author>Engle, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Teaching statistics and econometrics to undergraduates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, W. E.; Greene, W. H.
Traditionally econometrics and economics statistics have been taught in the theory and proof, chalk and talk mode commonly found in the teaching of mathematics. We advance the use of computer technology in the teaching of quantitative methods to get students actively engaged in the learning process. We also assert that the essential tasks for those who teach these courses are to identify important issues that lend themselves to quantitative analyses and then to help students develop an understanding of the appropriate key concepts for those analyses.</description><author>Becker, W. E.; Greene, W. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Free labor for costly journals?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergstrom, T. C.
nan</description><author>Bergstrom, T. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retrospectives - Cost-benefit analysis and the classical creed</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Persky, J.
nan</description><author>Persky, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revolutions in economic thought</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>King, J. E.
nan</description><author>King, J. E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revolutions in economic thought - Response from Mark Blaug</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blaug, M.
nan</description><author>Blaug, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revolutions in economic thought</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rothschild, K. W.
nan</description><author>Rothschild, K. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A public choice explanation for the budget surplus</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sobel, R. S.
nan</description><author>Sobel, R. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reassessing discretionary fiscal policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, J. B.
Recent changes in policy research and in policy-making call for a reassessment of countercyclical fiscal policy. Such a reassessment indicates that countercyclical fiscal policy should focus on automatic stabilizers rather than discretionary actions. Monetary policy has been reacting more systematically to output and inflation; long expansions in the 1980s and 1990s demonstrate policy effectiveness. It is unlikely that discretionary countercyclical fiscal policy could improve things, even with less uncertainty about fiscal impacts. A discretionary countercyclical fiscal policy could make monetary policy making more difficult. Discretionary fiscal policy should focus on long-run issues, such as tax reform and social security reform.</description><author>Taylor, J. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The political economy of the budget surplus in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alesina, A.
Current surpluses in the U.S. have been achieved by a combination of a strong economy, low interest rates, and sharp cuts in defense spending. These surpluses follow a period (the 1980s) of rather exceptional budget deficit. This paper investigates the origin, size, and expected future patterns of the U.S. budget balance. It discusses how different political forces may generate alternative fiscal scenarios for the U.S. in the next decade.</description><author>Alesina, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The significance of federal taxes as automatic stabilizers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Auerbach, A. J.; Feenberg, D.
Using the TAXSIM model for the period 1962-95, we consider the federal tax system's impact as an automatic stabilizer. Despite the many changes in the tax system, there has been relatively little change in its role as an automatic stabilizer. We estimate that individual federal taxes offset perhaps as much as 8 percent of initial shocks to GDP. We also suggest that the progressive income tax may help to stabilize output via its effect on the supply of labor, an additional effect that may even be of similar magnitude to the more traditional path of stabilization through aggregate demand.</description><author>Auerbach, A. J.; Feenberg, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should America save for its old age? Fiscal policy, population aging, and national saving</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elmendorf, D. W.; Sheiner, L. M.
We examine whether the aging of the U.S. population adds force to traditional arguments for boosting national saving and conclude--perhaps surprisingly--that it may not. Aging boosts the demands on future resources, but it also changes the rate of return the U.S. economy can expect from saving. We find that the net effect on desired saving is small: some specifications imply that present consumption should fall by a fraction of 1 percent; others imply that consumption should actually increase. Thus, it is optimal to allow future cohorts to bear much/all of the burden of population aging.</description><author>Elmendorf, D. W.; Sheiner, L. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The sports business as a labor market laboratory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahn, L. M.
With superior data on compensation and productivity, as well as the occurrence of abrupt, dramatic market structure and player allocation rules changes, sports labor markets offer an excellent setting in which to test economic hypotheses. This paper reviews evidence from sports in four areas: employer monopsony, discrimination, the Coase Theorem, and incentive contracts, supervision and performance. There is considerable evidence of monopsony as well as for the existence of some forms of discrimination against minority athletes. Incentive contracts have strong effects on player performance and behavior, and there is mixed evidence on the predictions of the Coase Theorem.</description><author>Kahn, L. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of sports facilities and their communities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siegfried, J.; Zimbalist, A.
Since the 1950s, taxpayers have been the primary investors in stadia built for the use of privately-owned professional sports teams. Team owners have argued that sports facilities boost local economic activity; however, economic reasoning and empirical evidence suggest the opposite. Public support for stadia is also driven by demand for community image, and owners of sports teams supply a scarce input into image enhancement--participation in the major league--for which they have been able to extract monopoly rents from dispersed taxpayers. We suggest reforms to dissipate the monopoly sports leagues exercise when negotiating with host communities for their teams.</description><author>Siegfried, J.; Zimbalist, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic analysis of social interactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manski, C. F.
Economics is broadening its scope from analysis of markets to study of general social interactions. Developments in game theory, the economics of the family, and endogenous growth theory have led the way. Economists have also performed new empirical research using observational data on social interactions, but with much less to show. The fundamental problem is that observable outcomes may be generated by many different interaction processes, so empirical findings are open to a wide variety of interpretations. To make sustained progress, empirical research will need richer data, including experiments in controlled environments and subjective data on preferences and expectations.</description><author>Manski, C. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collective action and the evolution of social norms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ostrom, E.
I assume multiple types of players--"rational egoists," as well as "conditional cooperators" and "willing punishers"--in models of nonmarket behavior. I use an indirect evolutionary approach to explain how multiple types of players could survive and flourish in social dilemma situations. Contextual variables that enhance knowledge about past behavior assist in explaining the origin of collective action. Among the important contextual variables are types of goods, types of groups, and rules that groups use to provide and allocate goods. Finally, I reexamine a series of design principles that were derived earlier from an examination of extensive case materials.</description><author>Ostrom, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fairness and retaliation: The economics of reciprocity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fehr, E.; Gachter, S.
This paper shows that reciprocity has powerful implications for many economic domains. It is an important determinant in the enforcement of contracts and social norms and enhances the possibilities of collective action greatly. Reciprocity may render the provision of explicit incentive inefficient because the incentives may crowd out voluntary co-operation. It strongly limits the effects of competition in markets with incomplete contracts and gives rise to noncompetitive wage differences. Finally, reciprocity it is also a strong force contributing to the existence of incomplete contracts.</description><author>Fehr, E.; Gachter, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vickrey auctions in practice: From nineteenth-century philately to twenty-first-century e-commerce</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucking-Reiley, D.
William Vickrey (1961) proposed an auction mechanism in which bidders submit sealed bids, and the highest bidder wins the good in return for payment of the second-highest bid amount. For decades, economists have credited Vickrey with inventing this auction format, and have believed that the Vickrey auction is rarely used in practice. This paper presents evidence that Vickrey auctions have long been the predominant auction format for mail sales of collectible postage stamps. Stamp auctioneers developed this auction format on their own, as early as 1893, even before Vickrey was born.</description><author>Lucking-Reiley, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In honor of Kevin M. Murphy: Winner of the John Bates Clark Medal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Welch, F.
Kevin M. Murphy is the winner of the 1998 John Bates Clark Medal, presented by the American Economic Association every second year to an outstanding economist under the age of forty who is selected for special recognition. He is the George Pratt Schultz Professor of Business Economics and Industrial Relations in the University of Chicago's Graduate School of Business and is the model of an applied economist. I will survey a selection of his papers, highlighting his accomplisments in three principle areas-income inequality, unemployment, and economic growth-and considering a representative smattering of other topics.</description><author>Welch, F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - The tyranny of budget forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foster, J. D.; Miller, J. C.
The evolving federal budget process has placed increasing demands on, and given unique powers to, the economic forecasters at OMB, Treasury, CBO, and the Joint Tax Committee of Congress. On the whole, the forecasters have been highly professional in their work, but differences in estimating techniques and, especially, constraints imposed on their analysis by elected officials have limited their credibility. Both the Administration and Congress "game" the system and even ignore the budget rules when convenient. Thus, a sophisticated budget process can help, but cannot assure, sound fiscal policy in the absence of political will to make hard decisions.</description><author>Foster, J. D.; Miller, J. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>History lessons - Institutions, factor endowments, and paths of development in the new world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sokoloff, K. L.; Engerman, S. L.
The explanations offered for the contrasting records of long-run growth and development among the societies of North and South America most often focus on institutions. The traditional explanations for the sources of these differences in institutions, typically highlight the significance of national heritage or religion. We, in contrast, argue that a hemispheric perspective across the wide range of colonies established in the New World by the Europeans suggests that although there were many influences, factor endowments or initial conditions had profound and enduring effects on the long-run paths of institutional and economic development followed by the respective economies.</description><author>Sokoloff, K. L.; Engerman, S. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance and growth in sub-Saharan Africa (vol 14, pg 241, 2000)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ndulu, B. J.; O'Connell, S. A.
nan</description><author>Ndulu, B. J.; O'Connell, S. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making the transition to prepaid Medicare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saving, T. R.
The Medicare system is facing a financial crisis brought on by the combination of rapidly rising consumption of health care services by beneficiaries and financing based on generation transfers. This paper simulates a transition to prepaid Medicare where each generation puts aside funds for the health care it will demand later in life. By prepaying Medicare we increase the nation's capital stock which in the long run will allow the nation to enjoy greater consumption for both working and retired generations and we achieve immunity from generation size shocks. By transferring the baby boomers and younger generations into a prepaid system we can complete the transition in less than fifty years and achieve an ultimate contribution rate of 1.26% of taxable payroll instead of the more than 12% of taxable payroll that will be required if we remain in the status quo.</description><author>Saving, T. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy watch - The repeal of glass-steagall and the advent of broad banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barth, J. R.; Brumbaugh, R. D.; Wilcox, J. A.
Enactment of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA) in November 1999 effectively repealed the long-standing prohibitions on the mixing of banking with securities or insurance businesses and thus permits "broad banking." We attribute repeal of these prohibitions to the increasingly persuasive evidence from academic studies of the pre-Glass-Steagall era, the recent favorable experience in the United States following partial deregulation of banking activities, the experience of banking systems abroad with broader scopes for banking activities, and rapid technological change in telecommunications and data processing. How regulators will in practice coordinate their efforts so that the safety and soundness of the banking system is maintained efficiently remains to be seen.</description><author>Barth, J. R.; Brumbaugh, R. D.; Wilcox, J. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An interview with Zvi Griliches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, A. B.; Taylor, T.
Alan Krueger and Timothy Taylor interviewed Zvi Griliches, Paul M. Warburg Professor of Economics at Harvard University, at his home near the Harvard campus on June 21, 1999. The interview touches on his harrowing journey from Lithuania to Chicago; years at the University of Chicago; the move to Harvard University; work on diffusion and technology and on returns to education; thoughts on the data infrastructure; government service and economic research; and hobbies.</description><author>Krueger, A. B.; Taylor, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Keynesian macroeconomics without the LM curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Romer, D.
Changes in both the macroeconomy and in macroeconomics suggest that the IS-LM-AS model is no longer the best baseline model of short-run fluctuations for teaching and policy analysis. This paper presents an alternative model that replaces the assumption that the central bank targets the money supply with an assumption that it follows a simple interest rate rule. The resulting model is simpler, more realistic, and more coherent than IS-LM-AS, not just in its treatment of monetary policy but in many other ways. The paper also discusses other alternatives to IS-LM-AS.</description><author>Romer, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minority groups in the economics profession</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collins, S. M.
The primary objective of this paper is to provide information about minorities (blacks, Hispanics and Native Americans)in economics, at various stages in the education pipeline, and in the labor market. Despite sustained increases in the numbers and percentages of minorities earning bachelors degrees and Ph.D.s, the absolute numbers remain very small--only about 36 new Ph.D.s per year, including permanent residents. Minority economists are relatively underrepresented on four-year college faculties and in government employment. The paper also discusses activities by the AEA's committee on minority groups, aimed at increasing minority representation in the profession.</description><author>Collins, S. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economics in the cyberclassroom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Navarro, P.
The coming of the cyberclassroom may change almost everything we do in teaching economics. This article discusses the size and scope of the cybereconomics market; the range and mix of instructional technologies; course design, development, and content; cyberinfrastructure and technical support; student characteristics, performance, and access; and labor issues. Some key findings include: the cybereconomics market is small but rapidly growing. Technical problems are common but can be minimized. It takes instructors significantly more time both to develop and teach a typical cybereconomics courses. Institutions, rather than instructors, are capturing a lion's share of the intellectual property rights.</description><author>Navarro, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market wealth and consumption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poterba, J. M.
This paper explores the link between changes in the aggregate value of corporate stock and changes in consumer spending. It presents data on the distribution of corporate stock ownership based on the 1998 Survey of Consumer Finances. It also uses time-series evidence on the comovement of stock market wealth and various categories of consumer spending to calibrate "the wealth effect." It concludes that in the year after a change in stock market values, consumer spending is likely to rise by between one and two cents for each dollar increase in the value of corporate stock.</description><author>Poterba, J. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Health care for the aging baby boom: Lessons from abroad</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reinhardt, U. E.
The economic, social, and political challenges posed by the aging of the population are real in many nations, under virtually any set of assumptions about the future. However, cross-national data on health spending on the elderly, to be presented in the following section, suggest that in health care this challenge appears to be manageable, as long as the nation's health system is being managed smartly. Unfortunately, Americans tend to be unimpressed by cross-national comparisons of health systems, apparently on the axiom that American health care is so vastly superior to that anywhere else on the globe as to render any cross-national comparison irrelevant for American health policy. In deference to that sentiment, the cross-national data presented here are supplemented with data on intra-U.S. variation in health spending on the elderly. Jointly, these cross-national and intranational data suggest that, in the United States, the economic burden of providing health care for the aging baby boom generation is amplified by a poorly managed and needlessly expensive health system.</description><author>Reinhardt, U. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Walking the tightrope on Medicare reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cutler, D. M.
A central controversy in the debate about Medicare is whether the program spends too much money or whether instead it should be expanded to cover more. I consider the value of increased Medicare spending. I argue that on average Medicare spending is worth it: the health gains brought by medicare have been greater than their cost. At the margin, however, services are overused and have low value. Medicare reforms need to promote the high average value of care while eliminating care of low value. Many of the proposed reforms fall short of this goal.</description><author>Cutler, D. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Medicare reform: Fundamental problems, incremental steps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McClellan, M.
This paper presents an overview of the Medicare reform debate. I begin by reviewing some of the features of Medicare and then turn to a discussion of reforms, both on the benefits side and on the financing side of the program. The reform proposals raise difficult policy and political issues, and could have important implications for the federal budget, the efficiency of the health sector, and the well-being of the elderly and disabled.</description><author>McClellan, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distinguished lecture on economics in government - Fighting poverty: Lessons from recent US history</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blank, R. M.
Welfare reform efforts in the 1990s aimed at reducing welfare dependence and moving women into work. Public assistance use fell and labor force participation among mothers rose at a stunning rate over the decade. Poverty declined, but at a slower rate. These changes are causally related to the strong macroeconomy, welfare reform efforts, and other policy changes, especially the EITC and minimum wage expansions. This paper concludes that all of these effects reinforced each other, producing very large behavioral changes. It is too early to predict the effects of these changes on long-term family well-being.</description><author>Blank, R. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Classroom games - Making money</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Laury, S. K.; Holt, C. A.
Economics is often taught at a level of abstraction that can hinder some students from gaining basic intuition. However, lecture and textbook presentations can be complemented with classroom exercises in which students make decisions and interact. The approach can increase interest in and decrease skepticism about economic theory. This feature offers short descriptions of classroom exercises for a variety of economics courses, with something of an emphasis on the more popular undergraduate courses.</description><author>Laury, S. K.; Holt, C. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Data watch - The US national income and product accounts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Popkin, J.
GDP is arguably the most widely used economic statistic. It is part of the National Income and Product Accounts (NIPAs). The concepts, methods and source data for the NIPAs are described in this article. It contains citations to more detailed information obtainable from the publications and web sites of the U.S. Bureau of Economic Analysis, the agency responsible for the NIPAs. A brief history describes the evolution of the accounts. It explains the growing congruence between the U.S. accounts and the UN's System of National Accounts (SNA). The integration of financial and satellite accounts into the NIPAs is summarized.</description><author>Popkin, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recommendations for further reading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saffran, B.
nan</description><author>Saffran, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>GM and Fisher Body</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brooks, R.; Helper, S.
nan</description><author>Brooks, R.; Helper, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>GM and Fisher Body - Response from Patrick Bolton and David S. Scharfstein</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, P.; Scharfstein, D. S.
nan</description><author>Bolton, P.; Scharfstein, D. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Slow growth in Africa</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamarck, A. M.
nan</description><author>Kamarck, A. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discounting in policy analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Orszag, P. R.
nan</description><author>Orszag, P. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discounting in policy analysis - Response from Coleman Bazelon and Kent Smetters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bazelon, C.; Smetters, K.
nan</description><author>Bazelon, C.; Smetters, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What the change of system from socialism to capitalism does and does not mean</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kornai, J.
nan</description><author>Kornai, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New millennium economics: How did it get this way, and what way is it?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colander, D.
This paper is a discussion of the changes in the economics profession that occurred (or at least are suggested will occur) between 2000 and 2050. Structural changes include the growth of virtual universities, the movement of the center of economics out of the U.S. and the shrinking of traditional graduate economics programs as we know them today, and their replacement by public policy and specialty programs. Changes in content include an increase in simulation work, experimental work, and the replacement of a neoclassical vision with a New Millennium vision based on a complexity foundation in which patterns develop spontaneously.</description><author>Colander, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Teaching economics in the 21st century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, W. E.
The desire to reverse a downward trend in the number of undergraduates majoring in economics is an impetus to advance the scholarship of teaching economics as we enter the 21st century. This article offers suggestions for changing the concepts taught and the applications used in college and university economics courses within the United States. It provides practical methods to improve the way economics is taught. The assessment of students and the evaluation of pedagogical practices are also addressed.</description><author>Becker, W. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The neoclassical advent: American economics at the dawn of the 20th century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Persky, J.
For the U.S. economy, the last quarter of the 19th century brought the closing of the Western frontier, agricultural hardship in the South, the rise of large corporations and trusts, and the emergence of a serious labor movement. The fledgling American economics profession struggled to document and prescribe for the confounding mix of industrialization, urbanization, and rural crisis. In 1900, the relatively small community of serious economic researchers focused on applied issues in public policy and industrial organization. The prominent institutionalist school, strongly influenced by the almost millennial theories of the social gospel movement, emphasized the inequities of the emerging economy and looked forward to a new, more cooperative system of production. On the eve of the 20th century, John Bates Clark published in 1899 The Distribution of Wealth: A Theory of Wages, Interest and Profit. With this volume, neoclassicism matured into a major intellectual force within American economic thought, with Clark as its defining figure. Clark's analytical approach and his normative purposes hardly went unchallenged. Moreover, the great majority of economists in the United States continued to work in the institutionalist vein up to World War II. Nevertheless, by viewing the American neoclassical advent in the context of its own time, we can gain a deeper understanding of both American economics at the turn of the 20th century and the early character of the school that came to dominate our discipline.</description><author>Persky, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The triumph of monetarism?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Long, J. B.
The story of 20th century macroeconomics begins with Irving Fisher. In his books Appreciation and Interest (1896), The Rate of Interest (1907), and The Purchasing Power of Money (1911), Fisher fueled the intellectual fire that became known as monetarism. But what has happened to monetarism at the end of the 20th century? The short answer is that much of this current of thought is still there, but its insights pass under another name. We may not all be Keynesians now, but the influence of monetarism on how we all think about macroeconomics today has been deep, pervasive, and subtle. Why then do we today talk much more about the "New Keynesian" economists than about the "New Monetarist" economists? I believe that to answer this question we need to look at the history of monetarism over the 20th century. One fruitful way to look at the history of monetarism is to distinguish between four different variants or subspecies of monetarism that emerged and for a time flourished in the century just past: First Monetarism, Old Chicago Monetarism, High Monetarism, and Political Monetarism.</description><author>De Long, J. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>American government finance in the long run: 1790 to 1990</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wallis, J. J.
Government in America has gone through three distinct fiscal systems in the last two hundred years. Each system utilized a dominant revenue source, and had a distinctly active level of government. The changing structure of government by level seems to be related to changing revenue structures. When new taxes become important, the relative importance of each level of government changes. On the other hand, growth in the overall size of government is not directly related to the structure of revenues or the distribution of activity by level of government. Government growth is the result of long term commitments to provide education, transportation, social welfare services, old age security, and military forces.</description><author>Wallis, J. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Antitrust policy: A century of economic and legal thinking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kovacic, W. E.; Shapiro, C.
This article follows the evolution of thinking about competition since the passage of the Sherman Act in 1890 as reflected by major antitrust decisions and research in industrial organization. We divide the U.S. antitrust experience into five periods and discuss each period's legal trends and economic thinking in three core areas of antitrust: cartels, cooperation, or other interactions among independent firms; abusive conduct by dominant firms; and mergers.</description><author>Kovacic, W. E.; Shapiro, C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The worldwide standard of living since 1800</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easterlin, R. A.
By many measures a revolution in living conditions is sweeping the world. Most people today are better fed, clothed, and house than their predecessors two centuries ago. They are healthier, live longer, and are better educated. Women's lives are less centered on reproduction, and political democracy has gained a foothold. Current international differences in a number of standard of living indicators are significantly correlated. Historically, however, these improvements often started at quite different times, suggesting that the determinants of change in different aspects of the standard of living are varied.</description><author>Easterlin, R. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reflections on economics at the turn of the millennium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, A. B.; De Long, J. B.; Taylor, T.
To commemorate the new millennium and 50 issues of JEP, we have commissioned a series of essays in three broad areas. The first set of papers in this issue look back at key developments in the economy and economic thinking. In a second group of articles, we asked for predictions about the future of the subject of economics. Finally, in a third group of articles, we encouraged authors to make predictions about future developments in the economy.</description><author>Krueger, A. B.; De Long, J. B.; Taylor, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From homo economicus to homo sapiens</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thaler, R. H.
In responding to a request for predictions about the future of economics, I predict that Homo Economicus will evolve into Homo Sapiens, or, more simply put, economics will become more related to human behavior. My specific predictions are that Homo Economicus will start to lose IQ, will become a slower learner, will start interacting with other species, and that economists will start to study human cognition, human emotion, and will distinguish more clearly between normative and descriptive theories.</description><author>Thaler, R. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The future of microeconomic theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, B.
The question of what constitutes good economic theory is analyzed. Current good and bad aspects of its methodologies are discussed. Interdisciplinary work that goes beyond the social sciences is advocated. The future predictions are presented concerning research in game theory and the economics of information. Finally, the importance of technology and the need for microeconomists to understand it better are argued.</description><author>Allen, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toward a macroeconomics of the medium run</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Solow, R. M.
My main goal in this essay is to say something about leftover open questions in macroeconomics, as well as new phenomena that need to be accommodated in early 21st century macroeconomics, and the sorts of ideas that might make progress possible. The essay first considers foundational questions and then the analysis of growth, fluctuations, wages and prices, and the medium run.</description><author>Solow, R. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Some macroeconomics for the 21st century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucas, R. E.
This note describes a numerical simulation of a model of economic growth, a simplified version of Robert Tamura's (1996) model of world income dynamics, based on technology diffusion. The model makes predictions for trends in average world income growth and about the evolution of the relative income distribution that accord well with observation. The model is used to forecast the course of world income growth and income inequality over the century to come.</description><author>Lucas, R. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can America stay on top?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krugman, P.
The United States has long enjoyed a unique position of economic supremacy. By the early 1990s, however, almost everyone believed that the age of U.S. supremacy was nearing its end. Circa 1992 few people would have dared to suggest that a second "American Century" might be in prospect. At the millennium, however, such suggestions are indeed being made. Several years of extremely favorable U.S. economic performance, all the more dramatic in contrast to some of the crises and setbacks elsewhere, have made it seem possible that American supremacy, far from being further eroded, will return to something like its early post-World War II levels. But can America really stay on top? To raise this question is not in any sense to accept the idea that the world economy is a zero-sum game; if America does well, this is not bad news for the rest of the world, nor is a renewed supremacy based on dismal performance elsewhere good for us. But it is still interesting to ask whether the special position of the United States in the world economy has gained a new lease on life.</description><author>Krugman, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How far will international economic integration go?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rodrik, D.
This article speculates about the future of the world economy 100 years from now. It argues that the spread of markets is restricted by the reach of jurisdictional boundaries, and that national sovereignty imposes serious constraints on international economic integration. The political trilemma of the world economy is that international economic integration, the nation-state, and mass politics cannot co-exist. We have to pick two out of three. The article predicts that it will be the nation-state system that disappears, with global federalism taking its place.</description><author>Rodrik, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anti-poverty policy for families in the next century: From welfare to work and worries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellwood, D. T.
This paper reveals that recent changes in social policy have included both sharp cutbacks in welfare for non-working families and dramatic increases in supports for low income working families. It explores the reasons for these changes, and documents how they have radically changed work incentives for some persons, notable single mothers. The result has been a large increase in work by low wage single parents. The paper concludes by examining several potential dangers of this new direction and explores the challenges that remain for the next century.</description><author>Ellwood, D. T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Environmental problems and policy: 2000-2050</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Portney, P. R.
The next 50 years will see more use of market-based tools for environmental protection. Regulatory authorities everywhere will require polluters to report emissions. Authority will leak away from national governments; some will be devolved to lower levels of government, but some will be lost to international bodies. Environmental conditions will continue to improve steadily in developed countries. The developing countries will be less fortunate; at least until rising incomes provide the impetus for stricter standards. Some losses will be irreversible, as with species that are extinguished.</description><author>Portney, P. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Worker protection policies in the new century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, B. E.
Federal workplace regulations describe a set of baseline requirements which must apply in every employment relationship. The purpose of such policies is to help improve the standard of living and assure a satisfactory quality of worklife for the workforce. As the new century begins, it is useful to consider the challenge for worker protection policies in the years ahead. Clearly, the challenge will be framed by the demographic and economic changes that are influencing the American workforce.</description><author>Anderson, B. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Casino gambling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinols, E. L.; Mustard, D.
nan</description><author>Grinols, E. L.; Mustard, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Casino gambling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leone, R. C.; Wasow, B.
nan</description><author>Leone, R. C.; Wasow, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Casino gambling - Response</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eadington, W. R.
nan</description><author>Eadington, W. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>