<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JF0</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Asset Allocation in Bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Shai; Colonnelli, Emanuele; Iverson, Benjamin
This paper investigates the consequences of liquidation and reorganization on the allocation and subsequent utilization of assets in bankruptcy. Using the random assignment of judges to bankruptcy cases as a natural experiment that forces some firms into liquidation, we find that the long-run utilization of assets of liquidated firms is lower relative to assets of reorganized firms. These effects are concentrated in thin markets with few potential users and in areas with low access to finance. These findings suggest that when search frictions are large, liquidation can lead to inefficient allocation of assets in bankruptcy.</description><author>Bernstein, Shai; Colonnelli, Emanuele; Iverson, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The International Bank Lending Channel of Monetary Policy Rates and QE: Credit Supply, Reach-for-Yield, and Real Effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morais, Bernardo; Peydro, Jose-Luis; Roldan-Pena, Jessica; Ruiz-Ortega, Claudia
We identify the international credit channel by exploiting Mexican supervisory data sets and foreign monetary policy shocks in a country with a large presence of European and U.S. banks. A softening of foreign monetary policy expands credit supply of foreign banks (e.g., U.K. policy affects credit supply in Mexico via U.K. banks), inducing strong firm-level real effects. Results support an international risk-taking channel and spillovers of core countries' monetary policies to emerging markets, both in the foreign monetary softening part (with higher credit and liquidity risk-taking by foreign banks) and in the tightening part (with negative local firm-level real effects).</description><author>Morais, Bernardo; Peydro, Jose-Luis; Roldan-Pena, Jessica; Ruiz-Ortega, Claudia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dealer Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Dan; Schurhoff, Norman
Dealers in the over-the-counter municipal bond market form trading networks with other dealers to mitigate search frictions. Regulatory data show that this network has a core-periphery structure with 10 to 30 hubs and over 2,000 peripheral broker-dealers in which bonds flow from periphery to core and partially back. Central dealers charge investors up to double the round-trip markups compared to peripheral dealers. In turn, central dealers provide immediacy by matching buyers with sellers more directly and prearranging fewer trades, especially during stress times. Investors thus face a trade-off between execution cost and speed, consistent with network models of decentralized trade.</description><author>Li, Dan; Schurhoff, Norman</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Funding Value Adjustments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, Leif; Duffie, Darrell; Song, Yang
In this paper, we demonstrate that the funding value adjustments (FVAs) of major dealers are debt overhang costs to their shareholders. To maximize shareholder value, dealer quotations therefore adjust for FVAs. Our case studies include interest-rate swap FVAs and violations of covered interest parity. Contrary to current valuation practice, FVAs are not themselves components of the market values of the positions being financed. Current dealer practice does, however, align incentives between trading desks and shareholders. We also establish a pecking order for preferred asset financing strategies and provide a new interpretation of the standard debit value adjustment.</description><author>Andersen, Leif; Duffie, Darrell; Song, Yang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Crashes Develop: Intradaily Volatility and Crash Evolution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, David S.
This paper explores whether affine models with volatility jumps estimated on intradaily S&amp;P 500 futures data over 1983 to 2008 can capture major daily outliers such as the 1987 stock market crash. Intradaily jumps in futures prices are typically small; self-exciting but short-lived volatility spikes capture intradaily and daily returns better. Multifactor models of the evolution of diffusive variance and jump intensities improve fits substantially, including out-of-sample over 2009 to 2016. The models capture reasonably well the conditional distributions of daily returns and realized variance outliers, but underpredict realized variance inliers. I also examine option pricing implications.</description><author>Bates, David S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Basis-Momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boons, Martijn; Prado, Melissa Porras
We introduce a return predictor related to the slope and curvature of the futures term structure: basis-momentum. Basis-momentum strongly outperforms benchmark characteristics in predicting commodity spot and term premiums in both the time series and the cross section. Exposure to basis-momentum is priced among commodity-sorted portfolios and individual commodities. We argue that basis-momentum captures imbalances in the supply and demand of futures contracts that materialize when the market-clearing ability of speculators and intermediaries is impaired, and that it represents compensation for priced risk. Our findings are inconsistent with alternative explanations based on storage, inventory, and hedging pressure.</description><author>Boons, Martijn; Prado, Melissa Porras</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment and the Cross-Section of Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clementi, Gian Luca; Palazzo, Berardino
The data show that, upon being hit by adverse profitability shocks, large public firms have ample latitude to divest their least productive assets, reducing the risk faced by shareholders and the returns that they are likely to demand. In the one-factor production-based asset pricing model, when the frictions to capital adjustment are shaped to respect the evidence on investment, the model-generated cross-sectional dispersion of returns is only a small fraction of that documented in the data. Our conclusions hold even when operating or labor leverage is modeled in ways shown to be promising in the extant literature.</description><author>Clementi, Gian Luca; Palazzo, Berardino</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>(Almost) Model-Free Recovery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schneider, Paul; Trojani, Fabio
Under mild assumptions, we recover the model-free conditional minimum variance projection of the pricing kernel on various tradeable realized moments of market returns. Recovered conditional moments predict future realizations and give insight into the cyclicality of equity premia, variance risk premia, and the highest attainable Sharpe ratios under the minimum variance probability. The pricing kernel projections are often U-shaped and give rise to optimal conditional portfolio strategies with plausible market timing properties, moderate countercyclical exposures to higher realized moments, and favorable out-of-sample Sharpe ratios.</description><author>Schneider, Paul; Trojani, Fabio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Markets Where Traders Neglect the Informational Content of Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eyster, Erik; Rabin, Matthew; Vayanos, Dimitri
We model a financial market where some traders of a risky asset do not fully appreciate what prices convey about others' private information. Markets comprising solely such "cursed" traders generate more trade than those comprising solely rationals. Because rationals arbitrage away distortions caused by cursed traders, mixed markets can generate even more trade. Per-trader volume in cursed markets increases with market size; volume may instead disappear when traders infer others' information from prices, even when they dismiss it as noisier than their own. Making private information public raises rational and "dismissive" volume, but reduces cursed volume given moderate noninformational trading motives.</description><author>Eyster, Erik; Rabin, Matthew; Vayanos, Dimitri</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend Dynamics, Learning, and Expected Stock Index Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, Ravi; Liu, Binying
We present a latent variable model of dividends that predicts, out-of-sample, 39.5% to 41.3% of the variation in annual dividend growth rates between 1975 and 2016. Further, when learning about dividend dynamics is incorporated into a long-run risks model, the model predicts, out-of-sample, 25.3% to 27.1% of the variation in annual stock index returns over the same time horizon, with learning contributing approximately half of the predictability in returns. These findings support the view that investors' aversion to long-run risks and their learning about these risks are important in determining stock index prices and expected returns.</description><author>Jagannathan, Ravi; Liu, Binying</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sparse Signals in the Cross-Section of Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chinco, Alex; Clark-Joseph, Adam D.; Ye, Mao
This paper applies the Least Absolute Shrinkage and Selection Operator (LASSO) to make rolling one-minute-ahead return forecasts using the entire cross-section of lagged returns as candidate predictors. The LASSO increases both out-of-sample fit and forecast-implied Sharpe ratios. This out-of-sample success comes from identifying predictors that are unexpected, short-lived, and sparse. Although the LASSO uses a statistical rule rather than economic intuition to identify predictors, the predictors it identifies are nevertheless associated with economically meaningful events: the LASSO tends to identify as predictors stocks with news about fundamentals.</description><author>Chinco, Alex; Clark-Joseph, Adam D.; Ye, Mao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Test of the Modigliani-Miller Invariance Theorem and Arbitrage in Experimental Asset Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charness, Gary; Neugebauer, Tibor
Modigliani and Miller show that the total market value of a firm is unaffected by a repackaging of asset return streams to equity and debt if pricing is arbitrage-free. We investigate this invariance theorem in experimental asset markets, finding value-invariance for assets of identical risks when returns are perfectly correlated. However, exploiting price discrepancies has risk when returns have the same expected value but are uncorrelated, in which case the law of one price is violated. Discrepancies shrink in consecutive markets, but persist even with experienced traders. In markets where overall trader acuity is high, assets trade closer to parity.</description><author>Charness, Gary; Neugebauer, Tibor</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Connections and Allocative Distortions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schoenherr, David
Exploiting a unique institutional setting in Korea, this paper documents that politicians can increase the amount of government resources allocated through their social networks to the benefit of private firms connected to these networks. After winning the election, the new president appoints members of his networks as CEOs of state-owned firms that act as intermediaries in allocating government contracts to private firms. In turn, these state firms allocate significantly more procurement contracts to private firms with a CEO from the same network. Contracts allocated to connected private firms are executed systematically worse and exhibit more frequent cost increases through renegotiations.</description><author>Schoenherr, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Manager Compensation in the US Mutual Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ma, Linlin; Tang, Yuehua; Gomez, Juan-Pedro
We study compensation contracts of individual portfolio managers using hand-collected data of over 4,500 U.S. mutual funds. Variations in the compensation structures are broadly consistent with an optimal contracting equilibrium. The likelihood of explicit performance-based incentives is positively correlated with the intensity of agency conflicts, as proxied by the advisor's clientele dispersion, its affiliations in the financial industry, and its ownership structure. Investor sophistication and the threat of dismissal in outsourced funds serve as substitutes for explicit performance-based incentives. Finally, we find little evidence of differences in future performance associated with any particular compensation arrangement.</description><author>Ma, Linlin; Tang, Yuehua; Gomez, Juan-Pedro</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sticky Expectations and the Profitability Anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouchaud, Jean-Philippe; Krueger, Philipp; Landier, Augustin; Thesmar, David
We propose a theory of the "profitability" anomaly. In our model, investors forecast future profits using a signal and sticky belief dynamics. In this model, past profits forecast future returns (the profitability anomaly). Using analyst forecast data, we measure expectation stickiness at the firm level and find strong support for three additional model predictions: (1) analysts are on average too pessimistic regarding the future profits of high-profit firms, (2) the profitability anomaly is stronger for stocks that are followed by stickier analysts, and (3) the profitability anomaly is stronger for stocks with more persistent profits.</description><author>Bouchaud, Jean-Philippe; Krueger, Philipp; Landier, Augustin; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Explanation of Negative Swap Spreads: Demand for Duration from Underfunded Pension Plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klingler, Sven; Sundaresan, Suresh
The 30-year U.S. swap spreads have been negative since September 2008. We offer a novel explanation for this persistent anomaly. Through an illustrative model, we show that underfunded pension plans optimally use swaps for duration hedging. Combined with dealer banks' balance sheet constraints, this demand can drive swap spreads to become negative. Empirically, we construct a measure of the aggregate funding status of defined benefit pension plans and show that this measure helps explain 30-year swap spreads. We find a similar link between pension funds' underfunding and swap spreads for two other regions.</description><author>Klingler, Sven; Sundaresan, Suresh</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stealing Deposits: Deposit Insurance, Risk-Taking, and the Removal of Market Discipline in Early 20(th)-Century Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calomiris, Charles W.; Jaremski, Matthew
Deposit insurance reduces liquidity risk but can increase insolvency risk by encouraging reckless behavior. Several U.S. states installed deposit insurance laws before the creation of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and those laws applied only to some depository institutions within those states. These experiments present a unique testing ground for investigating the effect of deposit insurance. We show that deposit insurance removed market discipline constraining uninsured banks. Taking advantage of World War I's rise in world agricultural prices, insured banks increased their insolvency risk and competed aggressively for deposits. When prices fell after the war, the insurance systems collapsed and suffered high losses.</description><author>Calomiris, Charles W.; Jaremski, Matthew</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Finances Durable Goods and Why It Matters: Captive Finance and the Coase Conjecture</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murfin, Justin; Pratt, Ryan
We propose that, by financing their own product sales through captive finance subsidiaries, durable goods manufacturers commit to higher resale values for their products in future periods. Using data on captive financing by the manufacturers of heavy equipment, we find that captive-backed models have lower price depreciation. The evidence is consistent with captive finance helping manufacturers commit to ex-post actions that support used machine prices. This, in turn, conveys higher pledgeability for captive-backed products, even for individual machines financed by banks. Although motivated as a rent-seeking device, captive financing generates positive spillovers by relaxing credit constraints.</description><author>Murfin, Justin; Pratt, Ryan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamic Properties of Financial-Market Equilibrium with Trading Fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buss, Adrian; Dumas, Bernard
We incorporate trading fees into a dynamic, multiagent general-equilibrium model in which traders optimally decide when to trade. For that purpose, we propose an innovative algorithm that synchronizes the traders. Securities prices are not so much affected by the payment of the fees itself, but rather by the trade-off that the traders face between smoothing consumption and smoothing holdings. In calibrated examples, the interest rate and welfare decline with trading fees, while risk premia and volatilities increase. Liquidity risk and expected liquidity are priced, leading to deviations from the consumption-CAPM. With trading fees, capital is slow-moving, generating slow price reversal.</description><author>Buss, Adrian; Dumas, Bernard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity Misvaluation and Default Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisdorfer, Assaf; Goyal, Amit; Zhdanov, Alexei
We study whether default options are mispriced in equity values by employing a structural equity valuation model that explicitly takes into account the value of the option to default (or abandon the firm) and uses firm-specific inputs. We implement our model on the entire cross section of stocks and identify both over- and underpriced equities. An investment strategy that buys undervalued stocks and shorts overvalued stocks generates an annual four-factor alpha of about 11% for U.S. stocks. The model's performance is stronger for stocks with a higher value of the default option, such as distressed or highly volatile stocks.</description><author>Eisdorfer, Assaf; Goyal, Amit; Zhdanov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stockholders' Unrealized Returns and the Market Reaction to Financial Disclosures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weisbrod, Eric
Using both investor- and stock-level data, I examine the relation between stockholders' unrealized returns since purchase and the market response to earnings announcements. I demonstrate that stockholders' unrealized gain/loss position moderates their trading behavior in response to earnings announcements. I also find that this behavior generates a short-window return underreaction to earnings news. My results are generally consistent with predictions from prospect theory regarding the manner in which stockholders' unrealized returns moderate their trading response to belief shocks. However, my results also suggest that an emotional component (i.e., regret-avoidance/pride-seeking) is necessary to explain the observed investor behavior.</description><author>Weisbrod, Eric</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Measures of Earnings Surprises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiang, Chin-Han; Dai, Wei; Fan, Jianqing; Hong, Harrison; Tu, Jun
Event studies of market efficiency measure earnings surprises using the consensus error (CE), given as actual earnings minus the average professional forecast. If a subset of forecasts can be biased, the ideal but difficult to estimate parameter-dependent alternative to CE is a nonlinear filter of individual errors that adjusts for bias. We show that CE is a poor parameter-free approximation of this ideal measure. The fraction of misses on the same side (FOM), which discards the magnitude of misses, offers a far better approximation. FOM performs particularly well against CE in predicting the returns of U.S. stocks, where bias is potentially large.</description><author>Chiang, Chin-Han; Dai, Wei; Fan, Jianqing; Hong, Harrison; Tu, Jun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sentiment Metrics and Investor Demand</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeVault, Luke; Sias, Richard; Starks, Laura
Recent work suggests that sentiment traders shift from safer to more speculative stocks when sentiment increases. Exploiting these cross-sectional patterns and changes in share ownership, we find that sentiment metrics capture institutional rather than individual investors' demand shocks. We investigate the underlying economic mechanisms and find that common institutional investment styles (e.g., risk management, momentum trading) explain a significant portion of the relation between institutions and sentiment.</description><author>DeVault, Luke; Sias, Richard; Starks, Laura</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cautious Risk Takers: Investor Preferences and Demand for Active Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Polkovnichenko, Valery; Wei, Kelsey D.; Zhao, Feng
Despite their mediocre mean performance, actively managed mutual funds are distinct from passive funds in their return distributions. Active value funds better hedge downside risk, while active growth funds better capture upside potential. Since such performance features may appeal to investors with tail-overweighting preferences, we show that preferences for downside protection and upside potential estimated from the empirical pricing kernel can help explain active fund flows in the value and growth categories, respectively. This effect of investor risk preferences varies significantly with funds' downside-hedging and upside-capturing ability, with levels of active management, and across retirement and retail funds.</description><author>Polkovnichenko, Valery; Wei, Kelsey D.; Zhao, Feng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Is the Expected Return on a Stock?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martin, Ian W. R.; Wagner, Christian
We derive a formula for the expected return on a stock in terms of the risk-neutral variance of the market and the stock's excess risk-neutral variance relative to that of the average stock. These quantities can be computed from index and stock option prices; the formula has no free parameters. The theory performs well empirically both in and out of sample. Our results suggest that there is considerably more variation in expected returns, over time and across stocks, than has previously been acknowledged.</description><author>Martin, Ian W. R.; Wagner, Christian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinearity and Flight-to-Safety in the Risk-Return Trade-Off for Stocks and Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adrian, Tobias; Crump, Richard K.; Vogt, Erik
We document a highly significant, strongly nonlinear dependence of stock and bond returns on past equity market volatility as measured by the VIX. We propose a new estimator for the shape of the nonlinear forecasting relationship that exploits variation in the cross-section of returns. The nonlinearities are mirror images for stocks and bonds, revealing flight-to-safety: expected returns increase for stocks when volatility increases from moderate to high levels while they decline for Treasuries. These findings provide support for dynamic asset pricing theories in which the price of risk is a nonlinear function of marketvolatility.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Crump, Richard K.; Vogt, Erik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Costly Information Acquisition, Social Networks, and Asset Prices: Experimental Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Halim, Edward; Riyanto, Yohanes E.; Roy, Nilanjan
We design an experiment to study the implications of information networks for incentives to acquire costly information, market liquidity, investors' earnings, and asset price characteristics in a financial market. Social communication crowds out information production as a result of an agent's temptation to free ride on the signals purchased by her neighbors. Although information exchange among traders increases trading volume, improves liquidity, and enhances the ability of asset prices to reflect the available information in the market, it fails to improve price informativeness. Net earnings and social welfare are higher with information sharing due to reduced acquisition of costlysignals.</description><author>Halim, Edward; Riyanto, Yohanes E.; Roy, Nilanjan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Horizon, Optimal Pay Duration, and the Escalation of Short-Termism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marinovic, Ivan; Varas, Felipe
This paper studies optimal contracts when managers manipulate their performance measure at the expense of firm value. Optimal contracts defer compensation. The manager's incentives vest over time at an increasing rate, and compensation becomes very sensitive to short-term performance. This generates an endogenous horizon problem whereby managers intensify performance manipulation in their final years in office. Contracts are designed to encourage effort while minimizing the adverse effects of manipulation. We characterize the optimal mix of short- and long-term compensation along the manager's tenure, the optimal vesting period of incentive pay, and the dynamics of short-termism over the CEO'stenure.</description><author>Marinovic, Ivan; Varas, Felipe</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Income Hedging, Dynamic Style Preferences, and Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Addoum, Jawad M.; Delikouras, Stefanos; Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok
We propose a theoretical measure of income hedging demand and show that it affects asset prices. We focus on the value factor and first demonstrate that our demand estimates are correlated with the actual demands of retail and mutual fund investors. We then show that the aggregate high-minus-low (HML) demand predicts HML returns. Exploiting the state-level variation in income risk, we demonstrate that state-level hedging demands predict state-level HML returns. A long-short portfolio that exploits this hedging-induced predictability earns an annualized risk-adjusted return of 6%.</description><author>Addoum, Jawad M.; Delikouras, Stefanos; Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend Dynamics, Learning, and Expected Stock Index Returns (vol 74, pg 401, 2019)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, Ravi; Liu, Binying; Zhang, Jiaqi
nan</description><author>Jagannathan, Ravi; Liu, Binying; Zhang, Jiaqi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Editor of The Journal of Finance for the Year 2018</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagel, Stefan
nan</description><author>Nagel, Stefan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-Varying Asset Volatility and the Credit Spread Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Du; Elkamhi, Redouane; Ericsson, Jan
Most extant structural credit risk models underestimate credit spreads-a shortcoming known as the credit spread puzzle. We consider a model with priced stochastic asset risk that is able to fit medium- to long-term spreads. The model, augmented by jumps to help explain short-term spreads, is estimated on firm-level data and identifies significant asset variance risk premia. An important feature of the model is the significant time variation in risk premia induced by the uncertainty about asset risk. Various extensions are considered, among them optimal leverage and endogenousdefault.</description><author>Du, Du; Elkamhi, Redouane; Ericsson, Jan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor-Technology Substitution: Implications for Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Miao Ben
This paper studies the asset pricing implications of a firm's opportunities to replace routine-task labor with automation. I develop a model in which firms optimally undertake such replacement when their productivity is low. Hence, firms with routine-task labor maintain a replacement option that hedges their value against unfavorable macroeconomic shocks and lowers their expected returns. Using establishment-level occupational data, I construct a measure of firms' share of routine-task labor. Compared to their industry peers, firms with a higher share of routine-task labor (i) invest more in machines and reduce more routine-task labor during economic downturns, and (ii) have lower expected stockreturns.</description><author>Zhang, Miao Ben</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Share Risk in US Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lettau, Martin; Ludvigson, Sydney C.; Ma, Sai
A single macroeconomic factor based on growth in the capital share of aggregate income exhibits significant explanatory power for expected returns across a range of equity characteristic portfolios and nonequity asset classes, with risk price estimates that are of the same sign and similar in magnitude. Positive exposure to capital share risk earns a positive risk premium, commensurate with recent asset pricing models in which redistributive shocks shift the share of income between the wealthy, who finance consumption primarily out of asset ownership, and workers, who finance consumption primarily out of wages andsalaries.</description><author>Lettau, Martin; Ludvigson, Sydney C.; Ma, Sai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Share Dynamics When Firms Insure Workers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartman-Glaser, Barney; Lustig, Hanno; Xiaolan, Mindy Z.
Although the aggregate capital share of U.S. firms has increased, capital share at the firm-level has decreased. This divergence is due to mega-firms that produce a larger output share without a proportionate increase in labor compensation. We develop a model in which firms insure workers against firm-specific shocks, with more productive firms allocating more rents to shareholders, while less productive firms endogenously exit. Increasing firm-level risk delays exit and increases the measure of mega-firms, raising (lowering) the aggregate (average) capital share. An increase in the level of rents magnifies this effect. We present evidence that supports thismechanism.</description><author>Hartman-Glaser, Barney; Lustig, Hanno; Xiaolan, Mindy Z.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential Address: Collateral and Commitment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demarzo, Peter M.
Optimal dynamic capital structure choice is fundamentally a problem of commitment. In a standard trade-off setting with shareholder-debtholder agency conflicts, full commitment counterfactually predicts the firm would rely almost exclusively on debt financing. Conversely, absent commitment a Modigliani-Miller-like value irrelevance and policy indeterminacy result holds. Thus, the content of dynamic trade-off theory must depend on the commitment technology. In this context, collateral is valuable as a low-cost commitment device. Because ex ante optimal commitments are likely to be suboptimal ex post, observed capital structure dynamics will exhibit hysteresis and depart significantly from standard predictions.</description><author>Demarzo, Peter M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Discovery without Trading: Evidence from Limit Orders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brogaard, Jonathan; Hendershott, Terrence; Riordan, Ryan
We analyze the contribution to price discovery of market and limit orders by high-frequency traders (HFTs) and non-HFTs. While market orders have a larger individual price impact, limit orders are far more numerous. This results in price discovery occurring predominantly through limit orders. HFTs submit the bulk of limit orders and these limit orders provide most of the price discovery. Submissions of limit orders and their contribution to price discovery fall with volatility due to changes in HFTs' behavior. Consistent with adverse selection arising from faster reactions to public information, HFTs' informational advantage is partially explained by public information.</description><author>Brogaard, Jonathan; Hendershott, Terrence; Riordan, Ryan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Opp, Christian C.
We examine the importance of cross-sectional asset pricing anomalies (alphas) for the real economy. To this end, we develop a novel quantitative model of the cross-section of firms that features lumpy investment and informational inefficiencies, while yielding distributions in closed form. Our findings indicate that anomalies can cause material real inefficiencies, which raises the possibility that agents who help eliminate them add significant value to the economy. The model shows that the magnitude of alphas alone is a poor indicator of real outcomes, and highlights the importance of the alpha persistence, the amount of mispriced capital, and the Tobin's q of firmsaffected.</description><author>van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Opp, Christian C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ratings Quality and Borrowing Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Badoer, Dominique C.; Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher M.
Past studies document that incentive conflicts may lead issuer-paid credit rating agencies to provide optimistically biased ratings. In this paper, we present evidence that investors question the quality of issuer-paid ratings and raise corporate bond yields where the issuer-paid rating is more positive than benchmark investor-paid ratings. We also find that some firms with favorable issuer-paid ratings substitute public bonds with borrowings from informed intermediaries to mitigate the "lemons discount" associated with poor quality ratings. Overall, our results suggest that the quality of issuer-paid ratings has significant effects on borrowing costs and the choice of debt.</description><author>Badoer, Dominique C.; Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dividend Disconnect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.
Many individual investors, mutual funds, and institutions trade as if dividends and capital gains are disconnected attributes, not fully appreciating that dividends result in price decreases. Behavioral trading patterns (e.g., the disposition effect) are driven by price changes instead of total returns. Investors rarely reinvest dividends, and trade as if dividends are a separate, stable income stream. Analysts fail to account for the effect of dividends on price, leading to optimistic price forecasts for dividend-paying stocks. Demand for dividends is systematically higher in periods of low interest rates and poor market performance, leading to lower returns for dividend-paying stocks.</description><author>Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Returns over the FOMC Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cieslak, Anna; Morse, Adair; Vissing-Jorgensen, Annette
We document that since 1994, the equity premium is earned entirely in weeks 0, 2, 4, and 6 in Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) cycle time, that is, even weeks starting from the last FOMC meeting. We causally tie this fact to the Fed by studying intermeeting target changes, Fed funds futures, and internal Board of Governors meetings. The Fed has affected the stock market via unexpectedly accommodating policy, leading to large reductions in the equity premium. Evidence suggests systematic informal communication of Fed officials with the media and financial sector as a channel through which news about monetary policy has reached the market.</description><author>Cieslak, Anna; Morse, Adair; Vissing-Jorgensen, Annette</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreclosure Contagion and the Neighborhood Spillover Effects of Mortgage Defaults</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, Arpit
In this paper, I identify shocks to interest rates resulting from two administrative details in adjustable-rate mortgage contract terms: the choice of financial index and the choice of lookback period. I find that a 1 percentage point increase in interest rate at the time of adjustable-rate mortgage (ARM) reset results in a 2.5 percentage increase in the probability of foreclosure in the following year, and that each foreclosure filing leads to an additional 0.3 to 0.6 completed foreclosures within a 0.10-mile radius. In explaining this result, I emphasize price effects, bank-supply responses, and borrower responses arising from peer effects.</description><author>Gupta, Arpit</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited Investment Capital and Credit Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siriwardane, Emil N.
Using proprietary credit default swap (CDS) data, I investigate how capital shocks at protection sellers impact pricing in the CDS market. Seller capital shocks-measured as CDS portfolio margin payments-account for 12% of the time-series variation in weekly spread changes, a significant amount given that standard credit factors account for 18% during my sample. In addition, seller shocks possess information for spreads that is independent of institution-wide measures of constraints. These findings imply a high degree of market segmentation, and suggest that frictions within specialized financial institutions prevent capital from flowing into the market at shorter horizons.</description><author>Siriwardane, Emil N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Investment Ideas Spread through Social Interaction? Evidence from a Ponzi Scheme</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rantala, Ville
A unique data set from a large Ponzi scheme allows me to study word-of-mouth diffusion of investment information. Investors could join the scheme only by invitation from an existing member, which allows me to observe how the idea spreads from one person to the next based on inviter-invitee relationships. I find that the observed social network has a scale-free connectivity structure, which significantly facilitates the diffusion of the investment idea and contributes to the growth and survival of the socially spreading Ponzi scheme. I further find that investors invest more if their inviter has comparatively higher age, education, and income.</description><author>Rantala, Ville</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Globalization Risk Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barrot, Jean-Noel; Loualiche, Erik; Sauvagnat, Julien
In this paper, we investigate how globalization is reflected in asset prices. We use shipping costs to measure firms' exposure to globalization. Firms in low shipping cost industries carry a 7% risk premium, suggesting that their cash flows covary negatively with investors' marginal utility. We find that the premium emanates from the risk of displacement of least efficient firms triggered by import competition. These findings suggest that foreign productivity shocks are associated with times when consumption is dear for investors. We discuss conditions under which a standard model of trade with asset prices can rationalize this puzzle.</description><author>Barrot, Jean-Noel; Loualiche, Erik; Sauvagnat, Julien</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Proxy Advisory Firms: The Economics of Selling Information to Voters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malenko, Andrey; Malenko, Nadya
We analyze how proxy advisors, which sell voting recommendations to shareholders, affect corporate decision-making. If the quality of the advisor's information is low, there is overreliance on its recommendations and insufficient private information production. In contrast, if the advisor's information is precise, it may be underused because the advisor rations its recommendations to maximize profits. Overall, the advisor's presence leads to more informative voting only if its information is sufficiently precise. We evaluate several proposals on regulating proxy advisors and show that some suggested policies, such as reducing proxy advisors' market power or decreasing litigation pressure, can have negative effects.</description><author>Malenko, Andrey; Malenko, Nadya</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Personal Experiences and Expectations about Aggregate Outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuchler, Theresa; Zafar, Basit
Using novel survey data, we document that individuals extrapolate from recent personal experiences when forming expectations about aggregate economic outcomes. Recent locally experienced house price movements affect expectations about future U.S. house price changes and higher experienced house price volatility causes respondents to report a wider distribution over expected U.S. house price movements. When we exploit within-individual variation in employment status, we find that individuals who personally experience unemployment become more pessimistic about future nationwide unemployment. The extent of extrapolation is unrelated to how informative personal experiences are, is inconsistent with risk adjustment, and is more pronounced for less sophisticated individuals.</description><author>Kuchler, Theresa; Zafar, Basit</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Portfolio Manager Contracts Contract Portfolio Management?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Jung Hoon; Trzcinka, Charles; Venkatesan, Shyam
Most mutual fund managers have performance-based contracts. Our theory predicts that mutual fund managers with asymmetric contracts and mid-year performance close to their announced benchmark increase their portfolio risk in the second part of the year. As predicted by our theory, performance deviation from the benchmark decreases risk-shifting only for managers with performance contracts. Deviation from the benchmark dominates incentives from the flow-performance relation, suggesting that risk-shifting is motivated more by management contracts than by a tournament to capture flows.</description><author>Lee, Jung Hoon; Trzcinka, Charles; Venkatesan, Shyam</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Best of Both Worlds: Accessing Emerging Economies via Developed Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, Joon Woo; Elkamhi, Redouane; Simutin, Mikhail
A growing body of evidence suggests that the benefits of international diversification via developed markets have declined dramatically. While emerging markets still offer diversification opportunities, their public equity indices capture only a fraction of emerging countries' economic activity. We propose a diversification approach that exploits the global connectedness of developed countries to gain exposure to emerging countries' overall economies rather than their shallow equity markets. In doing so, we demonstrate that developed markets still offer substantial diversification benefits beyond those available through equity indices. Our results suggest that relying on equity indices to assess diversification benefits understates diversification gains.</description><author>Bae, Joon Woo; Elkamhi, Redouane; Simutin, Mikhail</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reassessing False Discoveries in Mutual Fund Performance: Skill, Luck, or Lack of Power?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrikogiannopoulou, Angie; Papakonstantinou, Filippos
Barras, Scaillet, and Wermers propose the false discovery rate (FDR) to separate skill (alpha) from luck in fund performance. Using simulations with parameters informed by the data, we find that this methodology is conservative and underestimates the proportion of nonzero-alpha funds. For example, 65% of funds with economically large alphas of +/- 2% are misclassified as zero alpha. This bias arises from the low signal-to-noise ratio in fund returns and the resulting low statistical power. Our results question FDR's applicability in performance evaluation and other domains with low power, and can materially change the conclusion that most funds have zero alpha.</description><author>Andrikogiannopoulou, Angie; Papakonstantinou, Filippos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Markets, the Real Economy, and Self-Fulfilling Uncertainties</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benhabib, Jess; Liu, Xuewen; Wang, Pengfei
We develop a model of informational interdependence between financial markets and the real economy, linking economic uncertainty to information production and aggregate economic activities in general equilibrium. The mutual learning between financial markets and the real economy creates a strategic complementarity in their information production, leading to self-fulfilling surges in economic uncertainties. In a dynamic setting, our model characterizes self-fulfilling uncertainty traps with two steady-state equilibria and a two-stage economic crisis in transitional dynamics.</description><author>Benhabib, Jess; Liu, Xuewen; Wang, Pengfei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage and the Cross-Section of Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doshi, Hitesh; Jacobs, Kris; Kumar, Praveen; Rabinovitch, Ramon
Building on theoretical asset pricing literature, we examine the role of market risk and the size, book-to-market (BTM), and volatility anomalies in the cross-section of unlevered equity returns. Compared with levered (stock) returns, unlevered market beta plays a more important role in explaining the cross-section of unlevered equity returns, even after controlling for size and BTM. The size effect is weakened, while the value premium and the volatility puzzle virtually disappear for unlevered returns. We show that leverage induces heteroskedasticity in returns. Unlevering returns removes this pattern, which is otherwise difficult to address by controlling for leverage in regressions.</description><author>Doshi, Hitesh; Jacobs, Kris; Kumar, Praveen; Rabinovitch, Ramon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Contracting, Corporate Finance, and Valuation with Inalienable Human Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Wang, Neng; Yang, Jinqiang
A risk-averse entrepreneur with access to a profitable venture needs to raise funds from investors. She cannot indefinitely commit her human capital to the venture, which limits the firm's debt capacity, distorts investment and compensation, and constrains the entrepreneur's risk sharing. This puts dynamic liquidity and state-contingent risk allocation at the center of corporate financial management. The firm balances mean-variance investment efficiency and the preservation of financial slack. We show that in general the entrepreneur's net worth is overexposed to idiosyncratic risk and underexposed to systematic risk. These distortions are greater the closer the firm is to exhausting its debt capacity.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Wang, Neng; Yang, Jinqiang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade Network Centrality and Currency Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Richmond, Robert J.
I uncover an economic source of exposure to global risk that drives international asset prices. Countries that are more central in the global trade network have lower interest rates and currency risk premia. To explain these findings, I present a general equilibrium model in which central countries' consumption growth is more exposed to global consumption growth shocks. This causes the currencies of central countries to appreciate in bad times, resulting in lower interest rates and currency risk premia. Empirically, central countries' consumption growth covaries more with world consumption growth, further validating the proposed mechanism.</description><author>Richmond, Robert J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture Capital and Capital Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piacentino, Giorgia
I show that venture capitalists' motivation to build reputation can have beneficial effects in the primary market, mitigating information frictions and helping firms go public. Because uninformed reputation-motivated venture capitalists want to appear informed, they are biased against backing firms-by not backing firms, they avoid taking low-value firms to market, which would ultimately reveal their lack of information. In equilibrium, reputation-motivated venture capitalists back relatively few bad firms, creating a certification effect that mitigates information frictions. However, they also back relatively few good firms, and thus, reputation motivation decreases welfare when good firms are abundant or profitable.</description><author>Piacentino, Giorgia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Brokers versus Retail Investors: Conflicting Interests and Dominated Products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Egan, Mark
I study how brokers distort household investment decisions. Using a novel convertible bond data set, I find that consumers often purchase dominated bonds-cheap and expensive otherwise-identical bonds coexist in the market. Brokers are incentivized to sell the dominated bonds, typically earning two times greater fees for selling them. I develop and estimate a broker-intermediated search model that rationalizes this behavior. The estimates indicate that costly search is a key friction in financial markets, but the effects of search costs are compounded when brokers are incentivized to direct the search of consumers toward high-fee inferior products.</description><author>Egan, Mark</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee Stock Option Exercise and Firm Cost</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carpenter, Jennifer N.; Stanton, Richard; Wallace, Nancy
We develop an empirical model of employee stock option exercise that is suitable for valuation and allows for behavioral channels. We estimate exercise rates as functions of option, stock, and employee characteristics using all employee exercises at 88 public firms, 27 of them in the S&amp;P 500. Increasing vesting frequency from annual to monthly reduces option value by 11% to 16%. Men exercise faster, reducing value by 2% to 4%, while top employees exercise slower, increasing value by 2% to 7%. Finally, we develop an analytic valuation approximation that is more accurate than methods used in practice.</description><author>Carpenter, Jennifer N.; Stanton, Richard; Wallace, Nancy</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Risk and the Dynamics of Arbitrage Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kondor, Peter; Vayanos, Dimitri
We develop a continuous-time model of liquidity provision in which hedgers can trade multiple risky assets with arbitrageurs. Arbitrageurs have constant relative risk-aversion (CRRA) utility, while hedgers' asset demand is independent of wealth. An increase in hedgers' risk aversion can make arbitrageurs endogenously more risk-averse. Because arbitrageurs generate endogenous risk, an increase in their wealth or a reduction in their CRRA coefficient can raise risk premia despite Sharpe ratios declining. Arbitrageur wealth is a priced risk factor because assets held by arbitrageurs offer high expected returns but suffer the most when wealth drops. Aggregate illiquidity, which declines in wealth, captures that factor.</description><author>Kondor, Peter; Vayanos, Dimitri</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-Frequency Trading around Large Institutional Orders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Kervel, Vincent; Menkveld, Albert J.
Liquidity suppliers lean against the wind. We analyze whether high-frequency traders (HFTs) lean against large institutional orders that execute through a series of child orders. The alternative is HFTs trading with the wind, that is, in the same direction. We find that HFTs initially lean against these orders but eventually change direction and take positions in the same direction for the most informed institutional orders. Our empirical findings are consistent with investors trading strategically on their information. When deciding trade intensity, they seem to trade off higher speculative profits against higher risk of being detected and preyed on by HFTs.</description><author>van Kervel, Vincent; Menkveld, Albert J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Household Debt Overhang and Unemployment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donaldson, Jason Roderick; Piacentino, Giorgia; Thakor, Anjan
We use a labor-search model to explain why the worst employment slumps often follow expansions of household debt. We find that households protected by limited liability suffer from a household-debt-overhang problem that leads them to require high wages to work. Firms respond by posting high wages but few vacancies. This vacancy posting effect implies that high household debt leads to high unemployment. Even though households borrow from banks via bilaterally optimal contracts, the equilibrium level of household debt is inefficiently high due to a household-debt externality. We analyze the role that a financial regulator can play in mitigating this externality.</description><author>Donaldson, Jason Roderick; Piacentino, Giorgia; Thakor, Anjan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Equilibrium When Contingent Capital Has a Market Trigger (vol 70, pg 881, 2015)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pennacchi, George; Tchistyi, Alexei
This paper identifies an error in Sundaresan and Wang (2015, hereafter SW) that invalidates its Theorem 1. The paper develops a model of contingent capital (CC) with a stock price trigger that is consistent with SW's framework and yields closed-form solutions for stock and CC prices. Yet, the model shows that unique stock price equilibria exist for a broader range of CC contractual terms than those required by SW. Specifically, when conversion terms benefit CC investors and penalize shareholders, a unique equilibrium can exist rather than the multiple equilibria stated in SW.</description><author>Pennacchi, George; Tchistyi, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Reduction in Large Portfolios: Why Imposing the Wrong Constraints Helps (vol 58, pg 1655, 2003)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, Ravi; Ma, Tongshu; Zhang, Jiaqi
This note corrects an error in the proof of Proposition 2 of "Risk Reduction in Large Portfolios: Why Imposing the Wrong Constraint Helps" that appeared in the Journal of Finance, August 2003.</description><author>Jagannathan, Ravi; Ma, Tongshu; Zhang, Jiaqi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Liquidity Mismatch in the Banking Sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Jennie; Krishnamurthy, Arvind; Weymuller, Charles-Henri
This paper constructs a liquidity mismatch index (LMI) to gauge the mismatch between the market liquidity of assets and the funding liquidity of liabilities, for 2,882 bank holding companies over 2002 to 2014. The aggregate LMI decreases from +$4 trillion precrisis to -$6 trillion in 2008. We conduct an LMI stress test revealing the fragility of the banking system in early 2007. Moreover, LMI predicts a bank's stock market crash probability and borrowing decisions from the government during the financial crisis. The LMI is therefore informative about both individual bank liquidity and the liquidity risk of the entire banking system.</description><author>Bai, Jennie; Krishnamurthy, Arvind; Weymuller, Charles-Henri</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Leverage Ratchet Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Admati, Anat R.; DeMarzo, Peter M.; Hellwig, Martin F.; Pfleiderer, Paul
Firms' inability to commit to future funding choices has profound consequences for capital structure dynamics. With debt in place, shareholders pervasively resist leverage reductions no matter how much such reductions may enhance firm value. Shareholders would instead choose to increase leverage even if the new debt is junior and would reduce firm value. These asymmetric forces in leverage adjustments, which we call the leverage ratchet effect, cause equilibrium leverage outcomes to be history-dependent. If forced to reduce leverage, shareholders are biased toward selling assets relative to potentially more efficient alternatives such as pure recapitalizations.</description><author>Admati, Anat R.; DeMarzo, Peter M.; Hellwig, Martin F.; Pfleiderer, Paul</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diagnostic Expectations and Credit Cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bordalo, Pedro; Gennaioli, Nicola; Shleifer, Andrei
We present a model of credit cycles arising from diagnostic expectationsa belief formation mechanism based on Kahneman and Tversky's representativeness heuristic. Diagnostic expectations overweight future outcomes that become more likely in light of incoming data. The expectations formation rule is forward looking and depends on the underlying stochastic process, and thus is immune to the Lucas critique. Diagnostic expectations reconcile extrapolation and neglect of risk in a unified framework. In our model, credit spreads are excessively volatile, overreact to news, and are subject to predictable reversals. These dynamics can account for several features of credit cycles and macroeconomic volatility.</description><author>Bordalo, Pedro; Gennaioli, Nicola; Shleifer, Andrei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Paradox of Financial Fire Sales: The Role of Arbitrage Capital in Determining Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dow, James; Han, Jungsuk
How can fire sales for financial assets happen when the economy contains well-capitalized but nonspecialist investors? Our explanation combines rational expectations equilibrium and lemons models. When specialist (informed) market participants are liquidity-constrained, prices become less informative. This creates an adverse selection problem, decreasing the supply of high-quality assets, and lowering valuations by nonspecialist (uninformed) investors, who become unwilling to supply capital to support the price. In normal times, arbitrage capital can multiply itself by making uninformed capital function as informed capital, but in a crisis, this stabilizing mechanism fails.</description><author>Dow, James; Han, Jungsuk</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government Credit, a Double-Edged Sword: Evidence from the China Development Bank</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ru, Hong
Using proprietary data from the China Development Bank (CDB), this paper examines the effects of government credit on firm activities. Tracing the effects of government credit across different levels of the supply chain, I find that CDB industrial loans to state-owned enterprises (SOEs) crowd out private firms in the same industry but crowd in private firms in downstream industries. On average, a $1 increase in CDB SOE loans leads to a $0.20 decrease in private firms' assets. Moreover, CDB infrastructure loans crowd in private firms. I use exogenous timing of municipal politicians' turnover as an instrument for CDB credit flows.</description><author>Ru, Hong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Share of Systematic Variation in Bilateral Exchange Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Verdelhan, Adrien
Sorting countries by their dollar currency betas produces a novel cross section of average currency excess returns. A slope factor (long in high beta currencies and short in low beta currencies) accounts for this cross section of currency risk premia. This slope factor is orthogonal to the high-minus-low carry trade factor built from portfolios of countries sorted by their interest rates. The two high-minus-low risk factors account for 18% to 80% of the monthly exchange rate movements. The two risk factors suggest that stochastic discount factors in complete markets' models should feature at least two global shocks to describe exchange rates.</description><author>Verdelhan, Adrien</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency, Firm Growth, and Managerial Turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Ronald W.; Bustamante, M. Cecilia; Guibaud, Stephane; Zervos, Mihail
We study managerial incentive provision under moral hazard when growth opportunities arrive stochastically and pursuing them requires a change in management. A trade-off arises between the benefit of always having the right manager and the cost of incentive provision. The prospect of growth-induced turnover limits the firm's ability to rely on deferred pay, resulting in more front-loaded compensation. The optimal contract may insulate managers from the risk of growth-induced dismissal after periods of good performance. The evidence for the United States broadly supports the model's predictions: Firms with better growth prospects experience higher CEO turnover and use more front-loaded compensation.</description><author>Anderson, Ronald W.; Bustamante, M. Cecilia; Guibaud, Stephane; Zervos, Mihail</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Personal Lending Relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karolyi, Stephen Adam
I identify the effects of personal relationships on loan contracting using executive deaths and retirements at other firms as a source of exogenous variation in executive turnover. After plausibly exogenous turnover, borrowers choose lenders with which their new executives have personal relationships 4.1 times as frequently, and loans from these lenders have 20 basis points lower spreads and 12.5% larger amounts. Personal relationships benefit firms across loan terms, especially during macroeconomic downturns. Increased financial flexibility from personal relationships insulated firms from financial shocks during the recent financial crisis: they exhibited less constrained investment and were less likely to layoff employees.</description><author>Karolyi, Stephen Adam</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Debt and Profitability in the Trade-Off Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abel, Andrew B.
I develop a dynamic model of leverage with tax deductible interest and an endogenous cost of default. The interest rate includes a premium to compensate lenders for expected losses in default. A borrowing constraint is generated by lenders' unwillingness to lend an amount that would trigger immediate default. When the borrowing constraint is not binding, the trade-off theory of debt holds: optimal debt equates the marginal interest tax shield and the marginal expected cost of default. Contrary to conventional interpretation, but consistent with empirical findings, increases in current or future profitability reduce the optimal leverage ratio when the trade-off theory holds.</description><author>Abel, Andrew B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model of Monetary Policy and Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drechsler, Itamar; Savov, Alexi; Schnabl, Philipp
We develop a dynamic asset pricing model in which monetary policy affects the risk premium component of the cost of capital. Risk-tolerant agents (banks) borrow from risk-averse agents (i.e., take deposits) to fund levered investments. Leverage exposes banks to funding risk, which they insure by holding liquidity buffers. By changing the nominal rate the central bank influences the liquidity premium, and hence the cost of taking leverage. Lower nominal rates make liquidity cheaper and raise leverage, resulting in lower risk premia and higher asset prices, volatility, investment, and growth. We analyze forward guidance, a "Greenspan put," and the yield curve.</description><author>Drechsler, Itamar; Savov, Alexi; Schnabl, Philipp</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected Inflation and Other Determinants of Treasury Yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffee, Gregory R.
Shocks to nominal bond yields consist of news about expected future inflation, expected future real short rates, and expected excess returnsall over the bond's life. I estimate the magnitude of the first component for short- and long-maturity Treasury bonds. At a quarterly frequency, variances of news about expected inflation account for between 10% to 20% of variances of yield shocks. Standard dynamic models with long-run risk imply variance ratios close to 1. Habit formation models fare somewhat better. The magnitudes of shocks to real rates and expected excess returns cannot be determined reliably.</description><author>Duffee, Gregory R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rankings and Risk-Taking in the Finance Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kirchler, Michael; Lindner, Florian; Weitzel, Utz
Rankings are omnipresent in the finance industry, yet the literature is silent on how they impact financial professionals' behavior. Using lab-in-the-field experiments with 657 professionals and lab experiments with 432 students, we investigate how rank incentives affect investment decisions. We find that both rank and tournament incentives increase risk-taking among underperforming professionals, while only tournament incentives affect students. This rank effect is robust to the experimental frame (investment frame vs. abstract frame), to payoff consequences (own return vs. family return), to social identity priming (private identity vs. professional identity), and to professionals' gender (no gender differences among professionals).</description><author>Kirchler, Michael; Lindner, Florian; Weitzel, Utz</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Rare Events Explain CDX Tranche Spreads?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seo, Sang Byung; Wachter, Jessica A.
We investigate whether a model with time-varying probability of economic disaster can explain prices of collateralized debt obligations. We focus on senior tranches of the CDX, an index of credit default swaps on investment grade firms. These assets do not incur losses until a large fraction of previously stable firms default, and thus are deep out-of-the money put options on the overall economy. When calibrated to consumption data and to the equity premium, the model explains the spreads on CDX tranches prior to and during the 2008 to 2009 crisis.</description><author>Seo, Sang Byung; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Management within Commercial Banking Groups: International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro; Pires, Pedro
We study the performance of equity mutual funds run by asset management divisions of commercial banking groups using a worldwide sample. We show that bank-affiliated funds underperform unaffiliated funds by 92 basis points per year. Consistent with conflicts of interest, the underperformance is more pronounced among those affiliated funds that overweight the stock of the bank's lending clients to a great extent. Divestitures of asset management divisions by banking groups support a causal interpretation of the results. Our findings suggest that affiliated fund managers support their lending divisions' operations to reduce career concerns at the expense of fund investors.</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro; Pires, Pedro</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Herding Behavior Reveal Skill? An Analysis of Mutual Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Hao; Verardo, Michela
We uncover a negative relation between herding behavior and skill in the mutual fund industry. Our new, dynamic measure of fund-level herding captures the tendency of fund managers to follow the trades of the institutional crowd. We find that herding funds underperform their antiherding peers by over 2% per year. Differences in skill drive this performance gap: Antiherding funds make superior investment decisions even on stocks not heavily traded by institutions, and can anticipate the trades of the crowd; furthermore, the herding-antiherding performance gap is persistent, wider when skill is more valuable, and larger among managers with stronger career concerns.</description><author>Jiang, Hao; Verardo, Michela</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Geography of Financial Misconduct</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parsons, Christopher A.; Sulaeman, Johan; Titman, Sheridan
Financial misconduct (FM) rates differ widely between major U.S. cities, up to a factor of 3. Although spatial differences in enforcement and firm characteristics do not account for these patterns, city-level norms appear to be very important. For example, FM rates are strongly related to other unethical behavior, involving politicians, doctors, and (potentially unfaithful) spouses, in the city.</description><author>Parsons, Christopher A.; Sulaeman, Johan; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Representation and Governance: Evidence from the Investment Decisions of Public Pension Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andonov, Aleksandar; Hochberg, Yael V.; Rauh, Joshua D.
Representation on pension fund boards by state officialsoften determined by statute decades pastis negatively related to the performance of private equity investments made by the pension fund, despite state officials' relatively strong financial education and experience. Their underperformance appears to be partly driven by poor investment decisions consistent with political expediency, and is also positively related to political contributions from the finance industry. Boards dominated by elected rank-and-file plan participants also underperform, but to a smaller extent and due to these trustees' lesser financial experience.</description><author>Andonov, Aleksandar; Hochberg, Yael V.; Rauh, Joshua D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anomalies and News</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engelberg, Joseph; McLean, R. David; Pontiff, Jeffrey
Using a sample of 97 stock return anomalies, we find that anomaly returns are 50% higher on corporate news days and six times higher on earnings announcement days. These results could be explained by dynamic risk, mispricing due to biased expectations, or data mining. We develop and conduct several unique tests to differentiate between these three explanations. Our results are most consistent with the idea that anomaly returns are driven by biased expectations, which are at least partly corrected upon news arrival.</description><author>Engelberg, Joseph; McLean, R. David; Pontiff, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Innovation Help US Manufacturing Firms Escape Import Competition from China?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hombert, Johan; Matray, Adrien
We study whether R&amp;D-intensive firms are more resilient to trade shocks. We correct for the endogeneity of R&amp;D using tax-induced changes to R&amp;D costs. While rising imports from China lead to slower sales growth and lower profitability, these effects are significantly smaller for firms with a larger stock of R&amp;D (about half when moving from the bottom quartile to the top quartile of R&amp;D). We provide evidence that this effect is explained by R&amp;D allowing firms to increase product differentiation. As a result, while firms in import-competing industries cut capital expenditures and employment, R&amp;D-intensive firms downsize considerably less.</description><author>Hombert, Johan; Matray, Adrien</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CMBS and Conflicts of Interest: Evidence from Ownership Changes for Servicers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wong, Maisy
Self-dealing is potentially important but difficult to measure. In this paper, I study special servicers in commercial mortgage-backed securities (CMBS), which sell distressed assets on behalf of bondholders. Around 2010, ownership changes of four major servicers raised concerns that they may direct benefits to new owners' affiliates (buyers and service providers). Loans liquidated after ownership changes have greater loss rates than before (8 percentage points (p.p.), $2.3 billion in losses), relative to other (placebo) servicers. Together with a case study that tracks self-dealing purchases, the findings point to potential steering conflicts that could incentivize tunneling through fees to service providers.</description><author>Wong, Maisy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential Address: Pension Policy and the Financial System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scharfstein, David S.
In this paper, I examine the effect of pension policy on the structure of financial systems around the world. In particular, I explore the hypothesis that policies that promote pension savings also promote the development of capital markets. I present a model that endogenizes the extent to which savings are intermediated through banks or capital markets, and derive implications for corporate finance, household finance, banking, and the size of the financial sector. I then present a number of facts that are broadly consistent with the theory and examine a variety of alternative explanations of my findings.</description><author>Scharfstein, David S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamics of Financially Constrained Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gromb, Denis; Vayanos, Dimitri
We develop a model in which financially constrained arbitrageurs exploit price discrepancies across segmented markets. We show that the dynamics of arbitrage capital are self-correcting: following a shock that depletes capital, returns increase, which allows capital to be gradually replenished. Spreads increase more for trades with volatile fundamentals or more time to convergence. Arbitrageurs cut their positions more in those trades, except when volatility concerns the hedgeable component. Financial constraints yield a positive cross-sectional relationship between spreads/returns and betas with respect to arbitrage capital. Diversification of arbitrageurs across markets induces contagion, but generally lowers arbitrageurs' risk and price volatility.</description><author>Gromb, Denis; Vayanos, Dimitri</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Editor of the Journal of Finance for the Year 2017</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagel, Stefan
nan</description><author>Nagel, Stefan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Asset Allocation of a Default Pension Fund</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahlquist, Magnus; Setty, Ofer; Vestman, Roine
We characterize the optimal default fund in a defined contribution (DC) pension plan. Using detailed data on individuals' holdings inside and outside the pension system, we find substantial heterogeneity within and between passive and active investors in terms of labor income, financial wealth, and stock market participation. We build a life-cycle consumption-savings model, with a DC pension account and an opt-out/default choice, that produces realistic investor heterogeneity. Relative to a common age-based allocation, implementing the optimal default asset allocation implies a welfare gain of 1.5% during retirement. Much of the gain is attainable with a simple rule of thumb.</description><author>Dahlquist, Magnus; Setty, Ofer; Vestman, Roine</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Experimental Study of Bond Market Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weber, Matthias; Duffy, John; Schram, Arthur
An important feature of bond markets is the relationship between the initial public offering (IPO) price and the probability that the issuer defaults. On the one hand, the default probability affects the IPO price; on the other hand, the IPO price affects the default probability. It is a priori unclear whether agents can competitively price such assets. Our paper is the first to explore this question. To do so, we use laboratory experiments. We develop two flexible bond market models that are easily implemented in the laboratory. We find that subjects learn to price the bonds well after only a few repetitions.</description><author>Weber, Matthias; Duffy, John; Schram, Arthur</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Taxes Shape an Industry? Evidence from the Implementation of the "Amazon Tax"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baugh, Brian; Ben-David, Itzhak; Park, Hoonsuk
For years, online retailers have maintained a price advantage over brick-and-mortar retailers by not collecting sales tax at the time of sale. Recently, several states have required that online retailer Amazon collect sales tax during checkout. Using transaction-level data, we document that households living in these states reduced their Amazon purchases by 9.4% following the implementation of the sales tax laws, implying elasticities of -1.2 to -1.4. The effect is stronger for large purchases, where purchases declined by 29.1%, corresponding to an elasticity of -3.9. Studying competitors in the electronics field, we find some evidence of substitution toward competing retailers.</description><author>Baugh, Brian; Ben-David, Itzhak; Park, Hoonsuk</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Networks in Production: Asset Pricing Implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herskovic, Bernard
In this paper, I examine asset pricing in a multisector model with sectors connected through an input-output network. Changes in the network are sources of systematic risk reflected in equilibrium asset prices. Two characteristics of the network matter for asset prices: network concentration and network sparsity. These two production-based asset pricing factors are determined by the structure of the network and are computed from input-output data. Consistent with the model predictions, I find return spreads of 4.6% and -3.2% per year on sparsity and concentration beta-sorted portfolios, respectively.</description><author>Herskovic, Bernard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating Private Equity Returns from Limited Partner Cash Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Chen, Bingxu; Goetzmann, William N.; Phalippou, Ludovic
We introduce a methodology to estimate the historical time series of returns to investment in private equity funds. The approach requires only an unbalanced panel of cash contributions and distributions accruing to limited partners and is robust to sparse data. We decompose private equity returns from 1994 to 2015 into a component due to traded factors and a time-varying private equity premium not spanned by publicly traded factors. We find cyclicality in private equity returns that differs according to fund type and is consistent with the conjecture that capital market segmentation contributes to private equity returns.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Chen, Bingxu; Goetzmann, William N.; Phalippou, Ludovic</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiently Inefficient Markets for Assets and Asset Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garleanu, Nicolae; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
We consider a model where investors can invest directly or search for an asset manager, information about assets is costly, and managers charge an endogenous fee. The efficiency of asset prices is linked to the efficiency of the asset management market: if investors can find managers more easily, more money is allocated to active management, fees are lower, and asset prices are more efficient. Informed managers outperform after fees, uninformed managers underperform, while the average manager's performance depends on the number of "noise allocators." Small investors should remain uninformed, but large and sophisticated investors benefit from searching for informed active managers since their search cost is low relative to capital. Hence, managers with larger and more sophisticated investors are expected to outperform.</description><author>Garleanu, Nicolae; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Commitment and Illiquidity in Corporate Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Jacobsen, Stacey; Maxwell, William; Venkataraman, Kumar
We study trading costs and dealer behavior in U.S. corporate bond markets from 2006 to 2016. Despite a temporary spike during the financial crisis, average trade execution costs have not increased notably over time. However, dealer capital commitment, turnover, block trade frequency, and average trade size decreased during the financial crisis and thereafter. These declines are attributable to bank-affiliated dealers, as nonbank dealers have increased their market commitment. Our evidence indicates that liquidity provision in the corporate bond markets is evolving away from the commitment of bank-affiliated dealer capital to absorb customer imbalances, and that postcrisis banking regulations likely contribute.</description><author>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Jacobsen, Stacey; Maxwell, William; Venkataraman, Kumar</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Tough Act to Follow: Contrast Effects in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Shue, Kelly
A contrast effect occurs when the value of a previously observed signal inversely biases perception of the next signal. We present the first evidence that contrast effects can distort prices in sophisticated and liquid markets. Investors mistakenly perceive earnings news today as more impressive if yesterday's earnings surprise was bad and less impressive if yesterday's surprise was good. A unique advantage of our financial setting is that we can identify contrast effects as an error in perceptions rather than expectations. Finally, we show that our results cannot be explained by an alternative explanation involving information transmission from previous earnings announcements.</description><author>Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Shue, Kelly</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticompetitive Effects of Common Ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Azar, Jose; Schmalz, Martin C.; Tecu, Isabel
Many natural competitors are jointly held by a small set of large institutional investors. In the U.S. airline industry, taking common ownership into account implies increases in market concentration that are 10 times larger than what is "presumed likely to enhance market power" by antitrust authorities. Within-route changes in common ownership concentration robustly correlate with route-level changes in ticket prices, even when we only use variation in ownership due to the combination of two large asset managers. We conclude that a hidden social cost-reduced product market competition-accompanies the private benefits of diversification and good governance.</description><author>Azar, Jose; Schmalz, Martin C.; Tecu, Isabel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quid Pro Quo? What Factors Influence IPO Allocations to Investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jenkinson, Tim; Jones, Howard; Suntheim, Felix
Using data from all of the leading international investment banks on 220 initial public offerings (IPOs) raising $160 billion between January 2010 and May 2015, we test the determinants of IPO allocations. We compare investors' IPO allocations with proxies for their information production during bookbuilding and the broking (and other) revenues they generate for bookrunners. We find evidence consistent with information revelation theories. We also find strong support for the existence of a quid pro quo whereby broking revenues are a significant determinant of investors' IPO allocations and profits. The quid pro quo remains when we control for unobserved investor characteristics and investor-bank relationships.</description><author>Jenkinson, Tim; Jones, Howard; Suntheim, Felix</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional and Legal Context in Natural Experiments: The Case of State Antitakeover Laws</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Wittry, Michael D.
We argue and demonstrate empirically that a firm's institutional and legal context has first-order effects in tests that use state antitakeover laws for identification. A priori, the size and direction of a law's effect on a firm's takeover protection depends on (i) other state antitakeover laws, (ii) preexisting firm-level takeover defenses, and (iii) the legal regime as reflected by important court decisions. In addition, (iv) state antitakeover laws are not exogenous for many easily identifiable firms. We show that the inferences from nine prior studies related to nine different outcome variables change substantially when we include controls for these considerations.</description><author>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Wittry, Michael D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unshrouding: Evidence from Bank Overdrafts in Turkey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alan, Sule; Cemalcilar, Mehmet; Karlan, Dean; Zinman, Jonathan
Lower prices produce higher demand... or do they? A bank's direct marketing to holders of free checking accounts shows that a large discount on 60% APR overdrafts reduces overdraft usage, especially when bundled with a discount on debit card or autodebit transactions. In contrast, messages mentioning overdraft availability without mentioning price increase usage. Neither change persists long after the messages stop. These results do not square easily with classical models of consumer choice and firm competition. Instead, they support behavioral models where consumers underestimate and are inattentive to overdraft costs, and firms respond by shrouding overdraft prices in equilibrium.</description><author>Alan, Sule; Cemalcilar, Mehmet; Karlan, Dean; Zinman, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Financing Constraints Affect Firms' Equity Volatility?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carvalho, Daniel
Theory suggests that financing frictions can have significant implications for equity volatility by shaping firms' exposure to economic risks. This paper provides evidence that an important determinant of higher equity volatility among research and development (R&amp;D)-intensive firms is fewer financing constraints on firms' ability to access growth options. I provide evidence for this effect by studying how persistent shocks to the value of firms' tangible assets (real estate) affect their subsequent equity volatility. The analysis addresses concerns about the identification of these balance sheet effects and shows that these effects are consistent with broader patterns on the equity volatility of R&amp;D-intensive firms.</description><author>Carvalho, Daniel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Options Models of the Firm, Capacity Overhang, and the Cross Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aretz, Kevin; Pope, Peter F.
We use a stochastic frontier model to obtain a stock-level estimate of thedifferencebetweenafirm's installed production capacity and its optimal capacity. We show that this "capacity overhang" estimate relates significantly negatively to the cross section of stock returns, even when controlling for popular pricing factors. The negative relation persists among small and largestocks,stockswith more or less reversible investments, and in good and bad economic states. Capacity overhang helps explain momentum and profitability anomalies, but not value and investment anomalies. Our evidence supports real options models of the firm featuring valuable divestment options.</description><author>Aretz, Kevin; Pope, Peter F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Proprietary Trading Detrimental to Retail Investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fecht, Falko; Hackethal, Andreas; Karabulut, Yigitcan
We study the conflict of interest that arises when a universal bank conducts proprietary trading alongside its retail banking services. Our data set contains the stock holdings of every German bank and those of their corresponding retail clients. We investigate (i) whether banks sell stocks from their proprietary portfolios to their retail customers, (ii) whether those stocks subsequently underperform, and (iii) whether retail customers of banks engaging in proprietary trading earn lower portfolio returns than their peers. We present affirmative evidence for all three questions and conclude that proprietary trading can, in fact, be detrimental to retail investors.</description><author>Fecht, Falko; Hackethal, Andreas; Karabulut, Yigitcan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Margin Requirements and the Security Market Line</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jylhae, Petri
Between 1934 and 1974, the Federal Reserve changed the initial margin requirement for the U.S. stock market 22 times. I use this variation to show that investors' leverage constraints affect the pricing of risk. Consistent with earlier theoretical predictions, I find that tighter leverage constraints result in a flatter relation between betas and expected returns. My results provide strong empirical support for the idea that the constraints investors face may help explain the empirical failure of the capital asset pricing model.</description><author>Jylhae, Petri</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Belief Dispersion in the Stock Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atmaz, Adem; Basak, Suleyman
We develop a dynamic model of belief dispersion with a continuum of investors differing in beliefs. The model is tractable and qualitatively matches many of the empirical regularities in a stock price and its mean return, volatility, and trading volume. We find that the stock price is convex in cash-flow news and increases in belief dispersion, while its mean return decreases when the view on the stock is optimistic, and vice versa when pessimistic. Moreover, belief dispersion leads to higher stock volatility and trading volume. We demonstrate that otherwise identical two-investor heterogeneous-beliefs economies do not necessarily generate our main results.</description><author>Atmaz, Adem; Basak, Suleyman</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interpreting Factor Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kozak, Serhiy; Nagel, Stefan; Santosh, Shrihari
We argue that tests of reduced-form factor models and horse races between characteristics and covariances cannot discriminate between alternative models of investor beliefs. Since asset returns have substantial commonality, absence of near-arbitrage opportunities implies that the stochastic discount factor can be represented as a function of a few dominant sources of return variation. As long as some arbitrageurs are present, this conclusion applies even in an economy in which all cross-sectional variation in expected returns is caused by sentiment. Sentiment-investor demand results in substantial mispricing only if arbitrageurs are exposed to factor risk when taking the other side of these trades.</description><author>Kozak, Serhiy; Nagel, Stefan; Santosh, Shrihari</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Makes a Good Trader? On the Role of Intuition and Reflection on Trader Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corgnet, Brice; Desantis, Mark; Porter, David
Using laboratory experiments, we provide evidence on three factors influencing trader performance: fluid intelligence, cognitive reflection, and theory of mind (ToM). Fluid intelligence provides traders with computational skills necessary to draw a statistical inference. Cognitive reflection helps traders avoid behavioral biases and thereby extract signals from market orders and update their prior beliefs accordingly. ToM describes the degree to which traders correctly assess the informational content of orders. We show that cognitive reflection and ToM are complementary because traders benefit from understanding signals' quality only if they are capable of processing these signals.</description><author>Corgnet, Brice; Desantis, Mark; Porter, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Higher Order Effects in Asset Pricing Models with Long-Run Risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pohl, Walter; Schmedders, Karl; Wilms, Ole
This paper shows that the latest generation of asset pricing models with long-run risk exhibit economically significant nonlinearities, and thus the ubiquitous Campbell-Shiller log-linearization can generate large numerical errors. These errors translate in turn to considerable errors in the model predictions, for example, for the magnitude of the equity premium or return predictability. We demonstrate that these nonlinearities arise from the presence of multiple highly persistent processes, which cause the exogenous states to attain values far away from their long-run means with nonnegligible probability. These extreme values have a significant impact on asset price dynamics.</description><author>Pohl, Walter; Schmedders, Karl; Wilms, Ole</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Fed, the Bond Market, and Gradualism in Monetary Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stein, Jeremy C.; Sunderam, Adi
We develop a model of monetary policy with two key features: the central bank has private information about its long-run target rate and is averse to bond market volatility. In this setting, the central bank gradually impounds changes in its target into the policy rate. Such gradualism represents an attempt to not spook the bond market. However, this effort is partially undone in equilibrium, as markets rationally react more to a given move when the central bank moves more gradually. This time-consistency problem means that society would be better off if the central bank cared less about the bond market.</description><author>Stein, Jeremy C.; Sunderam, Adi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Sell-Side Research More Valuable in Bad Times?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loh, Roger K.; Stulz, Rene M.
Because uncertainty is high in bad times, investors find it harder to assess firm prospects and hence should value analyst output more. However, higher uncertainty makes analysts' tasks harder, so it is unclear whether analyst output is more valuable in bad times. We find that in bad times, analyst revisions have a larger stock-price impact, earnings forecast errors per unit of uncertainty fall, and analyst reports are more frequent and longer. The increased impact of analysts is also more pronounced for harder-to-value firms. These results are consistent with analysts working harder and investors relying more on analysts in bad times.</description><author>Loh, Roger K.; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Mispricing around Nontrading Periods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Christopher S.; Shemesh, Joshua
We find that option returns are significantly lower over nontrading periods, the vast majority of which are weekends. Our evidence suggests that nontrading returns cannot be explained by risk, but rather are the result of widespread and highly persistent option mispricing driven by the incorrect treatment of stock return variance during periods of market closure. The size of the effect implies that the broad spectrum of finance research involving option prices should account for nontrading effects. Our study further suggests how alternative industry practices could improve the efficiency of option markets in a meaningful way.</description><author>Jones, Christopher S.; Shemesh, Joshua</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Literacy and Portfolio Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bianchi, Milo
We match administrative panel data on portfolio choices with survey measures of financial literacy. When we control for portfolio risk, the most literate households experience 0.4% higher annual returns than the least literate households. Distinct portfolio dynamics are the key determinant of this difference. More literate households hold riskier positions when expected returns are higher, they more actively rebalance their portfolios and do so in a way that holds their risk exposure relatively constant over time, and they are more likely to buy assets that provide higher returns than the assets that they sell.</description><author>Bianchi, Milo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Capital and Lending Relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, Michael
This paper investigates the mechanisms behind the matching of banks and firms in the loan market and the implications of this matching for lending relationships, bank capital, and credit provision. I find that bank-dependent firms borrow from well-capitalized banks, while firms with access to the bond market borrow from banks with less capital. This matching of bank-dependent firms with stable banks smooths cyclicality in aggregate credit provision and mitigates the effects of bank shocks on the real economy.</description><author>Schwert, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Selling Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engelberg, Joseph E.; Reed, Adam V.; Ringgenberg, Matthew C.
Short sellers face unique risks, such as the risk that stock loans become expensive and the risk that stock loans are recalled. We show that short-selling risk affects prices among the cross-section of stocks. Stocks with more short-selling risk have lower returns, less price efficiency, and less short selling.</description><author>Engelberg, Joseph E.; Reed, Adam V.; Ringgenberg, Matthew C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparing Asset Pricing Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barillas, Francisco; Shanken, Jay
A Bayesian asset pricing test is derived that is easily computed in closed form from the standard F-statistic. Given a set of candidate traded factors, we develop a related test procedure that permits the computation of model probabilities for the collection of all possible pricing models that are based on subsets of the given factors. We find that the recent models of Hou, Xue, and Zhang (2015a, 2015b) and Fama and French (2015, 2016) are dominated by a variety of models that include a momentum factor, along with value and profitability factors that are updated monthly.</description><author>Barillas, Francisco; Shanken, Jay</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity as Social Expertise</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kurlat, Pablo
This paper proposes a theory of liquidity dynamics. Illiquidity results from asymmetric information. Observing the historical track record teaches agents how to interpret public information and helps overcome information asymmetry. However, an illiquidity trap can arise: too much asymmetric information leads to the breakdown of trade, which interrupts learning and perpetuates illiquidity. Liquidity falls in response to unexpected events that lead agents to question their valuation models (especially in newer markets) may be slow to recover after a crisis, and is higher in periods of stability.</description><author>Kurlat, Pablo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wholesale Funding Dry-Ups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perignon, Christophe; Thesmar, David; Vuillemey, Guillaume
We empirically explore the fragility of wholesale funding of banks, using transaction-level data on short-term, unsecured certificates of deposit in the European market. We do not observe a market-wide freeze during the 2008 to 2014 period. Yet, many banks suddenly experience funding dry-ups. Dry-ups predict, but do not cause, future deterioration in bank performance. Furthermore, during periods of market stress, banks with high future performance tend to increase reliance on wholesale funding. We therefore fail to find evidence consistent with adverse selection models of funding market freezes. Our evidence is in line with theories highlighting heterogeneity between informed and uninformed lenders.</description><author>Perignon, Christophe; Thesmar, David; Vuillemey, Guillaume</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Homeowner Borrowing and Housing Collateral: New Evidence from Expiring Price Controls</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Defusco, Anthony A.
I empirically analyze how changes in access to housing collateral affect homeowner borrowing behavior. To isolate the role of collateral constraints from that of wealth effects, I exploit the fully anticipated expiration of resale price controls on owner-occupied housing in Montgomery County, Maryland. I estimate a marginal propensity to borrow out of housing collateral that ranges between $0.04 and $0.13 and is correlated with homeowners' initial leverage. Additional analysis of residential investment and ex-post loan performance indicates that some of the extracted funds generated new expenditures. These results suggest a potentially important role for collateral constraints in driving household expenditures.</description><author>Defusco, Anthony A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Influencing Control: Jawboning in Risk Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Wei; Li, Tao; Mei, Danqing
In an "activist risk arbitrage," a shareholder attempts to improve terms of an announced M&amp;A through public campaigns. Activists target deals with low premiums and those susceptible to managerial conflicts of interest, including going-private deals and deals in which CEOs receive outsized payments. Activist arbitrageurs are associated with a significant decrease in the probability that targets will be sold to the announced bidders, and an increase in the premium paid, both ex post among surviving deals and ex ante among all deals. Activist arbitrage serves as a governance mechanism in M&amp;A and earns higher returns than passive arbitrage.</description><author>Jiang, Wei; Li, Tao; Mei, Danqing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do ETFs Increase Volatility?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-David, Itzhak; Franzoni, Francesco; Moussawi, Rabih
Due to their low trading costs, exchange-traded funds (ETFs) are a potential catalyst for short-horizon liquidity traders. The liquidity shocks can propagate to the underlying securities through the arbitrage channel, and ETFs may increase the nonfundamental volatility of the securities in their baskets. We exploit exogenous changes in index membership and find that stocks with higher ETF ownership display significantly higher volatility. ETF ownership increases the negative autocorrelation in stock prices. The increase in volatility appears to introduce undiversifiable risk in prices because stocks with high ETF ownership earn a significant risk premium of up to 56 basis points monthly.</description><author>Ben-David, Itzhak; Franzoni, Francesco; Moussawi, Rabih</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unscheduled News and Market Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dugast, Jerome
When unscheduled news arrives, investors react with a stochastic delay yet still may exploit new information. In this context, I study the equilibrium dynamics of limit order markets. Continuous idiosyncratic liquidity shocks result in trades on both sides of the order book. News therefore arrives at random times. Following news, order flows become unbalanced and market depth is consumed, leading to positive covariance between price variability, trading volume, and order book unbalances. Holding the unconditional price variability constant, news frequency has a negative effect on both market depth and the variability-volume covariance.</description><author>Dugast, Jerome</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arrested Development: Theory and Evidence of Supply-Side Speculation in the Housing Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nathanson, Charles G.; Zwick, Eric
This paper studies the role of disagreement in amplifying housing cycles. Speculation is easier in the land market than in the housing market due to frictions that make renting less efficient than owner-occupancy. As a result, undeveloped land facilitates construction and intensifies the speculation that causes booms and busts in house prices. This observation challenges the standard intuition that in cities where construction is easier, house price booms are smaller. It can also explain why the largest house price booms in the United States between 2000 and 2006 occurred in areas with elastic housing supply.</description><author>Nathanson, Charles G.; Zwick, Eric</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Politics of Foreclosures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Amromin, Gene; Ben-David, Itzhak; Dinc, Serdar
The U.S. House of Representatives Financial Services Committee considered many important banking reforms in 2009 to 2010. We show that, during this period, foreclosure starts on delinquent mortgages were delayed in the districts of committee members although there was no difference in delinquency rates between committee and noncommittee districts. In these areas, banks delayed the foreclosure starts by 0.5 months (relative to the 12-month average). The estimated cost of delay to lenders is an order of magnitude greater than the campaign contributions by the political action committees of the largest mortgage servicing banks to the committee members in that period.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Amromin, Gene; Ben-David, Itzhak; Dinc, Serdar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency Risk Factors in a Recursive Multicountry Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colacito, Ric; Croce, Mariano M.; Gavazzoni, Federico; Ready, Robert
Focusing on the 10 most traded currencies, we provide empirical evidence regarding a significant heterogeneous exposure to global growth news shocks. We incorporate this empirical fact in a frictionless risk-sharing model with recursive preferences, multiple countries, and multiple consumption goods whose supply features both global and local short- and long-run shocks. Since news shocks are priced, heterogeneous exposure to long-lasting global growth shocks results in a relevant reallocation of international resources and currency adjustments. Our unified framework replicates the properties of the HML-FX and HML-NFA carry-trade strategies studied by Lustig, Roussanov, and Verdelhan and Della Corte, Riddiough, and Sarno.</description><author>Colacito, Ric; Croce, Mariano M.; Gavazzoni, Federico; Ready, Robert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral Constraints and the Law of One Price: An Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cipriani, Marco; Fostel, Ana; Houser, Daniel
We test the asset pricing implications of collateralized borrowing (that is, of using assets as collateral to borrow money) in the laboratory. To this purpose, we develop a general equilibrium model with collateral constraints amenable to laboratory implementation and gather experimental data. In the laboratory, assets that can be leveraged fetch higher prices than assets that cannot, even though assets' payoffs are identical in all states of the world. Collateral value, therefore, creates deviations from the Law of One Price. The spread between collateralizeable and noncollateralizeable assets is significant and quantitatively close to theoretical predictions.</description><author>Cipriani, Marco; Fostel, Ana; Houser, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Bank Credit on Labor Reallocation and Aggregate Industry Productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, John; Carvalho, Daniel; Phillips, Gordon M.
We provide evidence that the deregulation of U.S. state banking markets leads to a significant increase in the relative employment and capital growth of local firms with higher productivity, and that this effect is concentrated among young firms. Using financial data for a broad range of firms, our analysis suggests that this effect is driven by a shift in the composition of local bank credit supply toward more productive firms. We estimate that this effect translates into economically important gains in aggregate industry productivity and that changes in the allocation of labor play a central role in driving these gains.</description><author>Bai, John; Carvalho, Daniel; Phillips, Gordon M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Noncognitive Abilities and Financial Delinquency: The Role of Self-Efficacy in Avoiding Financial Distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuhnen, Camelia M.; Melzer, Brian T.
We investigate a novel determinant of financial distress, namely, individuals' self-efficacy, or belief that their actions can influence the future. Individuals with high self-efficacy are more likely to take precautions that mitigate adverse financial shocks. They are subsequently less likely to default on their debt and bill payments, especially after experiencing negative shocks such as job loss or illness. Thus, noncognitive abilities are an important determinant of financial fragility and subjective expectations are an important factor in household financial decisions.</description><author>Kuhnen, Camelia M.; Melzer, Brian T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sensation Seeking and Hedge Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Stephen; Lu, Yan; Ray, Sugata; Teo, Melvyn
We show that, motivated by sensation seeking, hedge fund managers who own powerful sports cars take on more investment risk but do not deliver higher returns, resulting in lower Sharpe ratios, information ratios, and alphas. Moreover, sensation-seeking managers trade more frequently, actively, and unconventionally, and prefer lottery-like stocks. We show further that some investors are themselves susceptible to sensation seeking and that sensation-seeking investors fuel the demand for sensation-seeking managers. While investors perceive sensation seekers to be less competent, they do not fully appreciate the superior investment skills of sensation-avoiding fund managers.</description><author>Brown, Stephen; Lu, Yan; Ray, Sugata; Teo, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor Control Rights and Board Independence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Daniel; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Mariano, Beatriz
We find that the number of independent directors on corporate boards increases by approximately 24% following financial covenant violations in credit agreements. Most of these new directors have links to creditors. Firms that appoint new directors after violations are more likely to issue new equity, and to decrease payout, operational risk, and CEO cash compensation, than firms without such appointments. We conclude that a firm's board composition, governance, and policies are shaped by current and past credit agreements.</description><author>Ferreira, Daniel; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Mariano, Beatriz</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Fraud Contagious? Coworker Influence on Misconduct by Financial Advisors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimmock, Stephen G.; Gerken, William C.; Graham, Nathaniel P.
Using a novel data set of U.S. financial advisors that includes individuals' employment histories and misconduct records, we show that coworkers influence an individual's propensity to commit financial misconduct. We identify coworkers' effect on misconduct using changes in coworkers caused by mergers of financial advisory firms. The tests include merger-firm fixed effects to exploit the variation in changes to coworkers across branches of the same firm. The probability of an advisor committing misconduct increases if his new coworkers, encountered in the merger, have a history of misconduct. This effect is stronger between demographically similar coworkers.</description><author>Dimmock, Stephen G.; Gerken, William C.; Graham, Nathaniel P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deviations from Covered Interest Rate Parity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Wenxin; Tepper, Alexander; Verdelhan, Adrien
We find that deviations from the covered interest rate parity (CIP) condition imply large, persistent, and systematic arbitrage opportunities in one of the largest asset markets in the world. Contrary to the common view, these deviations for major currencies are not explained away by credit risk or transaction costs. They are particularly strong for forward contracts that appear on banks' balance sheets at the end of the quarter, pointing to a causal effect of banking regulation on asset prices. The CIP deviations also appear significantly correlated with other fixed income spreads and with nominal interest rates.</description><author>Du, Wenxin; Tepper, Alexander; Verdelhan, Adrien</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Dividend Profitability and Institutional Trading Skill</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henry, Tyler R.; Koski, Jennifer L.
We use institutional trading data to examine whether skilled institutions exploit positive abnormal ex-dividend returns. Results show that institutions concentrate trading around certain ex-dates, and earn higher profits around these events. Dividend capture trades represent 6% of all institutional buy trades but contribute 15% of overall abnormal returns. Institutional dividend capture trading is persistent. Institutional ex-day profitability is also strongly cross-sectionally related to trade execution skill. The relation between execution skill and profits disappears around placebo non-ex-days. Results suggest that skilled institutions target certain opportunities rather than benefiting uniformly over time. Furthermore, only skilled institutions can profit from dividend capture.</description><author>Henry, Tyler R.; Koski, Jennifer L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing with Countercyclical Household Consumption Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Constantinides, George M.; Ghosh, Anisha
We show that shocks to household consumption growth are negatively skewed, persistent, countercyclical, and drive asset prices. We construct a parsimonious model where heterogeneous households have recursive preferences. A single state variable drives the conditional cross-sectional moments of household consumption growth. The estimated model fits well the unconditional cross-sectional moments of household consumption growth and the moments of the risk-free rate, equity premium, price-dividend ratio, and aggregate dividend and consumption growth. The model-implied risk-free rate and price-dividend ratio are procyclical, while the market return has countercyclical mean and variance. Finally, household consumption risk explains the cross section of excess returns.</description><author>Constantinides, George M.; Ghosh, Anisha</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buyout Activity: The Impact of Aggregate Discount Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haddad, Valentin; Loualiche, Erik; Plosser, Matthew
Buyout booms form in response to declines in the aggregate risk premium. We document that the equity risk premium is the primary determinant of buyout activity rather than credit-specific conditions. We articulate a simple explanation for this phenomenon: a low risk premium increases the present value of performance gains and decreases the cost of holding an illiquid investment. A panel of U.S. buyouts confirms this view. The risk premium shapes changes in buyout characteristics over the cycle, including their riskiness, leverage, and performance. Our results underscore the importance of the risk premium in corporate finance decisions.</description><author>Haddad, Valentin; Loualiche, Erik; Plosser, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Risk, Local Factors, and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tuzel, Selale; Zhang, Miao Ben
Firm location affects firm risk through local factor prices. We find more procyclical factor prices such as wages and real estate prices in areas with more cyclical economies, namely, high "local beta" areas. While procyclical wages provide a natural hedge against aggregate shocks and reduce firm risk, procyclical prices of real estate, which are part of firm assets, increase firm risk. We confirm that firms located in higher local beta areas have lower industry-adjusted returns and conditional betas, and show that the effect is stronger among firms with low real estate holdings. A production-based equilibrium model explains these empirical findings.</description><author>Tuzel, Selale; Zhang, Miao Ben</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Contracting and Organizational Form: Evidence from the Regulation of Trade Credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breza, Emily; Liberman, Andres
We present evidence that restrictions to the set of feasible financial contracts affect buyer-supplier relationships and the organizational form of the firm. We exploit a regulation that restricted the maturity of the trade credit contracts that a large retailer could sign with some of its small suppliers. Using a within-product difference-indifferences identification strategy, we find that the restriction reduces the likelihood of trade by 11%. The retailer also responds by internalizing procurement to its own subsidiaries and reducing overall purchases. Finally, we find that relational contracts can mitigate the inability to extend long trade credit terms.</description><author>Breza, Emily; Liberman, Andres</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resident Networks and Corporate Connections: Evidence from World War II Internment Camps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren; Gurun, Umit G.; Malloy, Christopher
Using customs and port authority data, we show that firms are significantly more likely to trade with countries that have a large resident population near their firm headquarters, and that these connected trades are their most valuable international trades. Using the formation of World War II Japanese internment camps to isolate exogenous shocks to local ethnic populations, we identify a causal link between local networks and firm trade. Firms are also more likely to acquire target firms, and report increased segment sales, in connected countries. Our results point to a surprisingly large role of immigrants as economic conduits for firms.</description><author>Cohen, Lauren; Gurun, Umit G.; Malloy, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Formative Experiences and Portfolio Choice: Evidence from the Finnish Great Depression</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knupfer, Samuli; Rantapuska, Elias; Sarvimaki, Matti
We trace the impact of formative experiences on portfolio choice. Plausibly exogenous variation in workers' exposure to a depression allows us to identify the effects and a new estimation approach makes addressing wealth and income effects possible. We find that adversely affected workers are less likely to invest in risky assets. This result is robust to a number of control variables and it holds for individuals whose income, employment, and wealth were unaffected. The effects travel through social networks: individuals whose neighbors and family members experienced adverse circumstances also avoid risky investments.</description><author>Knupfer, Samuli; Rantapuska, Elias; Sarvimaki, Matti</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing without Garbage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kroencke, Tim A.
This paper provides an explanation for why garbage implies a much lower relative risk aversion in the consumption-based asset pricing model than National Income and Product Accounts (NIPA) consumption expenditure: Unlike garbage, NIPA consumption is filtered to mitigate measurement error. I apply a simple model of the filtering process that allows one to undo the filtering inherent in NIPA consumption. "Unfiltered NIPA consumption" well explains the equity premium and is priced in the cross-section of stock returns. I discuss the likely properties of true consumption (i.e., without measurement error and filtering) and quantify implications for habit and long-run risk models.</description><author>Kroencke, Tim A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Are the Value and Growth Investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Betermier, Sebastien; Calvet, Laurent E.; Sodini, Paolo
This paper investigates value and growth investing in a large administrative panel of Swedish residents. We show that, over the life cycle, households progressively shift from growth to value as they become older and their balance sheets improve. Furthermore, investors with high human capital and high exposure to macroeconomic risk tilt their portfolios away from value. While several behavioral biases seem evident in the data, the patterns we uncover are overall remarkably consistent with the portfolio implications of risk-based theories of the value premium.</description><author>Betermier, Sebastien; Calvet, Laurent E.; Sodini, Paolo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selling Failed Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Granja, Joao; Matvos, Gregor; Seru, Amit
The average FDIC loss from selling a failed bank is 28% of assets. We document that failed banks are predominantly sold to bidders within the same county, with similar assets business lines, when these bidders are well capitalized. Otherwise, they are acquired by less similar banks located further away. We interpret these facts within a model of auctions with budget constraints, in which poor capitalization of some potential acquirers drives a wedge between their willingness and ability to pay for failed banks. We document that this wedge drives misallocation, and partially explains the FDIC losses from failed bank sales.</description><author>Granja, Joao; Matvos, Gregor; Seru, Amit</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advance Refundings of Municipal Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Green, Richard C.; Longstaff, Francis A.; Xing, Yuhang
The advance refunding of debt is a widespread practice in municipal finance. In an advance refunding, municipalities retire callable bonds early and refund them with bonds with lower coupon rates. We find that 85% of all advance refundings occur at a net present value loss, and that the aggregate losses over the past 20 years exceed $15 billion. We explore why municipalities advance refund their debt at loss. Financially constrained municipalities may face pressure to advance refund since it allows them to reduce short-term cash outflows. We find strong evidence that financial constraints are a major driver of advance refunding activity.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Green, Richard C.; Longstaff, Francis A.; Xing, Yuhang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trader Leverage and Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahraman, Bige; Tookes, Heather E.
Does trader leverage drive equity market liquidity? We use the unique features of the margin trading system in India to identify a causal relationship between traders' ability to borrow and a stock's market liquidity. To quantify the impact of trader leverage, we employ a regression discontinuity design that exploits threshold rules that determine a stock's margin trading eligibility. We find that liquidity is higher when stocks become eligible formargin trading and that this liquidity enhancement is driven by margin traders' contrarian strategies. Consistent with downward liquidity spirals due to deleveraging, we also find that this effect reverses during crises.</description><author>Kahraman, Bige; Tookes, Heather E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retail Financial Advice: Does One Size Fit All?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foerster, Stephen; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Melzer, Brian T.; Previtero, Alessandro
Using unique data on Canadian households, we show that financial advisors exert substantial influence over their clients' asset allocation, but provide limited customization. Advisor fixed effects explain considerably more variation in portfolio risk and home bias than a broad set of investor attributes that includes risk tolerance, age, investment horizon, and financial sophistication. Advisor effects remain important even when controlling flexibly for unobserved heterogeneity through investor fixed effects. An advisor's own asset allocation strongly predicts the allocations chosen on clients' behalf. This one-size-fits-all advice does not come cheap: advised portfolios cost 2.5% per year, or 1.5% more than life cycle funds.</description><author>Foerster, Stephen; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Melzer, Brian T.; Previtero, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Default, Credit Reporting, and Borrowing Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, Mark J.; Natividad, Gabriel
Why do negative credit events lead to long-term borrowing constraints? Exploiting banking regulations in Peru and utilizing currency movements, we show that consumers who face a credit rating downgrade due to bad luck experience a three-year reduction in financing. Consumers respond to the shock by paying down their most troubled loans, but nonetheless end up more likely to exit the credit market. For a set of borrowers who experience severe delinquency, we find that the associated credit reporting downgrade itself accounts for 25% to 65% of their observed decline in borrowing at various horizons over the following several years.</description><author>Garmaise, Mark J.; Natividad, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Drives the Cross-Section of Credit Spreads?: A Variance Decomposition Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nozawa, Yoshio
I decompose the variation of credit spreads for corporate bonds into changing expected returns and changing expectation of credit losses. Using a log-linearized pricing identity and a vector autoregression applied to microlevel data from 1973 to 2011, I find that expected returns contribute to the cross-sectional variance of credit spreads nearly as much as expected credit loss does. However, most of the time-series variation in credit spreads for the market portfolio corresponds to risk premiums.</description><author>Nozawa, Yoshio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Account Liberalization and Aggregate Productivity: The Role of Firm Capital Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larrain, Mauricio; Stumpner, Sebastian
We study the effects of capital account liberalization on firm capital allocation and aggregate productivity in 10 Eastern European countries. Using a large firm-level data set, we show that capital account liberalization decreases the dispersion in the return to capital across firms, particularly in sectors more dependent on external finance. We provide evidence that capital account liberalization improves capital allocation by allowing financially constrained firms to demand more capital and produce at a more efficient level. Finally, using a model of misallocation we document that capital account liberalization increases aggregate productivity through more efficient capital allocation by 10% to 16%.</description><author>Larrain, Mauricio; Stumpner, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Editor of the Journal of Finance for the Year 2016</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagel, Stefan
nan</description><author>Nagel, Stefan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minutes of the 2017 Annual Membership Meeting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schallheim, Jim
nan</description><author>Schallheim, Jim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential Address: The Scientific Outlook in Financial Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harvey, Campbell R.
Given the competition for top journal space, there is an incentive to produce "significant" results. With the combination of unreported tests, lack of adjustment for multiple tests, and direct and indirect p-hacking, many of the results being published will fail to hold up in the future. In addition, there are basic issues with the interpretation of statistical significance. Increasing thresholds may be necessary, but still may not be sufficient: if the effect being studied is rare, even t &gt; 3 will produce a large number of false positives. Here I explore the meaning and limitations of a p-value. I offer a simple alternative (the minimum Bayes factor). I present guidelines for a robust, transparent research culture in financial economics. Finally, I offer some thoughts on the importance of risk-taking (from the perspective of authors and editors) to advance our field.</description><author>Harvey, Campbell R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Capital, Trust, and Firm Performance: The Value of Corporate Social Responsibility during the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lins, Karl V.; Servaes, Henri; Tamayo, Ane
During the 2008-2009 financial crisis, firms with high social capital, as measured by corporate social responsibility (CSR) intensity, had stock returns that were four to seven percentage points higher than firms with low social capital. High-CSR firms also experienced higher profitability, growth, and sales per employee relative to low-CSR firms, and they raised more debt. This evidence suggests that the trust between a firm and both its stakeholders and investors, built through investments in social capital, pays off when the overall level of trust in corporations and markets suffers a negative shock.</description><author>Lins, Karl V.; Servaes, Henri; Tamayo, Ane</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Municipal Bond Liquidity and Default Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, Michael
This paper examines the pricing of municipal bonds. I use three distinct, complementary approaches to decompose municipal bond spreads into default and liquidity components, and find that default risk accounts for 74% to 84% of the average spread after adjusting for tax-exempt status. The first approach estimates the liquidity component using transaction data, the second measures the default component with credit default swap data, and the third is a quasi-natural experiment that estimates changes in default risk around pre-refunding events. The price of default risk is high given the rare incidence of municipal default and implies a high risk premium.</description><author>Schwert, Michael</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility-Managed Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moreira, Alan; Muir, Tyler
Managed portfolios that take less risk when volatility is high produce large alphas, increase Sharpe ratios, and produce large utility gains for mean-variance investors. We document this for the market, value, momentum, profitability, return on equity, investment, and betting-against-beta factors, as well as the currency carry trade. Volatility timing increases Sharpe ratios because changes in volatility are not offset by proportional changes in expected returns. Our strategy is contrary to conventional wisdom because it takes relatively less risk in recessions. This rules out typical risk-based explanations and is a challenge to structural models of time-varying expected returns.</description><author>Moreira, Alan; Muir, Tyler</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term Structure of Consumption Risk Premia in the Cross Section of Currency Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zviadadze, Irina
I relate the downward-sloping term structure of currency carry returns to compensation for currency exposures to macroeconomic risk embedded in the joint dynamics of U.S. consumption, inflation, nominal interest rate, and their stochastic variance. The interest rate and inflation shocks play a prominent role. Higher yield currencies exhibit higher multiperiod exposures to these shocks. The prices of these risk exposures are positive and sizeable across all investment horizons. The interest rate shock is qualitatively similar to the long-run risk of Bansal and Yaron.</description><author>Zviadadze, Irina</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Funds Make More When They Trade More?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, Lubos; Stambaugh, Robert F.; Taylor, Lucian A.
We model fund turnover in the presence of time-varying profit opportunities. Our model predicts a positive relation between an active fund's turnover and its subsequent benchmark-adjusted return. We find such a relation for equity mutual funds. This time-series relation between turnover and performance is stronger than the cross-sectional relation, as the model predicts. Also as predicted, the turnover-performance relation is stronger for funds trading less-liquid stocks and funds likely to possess greater skill. Turnover is correlated across funds. The common component of turnover is positively correlated with proxies for stock mispricing. Turnover of similar funds helps predict a fund's performance.</description><author>Pastor, Lubos; Stambaugh, Robert F.; Taylor, Lucian A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Executive Secretary and Treasurer for the Fiscal Year Ending June 30, 2016</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schallheim, Jim
nan</description><author>Schallheim, Jim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Does Return Predictability Concentrate in Bad Times?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cujean, Julien; Hasler, Michael
We build an equilibrium model to explain why stock return predictability concentrates in bad times. The key feature is that investors use different forecasting models, and hence assess uncertainty differently. As economic conditions deteriorate, uncertainty rises and investors' opinions polarize. Disagreement thus spikes in bad times, causing returns to react to past news. This phenomenon creates a positive relation between disagreement and future returns. It also generates time-series momentum, which strengthens in bad times, increases with disagreement, and crashes after sharp market rebounds. We provide empirical support for these new predictions.</description><author>Cujean, Julien; Hasler, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Investors Hold Socially Responsible Mutual Funds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Riedl, Arno; Smeets, Paul
To understand why investors hold socially responsible mutual funds, we link administrative data to survey responses and behavior in incentivized experiments. We find that both social preferences and social signaling explain socially responsible investment (SRI) decisions. Financial motives play less of a role. Socially responsible investors in our sample expect to earn lower returns on SRI funds than on conventional funds and pay higher management fees. This suggests that investors are willing to forgo financial performance in order to invest in accordance with their social preferences.</description><author>Riedl, Arno; Smeets, Paul</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Matching Capital and Labor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berk, Jonathan B.; van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Liu, Binying
We establish an important role for the firm by studying capital reallocation decisions of mutual fund firms. The firm's decision to reallocate capital among its mutual fund managers adds at least $474,000 a month, which amounts to over 30% of the total value added of the industry. We provide evidence that this additional value added results from the firm's private information about the skill of its managers. The firm captures this value because investors reward the firm following a capital reallocation decision by allocating additional capital to the firm's funds.</description><author>Berk, Jonathan B.; van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Liu, Binying</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonfundamental Speculation Revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Liyan; Zhu, Haoxiang
We show that a linear pure strategy equilibrium may not exist in the model of Madrigal (1996), contrary to the claim of the original paper. This is because Madrigal's characterization of a pure strategy equilibrium omits a second-order condition. If the nonfundamental speculator's information about noise trading is sufficiently precise, a linear pure strategy equilibrium fails to exist. In parameter regions where a pure strategy equilibrium does exist, we identify a few calculation errors in Madrigal (1996) that result in misleading implications.</description><author>Yang, Liyan; Zhu, Haoxiang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Transaction Taxes, Market Composition, and Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colliard, Jean-Edouard; Hoffmann, Peter
We use the introduction of a financial transaction tax (FTT) in France in 2012 to test competing theories on its impact. We find no support for the idea that an FTT improves market quality by affecting the composition of trading volume. Instead, our results are in line with the hypothesis that a lower trading volume reduces liquidity and in turn market quality. Consistent with theories of asset pricing under transaction costs, we document a shift in security holdings from short-term to long-term investors. Finally, we find that moderate aggregate effects on market quality can mask large adjustments made by individual agents.</description><author>Colliard, Jean-Edouard; Hoffmann, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodity Trade and the Carry Trade: A Tale of Two Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ready, Robert; Roussanov, Nikolai; Ward, Colin
Persistent interest rate differentials account for much of the currency carry trade profitability. Commodity currencies offer high interest rates on average, while countries that export finished goods tend to have low interest rates. We develop a general equilibrium model of international trade and currency pricing where countries have an advantage in producing either basic inputs or final goods. In the model, domestic production insulates commodity-producing countries from global productivity shocks, forcing final-good producers to absorb them. Commodity-currency exchange rates and risk premia increase with productivity differentials and trade frictions. These predictions are strongly supported in the data.</description><author>Ready, Robert; Roussanov, Nikolai; Ward, Colin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are CDS Auctions Biased and Inefficient?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Songzi; Zhu, Haoxiang
We study the design of credit default swaps (CDS) auctions, which determine the payments by CDS sellers to CDS buyers following defaults of bonds. Using a simple model, we find that the current design of CDS auctions leads to biased prices and inefficient allocations. This is because various restrictions imposed in CDS auctions prevent certain investors from participating in the price discovery and allocation process. The imposition of a price cap or floor also gives dealers large influence on the final auction price. We propose an alternative double auction design that delivers more efficient price discovery and allocations.</description><author>Du, Songzi; Zhu, Haoxiang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Quasi-Random Option Grants Affect CEO Risk-Taking?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shue, Kelly; Townsend, Richard R.
We examine how an increase in stock option grants affects CEO risk-taking. The overall net effect of option grants is theoretically ambiguous for risk-averse CEOs. To overcome the endogeneity of option grants, we exploit institutional features of multiyear compensation plans, which generate two distinct types of variation in the timing of when large increases in new at-the-money options are granted. We find that, given average grant levels during our sample period, a 10% increase in new options granted leads to a 2.8% to 4.2% increase in equity volatility. This increase in risk is driven largely by increased leverage.</description><author>Shue, Kelly; Townsend, Richard R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Ruthlessness and Mortgage Default during the 2007 to 2009 Housing Bust</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhutta, Neil; Dokko, Jane; Shan, Hui
From 2007 to 2009 U.S. house prices plunged and mortgage defaults surged. While ostensibly consistent with widespread ruthless default, analysis of detailed mortgage and house price data indicates that borrowers do not walk away until they are deeply underwaterfar deeper than traditional models predict. The evidence suggests that lender recourse is not the major driver of this result. We argue that emotional and behavioral factors play an important role in decisions to continue paying. Borrower reluctance to walk away implies that the moral hazard cost of default as a form of social insurance may be lower than suspected.</description><author>Bhutta, Neil; Dokko, Jane; Shan, Hui</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Macroeconomics of Shadow Banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moreira, Alan; Savov, Alexi
We build a macrofinance model of shadow bankingthe transformation of risky assets into securities that are money-like in quiet times but become illiquid when uncertainty spikes. Shadow banking economizes on scarce collateral, expanding liquidity provision, boosting asset prices and growth, but also building up fragility. A rise in uncertainty raises shadow banking spreads, forcing financial institutions to switch to collateral-intensive funding. Shadow banking collapses, liquidity provision shrinks, liquidity premia and discount rates rise, asset prices and investment fall. The model generates slow recoveries, collateral runs, and flight-to-quality effects, and it sheds light on Large-Scale Asset Purchases, Operation Twist, and other interventions.</description><author>Moreira, Alan; Savov, Alexi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Cash Flows of Growth Stocks Really Grow Faster?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Huafeng
Contrary to conventional wisdom, growth stocks (i.e., low book-to-market stocks) do not have substantially higher future cash-flow growth rates than value stocks, in both rebalanced and buy-and-hold portfolios. Efficiency growth, survivorship and look-back biases, and the rebalancing effect help explain the results. These findings suggest that duration alone is unlikely to explain the value premium.</description><author>Chen, Huafeng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Origins of Risk-Taking in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Black, Sandra E.; Devereux, Paul J.; Lundborg, Petter; Majlesi, Kaveh
Financial investment behavior is highly correlated between parents and their children. Using Swedish data, we find that the decision of adoptees to hold equities is associated with the behavior of both biological and adoptive parents, implying a role for both genetic and environmental influences. However, we find that nurture has a stronger influence on the share of financial assets invested in equities and on portfolio volatility, suggesting that financial risk-taking is substantially environmentally determined. The parental investment variables substantially increase the explanatory power of cross-sectional regressions and so may play an important role in understanding cross-sectional heterogeneity in investment behavior.</description><author>Black, Sandra E.; Devereux, Paul J.; Lundborg, Petter; Majlesi, Kaveh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Investment and Stakeholder Choices: A Top-Down Theory of Capital Budgeting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almazan, Andres; Chen, Zhaohui; Titman, Sheridan
This paper develops a top-down model of capital budgeting in which privately informed executives make investment choices that convey information to the firm's stakeholders (e.g., employees). Favorable information in this setting encourages stakeholders to take actions that positively contribute to the firm's success (e.g., employees work harder). Within this framework we examine how firms may distort their investment choices to influence the information conveyed to stakeholders and show that investment rigidities and overinvestment can arise as optimal investment distortions. We also examine investment distortions in multi-divisional firms and compare such distortions to those in single-division firms.</description><author>Almazan, Andres; Chen, Zhaohui; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Labor Capital Asset Pricing Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuehn, Lars-Alexander; Simutin, Mikhail; Wang, Jessie Jiaxu
We show that labor search frictions are an important determinant of the cross-section of equity returns. Empirically, we find that firms with low loadings on labor market tightness outperform firms with high loadings by 6% annually. We propose a partial equilibrium labor market model in which heterogeneous firms make dynamic employment decisions under labor search frictions. In the model, loadings on labor market tightness proxy for priced time-variation in the efficiency of the aggregate matching technology. Firms with low loadings are more exposed to adverse matching efficiency shocks and require higher expected stock returns.</description><author>Kuehn, Lars-Alexander; Simutin, Mikhail; Wang, Jessie Jiaxu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Income Insurance and the Equilibrium Term Structure of Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marfe, Roberto
Output, wages, and dividends feature term structures of variance ratios that are respectively flat, increasing, and decreasing. Income insurance from shareholders to workers explains these term structures. Risk-sharing smooths wages but only concerns transitory risk and hence enhances short-run dividend risk. As a result, actual labor-share variation largely forecasts the risk, premium, and slope of dividend strips. A simple general equilibrium model in which labor rigidity affects dividend dynamics and the price of short-run risk reconciles standard asset pricing facts with the term structures of the equity premium, volatility, and macroeconomic variables, which are at odds in leading models.</description><author>Marfe, Roberto</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Benchmarks in Search Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffie, Darrell; Dworczak, Piotr; Zhu, Haoxiang
We characterize the role of benchmarks in price transparency of over-the-counter markets. A benchmark can raise social surplus by increasing the volume of beneficial trade, facilitating more efficient matching between dealers and customers, and reducing search costs. Although the market transparency promoted by benchmarks reduces dealers' profit margins, dealers may nonetheless introduce a benchmark to encourage greater market participation by investors. Low-cost dealers may also introduce a benchmark to increase their market share relative to high-cost dealers. We construct a revelation mechanism that maximizes welfare subject to search frictions, and show conditions under which it coincides with announcing the benchmark.</description><author>Duffie, Darrell; Dworczak, Piotr; Zhu, Haoxiang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Downside of Asset Screening for Market Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vanasco, Victoria
This paper explores the tension between asset quality and market liquidity. I model an originator who screens assets whose cash flows are later sold in secondary markets. Screening improves asset quality but gives rise to asymmetric information, hindering trade of the asset cash flows. In the optimal mechanism (second-best), costly retention of cash flows is essential to implement asset screening. Market allocations can feature too much or too little screening relative to second-best, where too much screening generates inefficiently illiquid markets. Furthermore, the economy is prone to multiple equilibria. The optimal mechanism is decentralized with two tools: retention rules and transfers.</description><author>Vanasco, Victoria</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Front Men of Wall Street: The Role of CDO Collateral Managers in the CDO Boom and Bust</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernenko, Sergey
I study the incentives of the collateral managers who selected securities for ABS CDOs-securitizations that figured prominently in the financial crisis. Specialized managers without other businesses that could suffer negative reputational consequences invested in low-quality securities underwritten by the CDO's arranger. These securities performed significantly worse than observationally similar securities. Managers investing in these securities were rewarded with additional collateral management assignments. Diversified managers who did assemble CDOs suffered negative reputational consequences during the crisis: institutional investors withdrew from their mutual funds. Overall, the results are consistent with a quid pro quo between collateral managers and CDO underwriters.</description><author>Chernenko, Sergey</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reverse Mortgage Loans: A Quantitative Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nakajima, Makoto; Telyukova, Irina A.
Reverse mortgage loans (RMLs) allow older homeowners to borrow against housing wealth without moving. Despite rapid growth in this market, only 1.9% of eligible homeowners had RMLs in 2013. In this paper, we analyze reverse mortgages in a calibrated life-cycle model of retirement. The average welfare gain from RMLs is $252 per homeowner, and $1,770 per RML borrower. Bequest motives, uncertainty about health and expenses, and loan costs account for low demand. According to the model, the Great Recession's impact differs across age, income, and wealth distributions, with a threefold increase in RML demand for lowest income and oldest households.</description><author>Nakajima, Makoto; Telyukova, Irina A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Precautionary Savings with Risky Assets: When Cash Is Not Cash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duchin, Ran; Gilbert, Thomas; Harford, Jarrad; Hrdlicka, Christopher
U.S. industrial firms invest heavily in noncash, risky financial assets such as corporate debt, equity, and mortgage-backed securities. Risky assets represent 40% of firms' financial portfolios, or 6% of total book assets. We present a formal model to assess the optimality of this behavior. Consistent with the model, risky assets are concentrated in financially unconstrained firms holding large financial portfolios, are held by poorly governed firms, and are discounted by 13% to 22% compared to safe assets. We conclude that this activity represents an unregulated asset management industry of more than $1.5 trillion, questioning the traditional boundaries of nonfinancial firms.</description><author>Duchin, Ran; Gilbert, Thomas; Harford, Jarrad; Hrdlicka, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Before an Analyst Becomes an Analyst: Does Industry Experience Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, Daniel; Gokkaya, Sinan; Liu, Xi
Using hand-collected biographical information on financial analysts from 1983 to 2011, we find that analysts making forecasts on firms in industries related to their preanalyst experience have better forecast accuracy, evoke stronger market reactions to earning revisions, and are more likely to be named Institutional Investor all-stars. Plausibly exogenous losses of analysts with related industry experience have real financial market implications-changes in firms' information asymmetry and price reactions are significantly larger than those of other analysts. Overall, industry expertise acquired from preanalyst work experience is valuable to analysts, consistent with the emphasis placed on their industry knowledge by institutional investors.</description><author>Bradley, Daniel; Gokkaya, Sinan; Liu, Xi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Market Participation and Portfolio Choice over the Life-Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fagereng, Andreas; Gottlieb, Charles; Guiso, Luigi
Using error-free data on life-cycle portfolio allocations of a large sample of Norwegian households, we document a double adjustment as households age: a rebalancing of the portfolio composition away from stocks as they approach retirement and stock market exit after retirement. When structurally estimating an extended life-cycle model, the parameter combination that best fits the data is one with a relatively large risk aversion, a small per-period participation cost, and a yearly probability of a large stock market loss in line with the frequency of stock market crashes in Norway.</description><author>Fagereng, Andreas; Gottlieb, Charles; Guiso, Luigi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Linear-Rational Term Structure Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Filipovic, Damir; Larsson, Martin; Trolle, Anders B.
We introduce the class of linear-rational term structure models in which the state price density is modeled such that bond prices become linear-rational functions of the factors. This class is highly tractable with several distinct advantages: (i) ensures non-negative interest rates, (ii) easily accommodates unspanned factors affecting volatility and risk premiums, and (iii) admits semi-analytical solutions to swaptions. A parsimonious model specification within the linear-rational class has a very good fit to both interest rate swaps and swaptions since 1997 and captures many features of term structure, volatility, and risk premium dynamics-including when interest rates are close to the zero lower bound.</description><author>Filipovic, Damir; Larsson, Martin; Trolle, Anders B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage Debt Overhang: Reduced Investment by Homeowners at Risk of Default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Melzer, Brian T.
Homeowners at risk of default face a debt overhang that reduces their incentive to invest in their property: in expectation, some value created by investments in the property will go to the lender. This agency conflict affects housing investments. Homeowners at risk of default cut back substantially on home improvements and mortgage principal payments, even when they appear financially unconstrained. Meanwhile, they do not reduce spending on assets that they may retain in default, including home appliances, furniture, and vehicles. These findings highlight an important financial friction that has stifled housing investment since the Great Recession.</description><author>Melzer, Brian T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Attracting Early-Stage Investors: Evidence from a Randomized Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Shai; Korteweg, Arthur; Laws, Kevin
This paper uses a randomized field experiment to identify which start-up characteristics are most important to investors in early-stage firms. The experiment randomizes investors' information sets of fund-raising start-ups. The average investor responds strongly to information about the founding team, but not to firm traction or existing lead investors. We provide evidence that the team is not merely a signal of quality, and that investing based on team information is a rational strategy. Together, our results indicate that information about human assets is causally important for the funding of early-stage firms and hence for entrepreneurial success.</description><author>Bernstein, Shai; Korteweg, Arthur; Laws, Kevin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Politically Connected Private Equity and Employment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faccio, Mara; Hsu, Hung-Chia
We investigate the employment consequences of private equity buyouts. We find evidence of higher job creation, on average, at the establishments operated by targets of politically connected private equity firms than at those operated by targets of nonconnected private equity firms. Consistent with an exchange of favors story, establishments operated by targets of politically connected private equity firms increase employment more during election years and in states with high levels of corruption. In additional analyses, we provide evidence of specific benefits experienced by target firms from their political connections. Our results are robust to tests designed to mitigate selection concerns.</description><author>Faccio, Mara; Hsu, Hung-Chia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Leverage and Monetary Policy's Risk-Taking Channel: Evidence from the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Laeven, Luc; Suarez, Gustavo A.
We present evidence of a risk-taking channel of monetary policy for the U.S. banking system. We use confidential data on banks' internal ratings on loans to businesses over the period 1997 to 2011 from the Federal Reserve's Survey of Terms of Business Lending. We find that ex ante risk-taking by banks (measured by the risk rating of new loans) is negatively associated with increases in short-term interest rates. This relationship is more pronounced in regions that are less in sync with the nationwide business cycle, and less pronounced for banks with relatively low capital or during periods of financial distress.</description><author>Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Laeven, Luc; Suarez, Gustavo A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Foundations of Corporate Social Responsibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liang, Hao; Renneboog, Luc
Using corporate social responsibility (CSR) ratings for 23,000 companies from 114 countries, we find that a firm's CSR rating and its country's legal origin are strongly correlated. Legal origin is a stronger explanation than "doing good by doing well" factors or firm and country characteristics (ownership concentration, political institutions, and globalization): firms from common law countries have lower CSR than companies from civil law countries, with Scandinavian civil law firms having the highest CSR ratings. Evidence from quasi-natural experiments such as scandals and natural disasters suggests that civil law firms are more responsive to CSR shocks than common law firms.</description><author>Liang, Hao; Renneboog, Luc</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing Collateral and Entrepreneurship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmalz, Martin C.; Sraer, David A.; Thesmar, David
We show that collateral constraints restrict firm entry and postentry growth, using French administrative data and cross-sectional variation in local house-price appreciation as shocks to collateral values. We control for local demand shocks by comparing treated homeowners to controls in the same region that do not experience collateral shocks: renters and homeowners with an outstanding mortgage, who (in France) cannot take out a second mortgage. In both comparisons, an increase in collateral value leads to a higher probability of becoming an entrepreneur. Conditional on entry, treated entrepreneurs use more debt, start larger firms, and remain larger in the long run.</description><author>Schmalz, Martin C.; Sraer, David A.; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effects of Credit Ratings: The Sovereign Ceiling Channel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor; Cunha, Igor; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Restrepo, Felipe
We show that sovereign debt impairments can have a significant effect on financial markets and real economies through a credit ratings channel. Specifically, we find that firms reduce their investment and reliance on credit markets due to a rising cost of debt capital following a sovereign rating downgrade. We identify these effects by exploiting exogenous variation in corporate ratings due to rating agencies' sovereign ceiling policies, which require that firms' ratings remain at or below the sovereign rating of their country of domicile.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Cunha, Igor; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Restrepo, Felipe</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Doesn't Kill You Will Only Make You More Risk-Loving: Early-Life Disasters and CEO Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernile, Gennaro; Bhagwat, Vineet; Rau, P. Raghavendra
The literature on managerial style posits a linear relation between a chief executive officer's (CEOs) past experiences and firm risk. We show that there is a nonmonotonic relation between the intensity of CEOs' early-life exposure to fatal disasters and corporate risk-taking. CEOs who experience fatal disasters without extremely negative consequences lead firms that behave more aggressively, whereas CEOs who witness the extreme downside of disasters behave more conservatively. These patterns manifest across various corporate policies including leverage, cash holdings, and acquisition activity. Ultimately, the link between CEOs' disaster experience and corporate policies has real economic consequences on firm riskiness and cost of capital.</description><author>Bernile, Gennaro; Bhagwat, Vineet; Rau, P. Raghavendra</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Term Market Risks Implied by Weekly Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, Torben G.; Fusari, Nicola; Todorov, Viktor
We study short-maturity (weekly) S&amp;P 500 index options, which provide a direct way to analyze volatility and jump risks. Unlike longer-dated options, they are largely insensitive to the risk of intertemporal shifts in the economic environment. Adopting a novel seminonparametric approach, we uncover variation in the negative jump tail risk, which is not spanned by market volatility and helps predict future equity returns. As such, our approach allows for easy identification of periods of heightened concerns about negative tail events that are not always signaled by the level of market volatility and elude standard asset pricing models.</description><author>Andersen, Torben G.; Fusari, Nicola; Todorov, Viktor</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange Rates and Monetary Policy Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mueller, Philippe; Tahbaz-Salehi, Alireza; Vedolin, Andrea
We document that a trading strategy that is short the U.S. dollar and long other currencies exhibits significantly larger excess returns on days with scheduled Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) announcements. We show that these excess returns (i) are higher for currencies with higher interest rate differentials vis-a-vis the United States, (ii) increase with uncertainty about monetary policy, and (iii) increase further when the Federal Reserve adopts a policy of monetary easing. We interpret these excess returns as compensation for monetary policy uncertainty within a parsimonious model of constrained financiers who intermediate global demand for currencies.</description><author>Mueller, Philippe; Tahbaz-Salehi, Alireza; Vedolin, Andrea</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Housing on Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chetty, Raj; Sandor, Laszlo; Szeidl, Adam
We show that characterizing the effects of housing on portfolios requires distinguishing between the effects of home equity and mortgage debt. We isolate exogenous variation in home equity and mortgages by using differences across housing markets in house prices and housing supply elasticities as instruments. Increases in property value (holding home equity constant) reduce stockholdings, while increases in home equity wealth (holding property value constant) raise stockholdings. The stock share of liquid wealth would rise by 1 percentage point6% of the mean stock shareif a household were to spend 10% less on its house, holding fixed wealth.</description><author>Chetty, Raj; Sandor, Laszlo; Szeidl, Adam</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity in a Market for Unique Assets: Specified Pool and To-Be-Announced Trading in the Mortgage-Backed Securities Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Pengjie; Schultz, Paul; Song, Zhaogang
Agency mortgage-backed securities (MBS) trade simultaneously in a market for specified pools (SPs) and in the to-be-announced (TBA) forward market. TBA trading creates liquidity by allowing thousands of different MBS to be traded in a handful of TBA contracts. SPs that are eligible to be traded as TBAs have significantly lower trading costs than other SPs. We present evidence that TBA eligibility, in addition to characteristics of TBA-eligible SPs, lowers trading costs. We show that dealers hedge SP inventory with TBA trades, and they are more likely to prearrange trades in SPs that are difficult to hedge.</description><author>Gao, Pengjie; Schultz, Paul; Song, Zhaogang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forced Asset Sales and the Concentration of Outstanding Debt: Evidence from the Mortgage Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Favara, Giovanni; Giannetti, Mariassunta
We provide evidence that lenders differ in their ex post incentives to internalize price-default externalities associated with the liquidation of collateralized debt. Using the mortgage market as a laboratory, we conjecture that lenders with a large share of outstanding mortgages on their balance sheets internalize the negative spillovers associated with the liquidation of defaulting mortgages and thus are less inclined to foreclose. We provide evidence consistent with our conjecture. Arguably as a consequence, zip codes with a higher concentration of outstanding mortgages experience smaller house prices declines. These results are not driven by unobservable zip code or lender characteristics.</description><author>Favara, Giovanni; Giannetti, Mariassunta</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and Growth at the Firm Level: Evidence from SBA Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, J. David; Earle, John S.
We analyze linked databases on all SBA loans and lenders and on all U.S. employers to estimate the effects of financial access on employment growth. Estimation exploits the long panels and variation in local availability of SBA-intensive lenders. The results imply an increase of 3-3.5 jobs for each million dollars of loans, suggesting real effects of credit constraints. Estimated impacts are stronger for younger and larger firms and when local credit conditions are weak, but we find no clear evidence of cyclical variation. We estimate taxpayer costs per job created in the range of $21,000-$25,000.</description><author>Brown, J. David; Earle, John S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Scope of the Sell-Side Analyst Industry Matter? An Examination of Bias, Accuracy, and Information Content of Analyst Reports</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Merkley, Kenneth; Michaely, Roni; Pacelli, Joseph
We examine changes in the scope of the sell-side analyst industry and whether these changes impact information dissemination and the quality of analysts' reports. Our findings suggest that changes in the number of analysts covering an industry impact analyst competition and have significant spillover effects on other analysts' forecast accuracy, bias, report informativeness, and effort. These spillover industry effects are incremental to the effects of firm level changes in analyst coverage. Overall, a more significant sell-side analyst industry presence has positive externalities that can result in better functioning capital markets.</description><author>Merkley, Kenneth; Michaely, Roni; Pacelli, Joseph</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Correlated Default and Financial Intermediation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phelan, Gregory
Financial intermediation naturally arises when knowing how loan payoffs are correlated is valuable for managing investments but lenders cannot easily observe that relationship. I show this result using a costly enforcement model in which lenders need ex post incentives to enforce payments from defaulted loans and borrowers' payoffs are correlated. When projects have correlated outcomes, learning the state of one project (via enforcement) provides information about the states of other projects. A large correlated portfolio provides ex post incentives for enforcement. Thus, intermediation dominates direct lending, and intermediaries are financed with risk-free deposits, earn positive profits, and hold systemic default risk.</description><author>Phelan, Gregory</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Age, Investment Opportunities, and Job Creation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelino, Manuel; Ma, Song; Robinson, David
New firms are an important source of job creation, but the underlying economic mechanisms for why this is so are not well understood. Using an identification strategy that links shocks to local income to job creation in the nontradable sector, we ask whether job creation arises more through new firm creation or through the expansion of existing firms. We find that new firms account for the bulk of net employment creation in response to local investment opportunities. We also find significant gross job creation and destruction by existing firms, suggesting that positive local shocks accelerate churn.</description><author>Adelino, Manuel; Ma, Song; Robinson, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Flash Crash: High-Frequency Trading in an Electronic Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kirilenko, Andrei; Kyle, Albert S.; Samadi, Mehrdad; Tuzun, Tugkan
We study intraday market intermediation in an electronic market before and during a period of large and temporary selling pressure. On May 6, 2010, U.S. financial markets experienced a systemic intraday eventthe Flash Crashwhere a large automated selling program was rapidly executed in the E-mini S&amp;P 500 stock index futures market. Using audit trail transaction-level data for the E-mini on May 6 and the previous three days, we find that the trading pattern of the most active nondesignated intraday intermediaries (classified as High-Frequency Traders) did not change when prices fell during the Flash Crash.</description><author>Kirilenko, Andrei; Kyle, Albert S.; Samadi, Mehrdad; Tuzun, Tugkan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Flows in Foreign Exchange Markets: Dissecting Customer Currency Trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkhoff, Lukas; Sarno, Lucio; Schmeling, Maik; Schrimpf, Andreas
We study the information in order flows in the world's largest over-the-counter market, the foreign exchange (FX) market. The analysis draws on a data set covering a broad cross-section of currencies and different customer segments of FX end-users. The results suggest that order flows are highly informative about future exchange rates and provide significant economic value. We also find that different customer groups can share risk with each other effectively through the intermediation of a large dealer, and differ markedly in their predictive ability, trading styles, and risk exposure.</description><author>Menkhoff, Lukas; Sarno, Lucio; Schmeling, Maik; Schrimpf, Andreas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Information-Based Theory of Time-Varying Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daley, Brendan; Green, Brett
We propose an information-based theory to explain time variation in liquidity and link it to a variety of patterns in asset markets. In normal times, the market is fully liquid and gains from trade are realized immediately. However, the equilibrium also involves periods during which liquidity dries up, which leads to endogenous liquidation costs. Traders correctly anticipate such costs, which reduces their willingness to pay. This foresight leads to a novel feedback effect between prices and market liquidity, which are jointly determined in equilibrium. The model also predicts that contagious sell-offs can occur after sufficiently bad news.</description><author>Daley, Brendan; Green, Brett</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Procyclical Capital Regulation and Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Behn, Markus; Haselmann, Rainer; Wachtel, Paul
We use a quasi-experimental research design to examine the effect of model-based capital regulation on the procyclicality of bank lending and firms' access to funds. In response to an exogenous shock to credit risk in the German economy, capital charges for loans under model-based regulation increased by 0.5percentage points. As a consequence, banks reduced the amount of these loans by 2.1 to 3.9percentage points more than for loans under the traditional approach with fixed capital charges. We find an even stronger effect when we examine aggregate firm borrowing, suggesting that microprudential capital regulation can have sizeable real effects.</description><author>Behn, Markus; Haselmann, Rainer; Wachtel, Paul</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Health and Mortality Delta: Assessing the Welfare Cost of Household Insurance Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; Yogo, Motohiro
We develop a pair of risk measures, health and mortality delta, for the universe of life and health insurance products. A life-cycle model of insurance choice simplifies to replicating the optimal health and mortality delta through a portfolio of insurance products. We estimate the model to explain the observed variation in health and mortality delta implied by the ownership of life insurance, annuities including private pensions, and long-term care insurance in the Health and Retirement Study. For the median household aged 51 to 57, the lifetime welfare cost of market incompleteness and suboptimal choice is 3.2% of total wealth.</description><author>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; Yogo, Motohiro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Boarding a Sinking Ship? An Investigation of Job Applications to Distressed Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Jennifer; Matsa, David A.
We use novel data from a leading online job search platform to examine the impact of corporate distress on firms' ability to attract job applicants. Survey responses suggest that job seekers accurately perceive firms' financial condition, as measured by companies' credit default swap prices and accounting data. Analyzing responses to job postings by major financial firms during the Great Recession, we find that an increase in an employer's distress results in fewer and lower quality applicants. These effects are particularly evident when the social safety net provides workers with weak protection against unemployment and for positions requiring a college education.</description><author>Brown, Jennifer; Matsa, David A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning about Consumption Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johannes, Michael; Lochstoer, Lars A.; Mou, Yiqun
This paper characterizes U.S. consumption dynamics from the perspective of a Bayesian agent who does not know the underlying model structure but learns over time from macroeconomic data. Realistic, high-dimensional macroeconomic learning problems, which entail parameter, model, and state learning, generate substantially different subjective beliefs about consumption dynamics compared to the standard, full-information rational expectations benchmark. Beliefs about long-run dynamics are volatile, with counter-cyclical conditional volatility, and drift over time. Embedding these beliefs in a standard asset pricing model significantly improves the model's ability to match the stylized facts, as well as the sample path of the market price-dividend ratio.</description><author>Johannes, Michael; Lochstoer, Lars A.; Mou, Yiqun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>