<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JF6</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Founding-family ownership and firm performance: Evidence from the S&amp;P 500</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, R. C.; Reeb, D. M.
We investigate the relation between founding-family ownership and firm performance. We find that family ownership is both prevalent and substantial; families are present in one-third of the S&amp;P 500 and account for 18 percent of outstanding equity. Contrary to our conjecture, we find family firms perform better than nonfamily firms. Additional analysis reveals that the relation between family holdings and firm performance is nonlinear and that when family members serve as CEO, performance is better than with outside CEOs. Overall, our results are inconsistent with the hypothesis that minority shareholders are adversely affected by family ownership, suggesting that family ownership is an effective organizational structure.</description><author>Anderson, R. C.; Reeb, D. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of jumps in volatility and returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eraker, B.; Johannes, M.; Polson, N.
This paper examines continuous-time stochastic volatility models incorporating Jumps in returns and volatility. We develop a likelihood-based estimation strategy and provide estimates of parameters, spot volatility, jump times, and jump sizes using S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq 100 index returns. Estimates of jump times, jump sizes, and volatility are particularly useful for identifying the effects of these factors during periods of market stress, such as those in 1987, 1997, and 1998. Using formal and informal diagnostics, we find strong evidence for jumps in volatility and jumps in returns. Finally, we study how these factors and estimation risk impact option pricing.</description><author>Eraker, B.; Johannes, M.; Polson, N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market maker quotation behavior and pretrade transparency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Simaan, Y.; Weaver, D. G.; Whitcomb, D. K.
We examine the impact of differing levels of pretrade transparency on the quotation behavior of Nasdaq market makers. We find that market makers are more likely to quote on odd ticks, and to actively narrow the spread, when they can do so anonymously by posting limit orders on Electronic Communication Networks (ECNs). From a public policy perspective, our findings suggest that making the level of pretrade transparency on Nasdaq more opaque by allowing anonymous quotes could improve price competition and narrow spreads further.</description><author>Simaan, Y.; Weaver, D. G.; Whitcomb, D. K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What if trading location is different from business location? Evidence from the Jardine Group</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, K.; Hameed, A.; Lau, S. T.
We examine the price behavior and market activity of the Jardine Group companies after they were delisted from Hong Kong in 1994. Although the trading activity of the Jardine Group moved to Singapore, the core businesses remained in Hong Kong and Mainland China. Evidence indicates the Jardine stocks are correlated less (more) with the Hong Kong (Singapore) market after the delisting. This result cannot be explained by various hypotheses, such as relocation of core business, time-varying betas, migration of trading activity, and currency and tax distortions. We conclude that price fluctuations are affected by country-specific investor sentiment.</description><author>Chan, K.; Hameed, A.; Lau, S. T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial incentives and internal capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Motta, A.
Capital budgeting in multidivisional firms depends on the external assessment of the whole firm, as well as on headquarters' assessment of the divisions. While corporate headquarters may create value by directly monitoring divisions, the external assessment of the firm is a public good for division managers who, consequently, are tempted to free ride. As the number of divisions increases, the free-rider problem is aggravated, and internal capital markets substitute for external capital markets in the provision of managerial incentives. The analysis relates the value of diversification to characteristics of the firm, the industry, and the capital market.</description><author>De Motta, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integration of lending and underwriting: Implications of scope economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kanatas, G.; Qi, J. P.
Informational scope economies provide a cost advantage to universal banks offering "one-stop shopping" for lending and underwriting that enables them to "lock in" their clients' subsequent business. This market power reduces universal banks' incentive, relative to that of specialized investment banks, to apply costly underwriting efforts; consequently, universal banks are less successful in selling their clients' securities. Our results suggest that an integrated financial services market is less innovative than one with specialized intermediaries. Our analysis also identifies economy, intermediary, and firm characteristics that motivate either the integration or segmentation of bank lending and underwriting.</description><author>Kanatas, G.; Qi, J. P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convertible securities and venture capital finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmidt, K. M.
This paper offers a new explanation for the prevalent use of convertible securities in venture capital finance. Convertible securities can be used to endogenously allocate cash-flow rights as a function of the state of the world and the entrepreneur's effort. This property can be used to induce the entrepreneur and the venture capitalist to invest efficiently into the project. The result is robust to renegotiation and to changes in the timing of investments and information flows. The model is consistent with the observations that conversion is often automatic and that convertible securities are rarely used by outside investors.</description><author>Schmidt, K. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>DotCom mania: The rise and fall of Internet stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ofek, E.; Richardson, M.
This paper explores a model based on agents with heterogenous beliefs facing short sales restrictions, and its explanation for the rise, persistence, and eventual fall of Internet stock prices. First, we document substantial short sale restrictions for Internet stocks. Second, using data on Internet holdings and block trades, we show a link between heterogeneity and price effects for Internet stocks. Third, arguing that lockup expirations are a loosening of the short sale constraint, we document average, long-run excess returns as low as - 33 percent for Internet stocks postlockup. We link the Internet bubble burst to the unprecedented level of lockup expirations and insider selling.</description><author>Ofek, E.; Richardson, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Too busy to mind the business? Monitoring by directors with multiple board appointments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferris, S. P.; Jagannathan, M.; Pritchard, A. C.
We examine the number of external appointments held by corporate directors. Directors who serve larger firms and sit on larger boards are more likely to attract directorships. Consistent with Fama and Jensen (1983), we find that firm performance has a positive effect on the number of appointments held by a director. We find no evidence that multiple directors shirk their responsibilities to serve on board committees. We do not find that multiple directors are associated with a greater likelihood of securities fraud litigation. We conclude that the evidence does not support calls for limits on directorships held by an individual.</description><author>Ferris, S. P.; Jagannathan, M.; Pritchard, A. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-run performance after stock splits: 1927 to 1996</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Byun, J.; Rozeff, M. S.
We measure the postsplit performance of 12,747 stock splits from 1927 to 1996 using two methods to measure abnormal returns: size and book-to-market reference portfolios with bootstrapping, and calendar-time abnormal returns combined with factor models. Between 1927 and 1996, neither method applied to splits 25 percent or larger finds performance significantly different from zero. Over selected subperiods, subsamples of 2-1 splits restricted by book-to-market availability requirements display positive abnormal returns using some methods. However, these samples show small or negligible abnormal returns using the calendar-time method. Overall, the stock split evidence against market efficiency is neither pervasive nor compelling.</description><author>Byun, J.; Rozeff, M. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal versus external financing: An optimal contracting approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, R.; Muller, H. M.
We study optimal financial contracting for centralized and decentralized firms. Under centralized contracting, headquarters raises funds on behalf of multiple projects. Under decentralized contracting, each project raises funds separately on the external capital market. The benefit of centralization is that headquarters can use excess liquidity from high cash-flow projects to buy continuation rights for low cash-flow projects. The cost is that headquarters may pool cash flows from several projects and self-finance follow-up investments without having to return to the capital market. Absent any capital market discipline, it is more difficult to force headquarters to make repayments, which tightens financing constraints ex ante. Cross-sectionally, our model implies that conglomerates should have a lower average productivity than stand-alone firms.</description><author>Inderst, R.; Muller, H. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good day sunshine: Stock returns and the weather</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, D.; Shumway, T.
Psychological evidence and casual intuition predict that sunny weather is associated with upbeat mood. This paper examines the relationship between morning sunshine in the city of a country's leading stock exchange and daily market index returns across 26 countries from 1982 to 1997. Sunshine is strongly significantly correlated with stock returns. After controlling for sunshine, rain and snow are unrelated to returns. Substantial use of weather-based strategies was optimal for a trader with very low transactions costs. However, because these strategies involve frequent trades, fairly modest costs eliminate the gains. These findings are difficult to reconcile with fully rational price setting.</description><author>Hirshleifer, D.; Shumway, T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic risk matters!</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyal, A.; Santa-Clara, P.
This paper takes a new look at the predictability of stock market returns with risk measures. We find a significant positive relation between average stock variance (largely idiosyncratic) and the return on the market. In contrast, the variance of the market has no forecasting power for the market return. These relations persist after we control for macroeconomic variables known to forecast the stock market. The evidence is consistent with models of time-varying risk premia based on background risk and investor heterogeneity Alternatively, our findings can be justified by the option value of equity in the capital structure of the firms.</description><author>Goyal, A.; Santa-Clara, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate financing: An artificial agent-based analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Noe, T. H.; Rebello, M. J.; Wang, J.
We examine corporate security choice by simulating an economy populated by adaptive agents who learn about the structure of security returns and prices through experience. Through a process of evolutionary selection, each agent gravitates toward strategies that generate the highest payoffs. Despite the fact that markets are perfect and agents maximize value, a financing hierarchy emerges in which straight debt dominates other financing choices. Equity and convertible debt display significant underpricing. In general, the smaller the probability of loss to outside investors, the more likely the firm is to issue the security and the smaller the security's underpricing.</description><author>Noe, T. H.; Rebello, M. J.; Wang, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How sensitive is investment to cash flow when financing is frictionless?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alti, A.
I analyze the sensitivity of a firm's investment to its own cash flow in the benchmark case where financing is frictionless. This sensitivity has been proposed as a measure of financing constraints in earlier studies. I find that the investment-cash flow sensitivities that obtain in the frictionless benchmark are very similar, both in magnitude and in patterns they exhibit, to those observed in the data. In particular, the sensitivity is higher for firms with high growth rates and low dividend payout ratios. Tobin's q is shown to be a more noisy measure of near-term investment plans for these firms.</description><author>Alti, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The finite moment log stable process and option pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carr, P.; Wu, L. R.
We document a surprising pattern in S&amp;P 500 option prices. When implied volatilities are graphed against a standard measure of moneyness, the implied volatility smirk does not flatten out as maturity increases up to the observable horizon of two years. This behavior contrasts sharply with the implications of many pricing models and with the asymptotic behavior implied by the central limit theorem (CLT). We develop a parsimonious model which deliberately violates the CLT assumptions and thus captures the observed behavior of the volatility smirk over the maturity horizon. Calibration exercises demonstrate its superior performance against several widely used alternatives.</description><author>Carr, P.; Wu, L. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Building financial derivatives applications with C++</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robel, G. F.
nan</description><author>Robel, G. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lectures on corporate finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, B. M.
nan</description><author>Lambrecht, B. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital gains, dividend yields, and expected inflation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pilotte, E. A.
One explanation for the negative relationship between short-horizon stock returns and inflation is that inflation proxies (inversely) for expected future real output. In this paper, I examine the possibility that inflation also proxies for variation in real price/dividend ratios (excess returns). I show that when the covariance between real price/dividend ratios and inflation is nonzero, the relationship between returns and expected inflation differs for the two components of returns: dividend yields and capital gains returns. My empirical evidence demonstrates that dividend yields and capital gains are related differently to expected inflation in U.S. and foreign markets.</description><author>Pilotte, E. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Monte Carlo method for optimal portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Detemple, J. B.; Garcia, R.; Rindisbacher, M.
This paper proposes a new simulation-based approach for optimal portfolio allocation in realistic environments with complex dynamics for the state variables and large numbers of factors and assets. A first illustration involves a choice between equity and cash with nonlinear interest rate and market price of risk dynamics. Intertemporal hedging demands significantly increase the demand for stocks and exhibit low volatility. We then analyze settings where stock returns are also predicted by dividend yields and where investors have wealth-dependent relative risk aversion. Large-scale problems with many assets, including the Nasdaq, SP500, bonds, and cash, are also examined.</description><author>Detemple, J. B.; Garcia, R.; Rindisbacher, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial distress and bank lending relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahiya, S.; Saunders, A.; Srinivasan, A.
We use a unique data set of bank loans to examine the wealth effects on lead lending banks when their borrowers suffer financial distress. We find a significant negative announcement return for the lead lending bank when a major corporate borrower announces default or bankruptcy. Banks with higher exposure to the distressed firm have larger negative announcement-period returns. The existence of a past lending relationship with the distressed firm results in larger wealth declines for the bank shareholders. Finally, financial distress also has a significant negative effect on borrower's returns.</description><author>Dahiya, S.; Saunders, A.; Srinivasan, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade credit, financial intermediary development, and industry growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fisman, R.; Love, I.
Recent work suggests that financial development is important for economic growth, since financial markets more effectively allocate capital to firms with high value projects. For firms in poorly developed financial markets, implicit borrowing in the form of trade credit may provide an alternative source of funds. We show that industries with higher dependence on trade credit financing exhibit higher rates of growth in countries with weaker financial institutions. Furthermore, consistent with barriers to trade credit access among young firms, we show that most of the effect that we report comes from growth in the size of preexisting firms.</description><author>Fisman, R.; Love, I.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing the analysts: Career concerns and biased earnings forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, H.; Kubik, J. D.
We examine security analysts' career concerns by relating their earnings forecasts to job separations. Relatively accurate forecasters are more likely to experience favorable career outcomes like moving up to a high-status brokerage house.. Controlling for accuracy, analysts who are optimistic relative to the consensus are more likely to experience favorable job separations. For analysts who cover stocks underwritten by their houses, job separations depend less on accuracy and more on optimism. Job separations were less sensitive to accuracy and more sensitive to optimism during the recent stock market mania. Brokerage houses apparently reward optimistic analysts who promote stocks.</description><author>Hong, H.; Kubik, J. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Delegated portfolio management and rational prolonged mispricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldman, E.; Slezak, S. L.
This paper examines how information becomes reflected in prices when investment decisions are delegated to fund managers whose tenure may be shorter than the time it takes for their private information to become public. We consider a sequence of managers, where each subsequent manager inherits the portfolio of their predecessor. We show that the inherited portfolio distorts the subsequent manager's incentive to trade on long-term information. This allows erroneous past information to persist, causing mispricing similar to a bubble. We investigate the magnitude of the mispricing. In addition, we examine endogenous information quality. In some cases, information quality increases when the manager's expected tenure decreases.</description><author>Goldman, E.; Slezak, S. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend taxes and share prices: Evidence from real estate investment trusts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gentry, W. M.; Kemsley, D.; Mayer, C. J.
Prior empirical evidence regarding the impact of dividend taxes on firm valuation is mixed. This study avoids some of the complications encountered in previous empirical work by exploiting institutional characteristics of REITs, such as their limited discretion over dividend policy and the relative transparency of REIT assets. We regress the market value of equity on the market value of assets and tax basis, which creates tax deductions that lower future dividend taxes without affecting future pretax cash flow. We find that firm value is positively related to tax basis, suggesting that future dividend taxes are capitalized into share prices.</description><author>Gentry, W. M.; Kemsley, D.; Mayer, C. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic asset allocation with event risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, J.; Longstaff, F. A.; Pan, J.
Major events often trigger abrupt changes in stock prices and volatility. We study the implications of jumps in prices and volatility on investment strategies. Using the event-risk framework of Duffie, Pan, and Singleton (2000), we provide analytical solutions to the optimal portfolio problem. Event risk dramatically affects the optimal strategy An investor facing event risk is less willing to take leveraged or short positions. The investor acts as if some portion of his wealth may become illiquid and the optimal strategy blends both dynamic and buy-and-hold strategies. Jumps in prices and volatility both have important effects.</description><author>Liu, J.; Longstaff, F. A.; Pan, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New evidence on the market for directors: Board membership and Pennsylvania Senate Bill 1310</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coles, J. L.; Hoi, C. K.
We examine the relation between a boards decision to reject antitakeover provisions of Pennsylvania Senate Bill 1310 and subsequent labor market opportunities of those same board members. Compared to directors retaining all provisions, directors rejecting all protective provisions of SB1310 are three times as likely to gain additional external directorships and are 30 percent more likely to retain their internal slot on the board of that same Pennsylvania company. For external board seats, the results are driven by nonexecutive directors who are not members of the management team; for internal board seats, the results are driven by executive directors.</description><author>Coles, J. L.; Hoi, C. K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing with conditioning information: A new test</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, K. Q.
This paper presents a new test of conditional versions of the Sharpe-Lintner CAPM, the Jagannathan and Wang (1996) extension of the CAPM, and the Fama and French (1993) three-factor model. The test is based on a general non-parametric methodology that avoids functional form misspecification of betas, risk premia, and the stochastic discount factor. Our results provide a novel view of empirical performance of these models. In particular, we find that a nonparametric version of the Fama and French model performs well, even when challenged by momentum portfolios.</description><author>Wang, K. Q.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling sovereign yield spreads: A case study of Russian debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffie, D.; Pedersen, L. H.; Singleton, K. J.
We construct a model for pricing sovereign debt that accounts for the risks of both default and restructuring, and allows for compensation for illiquidity Using a new and relatively efficient method, we estimate the model using Russian dollar-denominated bonds. We consider the determinants of the Russian yield spread, the yield differential across different Russian bonds, and the implications for market integration, relative liquidity, relative expected recovery rates, and implied expectations of different default scenarios.</description><author>Duffie, D.; Pedersen, L. H.; Singleton, K. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do managers diversify their firms? Agency reconsidered</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, R. K.; Samwick, A. A.
We develop a contracting model between shareholders and managers in which managers diversify their firms for two reasons: to reduce idiosyncratic risk and to capture private benefits. We test the comparative static predictions of our model. In contrast to previous work, we find that diversification is positively related to managerial incentives. Further, the link between firm performance and managerial incentives is weaker for firms that experience changes in diversification than it is for firms that do not. Our findings suggest that managers diversify their firms in response to changes in private benefits rather than to reduce their exposure to risk.</description><author>Aggarwal, R. K.; Samwick, A. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Clearly irrational financial market behavior: Evidence from the early exercise of exchange traded stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poteshman, A. M.; Serbin, V.
This paper analyzes the early exercise of exchange-traded options by different classes of investors over the 1996 to 1999 period. A large number of exercises are identified as clearly irrational without invoking any model of market equilibrium. Customers of discount brokers and customers of full-service brokers both engage in a significant number of irrational exercises while traders at large investment houses exhibit no irrational early exercise behavior. Rational and irrational exercise is triggered for discount and full-service customers by the underlying stock price attaining its highest level over the past year and by high returns on the underlying stock.</description><author>Poteshman, A. M.; Serbin, V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The quiet period goes out with a bang</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, D. J.; Jordan, B. D.; Ritter, J. R.
We examine the expiration of the IPO quiet period, which occurs after the 25th calendar day following the offering. For IPOs during 1996 to. 2000, we find that analyst coverage is initiated immediately for 76 percent of these firms, almost always with a favorable rating. Initiated firms experience a five-day abnormal return of 4.1 percent versus 0.1 percent for firms with no coverage. The abnormal returns are concentrated in the days just before the quiet period expires. Abnormal returns are much larger when coverage is initiated by multiple analysts. It does not matter whether a recommendation comes from the lead underwriter or not.</description><author>Bradley, D. J.; Jordan, B. D.; Ritter, J. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentive fees and mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.; Blake, C. R.
This paper examines the effect of incentive fees on the behavior of mutual fund managers. Funds with incentive fees exhibit positive stock selection ability, but a beta less than one results in funds not earning positive fees. From an investor's perspective, positive alphas plus lower expense ratios make incentive-fee funds attractive. However, incentive-fee funds take on more risk than non-incentive-fee funds, and they increase risk after a period of poor performance. Incentive fees are useful marketing tools, since more new cash flows go into incentive-fee funds than into non-incentive-fee funds, ceteris paribus.</description><author>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.; Blake, C. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection and firm liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, P.; Chung, D. Y.
The purpose of this study is to investigate the relation between investor protection and firm liquidity We posit that less protective environments lead to wider bid-ask spreads and thinner depths because they fail to minimize information asymmetries. The Hong Kong equity market provides a unique opportunity to compare liquidity costs across distinct investor protection environments, but still within a common trading mechanism and currency. Our empirical findings verify that firm liquidity is significantly affected by investor protection. Regression and matched-sample results show that Hong Kong-based equities exhibit narrower spreads and thicker depths than their China-based counterparts.</description><author>Brockman, P.; Chung, D. Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The wealth effects of repurchases on bondholders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maxwell, W. F.; Stephens, C. P.
Prior research has documented positive abnormal stock returns around the announcements of repurchase programs; several explanations of these returns have been suggested, including signaling, free cash flow, and wealth redistributions. This study analyzes abnormal stock, bond, and firm returns,around repurchase announcements to examine these hypotheses. We find evidence consistent with both signaling and wealth redistribution. The loss to bondholders is a function of the size of the repurchase, and the risk of the firm's debt. We also find that bond ratings are twice as likely to be downgraded as upgraded after the announcement of the repurchase program.</description><author>Maxwell, W. F.; Stephens, C. P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Excessive dollar debt: Financial development and underinsurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caballero, R. J.; Krishnamurthy, A.
We propose that the limited financial development of emerging markets is a significant factor behind the large share of dollar-denominated external debt present in these markets. We show that when financial constraints affect borrowing and lending between domestic agents, agents undervalue insuring against an exchange rate depreciation. Since more of this insurance is present when external debt is denominated in domestic currency rather than in dollars, this result implies that domestic agents choose excessive dollar debt. We also show that limited financial development reduces the incentives for foreign lenders to enter emerging markets. The retarded entry reinforces the underinsurance problem.</description><author>Caballero, R. J.; Krishnamurthy, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure with semi credible targeting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farnsworth, H.; Bass, R.
The Federal Reserve sets targets for interest rates which it enforces through direct market intervention. These targets are changed periodically. In this paper, we develop a term structure model in which the short rate is subject to a control which keeps it close to a target which changes from time to time. The probability of target changes is not constant in the model, but changes as a function of observables. The model performs well at explaining the shifts in the yield curve that accompany target changes.</description><author>Farnsworth, H.; Bass, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluation periods and asset prices in a market experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gneezy, U.; Kapteyn, A.; Potters, J.
We test whether the frequency of feedback information about the performance of an investment portfolio and the flexibility with which the investor can change the portfolio influence her risk;attitude in markets. In line with the prediction of myopic loss aversion (Benartzi and Thaler (1995)), we find that more-information and more flexibility result in less risk taking. Market prices of risky assets are significantly higher if feedback frequency and decision flexibility are reduced. This result supports the findings from individual decision making and shows that market interactions do not eliminate such behavior or its consequences for prices.</description><author>Gneezy, U.; Kapteyn, A.; Potters, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A generalization of the Brennan-Rubinstein approach for the pricing of derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Camara, A.
This paper derives preference-free option pricing equations in a discrete time economy where asset returns have continuous ditributions. There is a representative agent who has risk preferences with an exponential representation. Aggregate wealth and the underlying asset price have transformed normal distributions which may or may not belong to the same family of distributions. Those pricing results are particularly valuable (a) to show new sufficient conditions for existing risk-neutral option pricing equations (e.g., the Black-Scholes model), and (b) to obtain new analytical solutions for the price of European-style contingent claims when the underlying asset has a transformed normal distribution (e.g., a negatively skew lognormal distribution).</description><author>Camara, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management with derivatives by dealers and market quality in government bond markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Naik, N. Y.; Yadav, P. K.
This paper investigates how bond dealers manage core business risk with interest rate futures and the extent to which market quality is affected by their selective risk taking. We observe that dealers use futures to take directional bets and hedge changes in their spot exposure. We find that, cross-sectionally, a dealer with longer (shorter) risk exposure sells (buys) a larger amount of exposure the next day. However, this risk control takes place via the futures market and not the spot market. Finally, we find strong support for the price effects of capital constraints emphasized by Froot and Stein (1998).</description><author>Naik, N. Y.; Yadav, P. K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical tests for stochastic dominance efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Post, T.
We derive empirical tests for the stochastic dominance efficiency of a given portfolio with respect to all possible portfolios constructed from a set of assets. The tests can be computed using straightforward linear programming. Bootstrapping techniques and asymptotic distribution theory can approximate the sampling properties of the test results and allow for statistical inference. Our results could provide a stimulus to the further proliferation of stochastic dominance for the problem of portfolio selection and evaluation. Using our tests, the Fama and French market portfolio is significantly inefficient relative to benchmark portfolios formed on market capitalization and book-to-market equity ratio.</description><author>Post, T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical analysis of analysts' target prices: Short-term informativeness and long-term dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, A.; Lehavy, R.
Using a large database of analysts' target prices issued over the period 19971999, we examine short-term market reactions to target price revisions and long-term comovement of target and stock prices. We find a significant market reaction to the information contained in analysts' target prices, both unconditionally and conditional on contemporaneously issued stock recommendation and earnings forecast revisions. Using a cointegration approach, we analyze the long-term behavior of market and target prices. We find that, on average, the one-year-ahead target price is 28 percent higher than the current market price.</description><author>Brav, A.; Lehavy, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value versus glamour</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, J.; Cooper, M.; Kaul, G.
The fragility of the CAPM has led to a resurgence of research that frequently uses trading strategies based on sorting procedures to uncover relations between firm characteristics (such as "value" or "glamour") and equity returns. We examine the propensity of these strategies to generate statistically and economically significant profits due to our familiarity with the data. Under plausible assumptions, data snooping can account for up to 50 percent of the in-sample relations between firm characteristics and returns uncovered using single (one-way) sorts. The biases can be much larger if we simultaneously condition returns on two (or more) characteristics.</description><author>Conrad, J.; Cooper, M.; Kaul, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate board composition, protocols, and voting behavior: Experimental evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gillette, A. B.; Noe, T. H.; Rebello, M. J.
We examine voting by a board designed to mitigate conflicts of interest between privately informed insiders and owners. Our model demonstrates that, as argued by researchers and the business press, boards with a majority of trustworthy but uninformed "watchdogs" can implement institutionally preferred policies. Our laboratory experiments strongly support this conclusion. Our model also highlights the necessity of penalties on insiders when there is dissension among board members. However, penalties for dissent appeared to have little impact on the experimental outcomes.</description><author>Gillette, A. B.; Noe, T. H.; Rebello, M. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing and advising: Optimal financial contracts with venture capitalists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casamatta, C.
This paper analyses the joint provision of effort by an entrepreneur and by an advisor to improve the productivity of an investment project. Without moral hazard, it is optimal that both exert effort. With moral hazard, if the entrepreneur's effort is more efficient (less costly) than the advisor's effort, the latter is not hired if she does not provide funds. Outside financing arises endogenously. This explains why investors like venture capitalists are value enhancing. The level of outside financing determines whether common stocks or convertible bonds should be issued in response to incentives.</description><author>Casamatta, C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do spin-offs expropriate wealth from bondholders?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maxwell, W. F.; Rao, R. P.
A wealth transfer from bondholders to stockholders is one of several hypotheses used to explain stockholder gains on the announcement of a spin-off. However, previous empirical research has not found systematic evidence supporting the wealth expropriation hypothesis. Using a larger sample with comprehensive bond data, we find evidence consistent with wealth expropriation. Bondholders, on average, suffer a significant negative abnormal return during the month of the spin-off announcement. However, even accounting for the loss to the bondholders, the aggregate value of the publicly traded debt and equity increases on a spin-off announcement, suggesting that the wealth expropriation hypothesis is not a complete explanation of the stockholder gains. In explaining the magnitude of the losses to bondholders, we find they are a function of the loss in collateral in the spun-off subsidiary and the level of financial risk of the parent firm. Consistent with a loss to bondholders, firms are more likely to have their credit rating downgraded than upgraded after a spinoff. Additionally, consistent with the wealth transfer hypothesis, losses to bondholders tend to be more severe, the larger the gains to shareholders.</description><author>Maxwell, W. F.; Rao, R. P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticompetitive financial contracting: The design of financial claims</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cestone, G.; White, L.
This paper presents the first model where entry deterrence takes place through financial rather than product-market channels. In existing models, a firm's choice of financial instruments deters entry by affecting product market behavior; here entry deterrence occurs by affecting the credit market behavior of investors towards entrant firms. We find that to deter entry, the claims held on incumbent firms should be sufficiently risky, that is, equity. This contrasts with the standard Brander and Lewis (1986) result that debt deters entry. This effect is more marked the less competitive the credit market is-so more credit market competition spurs more product market competition.</description><author>Cestone, G.; White, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment, uncertainty, and liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyle, G. W.; Guthrie, G. A.
We analyze the dynamic investment decision of a firm subject to an endogenous financing constraint. The threat of future funding shortfalls lowers the value of the firm's timing options and encourages acceleration of investment beyond the first-best optimal level. As well as highlighting another way by which capital market frictions can distort investment behavior, this result implies that (1) the sensitivity of investment to cash flow can be greatest for high-liquidity firms and (2) greater uncertainty has an ambiguous effect on investment.</description><author>Boyle, G. W.; Guthrie, G. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Family firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burkart, M.; Panunzi, F.; Shleifer, A.
We present a model of succession in a firm owned and managed by its founder. The founder decides between hiring a professional manager or leaving management to his heir, as well as on what fraction of the company to float on the stock exchange. We assume that a professional is a better manager than the heir, and describe how the founder's decision is shaped by the legal environment. This theory of separation of ownership from management includes the Anglo-Saxon and the Continental European patterns of corporate governance as special cases, and generates additional empirical predictions consistent with cross-country evidence.</description><author>Burkart, M.; Panunzi, F.; Shleifer, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset trading volume with dynamically complete markets and heterogeneous agents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Judd, K. L.; Kubler, F.; Schmedders, K.
Trading volume of infinitely lived securities, such as equity, is generically zero in Lucas asset pricing models with heterogeneous agents. More generally, the end-of-period portfolio of all securities is constant over time and states in the generic economy. General equilibrium restrictions rule out trading of equity after an initial period. This result contrasts the prediction of portfolio allocation analyses that portfolio rebalancing motives produce nontrivial trade volume. Therefore, other causes of trade must be present in asset markets with large trading volume.</description><author>Judd, K. L.; Kubler, F.; Schmedders, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging in the possible presence of unspanned stochastic volatility: Evidence from swaption markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, R.; Gupta, A.; Ritchken, P.
This paper examines whether higher order multifactor models, with state variables linked solely to underlying LIBOR-swap rates, are by themselves capable of explaining and hedging interest rate derivatives, or whether models explicitly exhibiting features such as unspanned stochastic volatility are necessary. Our research shows that swaptions and even swaption straddles can be well hedged with LIBOR bonds alone. We examine the potential benefits of looking outside the LIBOR market for factors that might impact swaption prices without impacting swap rates, and find them to be minor, indicating that the swaption market is well integrated with the LIBOR-swap market.</description><author>Fan, R.; Gupta, A.; Ritchken, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of underpricing for seasoned equity offers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corwin, S. A.
Seasoned offers were underpriced by an average of 2.2 percent during the 1980s and 1990s, with the discount increasing substantially over time. The increase appears to be related to Rule 10b-21 and to economic changes affecting both IPOs and SEOs. Consistent with temporary price pressure, underpricing is positively related to offer size especially for securities with relatively inelastic demand. Underpricing is also positively related to price uncertainty and, after Rule 10b-21, to the magnitude of preoffer returns. Additionally, I find that underpricing is significantly related to underwriter pricing conventions such as price rounding and pricing relative to the bid quote.</description><author>Corwin, S. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>S&amp;P 500 Index additions and earnings expectations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, D. K.; McConnell, J. J.; Ovtchinnikov, A. V.; Yu, Y.
Stock price increases associated with addition to the S&amp;P 500 Index have been interpreted as evidence that demand curves for stocks slope downward. A key premise underlying this interpretation is that Index inclusion provides no new information about companies' future prospects. We examine this premise by analyzing analysts' earnings per share (eps) forecasts around Index inclusion and by comparing postinclusion realized earnings to preinclusion forecasts. Relative to benchmark companies, companies newly added to the Index experience significant increases in eps forecasts and significant improvements in realized earnings. These results indicate that S&amp;P Index inclusion is not an information-free event.</description><author>Denis, D. K.; McConnell, J. J.; Ovtchinnikov, A. V.; Yu, Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential address: Liquidity and price discovery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Hara, M.
This paper examines the implications of market microstructure for asset pricing. I argue that asset pricing ignores the central fact that asset prices evolve in markets. Markets provide liquidity and price discovery, and T argue that asset pricing models need to be recast in broader terms to incorporate the transactions costs of liquidity and the risks of price discovery. I argue that symmetric information-based asset pricing models do not work because they assume that the underlying problems of liquidity and price discovery have been solved. T develop an asymmetric information asset pricing model that incorporates these effects.</description><author>O'Hara, M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The really long-run performance of initial public offerings: The pre-Nasdaq evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gompers, P. A.; Lerner, J.
Financial economists have intensely debated the performance of IPOs using data after the formation of Nasdaq. This paper sheds light on this controversy by undertaking a large, out-of-sample study: We examine the performance for five years after listing of 3,661 U.S. IPOs from 1935 to 1972. The sample displays some underperformance when event-time buy-and-hold abnormal returns are used. The underperformance disappears, however, when cumulative abnormal returns are utilized. A calendar-time analysis shows that over the entire period, IPOs return as much as the market. The intercepts in CAPM and Fama-French regressions are insignificantly different from zero, suggesting no abnormal performance.</description><author>Gompers, P. A.; Lerner, J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spurious regressions in financial economics?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, W. E.; Sarkissian, S.; Simin, T. T.
Even though stock returns are not highly autocorrelated, there is a spurious regression bias in predictive regressions for stock returns related to the classic studies of Yule (1926) and Granger and Newbold (1974). Data mining for predictor variables interacts with spurious regression bias. The two effects reinforce each other, because more highly persistent series are more likely to be found significant in the search for predictor variables. Our simulations suggest that many of the regressions in the literature, based on individual predictor variables, may be spurious.</description><author>Ferson, W. E.; Sarkissian, S.; Simin, T. T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bookbuilding: How informative is the order book?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornelli, F.; Goldreich, D.
We examine the institutional bids submitted under the bookbuilding procedure for a sample of international equity issues. We find that information in bids which include a limit price, especially those of large and frequent bidders, affects the issue price. Oversubscription has a smaller but significant effect for IPOs. Public information affects the issue price to the extent that it is reflected in the bids. Oversubscription and demand elasticity are positively correlated with the first-day aftermarket return, and demand elasticity is negatively correlated with aftermarket volatility. Our results support the view that bookbuilding is designed to extract information from investors.</description><author>Cornelli, F.; Goldreich, D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership structure, corporate governance, and firm value: Evidence from the East Asian financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lemmon, M. L.; Lins, K. V.
We use a sample of 800 firms in eight East Asian countries to study the effect of ownership structure on value during the regions financial crisis. The crisis negatively impacted firms' investment opportunities, raising the incentives of controlling shareholders to expropriate minority investors. Crisis period stock returns of firms in which managers have high levels of control rights, but have separated their control and cash flow ownership, are 10-20 percentage points lower than those of other firms. The evidence is consistent with the view that ownership structure plays an important role in determining whether insiders expropriate minority shareholders.</description><author>Lemmon, M. L.; Lins, K. V.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does shareholder composition matter? Evidence from the market reaction to corporate earnings announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hotchkiss, E. S.; Strickland, D.
We examine whether institutional ownership composition is related to parameters of the market reaction to negative earnings announcements. When firms report earnings below analysts' expectations, the stock price response is more negative for firms with higher levels of ownership by momentum or aggressive growth investors. There is no evidence, however, that these institutions cause an "overreaction" to earnings news. Ownership structure is also related to trading volume and to stock price volatility on days around earnings announcements. Our findings are consistent with the idea that the composition of institutional shareholders effects stock price behavior around the release of corporate information.</description><author>Hotchkiss, E. S.; Strickland, D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rumors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Bommel, J.
A Kyle (1985) model with private information diffusion is used to examine the motivation to spread stock tips. An informed investor with limited investment capacity spreads imprecise rumors to an audience of followers. Followers trade on the advice and move the price. Due to the imprecision of the rumor, the price overshoots with positive probability. This gives the rumormonger the opportunity to trade twice: First when she receives information, then when she knows the price to be overshooting. In equilibrium, rumors are informative and both rumormongers and followers increase their profits at the expense of uninformed liquidity traders.</description><author>Van Bommel, J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum and reversals in equity-index returns during periods of abnormal turnover and return dispersion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Connolly, R.; Stivers, C.
We document new patterns in the dynamics between stock returns and trading volume. Specifically, we find substantial momentum (reversals) in consecutive weekly returns when the latter week has unexpectedly high (low) turnover. This pattern is evident in equity indices, index futures, and individual stocks. Similarly, we also find that the autocorrelation in equity-index returns is increasing with the unexpected dispersion across the latter week's firm-level returns. Weeks with extreme turnover and dispersion shocks (both high and low) tend to have more macroeconomic news releases. Our findings bear on understanding price formation and the economic interpretation of turnover and dispersion shocks.</description><author>Connolly, R.; Stivers, C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentive compensation when executives can hedge the market: Evidence of relative performance evaluation in the cross section</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garvey, G.; Milbourn, T.
Little evidence exists that firms index executive compensation to remove the influence of marketwide factors. We argue that executives can, in principle, replicate such indexation in their private portfolios. In support, we find that market risk has little effect on the use of stock-based pay for the average executive. But executives' ability to "undo" excessive market risk can be hindered by wealth constraints and inalienability of human capital. We replicate the standard result that there is little relative performance evaluation (RPE) for the average executive, but find strong evidence of RPE for younger executives and executives with less financial wealth.</description><author>Garvey, G.; Milbourn, T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax-induced trading of equity securities: Evidence from the ADR market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Callaghan, S. R.; Barry, C. B.
We examine ex-dividend date trading of American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) using a sample of 1,043 dividends over the period 1988 to 1995. ADR dividends are often subject to foreign withholding taxes, creating incentives for certain investors to avoid the distribution. ADRs exhibit negative abnormal ex-dividend day returns, and their prices behave consistently with their related withholding taxes. Abnormal trading volume for taxable issues exceeds 130 percent and 300 percent of normal volume on the cum- and ex-dates, respectively. Abnormal volume is an increasing function of foreign withholding tax rates and decreasing function of transactions costs. This abnormal ex-date trading activity is consistent with tax-motivated trading.</description><author>Callaghan, S. R.; Barry, C. B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance incentives within firms: The effect of managerial responsibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, R. K.; Samwick, A. A.
We show that top management incentives vary by responsibility. For oversight executives, pay-performance incentives are $1.22 per thousand dollar increase in shareholder wealth higher than for divisional executives. For CEOs, incentives are $5.65 higher than for divisional executives. Incentives for the median top management team are substantial at $32.32. CEOs account for 42 to 58 percent of aggregate team incentives. For divisional executives, the pay divisional performance sensitivity is positive and increasing in the precision of divisional performance and the pay-firm performance sensitivity is decreasing in the precision of divisional performance. These results support principal-agent models with multiple signals of managerial effort.</description><author>Aggarwal, R. K.; Samwick, A. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk reduction in large portfolios: Why imposing the wrong constraints helps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, R.; Ma, T. S.
Green and Hollifield (1992) argue that the presence of a dominant factor would result in extreme negative weights in mean-variance efficient portfolios even in the absence of estimation errors. In that case, imposing no-short-sale constraints should hurt, whereas empirical evidence is often to the contrary We reconcile this apparent contradiction. We explain why constraining portfolio weights to be nonnegative can reduce the risk in estimated optimal portfolios even when the constraints are wrong. Surprisingly, with no-short-sale constraints in place, the sample covariance matrix performs as well as covariance matrix estimates based on factor models, shrinkage estimators, and daily data.</description><author>Jagannathan, R.; Ma, T. S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-water marks and hedge fund management contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goetzmann, W. N.; Ingersoll, J. E.; Ross, S. A.
Incentive fees for money managers are frequently accompanied by high-water mark provisions that condition the payment of the performance fee upon exceeding the previously achieved maximum share value. In this paper, we show that hedge fund performance fees are valuable to money managers, and conversely, represent a claim on a significant proportion of investor wealth. The high-water mark provisions in these contracts limit the value of the performance fees. We provide a closed-form solution to the cost of the high-water mark contract under certain conditions. Our results provide a framework for valuation of a hedge fund management company.</description><author>Goetzmann, W. N.; Ingersoll, J. E.; Ross, S. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivatives: The tools that changed finance.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milevsky, M. A.
nan</description><author>Milevsky, M. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Editor of The Journal of Finance for the year 2002</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, R. C.
nan</description><author>Green, R. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The presidential puzzle: Political cycles and the stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santa-Clara, P.; Valkanov, R.
The excess return in the stock market is higher under Democratic than Republican presidencies: 9 percent for the value-weighted and 16 percent for the equal-weighted portfolio. The difference comes from higher real stock returns and lower real interest rates, is statistically significant, and is robust in subsamples. The difference in returns is not explained by business-cycle variables related to expected returns, and is not concentrated around election dates. There is no difference in the riskiness of the stock market across presidencies that could justify a risk premium. The difference in returns through the political cycle is therefore a puzzle.</description><author>Santa-Clara, P.; Valkanov, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How investors interpret past fund returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lynch, A. W.; Musto, D. K.
The literature documents a convex relation between past returns and fund flows of mutual funds. We show this to be consistent with fund incentives, because funds discard exactly those strategies which underperform. Past returns tell less about the future performance of funds which discard, so flows are less sensitive to them when they are poor. Our model predicts that strategy changes only occur after bad performance, and that bad performers who change strategy have dollar flow and future performance that are less sensitive to current performance than those that do not. Empirical tests support both predictions.</description><author>Lynch, A. W.; Musto, D. K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency orders and exchange rate dynamics: An explanation for the predictive success of technical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Osler, C. L.
This paper documents clustering in currency stop-loss and take-profit orders, and uses that clustering to provide an explanation for two familiar predictions from technical analysis: (1) trends tend to reverse course at predictable support and resistance levels, and (2) trends tend to be unusually rapid after rates cross such levels. The data are the first available on individual currency stop-loss and take-profit orders. Take-profit orders cluster particularly strongly at round numbers, which could explain the first prediction. Stop-loss orders cluster strongly just beyond round numbers, which could explain the second prediction.</description><author>Osler, C. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the international convergence of capital adequacy regulation desirable?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, V. V.
The merit of international convergence of bank capital requirements in the presence of divergent closure policies of different central banks is examined. The lack of a complementary variation between minimum bank capital requirements and regulatory forbearance leads to a spillover from more forbearing to less forbearing economies and reduces the competitive advantage of banks in less forbearing economies. Linking the central bank's forbearance to its alignment with domestic bank owners, it is shown that in equilibrium, a regression toward the worst closure policy may result: The central banks of initially less forbearing economies also adopt greater forbearance.</description><author>Acharya, V. V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder taxes in acquisition premiums: The effect of capital gains taxation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayers, B. C.; Lefanowicz, C. E.; Robinson, J. R.
We exploit cross-temporal differences in capital gains tax rates to test whether shareholder-level capital gains taxes are associated with higher acquisition premiums for taxable acquisitions. We model acquisition premiums as a function of proxies for the capital gains taxes of target shareholders, taxability of the acquisition, and tax status of the price-setting shareholder as represented by the level of target institutional ownership. Consistent with a lock-in effect for acquisition premiums, results suggest a unique positive association between shareholder capital gains taxes for individual investors and acquisition premiums for taxable acquisitions, which is mitigated by target institutional ownership.</description><author>Ayers, B. C.; Lefanowicz, C. E.; Robinson, J. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Divestitures and divisional investment policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, A.; Shivdasani, A.
We study a sample of diversified firms that alter their organizational structure by divesting a business segment. These firms experience a reduction in the diversification discount after the divestiture. We show that the efficiency of segment investment increases substantially following the divestiture and that this improvement is associated with a decrease in the diversification discount. Our results support the corporate focus and financing hypotheses for corporate divestitures. We demonstrate that inefficient investment is partly responsible for the diversification discount and show that asset sales lead to an improvement in the efficiency of investment for remaining divisions.</description><author>Dittmar, A.; Shivdasani, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure and financial risk: Evidence from foreign debt use in East Asia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allayannis, G.; Brown, G. W.; Klapper, L. F.
Using a data set of East Asian nonfinancial companies, we examine a firm's choice between local, foreign, and synthetic local currency (hedged foreign currency) debt. We find evidence of unique as well as common factors that determine each debt type's use, indicating the importance of examining debt at a disaggregated level. We exploit the Asian financial crisis as a natural experiment to investigate the role of debt type in firm performance. Surprisingly, we find that the use of synthetic local currency debt is associated with the biggest drop in market value, possibly due to currency derivative market illiquidity during the crisis.</description><author>Allayannis, G.; Brown, G. W.; Klapper, L. F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of institutional and individual trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, J. M.; Harris, J. H.; Topaloglu, S.
We study the daily and intradaily cross-sectional relation between stock returns and the trading of institutional and individual investors in Nasdaq 100 securities. Based on the previous day's stock return, the top performing decile of securities is 23.9% more likely to be bought in net by institutions (and sold by individuals) than those in the bottom performance decile. Strong contemporaneous daily patterns can largely be explained by net institutional (individual) trading positively (negatively) following past intradaily excess stock returns (or the news associated therein). In comparison, evidence of return predictability and price pressure are economically small.</description><author>Griffin, J. M.; Harris, J. H.; Topaloglu, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity volatility and corporate bond yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, J. Y.; Taksler, G. B.
This paper explores the effect of equity volatility on corporate bond yields. Panel data for the late 1990s show that idiosyncratic firm-level volatility can explain as much cross-sectional variation in yields as can credit ratings. This finding, together with the upward trend in idiosyncratic equity volatility documented by Campbell, Lettau, Malkiel, and Xu (2001), helps to explain recent increases in corporate bond yields.</description><author>Campbell, J. Y.; Taksler, G. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional investors and executive compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartzell, J. C.; Starks, L. T.
We find that institutional ownership concentration is positively related to the pay-for-performance sensitivity of executive compensation and negatively related to the level of compensation, even after controlling for firm size, industry, investment opportunities, and performance. These results suggest that the institutions serve a monitoring role in mitigating the agency problem between shareholders and managers. Additionally, we find that clientele effects exist among institutions for firms with certain compensation structures, suggesting that institutions also influence compensation structures through their preferences.</description><author>Hartzell, J. C.; Starks, L. T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday price formation in US equity index markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasbrouck, J.
The market for U.S. equity indexes presently comprises floor-traded index futures contracts, exchange-traded funds (ETFs), electronically traded, small-denomination futures contracts (E-minis), and sector ETFs that decompose the S&amp;P 500 index into component industry portfolios. This paper empirically investigates price discovery in this environment. For the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq-100 indexes, most of the price discovery occurs in the E-mini market. For the S&amp;P 400 MidCap index, price discovery is shared between the regular futures contract and the ETF. The S&amp;P 500 ETF contributes markedly to price discovery in the sector ETFs, but there are only minor effects in the reverse direction.</description><author>Hasbrouck, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial development, property rights, and growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claessens, S.; Laeven, L.
In countries with more secure property rights, firms might allocate resources better and consequentially grow faster as the returns on different types of assets are more protected against competitors' actions. Using data on sectoral value added for a large number of countries, we find evidence consistent with better property rights leading to higher growth through improved asset allocation. Quantitatively, the growth effect is as large as that of improved access to financing due to greater financial development. Our results are robust using various samples and specifications, including controlling for growth opportunities.</description><author>Claessens, S.; Laeven, L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Behavior of bid-ask spreads and volume in options markets during the competition for listings in 1999</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Fontnouvelle, P.; Fishe, R. P. H.; Harris, J. H.
In August 1999, U.S. exchanges began to compete directly for order flow in many options that had been exclusively listed on another exchange, shifting 37% of option volume to multiple-listing status by the end of September. Effective and quoted bid-ask spreads decrease significantly after multiple listings with spreads generally maintaining their initial lower levels 1 year later. These results hold for both time series and pooled regressions and are robust. We reject that economies of scale in market making cause the decrease in spreads and support the view that interexchange competition reduces option transaction costs.</description><author>De Fontnouvelle, P.; Fishe, R. P. H.; Harris, J. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model misspecification and underdiversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uppal, R.; Wang, T.
In this paper, we study intertemporal portfolio choice when an investor accounts explicitly for model misspecification. We develop a framework that allows for ambiguity about not just the joint distribution of returns for all stocks in the portfolio, but also for different levels of ambiguity for the marginal distribution of returns for any subset of these stocks. We find that when the overall ambiguity about the joint distribution of returns is high, then small differences in ambiguity for the marginal return distribution will result in a portfolio that is significantly underdiversified relative to the standard mean-variance portfolio.</description><author>Uppal, R.; Wang, T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulation fair disclosure and earnings information: Market, analyst, and corporate responses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bailey, W.; Li, H. T.; Mao, C. X.; Zhong, R.
With the adoption of Regulation Fair Disclosure (Reg FD), market behavior around earnings releases displays no significant change in return volatility (after controlling for decimalization of stock trading) but significant increases in trading volume due to difference in opinion. Analyst forecast dispersion increases, and increases in other measures of disagreement and difference of opinion suggest greater difficulty in forming forecasts beyond the current quarter. Corporations increase the quantity of voluntary disclosures, but only for current quarter earnings. Thus, Reg FD seems to increase the quantity of information available to the public while imposing greater demands on investment professionals.</description><author>Bailey, W.; Li, H. T.; Mao, C. X.; Zhong, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum investing and business cycle risk: Evidence from pole to pole</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, J. M.; Ji, X. Q.; Martin, J. S.
We examine whether macroeconomic risk can explain momentum profits internationally. Neither an unconditional model based on the Chen, Roll, and Ross (1986) factors nor a conditional forecasting model based on lagged instruments provides any evidence that macroeconomic risk variables can explain momentum. In addition, momentum profits around the world are economically large and statistically reliable in both good and bad economic states. Further, these momentum profits reverse over 1- to 5-year horizons, an action inconsistent with existing risk-based explanations of momentum.</description><author>Griffin, J. M.; Ji, X. Q.; Martin, J. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock valuation and learning about profitability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, L.; Veronesi, P.
We develop a simple approach to valuing stocks in the presence of learning about average profitability. The market-to-book ratio (M/B) increases with uncertainty about average profitability, especially for firms that pay no dividends. M/B is predicted to decline over a firm's lifetime due to learning, with steeper decline when the firm is young. These predictions are confirmed empirically. Data also support the predictions that younger stocks and stocks that pay no dividends have more volatile returns. Firm profitability has become more volatile recently, helping explain the puzzling increase in average idiosyncratic return volatility observed over the past few decades.</description><author>Pastor, L.; Veronesi, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What type of process underlies options? A simple robust test</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carr, P.; Wu, L. R.
We develop a simple robust method to distinguish the presence of continuous and discontinuous components in the price of an asset underlying options. Our method examines the prices of at-the-money and out-of-the-money options as the option's time-to-maturity approaches zero. We show that these prices converge to zero at speeds that depend upon whether the underlying asset price process is purely continuous, purely discontinuous, or a combination of both. We apply the method to S&amp;P 500 index options and find the existence of both a continuous component and a jump component in the index.</description><author>Carr, P.; Wu, L. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do price discreteness and transactions costs affect stock returns? Comparing ex-dividend pricing before and after decimalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, J. R.; Michaely, R.; Roberts, M. R.
By the end of January 2001, all NYSE stocks had converted their price quotations from 1/8s and 1/16s to decimals. This study examines the effect of this change in price quotations on ex-dividend day activity. We find that abnormal ex-dividend day returns increase in the 1/16 and decimal pricing eras, relative to the 1/8 era, which is inconsistent with microstructure explanations of exday price movements. We also find that abnormal returns increase in conjunction with a May 1997 reduction in the capital gains tax rate, as they should if relative taxation of dividends and capital gains affects ex-day pricing.</description><author>Graham, J. R.; Michaely, R.; Roberts, M. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition among trading venues: Information and trading on electronic communications networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barclay, M. J.; Hendershott, T.; McCormick, D. T.
This paper explores the competition between two trading venues, Electronic Communication Networks (ECNs) and Nasdaq market makers. ECNs offer the advantages of anonymity and speed of execution, which attract informed traders. Thus, trades are more likely to occur on ECNs when information asymmetry is greater and when trading volume and stock-return volatility are high. ECN trades have greater permanent price impacts and more private information is revealed through ECN trades than though market-maker trades. However, ECN trades have higher ex ante trading costs because market makers can preference or internalize the less informed trades and offer them better executions.</description><author>Barclay, M. J.; Hendershott, T.; McCormick, D. T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium "anomalies"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferguson, M. F.; Shockley, R. L.
Many empirical "anomalies" are actually consistent with the single beta capital asset pricing model if the empiricist utilizes an equity-only proxy for the true market portfolio. Equity betas estimated against this particular inefficient proxy will be understated, with the error increasing with the firm's leverage. Thus, firm-specific variables that correlate with leverage (such as book-to-market and size) will appear to explain returns after controlling for proxy beta simply because they capture the missing beta risk. Loadings on portfolios formed on relative leverage and relative distress completely subsume the powers of the Fama and French (1993) returns to small minus big market capitalization (SMB) portfolios and returns to high minus low book-to-market (HML) portfolios factors in explaining cross-sectional returns.</description><author>Ferguson, M. F.; Shockley, R. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation of the debt tax shield</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kemsley, D.; Nissim, D.
In this study, we use cross-sectional regressions to estimate the value of the debt tax shield. Recognizing that debt is correlated with the value of operations along nontax dimensions, we estimate reverse regressions in which we regress future profitability on firm value and debt rather than regressing firm value on debt and profitability. Reversing the regressions mitigates bias and facilitates the use of market information to control for differences in risk and expected growth. Our estimated value for the debt tax shield is approximately 40 percent (10 percent) of debt balances (firm value), net of the personal tax disadvantage of debt.</description><author>Kemsley, D.; Nissim, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The making of a dealer market: From entry to equilibrium in the trading of Nasdaq stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, K.; Michaely, R.; O'Hara, M.
This paper provides an analysis of the nature and evolution of a dealer market for Nasdaq stocks. Despite size differences in sample stocks, there is a surprising consistency to their trading. One dealer tends to dominate trading in a stock. Markets are concentrated and spreads are increasing in the volume and market share of the dominant dealer. Entry and exit are ubiquitous. Exiting dealers are those with very low profits and trading volume. Entering market makers fail to capture a meaningful share of trading or profits. Thus, free entry does little to improve the competitive nature of the market as entering dealers have little impact. We find, however, that for small stocks, the Nasdaq dealer market is being more competitive than the specialist market.</description><author>Ellis, K.; Michaely, R.; O'Hara, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Telling from discrete data whether the underlying continuous-time model is a diffusion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ait-Sahalia, Y.
Can discretely sampled financial data help us decide which continuous-time models are sensible? Diffusion processes are characterized by the continuity of their sample paths. This cannot be verified from the discrete sample path: Even if the underlying path were continuous, data sampled at discrete times will always appear as a succession of jumps. Instead, I rely on the transition density to determine whether the discontinuities observed are the result of the discreteness of sampling, or rather evidence of genuine jump dynamics for the underlying continuous-time process. I then focus on the implications of this approach for option pricing models.</description><author>Ait-Sahalia, Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differences of opinion and the cross section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diether, K. B.; Malloy, C. J.; Scherbina, A.
We provide evidence that stocks with higher dispersion in analysts' earnings forecasts earn lower future returns than otherwise similar stocks. This effect is most pronounced in small stocks and stocks that have performed poorly over the past year. Interpreting dispersion in analysts' forecasts as a proxy for differences in opinion about a stock, we show that this evidence is consistent with the hypothesis that prices will reflect the optimistic view whenever investors with the lowest valuations do not trade. By contrast, our evidence is inconsistent with a view that dispersion in analysts' forecasts proxies for risk.</description><author>Diether, K. B.; Malloy, C. J.; Scherbina, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A test of the errors-in-expectations explanation of the value/glamour stock returns performance: Evidence from analysts' forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doukas, J. A.; Kim, C.; Pantzalis, C.
Several empirical studies show that investment strategies that favor the purchase of stocks with low prices relative to conventional measures of value yield higher returns. Some of these studies imply that investors are too optimistic about (glamour) stocks that have had good performance in the recent past and too pessimistic about (value) stocks that have performed poorly. We examine whether investors systematically overestimate (underestimate) the future earnings performance of glamour (value) stocks over the 1976 to 1997 period. Our results fail to support the extrapolation hypothesis that posits that the superior performance of value stocks is because investors make systematic errors in predicting future growth in earnings of out-of-favor stocks.</description><author>Doukas, J. A.; Kim, C.; Pantzalis, C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate diversification: What gets discounted?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mansi, S. A.; Reeb, D. M.
Prior literature finds that diversified firms sell at a discount relative to the sum of the imputed values of their business segments. We explore this documented discount and argue that it stems from risk-reducing effects of corporate diversification. Consistent with this risk-reduction hypothesis, we find that (a) shareholder losses in diversification are a function of firm leverage, (b) all equity firms do not exhibit a diversification discount, and (c) using book values of debt to compute excess value creates a downward bias for diversified firms. Overall, the results indicate that diversification is insignificantly related to excess firm value.</description><author>Mansi, S. A.; Reeb, D. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is information risk a determinant of asset returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, D.; Hvidkjaer, S.; O'Hara, M.
We investigate the role of information-based trading in affecting asset returns. We show in a rational expectation example how private information affects equilibrium asset returns. Using a market microstructure model, we derive a measure of the probability of information-based trading, and we estimate this measure using data for individual NYSE-listed stocks for 1983 to 1998. We then incorporate our estimates into a Fama and French (1992) asset-pricing framework. Our main result is that information does affect asset prices. A difference of 10 percentage points in the probability of information-based trading between two stocks leads to a difference in their expected returns of 2.5 percent per year.</description><author>Easley, D.; Hvidkjaer, S.; O'Hara, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No contagion, only interdependence: Measuring stock market comovements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Forbes, K. J.; Rigobon, R.
Heteroskedasticity biases tests for contagion based on correlation coefficients. When contagion is defined as a significant increase in market comovement after a shock to one country, previous work suggests contagion occurred during recent crises. This paper shows that correlation coefficients are conditional on market volatility. Under certain assumptions, it is possible to adjust for this bias. Using this adjustment, there was virtually no increase in unconditional correlation coefficients (i.e., no contagion) during the 1997 Asian crisis, 1994 Mexican devaluation, and 1987 U.S. market crash. There is a high level of market comovement in all periods, however, which we call interdependence.</description><author>Forbes, K. J.; Rigobon, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An investigation of the informational role of short interest in the Nasdaq market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, H.; Ramesh, K.; Thiagarajan, S. R.; Balachandran, B. V.
This paper examines the relationship between the level of short interest and stock returns in the Nasdaq market from June 1988 through December 1994. We find that heavily shorted firms experience significant negative abnormal returns ranging from -0. 76 to -1.13 percent per month after controlling for the market, size, book-to-market, and momentum factors. These negative returns increase with the level of short interest, indicating that a higher level of short interest is a stronger bearish signal. We find that heavily shorted firms are more likely to be delisted compared to their size, book-to-market, and momentum matched control firms.</description><author>Desai, H.; Ramesh, K.; Thiagarajan, S. R.; Balachandran, B. V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Book-to-market equity, distress risk, and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, J. M.; Lemmon, M. L.
This paper examines the relationship between book-to-market equity, distress risk, and stock returns. Among firms with the highest distress risk as proxied by Ohlson's (1980) O-score, the difference in returns between high and low book-to-market securities is more than twice as large as that in other firms. This large return differential cannot be explained by the three-factor model or by differences in economic fundamentals. Consistent with mispricing arguments, firms with high distress risk exhibit the largest return reversals around earnings announcements, and the book-to-market effect is largest in small firms with low analyst coverage.</description><author>Griffin, J. M.; Lemmon, M. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical evaluation of asset-pricing models: A comparison of the SDF and beta methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, R.; Wang, Z. Y.
The stochastic discount factor (SDF) method provides a unified general framework for econometric analysis of asset-pricing models. There have been concerns that, compared to the classical beta method, the generality of the SDF method comes at the cost of efficiency in parameter estimation and power in specification tests. We establish the correct framework for comparing the two methods and show that the SDF method is as efficient as the beta method for estimating risk premiums. Also, the specification test based on the SDF method is as powerful as the one based on the beta method.</description><author>Jagannathan, R.; Wang, Z. Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Survival bias and the equity premium puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, H. T.; Xu, Y. W.
Previous authors have raised the concern that there could be serious survival bias in the observed U.S. equity premium. Contrary to conventional wisdom, we argue that the survival bias in the U.S. data is unlikely to be significant. To reach this conclusion, we introduce a general framework for modeling survival and derive a mathematical relationship between the ex ante survival probability and the average survival bias. This relationship reveals the fundamental difficulty facing the survival argument: High survival bias requires an ex ante probability of market failure, which seems unrealistically high given the history of world financial markets.</description><author>Li, H. T.; Xu, Y. W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global diversification, industrial diversification, and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, D. J.; Denis, D. K.; Yost, K.
Using a sample of 44,288 firm-years between 1984 and 1997, we document an increase in the extent of global diversification over time. This trend does not reflect a substitution of global for industrial diversification. We also find that global diversification results in average valuation discounts of approximately the same magnitude as those for industrial diversification. Analysis of the changes in excess value associated with changes in diversification reveals that increases in global diversification reduce excess value, while reductions in global diversification increase excess value. These findings support the view that the costs of global diversification outweigh the benefits.</description><author>Denis, D. J.; Denis, D. K.; Yost, K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who blinks in volatile markets, individuals or institutions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dennis, P. J.; Strickland, D.
We investigate the relationship between the ownership structure and returns of firms on days when the absolute value of the market's return is two percent or more. We find that a firm's abnormal return on these days is related to the percentage of institutional ownership, that there is abnormally high turnover in the firm's shares on these days, and that this abnormal turnover is significantly related to the percentage of institutional ownership in the firm. Taken together, these results are consistent with positive feedback herding behavior on the part of some institutions, particularly mutual and pension funds.</description><author>Dennis, P. J.; Strickland, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information production and capital allocation: Decentralized versus hierarchical firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stein, J. C.
This paper asks how well different organizational structures perform in terms of generating information about investment projects and allocating capital to these projects. A decentralized approach-with small, single-manager firms-is most likely to be attractive when information about projects is "soft" and cannot be credibly transmitted. In contrast, large hierarchies perform better when information can be costlessly "hardened" and passed along inside the firm. The model can be used to think about the consequences of consolidation in the banking industry, particularly the documented tendency for mergers to lead to declines in small-business lending.</description><author>Stein, J. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Takeover defenses of IPO firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Field, L. C.; Karpoff, J. M.
Many firms deploy takeover defenses when they go public. IPO managers tend to deploy defenses when their compensation is high, shareholdings are small, and oversight from nonmanagerial shareholders is weak. The presence of a defense is negatively related to subsequent acquisition likelihood, yet has no impact on takeover premiums for firms that are acquired. These results do not support arguments that takeover defenses facilitate the eventual sale of IPO firms at high takeover premiums. Rather, they suggest that managers shift the cost of takeover protection onto nonmanagerial shareholders. Thus, agency problems are important even for firms at the IPO stage.</description><author>Field, L. C.; Karpoff, J. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term structure of interest rates with regime shifts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bansal, R.; Zhou, H.
We develop a term structure model where the short interest rate and the market price of risks are subject to discrete regime shifts. Empirical evidence from efficient method of moments estimation provides considerable support for the regime shifts model. Standard models, which include affine specifications with up to three factors, are sharply rejected in the data. Our diagnostics show that only the regime shifts model can account for the well-documented violations of the expectations hypothesis, the observed conditional volatility, and the conditional correlation across yields. We find that regimes are intimately related to business cycles.</description><author>Bansal, R.; Zhou, H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited arbitrage in equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitchell, M.; Pulvino, T.; Stafford, E.
We examine 82 situations where the market value of a company is less than its subsidiary, These situations imply arbitrage opportunities, providing an ideal setting to study the risks and market frictions that prevent arbitrageurs from immediately forcing prices to fundamental values. For 30 percent of the sample, the link between the parent and its subsidiary is severed before the relative value discrepancy is corrected. Furthermore, returns to a specialized arbitrageur would be 50 percent larger if the path to convergence was smooth rather than as observed. Uncertainty about the distribution of returns and characteristics of the risks limits arbitrage.</description><author>Mitchell, M.; Pulvino, T.; Stafford, E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational momentum effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, T. C.
Momentum effects in stock returns need not imply investor irrationality, heterogeneous information, or market frictions. A simple, single-firm model with a standard pricing kernel can produce such effects when expected dividend growth rates vary over time. An enhanced model, under which persistent growth rate shocks occur episodically, can match many of the features documented by the empirical research. The same basic mechanism could potentially account for underreaction anomalies in general.</description><author>Johnson, T. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial opportunism? Evidence from directors' and officers' insurance purchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chalmers, J. M. R.; Dann, L. Y.; Harford, J.
We analyze a sample of 72 IPO firms that went public between 1992 and 1996 for which we have detailed proprietary information about the amount and cost of D&amp;O liability insurance. If managers of IPO firms are exploiting superior inside information, we hypothesize that the amount of insurance coverage chosen will be related to the post-offering performance of the issuing firm's shares. Consistent with the hypothesis, we find a significant negative relation between the three-year post-IPO stock price performance and the insurance coverage purchased in conjunction with the IPO. One plausible interpretation is that, like insider securities transactions, D&amp;O insurance decisions reveal opportunistic behavior by managers. This provides some motivation to argue that disclosure of the details of D&amp;O insurance decisions, as is required in some other countries, is valuable.</description><author>Chalmers, J. M. R.; Dann, L. Y.; Harford, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The equity premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.
We estimate the equity premium using dividend and earnings growth rates to measure the expected rate of capital gain. Our estimates for 1951 to 2000, 2.55 percent and 4.32 percent, are much lower than the equity premium produced by the average stock return, 7.43 percent. Our evidence suggests that the high average return for 1951 to 2000 is due to a decline in discount rates that produces a large unexpected capital gain. Our main conclusion is that the average stock return of the last half-century is a lot higher than expected.</description><author>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leaning for the tape: Evidence of gaming behavior in equity mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carhart, M. M.; Kaniel, R.; Musto, D. K.; Reed, A. V.
We present evidence that fund managers inflate quarter-end portfolio prices with last-minute purchases of stocks already held. The magnitude of price inflation ranges from 0.5 percent per year for large-cap funds to well over 2 percent for small-cap funds. We find that the cross section of inflation matches the cross section of incentives from the flow/performance relation, that a surge of trading in the quarter's last minutes coincides with a surge in equity prices, and that the inflation is greatest for the stocks held by funds with the most incentive to inflate, controlling for the stocks' size and performance.</description><author>Carhart, M. M.; Kaniel, R.; Musto, D. K.; Reed, A. V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does corporate diversification destroy value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, J. R.; Lemmon, M. L.; Wolf, J. G.
We analyze several hundred firms that expand via acquisition and/or increase their number of business segments. The combined market reaction to acquisition announcements is positive but acquiring firm excess values decline after the diversifying event. Much of the excess value reduction occurs because our sample firms acquire already discounted business units, and not because diversifying destroys value. This implies that the standard assumption that conglomerate divisions can be benchmarked to typical stand-alone firms should be carefully reconsidered. We also show that excess value does not decline when firms increase their number of business segments because of pure reporting changes.</description><author>Graham, J. R.; Lemmon, M. L.; Wolf, J. G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do conglomerate firms allocate resources inefficiently across industries? Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maksimovic, V.; Phillips, G.
We develop a profit - maximizing neoclassical model of optimal firm size and growth across different industries based on differences in industry fundamentals and firm productivity. In the model, a conglomerate discount is consistent with profit maximization. The model predicts how conglomerate firms will allocate resources across divisions over the business cycle and how their responses to industry shocks will differ from those of single-segment firms. Using plant level data, we find that growth and investment of conglomerate and single-segment firms is related to fundamental industry factors and individual segment level productivity. The majority of conglomerate firms exhibit growth across industry segments that is consistent with optimal behavior.</description><author>Maksimovic, V.; Phillips, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A rational expectations model of financial contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kodres, L. E.; Pritsker, M.
We develop a multiple asset rational expectations model of asset prices to explain financial market contagion. Although the model allows contagion through several channels, our focus is on contagion through cross-market rebalancing. Through this channel, investors transmit idiosyncratic shocks from one market to others by adjusting their portfolios' exposures to shared macroeconomic risks. The pattern and severity of financial contagion depends on markets' sensitivities to shared macroeconomic risk factors, and on the amount of information asymmetry in each market. The model can generate contagion in the absence of news, as well as between markets that do not directly share macroeconomic risks.</description><author>Kodres, L. E.; Pritsker, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The volatility and price sensitivities of managerial stock option portfolios and corporate hedging</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knopf, J. D.; Nam, J.; Thornton, J. H.
We use estimates of the Black-Scholes sensitivity of managers' stock option portfolios to stock return volatility and the sensitivity of managers' stock and stock option portfolios to stock price to test the relationship between managers' risk preferences and hedging activities. We find that as the sensitivity of managers' stock and stock option portfolios to stock price increases, firms tend to hedge more. However, as the sensitivity of managers' stock option portfolios to stock return volatility increases, firms tend to hedge less.</description><author>Knopf, J. D.; Nam, J.; Thornton, J. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do firms hedge in response to tax incentives?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, J. R.; Rogers, D. A.
There are two tax incentives for corporations to hedge: to increase debt capacity and interest tax deductions, and to reduce expected tax liability if the tax function is convex. We test whether these incentives affect the extent of corporate hedging with derivatives. Using an explicit measure of tax function convexity, we find no evidence that firms hedge in response to tax convexity. Our analysis does, however, indicate that firms hedge to increase debt capacity, with increased tax benefits averaging 1.1 percent of firm value. Our results also indicate that firms hedge because of expected financial distress costs and firm size.</description><author>Graham, J. R.; Rogers, D. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity provision and the organizational form of NYSE specialist firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coughenour, J. F.; Deli, D. N.
We examine the influence of NYSE specialist firm organizational form on the nature of liquidity provision. We compare closely held firms whose specialists provide liquidity with their own capital to widely held firms whose specialists provide liquidity with diffusely owned capital. We argue that specialists using their own capital have a greater incentive and ability to reduce adverse selection costs, but face a greater cost of capital. Differences in the proportion of spreads due to adverse selection costs, large trade frequency, the sensitivity between depth and spreads, and price stabilization support this argument.</description><author>Coughenour, J. F.; Deli, D. N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The long-run performance following dividend initiations and resumptions: Underreaction or product of chance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehme, R. D.; Sorescu, S. M.
We examine the long-term stock performance following dividend initiations and resumptions from 1927 to 1998. We show that post announcement abnormal returns are significantly positive for equally weighted calendar time portfolios, but become insignificant when the portfolios are value weighted. Moreover, the equally weighted results are not robust across subsamples. We also document postannouncement reductions in the risk factor loadings of underlying stocks. Cross-sectionally, these reductions are negatively related to the contemporaneous price drifts, suggesting the price drifts may be a sample-specific result of chance. Our results underscore the importance of testing for changes in risk loadings in future long-term event studies.</description><author>Boehme, R. D.; Sorescu, S. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where does State Street lead? A first look at finance patents, 1971 to 2000</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lerner, J.
This paper empirically examines patents for financial formulas and methods, whose patentability was recently confirmed in the litigation between State Street Bank and Trust and Signature Financial Group. The number of such filings and awards has been accelerating. Patent filings by academics have been very infrequent, which appears to be a consequence of a lack of awareness or interest on the part of faculty members, rather than any fundamental unsuitability of their research for patenting. The failure to cite academic research in this area appears to be problematic and may reflect patent examiners' limited exposure to finance research and patents.</description><author>Lerner, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, market structure, and bid-ask spreads in stock option markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mayhew, S.
This paper examines the effects of competition and market structure on equity option bid-ask spreads from 1986 to 1997. Options listed on multiple exchanges have narrower spreads than those listed on a single exchange, but the difference diminishes as option volume increases. Option spreads become wider when a competing exchange delists the option. Options traded under a "Designated Primary Marketmaker" (DPM) have narrower quoted spreads than those traded in a traditional open outcry crowd. Effective spreads are found to be slightly narrower under the DPM than in the crowd, but only since 1992, and only on low-volume options.</description><author>Mayhew, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk aversion, transparency, and market performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Frutos, M. A.; Manzano, C.
Using a model of market making with inventories based on Biais (1993), we find that investors obtain more favorable execution prices, and they hence invest more, when markets are fragmented. In our model, risk-averse dealers use less aggressive price strategies in more transparent markets (centralized) because quote dissemination alleviates uncertainty about the prices quoted by other dealers and, hence, reduces the need to compete aggressively for order flow. Further, we show that the move toward greater transparency (centralization) may have detrimental effects on liquidity and welfare.</description><author>De Frutos, M. A.; Manzano, C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum, business cycle, and time-varying expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, T.; Shivakumar, L.
A growing number of researchers argue that time-series patterns in returns are due to investor irrationality and thus can be translated into abnormal profits. Continuation of short-term returns or momentum is one such pattern that has defied any rational explanation and is at odds with market efficiency. This paper shows that profits to momentum strategies can be explained by a set of lagged macroeconomic variables and payoffs to momentum strategies disappear once stock returns are adjusted for their predictability based on these macroeconomic variables. Our results provide a possible role for time-varying expected returns as an explanation for momentum payoffs.</description><author>Chordia, T.; Shivakumar, L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial markets and corporate finance: Selected papers of Michael J. Brennan.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kraus, A.; Sagi, J.
nan</description><author>Kraus, A.; Sagi, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of executive compensation.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shivdasani, A.
nan</description><author>Shivdasani, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing derivative securities.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elliott, R. J.
nan</description><author>Elliott, R. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Constantinides, G. M.
The mean, covariability, and predictability of the return of different classes of financial assets challenge the rational economic model for an explanation. The unconditional mean aggregate equity premium is almost seven percent per year and remains high after adjusting downwards the sample mean premium by introducing prior beliefs about the stationarity of the price-dividend ratio and the (non) forecastability of the long-term dividend growth and price-dividend ratio. Recognition that idiosyncratic income shocks are uninsurable and concentrated in recessions contributes toward an explanation. Also borrowing constraints over the investors' life cycle that shift the stock market risk to the saving middle-aged consumers contribute toward an explanation.</description><author>Constantinides, G. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How much is investor autonomy worth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benartzi, S.; Thaler, R. H.
There is a worldwide trend towards defined contribution savings plans, where investors are often able to select their own portfolios. How much is this freedom of choice worth? We present retirement investors with information about the distribution of outcomes they could expect to obtain from the portfolios they picked for themselves, and the same information for the median portfolio selected by their peers. A majority of our survey participants actually prefer the median portfolio to the one they picked for themselves. We investigate various explanations for these findings and offer some evidence that the results are partly attributable to the fact that investors do not have well-defined preferences.</description><author>Benartzi, S.; Thaler, R. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is disinflation good for the stock market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henry, P. B.
The stock market appreciates by an average of 24 percent in real dollar terms when countries attempt to stabilize annual inflation rates that are greater than 40 percent. In contrast, the average market response is 0 when the pre-stabilization rate of inflation is less than 40 percent. These results suggest that the potential long-run benefits of stabilization may dominate short-run costs at high levels of inflation, but at low to moderate levels of inflation, benefits may be offset by costs in a present value sense. Stock market responses also help predict the change in inflation and output in the year following all 81 stabilization efforts.</description><author>Henry, P. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividends, share repurchases, and the substitution hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grullon, G.; Michaely, R.
We show that repurchases have not only became an important form of payout for U.S. corporations, but also that firms finance their share repurchases with funds that otherwise would have been used to increase dividends. We find that young firms have a higher propensity to pay cash through repurchases than they did in the past and that repurchases have become the preferred form of initiating a cash payout. Although large, established firms have generally not cut their dividends, they also show a higher propensity to pay out cash through repurchases. These findings indicate that firms have gradually substituted repurchases for dividends. Our results also suggest that before 1983, regulatory constraints inhibited firms from aggressively repurchasing shares.</description><author>Grullon, G.; Michaely, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do bonds span the fixed income markets? Theory and evidence for unspanned stochastic volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collin-Dufresne, P.; Goldstein, R. S.
Most term structure models assume bond markets are complete, that is, that all fixed income derivatives can be perfectly replicated using solely bonds. However, we find that, in practice, swap rates have limited explanatory power for returns on at-the-money straddles-portfolios mainly exposed to volatility risk. We term this empirical feature "unspanned stochastic volatility" (USV). While USV can be captured within an HJM framework, we demonstrate that bivariate models cannot exhibit USV We determine necessary and sufficient conditions for trivariate Markov affine systems to exhibit USV For such USV models, bonds alone may not be sufficient to identify all parameters. Rather, derivatives are needed.</description><author>Collin-Dufresne, P.; Goldstein, R. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining the diversification discount</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campa, J. M.; Kedia, S.
This paper argues that the documented discount on diversified firms is not per se evidence that diversification destroys value. Firms choose to diversify. We use three alternative econometric techniques to control for the endogeneity of the diversification decision, and find evidence supporting the self-selection of diversifying firms. We find a strong negative correlation between a firm's choice to diversify and firm value. The diversification discount always drops, and sometimes turns into a premium. There also exists evidence of self-selection by refocusing firms. These results point to the importance of explicitly modeling the endogeneity of the diversification status in analyzing its effect on firm value.</description><author>Campa, J. M.; Kedia, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do returns to acquiring firms tell us? Evidence from firms that make many acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuller, K.; Netter, J.; Stegemoller, M.
We study shareholder returns for firms that acquired five or more public, private, and/or subsidiary targets within a short time period. Since the same bidder chooses different types of targets and methods of payment, any variation in returns must be due to the characteristics of the target and the bid. Results indicate bidder shareholders gain when buying a private firm or subsidiary but lose when purchasing a public firm. Further, the return is greater the larger the target and if the bidder offers stock. These results are consistent with a liquidity discount, and tax and control effects in this market.</description><author>Fuller, K.; Netter, J.; Stegemoller, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A review of IPO activity, pricing, and allocations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ritter, J. R.; Welch, I.
We review the theory and evidence on IPO activity: why firms go public, why they reward first-day investors with considerable underpricing, and how. IPOs perform in the long run. Our perspective is threefold: First, we believe that many IPO phenomena are not stationary. Second, we believe research into share allocation issues is the most promising area of research in IPOs at the moment. Third, we argue that asymmetric information is not the primary driver of many IPO phenomena. Instead, we believe future progress in the literature will come from non-rational and agency conflict explanations. We describe some promising such alternatives.</description><author>Ritter, J. R.; Welch, I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markowitz's "Portfolio Selection": A fifty-year retrospective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rubinstein, M.
nan</description><author>Rubinstein, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic asset allocation under inflation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brennan, M. J.; Xia, Y. H.
We develop a simple framework for analyzing a finite-horizon investor's asset allocation problem under inflation when only nominal assets are available. The investor's optimal investment strategy and indirect utility are given in simple closed form. Hedge demands depend on the investor's horizon and risk aversion and on the maturities of the bonds included in the portfolio, When short positions are precluded, the optimal strategy consists of investments in cash, equity, and a single nominal bond with optimally chosen maturity. Both the optimal stock-bond mix and the optimal bond maturity depend on the investor's horizon and risk aversion.</description><author>Brennan, M. J.; Xia, Y. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO market cycles: Bubbles or sequential learning?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lowry, M.; Schwert, G. W.
Both IPO volume and average initial returns are highly autocorrelated. Further, more companies tend to go public following periods of high initial returns. However, we find that the level of average initial returns at the time of filing contains no information about that company's eventual underpricing. Both the cycles in initial returns and the lead-lag relation between initial returns and IPO volume are predominantly driven by information learned during the registration period. More positive information results in higher initial returns and more companies filing IPOs soon thereafter.</description><author>Lowry, M.; Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection and corporate valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>La Porta, R.; Lopez-De-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A.; Vishny, R.
We present a model of the effects of legal protection of minority shareholders and of cash-flow ownership by a controlling shareholder on the valuation of firms. We then test this model using a sample of 539 large firms from 27 wealthy economies. Consistent with the model, we find evidence of higher valuation of firms in countries with better protection of minority shareholders and in firms with higher cash-flow ownership by the controlling shareholder.</description><author>La Porta, R.; Lopez-De-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A.; Vishny, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning, asset-pricing tests, and market efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewellen, J.; Shanken, J.
This paper studies the asset-pricing implications of parameter uncertainty. We show that, when investors must learn about expected cash flows, empirical tests can find patterns in the data that differ from those perceived by rational investors. Returns might appear predictable to an econometrician, or appear to deviate from the Capital Asset Pricing Model, but investors can neither perceive nor exploit this predictability. Returns may also appear excessively volatile even though prices react efficiently to cash-flow news. We conclude that parameter uncertainty can be important for characterizing and testing market efficiency.</description><author>Lewellen, J.; Shanken, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How accurate are value-at-risk models at commercial banks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkowitz, J.; O'Brien, J.
In recent years, the trading accounts at large commercial banks have grown substantially and become progressively more diverse and complex. We provide descriptive statistics on the trading revenues from such activities and on the associated Value-at-Risk (VaR) forecasts internally estimated by banks. For a sample of large bank holding companies, we evaluate the performance of banks' trading risk models by examining the statistical accuracy of the VaR forecasts. Although a substantial literature has examined the statistical and economic meaning of Value-at-Risk models, this article is the first to provide a detailed analysis of the performance of models actually in use.</description><author>Berkowitz, J.; O'Brien, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Range-based estimation of stochastic volatility models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alizadeh, S.; Brandt, M. W.; Diebold, F. X.
We propose using the price range in the estimation of stochastic volatility models. We show theoretically, numerically, and empirically that range-based volatility proxies are not only highly efficient, but also approximately Gaussian and robust to microstructure noise. Hence range-based Gaussian quasi-maximum likelihood estimation produces highly efficient estimates of stochastic volatility models and extractions of latent volatility. We use our method to examine the dynamics of daily exchange rate volatility and find the evidence points strongly toward two-factor models with one highly persistent factor and one quickly mean-reverting factor.</description><author>Alizadeh, S.; Brandt, M. W.; Diebold, F. X.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical investigation of continuous-time equity return models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, T. G.; Benzoni, L.; Lund, J.
This paper extends the class of stochastic volatility diffusions for asset returns to encompass Poisson jumps of time-varying intensity. We find that any reasonably descriptive continuous-time model for equity-index returns must allow for discrete jumps as well as stochastic volatility with a pronounced negative relationship between return and volatility innovations. We also find that the dominant empirical characteristics of the return process appear to be priced by the option market. Our analysis indicates a general correspondence between the evidence extracted from daily equity-index returns and the stylized features of the corresponding options market prices.</description><author>Andersen, T. G.; Benzoni, L.; Lund, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The quality of ECN and Nasdaq market maker quotes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, R. D.
This paper compares the quality of quotes submitted by electronic communication networks (ECNs) and by traditional market makers to the Nasdaq quote montage. An analysis of the most active Nasdaq stocks shows that ECNs not only post informative quotes, but also, compared to market makers, ECNs post quotes rapidly and are more often at the inside. Additionally, ECN quoted spreads are smaller than dealer quoted spreads. The evidence suggests that the proliferation of alternative trading venues, such as ECNs, may promote quote quality rather than fragmenting markets. Moreover, the results suggest that a more open book contributes to quote quality.</description><author>Huang, R. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New evidence of the impact of dividend taxation and on the identity of the marginal investor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bell, L.; Jenkinson, T.
This paper examines the impact of a major change in dividend taxation introduced in the United Kingdom in July 1997, The reform was structured in such a way that the immediate impact fell almost entirely on the largest investor class in the United Kingdom, namely pension funds. We find significant changes in the valuation of dividend income after the reform, in particular for high-yielding companies. These results provide strong support for the hypothesis that taxation affects the valuation of companies, and that pension funds were the effective marginal investors for high-yielding companies.</description><author>Bell, L.; Jenkinson, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium pricing and optimal hedging in electricity forward markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, H.; Lemmon, M. L.
Spot power prices are volatile and since electricity cannot be economically stored, familiar arbitrage-based methods are not applicable for pricing power derivative contracts. This paper presents an equilibrium model implying that the forward power price is a downward biased predictor of the future spot price if expected power demand is low and demand risk is moderate. However, the equilibrium forward premium increases when either expected demand or demand variance is high, because of positive skewness in the spot power price distribution. Preliminary empirical evidence indicates that the premium in forward power prices is greatest during the summer months.</description><author>Bessembinder, H.; Lemmon, M. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do banks provide financial slack?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hadlock, C. J.; James, C. M.
We study the decision to choose bank debt rather than public securities in a firm's marginal financing choice. Using a sample of 500 firms over the 1980 to 1993 time period, we find that firms are relatively more likely to choose bank loans when variables that measure asymmetric information problems are elevated. The sensitivity of the likelihood of choosing bank debt to information problems is greater for firms with no public debt outstanding. These results are consistent with the hypothesis that banks help alleviate asymmetric information problems and that firms weigh these information benefits against a wide range of contracting costs when choosing bank financing.</description><author>Hadlock, C. J.; James, C. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional allocation in initial public offerings: Empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, R.; Prabhala, N. R.; Puri, M.
We analyze institutional allocation in initial public offerings (IPOs) using a new data set of U.S. offerings between 1997 and 1998. We document a positive relationship between institutional allocation and day one IPO returns. This is partly explained by the practice of giving institutions more shares in IPOs with strong premarket demand, consistent with book-building theories. However, institutional allocation also contains private information about first-day IPO returns not reflected in premarket demand and other public information. Our evidence supports book-building theories of IPO underpricing, but suggests that institutional allocation in underpriced issues is in excess of that explained by book-building alone.</description><author>Aggarwal, R.; Prabhala, N. R.; Puri, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nasdaq trading halts: The impact of market mechanisms on prices, trading activity, and execution costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christie, W. G.; Corwin, S. A.; Harris, J. H.
We study the effects of alternative halt and reopening procedures on prices, transaction costs, and trading activity for a sample of news-related trading halts on Nasdaq. For intraday halts that reopen after only a five-minute quotation period, inside quoted spreads more than double following halts and volatility increases to more than nine times normal levels. In contrast, halts that reopen the following day with a longer 90-minute quotation period are associated with insignificant spread effects and significantly dampened volatility effects. These results are consistent with the hypothesis that increased information transmission during the halt results in reduced posthalt uncertainty.</description><author>Christie, W. G.; Corwin, S. A.; Harris, J. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical analysis of the yield curve: The information in the data viewed through the window of Cox, Ingersoll, and Ross</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lamoureux, C. G.; Witte, H. D.
This paper uses recent advances in Bayesian estimation methods to exploit fully and efficiently the time-series and cross-sectional empirical restrictions of the Cox, Ingersoll, and Ross model of the term structure. We examine the extent to which the cross-sectional data (five different instruments) provide information about the model. We find that the time-series restrictions of the two-factor model are generally consistent with the data. However, the model's cross-sectional restrictions are not. We show that adding a third factor produces a significant statistical improvement, but causes the average time-series fit to the yields themselves to deteriorate.</description><author>Lamoureux, C. G.; Witte, H. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of the determinants and shareholder wealth effects of mutual fund mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jayaraman, N.; Khorana, A.; Nelling, E.
This study examines the determinants of mutual fund mergers and their subsequent wealth impact on shareholders of target and acquiring funds. Results indicate significant improvements in postmerger performance and a reduction in expense ratios for target fund shareholders. In contrast, acquiring fund shareholders experience a significant deterioration in postmerger performance. The net asset flows continue to remain negative for the combined fund in the year following the merger. The likelihood of a fund merger is inversely related to fund size for both within- and across-family mutual fund mergers. However, poor past performance is a significant determinant for only within-family mergers.</description><author>Jayaraman, N.; Khorana, A.; Nelling, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Concentrated corporate ownership.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, A.
nan</description><author>Dittmar, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic calculus and financial applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cassano, M. A.
nan</description><author>Cassano, M. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of corporate diversification on productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schoar, A.
Using plant-level observations from the Longitudinal Research Database I show that conglomerates are more productive than stand-alone firms at a given point in time. Dynamically, however, firms that diversify experience a net reduction in productivity. While the acquired plants increase productivity, incumbent plants suffer. Moreover, stock prices track firm productivity and this tracking is equally strong for diversified and stand-alone firms. Therefore, lower transparency of conglomerates is unlikely to explain the discrepancy between productivity and stock prices on average. Finally, I offer some evidence that this discrepancy may arise because conglomerates dissipate rents in the form of higher wages.</description><author>Schoar, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>FX trading and exchange rate dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evans, M. D. D.
I examine the sources of exchange rate dynamics by focusing on the information structure of FX trading. This structure permits the existence of an equilibrium distribution of transaction prices at a point in time. I develop and estimate a model of the price distribution using data from the Deutsche mark/dollar market that produces two striking results: (1) Much of the short-term volatility in exchange rates comes from sampling the heterogeneous trading decisions of dealers in a distribution that, under normal market conditions, changes comparatively slowly; (2) public news is rarely the predominant source of exchange rate movements over any horizon.</description><author>Evans, M. D. D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum trading by institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Badrinath, S. G.; Wahal, S.
We document the equity trading practices of approximately 1,200 institutions from the third quarter of 1987 through the third quarter of 1995. We decompose trading by institutions into the initiation of new positions (entry), the termination of previous positions (exit), and adjustments to ongoing holdings. Institutions act as momentum traders when they enter stocks but as contrarian traders when they exit or make adjustments to ongoing holdings. We find significant differences in trading practices among different types of institutions.</description><author>Badrinath, S. G.; Wahal, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning about internal capital markets from corporate spin-offs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gertner, R.; Powers, E.; Scharfstein, D.
We examine the investment behavior of firms before and after being spun off from their parent companies. Their investment, after the spin-off is significantly more sensitive to measures of investment opportunities (e.g., industry Tobin's Q or industry investment) than it is before the spin-off. Spin-offs tend to cut investment in low Q industries and increase investment in high Q industries. These changes are observed primarily in spin-offs of firms in industries unrelated to the parents' industries and in spin-offs where the stock market reacts favorably to the spin-off announcement. Our findings suggest that spin-offs may improve the allocation of capital.</description><author>Gertner, R.; Powers, E.; Scharfstein, D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When is bad news really bad news?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, J.; Cornell, B.; Landsman, W. R.
We examine whether the price response to bad and good earnings shocks changes as the relative level of the market changes. The study is based on a complete sample of annual earnings announcements during the period 1988 to 1998. The relative level of the market is based on the difference between the current market P/E and the average market P/E over the prior 12 months. We find that the stock price response to negative earnings surprises increases as the relative level of the market rises. Furthermore, the difference between bad news and good news earnings response coefficients rises with the market.</description><author>Conrad, J.; Cornell, B.; Landsman, W. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does distance still matter? The information revolution in small business lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Petersen, M. A.; Rajan, R. G.
The distance between small firms and their lenders is increasing, and they are communicating in more impersonal ways. After documenting these systematic changes, we demonstrate they do not arise from small firms locating differently, consolidation in the banking industry, or biases in the sample. Instead, improvements in lender productivity appear to explain our findings. We also find distant firms no longer have to be the highest quality credits, indicating they have greater access to credit. The evidence indicates there has been substantial development of the financial sector, even in areas such as small business lending.</description><author>Petersen, M. A.; Rajan, R. G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Noise trading, costly arbitrage, and asset prices: Evidence from closed-end funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gemmill, G.; Thomas, D. C.
If arbitrage is costly and noise traders are active, asset prices may deviate from fundamental values for long periods of time. We use a sample of 158 closed-end funds to show that noise-trader sentiment, as proxied by retail-investor flows, leads to fluctuations in the discount. Nevertheless, we reject the hypothesis that noise-trader risk is the cause of the long-run discount. Instead we find that funds which are more difficult to arbitrage have larger discounts, due to: (1) the censoring of the discount by the arbitrage bounds, and (2) the freedom of managers to increase charges. when arbitrage is costly.</description><author>Gemmill, G.; Thomas, D. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-run performance following private placements of equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hertzel, M.; Lemmon, M.; Linck, J. S.; Rees, L.
Public firms that place equity privately experience positive announcements effects, with negative post-announcement stock-price performance. This finding is inconsistent with the underreaction hypothesis. Instead, it suggests that investors are overoptimistic about the prospects of firms issuing equity, regardless of the method of issuance. Further, in contrast to public offerings, private issues follow periods of relatively poor operating performance. Thus, investor overoptimism at the time of private issues is not due to the behavioral tendency to overweight recent experience at the expense of long-term averages.</description><author>Hertzel, M.; Lemmon, M.; Linck, J. S.; Rees, L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial turnover and leverage under a takeover threat</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Novaes, W.
How do shareholders perceive managers who lever up under a takeover threat? Increasing leverage conveys good news if it reflects management's ability to enhance value. It conveys bad news, though, if inefficient managers are more pressured to lever up than the efficient ones. This paper demonstrates that negative updating may prevail. Managers who lever up to end a takeover threat may thus commit to enhance value and yet increase their chances of being replaced by their shareholders. The model provides implications for the dispersion of intraindustry leverage and for the stock price reaction to debt-for-equity exchanges.</description><author>Novaes, W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The geography of equity listing: Why do companies list abroad?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pagano, M.; Roell, A. A.; Zechner, J.
This paper documents aggregate trends in the foreign listings of companies, and analyzes their distinctive prelisting characteristics and postlisting performance. In 1986-1997, many European companies listed abroad, mainly on U.S. exchanges, while the number of U.S. companies listed in Europe decreased. European companies that cross-list tend to be large and recently privatized firms, and expand their foreign sales after listing abroad. They differ sharply depending on where they cross-list: The U.S. exchanges attract high-tech and export-oriented companies that expand rapidly without significant leveraging. Companies cross-listing within Europe do not grow unusually fast, and increase their leverage after cross-listing.</description><author>Pagano, M.; Roell, A. A.; Zechner, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tunneling or value added? Evidence from mergers by Korean business groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, K. H.; Kang, J. K.; Kim, J. M.
We examine whether firms belonging to Korean business groups (chaebols) benefit from acquisitions they make or whether such acquisitions provide a way for controlling shareholders to increase their wealth by increasing the value of other group firms (tunneling). We find that when a chaebol-affiliated firm makes an acquisition, its stock price on average falls. While minority shareholders of a chaebol-affiliated firm making an acquisition lose, the controlling shareholder of that firm on average benefits because the acquisition enhances the value of other firms in the group. This evidence is consistent with the tunneling hypothesis.</description><author>Bae, K. H.; Kang, J. K.; Kim, J. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disentangling the incentive and entrenchment effects of large shareholdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claessens, S.; Djankov, S.; Fan, J. P. H.; Lang, L. H. P.
This article disentangles the incentive and entrenchment effects of large ownership. Using data for 1,301 publicly traded corporations in eight East Asian economies, we find that firm value increases with the cash-flow ownership of the largest shareholder, consistent with a positive incentive effect. But firm value falls when the control rights of the largest shareholder exceed its cash-flow ownership, consistent with an entrenchment effect. Given that concentrated corporate ownership is predominant in most countries, these findings have relevance for corporate governance across the world.</description><author>Claessens, S.; Djankov, S.; Fan, J. P. H.; Lang, L. H. P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal capital markets in financial conglomerates: Evidence from small bank responses to monetary policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, M.
This paper looks at internal capital markets in financial conglomerates by comparing the responses of small subsidiary and independent banks to monetary policy. I find that internal capital markets in financial conglomerates relax the credit constraints faced by smaller bank affiliates. Further analysis indicates that those markets lessen the impact of Fed policies on bank lending activity. The paper also examines the role of internal capital markets in influencing the investment allocation process of those conglomerates. My findings suggest that frictions between conglomerate headquarters and external capital markets are at the root of investment inefficiencies generated by internal capital markets.</description><author>Campello, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurship and bank credit availability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Black, S. E.; Strahan, P. E.
The literature is divided on the expected effects of increased competition and consolidation in the financial sector on the supply of credit to relationship borrowers. This paper tests whether policy changes fostering competition and consolidation in U.S. banking helped or harmed entrepreneurs. We find that the rate of new incorporations increases following deregulation of branching restrictions, and that deregulation reduces the negative effect of concentration on new incorporations. We also find the formation of new incorporations increases as the share of small banks decreases, suggesting that diversification benefits of size outweigh the possible comparative advantage small banks may have in forging relationships.</description><author>Black, S. E.; Strahan, P. E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio choice in the presence of personal illiquid projects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faig, M.; Shum, P.
Personal projects, such as a private business or the purchase of a home, influence individuals' portfolio choice. We conduct a theoretical analysis of this influence when financial assets are required to provide liquidity to personal projects. Due to this liquidity consideration, individuals behave in a more risk-averse fashion when there is a large penalty for discontinuing or underinvesting in the final stages of the projects. In addition, using data from the 1995 Survey of Consumer Finances, we find that households that are saving to invest in their own businesses or in their own homes indeed have significantly safer financial portfolios.</description><author>Faig, M.; Shum, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives firm-level stock returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vuolteenaho, T.
I use a vector autoregressive model (VAR) to decompose an individual firm's stock return into two components: changes in cash-flow expectations (i.e., cash-flow news) and changes in discount rates (i.e., expected-return news). The VAR yields three main results. First, firm-level stock returns are mainly driven by cash-flow news. For a typical stock, the variance of cash-flow news is more than twice that of expected-return news. Second, shocks to expected returns and cash flows are positively correlated for a typical small stock. Third, expected-return-news series are highly correlated across firms, while cash-flow news can largely be diversified away in aggregate portfolios.</description><author>Vuolteenaho, T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pass-through and exposure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodnar, G. M.; Dumas, B.; Marston, R. C.
Firms differ in the extent to which they "pass through" changes in exchange rates into foreign currency prices and in their "exposure" to exchange rates-the responsiveness of their profits to changes in exchange rates. Because pricing affects profitability, a firm's pass-through and exposure should be related. This paper develops models of exporting firms under imperfect competition to study these related phenomena. From these models we derive the optimal pass-through decisions and the resulting exchange rate exposure. The models are estimated on eight Japanese export industries using both the price data pass-through and financial data for exposure.</description><author>Bodnar, G. M.; Dumas, B.; Marston, R. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture capital and the professionalization of start-up firms: Empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hellmann, T.; Puri, M.
This paper examines the impact venture capital can have on the development of new firms. Using a hand-collected data set on Silicon Valley start-ups, we find that venture capital is related to a variety of professionalization measures, such as human resource policies, the adoption of stock option plans, and the hiring of a marketing VP Venture-capital-backed companies are also more likely and faster to replace the founder with an outside CEO, both in situations that appear adversarial and those mutually agreed to. The evidence suggests that venture capitalists play roles over and beyond those of traditional financial intermediaries.</description><author>Hellmann, T.; Puri, M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic distress, financial distress, and dynamic liquidation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahl, M.
Many firms emerging from a debt restructuring remain highly leveraged, continue to invest little, perform poorly, and often reenter financial distress. The existing literature interprets these findings as inefficiencies arising from coordination problems among many creditors or an inefficient design of bankruptcy law. In contrast, this paper emphasizes that creditors lack the information that is needed to make quick and correct liquidation decisions. It can explain the long-term nature of financial distress solely as the result of dynamic learning strategies of creditors and suggests that it may be an unavoidable byproduct of an efficient resolution of financial distress.</description><author>Kahl, M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund advisory contracts: An empirical investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deli, D. N.
We investigate marginal compensation rates in mutual fund advisory contracts and find the following. Equity and foreign fund advisors receive higher marginal compensation than debt and domestic fund advisors. Advisors of funds with greater turnover receive higher marginal compensation. Also, closed-end fund advisors receive higher marginal compensation than open-end fund advisors. Finally, we find that marginal compensation is lower for advisors of large funds and members of large fund families. We argue that these differences in marginal compensation reflect differences in advisor marginal product, differences in the difficulty of monitoring performance, differences in control environments, and scale economies.</description><author>Deli, D. N.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The world price of insider trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, U.; Daouk, H.
The existence and the enforcement of insider trading laws in stock markets is a phenomenon of the 1990s. A study of the 103 countries that have stock markets reveals that insider trading laws exist in 87 of them, but enforcement-as evidenced by prosecutions-has taken place in only 38 of them. Before 1990, the respective numbers were 34 and 9. We find that the cost of equity in a country, after controlling for a number of other variables, does not change after the introduction of insider trading laws, but decreases significantly after the first prosecution.</description><author>Bhattacharya, U.; Daouk, H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks as liquidity providers: An explanation for the coexistence of lending and deposit-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kashyap, A. K.; Rajan, R.; Stein, J. C.
What ties together the traditional commercial banking activities of deposit-taking and lending? We argue that since banks often lend via commitments, their lending and deposit-taking may be two manifestations of one primitive function: the provision of liquidity on demand. There will be synergies between the two activities to the extent that both require banks to hold large balances of liquid assets: If deposit withdrawals and commitment takedowns are imperfectly correlated, the two activities can share the costs of the liquid-asset stockpile. We develop this idea with a simple model, and use a variety of data to test the model empirically.</description><author>Kashyap, A. K.; Rajan, R.; Stein, J. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government ownership of banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>La Porta, R.; Lopez-de-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A.
We assemble data on government ownership of banks around the world. The data show that such ownership is large and pervasive, and higher in countries with low levels of per capita income, backward financial systems, interventionist and inefficient governments, and poor protection of property rights. Higher government ownership of banks in 1970 is associated with slower subsequent financial development and lower growth of per capita income and productivity. This evidence supports "political" theories of the effects of government ownership of firms.</description><author>La Porta, R.; Lopez-de-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market timing and capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, M.; Wurgler, J.
It is well known that firms are more likely to issue equity when their market values are high, relative to book and past market values, and to repurchase equity when their market values are low. We document that the resulting effects on capital structure are very persistent. As a consequence, current capital structure is strongly related to historical market values. The results suggest the theory that capital structure is the cumulative outcome of past attempts to time the equity market.</description><author>Baker, M.; Wurgler, J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of banking mergers on loan contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sapienza, P.
This paper studies the effects of banking mergers on individual business borrowers. Using information on individual loan contracts between banks and companies, I analyze the effect of banking consolidation on banks' credit policies. I find that in-market mergers benefit borrowers if these mergers involve the acquisition of banks with small market shares. Interest rates charged by the consolidated banks decrease, but as the local market share of the acquired bank increases, the efficiency effect is offset by market power. Mergers have different distributional effects across borrowers. When banks become larger, they reduce the supply of loans to small borrowers.</description><author>Sapienza, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Continuous trading or call auctions: Revealed preferences of investors at the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalay, A.; Wei, L.; Wohl, A.
We use the move of Israeli stocks from call auction trading to continuous trading to show that investors have a preference for stocks that trade continuously. When large stocks move from call auction to continuous trading, the small stocks that still trade by call auction experience a significant loss in volume relative to the overall market volume. As small stocks move to continuous trading, they experience an increase in volume and positive abnormal returns because of the associated increase in liquidity. Overall, though, a move to continuous trading increases the volume of large stocks relative to small stocks.</description><author>Kalay, A.; Wei, L.; Wohl, A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank performance around the introduction of a Section 20 subsidiary</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornett, M. M.; Ors, E.; Tehranian, H.
As of 1987, commercial banks in the United States were allowed to establish Section 20 subsidiaries to conduct investment-banking activities. A concern of regulators was that these activities would result in a decrease in performance of commercial banks relative to the risk being undertaken. This paper examines the performance of commercial banks around the establishment of a Section 20 subsidiary. We find that Section 20 activities undertaken by banks result in increased industry-adjusted operating cash flow return on assets, due mainly to revenues from noncommercial-banking activities. Further, risk measures for the sample banks do not change significantly.</description><author>Cornett, M. M.; Ors, E.; Tehranian, H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Research dissemination and impact: Evidence from Web site downloads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pinkowitz, L.
The Journal of Finance Web site disseminates research expediently to a broad audience. Papers were downloaded 284,170 times from November 1997 to November 1999. The average paper receives 85 downloads per month and is available 10 months before publication. Articles are downloaded more than shorter papers. Lead articles are downloaded more than other articles because they are of greater interest, and they receive an endorsement as the lead. Downloads are positively correlated with citations and may be a useful measure of research impact. Finally, placing forthcoming articles online does not adversely affect subscriptions and may increase the SSCI impact factor.</description><author>Pinkowitz, L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cadbury Committee, corporate performance, and top management turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahya, J.; McConnell, J. J.; Travlos, N. G.
In 1992, the Cadbury Committee issued the Code of Best Practice which recommends that boards of U.K. corporations include at least three outside directors and that the positions of chairman and CEO be held by different individuals. The underlying presumption was that these recommendations would lead to improved board oversight. We empirically analyze the relationship between CEO turnover and corporate performance. CEO turnover increased following issuance of the Code; the negative relationship between CEO turnover and performance became stronger following the Code's issuance; and the increase in sensitivity of turnover to performance was concentrated among firms that adopted the Code.</description><author>Dahya, J.; McConnell, J. J.; Travlos, N. G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ex ante costs of violating absolute priority in bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bebchuk, L. A.
A basic question for the design of bankruptcy law concerns whether value should be divided in accordance with absolute priority. Research done in the past decade has suggested that deviations from absolute priority have beneficial ex ante effects. In contrast, this paper shows that ex post deviations from absolute priority also have negative effects on ex ante decisions taken by shareholders, Such deviations aggravate the moral hazard problem with respect to project choice-increasing the equityholders' incentive to favor risky projects-as well as with respect to borrowing and dividend decisions.</description><author>Bebchuk, L. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term premia and interest rate forecasts in affine models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffee, G. R.
The standard class of affine models produces poor forecasts of future Treasury yields. Better forecasts are generated by assuming that yields follow random walks. The failure of these models is driven by one of their key features: Compensation for risk is a multiple of the variance of the risk. Thus risk compensation cannot vary independently of interest rate volatility. I also describe a broader class of models. These "essentially affine" models retain the tractability of standard models, but allow compensation for interest rate risk to vary independently of interest rate volatility. This additional flexibility proves useful in forecasting future yields.</description><author>Duffee, G. R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear pricing kernels, kurtosis preference, and evidence from the cross section of equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, R. F.
This paper investigates nonlinear pricing kernels in which the risk factor is endogenously determined and preferences restrict the definition of the pricing kernel. These kernels potentially generate the empirical performance of nonlinear and multifactor models, while maintaining empirical power and avoiding ad hoc specifications of factors or functional form. Our test results indicate that preference-restricted nonlinear pricing kernels are both admissible for the cross section of returns and are able to significantly improve upon linear single- and multifactor kernels. Further, the nonlinearities in the pricing kernel drive out the importance of the factors in the linear multi-factor model.</description><author>Dittmar, R. F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structures in developing countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Booth, L.; Aivazian, V.; Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Maksimovic, V.
This study uses a new data set to assess whether capital structure theory is portable across countries with different institutional structures. We analyze capital structure choices of firms in 10 developing countries, and provide evidence that these decisions are affected by the same variables as in developed countries. However, there are persistent differences across countries, indicating that specific country factors are at work. Our findings suggest that although some of the insights from modern finance theory are portable across countries, much remains to be done to understand the impact of different institutional features on capital structure choices.</description><author>Booth, L.; Aivazian, V.; Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Maksimovic, V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The long-run stock returns following bond ratings changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dichev, L. D.; Piotroski, J. D.
Using essentially all Moody's bond ratings changes between 1970 and 1997, we find no reliable abnormal returns following upgrades. However, we find negative abnormal returns on the magnitude of 10 to 14 percent in the first year following downgrades. Additional results reveal that this underperformance is especially pronounced for small, low-credit-quality firms. Also, downgrades underperform in nearly all years in the sample, and a large part of the abnormal returns occur at subsequent earnings announcements. Thus, the evidence suggests that the poor returns result from an underreaction to the announcement of downgrades, rather than from lower systematic risk.</description><author>Dichev, L. D.; Piotroski, J. D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning about predictability: The effects of parameter uncertainty on dynamic asset allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xia, Y. H.
This paper examines the effects of uncertainty about the stock return predictability on optimal dynamic portfolio choice in a continuous time setting for a long-horizon investor. Uncertainty about the predictive relation affects the optimal portfolio choice through dynamic learning, and leads to a state-dependent relation between the optimal portfolio choice and the investment horizon. There is substantial market timing in the optimal hedge demands, which is caused by stochastic covariance between stock return and dynamic learning. The opportunity cost of ignoring predictability or learning is found to be quite substantial.</description><author>Xia, Y. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining the rate spread on corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.; Agrawal, D.; Mann, C.
The purpose of this article is to explain the spread between rates on corporate and government bonds. We show that expected default accounts for a surprisingly small fraction of the premium in corporate rates over treasuries. While state taxes explain a substantial portion of the difference, the remaining portion of the spread is closely related to the factors that we commonly accept as explaining risk premiums for common stocks. Bath our time series and cross-sectional tests support the existence of a risk premium on corporate bonds.</description><author>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.; Agrawal, D.; Mann, C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Affine term structure models and the forward premium anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Backus, D. K.; Foresi, S.; Telmer, C. I.
One of the most puzzling features of currency prices is the forward premium anomaly: the tendency for high interest rate currencies to appreciate. We characterize the anomaly in the context of affine models of the term structure of interest rates. In affine models, the anomaly requires either that state variables have asymmetric effects on state prices in different currencies or that nominal interest rates take on negative values with positive probability. We find the quantitative properties of either alternative to have important shortcomings.</description><author>Backus, D. K.; Foresi, S.; Telmer, C. I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variance-ratio statistics and high-frequency data: Testing for changes in intraday volatility patterns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, T. G.; Bollerslev, T.; Das, A.
Variance-ratio tests are routinely employed to assess the Variation in return Volatility over time and across markets. However, such tests are not statistically robust and can be seriously misleading within a high-frequency context. We develop improved inference procedures using a Fourier Flexible Form regression framework. The practical significance is illustrated through tests for changes in the FX intraday Volatility pattern following the removal of trading restrictions in Tokyo. Contrary to earlier evidence, Ne find no discernible changes outside of the Tokyo lunch period. We ascribe the difference to the fragile finite-sample inference of conventional variance-ratio procedures and a single outlier.</description><author>Andersen, T. G.; Bollerslev, T.; Das, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economic value of volatility timing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleming, J.; Kirby, C.; Ostdiek, B.
Numerous studies report that standard volatility models have low explanatory power, leading some researchers to question whether these models have economic value. We examine this question by using conditional mean-variance analysis to assess the value of volatility timing to short-horizon investors. We find that the volatility timing strategies outperform the unconditionally efficient static portfolios that have the same target expected return and volatility. This finding is robust to estimation risk. and transaction costs.</description><author>Fleming, J.; Kirby, C.; Ostdiek, B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital gains tax rules, tax-loss trading, and turn-of-the-year returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poterba, J. M.; Weisbenner, S. J.
Changes in the capital gains tax rules facing individual investors do not affect the incentives for "window dressing" by institutional investors, but they can affect the incentives for year-end tax-induced trading by individual investors. Empirical evidence for the 1963 to 1996 period suggests that when the tax law encouraged taxable investors who accrued losses early in the year to realize their losses before year-end, the correlation between early year losses and turn-of-the-year returns was weaker than when the law did not provide such an early realization incentive. These findings suggest that tax-loss trading contributes to turn-of-the-year return patterns.</description><author>Poterba, J. M.; Weisbenner, S. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rationality and analysts' forecast bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, T.
This paper proposes and tests a quadratic-loss utility function for modeling corporate earnings forecasting, where financial analysts trade off bias to improve management access and forecast accuracy. Optimal forecasts with minimum expected error are optimistically biased and exhibit predictable cross-sectional variation related to analyst and company characteristics. Empirical evidence from individual analyst forecasts is consistent with the model's predictions. These results suggest that positive and predictable bias may be a rational property of optimal earnings forecasts. Prior studies using classical notions of unbiasedness may have prematurely dismissed analysts' forecasts as being irrational or inaccurate.</description><author>Lim, T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contagious speculation and a cure for cancer: A nonevent that made stock prices soar</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huberman, G.; Regev, T.
A Sunday Neu, York Times article on a potential development of new cancer-curing drugs caused EntreMed's stock price to rise from 12.063 at the Friday close, to open at 85 and close near 52 on Monday. It closed above 30 in the three following weeks. The enthusiasm spilled over to other biotechnology stocks. The potential breakthrough in cancer research already had been reported, however, in the journal Nature, and in various popular newspapers (including the Times) more than five months earlier Thus, enthusiastic public attention induced a permanent rise in share prices, even though no genuinely new information had been presented.</description><author>Huberman, G.; Regev, T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional trading and soft dollars</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, J. S.; Johnson, K. M.; Wahal, S.
Proprietary data allow us to distinguish between institutional investors' orders directed to soft-dollar brokers and those directed to other types of brokers. We find that soft-dollar brokers execute smaller orders in larger market Value stocks. Allowing for differences in order characteristics, we estimate the incremental implicit cost of soft-dollar execution at 29 (24) basis points for buyer- (seller-) initiated orders. Far large orders, incremental implicit costs are 41 (30) basis points for buys (sells). However, we document substantial variability in these estimates, and research services provided by soft-dollar brokers may at least partially offset these costs.</description><author>Conrad, J. S.; Johnson, K. M.; Wahal, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Microstructure: The organization of trading and short term price behavior, vol 1-2.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaul, A.
nan</description><author>Kaul, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Worldwide asset and liability modeling.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vorst, T.
nan</description><author>Vorst, T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic trading in a dynamic noisy market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vayanos, D.
This paper studies a dynamic model of a financial market with a strategic trader. In each period the strategic trader receives a privately observed endowment in the stock. He trades with competitive market makers to share risk. Noise traders are present in the market. After receiving a stock endowment, the strategic trader is shown to reduce his risk exposure either by selling at a decreasing rate over time or by selling and then buying back some of the shares sold. When the time between trades is small, the strategic trader reveals the information regarding his endowment very quickly.</description><author>Vayanos, D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should investors avoid all actively managed mutual funds? A study in Bayesian performance evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baks, K. P.; Metrick, A.; Wachter, J.
This paper analyzes mutual-fund performance from an investor's perspective. We study the portfolio-choice problem for a mean-variance investor choosing among a risk-free asset, index funds, and actively managed mutual funds. To solve this problem, we employ a Bayesian method of performance evaluation; a key innovation in our approach is the development of a flexible set of prior beliefs about managerial skill. We then apply our methodology to a sample of 1,437 mutual funds. We find that some extremely skeptical prior beliefs nevertheless lead to economically significant allocations to active managers.</description><author>Baks, K. P.; Metrick, A.; Wachter, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Have individual stocks become more volatile? An empirical exploration of idiosyncratic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, J. Y.; Lettau, M.; Malkiel, B. G.; Xu, Y. X.
This paper uses a disaggregated approach to study the volatility of common stocks at the market, industry, and firm levels. Over the period from 1962 to 1997 there has been a noticeable increase in firm-level volatility relative to market volatility. Accordingly, correlations among individual stocks and the explanatory power of the market model for a typical stock have declined, whereas the number of stocks needed to achieve a given level of diversification has increased. All the volatility measures move together countercyclically and help to predict GDP growth. Market volatility tends to lead the other volatility series. Factors that may be responsible for these findings are suggested.</description><author>Campbell, J. Y.; Lettau, M.; Malkiel, B. G.; Xu, Y. X.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The equity premium and structural breaks - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Z. Y.
nan</description><author>Wang, Z. Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>