<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JF1</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>The Labor Market for Directors and Externalities in Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levit, Doron; Malenko, Nadya
This paper studies how directors' reputational concerns affect board structure, corporate governance, and firm value. In our setting, directors affect their firms' governance, and governance in turn affects firms' demand for new directors. Whether the labor market rewards a shareholder-friendly or management-friendly reputation is determined in equilibrium and depends on aggregate governance. We show that directors' desire to be invited to other boards creates strategic complementarity of corporate governance across firms. Directors' reputational concerns amplify the governance system: strong systems become stronger and weak systems become weaker. We derive implications for multiple directorships, board size, transparency, and board independence.</description><author>Levit, Doron; Malenko, Nadya</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cream-Skimming in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Santos, Tano; Scheinkman, Jose A.
We propose a model in which investors may choose to acquire costly information that identifies good assets and purchase these assets in opaque (OTC) markets. Uninformed investors access an asset pool that has been cream-skimmed by informed investors. When the quality composition of assets for sale is fixed, there is too much information acquisition and the financial industry extracts excessive rents. In the presence of moral hazard in origination, the social value of information varies inversely with information acquisition. Low quality origination is associated with large rents in the financial sector. Equilibrium acquisition of information is generically inefficient.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Santos, Tano; Scheinkman, Jose A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indirect Incentives of Hedge Fund Managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Jongha; Sensoy, Berk A.; Weisbach, Michael S.
Indirect incentives exist in the money management industry when good current performance increases future inflows of capital, leading to higher future fees. For the average hedge fund, indirect incentives are at least 1.4 times as large as direct incentives from incentive fees and managers' personal stakes in the fund. Combining direct and indirect incentives,manager wealth increases by at least $0.39 for a $1 increase in investor wealth. Younger and more scalable hedge funds have stronger flow-performance relations, leading to stronger indirect incentives. These results have a number of implications for our understanding of incentives in the asset management industry.</description><author>Lim, Jongha; Sensoy, Berk A.; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does It Pay to Bet Against Beta? On the Conditional Performance of the Beta Anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cederburg, Scott; O'Doherty, Michael S.
Prior studies find that a strategy that buys high-beta stocks and sells low-beta stocks has a significantly negative unconditional capital asset pricing model (CAPM) alpha, such that it appears to pay to bet against beta. We show, however, that the conditional beta for the high-minus-low beta portfolio covaries negatively with the equity premium and positively with market volatility. As a result, the unconditional alpha is a downward-biased estimate of the true alpha. We model the conditional market risk for beta-sorted portfolios using instrumental variables methods and find that the conditional CAPM resolves the beta anomaly.</description><author>Cederburg, Scott; O'Doherty, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order Flow and Expected Option Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Muravyev, Dmitriy
I show that the inventory risk faced by market-makers has a first-order effect on option prices. I introduce a simple approach that decomposes the price impact of trades into inventory risk and asymmetric information components. While both components are large for option trades, the inventory risk component is larger. Using the full panel of daily option returns, I find that option order imbalances attributable to inventory risk have five times larger impact on option prices than previously thought. Finally, I find that past order imbalances have greater predictive power than any other commonly used predictor of option returns.</description><author>Muravyev, Dmitriy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conglomerate Investment, Skewness, and the CEO Long-Shot Bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schneider, Christoph; Spalt, Oliver
Do behavioral biases of executives matter for corporate investment decisions? Using segment-level capital allocation in multisegment firms (conglomerates) as a laboratory, we show that capital expenditure is increasing in the expected skewness of segment returns. Conglomerates invest more in high-skewness segments than matched stand-alone firms, and trade at a discount, which indicates overinvestment that is detrimental to shareholder wealth. Using geographical variation in gambling norms, we find that the skewness-investment relation is particularly pronounced when CEOs are likely to find long shots attractive. Our findings suggest that CEOs allocate capital with a long-shot bias.</description><author>Schneider, Christoph; Spalt, Oliver</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Acquisition in Rumor-Based Bank Runs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo; Manela, Asaf
We study information acquisition and dynamic withdrawal decisions when a spreading rumor exposes a solvent bank to a run. Uncertainty about the bank's liquidity and potential failure motivates depositors who hear the rumor to acquire additional noisy signals. Depositors with less informative signals may wait before gradually running on the bank, leading to an endogenous aggregate withdrawal speed and bank survival time. Private information acquisition about liquidity can subject solvent-but-illiquid banks to runs, and shorten the survival time of failing banks. Public provision of solvency information can mitigate runs by indirectly crowding-out individual depositors' effort to acquire liquidity information.</description><author>He, Zhiguo; Manela, Asaf</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric Information about Collateral Values</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stroebel, Johannes
empirically analyze credit market outcomes when competing lenders are differentially informed about the expected return from making a loan. I study the residential mortgage market, where property developers often cooperate with vertically integrated mortgage lenders to offer financing to buyers of new homes. I show that these integrated lenders have superior information about the construction quality of individual homes and exploit this information to lend against higher quality collateral, decreasing foreclosures by up to 40%. To compensate for this adverse selection on collateral quality, nonintegrated lenders charge higher interest rates when competing against a better-informed integrated lender.</description><author>Stroebel, Johannes</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exporting Liquidity: Branch Banking and Financial Integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilje, Erik P.; Loutskina, Elena; Strahan, Philip E.
Using exogenous liquidity windfalls from oil and natural gas shale discoveries, we demonstrate that bank branch networks help integrate U.S. lending markets. Banks exposed to shale booms enjoy liquidity inflows, which increase their capacity to originate and hold new loans. Exposed banks increase mortgage lending in nonboom counties, but only where they have branches and only for hard-to-securitize mortgages. Our findings suggest that contracting frictions limit the ability of arm's length finance to integrate credit markets fully. Branch networks continue to play an important role in financial integration, despite the development of securitization markets.</description><author>Gilje, Erik P.; Loutskina, Elena; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Boats That Did Not Sail: Asset Price Volatility in a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koudijs, Peter
What explains short-term fluctuations of stock prices? This paper exploits a natural experiment from the 18th century in which information flows were regularly interrupted for exogenous reasons. English shares were traded on the Amsterdam exchange and news came in on sailboats that were often delayed because of adverse weather conditions. The paper documents that prices responded strongly to boat arrivals, but there was considerable volatility in the absence of news. The evidence suggests that this was largely the result of the revelation of (long-lived) private information and the (transitory) impact of uninformed liquidity trades on intermediaries' risk premia.</description><author>Koudijs, Peter</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short Selling and Earnings Management: A Controlled Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Vivian W.; Huang, Allen H.; Karpoff, Jonathan M.
During 2005 to 2007, the SEC ordered a pilot program in which one-third of the Russell 3000 index were arbitrarily chosen as pilot stocks and exempted from shortsale price tests. Pilot firms' discretionary accruals and likelihood of marginally beating earnings targets decrease during this period, and revert to pre-experiment levelswhen the program ends. After the program starts, pilot firms are more likely to be caught for fraud initiated before the program, and their stock returns better incorporate earnings information. These results indicate that short selling, or its prospect, curbs earnings management, helps detect fraud, and improves price efficiency.</description><author>Fang, Vivian W.; Huang, Allen H.; Karpoff, Jonathan M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateralization, Bank Loan Rates, and Monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cerqueiro, Geraldo; Ongena, Steven; Roszbach, Kasper
We show that collateral plays an important role in the design of debt contracts, the provision of credit, and the incentives of lenders tomonitor borrowers. Using a unique data set from a large bank containing timely assessments of collateral values, we find that the bank responded to a legal reform that exogenously reduced collateral values by increasing interest rates, tightening credit limits, and reducing the intensity of its monitoring of borrowers and collateral, spurring borrower delinquency on outstanding claims. We thus explain why banks are senior lenders and quantify the value of claimant priority.</description><author>Cerqueiro, Geraldo; Ongena, Steven; Roszbach, Kasper</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From Wall Street to Main Street: The Impact of the Financial Crisis on Consumer Credit Supply</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ramcharan, Rodney; Verani, Stephane; Van den Heuvel, Skander J.
HOW DID THE COLLAPSE of the asset-backed securities (ABS) market during the 2007 to 2009 financial crisis affect the supply of credit to the broader economy? Using new data on the U.S. credit union industry, we find that ABS-related losses are associated with a large contraction in the supply of credit to consumers, especially among those credit unions that began the crisis with weaker capitalization. We also find that this credit supply shock restricted the availability of mortgage and automobile credit. These results show how movements in the prices of financial assets can affect the real economy.</description><author>Ramcharan, Rodney; Verani, Stephane; Van den Heuvel, Skander J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Total Cost of Corporate Borrowing in the Loan Market: Don't Ignore the Fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berg, Tobias; Saunders, Anthony; Steffen, Sascha
More than 80% of U.S. syndicated loans contain at least one fee type and contracts typically specify a menu of spreads and fee types. We test the predictions of existing theories on the main purposes of fees and provide supporting evidence that: (1) fees are used to price options embedded in loan contracts such as the drawdown option for credit lines and the cancellation option in term loans, and (2) fees are used to screen borrowers based on the likelihood of exercising these options. We also propose a new total-cost-of-borrowing measure that includes various fees charged by lenders.</description><author>Berg, Tobias; Saunders, Anthony; Steffen, Sascha</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information in the Term Structure of Yield Curve Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cieslak, Anna; Povala, Pavol
Using a novel no-arbitrage model and extensive second-moment data, we decompose conditional volatility of U.S. Treasury yields into volatilities of short-rate expectations and term premia. Short-rate expectations become more volatile than premia before recessions and during asset market distress. Correlation between shocks to premia and shocks to short-rate expectations is close to zero on average and varies with the monetary policy stance. While Treasuries are nearly unexposed to variance shocks, investors pay a premium for hedging variance risk with derivatives. We illustrate the dynamics of the yield volatility components during and after the financial crisis.</description><author>Cieslak, Anna; Povala, Pavol</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-Adjusting the Returns to Venture Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korteweg, Arthur; Nagel, Stefan
We adapt stochastic discount factor (SDF) valuation methods for venture capital (VC) performance evaluation. Our approach generalizes the popular Public Market Equivalent (PME) method and allows statistical inference in the presence of crosssectionally dependent, skewed VC payoffs. We relax SDF restrictions implicit in the PME so that the SDF can accurately reflect risk-free rates and returns of public equity markets during the sample period. This generalized PME yields substantially different abnormal performance estimates for VC funds and start-up investments, especially in times of strongly rising public equity markets and for investments with betas far from one.</description><author>Korteweg, Arthur; Nagel, Stefan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Worrying about the Stock Market: Evidence from Hospital Admissions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engelberg, Joseph; Parsons, Christopher A.
Using individual patient records for every hospital in California from 1983 to 2011, we find a strong inverse link between daily stock returns and hospital admissions, particularly for psychological conditions such as anxiety, panic disorder, and major depression. The effect is nearly instantaneous (within the same day) for psychological conditions, suggesting that anticipation over future consumption directly influences instantaneous utility.</description><author>Engelberg, Joseph; Parsons, Christopher A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Currency Sovereign Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Wenxin; Schreger, Jesse
We introduce a new measure of emerging market sovereign credit risk: the local currency credit spread, defined as the spread of local currency bonds over the synthetic local currency risk-free rate constructed using cross-currency swaps. We find that local currency credit spreads are positive and sizable. Compared with credit spreads on foreign-currency-denominated debt, local currency credit spreads have lower means, lower cross-country correlations, and lower sensitivity to global risk factors. We discuss several major sources of credit spread differentials, including positively correlated credit and currency risk, selective default, capital controls, and various financial market frictions.</description><author>Du, Wenxin; Schreger, Jesse</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News Trading and Speed</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, Thierry; Hombert, Johan; Rosu, Ioanid
We compare the optimal trading strategy of an informed speculator when he can trade ahead of incoming news (is fast), versus when he cannot (is slow). We find that speed matters: the fast speculator's trades account for a larger fraction of trading volume, and are more correlated with short-run price changes. Nevertheless, he realizes a large fraction of his profits from trading on long-term price changes. The fast speculator's behavior matches evidence about high-frequency traders. We predict that stocks with more informative news are more liquid even though they attract more activity from informed high-frequency traders.</description><author>Foucault, Thierry; Hombert, Johan; Rosu, Ioanid</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Market Volatility and Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adam, Klaus; Marcet, Albert; Nicolini, Juan Pablo
We show that consumption-based asset pricing models with time-separable preferences generate realistic amounts of stock price volatility if one allows for small deviations from rational expectations. Rational investors with subjective beliefs about price behavior optimally learn from past price observations. This imparts momentum and mean reversion into stock prices. The model quantitatively accounts for the volatility of returns, the volatility and persistence of the price-dividend ratio, and the predictability of long-horizon returns. It passes a formal statistical test for the overall fit of a set of moments provided one excludes the equity premium.</description><author>Adam, Klaus; Marcet, Albert; Nicolini, Juan Pablo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disappearing Call Delay and Dividend-Protected Convertible Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grundy, Bruce D.; Verwijmeren, Patrick
Firms do not historically call their convertible bonds as soon as conversion can be forced. A number of explanations for the delay rely on the size of the dividends that bondholders forgo so long as they do not convert. We investigate an important change in convertible security design, namely, dividend protection of convertible bond issues. Dividend protection means that the conversion value of the convertible bond is unaffected by dividend payments and thus dividend-related rationales for call delay become moot. We document that call delay is near zero for dividend-protected convertible bonds.</description><author>Grundy, Bruce D.; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Markets Discipline Government Agencies? Evidence from the Weather Derivatives Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Purnanandam, Amiyatosh; Weagley, Daniel
We analyze the role of financial markets in shaping the incentives of government agencies using a unique empirical setting: the weather derivatives market. We show that the introduction of weather derivative contracts on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME) improves the accuracy of temperature measurement by 13% to 20% at the underlying weather stations. We argue that temperature-based financial markets generate additional scrutiny of the temperature data measured by the National Weather Service, which motivates the agency to minimize measurement errors. Our results have broader implications: the visibility and scrutiny generated by financial markets can potentially improve the efficiency of government agencies.</description><author>Purnanandam, Amiyatosh; Weagley, Daniel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Calm before the Storm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akbas, Ferhat
I provide evidence that stocks experiencing unusually low trading volume over the week prior to earnings announcements have more unfavorable earnings surprises. This effect is more pronounced among stocks with higher short-selling constraints. These findings support the view that unusually low trading volume signals negative information, since, under short-selling constraints, informed agents with bad news stay by the sidelines. Changes in visibility or risk-based explanations are insufficient to explain the results. This evidence provides insights into why unusually low trading volume predicts price declines.</description><author>Akbas, Ferhat</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund Flows and Cross-Fund Learning within Families</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, David P.; Wu, Youchang
We develop a model of performance evaluation and fund flows for mutual funds in a family. Family performance has two effects on a member fund's estimated skill and inflows: a positive common-skill effect, and a negative correlated-noise effect. The overall spillover can be either positive or negative, depending on the weight of common skill and correlation of noise in returns. Its absolute value increases with family size, and declines over time. The sensitivity of flows to a fund's own performance is affected accordingly. Empirical estimates of fund flow sensitivities show patterns consistent with rational cross-fund learning within families.</description><author>Brown, David P.; Wu, Youchang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic Cash Flows and Systematic Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Babenko, Ilona; Boguth, Oliver; Tserlukevich, Yuri
We show that unpriced cash flow shocks contain information about future priced risk. A positive idiosyncratic shock decreases the sensitivity of firm value to priced risk factors and simultaneously increases firm size and idiosyncratic risk. A simple model can therefore explain book-to-market and size anomalies, as well as the negative relation between idiosyncratic volatility and stock returns. Empirically, we find that anomalies are more pronounced for firms with high idiosyncratic cash flow volatility. More generally, our results imply that any economic variable correlated with the history of idiosyncratic shocks can help to explain expected stock returns.</description><author>Babenko, Ilona; Boguth, Oliver; Tserlukevich, Yuri</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Determinants of Long-Term Corporate Debt Issuances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Badoer, Dominique C.; James, Christopher M.
A significant proportion of the debt issued by investment-grade firms has maturities greater than 20 years. In this paper we provide evidence that gap-filling behavior is an important determinant of these very long-term issues. Using data on individual corporate debt issues between 1987 and 2009, we find that gap-filling behavior is more prominent in the very long end of the maturity spectrum where the required risk capital makes arbitrage costly. In addition, changes in the supply of long-term government bonds affect not just the choice of maturity but also the overall level of corporate borrowing.</description><author>Badoer, Dominique C.; James, Christopher M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Academic Research Destroy Stock Return Predictability?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McLean, R. David; Pontiff, Jeffrey
We study the out-of-sample and post-publication return predictability of 97 variables shown to predict cross-sectional stock returns. Portfolio returns are 26% lower out-of-sample and 58% lower post-publication. The out-of-sample decline is an upper bound estimate of data mining effects. We estimate a 32% (58%-26%) lower return from publication-informed trading. Post-publication declines are greater for predictors with higher in-sample returns, and returns are higher for portfolios concentrated in stocks with high idiosyncratic risk and low liquidity. Predictor portfolios exhibit post-publication increases in correlations with other published-predictor portfolios. Our findings suggest that investors learn about mispricing from academic publications.</description><author>McLean, R. David; Pontiff, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings Announcements and Systematic Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savor, Pavel; Wilson, Mungo
Firms scheduled to report earnings earn an annualized abnormal return of 9.9%. We propose a risk-based explanation for this phenomenon, whereby investors use announcements to revise their expectations for nonannouncing firms, but can only do so imperfectly. Consequently, the covariance between firm-specific and market cash flow news spikes around announcements, making announcers especially risky. Consistent with our hypothesis, announcer returns forecast aggregate earnings. The announcement premium is persistent across stocks, and early (late) announcers earn higher (lower) returns. Nonannouncers' response to announcements is consistent with our model, both over time and across firms. Finally, exposure to announcement risk is priced.</description><author>Savor, Pavel; Wilson, Mungo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Acquisitions, Diversification, and the Firm's Life Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arikan, Asli M.; Stulz, Rene M.
Agency theories predict that older firms make value-destroying acquisitions to benefit managers. Neoclassical theories predict instead that such firms make wealth-increasing acquisitions to exploit underutilized assets. Using IPO cohorts, we establish that, while younger firms make more related and diversifying acquisitions than mature firms, the acquisition rate follows a U-shape over firms' life cycle. Consistent with neoclassical theories, we show that acquiring firms have better performance and growth opportunities and create wealth through acquisitions of nonpublic firms throughout their life. Consistent with agency theories, older firms experience negative stock price reactions for acquisitions of public firms.</description><author>Arikan, Asli M.; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Looking for Someone to Blame: Delegation, Cognitive Dissonance, and the Disposition Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Tom Y.; Solomon, David H.; Westerfield, Mark M.
We analyze brokerage data and an experiment to test a cognitive dissonance based theory of trading: investors avoid realizing losses because they dislike admitting that past purchases were mistakes, but delegation reverses this effect by allowing the investor to blame the manager instead. Using individual trading data, we show that the disposition effectthe propensity to realize past gains more than past lossesapplies only to nondelegated assets like individual stocks; delegated assets, like mutual funds, exhibit a robust reverse-disposition effect. In an experiment, we show that increasing investors' cognitive dissonance results in both a larger disposition effect in stocks and a larger reverse-disposition effect in funds. Additionally, increasing the salience of delegation increases the reverse-disposition effect in funds. Cognitive dissonance provides a unified explanation for apparently contradictory investor behavior across asset classes and has implications for personal investment decisions, mutual fund management, and intermediation.</description><author>Chang, Tom Y.; Solomon, David H.; Westerfield, Mark M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Borrows from the Lender of Last Resort?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drechsler, Itamar; Drechsel, Thomas; Marques-Ibanez, David; Schnabl, Philipp
We analyze lender of last resort (LOLR) lending during the European sovereign debt crisis. Using a novel data set on all central bank lending and collateral, we show that weakly capitalized banks took out more LOLR loans and used riskier collateral than strongly capitalized banks. We also find that weakly capitalized banks used LOLR loans to buy risky assets such as distressed sovereign debt. This resulted in a reallocation of risky assets from strongly to weakly capitalized banks. Our findings cannot be explained by classical LOLR theory. Rather, they point to risk taking by banks, both independently and with the encouragement of governments, and highlight the benefit of unifying LOLR lending and bank supervision.</description><author>Drechsler, Itamar; Drechsel, Thomas; Marques-Ibanez, David; Schnabl, Philipp</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stewart C. Myers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade Credit and Industry Dynamics: Evidence from Trucking Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barrot, Jean-Noel
Long payment terms are a strong impediment to the entry and survival of liquidity-constrained firms. To test this idea and its implications, I consider the effect of a reform restricting the trade credit supply of French trucking firms. In a difference-in-differences setting, I find that trucking firms' corporate default probability decreases by 25% following the restriction. The effect is persistent, concentrated among liquidity-constrained firms, and not offset by a decrease in profits. The restriction also triggers an increase in the entry of small trucking firms.</description><author>Barrot, Jean-Noel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Constraints and Workplace Safety</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohn, Jonathan B.; Wardlaw, Malcolm I.
We present evidence that financing frictions adversely impact investment in work-place safety, with implications for worker welfare and firm value. Using several identification strategies, we find that injury rates increase with leverage and negative cash flow shocks, and decrease with positive cash flow shocks. We show that firm value decreases substantially with injury rates. Our findings suggest that investment in worker safety is an economically important margin on which firms respond to financing constraints.</description><author>Cohn, Jonathan B.; Wardlaw, Malcolm I.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Investment, Innovative Capacity, and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Praveen; Li, Dongmei
We study the dynamic implications of capital investment in innovative capacity (IC) on future stock returns, investment, and profitability bymodeling the unique effects of IC investment on uncertain option generation/exercise and postexercise revenue. The model highlights the diverse effects of IC investment on expected returns in different postinvestment regimes and yields the novel prediction that, under the neoclassical assumption of nonincreasing revenue returns, IC investment is positively related to subsequent cumulative stock returns with a lag. The model also predicts a positive effect of IC investment on future investment and profitability. We find strong empirical support for these predictions.</description><author>Kumar, Praveen; Li, Dongmei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculative Betas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Sraer, David A.
The risk and return trade-off, the cornerstone of modern asset pricing theory, is often of the wrong sign. Our explanation is that high-beta assets are prone to speculative overpricing. When investors disagree about the stock market's prospects, high-beta assets are more sensitive to this aggregate disagreement, experience greater divergence of opinion about their payoffs, and are overpriced due to short-sales constraints. When aggregate disagreement is low, the Security Market Line is upward-sloping due to risk-sharing. When it is high, expected returns can actually decrease with beta. We confirm our theory using a measure of disagreement about stock market earnings.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Sraer, David A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Invest in Emerging Markets? The Role of Conditional Return Asymmetry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghysels, Eric; Plazzi, Alberto; Valkanov, Rossen
We propose a quantile-based measure of conditional skewness, particularly suitable for handling recalcitrant emerging market (EM) returns. The skewness of international stock market returns varies significantly across countries over time, and persists at long horizons. In EMs, skewness is mostly positive and idiosyncratic, and significantly relates to a country's financial and trade openness and balance of payments. In an international portfolio setting, return asymmetry leads to sizeable certainty-equivalent gains and increases the weight on emerging countries to about 30%. Investing in EMs seems to be about expectations of a higher upside than down-side, consistent with recent theories.</description><author>Ghysels, Eric; Plazzi, Alberto; Valkanov, Rossen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Brokers Have It All? On the Relation between Make-Take Fees and Limit Order Execution Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battalio, Robert; Corwin, Shane A.; Jennings, Robert
We identify retail brokers that seemingly route orders to maximize order flow payments, by selling market orders and sending limit orders to venues paying large liquidity rebates. Angel, Harris, and Spatt argue that such routing may not always be in customers' best interests. For both proprietary limit order data and a broad sample of trades from TAQ, we document a negative relation between several measures of limit order execution quality and rebate/fee level. This finding suggests that order routing designed to maximize liquidity rebates does not maximize limit order execution quality and thus brokers cannot have it all.</description><author>Battalio, Robert; Corwin, Shane A.; Jennings, Robert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Boom and Gloom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Povel, Paul; Sertsios, Giorgo; Kosova, Renata; Kumar, Praveen
We study the performance of investments made at different points of an investment cycle. We use a large data set covering hotels in the United States, with rich details on their location, characteristics, and performance. We find that hotels built during hotel construction booms underperform their peers. For hotels built during local hotel construction booms, this underperformance persists for several decades. We examine possible explanations for this long-lasting underperformance. The evidence is consistent with information-based herding explanations.</description><author>Povel, Paul; Sertsios, Giorgo; Kosova, Renata; Kumar, Praveen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Picking Winners? Investment Consultants' Recommendations of Fund Managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jenkinson, Tim; Jones, Howard; Martinez, Jose Vicente
Investment consultants advise institutional investors on their choice of fund manager. Focusing on U.S. actively managed equity funds, we analyze the factors that drive consultants' recommendations, what impact these recommendations have on flows, and how well the recommended funds perform. We find that investment consultants' recommendations of funds are driven largely by soft factors, rather than the funds' past performance, and that their recommendations have a significant effect on fund flows. However, we find no evidence that these recommendations add value, suggesting that the search for winners, encouraged and guided by investment consultants, is fruitless.</description><author>Jenkinson, Tim; Jones, Howard; Martinez, Jose Vicente</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advertising Expensive Mortgages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gurun, Umit G.; Matvos, Gregor; Seru, Amit
Using information on advertising and mortgages originated by subprime lenders, we study whether advertising helped consumers find cheaper mortgages. Lenders that advertise more within a region sell more expensive mortgages, measured as the excess rate of a mortgage after accounting for borrower, contract, and regional characteristics. These effects are stronger for mortgages sold to less sophisticated consumers. We exploit regional variation in mortgage advertising induced by the entry of Craigslist and other tests to demonstrate that these findings are not spurious. Analyzing advertising content reveals that initial/introductory rates are frequently advertised in a salient fashion, where reset rates are not.</description><author>Gurun, Umit G.; Matvos, Gregor; Seru, Amit</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Price of Political Uncertainty: Theory and Evidence from the Option Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, Bryan; Pastor, Lubos; Veronesi, Pietro
We empirically analyze the pricing of political uncertainty, guided by a theoretical model of government policy choice. To isolate political uncertainty, we exploit its variation around national elections and global summits. We find that political uncertainty is priced in the equity option market as predicted by theory. Options whose lives span political events tend to be more expensive. Such options provide valuable protection against the price, variance, and tail risks associated with political events. This protection is more valuable in a weaker economy and amid higher political uncertainty. The effects of political uncertainty spill over across countries.</description><author>Kelly, Bryan; Pastor, Lubos; Veronesi, Pietro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Tale of Two Runs: Depositor Responses to Bank Solvency Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iyer, Rajkamal; Puri, Manju; Ryan, Nicholas
We examine heterogeneity in depositor responses to solvency risk using depositor-level data for a bank that faced two different runs. We find that depositors with loans and bank staff are less likely to run than others during a low-solvency-risk shock, but are more likely to run during a high-solvency-risk shock. Uninsured depositors are also sensitive to bank solvency. In contrast, depositors with older accounts run less, and those with frequent past transactions run more, irrespective of the underlying risk. Our results show that the fragility of a bank depends on the composition of its deposit base.</description><author>Iyer, Rajkamal; Puri, Manju; Ryan, Nicholas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Creditor Rights Increase Employment Risk? Evidence from Loan Covenants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Falato, Antonio; Liang, Nellie
Using a regression discontinuity design, we provide evidence that there are sharp and substantial employment cuts following loan covenant violations, when creditors gain rights to accelerate, restructure, or terminate a loan. The cuts are larger at firms with higher financing frictions and with weaker employee bargaining power, and during industry and macroeconomic downturns, when employees have fewer job opportunities. Union elections that create new labor bargaining units lead to higher loan spreads, consistent with creditors requiring compensation when employees gain bargaining power. Overall, binding financial contracts have a large impact on employees and are an amplification mechanism of economic downturns.</description><author>Falato, Antonio; Liang, Nellie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Lucas" in the Laboratory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asparouhova, Elena; Bossaerts, Peter; Roy, Nilanjan; Zame, William
We study the Lucas asset pricing model in a controlled setting. Participants trade two long-lived securities in a continuous open-book system. The experimental design emulates the stationary, infinite-horizon setting of the model and incentivizes participants to smooth consumption across periods. Consistent with the model, prices align with consumption betas and comove with aggregate dividends, particularly so when risk premia are higher. Trading significantly increases consumption smoothing compared to autarky. Nevertheless, as in field markets, prices are excessively volatile. The noise corrupts traditional generalized method of moment tests. Choices display substantial heterogeneity, with no subject representative for pricing.</description><author>Asparouhova, Elena; Bossaerts, Peter; Roy, Nilanjan; Zame, William</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Compensating Financial Experts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glode, Vincent; Lowery, Richard
We propose a labor market model in which financial firms compete for a scarce supply of workers who can be employed as either bankers or traders. While hiring bankers helps create a surplus that can be split between a firm and its trading counterparties, hiring traders helps the firm appropriate a greater share of that surplus away from its counterparties. Firms bid defensively for workers bound to become traders, who then earn more than bankers. As counterparties employ more traders, the benefit of employing bankers decreases. The model sheds light on the historical evolution of compensation in finance.</description><author>Glode, Vincent; Lowery, Richard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation Risk and Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Eichenbaum, Martin; Luo, Victor Xi; Rebelo, Sergio
Standard representative-agent models fail to account for the weak correlation between stock returns and measurable fundamentals, such as consumption and output growth. This failing, which underlies virtually all modern asset pricing puzzles, arises because these models load all uncertainty onto the supply side of the economy. We propose a simple theory of asset pricing in which demand shocks play a central role. These shocks give rise to valuation risk that allows the model to account for key asset pricing moments, such as the equity premium, the bond term premium, and the weak correlation between stock returns and fundamentals.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Eichenbaum, Martin; Luo, Victor Xi; Rebelo, Sergio</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Infrequent Rebalancing, Return Autocorrelation, and Seasonality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bogousslavsky, Vincent
A model of infrequent rebalancing can explain specific predictability patterns in the time series and cross-section of stock returns. First, infrequent rebalancing produces return autocorrelations that are consistent with empirical evidence from intraday returns and new evidence from daily returns. Autocorrelations can switch sign and become positive at the rebalancing horizon. Second, the cross-sectional variance in expected returns is larger when more traders rebalance. This effect generates seasonality in the cross-section of stock returns, which can help explain available empirical evidence.</description><author>Bogousslavsky, Vincent</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Misspecified Recovery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borovicka, Jaroslav; Hansen, Lars Peter; Scheinkman, Jose A.
Asset prices contain information about the probability distribution of future states and the stochastic discounting of those states as used by investors. To better understand the challenge in distinguishing investors' beliefs from risk-adjusted discounting, we use Perron-Frobenius Theory to isolate a positive martingale component of the stochastic discount factor process. This component recovers a probability measure that absorbs long-term risk adjustments. When the martingale is not degenerate, surmising that this recovered probability captures investors' beliefs distorts inference about risk-return tradeoffs. Stochastic discount factors in many structural models of asset prices have empirically relevant martingale components.</description><author>Borovicka, Jaroslav; Hansen, Lars Peter; Scheinkman, Jose A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Rationing, Income Exaggeration, and Adverse Selection in the Mortgage Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ambrose, Brent W.; Conklin, James; Yoshida, Jiro
We examine the role of borrower concerns about future credit availability in mitigating the effects of adverse selection and income misrepresentation in the mortgage market. We show that the majority of additional risk associated with low-doc mortgages originated prior to the Great Recession was due to adverse selection on the part of borrowers who could verify income but chose not to. We provide novel evidence that these borrowers were more likely to inflate or exaggerate their income. Our analysis suggests that recent regulatory changes that have essentially eliminated the low-doc loan product would result in credit rationing against self-employed borrowers.</description><author>Ambrose, Brent W.; Conklin, James; Yoshida, Jiro</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behind the Scenes: The Corporate Governance Preferences of Institutional Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McCahery, Joseph A.; Sautner, Zacharias; Starks, Laura T.
We survey institutional investors to better understand their role in the corporate governance of firms. Consistent with a number of theories, we document widespread behind-the-scenes intervention as well as governance-motivated exit. These governance mechanisms are viewed as complementary devices, with intervention typically occurring prior to a potential exit. We further find that long-term investors and investors that are less concerned about stock liquidity intervene more intensively. Finally, we find that most investors use proxy advisors and believe that the information provided by such advisors improves their own voting decisions.</description><author>McCahery, Joseph A.; Sautner, Zacharias; Starks, Laura T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning about Mutual Fund Managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Darwin; Kahraman, Bige; Mukherjee, Abhiroop
We study capital allocations to managers with two mutual funds, and show that investors learn about managers from their performance records. Flows into a fund are predicted by the manager's performance in his other fund, especially when he outperforms and when signals from the other fund are more useful. In equilibrium, capital should be allocated such that there is no cross-fund predictability. However, we find positive predictability, particularly among underperforming funds. Our results are consistent with incomplete learning: while investors move capital in the right direction, they do not withdraw enough capital when the manager underperforms in his other fund.</description><author>Choi, Darwin; Kahraman, Bige; Mukherjee, Abhiroop</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ties That Bind: How Business Connections Affect Mutual Fund Activism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cvijanovic, Dragana; Dasgupta, Amil; Zachariadis, Konstantinos E.
We investigate whether business ties with portfolio firms influence mutual funds' proxy voting using a comprehensive data set spanning 2003 to 2011. In contrast to prior literature, we find that business ties significantly influence promanagement voting at the level of individual pairs of fund families and firms after controlling for Institutional Shareholder Services (ISS) recommendations and holdings. The association is significant only for shareholder-sponsored proposals and stronger for those that pass or fail by relatively narrow margins. Our findings are consistent with a demand-driven model of biased voting in which company managers use existing business ties with funds to influence how they vote.</description><author>Cvijanovic, Dragana; Dasgupta, Amil; Zachariadis, Konstantinos E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firing Costs and Capital Structure Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Serfling, Matthew
I exploit the adoption of state-level labor protection laws as an exogenous increase in employee firing costs to examine how the costs associated with discharging workers affect capital structure decisions. I find that firms reduce debt ratios following the adoption of these laws, with this result stronger for firms that experience larger increases in firing costs. I also document that, following the adoption of these laws, a firm's degree of operating leverage rises, earnings variability increases, and employment becomes more rigid. Overall, these results are consistent with higher firing costs crowding out financial leverage via increasing financial distress costs.</description><author>Serfling, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Scandals and Household Stock Market Participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Wang, Tracy Yue
We show that, after the revelation of corporate fraud in a state, household stock market participation in that state decreases. Households decrease holdings in fraudulent as well as nonfraudulent firms, even if they do not hold stocks in fraudulent firms. Within a state, households with more lifetime experience of corporate fraud hold less equity. Following the exogenous increase in fraud revelation due to Arthur Andersen's demise, states with more Arthur Andersen clients experience a larger decrease in stock market participation. We provide evidence that the documented effect is likely to reflect a loss of trust in the stock market.</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Wang, Tracy Yue</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model of Financialization of Commodities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, Suleyman; Pavlova, Anna
We analyze how institutional investors entering commodity futures markets, referred to as the financialization of commodities, affect commodity prices. Institutional investors care about their performance relative to a commodity index. We find that all commodity futures prices, volatilities, and correlations go up with financialization, but more so for index futures than for nonindex futures. The equity-commodity correlations also increase. We demonstrate how financial markets transmit shocks not only to futures prices but also to commodity spot prices and inventories. Spot prices go up with financialization, and shocks to any index commodity spill over to all storable commodity prices.</description><author>Basak, Suleyman; Pavlova, Anna</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Venture Capital Monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Shai; Giroud, Xavier; Townsend, Richard R.
We show that venture capitalists' (VCs) on-site involvement with their portfolio companies leads to an increase in both innovation and the likelihood of a successful exit. We rule out selection effects by exploiting an exogenous source of variation in VC involvement: the introduction of new airline routes that reduce VCs' travel times to their existing portfolio companies. We confirm the importance of this channel by conducting a large-scale survey of VCs, of whom almost 90% indicate that direct flights increase their interaction with their portfolio companies and management, and help them better understand companies' activities.</description><author>Bernstein, Shai; Giroud, Xavier; Townsend, Richard R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Optimal Size of Hedge Funds: Conflict between Investors and Fund Managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yin, Chengdong
This study examines whether the standard compensation contract in the hedge fund industry aligns managers' incentives with investors' interests. I show empirically that managers' compensation increases when fund assets grow, even when diseconomies of scale in fund performance exist. Thus, managers' compensation is maximized at a much larger fund size than is optimal for fund performance. However, to avoid capital outflows, managers are also motivated to restrict fund growth to maintain style-average performance. Similarly, fund management firms have incentives to collect more capital for all funds under management, including their flagship funds, even at the expense of fund performance.</description><author>Yin, Chengdong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Editor of the Journal of Finance for the Year 2015</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singleton, Kenneth J.
nan</description><author>Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential Address: Debt and Money: Financial Constraints and Sovereign Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick
Economic analyses of corporate finance, money, and sovereign debt are largely considered separately. I introduce a novel corporate finance framing of sovereign finance based on the analogy between fiat liabilities for sovereigns and equity for corporations. The analysis focuses on financial constraints at the country level, making explicit the trade-offs involved in relying on domestic versus foreign-currency debt to finance investments or government expenditures. This framing provides new insights into issues ranging from the costs and benefits of inflation, optimal foreign exchange reserves, and sovereign debt restructuring.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return Seasonalities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keloharju, Matti; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Nyberg, Peter
A strategy that selects stocks based on their historical same-calendar-month returns earns an average return of 13% per year. We document similar return seasonalities in anomalies, commodities, and international stock market indices, as well as at the daily frequency. The seasonalities overwhelm unconditional differences in expected returns. The correlations between different seasonality strategies are modest, suggesting that they emanate from different systematic factors. Our results suggest that seasonalities are not a distinct class of anomalies that requires an explanation of its own, but rather that they are intertwined with other return anomalies through shared systematic factors.</description><author>Keloharju, Matti; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Nyberg, Peter</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Enhancing Shareholder Control: A (Dodd-) Frank Assessment of Proxy Access</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohn, Jonathan B.; Gillan, Stuart L.; Hartzell, Jay C.
We use events related to a proxy access rule passed by the Securities and Exchange Commission in 2010 as natural experiments to study the valuation effects of changes in shareholder control. We find that valuations increase (decrease) following increases (decreases) in perceived control, especially for firms that are poorly performing, have shareholders likely to exercise control, and where acquiring a stake is relatively inexpensive. These results suggest that an increase in shareholder control from its current level would generally benefit shareholders. However, we find that the benefits of increased control are muted for firms with shareholders whose interests may deviate from value maximization.</description><author>Cohn, Jonathan B.; Gillan, Stuart L.; Hartzell, Jay C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-Sharing or Risk-Taking? Counterparty Risk, Incentives, and Margins</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biais, Bruno; Heider, Florian; Hoerova, Marie
Derivatives activity, motivated by risk-sharing, can breed risk-taking. Bad news about the risk of an asset underlying a derivative increases protection sellers' expected liability and undermines their risk-prevention incentives. This limits risk-sharing, creates endogenous counterparty risk, and can lead to contagion from news about the hedged risk to the balance sheet of protection sellers. Margin calls after bad news can improve protection sellers' incentives and in turn enhance risk-sharing. Central clearing can provide insurance against counterparty risk but must be designed to preserve risk-prevention incentives.</description><author>Biais, Bruno; Heider, Florian; Hoerova, Marie</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good-Specific Habit Formation and the Cross-Section of Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Binsbergen, Jules H.
I study asset prices in a general equilibrium framework in which agents form habits over individual varieties of goods rather than over an aggregate consumption bundle. Goods are produced by monopolistically competitive firms whose elasticities of demand depend on consumers' habit formation. Firms that produce goods with a high habit level relative to consumption have low demand elasticities, set high prices for their product, have low expected returns on their stock, and have low asset pricing betas and stock return volatilities. I find supportive evidence for these predictions in the data.</description><author>van Binsbergen, Jules H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Private Firms Invest Differently than Public Firms? Taking Cues from the Natural Gas Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilje, Erik P.; Taillard, Jerome P.
We study how listing status affects investment behavior. Theory offers competing hypotheses on how listing-related frictions affect investment decisions. We use detailed data on 74,670 individual projects in the U.S. natural gas industry to show that private firms respond less than public firms to changes in investment opportunities. Private firms adjust drilling activity for low capital-intensity investments. However, they do not increase drilling in response to new capital-intensive growth opportunities. Instead, they sell these projects to public firms. Our evidence suggests that differences in access to external capital are important in explaining the investment behavior of public and private firms.</description><author>Gilje, Erik P.; Taillard, Jerome P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It Pays to Set the Menu: Mutual Fund Investment Options in 401(k) Plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pool, Veronika K.; Sialm, Clemens; Stefanescu, Irina
This paper investigates whether mutual fund families acting as service providers in 401(k) plans display favoritism toward their own affiliated funds. Using a hand-collected data set on the menu of investment options offered to plan participants, we show that fund deletions and additions are less sensitive to prior performance for affiliated than unaffiliated funds. We find no evidence that plan participants undo this affiliation bias through their investment choices. Finally, we find that the subsequent performance of poorly performing affiliated funds indicates that this favoritism is not information driven.</description><author>Pool, Veronika K.; Sialm, Clemens; Stefanescu, Irina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exodus from Sovereign Risk: Global Asset and Information Networks in the Pricing of Corporate Credit Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Jongsub; Naranjo, Andy; Sirmans, Stace
Using five-year credit default swap (CDS) spreads on 2,364 companies in 54 countries from 2004 to 2011, we find that firms exposed to stronger property rights through their foreign asset positions (institutional channel) and firms cross-listed on exchanges with stricter disclosure requirements (informational channel) reduce their CDS spreads by 40 bps for a one-standard-deviation increase in their exposure to the two channels. These channels capture effects beyond those associated with firm- and country-level fundamentals. Overall, we find that firm-level global asset and information connections are important mechanisms to delink firms from their sovereign and country risks.</description><author>Lee, Jongsub; Naranjo, Andy; Sirmans, Stace</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should Derivatives Be Privileged in Bankruptcy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Oehmke, Martin
Derivatives enjoy special status in bankruptcy: they are exempt from the automatic stay and effectively senior to virtually all other claims. We propose a corporate finance model to assess the effect of these exemptions on a firm's cost of borrowing and incentives to engage in derivative transactions. While derivatives are value-enhancing risk management tools, seniority for derivatives can lead to inefficiencies: it transfers credit risk to debtholders, even though this risk is borne more efficiently in the derivative market. Seniority for derivatives is efficient only if it provides sufficient cross-netting benefits to derivative counterparties that provide hedging services.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Oehmke, Martin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Wall Street Walk when Blockholders Compete for Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dasgupta, Amil; Piacentino, Giorgia
Effective monitoring by equity blockholders is important for good corporate governance. A prominent theoretical literature argues that the threat of block sale (exit) can be an effective governance mechanism. Many blockholders are money managers. We show that, when money managers compete for investor capital, the threat of exit loses credibility, weakening its governance role. Money managers with more skin in the game will govern more successfully using exit. Allowing funds to engage in activist measures (voice) does not alter our qualitative results. Our results link widely prevalent incentives in the ever-expanding money management industry to the nature of corporate governance.</description><author>Dasgupta, Amil; Piacentino, Giorgia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government Intervention and Information Aggregation by Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bond, Philip; Goldstein, Itay
Governments intervene in firms' lives in a variety of ways. To enhance the efficiency of government intervention, many researchers and policy makers call for governments to make use of information contained in stock market prices. However, price informativeness is endogenous to government policy. We analyze government policy in light of this endogeneity. In some cases, it is optimal for a government to commit to limit its reliance on market prices to avoid harming the aggregation of information into market prices. For similar reasons, it is optimal for a government to limit transparency in some dimensions.</description><author>Bond, Philip; Goldstein, Itay</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mandatory Portfolio Disclosure, Stock Liquidity, and Mutual Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Mullally, Kevin A.; Tang, Yuehua; Yang, Baozhong
We examine the impact of mandatory portfolio disclosure by mutual funds on stock liquidity and fund performance. We develop a model of informed trading with disclosure and test its predictions using the May 2004 SEC regulation requiring more frequent disclosure. Stocks with higher fund ownership, especially those held by more informed funds or subject to greater information asymmetry, experience larger increases in liquidity after the regulation change. More informed funds, especially those holding stocks with greater information asymmetry, experience greater performance deterioration after the regulation change. Overall, mandatory disclosure improves stock liquidity but imposes costs on informed investors.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Mullally, Kevin A.; Tang, Yuehua; Yang, Baozhong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreclosures, House Prices, and the Real Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mian, Atif; Sufi, Amir; Trebbi, Francesco
From 2007 to 2009, states without a judicial requirement for foreclosures were twice as likely to foreclose on delinquent homeowners. Analysis of borders of states with differing foreclosure laws reveals a discrete jump in foreclosure propensity as one enters nonjudicial states. Using state judicial requirement as an instrument for foreclosures, we show that foreclosures led to a large decline in house prices, residential investment, and consumer demand from 2007 to 2009. As foreclosures subsided from 2011 to 2013, the foreclosure rates in nonjudicial and judicial requirement states converged and we find some evidence of a stronger recovery in nonjudicial states.</description><author>Mian, Atif; Sufi, Amir; Trebbi, Francesco</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Historical Cost Accounting a Panacea? Market Stress, Incentive Distortions, and Gains Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellul, Andrew; Jotikasthira, Chotibhak; Lundblad, Christian T.; Wang, Yihui
Accounting rules, through their interactions with capital regulations, affect financial institutions' trading behavior. The insurance industry provides a laboratory to explore these interactions: life insurers have greater flexibility than property and casualty insurers to hold speculative-grade assets at historical cost, and the degree to which life insurers recognize market values differs across U.S. states. During the financial crisis, insurers facing a lesser degree of market value recognition are less likely to sell downgraded asset-backed securities. To improve their capital positions, these insurers disproportionately resort to gains trading, selectively selling otherwise unrelated bonds with high unrealized gains, transmitting shocks across markets.</description><author>Ellul, Andrew; Jotikasthira, Chotibhak; Lundblad, Christian T.; Wang, Yihui</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Overhang and Loan Portfolio Decisions: Small Business Loan Supply before and during the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deyoung, Robert; Gron, Anne; Torna, Goekhan; Winton, Andrew
We estimate a structural model of bank portfolio lending and find that the typical U.S. community bank reduced its business lending during the global financial crisis. The decline in business credit was driven by increased risk overhang effects (consistent with a reduction in the liquidity of assets held on bank balance sheets) and by reduced loan supply elasticities suggestive of credit rationing (consistent with an increase in lender risk aversion). Nevertheless, we identify a group of strategically focused relationship banks that made and maintained higher levels of business loans during the crisis.</description><author>Deyoung, Robert; Gron, Anne; Torna, Goekhan; Winton, Andrew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory Arbitrage and Cross-Border Bank Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karolyi, G. Andrew; Taboada, Alvaro G.
We study how differences in bank regulation influence cross-border bank acquisition flows and share price reactions to cross-border deal announcements. Using a sample of 7,297 domestic and 916 majority cross-border deals announced between 1995 and 2012, we find evidence of a form of regulatory arbitrage whereby acquisition flows involve acquirers from countries with stronger regulations than their targets. Target and aggregate abnormal returns around deal announcements are positive and larger when acquirers come from more restrictive bank regulatory environments. We interpret this evidence as more consistent with a benign form of regulatory arbitrage than a potentially destructive one.</description><author>Karolyi, G. Andrew; Taboada, Alvaro G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Control and the Costs of Illiquidity (vol 70, pg 1405, 2015)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Schroth, Enrique
nan</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Schroth, Enrique</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Institutional Investors in Voting: Evidence from the Securities Lending Market (vol 70, pg 2309, 2015)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Reena; Saffi, Pedro A. C.; Sturgess, Jason
nan</description><author>Aggarwal, Reena; Saffi, Pedro A. C.; Sturgess, Jason</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Preferences and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jenter, Dirk; Lewellen, Katharina
This paper explores the impact of target CEOs' retirement preferences on takeovers. Using retirement age as a proxy for CEOs' private merger costs, we find strong evidence that target CEOs' preferences affect merger activity. The likelihood of receiving a successful takeover bid is sharply higher when target CEOs are close to age 65. Takeover premiums and target announcement returns are similar for retirement-age and younger CEOs, implying that retirement-age CEOs increase firm sales without sacrificing premiums. Better corporate governance is associated with more acquisitions of firms led by young CEOs, and with a smaller increase in deals at retirement age.</description><author>Jenter, Dirk; Lewellen, Katharina</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The People in Your Neighborhood: Social Interactions and Mutual Fund Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pool, Veronika K.; Stoffman, Noah; Yonker, Scott E.
We find that socially connected fund managers have more similar holdings and trades. The overlap of funds whose managers reside in the same neighborhood is considerably higher than that of funds whose managers live in the same city but in different neighborhoods. These effects are larger when managers share a similar ethnic background, and are not explained by preferences. Valuable information is transmitted through these peer networks: a long-short strategy composed of stocks purchased minus sold by neighboring managers delivers positive risk-adjusted returns. Unlike prior empirical work, our tests disentangle the effects of social interactions from community effects.</description><author>Pool, Veronika K.; Stoffman, Noah; Yonker, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Quality Misrepresentation by Financial Intermediaries: Evidence from the RMBS Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piskorski, Tomasz; Seru, Amit; Witkin, James
We document that contractual disclosures by intermediaries during the sale of mortgages contained false information about the borrower's housing equity in 7-14% of loans. The rate of misrepresented loan default was 70% higher than for similar loans. These misrepresentations likely occurred late in the intermediation and exist among securities sold by all reputable intermediaries. Investorsincluding large institutionsholding securities with misrepresented collateral suffered severe losses due to loan defaults, price declines, and ratings downgrades. Pools with misrepresentations were not issued at a discount. Misrepresentation on another easy-to-quantify dimension shows that these effects are a conservative lower bound.</description><author>Piskorski, Tomasz; Seru, Amit; Witkin, James</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal Capital Markets in Business Groups: Evidence from the Asian Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor; Kim, Chang-Soo; Kim, Hwanki Brian
This paper examines capital reallocation among firms in Korean business groups (chaebol) in the aftermath of the 1997 Asian financial crisis, and the consequences of this capital reallocation for the investment and performance of chaebol firms. We show that chaebol transferred cash from low-growth to high-growth member firms, using cross-firm equity investments. This capital reallocation allowed chaebol firms with greater investment opportunities to invest more than control firms after the crisis. These firms also showed higher profitability and lower declines in valuation than control firms following the crisis. Our results suggest that chaebol internal capital markets helped them mitigate the negative effects of the Asian crisis on investment and performance.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Kim, Chang-Soo; Kim, Hwanki Brian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The WACC Fallacy: The Real Effects of Using a Unique Discount Rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, Philipp; Landier, Augustin; Thesmar, David
In this paper, we test whether firms properly adjust for risk in their capital budgeting decisions. If managers use a single discount rate within firms, we expect that conglomerates underinvest (overinvest) in relatively safe (risky) divisions. We measure division relative risk as the difference between the division's asset beta and a firm-wide beta. We establish a robust and significant positive relationship between division-level investment and division relative risk. Next, we measure the value loss due to this behavior in the context of acquisitions. When the bidder's beta is lower than that of the target, announcement returns are significantly lower.</description><author>Krueger, Philipp; Landier, Augustin; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Providing Peer Information on Retirement Savings Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beshears, John; Choi, James J.; Laibson, David; Madrian, Brigitte C.; Milkman, Katherine L.
Using a field experiment in a 401(k) plan, we measure the effect of disseminating information about peer behavior on savings. Low-saving employees received simplified plan enrollment or contribution increase forms. A randomized subset of forms stated the fraction of age-matched coworkers participating in the plan or age-matched participants contributing at least 6% of pay to the plan. We document an oppositional reaction: the presence of peer information decreased the savings of nonparticipants who were ineligible for 401(k) automatic enrollment, and higher observed peer savings rates also decreased savings. Discouragement from upward social comparisons seems to drive this reaction.</description><author>Beshears, John; Choi, James J.; Laibson, David; Madrian, Brigitte C.; Milkman, Katherine L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend Dynamics and the Term Structure of Dividend Strips</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belo, Frederico; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.
Many leading asset pricing models are specified so that the term structure of dividend volatility is either flat or upward sloping. These models predict that the term structures of expected returns and volatilities on dividend strips (i.e., claims to dividends paid over a prespecified interval) are also upward sloping. However, the empirical evidence suggests otherwise. This discrepancy can be reconciled if these models replace their proposed dividend dynamics with processes that generate stationary leverage ratios. Under such policies, shareholders are forced to divest (invest) when leverage is low (high), which shifts risk from long- to short-horizon dividend strips.</description><author>Belo, Frederico; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is a VC Partnership Greater Than the Sum of Its Partners?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ewens, Michael; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew
This paper investigates whether individual venture capitalists have repeatable investment skill and the extent to which their skill is impacted by the venture capital (VC) firm where they work. We examine a unique data set that tracks the performance of individual venture capitalists' investments over time and as they move between firms. We find evidence of skill and exit style differences even among venture partners investing at the same VC firm at the same time. Furthermore, our estimates suggest the partners' human capital is two to five times more important than the VC firm's organizational capital in explaining performance.</description><author>Ewens, Michael; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anchoring on Credit Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dougal, Casey; Engelberg, Joseph; Parsons, Christopher A.; Van Wesep, Edward D.
This paper documents that the path of credit spreads since a firm's last loan influences the level at which it can currently borrow. If spreads have moved in the firm's favor (i.e., declined), it is charged a higher interest rate than is justified by current fundamentals, whereas if spreads have moved to the firm's detriment, it is charged a lower rate. We evaluate several possible explanations for this finding, and conclude that anchoring to past deal terms is most plausible.</description><author>Dougal, Casey; Engelberg, Joseph; Parsons, Christopher A.; Van Wesep, Edward D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Innovation, Growth, and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kung, Howard; Schmid, Lukas
We examine the asset pricing implications of a production economy whose long-term growth prospects are endogenously determined by innovation and R&amp;D. In equilibrium, R&amp;D endogenously drives a small, persistent component in productivity that generates long-run uncertainty about economic growth. With recursive preferences, households fear that persistent downturns in economic growth are accompanied by low asset valuations and command high-risk premia in asset markets. Empirically, we find substantial evidence for innovation-driven low-frequency movements in aggregate growth rates and asset market valuations. In short, equilibrium growth is risky.</description><author>Kung, Howard; Schmid, Lukas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rewarding Trading Skills without Inducing Gambling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Makarov, Igor; Plantin, Guillaume
This paper develops a model of active asset management in which fund managers may forgo alpha-generating strategies, preferring instead to make negative-alpha trades that enable them to temporarily manipulate investors' perceptions of their skills. We show that such trades are optimally generated by taking on hidden tail risk, and are more likely to occur when fund managers are impatient and when their trading skills are scalable, and generate a high profit per unit of risk. We propose long-term contracts that deter this behavior by dynamically adjusting the dates on which the manager is compensated in response to her cumulative performance.</description><author>Makarov, Igor; Plantin, Guillaume</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Taxes and Securitization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Joongho; Park, Kwangwoo; Pennacchi, George
Most banks pay corporate income taxes, but securitization vehicles do not. Our model shows that, when a bank faces strong loan demand but limited deposit market power, this tax asymmetry creates an incentive to sell loans despite less-efficient screening and monitoring of sold loans. Moreover, loan-selling increases as a bank's corporate income tax rate and capital requirement rise. Our empirical tests show that U.S. commercial banks sell more of their mortgages when they operate in states that impose higher corporate income taxes. A policy implication is that tax-induced loan-selling will rise if banks' required equity capital increases.</description><author>Han, Joongho; Park, Kwangwoo; Pennacchi, George</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Connectedness and Corporate Fraud</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khanna, Vikramaditya; Kim, E. Han; Lu, Yao
We find that connections CEOs develop with top executives and directors through their appointment decisions increase the risk of corporate fraud. Appointment-based CEO connectedness in executive suites and boardrooms increases the likelihood of committing fraud and decreases the likelihood of detection. Additionally, it decreases the expected costs of fraud by helping conceal fraudulent activity, making CEO dismissal less likely upon discovery, and lowering the coordination costs of carrying out illegal activity. Connections based on network ties through past employment, education, or social organization memberships have insignificant effects on fraud. Appointment-based CEO connectedness warrants attention from regulators, investors, and corporate governance specialists.</description><author>Khanna, Vikramaditya; Kim, E. Han; Lu, Yao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Change You Can Believe In? Hedge Fund Data Revisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patton, Andrew J.; Ramadorai, Tarun; Streatfield, Michael
We analyze the reliability of voluntary disclosures of financial information, focusing on widely-employed publicly-available hedge fund databases. Tracking changes to statements of historical performance recorded between 2007 and 2011, we find that historical returns are routinely revised. These revisions are not merely random or corrections of earlier mistakes; they are partly forecastable by fund characteristics. Funds that revise their performance histories significantly and predictably underperform those that have never revised, suggesting that unreliable disclosures constitute a valuable source of information for investors. These results speak to current debates about mandatory disclosures by financial institutions to market regulators.</description><author>Patton, Andrew J.; Ramadorai, Tarun; Streatfield, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Design of Contingent Capital with a Market Trigger</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sundaresan, Suresh; Wang, Zhenyu
Contingent capital (CC), which aims to internalize the costs of too-big-to-fail in the capital structure of large banks, has been under intense debate by policy makers and academics. We show that CC with a market trigger, in which direct stakeholders are unable to choose optimal conversion policies, does not lead to a unique competitive equilibrium unless value transfer at conversion is not expected ex ante. The "no value transfer" restriction precludes penalizing bank managers for taking excessive risk. Multiplicity or absence of equilibrium introduces the potential for price uncertainty, market manipulation, inefficient capital allocation, and frequent conversion errors.</description><author>Sundaresan, Suresh; Wang, Zhenyu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size Anomalies in U.S. Bank Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gandhi, Priyank; Lustig, Hanno
The largest commercial bank stocks, ranked by total size of the balance sheet, have significantly lower risk-adjusted returns than small-and medium-sized bank stocks, even though large banks are significantlymore levered. We uncover a size factor in the component of bank returns that is orthogonal to the standard risk factors, including small minus big, which has the right covariance with bank returns to explain the average risk-adjusted returns. This factormeasures size-dependent exposure to bank-specific tail risk. These findings are consistent with government guarantees that protect shareholders of large banks, but not small banks, in disaster states.</description><author>Gandhi, Priyank; Lustig, Hanno</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subprime Mortgage Defaults and Credit Default Swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arentsen, Eric; Mauer, David C.; Rosenlund, Brian; Zhang, Harold H.; Zhao, Feng
We offer the first empirical evidence on the adverse effect of credit default swap (CDS) coverage on subprime mortgage defaults. Using a large database of privately securitized mortgages, we find that higher defaults concentrate in mortgage pools with concurrent CDS coverage, and within these pools the loans originated after or shortly before the start of CDS coverage have an even higher delinquency rate. The results are robust across zip code and origination quarter cohorts. Overall, we show that CDS coverage helped drive higher mortgage defaults during the financial crisis.</description><author>Arentsen, Eric; Mauer, David C.; Rosenlund, Brian; Zhang, Harold H.; Zhao, Feng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Succession Taxes on Family Firm Investment: Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsoutsoura, Margarita
This paper provides causal evidence on the impact of succession taxes on firm investment decisions and transfer of control. Using a 2002 policy change in Greece that substantially reduced the tax on intrafamily transfers of businesses, I show that succession taxes lead to a more than 40% decline in investment around family successions, slow sales growth, and a depletion of cash reserves. Furthermore, succession taxes strongly affect the decision to sell or retain the firm within the family. I conclude by discussing implications of my findings for firms in the United States and Europe.</description><author>Tsoutsoura, Margarita</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate Jump and Volatility Risk in the Cross-Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, Martijn; Halling, Michael; Weinbaum, David
We examine the pricing of both aggregate jump and volatility risk in the cross-section of stock returns by constructing investable option trading strategies that load on one factor but are orthogonal to the other. Both aggregate jump and volatility risk help explain variation in expected returns. Consistent with theory, stocks with high sensitivities to jump and volatility risk have low expected returns. Both can be measured separately and are important economically, with a two-standard-deviation increase in jump (volatility) factor loadings associated with a 3.5% to 5.1% (2.7% to 2.9%) drop in expected annual stock returns.</description><author>Cremers, Martijn; Halling, Michael; Weinbaum, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentivizing Calculated Risk-Taking: Evidence from an Experiment with Commercial Bank Loan Officers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cole, Shawn; Kanz, Martin; Klapper, Leora
We conduct an experiment with commercial bank loan officers to test how performance compensation affects risk assessment and lending. High-powered incentives lead to greater screening effort and more profitable lending decisions. This effect is muted, however, by deferred compensation and limited liability, two standard features of loan officer compensation contracts. We find that career concerns and personality traits affect loan officer behavior, but show that the response to incentives does not vary with traits such as risk-aversion, optimism, or overconfidence. Finally, we present evidence that incentives distort the assessment of credit risk, even among professionals with many years of experience.</description><author>Cole, Shawn; Kanz, Martin; Klapper, Leora</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subsidizing Liquidity: The Impact of Make/Take Fees on Market Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malinova, Katya; Park, Andreas
Facing increased competition over the last decade, many stock exchanges changed their trading fees to maker-taker pricing, an incentive scheme that rewards liquidity suppliers and charges liquidity demanders. Using a change in trading fees on the Toronto Stock Exchange, we study whether and why the breakdown of trading fees between liquidity demanders and suppliers matters. Posted quotes adjust after the change in fee composition, but the transaction costs for liquidity demanders remain unaffected once fees are taken into account. However, as posted bid-ask spreads decline, traders (particularly retail) use aggressive orders more frequently, and adverse selection costs decrease.</description><author>Malinova, Katya; Park, Andreas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Household Portfolio Diversification Vary with Financial Literacy and Financial Advice?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Von Gaudecker, Hans-Martin
Household investment mistakes are an important concern for researchers and policymakers alike. Portfolio underdiversification ranks among those mistakes that are potentially most costly. However, its roots and empirical importance are poorly understood. I estimate quantitatively meaningful diversification statistics and investigate their relationship with key variables. Nearly all households that score high on financial literacy or rely on professionals or private contacts for advice achieve reasonable investment outcomes. Compared to these groups, households with below-median financial literacy that trust their own decision-making capabilities lose an expected 50 bps on average. All group differences stem from the top of the loss distribution.</description><author>Von Gaudecker, Hans-Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Recovery Theorem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ross, Steve
We can only estimate the distribution of stock returns, but from option prices we observe the distribution of state prices. State prices are the product of risk aversion-the pricing kernel-and the natural probability distribution. The Recovery Theorem enables us to separate these to determine the market's forecast of returns and risk aversion from state prices alone. Among other things, this allows us to recover the pricing kernel, market risk premium, and probability of a catastrophe and to construct model-free tests of the efficient market hypothesis.</description><author>Ross, Steve</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Yesterday's Heroes: Compensation and Risk at Financial Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Ing-Haw; Hong, Harrison; Scheinkman, Jose A.
Many believe that compensation, misaligned from shareholders' value due to managerial entrenchment, caused financial firms to take risks before the financial crisis of 2008. We argue that, even in a classical principal-agent setting without entrenchment and with exogenous firm risk, riskier firms may offer higher total pay as compensation for the extra risk in equity stakes borne by risk-averse managers. Using long lags of stock price risk to capture exogenous firm risk, we confirm our conjecture and show that riskier firms are also more productive and more likely to be held by institutional investors, who are most able to influence compensation.</description><author>Cheng, Ing-Haw; Hong, Harrison; Scheinkman, Jose A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Defined Contribution Pension Plans: Sticky or Discerning Money?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sialm, Clemens; Starks, Laura T.; Zhang, Hanjiang
Participants in defined contribution (DC) retirement plans rarely adjust their portfolio allocations, suggesting that their investment choices and consequent money flows are sticky and not discerning. However, participants' inertia could be offset by DC plan sponsors, who adjust the plan's investment options. We examine these countervailing influences on flows into U.S. mutual funds. We find that flows into funds from DC assets are more volatile and exhibit more performance sensitivity than non-DC flows, primarily due to adjustments to the investment options by the plan sponsors. Thus, DC retirement money is less sticky and more discerning than non-DC money.</description><author>Sialm, Clemens; Starks, Laura T.; Zhang, Hanjiang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating Oil Risk Factors Using Information from Equity and Derivatives Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiang, I.-Hsuan Ethan; Hughen, W. Keener; Sagi, Jacob S.
We introduce a novel approach to estimating latent oil risk factors and establish their significance in pricing nonoil securities. Our model, which features four factors with simple economic interpretations, is estimated using both derivative prices and oil-related equity returns. The fit is excellent in and out of sample. The extracted oil factors carry significant risk premia, and are significantly related to macroeconomic variables as well as portfolio returns sorted on characteristics and industry. The average nonoil portfolio exhibits a sensitivity to the oil factors amounting to a sixth (in magnitude) of that of the oil industry itself.</description><author>Chiang, I.-Hsuan Ethan; Hughen, W. Keener; Sagi, Jacob S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Institutional Investors in Voting: Evidence from the Securities Lending Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Reena; Saffi, Pedro A. C.; Sturgess, Jason
This paper investigates voting preferences of institutional investors using the unique setting of the securities lending market. Investors restrict lendable supply and/or recall loaned shares prior to the proxy record date to exercise voting rights. Recall is higher for investors with greater incentives to monitor, for firms with poor performance or weak governance, and for proposals where returns to governance are likely higher. At the subsequent vote, recall is associated with less support for management and more support for shareholder proposals. Our results indicate that institutions value their vote and use the proxy process to affect corporate governance.</description><author>Aggarwal, Reena; Saffi, Pedro A. C.; Sturgess, Jason</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Outsourcing in the International Mutual Fund Industry: An Equilibrium View</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chuprinin, Oleg; Massa, Massimo; Schumacher, David
We study outsourcing relationships among international asset management firms. We find that, in companies that manage both outsourced and in-house funds, in-house funds outperform outsourced funds by 0.85% annually (57% of the expense ratio). We attribute this result to preferential treatment of in-house funds via the preferential allocation of IPOs, trading opportunities, and cross-trades, especially at times when in-house funds face steep outflows and require liquidity. We explain preferential treatment with agency problems: it increases with the subcontractor's market power and the difficulty of monitoring the subcontractor, and decreases with the subcontractor's amount of parallel in-house activity.</description><author>Chuprinin, Oleg; Massa, Massimo; Schumacher, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Turnover and Relative Performance Evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jenter, Dirk; Kanaan, Fadi
This paper shows that CEOs are fired after bad firm performance caused by factors beyond their control. Standard economic theory predicts that corporate boards filter out exogenous industry and market shocks from firm performance before deciding on CEO retention. Using a hand-collected sample of 3,365 CEO turnovers from 1993 to 2009, we document that CEOs are significantly more likely to be dismissed from their jobs after bad industry and, to a lesser extent, after bad market performance. A decline in industry performance from the 90(th) to the 10(th) percentile doubles the probability of a forced CEO turnover.</description><author>Jenter, Dirk; Kanaan, Fadi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Beauty Contest and Short-Term Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cespa, Giovanni; Vives, Xavier
Short-termism need not breed informational price inefficiency even when generating beauty contests. We demonstrate this claim in a two-period market with persistent liquidity trading and risk-averse, privately informed, short-term investors and find that prices reflect average expectations about fundamentals and liquidity trading. Informed investors engage in retrospective learning to reassess inferences (about fundamentals) made during the trading game's early stages. This behavior introduces strategic complementarities in the use of information and can yield two stable equilibria that can be ranked in terms of liquidity, volatility, and informational efficiency. We derive implications that explain market anomalies as well as empirical regularities.</description><author>Cespa, Giovanni; Vives, Xavier</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informational Frictions and Commodity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sockin, Michael; Xiong, Wei
This paper develops a model with a tractable log-linear equilibrium to analyze the effects of informational frictions in commodity markets. By aggregating dispersed information about the strength of the global economy among goods producers whose production has complementarity, commodity prices serve as price signals to guide producers' production decisions and commodity demand. Our model highlights important feedback effects of informational noise originating from supply shocks and futures market trading on commodity demand and spot prices. Our analysis illustrates the weakness common in empirical studies on commodity markets of assuming that different types of shocks are publicly observable to market participants.</description><author>Sockin, Michael; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric Learning from Financial Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuhnen, Camelia M.
This study asks whether investors learn differently from gains versus losses. I find experimental evidence that indicates that being in the negative domain leads individuals to form overly pessimistic beliefs about available investment options. This pessimism bias is driven by people reacting more to low outcomes in the negative domain relative to the positive domain. Such asymmetric learning may help explain documented empirical patterns regarding the differential role of poor versus good economic conditions on investment behavior and household economic choices.</description><author>Kuhnen, Camelia M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage Asymmetry and the Idiosyncratic Volatility Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yu, Jianfeng; Yuan, Yu
Buying is easier than shorting for many equity investors. Combining this arbitrage asymmetry with the arbitrage risk represented by idiosyncratic volatility (IVOL) explains the negative relation between IVOL and average return. The IVOL-return relation is negative among overpriced stocks but positive among underpriced stocks, with mispricing determined by combining 11 return anomalies. Consistent with arbitrage asymmetry, the negative relation among overpriced stocks is stronger, especially for stocks less easily shorted, so the overall IVOL-return relation is negative. Further supporting our explanation, high investor sentiment weakens the positive relation among underpriced stocks and, especially, strengthens the negative relation among overpriced stocks.</description><author>Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yu, Jianfeng; Yuan, Yu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency Conflicts, Investment, and Asset Pricing (vol 63, pg 1, 2008)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Wang, Neng
nan</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Wang, Neng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hidden Liquidity: Some New Light on Dark Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloomfield, Robert; O'Hara, Maureen; Saar, Gideon
Using a laboratory market, we investigate how the ability to hide orders affects traders' strategies and market outcomes in a limit order book environment. We find that order strategies are greatly affected by allowing hidden liquidity, with traders substituting nondisplayed for displayed shares and changing the aggressiveness of their trading. As traders adapt their behavior to the different opacity regimes, however, most aggregate market outcomes (such as liquidity and informational efficiency) are not affected as much. We also find that opacity appears to increase the profits of informed traders but only when their private information is very valuable.</description><author>Bloomfield, Robert; O'Hara, Maureen; Saar, Gideon</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cost of Capital for Alternative Investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jurek, Jakub W.; Stafford, Erik
Traditional risk factor models indicate that hedge funds capture pre-fee alphas of 6% to 10% per annum over the period from 1996 to 2012. At the same time, the hedge fund return series is not reliably distinguishable from the returns of mechanical S&amp;P 500 put-writing strategies. We show that the high excess returns to hedge funds and put-writing are consistent with an equilibrium in which a small subset of investors specialize in bearing downside market risks. Required rates of return in such an equilibrium can dramatically exceed those suggested by traditional models, affecting inference about the attractiveness of these investments.</description><author>Jurek, Jakub W.; Stafford, Erik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Making Contracts, Firm Value, and the IPO Decision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Hao, Jia; Zheng, Kuncheng
We examine the effects of secondary market liquidity on firm value and the IPO decision. Competitive aftermarket liquidity provision is associated with reduced welfare and a discounted secondary market price that can dissuade IPOs. The competitive market fails in particular for firms or at times when uncertainty regarding fundamental value and asymmetric information are large in combination. In these cases, firm value and welfare are improved by a contract where the firm engages a designated market maker to enhance liquidity. Such contracts represent a market solution to a market imperfection, particularly for small, growth firms.</description><author>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Hao, Jia; Zheng, Kuncheng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wall Street Occupations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Axelson, Ulf; Bond, Philip
Many finance jobs entail the risk of large losses, and hard-to-monitor effort. We analyze the equilibrium consequences of these features in a model with optimal dynamic contracting. We show that finance jobs feature high compensation, up-or-out promotion, and long work hours, and are more attractive than other jobs. Moral hazard problems are exacerbated in booms, even though pay increases. Employees whose talent would be more valuable elsewhere can be lured into finance jobs, while the most talented employees might be unable to land these jobs because they are too hard to manage.</description><author>Axelson, Ulf; Bond, Philip</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reaching for Yield in the Bond Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Bo; Ivashina, Victoria
This paper studies reaching for yieldinvestors' propensity to buy riskier assets to achieve higher yieldsin the corporate bond market. We show that insurance companies reach for yield in choosing their investments. Consistent with lower rated bonds bearing higher capital requirements, insurance firms prefer to hold higher rated bonds. However, conditional on credit ratings, insurance portfolios are systematically biased toward higher yield, higher CDS bonds. This behavior is related to the business cycle being most pronounced during economic expansions. It is also characteristic of firms with poor corporate governance and for which the regulatory capital requirement is more binding.</description><author>Becker, Bo; Ivashina, Victoria</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Change You Can Believe In? Hedge Fund Data Revisions (vol 70, pg 963, 2015)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patton, Andrew J.; Ramadorai, Tarun; Streatfield, Michael
nan</description><author>Patton, Andrew J.; Ramadorai, Tarun; Streatfield, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Editor of the Journal of Finance for the Year 2014</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singleton, Kenneth J.; Biais, Bruno; Roberts, Michael
nan</description><author>Singleton, Kenneth J.; Biais, Bruno; Roberts, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital and Labor Reallocation within Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giroud, Xavier; Mueller, Holger M.
We document how a positive shock to investment opportunities at one plant (treated plant) spills over to other plants within the same firm, but only if the firm is financially constrained. To provide the treated plant with resources, the firm's headquarters withdraws capital and labor from other plants, especially plants that are relatively less productive, not part of the firm's core industries, and located far away from headquarters. As a result of the resource reallocation, aggregate firm-wide productivity increases. We do not find evidence of capital or labor spillovers among plants of financially unconstrained firms.</description><author>Giroud, Xavier; Mueller, Holger M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Diversity and Complementarities in Trading and Information Acquisition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, Itay; Yang, Liyan
We analyze a model in which different traders are informed of different fundamentals that affect the security value. We identify a source for strategic complementarities in trading and information acquisition: aggressive trading on information about one fundamental reduces uncertainty in trading on information about the other fundamental, encouraging more trading and information acquisition on that fundamental. This tends to amplify the effect of exogenous changes in the underlying information environment. Due to complementarities, greater diversity of information in the economy improves price informativeness. We discuss the relation between our model and recent financial phenomena and derive testable empirical implications.</description><author>Goldstein, Itay; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Comparative-Advantage Approach to Government Debt Maturity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Hanson, Samuel G.; Stein, Jeremy C.
We study optimal government debt maturity in a model where investors derive monetary services from holding riskless short-term securities. In a setting where the government is the only issuer of such riskless paper, it trades off the monetary premium associated with short-term debt against the refinancing risk implied by the need to roll over its debt more often. We extend the model to allow private financial intermediaries to compete with the government in the provision of short-term money-like claims. We argue that, if there are negative externalities associated with private money creation, the government should tilt its issuance more toward short maturities, thereby partially crowding out the private sector's use of short-term debt.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Hanson, Samuel G.; Stein, Jeremy C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Prices Reveal the Presence of Informed Trading?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Fos, Vyacheslav
Using a comprehensive sample of trades from Schedule 13D filings by activist investors, we study how measures of adverse selection respond to informed trading. We find that on days when activists accumulate shares, measures of adverse selection and of stock illiquidity are lower, even though prices are positively impacted. Two channels help explain this phenomenon: (1) activists select times of higher liquidity when they trade, and (2) activists use limit orders. We conclude that, when informed traders can select when and how to trade, standard measures of adverse selection may fail to capture the presence of informed trading.</description><author>Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Fos, Vyacheslav</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Incentives and Communication Costs on Information Production and Use: Evidence from Bank Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Jun; Strahan, Philip E.; Yang, Zhishu
In 2002 and 2003, many Chinese banks implemented reforms that delegated authority to individual loan officers. The change followed China's entrance into the WTO and offers a plausibly exogenous shock to loan officer incentives to produce information. We find that the bank's internal risk rating becomes a stronger predictor of loan interest rates and ex post outcomes after reform. When the loan officer and the branch president who approves the loan work together longer, the rating also becomes more strongly related to loan prices and outcomes. Our results highlight how incentives and communication costs affect information production and use.</description><author>Qian, Jun; Strahan, Philip E.; Yang, Zhishu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Control and the Costs of Illiquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Schroth, Enrique
We develop a search model of block trades that values the illiquidity of controlling stakes. The model considers several dimensions of illiquidity. First, following a liquidity shock, the controlling blockholder is forced to sell, possibly to a less efficient acquirer. Second, this sale may occur at a fire sale price. Third, absent a liquidity shock, a trade occurs only if a potential buyer arrives. Using a structural estimation approach and U.S. data on trades of controlling blocks of public corporations, we estimate the value of control, blockholders' marketability discount, and dispersed shareholders' illiquidity-spillover discount.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Schroth, Enrique</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transparency in the Financial System: Rollover Risk and Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouvard, Matthieu; Chaigneau, Pierre; de Motta, Adolfo
We present a theory of optimal transparency when banks are exposed to rollover risk. Disclosing bank-specific information enhances the stability of the financial system during crises, but has a destabilizing effect in normal economic times. Thus, the regulator optimally increases transparency during crises. Under this policy, however, information disclosure signals a deterioration of economic fundamentals, which gives the regulator ex post incentives to withhold information. This commitment problem precludes a disclosure policy that provides ex ante optimal insurance against aggregate shocks, and can result in excess opacity that increases the likelihood of a systemic crisis.</description><author>Bouvard, Matthieu; Chaigneau, Pierre; de Motta, Adolfo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Brain Gain of Corporate Boards: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Liao, Guanmin; Yu, Xiaoyun
We study the impact of directors with foreign experience on firm performance in emerging markets. Using a unique data set from China, we exploit the introduction of policies to attract talented emigrants and increase the supply of individuals with foreign experience in different provinces at different times. We document that performance increases after firms hire directors with foreign experience and identify the channels through which the emigration of talent may lead to a brain gain. Our findings provide evidence on how directors transmit knowledge about management practices and corporate governance to firms in emerging markets.</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Liao, Guanmin; Yu, Xiaoyun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment Decisions of Nonprofit Firms: Evidence from Hospitals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelino, Manuel; Lewellen, Katharina; Sundaram, Anant
This paper examines investment choices of nonprofit hospitals. It tests how shocks to cash flows caused by the performance of the hospitals' financial assets affect hospital expenditures. Capital expenditures increase, on average, by 10 to 28 cents for every dollar received from financial assets. The sensitivity is similar to that found earlier for shareholder-owned corporations. Executive compensation, other salaries, and perks do not respond significantly to cash flow shocks. Hospitals with an apparent tendency to overspend on medical procedures do not exhibit higher investment-cash flow sensitivities. The sensitivities are higher for hospitals that appear financially constrained.</description><author>Adelino, Manuel; Lewellen, Katharina; Sundaram, Anant</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model of Mortgage Default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John Y.; Cocco, Joao F.
In this paper, we solve a dynamic model of households' mortgage decisions incorporating labor income, house price, inflation, and interest rate risk. Using a zero-profit condition for mortgage lenders, we solve for equilibrium mortgage rates given borrower characteristics and optimal decisions. The model quantifies the effects of adjustable versus fixed mortgage rates, loan-to-value ratios, and mortgage affordability measures on mortgage premia and default. Mortgage selection by heterogeneous borrowers helps explain the higher default rates on adjustable-rate mortgages during the recent U.S. housing downturn, and the variation in mortgage premia with the level of interest rates.</description><author>Campbell, John Y.; Cocco, Joao F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Going Public Affect Innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Shai
This paper investigates the effects of going public on innovation by comparing the innovation activity of firms that go public with firms that withdraw their initial public offering (IPO) filing and remain private. NASDAQ fluctuations during the book-building phase are used as an instrument for IPO completion. Using patent-based metrics, I find that the quality of internal innovation declines following the IPO, and firms experience both an exodus of skilled inventors and a decline in the productivity of the remaining inventors. However, public firms attract new human capital and acquire external innovation. The analysis reveals that going public changes firms' strategies in pursuing innovation.</description><author>Bernstein, Shai</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential Address: Does Finance Benefit Society?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zingales, Luigi
Academics' view of the benefits of finance vastly exceeds societal perception. This dissonance is at least partly explained by an underappreciation by academia of how, without proper rules, finance can easily degenerate into a rent-seeking activity. I outline what finance academics can do, from a research point of view and from an educational point of view, to promote good finance and minimize the bad.</description><author>Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Click or Call? Auction versus Search in the Over-the-Counter Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendershott, Terrence; Madhavan, Ananth
Over-the-counter (OTC) markets dominate trading in many asset classes. Will electronic trading displace traditional OTC voice trading? Can electronic and voice systems coexist? What types of securities and trades are best suited for electronic trading? We study these questions by focusing on an innovation in electronic trading technology that enables investors to simultaneously search many bond dealers. We show that periodic one-sided electronic auctions are a viable and important source of liquidity even in inactively traded instruments. These mechanisms are a natural compromise between bilateral search in OTC markets and continuous double auctions in electronic limit order books.</description><author>Hendershott, Terrence; Madhavan, Ananth</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Stable Are Corporate Capital Structures?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, Harry; Roll, Richard
Leverage cross-sections more than a few years apart differ markedly, with similarities evaporating as the time between them lengthens. Many firms have high and low leverage at different times, but few keep debt-to-assets ratios consistently above 0.500. Capital structure stability is the exception, not the rule, occurs primarily at low leverage, and is virtually always temporary, with many firms abandoning low leverage during the post-war boom. Industry-median leverage varies widely over time. Target-leverage models that place little or no weight on maintaining a particular ratio do a good job replicating the substantial instability of the actual leverage cross-section.</description><author>DeAngelo, Harry; Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taking the Long Way Home: US Tax Evasion and Offshore Investments in US Equity and Debt Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanlon, Michelle; Maydew, Edward L.; Thornock, Jacob R.
We empirically investigate one form of illegal investor-level tax evasion and its effect on foreign portfolio investment. In particular, we examine a form of round-tripping tax evasion in which U.S. individuals hide funds in entities located in offshore tax havens and then invest those funds in U.S. securities markets. Employing Becker's () economic theory of crime, we identify the tax evasion component by examining how foreign portfolio investment varies with changes in the incentives to evade and the risks of detection. To our knowledge, this is the first empirical evidence of investor-level tax evasion affecting cross-border equity and debt investment.</description><author>Hanlon, Michelle; Maydew, Edward L.; Thornock, Jacob R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Term Debt as Bridge Financing: Evidence from the Commercial Paper Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahl, Matthias; Shivdasani, Anil; Wang, Yihui
We analyze why firms use nonintermediated short-term debt by studying the commercial paper (CP) market. Using a comprehensive database of CP issuers and issuance activity, we show that firms use CP to provide start-up financing for capital investment. Firms' CP issuance is driven by a desire to minimize transaction costs associated with raising capital for new investment. We show that firms with high rollover risk are less likely to enter the CP market, borrow less CP, and borrow more from bank credit lines. Further, CP is often refinanced with long-term bond issuance to reduce rollover risk.</description><author>Kahl, Matthias; Shivdasani, Anil; Wang, Yihui</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation Risk in Corporate Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Johnny; Pflueger, Carolin E.
We argue that corporate bond yields reflect fears of debt deflation. When debt is nominal, unexpectedly low inflation increases real liabilities and default risk. In a real business cycle model with optimal but infrequent capital structure choice, more uncertain or procyclical inflation leads to quantitatively important increases in corporate log yields in excess of default-free log yields. A panel of credit spread indexes from six developed countries shows that credit spreads rise by 14 basis points if inflation volatility or the inflation-stock correlation increases by one standard deviation.</description><author>Kang, Johnny; Pflueger, Carolin E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes and Corporate Policies: Evidence from a Quasi Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doidge, Craig; Dyck, Alexander
We document important interactions between tax incentives and corporate policies using a quasi natural experiment provided by a surprise announcement that imposed corporate taxes on a group of Canadian publicly traded firms. The announcement caused a dramatic decrease in value. Prospective tax shields partially offset the losses, adding 4.6% to firm value on average, and vary with the tax status of the marginal investor. Further, firms adjust leverage, payout, cash holdings, and investment in response to changing tax incentives. Overall, the event study and time series evidence supports the view that taxes are important for corporate decision making.</description><author>Doidge, Craig; Dyck, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Crisis of Banks as Liquidity Providers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Mora, Nada
Can banks maintain their advantage as liquidity providers when exposed to a financial crisis? While banks honored credit lines drawn by firms during the 2007 to 2009 crisis, this liquidity provision was only possible because of explicit, large support from the government and government-sponsored agencies. At the onset of the crisis, aggregate deposit inflows into banks weakened and their loan-to-deposit shortfalls widened. These patterns were pronounced at banks with greater undrawn commitments. Such banks sought to attract deposits by offering higher rates, but the resulting private funding was insufficient to cover shortfalls and they reduced new credit.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Mora, Nada</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money Doctors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gennaioli, Nicola; Shleifer, Andrei; Vishny, Robert
We present a new model of investors delegating portfolio management to professionals based on trust. Trust in the manager reduces an investor's perception of the riskiness of a given investment, and allows managers to charge fees. Money managers compete for investor funds by setting fees, but because of trust, fees do not fall to costs. In equilibrium, fees are higher for assets with higher expected return, managers on average underperform the market net of fees, but investors nevertheless prefer to hire managers to investing on their own. When investors hold biased expectations, trust causes managers to pander to investor beliefs.</description><author>Gennaioli, Nicola; Shleifer, Andrei; Vishny, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Acquisitions Relieve Target Firms' Financial Constraints?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erel, Isil; Jang, Yeejin; Weisbach, Michael S.
Managers often claim that target firms are financially constrained prior to being acquired and that these constraints are eased following the acquisition. Using a large sample of European acquisitions, we document that the level of cash that target firms hold, the sensitivity of cash to cash flow, and the sensitivity of investment to cash flow all decline, while investment increases following the acquisition. These effects are stronger in deals that are more likely to be associated with financing improvements. Our findings suggest that acquisitions relieve financial frictions in target firms, especially when the target firm is relatively small.</description><author>Erel, Isil; Jang, Yeejin; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Pre-FOMC Announcement Drift</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucca, David O.; Moench, Emanuel
We document large average excess returns on U.S. equities in anticipation of monetary policy decisions made at scheduled meetings of the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) in the past few decades. These pre-FOMC returns have increased over time and account for sizable fractions of total annual realized stock returns. While other major international equity indices experienced similar pre-FOMC returns, we find no such effect in U.S. Treasury securities and money market futures. Other major U.S. macroeconomic news announcements also do not give rise to preannouncement excess equity returns. We discuss challenges in explaining these returns with standard asset pricing theory.</description><author>Lucca, David O.; Moench, Emanuel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Borrower Misreporting and Loan Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, Mark J.
Borrower misreporting is associated with seriously adverse loan outcomes. Significantly more residential mortgage borrowers reported personal assets just above round number thresholds than just below. Borrowers who reported above-threshold assets were almost 25 percentage points more likely to become delinquent (mean delinquency was 20%). For applicants with unverified assets, the increase in delinquency was greater than 40 percentage points. Misreporting was most frequent in areas with low financial literacy or social capital. Incorporating behavioral cues such as threshold effects into a risk assessment model improves its ability to uncover delinquencies, though at a cost of mischaracterizing some safe loans.</description><author>Garmaise, Mark J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Urban Vibrancy and Corporate Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dougal, Casey; Parsons, Christopher A.; Titman, Sheridan
We find that a firm's investment is highly sensitive to the investments of other firms headquartered nearby, even those in very different industries. A firm's investment also responds to fluctuations in the cash flows and stock prices (q) of local firms outside its sector. These patterns do not appear to reflect exogenous area shocks such as local shocks to labor or real estate values, but rather suggest that local agglomeration economies are important determinants of firm investment and growth.</description><author>Dougal, Casey; Parsons, Christopher A.; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Product Market Impact of Mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sheen, Albert
I document sources of value creation in mergers by analyzing novel data on the quality and price of goods sold by merging firms. When two competitors in a product market merge, their products converge in quality, and prices fall relative to the competition. These effects take two to three years to be fully realized and are stronger in mature industries. Prices do not fall, however, when the acquirer is diversifying into a new product market. This direct evidence of real changes induced by merger activity is consistent with consolidation by related merging firms to achieve operational efficiencies and lower costs.</description><author>Sheen, Albert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cross-Section of Managerial Ability, Incentives, and Risk Preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koijen, Ralph S. J.
I estimate a dynamic investment model for mutual managers to study the cross-sectional distribution of ability, incentives, and risk preferences. The manager's compensation depends on the size of the fund, which fluctuates due to fund returns and due to fund flows that respond to the fund's relative performance. The model provides an economic interpretation of time-varying coefficients in performance regressions in terms of the structural parameters. I document that the estimates of fund alphas are precise and virtually unbiased. I find substantial heterogeneity in ability, risk preferences, and pay-for-performance sensitivities that relates to observable fund characteristics.</description><author>Koijen, Ralph S. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stephen A. Ross</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Refinancing Risk and Cash Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Klasa, Sandy; Maxwell, William F.
We find that firms mitigate refinancing risk by increasing their cash holdings and saving cash from cash flows. The maturity of firms' long-term debt has shortened markedly, and this shortening explains a large fraction of the increase in cash holdings over time. Consistent with the inference that cash reserves are particularly valuable for firms with refinancing risk, we document that the value of these reserves is higher for such firms and that they mitigate underinvestment problems. Our findings imply that refinancing risk is a key determinant of cash holdings and highlight the interdependence of a firm's financial policy decisions.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Klasa, Sandy; Maxwell, William F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Connected Stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anton, Miguel; Polk, Christopher
We connect stocks through their common active mutual fund owners. We show that the degree of shared ownership forecasts cross-sectional variation in return correlation, controlling for exposure to systematic return factors, style and sector similarity, and many other pair characteristics. We argue that shared ownership causes this excess comovement based on evidence from a natural experimentthe 2003 mutual fund trading scandal. These results motivate a novel cross-stock-reversal trading strategy exploiting information contained in ownership connections. We show that long-short hedge fund index returns covary negatively with this strategy, suggesting these funds may exacerbate this excess comovement.</description><author>Anton, Miguel; Polk, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Legal Investor Protection and Takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burkart, Mike; Gromb, Denis; Mueller, Holger M.; Panunzi, Fausto
This paper examines the role of legal investor protection for the efficiency of the market for corporate control when bidders are financially constrained. In the model, stronger legal investor protection increases bidders' outside funding capacity. However, absent effective bidding competition, this does not improve efficiency, as the bid price, and thus bidders' need for funds, increases one-for-one with the pledgeable income. In contrast, under effective competition for the target, the increased outside funding capacity improves efficiency by making it less likely that more efficient but less wealthy bidders are outbid by less efficient but wealthier rivals.</description><author>Burkart, Mike; Gromb, Denis; Mueller, Holger M.; Panunzi, Fausto</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Thirty Years of Shareholder Rights and Firm Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, Martijn; Ferrell, Allen
This paper introduces a new hand-collected data set that tracks restrictions on shareholder rights at approximately 1,000 firms from 1978 to 1989. In conjunction with the 1990 to 2006 IRRC data, we track shareholder rights over 30 years. Most governance changes occurred during the 1980s. We find a robustly negative association between restrictions on shareholder rights (using G-Index as a proxy) and Tobin's Q. The negative association only appears after judicial approval of antitakeover defenses in the 1985 landmark Delaware Supreme Court decision of Moran v. Household. This decision was an unanticipated exogenous shock that increased the importance of shareholder rights.</description><author>Cremers, Martijn; Ferrell, Allen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Market Value of Corporate Votes: Theory and Evidence from Option Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalay, Avner; Karakas, Oguzhan; Pant, Shagun
This paper proposes a new method using option prices to estimate the market value of the shareholder voting rights associated with a stock. The method consists of synthesizing a nonvoting share using put-call parity, and comparing its price to that of the underlying stock. Empirically, we find this measure of the value of voting rights to be positive and increasing in the time to expiration of synthetic stocks. The measure also increases around special shareholder meetings, periods of hedge fund activism, and M&amp;A events. The method is likely useful in studies of corporate control and also has asset pricing implications.</description><author>Kalay, Avner; Karakas, Oguzhan; Pant, Shagun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor Mobility: Implications for Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donangelo, Andres
Labor mobility is the flexibility of workers to walk away from an industry in response to better opportunities. I develop a model in which labor flows make bad times worse for shareholders who are left with capital that is less productive. The model shows that firms face greater operating leverage by providing flexibility to mobile workers. I construct an empirical measure of labor mobility consistent with the model and document an economically significant cross-sectional relation between mobility, operating leverage, and stock returns. I find that firms in mobile industries earn returns over 5% higher than those in less mobile industries.</description><author>Donangelo, Andres</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Ownership, Stock Market Performance, and Managerial Discretion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Von Lilienfeld-Toal, Ulf; Ruenzi, Stefan
We examine the relationship between CEO ownership and stock market performance. A strategy based on public information about managerial ownership delivers annual abnormal returns of 4% to 10%. The effect is strongest among firms with weak external governance, weak product market competition, and large managerial discretion, suggesting that CEO ownership can reverse the negative impact of weak governance. Furthermore, owner-CEOs are value increasing: they reduce empire building and run their firms more efficiently. Overall, our findings indicate that the market does not correctly price the incentive effects of managerial ownership, suggesting interesting feedback effects between corporate finance and asset pricing.</description><author>Von Lilienfeld-Toal, Ulf; Ruenzi, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Premiums in Dynamic Term Structure Models with Unspanned Macro Risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joslin, Scott; Priebsch, Marcel; Singleton, Kenneth J.
This paper quantifies how variation in economic activity and inflation in the United States influences the market prices of level, slope, and curvature risks in Treasury markets. We develop a novel arbitrage-free dynamic term structure model in which bond investment decisions are influenced by output and inflation risks that are unspanned by (imperfectly correlated with) information about the shape of the yield curve. Our model reveals that, between 1985 and 2007, these risks accounted for a large portion of the variation in forward terms premiums, and there was pronounced cyclical variation in the market prices of level and slope risks.</description><author>Joslin, Scott; Priebsch, Marcel; Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Broad-Based Employee Stock Ownership: Motives and Outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, E. Han; Ouimet, Paige
Firms initiating broad-based employee share ownership plans often claim employee stock ownership plans (ESOPs) increase productivity by improving employee incentives. Do they? Small ESOPs comprising less than 5% of shares, granted by firms with moderate employee size, increase the economic pie, benefiting both employees and shareholders. The effects are weaker when there are too many employees to mitigate free-riding. Although some large ESOPs increase productivity and employee compensation, the average impacts are small because they are often implemented for nonincentive purposes such as conserving cash by substituting wages with employee shares or forming a worker-management alliance to thwart takeover bids.</description><author>Kim, E. Han; Ouimet, Paige</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Impact of Improved Access to Finance: Evidence from Mexico</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruhn, Miriam; Love, Inessa
This paper provides new evidence on the impact of access to finance on poverty. It highlights an important channel through which access affects povertythe labor market. The paper exploits the opening of Banco Azteca in Mexico, a unique natural experiment in which over 800 bank branches opened almost simultaneously in preexisting Elektra stores. Importantly, the bank has focused on previously underserved low-income clients. Our key finding is a sizeable effect of access to finance on labor market activity and income levels, especially among low-income individuals and those located in areas with lower preexisting bank penetration.</description><author>Bruhn, Miriam; Love, Inessa</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Business Cycle, Investor Sentiment, and Costly External Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mclean, R. David; Zhao, Mengxin
The recent financial crisis shows that financial markets can impact the real economy. We investigate whether access to finance typically time-varies and, if so, what are the real effects. Consistent with time-varying external finance costs, both investment and employment are less sensitive to Tobin's q and more sensitive to cash flow during recessions and low investor sentiment periods. Share issuance plays a bigger role than debt issuance in causing these effects. Alternative tests that do not rely on q and cash flow sensitivities suggest that recessions and low sentiment increase external finance costs, thereby limiting investment and employment.</description><author>Mclean, R. David; Zhao, Mengxin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Options as Lotteries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyer, Brian H.; Vorkink, Keith
We investigate the relationship between ex ante total skewness and holding returns on individual equity options. Recent theoretical developments predict a negative relationship between total skewness and average returns, in contrast to the traditional view that only coskewness is priced. We find, consistent with recent theory, that total skewness exhibits a strong negative relationship with average option returns. Differences in average returns for option portfolios sorted on ex ante skewness range from 10% to 50% per week, even after controlling for risk. Our findings suggest that these large premiums compensate intermediaries for bearing unhedgeable risk when accommodating investor demand for lottery-like options.</description><author>Boyer, Brian H.; Vorkink, Keith</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Executive Turnover Risk Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peters, Florian S.; Wagner, Alexander F.
We establish that CEOs of companies experiencing volatile industry conditions are more likely to be dismissed. At the same time, accounting for various other factors, industry risk is unlikely to be associated with CEO compensation other than through dismissal risk. Using this identification strategy, we document that CEO turnover risk is significantly positively associated with compensation. This finding is important because job-risk-compensating wage differentials arise naturally in competitive labor markets. By contrast, the evidence rejects an entrenchment model according to which powerful CEOs have lower job risk and at the same time secure higher compensation.</description><author>Peters, Florian S.; Wagner, Alexander F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alpha and Performance Measurement: The Effects of Investor Disagreement and Heterogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, Wayne; Lin, Jerchern
The literature has not established that a positive alpha, as traditionally measured, means that an investor would want to buy a fund. When alpha is defined using the client's utility function, a positive alpha generally means the client would want to buy. When markets are incomplete, investors will disagree about the attractiveness of a fund. We provide bounds on the expected disagreement with a traditional alpha and study the cross-sectional relation of disagreement and investor heterogeneity with the flow response to past fund alphas. The effects are both economically and statistically significant.</description><author>Ferson, Wayne; Lin, Jerchern</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skin in the Game and Moral Hazard</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemla, Gilles; Hennessy, Christopher A.
What determines securitization levels, and should they be regulated? To address these questions we develop a model where originators can exert unobservable effort to increase expected asset quality, subsequently having private information regarding quality when selling ABS to rational investors. Absent regulation, originators may signal positive information via junior retentions or commonly adopt low retentions if funding value and price informativeness are high. Effort incentives are below first-best absent regulation. Optimal regulation promoting originator effort entails a menu of junior retentions or one junior retention with size decreasing in price informativeness. Zero retentions and opacity are optimal among regulations inducing zero effort.</description><author>Chemla, Gilles; Hennessy, Christopher A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Merger Negotiations with Stock Market Feedback</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Betton, Sandra; Eckbo, B. Espen; Thompson, Rex; Thorburn, Karin S.
Do preoffer target stock price runups increase bidder takeover costs? We present model-based tests of this issue assuming runups are caused by signals that inform investors about potential takeover synergies. Rational deal anticipation implies a relation between target runups and markups (offer value minus runup) that is greater than minus one-for-one and inherently nonlinear. If merger negotiations force bidders to raise the offer with the runup-a costly feedback loop where bidders pay twice for anticipated target synergies-markups become strictly increasing in runups. Large-sample tests support rational deal anticipation in runups while rejecting the costly feedback loop.</description><author>Betton, Sandra; Eckbo, B. Espen; Thompson, Rex; Thorburn, Karin S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and Capital Structure in Nonfinancial Firms: An Empirical Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lemmon, Michael; Liu, Laura Xiaolei; Mao, Mike Qinghao; Nini, Greg
Contrary to recent accounts of off-balance-sheet securitization by financial firms, we show that asset securitization by nonfinancial firms provides a valuable form of financing for shareholders without harming debtholders. Using data from firms' SEC filings, we find that securitization is attractive to firms in the middle of the credit quality distribution, which are the firms with the most to gain. Upon initiation, firms experience positive abnormal stock returns and zero abnormal bond returns, and largely use the securitization proceeds to repay existing debt. Securitization minimizes financing costs by reducing expected bankruptcy costs and providing access to segmented credit markets.</description><author>Lemmon, Michael; Liu, Laura Xiaolei; Mao, Mike Qinghao; Nini, Greg</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Editor of the Journal of Finance for the Year 2013</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singleton, Kenneth J.
nan</description><author>Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minutes of the 2014 Annual Membership Meeting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schallheim, Jim
nan</description><author>Schallheim, Jim</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Executive Secretary and Treasurer</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schallheim, Jim
nan</description><author>Schallheim, Jim</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential Address: Investment Noise and Trends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stambaugh, Robert F.
During the past few decades, the fraction of the equity market owned directly by individuals declined significantly. The same period witnessed investment trends that include the growth of indexing as well as shifts by active managers toward lower fees and more index-like investing. I develop an equilibrium model linking these investment trends to the decline in individual ownership, interpreting the latter as a reduction in noise trading. Active management corrects most noise trader-induced mispricing, and the fraction left uncorrected shrinks as noise traders' stake in the market declines. Less mispricing then dictates a smaller footprint for active management.</description><author>Stambaugh, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-Varying Fund Manager Skill</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kacperczyk, Marcin; van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; Veldkamp, Laura
We propose a new definition of skill as general cognitive ability to pick stocks or time the market. We find evidence for stock picking in booms and market timing in recessions. Moreover, the same fund managers that pick stocks well in expansions also time the market well in recessions. These fund managers significantly outperform other funds and passive benchmarks. Our results suggest a new measure of managerial ability that weighs a fund's market timing more in recessions and stock picking more in booms. The measure displays more persistence than either market timing or stock picking alone and predicts fund performance.</description><author>Kacperczyk, Marcin; van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; Veldkamp, Laura</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Readability in Financial Disclosures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loughran, Tim; Mcdonald, Bill
Defining and measuring readability in the context of financial disclosures becomes important with the increasing use of textual analysis and the Securities and Exchange Commission's plain English initiative. We propose defining readability as the effective communication of valuation-relevant information. The Fog Index-the most commonly applied readability measure-is shown to be poorly specified in financial applications. Of Fog's two components, one is misspecified and the other is difficult to measure. We report that 10-K document file size provides a simple readability proxy that outperforms the Fog Index, does not require document parsing, facilitates replication, and is correlated with alternative readability constructs.</description><author>Loughran, Tim; Mcdonald, Bill</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund Performance and the Incentive to Generate Alpha</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Del Guercio, Diane; Reuter, Jonathan
To rationalize the well-known underperformance of the average actively managed mutual fund, we exploit the fact that retail funds in different market segments compete for different types of investors. Within the segment of funds marketed directly to retail investors, we show that flows chase risk-adjusted returns, and that funds respond by investing more in active management. Importantly, within this direct-sold segment, we find no evidence that actively managed funds underperform index funds. In contrast, we show that actively managed funds sold through brokers face a weaker incentive to generate alpha and significantly underperform index funds.</description><author>Del Guercio, Diane; Reuter, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Measurement Problems in Fast, Competitive Markets: Expensive and Cheap Solutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holden, Craig W.; Jacobsen, Stacey
Do fast, competitive markets yield liquidity measurement problems when using the popular Monthly Trade and Quote (MTAQ) database? Yes. MTAQ yields distorted measures of spreads, trade location, and price impact compared with the expensive Daily Trade and Quote (DTAQ) database. These problems are driven by (1) withdrawn quotes, (2) second (versus millisecond) time stamps, and (3) other causes, including canceled quotes. The expensive solution, using DTAQ, is first-best. For financially constrained researchers, the cheap solution-using MTAQ with our new Interpolated Time technique, adjusting for withdrawn quotes, and deleting economically nonsensical states-is second-best. These solutions change research inferences.</description><author>Holden, Craig W.; Jacobsen, Stacey</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Mean-Variance Benchmark for Intertemporal Portfolio Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cochrane, John H.
Mean-variance portfolio theory can apply to streams of payoffs such as dividends following an initial investment. This description is useful when returns are not independent over time and investors have nonmarketed income. Investors hedge their outside income streams. Then, their optimal payoff is split between an indexed perpetuitythe risk-free payoffand a long-run mean-variance efficient payoff. 'Long-run' moments sum over time as well as states of nature. In equilibrium, long-run expected returns vary with long-run market betas and outside-income betas. State-variable hedges do not appear.</description><author>Cochrane, John H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sources of Entropy in Representative Agent Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Backus, David; Chernov, Mikhail; Zin, Stanley
We propose two data-based performance measures for asset pricing models and apply them to models with recursive utility and habits. Excess returns on risky securities are reflected in the pricing kernel's dispersion and riskless bond yields are reflected in its dynamics. We measure dispersion with entropy and dynamics with horizon dependence, the difference between entropy over several periods and one. We compare their magnitudes to estimates derived from asset returns. This exercise reveals tension between a model's ability to generate one-period entropy, which should be large, and horizon dependence, which should be small.</description><author>Backus, David; Chernov, Mikhail; Zin, Stanley</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Asset Allocation in Money Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, Suleyman; Makarov, Dmitry
This paper analyzes the dynamic portfolio choice implications of strategic interaction among money managers who compete for fund flows. We study such interaction between two risk-averse managers in continuous time, characterizing analytically their unique equilibrium investments. Driven by chasing and contrarian mechanisms when one is well ahead, they gamble in the opposite direction when their performance is close. We also examine multiple and mixed-strategy equilibria. Equilibrium policy of each manager crucially depends on the opponent's risk attitude. Hence, client investors concerned about how a strategic manager may trade on their behalf should also learn competitors' characteristics.</description><author>Basak, Suleyman; Makarov, Dmitry</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mergers and Acquisitions Accounting and the Diversification Discount</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Custodio, Claudia
q-based measures of the diversification discount are biased upward by mergers and acquisitions and its accounting implications. Under purchase accounting, acquired assets are reported at their transaction value, which typically exceeds the target's pre-merger book value. Thus, measured q tends to be lower for the merged firm than for the portfolio of pre-merger entities. Because conglomerates are more acquisitive than focused firms, their q tends to be lower. To mitigate this bias, I subtract goodwill from the book value of assets and a substantial part of the diversification discount is eliminated. Market-to-sales-based measures do not have this bias.</description><author>Custodio, Claudia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Writes the News? Corporate Press Releases during Merger Negotiations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahern, Kenneth R.; Sosyura, Denis
Firms have an incentive to manage media coverage to influence their stock prices during important corporate events. Using comprehensive data on media coverage and merger negotiations, we find that bidders in stock mergers originate substantially more news stories after the start of merger negotiations, but before the public announcement. This strategy generates a short-lived run-up in bidders' stock prices during the period when the stock exchange ratio is determined, which substantially impacts the takeover price. Our results demonstrate that the timing and content of financial media coverage may be biased by firms seeking to manipulate their stock price.</description><author>Ahern, Kenneth R.; Sosyura, Denis</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Biased Beliefs, Asset Prices, and Investment: A Structural Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alti, Aydogan; Tetlock, Paul C.
We structurally estimate a model in which agents' information processing biases can cause predictability in firms' asset returns and investment inefficiencies. We generalize the neoclassical investment model by allowing for two biasesoverconfidence and overextrapolation of trendsthat distort agents' expectations of firm productivity. Our model's predictions closely match empirical data on asset pricing and firm behavior. The estimated bias parameters are well identified and exhibit plausible magnitudes. Alternative models without either bias or with efficient investment fail to match observed return predictability and firm behavior. These results suggest that biases affect firm behavior, which in turn affects return anomalies.</description><author>Alti, Aydogan; Tetlock, Paul C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed Trading through the Accounts of Children</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, Henk; Koch, Paul D.; Westerholm, P. Joakim
This study shows that the guardians behind underaged accounts are successful at picking stocks. Moreover, they tend to channel their best trades through the accounts of children, especially when they trade just before major earnings announcements, large price changes, and takeover announcements. Building on these results, we argue that the proportion of total trading activity through underaged accounts (labeled BABYPIN) should serve as an effective proxy for the probability of information trading in a stock. Consistent with this claim, we show that investors demand a higher return for holding stocks with a greater likelihood of private information, proxied by BABYPIN.</description><author>Berkman, Henk; Koch, Paul D.; Westerholm, P. Joakim</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing with Dynamic Margin Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rytchkov, Oleg
This paper provides a novel theoretical analysis of how endogenous time-varying margin requirements affect capital market equilibrium. I find that margin requirements, when there are no other market frictions, reduce the volatility and correlation of returns as well as the risk-free rate, but increase the market price of risk, the risk premium, and the price of risky assets. Furthermore, margin requirements generate a strong cross-sectional dispersion of stock return volatilities. The results emphasize that a general equilibrium analysis may reverse the conclusions of a partial equilibrium analysis often employed in the literature.</description><author>Rytchkov, Oleg</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Anatomy of Commodity Futures Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szymanowska, Marta; De Roon, Frans; Nijman, Theo; Van den Goorbergh, Rob
We identify two types of risk premia in commodity futures returns: spot premia related to the risk in the underlying commodity, and term premia related to changes in the basis. Sorting on forecasting variables such as the futures basis, return momentum, volatility, inflation, hedging pressure, and liquidity results in sizable spot premia between 5% and 14% per annum and term premia between 1% and 3% per annum. We show that a single factor, the high-minus-low portfolio from basis sorts, explains the cross-section of spot premia. Two additional basis factors are needed to explain the term premia.</description><author>Szymanowska, Marta; De Roon, Frans; Nijman, Theo; Van den Goorbergh, Rob</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Threats, Payouts, and Financial Flexibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoberg, Gerard; Phillips, Gordon; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand
We examine how product market threats influence firm payout policy and cash holdings. Using firms' product text descriptions, we develop new measures of competitive threats. Our primary measure, product market fluidity, captures changes in rival firms' products relative to the firm's products. We show that fluidity decreases firm propensity to make payouts via dividends or repurchases and increases the cash held by firms, especially for firms with less access to financial markets. These results are consistent with the hypothesis that firms' financial policies are significantly shaped by product market threats and dynamics.</description><author>Hoberg, Gerard; Phillips, Gordon; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Peer Firms Affect Corporate Financial Policy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leary, Mark T.; Roberts, Michael R.
We show that peer firms play an important role in determining corporate capital structures and financial policies. In large part, firms' financing decisions are responses to the financing decisions and, to a lesser extent, the characteristics of peer firms. These peer effects are more important for capital structure determination than most previously identified determinants. Furthermore, smaller, less successful firms are highly sensitive to their larger, more successful peers, but not vice versa. We also quantify the externalities generated by peer effects, which can amplify the impact of changes in exogenous determinants on leverage by over 70%.</description><author>Leary, Mark T.; Roberts, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Uncertainty Blows in the Orchard: Comovement and Equilibrium Volatility Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, Andrea; Trojani, Fabio; Vedolin, Andrea
We provide novel evidence for an equilibrium link between investors' disagreement, the market price of volatility and correlation, and the differential pricing of index and individual equity options. We show that belief disagreement is positively related to (i) the wedge between index and individual volatility risk premia, (ii) the different slope of the smile of index and individual options, and (iii) the correlation risk premium. Priced disagreement risk also explains returns of option volatility and correlation trading strategies in a way that is robust to the inclusion of other risk factors and different market conditions.</description><author>Buraschi, Andrea; Trojani, Fabio; Vedolin, Andrea</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effects of Government- Owned Banks: Evidence from an Emerging Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carvalho, Daniel
Using plant-level data for Brazilian manufacturing firms, this paper provides evidence that government control over banks leads to significant political influence over the real decisions of firms. I find that firms eligible for government bank lending expand employment in politically attractive regions near elections. These expansions are associated with additional (favorable) borrowing from government banks. Further, these persistent expansions take place just before competitive elections, and are associated with lower future employment growth by firms in other regions. The analysis suggests that politicians in Brazil use bank lending to shift employment towards politically attractive regions and away from unattractive regions.</description><author>Carvalho, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Debt Maturity: The Long and Short of Debt Overhang</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diamond, Douglas W.; He, Zhiguo
Debt maturity influences debt overhang, the reduced incentive for highly levered borrowers to make real investments because some value accrues to debt. Reducing maturity can increase or decrease overhang even when shorter term debt's value depends less on firm value. Future overhang is more volatile for shorter term debt, making future investment incentives volatile and influencing immediate investment incentives. With immediate investment, shorter term debt typically imposes lower overhang; longer term debt can impose less if asset volatility is higher in bad times. For future investments, reduced correlation between assets-in-place and investment opportunities increases the shorter term debt overhang.</description><author>Diamond, Douglas W.; He, Zhiguo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Firms Evade Taxes? The Role of Information Sharing and Financial Sector Outreach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue
Tax evasion is a widespread phenomenon across the globe and even an important factor in the ongoing sovereign debt crisis. We show that firms in countries with better credit information-sharing systems and higher branch penetration evade taxes to a lesser degree. This effect is stronger for smaller firms, firms in smaller cities and towns, firms in industries relying more on external financing, and firms in industries and countries with greater growth potential. This effect is robust to instrumental variable analysis, controlling for firm fixed effects in a smaller panel data set of countries, and many other robustness tests.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Twin Picks: Disentangling the Determinants of Risk- Taking in Household Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calvet, Laurent E.; Sodini, Paolo
This paper investigates risk-taking in the liquid portfolios held by a large panel of Swedish twins. We document that the portfolio share invested in risky assets is an increasing and concave function of financial wealth, leading to different risk sensitivities across investors. Human capital, which we estimate directly from individual labor income, also affects risk-taking positively, while internal habit and expenditure commitments tend to reduce it. Our microfindings lend strong support to decreasing relative risk aversion and habit formation preferences. Furthermore, heterogeneous risk sensitivities across investors help reconcile individual preferences with representative-agent models.</description><author>Calvet, Laurent E.; Sodini, Paolo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Self- Fulfilling Liquidity Dry- Ups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malherbe, Frederic
I analyze a model in which holding cash imposes a negative externality: it worsens future adverse selection in markets for long-term assets, which impairs their role for liquidity provision. Adverse selection worsens when potential sellers of long-term assets hold more cash because then fewer sales reflect cash needs, and proportionally more sales reflect private information. Moreover, future market illiquidity makes current cash holding more appealing. This feedback effect may result in hoarding behavior and a market breakdown, which I interpret as a self-fulfilling liquidity dry-up. This mechanism suggests that imposing liquidity requirements on financial institutions may backfire.</description><author>Malherbe, Frederic</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Incentives and Stock Price Manipulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peng, Lin; Roeell, Ailsa
We present a rational expectations model of optimal executive compensation in a setting where managers are in a position to manipulate short-term stock prices and the manipulation propensity is uncertain. We analyze the tradeoffs involved in conditioning pay on long- versus short-term performance and show how manipulation, and investors' uncertainty about it, affects the equilibrium pay contract and the informativeness of prices. Firm and manager characteristics determine the optimal compensation scheme: the strength of incentives, the pay horizon, and the use of options. We consider how corporate governance and disclosure regulations can help create an environment that enables better contracting.</description><author>Peng, Lin; Roeell, Ailsa</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Importance of Industry Links in Merger Waves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahern, Kenneth R.; Harford, Jarrad
We represent the economy as a network of industries connected through customer and supplier trade flows. Using this network topology, we find that stronger product market connections lead to a greater incidence of cross-industry mergers. Furthermore, mergers propagate in waves across the network through customer-supplier links. Merger activity transmits to close industries quickly and to distant industries with a delay. Finally, economy-wide merger waves are driven by merger activity in industries that are centrally located in the product market network. Overall, we show that the network of real economic transactions helps to explain the formation and propagation of merger waves.</description><author>Ahern, Kenneth R.; Harford, Jarrad</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign Default, Domestic Banks, and Financial Institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gennaioli, Nicola; Martin, Alberto; Rossi, Stefano
We present a model of sovereign debt in which, contrary to conventional wisdom, government defaults are costly because they destroy the balance sheets of domestic banks. In our model, better financial institutions allow banks to be more leveraged, thereby making them more vulnerable to sovereign defaults. Our predictions: government defaults should lead to declines in private credit, and these declines should be larger in countries where financial institutions are more developed and banks hold more government bonds. In these same countries, government defaults should be less likely. Using a large panel of countries, we find evidence consistent with these predictions.</description><author>Gennaioli, Nicola; Martin, Alberto; Rossi, Stefano</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using Neural Data to Test a Theory of Investor Behavior: An Application to Realization Utility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frydman, Cary; Barberis, Nicholas; Camerer, Colin; Bossaerts, Peter; Rangel, Antonio
We conduct a study in which subjects trade stocks in an experimental market while we measure their brain activity using functional magnetic resonance imaging. All of the subjects trade in a suboptimal way. We use the neural data to test a 'realization utility' explanation for their behavior. We find that activity in two areas of the brain that are important for economic decision-making exhibit activity consistent with the predictions of realization utility. These results provide support for the realization utility model. More generally, they demonstrate that neural data can be helpful in testing models of investor behavior.</description><author>Frydman, Cary; Barberis, Nicholas; Camerer, Colin; Bossaerts, Peter; Rangel, Antonio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth Opportunities, Technology Shocks, and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kogan, Leonid; Papanikolaou, Dimitris
We explore the impact of investment-specific technology (IST) shocks on the cross section of stock returns. Using a structural model, we show that IST shocks have a differential effect on the value of assets in place and the value of growth opportunities. This differential sensitivity to IST shocks has two main implications. First, firm risk premia depend on the contribution of growth opportunities to firm value. Second, firms with similar levels of growth opportunities comove with each other, giving rise to the value factor in stock returns and the failure of the conditional CAPM. Our empirical tests confirm the model's predictions.</description><author>Kogan, Leonid; Papanikolaou, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Analysts' Recommendations Informative? Intraday Evidence on the Impact of Time Stamp Delays</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, Daniel; Clarke, Jonathan; Lee, Suzanne; Ornthanalai, Chayawat
We demonstrate that time stamps reported in I/B/E/S for analysts' recommendations released during trading hours are systematically delayed. Using newswire-reported time stamps, we find 30-minute returns of 1.83% (-2.10%) for upgrades (downgrades), but for this subset of recommendations we find corresponding returns of -0.07% (-0.09%) using I/B/E/S-reported time stamps. We also examine the information content of recommendations relative to management guidance and earnings announcements. Our evidence suggests that analysts' recommendations are the most important information disclosure channel examined.</description><author>Bradley, Daniel; Clarke, Jonathan; Lee, Suzanne; Ornthanalai, Chayawat</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sequential Learning, Predictability, and Optimal Portfolio Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johannes, Michael; Korteweg, Arthur; Polson, Nicholas
This paper finds statistically and economically significant out-of-sample portfolio benefits for an investor who uses models of return predictability when forming optimal portfolios. Investors must account for estimation risk, and incorporate an ensemble of important features, including time-varying volatility, and time-varying expected returns driven by payout yield measures that include share repurchase and issuance. Prior research documents a lack of benefits to return predictability, and our results suggest that this is largely due to omitting time-varying volatility and estimation risk. We also document the sequential process of investors learning about parameters, state variables, and models as new data arrive.</description><author>Johannes, Michael; Korteweg, Arthur; Polson, Nicholas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic and Financial Bidders in Takeover Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorbenko, Alexander S.; Malenko, Andrey
Using data on auctions of companies, we estimate valuations (maximum willingness to pay) of strategic and financial bidders from their bids. We find that a typical target is valued higher by strategic bidders. However, 22.4% of targets in our sample are valued higher by financial bidders. These are mature, poorly performing companies. We also find that (i) valuations of different strategic bidders are more dispersed and (ii) valuations of financial bidders are correlated with aggregate economic conditions. Our results suggest that different targets appeal to different types of bidders, rather than that strategic bidders always value targets more because of synergies.</description><author>Gorbenko, Alexander S.; Malenko, Andrey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Global Crisis and Equity Market Contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, Geert; Ehrmann, Michael; Fratzscher, Marcel; Mehl, Arnaud
We analyze the transmission of the 2007 to 2009 financial crisis to 415 country-industry equity portfolios. We use a factor model to predict crisis returns, defining unexplained increases in factor loadings and residual correlations as indicative of contagion. While we find evidence of contagion from the United States and the global financial sector, the effects are small. By contrast, there has been substantial contagion from domestic markets to individual domestic portfolios, with its severity inversely related to the quality of countries' economic fundamentals. This confirms the wake-up call hypothesis, with markets focusing more on country-specific characteristics during the crisis.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Ehrmann, Michael; Fratzscher, Marcel; Mehl, Arnaud</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Pyrrhic Victory? Bank Bailouts and Sovereign Credit Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral; Drechsler, Itamar; Schnabl, Philipp
We model a loop between sovereign and bank credit risk. A distressed financial sector induces government bailouts, whose cost increases sovereign credit risk. Increased sovereign credit risk in turn weakens the financial sector by eroding the value of its government guarantees and bond holdings. Using credit default swap (CDS) rates on European sovereigns and banks, we show that bailouts triggered the rise of sovereign credit risk in 2008. We document that post-bailout changes in sovereign CDS explain changes in bank CDS even after controlling for aggregate and bank-level determinants of credit spreads, confirming the sovereign-bank loop.</description><author>Acharya, Viral; Drechsler, Itamar; Schnabl, Philipp</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment-Based Corporate Bond Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuehn, Lars-Alexander; Schmid, Lukas
A standard assumption of structural models of default is that firms' assets evolve exogenously. In this paper, we examine the importance of accounting for investment options in models of credit risk. In the presence of financing and investment frictions, firm-level variables that proxy for asset composition are significant determinants of credit spreads beyond leverage and asset volatility, because they capture the systematic risk of firms' assets. Cross-sectional studies of credit spreads that fail to control for the interdependence of leverage and investment decisions are unlikely to be very informative. Such frictions also give rise to a realistic term structure of credit spreads in a production economy.</description><author>Kuehn, Lars-Alexander; Schmid, Lukas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives and Endogenous Risk Taking: A Structural View on Hedge Fund Alphas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, Andrea; Kosowski, Robert; Sritrakul, Worrawat
Hedge fund managers are subject to several nonlinear incentives: performance fee options (call); equity investors' redemption options (put); and prime broker contracts allowing for forced deleverage (put). The interaction of these option-like incentives affects optimal leverage ex ante, depending on the distance of fund-value from the high-water mark. We study how these endogenous effects influence performance measures used in the literature. We show that reduced-form measures that do not account for these features are subject to economically significant false discovery biases. The result is stronger for low-quality funds. We propose an alternative structural methodology for conducting performance attribution in hedge funds.</description><author>Buraschi, Andrea; Kosowski, Robert; Sritrakul, Worrawat</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility, the Macroeconomy, and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bansal, Ravi; Kiku, Dana; Shaliastovich, Ivan; Yaron, Amir
How important are volatility fluctuations for asset prices and the macroeconomy? We find that an increase in macroeconomic volatility is associated with an increase in discount rates and a decline in consumption. We develop a framework in which cash flow, discount rate, and volatility risks determine risk premia and show that volatility plays a significant role in explaining the joint dynamics of returns to human capital and equity. Volatility risk carries a sizable positive risk premium and helps account for the cross section of expected returns. Our evidence demonstrates that volatility is important for understanding expected returns and macroeconomic fluctuations.</description><author>Bansal, Ravi; Kiku, Dana; Shaliastovich, Ivan; Yaron, Amir</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>