<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JF2</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Repo Runs: Evidence from the Tri-Party Repo Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Copeland, Adam; Martin, Antoine; Walker, Michael
The repo market has been viewed as a potential source of financial instability since the 2007 to 2009 financial crisis, based in part on findings that margins increased sharply in a segment of this market. This paper provides evidence suggesting that there was no system-wide run on repo. Using confidential data on tri-party repo, a major segment of this market, we show that, the level of margins and the amount of funding were surprisingly stable for most borrowers during the crisis. However, we also document a sharp decline in the tri-party repo funding of Lehman in September 2008.</description><author>Copeland, Adam; Martin, Antoine; Walker, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sizing Up Repo</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnamurthy, Arvind; Nagel, Stefan; Orlov, Dmitry
To understand which short-term debt markets experienced runs during the financial crisis, we analyze a novel data set of repurchase agreements (repo), that is, loans between nonbank cash lenders and dealer banks collateralized with securities. Consistent with a run, repo volume backed by private asset-backed securities falls to near zero in the crisis. However, the reduction is only $182 billion, which is small relative to the stock of private asset-backed securities as well as the contraction in asset-backed commercial paper. While the repo contraction is small in aggregate, it disproportionately affected a few dealer banks.</description><author>Krishnamurthy, Arvind; Nagel, Stefan; Orlov, Dmitry</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cross-Section of Credit Risk Premia and Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friewald, Nils; Wagner, Christian; Zechner, Josef
We explore the link between a firm's stock returns and credit risk using a simple insight from structural models following Merton (): risk premia on equity and credit instruments are related because all claims on assets must earn the same compensation per unit of risk. Consistent with theory, we find that firms' stock returns increase with credit risk premia estimated from CDS spreads. Credit risk premia contain information not captured by physical or risk-neutral default probabilities alone. This sheds new light on the distress puzzlethe lack of a positive relation between equity returns and default probabilitiesreported in previous studies.</description><author>Friewald, Nils; Wagner, Christian; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Intermediaries and the Cross-Section of Asset Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adrian, Tobias; Etula, Erkko; Muir, Tyler
Financial intermediaries trade frequently in many markets using sophisticated models. Their marginal value of wealth should therefore provide a more informative stochastic discount factor (SDF) than that of a representative consumer. Guided by theory, we use shocks to the leverage of securities broker-dealers to construct an intermediary SDF. Intuitively, deteriorating funding conditions are associated with deleveraging and high marginal value of wealth. Our single-factor model prices size, book-to-market, momentum, and bond portfolios with an R-2 of 77% and an average annual pricing error of 1%performing as well as standard multifactor benchmarks designed to price these assets.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Etula, Erkko; Muir, Tyler</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Duration of Executive Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Milbourn, Todd; Song, Fenghua; Thakor, Anjan V.
Extensive discussions on the inefficiencies of short-termism in executive compensation notwithstanding, little is known empirically about the extent of such short-termism. We develop a novel measure of executive pay duration that reflects the vesting periods of different pay components, thereby quantifying the extent to which compensation is short-term. We calculate pay duration in various industries and document its correlation with firm characteristics. Pay duration is longer in firms with more growth opportunities, more long-term assets, greater R&amp;D intensity, lower risk, and better recent stock performance. Longer CEO pay duration is negatively related to the extent of earnings-increasing accruals.</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Milbourn, Todd; Song, Fenghua; Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Innovations and Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bena, Jan; Li, Kai
Using a large and unique patent-merger data set over the period 1984 to 2006, we show that companies with large patent portfolios and low R&amp;D expenses are acquirers, while companies with high R&amp;D expenses and slow growth in patent output are targets. Further, technological overlap between firm pairs has a positive effect on transaction incidence, and this effect is reduced for firm pairs that overlap in product markets. We also show that acquirers with prior technological linkage to their target firms produce more patents afterwards. We conclude that synergies obtained from combining innovation capabilities are important drivers of acquisitions.</description><author>Bena, Jan; Li, Kai</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency Conflicts and Cash: Estimates from a Dynamic Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nikolov, Boris; Whited, Toni M.
Which agency problems affect corporate cash policy? To answer this question, we estimate a dynamic model of finance and investment with three mechanisms that misalign managerial and shareholder incentives: limited managerial ownership of the firm, compensation based on firm size, and managerial perquisite consumption. We find that perquisite consumption critically impacts cash policy. Size-based compensation also matters, but less. Firms with lower blockholder and institutional ownership have higher managerial perquisite consumption, low managerial ownership is a key factor in the secular upward trend in cash holdings, and agency plays little role in small firms' substantial cash holdings.</description><author>Nikolov, Boris; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Have Rating Agencies Become More Conservative? Implications for Capital Structure and Debt Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baghai, Ramin P.; Servaes, Henri; Tamayo, Ane
Rating agencies have become more conservative in assigning corporate credit ratings over the period 1985 to 2009; holding firm characteristics constant, average ratings have dropped by three notches. This change does not appear to be fully warranted because defaults have declined over this period. Firms affected more by conservatism issue less debt, have lower leverage, hold more cash, are less likely to obtain a debt rating, and experience lower growth. Their debt spreads are lower than those of unaffected firms with the same rating, which implies that the market partly undoes the impact of conservatism on debt prices. This evidence suggests that firms and capital markets do not perceive the increase in conservatism to be fully warranted.</description><author>Baghai, Ramin P.; Servaes, Henri; Tamayo, Ane</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rise of the Machines: Algorithmic Trading in the Foreign Exchange Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaboud, Alain P.; Chiquoine, Benjamin; Hjalmarsson, Erik; Vega, Clara
We study the impact of algorithmic trading (AT) in the foreign exchange market using a long time series of high-frequency data that identify computer-generated trading activity. We find that AT causes an improvement in two measures of price efficiency: the frequency of triangular arbitrage opportunities and the autocorrelation of high-frequency returns. We show that the reduction in arbitrage opportunities is associated primarily with computers taking liquidity. This result is consistent with the view that AT improves informational efficiency by speeding up price discovery, but that it may also impose higher adverse selection costs on slower traders. In contrast, the reduction in the autocorrelation of returns owes more to the algorithmic provision of liquidity. We also find evidence consistent with the strategies of algorithmic traders being highly correlated. This correlation, however, does not appear to cause a degradation in market quality, at least not on average.</description><author>Chaboud, Alain P.; Chiquoine, Benjamin; Hjalmarsson, Erik; Vega, Clara</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Stock Liquidity Enhance or Impede Firm Innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Vivian W.; Tian, Xuan; Tice, Sheri
We aim to tackle the longstanding debate on whether stock liquidity enhances or impedes firm innovation. This topic is of interest because innovation is crucial for firm- and national-level competitiveness and stock liquidity can be altered by financial market regulations. Using a difference-in-differences approach that relies on the exogenous variation in liquidity generated by regulatory changes, we find that an increase in liquidity causes a reduction in future innovation. We identify two possible mechanisms through which liquidity impedes innovation: increased exposure to hostile takeovers and higher presence of institutional investors who do not actively gather information or monitor.</description><author>Fang, Vivian W.; Tian, Xuan; Tice, Sheri</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shaping Liquidity: On the Causal Effects of Voluntary Disclosure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balakrishnan, Karthik; Billings, Mary Brooke; Kelly, Bryan; Ljungqvist, Alexander
Can managers influence the liquidity of their firms' shares? We use plausibly exogenous variation in the supply of public information to show that firms actively shape their information environments by voluntarily disclosing more information than regulations mandate and that such efforts improve liquidity. Firms respond to an exogenous loss of public information by providing more timely and informative earnings guidance. Responses appear motivated by a desire to reduce information asymmetries between retail and institutional investors. Liquidity improves as a result and in turn increases firm value. This suggests that managers can causally influence their cost of capital via voluntary disclosure.</description><author>Balakrishnan, Karthik; Billings, Mary Brooke; Kelly, Bryan; Ljungqvist, Alexander</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's Not There: Odd Lots and Market Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Hara, Maureen; Yao, Chen; Ye, Mao
We investigate odd-lot trades in equity markets. Odd lots are increasingly used in algorithmic and high-frequency trading, but are not reported to the consolidated tape or in databases such as TAQ. In our sample, the median number of odd-lot trades is 24% but in some stocks odd lots are 60% or more of trading. Odd-lot trades contribute 35% of price discovery, consistent with informed traders using odd lots to avoid detection. Omitting odd-lot trades leads to inaccuracies in order imbalance measures and makes sentiment measures unreliable. Excluding odd lots from the consolidated tape raises important regulatory issues.</description><author>O'Hara, Maureen; Yao, Chen; Ye, Mao</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Joint Cross Section of Stocks and Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>An, Byeong-Je; Ang, Andrew; Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret
Stocks with large increases in call (put) implied volatilities over the previous month tend to have high (low) future returns. Sorting stocks ranked into decile portfolios by past call implied volatilities produces spreads in average returns of approximately 1% per month, and the return differences persist up to six months. The cross section of stock returns also predicts option implied volatilities, with stocks with high past returns tending to have call and put option contracts that exhibit increases in implied volatility over the next month, but with decreasing realized volatility. These predictability patterns are consistent with rational models of informed trading.</description><author>An, Byeong-Je; Ang, Andrew; Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Equity Performance: What Do We Know?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, Robert S.; Jenkinson, Tim; Kaplan, Steven N.
We study the performance of nearly 1,400 U.S. buyout and venture capital funds using a new data set from Burgiss. We find better buyout fund performance than previously documentedperformance has consistently exceeded that of public markets. Outperformance versus the S&amp;P 500 averages 20% to 27% over a fund's life and more than 3% annually. Venture capital funds outperformed public equities in the 1990s, but underperformed in the 2000s. Our conclusions are robust to various indices and risk controls. Performance in Cambridge Associates and Preqin is qualitatively similar to that in Burgiss, but is lower in Venture Economics.</description><author>Harris, Robert S.; Jenkinson, Tim; Kaplan, Steven N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Media and the Diffusion of Information in Financial Markets: Evidence from Newspaper Strikes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peress, Joel
The media are increasingly recognized as key players in financial markets. I investigate their causal impact on trading and price formation by examining national newspaper strikes in several countries. Trading volume falls 12% on strike days. The dispersion of stock returns and their intraday volatility are reduced by 7%, while aggregate returns are unaffected. Moreover, analysis of return predictability indicates that newspapers propagate news from the previous day. These findings demonstrate that the media contribute to the efficiency of the stock market by improving the dissemination of information among investors and its incorporation into stock prices.</description><author>Peress, Joel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Protectionism? First Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rose, Andrew K.; Wieladek, Tomasz
We examine large public interventions in the financial sector, such as bank nationalizations and search for financial protectionism, a decrease in the quantity and/or an increase in the price of loans that banks from one country make to borrowers resident in another. We use a bank-level panel data set spanning all U.K.-resident banks between 1997Q3 and 2010Q1. After nationalization, foreign banks reduced their fraction of British loans by about 11% and increased their effective interest rates by about 70 basis points. In contrast, nationalized British banks did not significantly change either their loan mix or effective interest rates.</description><author>Rose, Andrew K.; Wieladek, Tomasz</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The TIPS-Treasury Bond Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleckenstein, Matthias; Longstaff, Francis A.; Lustig, Hanno
We show that the price of a Treasury bond and an inflation-swapped Treasury Inflation-Protected Securities (TIPS) issue exactly replicating the cash flows of the Treasury bond can differ by more than $20 per $100 notional. Treasury bonds are almost always overvalued relative to TIPS. Total TIPS-Treasury mispricing has exceeded $56 billion, representing nearly 8% of the total amount of TIPS outstanding. We find direct evidence that the mispricing narrows as additional capital flows into the markets. This provides strong support for the slow-moving-capital explanation of arbitrage persistence.</description><author>Fleckenstein, Matthias; Longstaff, Francis A.; Lustig, Hanno</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Hostile Takeovers Stifle Innovation? Evidence from Antitakeover Legislation and Corporate Patenting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanassov, Julian
I examine how strong corporate governance proxied by the threat of hostile takeovers affects innovation and firm value. I find a significant decline in the number of patents and citations per patent for firms incorporated in states that pass antitakeover laws relative to firms incorporated in states that do not. Most of the impact of antitakeover laws on innovation occurs 2 or more years after they are passed, indicating a causal effect. The negative effect of antitakeover laws is mitigated by the presence of alternative governance mechanisms such as large shareholders, pension fund ownership, leverage, and product market competition.</description><author>Atanassov, Julian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decentralized Investment Management: Evidence from the Pension Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blake, David; Rossi, Alberto G.; Timmermann, Allan; Tonks, Ian; Wermers, Russ
Using a unique data set, we document two secular trends in the shift from centralized to decentralized pension fund management over the past few decades. First, across asset classes, sponsors replace generalist balanced managers with better-performing specialists. Second, within asset classes, funds replace single managers with multiple competing managers following diverse strategies to reduce scale diseconomies as funds grow larger relative to capital markets. Consistent with a model of decentralized management, sponsors implement risk controls that trade off higher anticipated alphas of multiple specialists against the increased difficulty in coordinating their risk-taking and the greater uncertainty concerning their true skills.</description><author>Blake, David; Rossi, Alberto G.; Timmermann, Allan; Tonks, Ian; Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Regulation, Financial Globalization, and the Synchronization of Economic Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalemli-Ozcan, Sebnem; Papaioannou, Elias; Peydro, Jose-Luis
We analyze the impact of financial globalization on business cycle synchronization using a proprietary database on banks' international exposure for industrialized countries during 1978 to 2006. Theory makes ambiguous predictions and identification has been elusive due to lack of bilateral time-varying financial linkages data. In contrast to conventional wisdom and previous empirical studies, we identify a strong negative effect of banking integration on output synchronization, conditional on global shocks and country-pair heterogeneity. Similarly, we show divergent economic activity due to higher integration using an exogenous de-jure measure of integration based on financial regulations that harmonized EU markets.</description><author>Kalemli-Ozcan, Sebnem; Papaioannou, Elias; Peydro, Jose-Luis</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Maturity Rat Race (vol 68, pg 483, 2013)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunnermeier, M. K.; Oehmke, M.
nan</description><author>Brunnermeier, M. K.; Oehmke, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value and Momentum Everywhere</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asness, Clifford S.; Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
We find consistent value and momentum return premia across eight diverse markets and asset classes, and a strong common factor structure among their returns. Value and momentum returns correlate more strongly across asset classes than passive exposures to the asset classes, but value and momentum are negatively correlated with each other, both within and across asset classes. Our results indicate the presence of common global risks that we characterize with a three-factor model. Global funding liquidity risk is a partial source of these patterns, which are identifiable only when examining value and momentum jointly across markets. Our findings present a challenge to existing behavioral, institutional, and rational asset pricing theories that largely focus on U.S. equities.</description><author>Asness, Clifford S.; Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Time-Varying Risk of Rare Disasters Explain Aggregate Stock Market Volatility?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wachter, Jessica A.
Why is the equity premium so high, and why are stocks so volatile? Why are stock returns in excess of government bill rates predictable? This paper proposes an answer to these questions based on a time-varying probability of a consumption disaster. In the model, aggregate consumption follows a normal distribution with low volatility most of the time, but with some probability of a consumption realization far out in the left tail. The possibility of this poor outcome substantially increases the equity premium, while time-variation in the probability of this outcome drives high stock market volatility and excess return predictability.</description><author>Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Wise Are Crowds? Insights from Retail Orders and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelley, Eric K.; Tetlock, Paul C.
We analyze the role of retail investors in stock pricing using a database uniquely suited for this purpose. The data allow us to address selection bias concerns and to separately examine aggressive (market) and passive (limit) orders. Both aggressive and passive net buying positively predict firms' monthly stock returns with no evidence of return reversal. Only aggressive orders correctly predict firm news, including earnings surprises, suggesting they convey novel cash flow information. Only passive net buying follows negative returns, consistent with traders providing liquidity and benefiting from the reversal of transitory price movements. These actions contribute to market efficiency.</description><author>Kelley, Eric K.; Tetlock, Paul C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sentiment during Recessions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia, Diego
This paper studies the effect of sentiment on asset prices during the 20th century (1905 to 2005). As a proxy for sentiment, we use the fraction of positive and negative words in two columns of financial news from the New York Times. The main contribution of the paper is to show that, controlling for other well-known time-series patterns, the predictability of stock returns using news' content is concentrated in recessions. A one standard deviation shock to our news measure during recessions predicts a change in the conditional average return on the DJIA of 12 basis points over one day.</description><author>Garcia, Diego</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State-Level Business Cycles and Local Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok
This study examines whether local stock returns vary with local business cycles in a predictable manner. We find that U.S. state portfolios earn higher future returns when state-level unemployment rates are higher and housing collateral ratios are lower. During the 1978 to 2009 period, geography-based trading strategies earn annualized risk-adjusted returns of 5%. This abnormal performance reflects time-varying systematic risks and local-trading induced mispricing. Consistent with the mispricing explanation, the evidence of predictability is stronger among firms with low visibility and high local ownership. Nonlocal domestic and foreign investors arbitrage away the predictable patterns in local returns in 1 year.</description><author>Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Access to Collateral and Corporate Debt Structure: Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vig, Vikrant
We investigate how firms respond to strengthening of creditor rights by examining their financial decisions following a securitization reform in India. We find that the reform led to a reduction in secured debt, total debt, debt maturity, and asset growth, and an increase in liquidity hoarding by firms. Moreover, the effects are more pronounced for firms that have a higher proportion of tangible assets because these firms are more affected by the secured transactions law. These results suggest that strengthening of creditor rights introduces a liquidation bias and documents how firms alter their debt structures to contract around it.</description><author>Vig, Vikrant</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium Subprime Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Makarov, Igor; Plantin, Guillaume
This paper develops an equilibrium model of a subprime mortgage market. Our goal is to offer a benchmark with which the recent subprime boom and bust can be compared. The model is tractable and delivers plausible orders of magnitude for borrowing capacities, as well as default and trading intensities. We offer simple explanations for several phenomena in the subprime market, such as the prevalence of teaser rates and the clustering of defaults. In our model, both nondiversifiable and diversifiable income risks reduce debt capacities. Thus, debt capacities need not be higher when a larger fraction of income risk is diversifiable.</description><author>Makarov, Igor; Plantin, Guillaume</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Evolution of a Financial Crisis: Collapse of the Asset-Backed Commercial Paper Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Covitz, Daniel; Liang, Nellie; Suarez, Gustavo A.
This paper documents runs on asset-backed commercial paper (ABCP) programs in 2007. We find that one-third of programs experienced a run within weeks of the onset of the ABCP crisis and that runs, as well as yields and maturities for new issues, were related to program-level and macro-financial risks. These findings are consistent with the asymmetric information framework used to explain banking panics, have implications for commercial paper investors' degree of risk intolerance, and inform empirical predictions of recent papers on dynamic coordination failures.</description><author>Covitz, Daniel; Liang, Nellie; Suarez, Gustavo A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reverse Survivorship Bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linnainmaa, Juhani T.
Mutual funds often disappear following poor performance. When this poor performance is partly attributable to negative idiosyncratic shocks, funds' estimated alphas understate their true alphas. This paper estimates a structural model to correct for this bias. Although most funds still have negative alphas, they are not nearly as low as those suggested by the fund-by-fund regressions. Approximately 12% of funds have net four-factor model alphas greater than 2% per year. All studies that run fund-by-fund regressions to draw inferences about the prevalence of skill among mutual fund managers are subject to reverse survivorship bias.</description><author>Linnainmaa, Juhani T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring Managers: Does It Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornelli, Francesca; Kominek, Zbigniew; Ljungqvist, Alexander
We study how well-incentivized boards monitor CEOs and whether monitoring improves performance. Using unique, detailed data on boards' information sets and decisions for a large sample of private equitybacked firms, we find that gathering information helps boards learn about CEO ability. Soft information plays a much larger role than hard data, such as the performance metrics that prior literature focuses on, and helps avoid firing a CEO for bad luck or in response to adverse external shocks. We show that governance reforms increase the effectiveness of board monitoring and establish a causal link between forced CEO turnover and performance improvements.</description><author>Cornelli, Francesca; Kominek, Zbigniew; Ljungqvist, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Effective Were the Federal Reserve Emergency Liquidity Facilities? Evidence from the Asset-Backed Commercial Paper Money Market Mutual Fund Liquidity Facility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duygan-Bump, Burcu; Parkinson, Patrick; Rosengren, Eric; Suarez, Gustavo A.; Willen, Paul
The events following Lehman's failure in 2008 and the current turmoil emanating from Europe highlight the structural vulnerabilities of short-term credit markets and the role of central banks as back-stop liquidity providers. The Federal Reserve's response to financial disruptions in the United States importantly included the creation of liquidity facilities. Using a differences-in-differences approach, we evaluate one of the most unusual of these interventionsthe Asset-Backed Commercial Paper Money Market Mutual Fund Liquidity Facility. We find that this facility helped stabilize asset outflows from money market funds and reduced asset-backed commercial paper yields significantly.</description><author>Duygan-Bump, Burcu; Parkinson, Patrick; Rosengren, Eric; Suarez, Gustavo A.; Willen, Paul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the High-Frequency Dynamics of Hedge Fund Risk Exposures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patton, Andrew J.; Ramadorai, Tarun
We propose a new method to model hedge fund risk exposures using relatively high-frequency conditioning variables. In a large sample of funds, we find substantial evidence that hedge fund risk exposures vary across and within months, and that capturing within-month variation is more important for hedge funds than for mutual funds. We consider different within-month functional forms, and uncover patterns such as day-of-the-month variation in risk exposures. We also find that changes in portfolio allocations, rather than in the risk exposures of the underlying assets, are the main drivers of hedge funds' risk exposure variation.</description><author>Patton, Andrew J.; Ramadorai, Tarun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncovering Hedge Fund Skill from the Portfolio Holdings They Hide</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Jiang, Wei; Tang, Yuehua; Yang, Baozhong
This paper studies the confidential holdings of institutional investors, especially hedge funds, where the quarter-end equity holdings are disclosed with a delay through amendments to Form 13F and are usually excluded from the standard databases. Funds managing large risky portfolios with nonconventional strategies seek confidentiality more frequently. Stocks in these holdings are disproportionately associated with information-sensitive events or share characteristics indicating greater information asymmetry. Confidential holdings exhibit superior performance up to 12 months, and tend to take longer to build. Together the evidence supports private information and the associated price impact as the dominant motives for confidentiality.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Jiang, Wei; Tang, Yuehua; Yang, Baozhong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Noisy Prices and Inference Regarding Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asparouhova, Elena; Bessembinder, Hendrik; Kalcheva, Ivalina
Temporary deviations of trade prices from fundamental values impart bias to estimates of mean returns to individual securities, to differences in mean returns across portfolios, and to parameters estimated in return regressions. We consider a number of corrections, and show them to be effective under reasonable assumptions. In an application to the Center for Research in Security Prices monthly returns, the corrections indicate significant biases in uncorrected return premium estimates associated with an array of firm characteristics. The bias can be large in economic terms, for example, equal to 50% or more of the corrected estimate for firm size and share price.</description><author>Asparouhova, Elena; Bessembinder, Hendrik; Kalcheva, Ivalina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cost of Short-Selling Liquid Securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Snehal; Graveline, Jeremy J.
Standard models of liquidity argue that the higher price for a liquid security reflects the future benefits that long investors expect to receive. We show that short-sellers can also pay a net liquidity premium if their cost to borrow the security is higher than the price premium they collect from selling it. We provide a model-free decomposition of the price premium for liquid securities into the net premiums paid by both long investors and short-sellers. Empirically, we find that short-sellers were responsible for a substantial fraction of the liquidity premium for on-the-run Treasuries from November 1995 through July 2009.</description><author>Banerjee, Snehal; Graveline, Jeremy J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Multiple Lender Approach to Understanding Supply and Search in the Equity Lending Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolasinski, Adam C.; Reed, Adam V.; Ringgenberg, Matthew C.
Using unique data from 12 lenders, we examine how equity lending fees respond to demand shocks. We find that, when demand is moderate, fees are largely insensitive to demand shocks. However, at high demand levels, further increases in demand lead to significantly higher fees and the extent to which demand shocks impact fees is also related to search frictions in the loan market. Moreover, consistent with search models, we find significant dispersion in loan fees, with this dispersion increasing in loan scarcity and search frictions. Our findings imply that search frictions significantly impact short selling costs.</description><author>Kolasinski, Adam C.; Reed, Adam V.; Ringgenberg, Matthew C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Outsourcing Mutual Fund Management: Firm Boundaries, Incentives, and Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Joseph; Hong, Harrison; Jiang, Wenxi; Kubik, Jeffrey D.
We investigate the effects of managerial outsourcing on the performance and incentives of mutual funds. Fund families outsource the management of a large fraction of their funds to advisory firms. These funds underperform those run internally by about 52 basis points per year. After instrumenting for a fund's outsourcing status, the estimated underperformance is three times larger. We hypothesize that contractual externalities due to firm boundaries make it difficult to extract performance from an outsourced relationship. Consistent with this view, outsourced funds face higher powered incentives; they are more likely to be closed after poor performance and excessive risk-taking.</description><author>Chen, Joseph; Hong, Harrison; Jiang, Wenxi; Kubik, Jeffrey D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Maturity Rat Race</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunnermeier, Markus K.; Oehmke, Martin
Why do some firms, especially financial institutions, finance themselves so short-term? We show that extreme reliance on short-term financing may be the outcome of a maturity rat race: a borrower may have an incentive to shorten the maturity of an individual creditor's debt contract because this dilutes other creditors. In response, other creditors opt for shorter maturity contracts as well. This dynamic toward short maturities is present whenever interim information is mostly about the probability of default rather than the recovery in default. For borrowers that cannot commit to a maturity structure, equilibrium financing is inefficiently short-term.</description><author>Brunnermeier, Markus K.; Oehmke, Martin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Divisional Managers and Internal Capital Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duchin, Ran; Sosyura, Denis
Using hand-collected data on divisional managers at S&amp;P 500 firms, we study their role in internal capital budgeting. Divisional managers with social connections to the CEO receive more capital. Connections to the CEO outweigh measures of managers' formal influence, such as seniority and board membership, and affect both managerial appointments and capital allocations. The effect of connections on investment efficiency depends on the tradeoff between agency and information asymmetry. Under weak governance, connections reduce investment efficiency and firm value via favoritism. Under high information asymmetry, connections increase investment efficiency and firm value via information transfer.</description><author>Duchin, Ran; Sosyura, Denis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Cycles and Make/Take Fees in Electronic Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, Thierry; Kadan, Ohad; Kandel, Eugene
We develop a model in which the speed of reaction to trading opportunities is endogenous. Traders face a trade-off between the benefit of being first to seize a profit opportunity and the cost of attention required to be first to seize this opportunity. The model provides an explanation for maker/taker pricing, and has implications for the effects of algorithmic trading on liquidity, volume, and welfare. Liquidity suppliers and liquidity demanders trading intensities reinforce each other, highlighting a new form of liquidity externalities. Data on durations between trades and quotes could be used to identify these externalities.</description><author>Foucault, Thierry; Kadan, Ohad; Kandel, Eugene</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst Forecast Consistency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hilary, Gilles; Hsu, Charles
We show empirically that analysts who display more consistent forecast errors have greater ability to affect prices, and that this effect is larger than that of stated accuracy. These results lead to three implications. First, consistent analysts are less likely to be demoted and are more likely to be nominated All Star analysts. Second, analysts strategically deliver downward-biased forecasts to increase their consistency (if at the expense of stated accuracy). Finally, the benefits of consistency and of lowballing (accuracy) are increasing (decreasing) in institutional investors presence.</description><author>Hilary, Gilles; Hsu, Charles</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Budgeting versus Market Timing: An Evaluation Using Demographics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dellavigna, Stefano; Pollet, Joshua M.
Using demand shifts induced by demographics, we evaluate capital budgeting and market timing. Capital budgeting implies that industries anticipating positive demand shifts in the near future should issue more equity to finance greater capacity. To the extent that demand shifts in the distant future are not incorporated into equity prices, market timing implies that industries anticipating positive shifts in the distant future should issue less equity due to undervaluation. The evidence supports both theories: new listings and equity issuance respond positively to demand shifts during the next 5 years and negatively to demand shifts further in the future.</description><author>Dellavigna, Stefano; Pollet, Joshua M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflicting Family Values in Mutual Fund Families</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Lee, Jung H.; Pool, Veronika K.
We analyze the investment behavior of affiliated funds of mutual funds (AFoMFs), which are mutual funds that can only invest in other funds in the family, and are offered by most large families. Though never mentioned in any prospectus, we discover that AFoMFs provide an insurance pool against temporary liquidity shocks to other funds in the family. We show that, though the family benefits because funds can avoid fire sales, the cost of this insurance is borne by the investors in the AFoMFs. The paper thus uncovers some of the hidden complexities of fiduciary responsibility in mutual fund families.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Lee, Jung H.; Pool, Veronika K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Competition, Valuation, and Merger Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spiegel, Matthew; Tookes, Heather
We model the interactions between product market competition and investment valuation within a dynamic oligopoly. To our knowledge, the model is the first continuous-time corporate finance model in a multiple firm setting with heterogeneous products. The model is tractable and amenable to estimation. We use it to relate current industry characteristics with firm value and financial decisions. Unlike most corporate finance models, it produces predictions regarding parameter magnitudes as well their signs. Estimates of the model's parameters indicate strong linkages between model-implied and actual values. The paper uses the estimated parameters to predict rivals returns near merger announcements.</description><author>Spiegel, Matthew; Tookes, Heather</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry-Specific Human Capital, Idiosyncratic Risk, and the Cross-Section of Expected Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eiling, Esther
Human capital is one of the largest assets in the economy and in theory may play an important role for asset pricing. Human capital is heterogeneous across investors. One source of heterogeneity is industry affiliation. I show that the cross-section of expected stock returns is primarily affected by industry-level rather than aggregate labor income risk. Furthermore, when human capital is excluded from the asset pricing model, the resulting idiosyncratic risk may appear to be priced. I find that the premium for idiosyncratic risk documented by several empirical studies depends on the covariance between stock and human capital returns.</description><author>Eiling, Esther</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Recapitalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Philippon, Thomas; Schnabl, Philipp
We analyze government interventions to recapitalize a banking sector that restricts lending to firms because of debt overhang. We find that the efficient recapitalization program injects capital against preferred stock plus warrants and conditions implementation on sufficient bank participation. Preferred stock plus warrants reduces opportunistic participation by banks that do not require recapitalization, although conditional implementation limits free riding by banks that benefit from lower credit risk because of other banks participation. Efficient recapitalization is profitable if the benefits of lower aggregate credit risk exceed the cost of implicit transfers to bank debt holders.</description><author>Philippon, Thomas; Schnabl, Philipp</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Do Consumers' Fund Flows Maximize? Evidence from Their Brokers' Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Evans, Richard; Musto, David K.
We ask whether mutual funds flows reflect the incentives of the brokers intermediating them. The incentives we address are those revealed in statutory filings: the brokers shares of sales loads and other revenue, and their affiliation with the fund family. We find significant effects of these payments to brokers on funds inflows, particularly when the brokers are not affiliated. Tracking these investments forward, we find load sharing, but not revenue sharing, to predict poor performance, consistent with the different incentives these payments impart. We identify one benefit of captive brokerage, which is the recapture of redemptions elsewhere in the family.</description><author>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Evans, Richard; Musto, David K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Selling Bans Around the World: Evidence from the 2007-09 Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beber, Alessandro; Pagano, Marco
Most regulators around the world reacted to the 200709 crisis by imposing bans on short selling. These were imposed and lifted at different dates in different countries, often targeted different sets of stocks, and featured varying degrees of stringency. We exploit this variation in short-sales regimes to identify their effects on liquidity, price discovery, and stock prices. Using panel and matching techniques, we find that bans (i) were detrimental for liquidity, especially for stocks with small capitalization and no listed options; (ii) slowed price discovery, especially in bear markets, and (iii) failed to support prices, except possibly for U.S. financial stocks.</description><author>Beber, Alessandro; Pagano, Marco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ex Ante Skewness and Expected Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, Jennifer; Dittmar, Robert F.; Ghysels, Eric
We use option prices to estimate ex ante higher moments of the underlying individual securities risk-neutral returns distribution. We find that individual securities risk-neutral volatility, skewness, and kurtosis are strongly related to future returns. Specifically, we find a negative (positive) relation between ex ante volatility (kurtosis) and subsequent returns in the cross-section, and more ex ante negatively (positively) skewed returns yield subsequent higher (lower) returns. We analyze the extent to which these returns relations represent compensation for risk and find evidence that, even after controlling for differences in co-moments, individual securities skewness matters.</description><author>Conrad, Jennifer; Dittmar, Robert F.; Ghysels, Eric</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Untitled</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Schwert, G. William; Singleton, Kenneth J.
nan</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Schwert, G. William; Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Expectations in the Cross-Section of Present Values</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, Bryan; Pruitt, Seth
Returns and cash flow growth for the aggregate U.S. stock market are highly and robustly predictable. Using a single factor extracted from the cross-section of book-to-market ratios, we find an out-of-sample return forecasting R-2 of 13% at the annual frequency (0.9% monthly). We document similar out-of-sample predictability for returns on value, size, momentum, and industry portfolios. We present a model linking aggregate market expectations to disaggregated valuation ratios in a latent factor system. Spreads in value portfolios' exposures to economic shocks are key to identifying predictability and are consistent with duration-based theories of the value premium.</description><author>Kelly, Bryan; Pruitt, Seth</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity in the Foreign Exchange Market: Measurement, Commonality, and Risk Premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mancini, Loriano; Ranaldo, Angelo; Wrampelmeyer, Jan
We provide the first systematic study of liquidity in the foreign exchange market. We find significant variation in liquidity across exchange rates, substantial illiquidity costs, and strong commonality in liquidity across currencies and with equity and bond markets. Analyzing the impact of liquidity risk on carry trades, we show that funding (investment) currencies offer insurance against (exposure to) liquidity risk. A liquidity risk factor has a strong impact on carry trade returns from 2007 to 2009, suggesting that liquidity risk is priced. We present evidence that liquidity spirals may trigger these findings.</description><author>Mancini, Loriano; Ranaldo, Angelo; Wrampelmeyer, Jan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Stock Lending on Security Prices: An Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplan, Steven N.; Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Sensoy, Berk A.
We examine the impact of short selling by conducting a randomized stock lending experiment. Working with a large, anonymous money manager, we create an exogenous and sizeable shock to the supply of lendable shares by taking high loan fee stocks in the manager's portfolio and randomly making available and withholding stocks from the lending market. The experiment ran in two independent phases: the first, from September 5 to 18, 2008, with over $580 million of securities lent, and the second, from June 5 to September 30, 2009, with over $250 million of securities lent. While the supply shocks significantly reduce market lending fees and raise quantities, we find no evidence that returns, volatility, skewness, or bid-ask spreads are affected. The results provide novel evidence on the impact of shorting supply and do not indicate any adverse effects on stock prices from securities lending.</description><author>Kaplan, Steven N.; Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Sensoy, Berk A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading Complex Assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Kogan, Shimon; Lowery, Richard
We perform an experimental study to assess the effect of complexity on asset trading. We find that higher complexity leads to increased price volatility, lower liquidity, and decreased trade efficiency especially when repeated bargaining takes place. However, the channel through which complexity acts is not simply due to the added noise induced by estimation error. Rather, complexity alters the bidding strategies used by traders, making them less inclined to trade, even when we control for estimation error across treatments. As such, it appears that adverse selection plays an important role in explaining the trading abnormalities caused by complexity.</description><author>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Kogan, Shimon; Lowery, Richard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing Model Performance and the Two-Pass Cross-Sectional Regression Methodology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kan, Raymond; Robotti, Cesare; Shanken, Jay
Over the years, many asset pricing studies have employed the sample cross-sectional regression (CSR) R-2 as a measure of model performance. We derive the asymptotic distribution of this statistic and develop associated model comparison tests, taking into account the impact of model misspecification on the variability of the CSR estimates. We encounter several examples of large R-2 differences that are not statistically significant. A version of the intertemporal capital asset pricing model (CAPM) exhibits the best overall performance, followed by the Fama-French three-factor model. Interestingly, the performance of prominent consumption CAPMs is sensitive to variations in experimental design.</description><author>Kan, Raymond; Robotti, Cesare; Shanken, Jay</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Asset Pricing with Recursive Preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colacito, Riccardo; Croce, Mariano M.
Focusing on data from the United States and the United Kingdom, we document that both the anomaly identified by Backus and Smith, which concerns the low correlation between consumption differentials and exchange rates, and the forward premium anomaly, which concerns the tendency of high interest rate currencies to appreciate, have become more severe over time. Taking into account different capital mobility regimes, we show that these anomalies turn into general equilibrium regularities in a two-country and two-good economy with Epstein and Zin preferences, frictionless markets, and correlated long-run growth prospects.</description><author>Colacito, Riccardo; Croce, Mariano M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Noise as Information for Illiquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Grace Xing; Pan, Jun; Wang, Jiang
We propose a market-wide liquidity measure by exploiting the connection between the amount of arbitrage capital in the market and observed noise in U.S. Treasury bondsthe shortage of arbitrage capital allows yields to deviate more freely from the curve, resulting in more noise in prices. Our noise measure captures episodes of liquidity crises of different origins across the financial market, providing information beyond existing liquidity proxies. Moreover, as a priced risk factor, it helps to explain cross-sectional returns on hedge funds and currency carry trades, both known to be sensitive to the general liquidity conditions of the market.</description><author>Hu, Grace Xing; Pan, Jun; Wang, Jiang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fire Sales in a Model of Complexity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caballero, Ricardo J.; Simsek, Alp
We present a model of financial crises that stem from endogenous complexity. We conceptualize complexity as banks' uncertainty about the financial network of cross exposures. As conditions deteriorate, cross exposures generate the possibility of a domino effect of bankruptcies. As this happens, banks face an increasingly complex environment since they need to understand a greater fraction of the financial network to assess their own financial health. Complexity dramatically amplifies banks' perceived counterparty risk, and makes relatively healthy banks reluctant to buy risky assets. The model also features a novel complexity externality.</description><author>Caballero, Ricardo J.; Simsek, Alp</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption Volatility Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boguth, Oliver; Kuehn, Lars-Alexander
We show that time variation in macroeconomic uncertainty affects asset prices. Consumption volatility is a negatively priced source of risk for a wide variety of test portfolios. At the firm level, exposure to consumption volatility risk predicts future returns, generating a spread across quintile portfolios in excess of 7% annually. This premium is explained by cross-sectional differences in the sensitivity of dividend volatility to consumption volatility. Stocks with volatile cash flows in uncertain aggregate times require higher expected returns.</description><author>Boguth, Oliver; Kuehn, Lars-Alexander</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exit as Governance: An Empirical Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Jayaraman, Sudarshan; Nagar, Venky
Recent theory posits a new governance channel available to blockholders: threat of exit. Threat of exit, as opposed to actual exit, is difficult to measure directly. However, a crucial property is that it is weaker when stock liquidity is lower and vice versa. We use natural experiments of financial crises and decimalization as exogenous shocks to stock liquidity. Firms with larger blockholdings experience greater declines (increases) in firm value during the crises (decimalization), particularly if the manager's wealth is sensitive to the stock price and thus to exit threats. Additional tests suggest exit threats are distinct from blockholder intervention.</description><author>Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Jayaraman, Sudarshan; Nagar, Venky</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural Shifts in Credit Rating Standards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alp, Aysun
I examine the time-series variation in corporate credit rating standards from 1985 to 2007. A divergent pattern exists between investment-grade and speculative-grade rating standards from 1985 to 2002 as investment-grade standards tighten and speculative-grade loosen. In 2002, a structural shift occurs toward more stringent ratings. Holding characteristics constant, firms experience a drop of 1.5 notches in ratings due to tightened standards from 2002 to 2007. Credit spread tests suggest that the variation in standards is not completely due to changes in the economic climate. Rating standards affect credit spreads. Loose ratings are associated with higher default rates.</description><author>Alp, Aysun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Borrow Cheap, Buy High? The Determinants of Leverage and Pricing in Buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Axelson, Ulf; Jenkinson, Tim; Stromberg, Per; Weisbach, Michael S.
Private equity funds pay particular attention to capital structure when executing leveraged buyouts, creating an interesting setting for examining capital structure theories. Using a large, international sample of buyouts from 1980 to 2008, we find that buyout leverage is unrelated to the cross-sectional factors, suggested by traditional capital structure theories, that drive public firm leverage. Instead, variation in economy-wide credit conditions is the main determinant of leverage in buyouts. Higher deal leverage is associated with higher transaction prices and lower buyout fund returns, suggesting that acquirers overpay when access to credit is easier.</description><author>Axelson, Ulf; Jenkinson, Tim; Stromberg, Per; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Country Size, Currency Unions, and International Asset Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hassan, Tarek A.
Differences in real interest rates across developed economies are puzzlingly large and persistent. I propose a simple explanation: bonds issued in the currencies of larger economies are expensive because they insure against shocks that affect a larger fraction of the world economy. I show that, indeed, differences in the size of economies explain a large fraction of the cross-sectional variation in currency returns. The data also support additional implications of the model: the introduction of a currency union lowers interest rates in participating countries, and stocks in the nontraded sector of larger economies pay lower expected returns.</description><author>Hassan, Tarek A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Trading with Predictable Returns and Transaction Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garleanu, Nicolae; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
We derive a closed-form optimal dynamic portfolio policy when trading is costly and security returns are predictable by signals with different mean-reversion speeds. The optimal strategy is characterized by two principles: (1) aim in front of the target, and (2) trade partially toward the current aim. Specifically, the optimal updated portfolio is a linear combination of the existing portfolio and an aim portfolio, which is a weighted average of the current Markowitz portfolio (the moving target) and the expected Markowitz portfolios on all future dates (where the target is moving). Intuitively, predictors with slower mean-reversion (alpha decay) get more weight in the aim portfolio. We implement the optimal strategy for commodity futures and find superior net returns relative to more naive benchmarks.</description><author>Garleanu, Nicolae; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Hedge Funds Manipulate Stock Prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-David, Itzhak; Franzoni, Francesco; Landier, Augustin; Moussawi, Rabih
We provide evidence suggesting that some hedge funds manipulate stock prices on critical reporting dates. Stocks in the top quartile of hedge fund holdings exhibit abnormal returns of 0.30% on the last day of the quarter and a reversal of 0.25% on the following day. A significant part of the return is earned during the last minutes of trading. Analysis of intraday volume and order imbalance provides further evidence consistent with manipulation. These patterns are stronger for funds that have higher incentives to improve their ranking relative to their peers.</description><author>Ben-David, Itzhak; Franzoni, Francesco; Landier, Augustin; Moussawi, Rabih</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Diversification and the Cost of Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hann, Rebecca N.; Ogneva, Maria; Ozbas, Oguzhan
We examine whether organizational form matters for a firm's cost of capital. Contrary to the conventional view, we argue that coinsurance among a firm's business units can reduce systematic risk through the avoidance of countercyclical deadweight costs. We find that diversified firms have, on average, a lower cost of capital than comparable portfolios of stand-alone firms. In addition, diversified firms with less correlated segment cash flows have a lower cost of capital, consistent with a coinsurance effect. Holding cash flows constant, our estimates imply an average value gain of approximately 5% when moving from the highest to the lowest cash flow correlation quintile.</description><author>Hann, Rebecca N.; Ogneva, Maria; Ozbas, Oguzhan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Nationalism in Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dinc, I. Serdar; Erel, Isil
This paper studies government reactions to large corporate merger attempts in the European Union during 1997 to 2006 using hand-collected data. We document widespread economic nationalism in which the government prefers that target companies remain domestically owned rather than foreign-owned. This preference is stronger in times and countries with strong far-right parties and weak governments. Nationalist government reactions have both direct and indirect economic impacts on mergers. In particular, these reactions not only affect the outcome of the mergers that they target but also deter foreign companies from bidding for other companies in that country in the future.</description><author>Dinc, I. Serdar; Erel, Isil</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes, Theft, and Firm Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mironov, Maxim
This paper examines the interaction between income diversion and firm performance. Using unique Russian banking transaction data, I identify 42,483 spacemen, fly-by-night firms created specifically for income diversion. Next, I build a direct measure of income diversion for 45,429 companies and show that it is negatively related to firm performance. I identify the main reason for the observed effect as managerial diversion rather than tax evasion per se. I further show that stricter tax enforcement can improve firm performance: a one standard deviation increase in tax enforcement corresponds to an increase in the annual revenue growth rate of 2.6%.</description><author>Mironov, Maxim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Law, Stock Markets, and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, James R.; Martinsson, Gustav; Petersen, Bruce C.
We study a broad sample of firms across 32 countries and find that strong shareholder protections and better access to stock market financing lead to substantially higher long-run rates of R&amp;D investment, particularly in small firms, but are unimportant for fixed capital investment. Credit market development has a modest impact on fixed investment but no impact on R&amp;D. These findings connect law and stock markets with innovative activities key to economic growth, and show that legal rules and financial developments affecting the availability of external equity financing are particularly important for risky, intangible investments not easily financed with debt.</description><author>Brown, James R.; Martinsson, Gustav; Petersen, Bruce C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cheap Credit, Lending Operations, and International Politics: The Case of Global Microfinance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, Mark J.; Natividad, Gabriel
The provision of subsidized credit to financial institutions is an important and frequently used policy tool of governments and central banks. To assess its effectiveness, we exploit changes in international bilateral political relationships that generate shocks to the cost of financing for microfinance institutions (MFIs). MFIs that experience politically driven reductions in total borrowing costs hire more staff and increase administrative expenses. Cheap credit leads to greater profitability for MFIs and promotes a shift toward noncommercial loans but has no effect on total overall lending. Instead, the additional resources are either directed to promoting future growth or dissipated.</description><author>Garmaise, Mark J.; Natividad, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Opening the Black Box: Internal Capital Markets and Managerial Power</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glaser, Markus; Lopez-de-Silanes, Florencio; Sautner, Zacharias
We analyze the internal capital markets of a multinational conglomerate, using a unique panel data set of planned and actual allocations to business units and a survey of unit CEOs. Following cash windfalls, more powerful managers obtain larger allocations and increase investment substantially more than their less connected peers. We identify cash windfalls as a source of misallocation of capital, as more powerful managers overinvest and their units exhibit lower ex post performance and productivity. These findings contribute to our understanding of frictions in resource allocation within firms and point to an important channel through which power may lead to inefficiencies.</description><author>Glaser, Markus; Lopez-de-Silanes, Florencio; Sautner, Zacharias</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence on the Benefits of Alternative Mortgage Products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cocco, Joao F.
Alternative mortgage products have been identified by many as culprits in the financial crisis. However, because of their lower initial mortgage payments relative to loan amount, they may be a valuable tool for households that expect higher and more certain future labor income, and that wish to smooth consumption over the life-cycle. Using U.K. household-level panel data, this paper provides evidence in support of this hypothesis and highlights other important benefits of alternative mortgages, including portfolio diversification, tax benefits, and a reduction in the transaction costs incurred in housing transactions.</description><author>Cocco, Joao F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Editor of The Journal of Finance for the Year 2012</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singleton, Kenneth J.; Biais, Bruno; Roberts, Michael
nan</description><author>Singleton, Kenneth J.; Biais, Bruno; Roberts, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Executive Secretary and Treasurer: for the Year Ending September 30, 2012</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seppi, Duane J.
nan</description><author>Seppi, Duane J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minutes of the 2013 Annual Membership Meeting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seppi, Duane J.
nan</description><author>Seppi, Duane J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Markets and Investment Externalities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Titman, Sheridan
&lt;title content-type="main"&gt;ABSTRACT This address explores the link between financial market shocks, investment choices, and various externalities that can arise from these choices. My analysis, which emphasizes differences between shocks to debt and equity markets, provides insights about some stylized facts from the macro finance literature. These insights are illustrated with a discussion of the technology boom and bust in the late 1990s and early 2000s, and the housing boom and bust in the mid-2000s.</description><author>Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stronger Risk Controls, Lower Risk: Evidence from US Bank Holding Companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellul, Andrew; Yerramilli, Vijay
We construct a risk management index (RMI) to measure the strength and independence of the risk management function at bank holding companies (BHCs). The U.S. BHCs with higher RMI before the onset of the financial crisis have lower tail risk, lower nonperforming loans, and better operating and stock return performance during the financial crisis years. Over the period 1995 to 2010, BHCs with a higher lagged RMI have lower tail risk and higher return on assets, all else equal. Overall, these results suggest that a strong and independent risk management function can curtail tail risk exposures at banks.</description><author>Ellul, Andrew; Yerramilli, Vijay</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model of Shadow Banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gennaioli, Nicola; Shleifer, Andrei; Vishny, Robert W.
We present a model of shadow banking in which banks originate and trade loans, assemble them into diversified portfolios, and finance these portfolios externally with riskless debt. In this model: outside investor wealth drives the demand for riskless debt and indirectly for securitization, bank assets and leverage move together, banks become interconnected through markets, and banks increase their exposure to systematic risk as they reduce idiosyncratic risk through diversification. The shadow banking system is stable and welfare improving under rational expectations, but vulnerable to crises and liquidity dry-ups when investors neglect tail risks.</description><author>Gennaioli, Nicola; Shleifer, Andrei; Vishny, Robert W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effects of Financial Shocks: Evidence from Exogenous Changes in Analyst Coverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Derrien, Francois; Kecskes, Ambrus
We study the causal effects of analyst coverage on corporate investment and financing policies. We hypothesize that a decrease in analyst coverage increases information asymmetry and thus increases the cost of capital; as a result, firms decrease their investment and financing. We use broker closures and broker mergers to identify changes in analyst coverage that are exogenous to corporate policies. Using a difference-in-differences approach, we find that firms that lose an analyst decrease their investment and financing by 1.9% and 2.0% of total assets, respectively, compared to similar firms that do not lose an analyst.</description><author>Derrien, Francois; Kecskes, Ambrus</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Determinants of Attitudes toward Strategic Default on Mortgages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guiso, Luigi; Sapienza, Paola; Zingales, Luigi
We use survey data to measure households' propensity to default on mortgages even if they can afford to pay them (strategic default) when the value of the mortgage exceeds the value of the house. The willingness to default increases in both the absolute and the relative size of the home-equity shortfall. Our evidence suggests that this willingness is affected by both pecuniary and non-pecuniary factors, such as views about fairness and morality. We also find that exposure to other people who strategically defaulted increases the propensity to default strategically because it conveys information about the probability of being sued.</description><author>Guiso, Luigi; Sapienza, Paola; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Stock Return Predictability: What Is the Role of the United States?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rapach, David E.; Strauss, Jack K.; Zhou, Guofu
We investigate lead-lag relationships among monthly country stock returns and identify a leading role for the United States: lagged U.S. returns significantly predict returns in numerous non-U.S. industrialized countries, while lagged non-U.S. returns display limited predictive ability with respect to U.S. returns. We estimate a news-diffusion model, and the results indicate that return shocks arising in the United States are only fully reflected in equity prices outside of the United States with a lag, consistent with a gradual information diffusion explanation of the predictive power of lagged U.S. returns.</description><author>Rapach, David E.; Strauss, Jack K.; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organization Capital and the Cross-Section of Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisfeldt, Andrea L.; Papanikolaou, Dimitris
Organization capital is a production factor that is embodied in the firm's key talent and has an efficiency that is firm specific. Hence, both shareholders and key talent have a claim to its cash flows. We develop a model in which the outside option of the key talent determines the share of firm cash flows that accrue to shareholders. This outside option varies systematically and renders firms with high organization capital riskier from shareholders' perspective. We find that firms with more organization capital have average returns that are 4.6% higher than firms with less organization capital.</description><author>Eisfeldt, Andrea L.; Papanikolaou, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncertainty, Time-Varying Fear, and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drechsler, Itamar
I construct an equilibrium model that captures salient properties of index option prices, equity returns, variance, and the risk-free rate. A representative investor makes consumption and portfolio choice decisions that are robust to his uncertainty about the true economic model. He pays a large premium for index options because they hedge important model misspecification concerns, particularly concerning jump shocks to cash flow growth and volatility. A calibration shows that empirically consistent fundamentals and reasonable model uncertainty explain option prices and the variance premium. Time variation in uncertainty generates variance premium fluctuations, helping explain their power to predict stock returns.</description><author>Drechsler, Itamar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal CEO Compensation with Search: Theory and Empirical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Melanie; Wang, Rong
We integrate an agency problem into search theory to study executive compensation in a market equilibrium. A CEO can choose to stay or quit and search after privately observing an idiosyncratic shock to the firm. The market equilibrium endogenizes CEOs' and firms' outside options and captures contracting externalities. We show that the optimal pay-to-performance ratio is less than one even when the CEO is risk neutral. Moreover, the equilibrium pay-to-performance sensitivity depends positively on a firm's idiosyncratic risk and negatively on the systematic risk. Our empirical tests using executive compensation data confirm these results.</description><author>Cao, Melanie; Wang, Rong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate Risk and the Choice between Cash and Lines of Credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo
Banks can create liquidity for firms by pooling their idiosyncratic risks. As a result, bank lines of credit to firms with greater aggregate risk should be costlier and such firms opt for cash in spite of the incurred liquidity premium. We find empirical support for this novel theoretical insight. Firms with higher beta have a higher ratio of cash to credit lines and face greater costs on their lines. In times of heightened aggregate volatility, banks exposed to undrawn credit lines become riskier; bank credit lines feature fewer initiations, higher spreads, and shorter maturity; and, firms' cash reserves rise.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt Specialization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colla, Paolo; Ippolito, Filippo; Li, Kai
This paper examines debt structure using a new and comprehensive database on types of debt employed by public U.S. firms. We find that 85% of the sample firms borrow predominantly with one type of debt, and the degree of debt specialization varies widely across different subsampleslarge rated firms tend to diversify across multiple debt types, while small unrated firms specialize in fewer types. We suggest several explanations for why debt specialization takes place, and show that firms employing few types of debt have higher bankruptcy costs, are more opaque, and lack access to some segments of the debt markets.</description><author>Colla, Paolo; Ippolito, Filippo; Li, Kai</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Management and Firm Value: Evidence from Weather Derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perez-Gonzalez, Francisco; Yun, Hayong
This paper shows that active risk management policies lead to an increase in firm value. To identify the effect of hedging and to overcome endogeneity concerns, we exploit the introduction of weather derivatives as an exogenous shock to firms' ability to hedge weather risks. This innovation disproportionately benefits weather-sensitive firms, irrespective of their future investment opportunities. Using this natural experiment and data from energy firms, we find that derivatives lead to higher valuations, investments, and leverage. Overall, our results demonstrate that risk management has real consequences on firm outcomes.</description><author>Perez-Gonzalez, Francisco; Yun, Hayong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private and Public Merger Waves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maksimovic, Vojislav; Phillips, Gordon; Yang, Liu
We document that public firms participate more than private firms as buyers and sellers of assets in merger waves and their participation is affected more by credit spreads and aggregate market valuation. Public firm acquisitions realize higher gains in productivity, particularly for on-the-wave acquisitions and when the acquirer's stock is liquid and highly valued. Our results are not driven solely by public firms' better access to capital. Using productivity data from early in the firm's life, we find that better private firms subsequently select to become public. Initial size and productivity predict asset purchases and sales 10 and more years later.</description><author>Maksimovic, Vojislav; Phillips, Gordon; Yang, Liu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rollover Risk and Credit Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo; Xiong, Wei
Our model shows that deterioration in debt market liquidity leads to an increase in not only the liquidity premium of corporate bonds but also credit risk. The latter effect originates from firms debt rollover. When liquidity deterioration causes a firm to suffer losses in rolling over its maturing debt, equity holders bear the losses while maturing debt holders are paid in full. This conflict leads the firm to default at a higher fundamental threshold. Our model demonstrates an intricate interaction between the liquidity premium and default premium and highlights the role of short-term debt in exacerbating rollover risk.</description><author>He, Zhiguo; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Stocks Really Less Volatile in the Long Run?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, Lubos; Stambaugh, Robert F.
According to conventional wisdom, annualized volatility of stock returns is lower over long horizons than over short horizons, due to mean reversion induced by return predictability. In contrast, we find that stocks are substantially more volatile over long horizons from an investors perspective. This perspective recognizes that parameters are uncertain, even with two centuries of data, and that observable predictors imperfectly deliver the conditional expected return. Mean reversion contributes strongly to reducing long-horizon variance but is more than offset by various uncertainties faced by the investor. The same uncertainties reduce desired stock allocations of long-horizon investors contemplating target-date funds.</description><author>Pastor, Lubos; Stambaugh, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Secondary Market for Hedge Funds and the Closed Hedge Fund Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ramadorai, Tarun
Rational theories of the closed-end fund premium puzzle highlight fund share and asset illiquidity, managerial ability, and fees as important determinants of the premium. Several of these attributes are difficult to measure for mutual funds, and easier to measure for hedge funds. This paper employs new data from a secondary market for hedge funds, discovers a closed-hedge fund premium that is highly correlated with the closed-end mutual fund premium, and shows that the closed-hedge fund premium is well explained by variables suggested by rational theories. Sentiment-based explanations do not find support in the data.</description><author>Ramadorai, Tarun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Don't Believe the Hype: Local Media Slant, Local Advertising, and Firm Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gurun, Umit G.; Butler, Alexander W.
When local media report news about local companies, they use fewer negative words compared to the same media reporting about nonlocal companies. We document that one reason for this positive slant is the firms local media advertising expenditures. Abnormal positive local media slant strongly relates to firm equity values. The effect is stronger for small firms; firms held predominantly by individual investors; and firms with illiquid or highly volatile stock, low analyst following, or high dispersion of analyst forecasts. These findings show that news content varies systematically with the characteristics and conflicts of interest of the source.</description><author>Gurun, Umit G.; Butler, Alexander W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selective Publicity and Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Solomon, David H.
I examine how media coverage of good and bad corporate news affects stock prices, by studying the effect of investor relations (IR) firms. I find that IR firms spin their clients news, generating more media coverage of positive press releases than negative press releases. This spin increases announcement returns. Around earnings announcements, however, IR firms cannot spin the news and their clients returns are significantly lower. This pattern is consistent with positive media coverage increasing investor expectations, creating disappointment around hard information. Using reporter connections and geographical links, I argue that IR firms causally affect both media coverage and returns.</description><author>Solomon, David H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual Investor Trading and Return Patterns around Earnings Announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaniel, Ron; Liu, Shuming; Saar, Gideon; Titman, Sheridan
This paper provides evidence of informed trading by individual investors around earnings announcements using a unique data set of NYSE stocks. We show that intense aggregate individual investor buying (selling) predicts large positive (negative) abnormal returns on and after earnings announcement dates. We decompose abnormal returns following the event into information and liquidity provision components, and show that about half of the returns can be attributed to private information. We also find that individuals trade in both return-contrarian and news-contrarian manners after earnings announcements. The latter behavior has the potential to slow the adjustment of prices to earnings news.</description><author>Kaniel, Ron; Liu, Shuming; Saar, Gideon; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Share Issuance and Factor Timing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Hanson, Samuel G.
We show that characteristics of stock issuers can be used to forecast important common factors in stocks' returns such as those associated with book-to-market, size, and industry. Specifically, we use differences between the attributes of stock issuers and repurchasers to forecast characteristic-related factor returns. For example, we show that large firms underperform after years when issuing firms are large relative to repurchasing firms. While our strongest results are for portfolios based on book-to-market (i.e., HML), size (i.e., SMB), and industry, our approach is also useful for forecasting factor returns associated with distress, payout policy, and profitability.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Hanson, Samuel G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Simple Way to Estimate Bid-Ask Spreads from Daily High and Low Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corwin, Shane A.; Schultz, Paul
We develop a bid-ask spread estimator from daily high and low prices. Daily high (low) prices are almost always buy (sell) trades. Hence, the highlow ratio reflects both the stock's variance and its bid-ask spread. Although the variance component of the highlow ratio is proportional to the return interval, the spread component is not. This allows us to derive a spread estimator as a function of highlow ratios over 1-day and 2-day intervals. The estimator is easy to calculate, can be applied in a variety of research areas, and generally outperforms other low-frequency estimators.</description><author>Corwin, Shane A.; Schultz, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Funds and Chapter 11</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Wei; Li, Kai; Wang, Wei
This paper studies the presence of hedge funds in the Chapter 11 process and their effects on bankruptcy outcomes. Hedge funds strategically choose positions in the capital structure where their actions could have a bigger impact on value. Their presence, especially as unsecured creditors, helps balance power between the debtor and secured creditors. Their effect on the debtor manifests in higher probabilities of the latter's loss of exclusive rights to file reorganization plans, CEO turnover, and adoptions of key employee retention plan, while their effect on secured creditors manifests in higher probabilities of emergence and payoffs to junior claims.</description><author>Jiang, Wei; Li, Kai; Wang, Wei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Carry Trades and Global Foreign Exchange Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkhoff, Lukas; Sarno, Lucio; Schmeling, Maik; Schrimpf, Andreas
We investigate the relation between global foreign exchange (FX) volatility risk and the cross section of excess returns arising from popular strategies that borrow in low interest rate currencies and invest in high interest rate currencies, so-called carry trades. We find that high interest rate currencies are negatively related to innovations in global FX volatility, and thus deliver low returns in times of unexpected high volatility, when low interest rate currencies provide a hedge by yielding positive returns. Furthermore, we show that volatility risk dominates liquidity risk and our volatility risk proxy also performs well for pricing returns of other portfolios.</description><author>Menkhoff, Lukas; Sarno, Lucio; Schmeling, Maik; Schrimpf, Andreas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment, Idiosyncratic Risk, and Ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Panousi, Vasia; Papanikolaou, Dimitris
High-powered incentives may induce higher managerial effort, but they also expose managers to idiosyncratic risk. If managers are risk averse, they might underinvest when firm-specific uncertainty increases, leading to suboptimal investment decisions from the perspective of well-diversified shareholders. We empirically document that, when idiosyncratic risk rises, firm investment falls, and more so when managers own a larger fraction of the firm. This negative effect of managerial risk aversion on investment is mitigated if executives are compensated with options rather than with shares or if institutional investors form a large part of the shareholder base.</description><author>Panousi, Vasia; Papanikolaou, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of Cross-Border Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erel, Isil; Liao, Rose C.; Weisbach, Michael S.
The vast majority of cross-border mergers involve private firms outside of the United States. We analyze a sample of 56,978 cross-border mergers between 1990 and 2007. We find that geography, the quality of accounting disclosure, and bilateral trade increase the likelihood of mergers between two countries. Valuation appears to play a role in motivating mergers: firms in countries whose stock market has increased in value, whose currency has recently appreciated, and that have a relatively high market-to-book value tend to be purchasers, while firms from weaker-performing economies tend to be targets.</description><author>Erel, Isil; Liao, Rose C.; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which CEO Characteristics and Abilities Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplan, Steven N.; Klebanov, Mark M.; Sorensen, Morten
We exploit a unique data set to study individual characteristics of CEO candidates for companies involved in buyout and venture capital transactions and relate these characteristics to subsequent corporate performance. CEO candidates vary along two primary dimensions: one that captures general ability and another that contrasts communication and interpersonal skills with execution skills. We find that subsequent performance is positively related to general ability and execution skills. The findings expand our view of CEO characteristics and types relative to previous studies.</description><author>Kaplan, Steven N.; Klebanov, Mark M.; Sorensen, Morten</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effects of Financial Markets: The Impact of Prices on Takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei
Using mutual fund redemptions as an instrument for price changes, we identify a strong effect of market prices on takeover activity (the trigger effect). An interquartile decrease in valuation leads to a seven percentage point increase in acquisition likelihood, relative to a 6% unconditional takeover probability. Instrumentation addresses the fact that prices are endogenous and increase in anticipation of a takeover (the anticipation effect). Our results overturn prior literature that finds a weak relation between prices and takeovers without instrumentation. These findings imply that financial markets have real effects: They impose discipline on managers by triggering takeover threats.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Threshold Events and Identification: A Study of Cash Shortfalls</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakke, Tor-Erik; Whited, Toni M.
Threshold events are discrete events triggered when an observable continuous variable passes a known threshold. We demonstrate how to use threshold events as identification strategies by revisiting the evidence in Rauh (2006, Investment and financing constraints: Evidence from the funding of corporate pension plans, Journal of Finance 61, 3371) that mandatory pension contributions cause investment declines. Rauhs result stems from heavily underfunded firms that constitute a small fraction of the sample and that differ sharply from the rest of the sample. To alleviate this issue, we use observations near funding thresholds and find causal effects of mandatory contributions on receivables, R&amp;D, and hiring, but not on investment. We also provide useful suggestions and diagnostics for analyzing threshold events.</description><author>Bakke, Tor-Erik; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fellow of the American Finance Association for 2012</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shleifer, Andrei
nan</description><author>Shleifer, Andrei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decoding Inside Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren; Malloy, Christopher; Pomorski, Lukasz
Exploiting the fact that insiders trade for a variety of reasons, we show that there is predictable, identifiable routine insider trading that is not informative about firms futures. A portfolio strategy that focuses solely on the remaining opportunistic traders yields value-weighted abnormal returns of 82 basis points per month, while abnormal returns associated with routine traders are essentially zero. The most informed opportunistic traders are local, nonexecutive insiders from geographically concentrated, poorly governed firms. Opportunistic traders are significantly more likely to have SEC enforcement action taken against them, and reduce trading following waves of SEC insider trading enforcement.</description><author>Cohen, Lauren; Malloy, Christopher; Pomorski, Lukasz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Compensation and Board Structure Revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guthrie, Katherine; Sokolowsky, Jan; Wan, Kam-Ming
Chhaochharia and Grinstein estimate that CEO pay decreases 17% more in firms that were not compliant with the recent NYSE/Nasdaq board independence requirement than in firms that were compliant. We document that 74% of this magnitude is attributable to two outliers of 865 sample firms. In addition, we find that the compensation committee independence requirement increases CEO total pay, particularly in the presence of effective shareholder monitoring. Our evidence casts doubt on the effectiveness of independent directors in constraining CEO pay as suggested by the managerial power hypothesis.</description><author>Guthrie, Katherine; Sokolowsky, Jan; Wan, Kam-Ming</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The International Transmission of Bank Liquidity Shocks: Evidence from an Emerging Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schnabl, Philipp
I exploit the 1998 Russian default as a negative liquidity shock to international banks and analyze its transmission to Peru. I find that after the shock international banks reduce bank-to-bank lending to Peruvian banks and Peruvian banks reduce lending to Peruvian firms. The effect is strongest for domestically owned banks that borrow internationally, intermediate for foreign-owned banks, and weakest for locally funded banks. I control for credit demand by examining firms that borrow from several banks. These results suggest that international banks transmit liquidity shocks across countries and that negative liquidity shocks reduce bank lending in affected countries.</description><author>Schnabl, Philipp</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance and Capital Structure Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morellec, Erwan; Nikolov, Boris; Schuerhoff, Norman
We develop a dynamic tradeoff model to examine the importance of managershareholder conflicts in capital structure choice. In the model, firms face taxation, refinancing costs, and liquidation costs. Managers own a fraction of the firms equity, capture part of the free cash flow to equity as private benefits, and have control over financing decisions. Using data on leverage choices and the models predictions for different statistical moments of leverage, we find that agency costs of 1.5% of equity value on average are sufficient to resolve the low-leverage puzzle and to explain the dynamics of leverage ratios. Our estimates also reveal that agency costs vary significantly across firms and correlate with commonly used proxies for corporate governance.</description><author>Morellec, Erwan; Nikolov, Boris; Schuerhoff, Norman</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Case for Intervening in Bankers' Pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thanassoulis, John
This paper studies the default risk of banks generated by investment and remuneration pressures. Competing banks prefer to pay their banking staff in bonuses and not in fixed wages as risk sharing on the remuneration bill is valuable. Competition for bankers generates a negative externality, driving up market levels of banker remuneration and hence rival banks default risk. Optimal financial regulation involves an appropriately structured limit on the proportion of the balance sheet used for bonuses. However, stringent bonus caps are value destroying, default risk enhancing, and suboptimal for regulators who control only a small number of banks.</description><author>Thanassoulis, John</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Investment Banking Relationships: Evidence from the Collapse of Lehman Brothers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernando, Chitru S.; May, Anthony D.; Megginson, William L.
We examine the long-standing question of whether firms derive value from investment bank relationships by studying how the Lehman collapse affected industrial firms that received underwriting, advisory, analyst, and market-making services from Lehman. Equity underwriting clients experienced an abnormal return of around 5%, on average, in the 7 days surrounding Lehman's bankruptcy, amounting to $23 billion in aggregate risk-adjusted losses. Losses were especially severe for companies that had stronger and broader security underwriting relationships with Lehman or were smaller, younger, and more financially constrained. Other client groups were not adversely affected.</description><author>Fernando, Chitru S.; May, Anthony D.; Megginson, William L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tiebreaker: Certification and Multiple Credit Ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bongaerts, Dion; Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Goetzmann, William N.
This paper explores the economic role credit rating agencies play in the corporate bond market. We consider three existing theories about multiple ratings: information production, rating shopping, and regulatory certification. Using differences in rating composition, default prediction, and credit spread changes, our evidence only supports regulatory certification. Marginal, additional credit ratings are more likely to occur because of, and seem to matter primarily for, regulatory purposes. They do not seem to provide significant additional information related to credit quality.</description><author>Bongaerts, Dion; Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Goetzmann, William N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>External Networking and Internal Firm Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fracassi, Cesare; Tate, Geoffrey
We use panel data on S&amp;P 1500 companies to identify external network connections between directors and CEOs. We find that firms with more powerful CEOs are more likely to appoint directors with ties to the CEO. Using changes in board composition due to director death and retirement for identification, we find that CEO-director ties reduce firm value, particularly in the absence of other governance mechanisms to substitute for board oversight. Moreover, firms with more CEO-director ties engage in more value-destroying acquisitions. Overall, our results suggest that network ties with the CEO weaken the intensity of board monitoring.</description><author>Fracassi, Cesare; Tate, Geoffrey</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When It Pays to Pay Your Investment Banker: New Evidence on the Role of Financial Advisors in M&amp;As</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golubov, Andrey; Petmezas, Dimitris; Travlos, Nickolaos G.
We provide new evidence on the role of financial advisors in M&amp;As. Contrary to prior studies, top-tier advisors deliver higher bidder returns than their non-top-tier counterparts but in public acquisitions only, where the advisor reputational exposure and required skills set are relatively larger. This translates into a $65.83 million shareholder gain for an average bidder. The improvement comes from top-tier advisors ability to identify more synergistic combinations and to get a larger share of synergies to accrue to bidders. Consistent with the premium pricepremium quality equilibrium, top-tier advisors charge premium fees in these transactions.</description><author>Golubov, Andrey; Petmezas, Dimitris; Travlos, Nickolaos G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Does the Law Matter? Investor Protection and Its Effects on Investment, Finance, and Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McLean, R. David; Zhang, Tianyu; Zhao, Mengxin
Investor protection is associated with greater investment sensitivity to q and lower investment sensitivity to cash flow. Finance plays a role in causing these effects; in countries with strong investor protection, external finance increases more strongly with q, and declines more strongly with cash flow. We further find that q and cash flow sensitivities are associated with ex post investment efficiency; investment predicts growth and profits more strongly in countries with greater q sensitivities and lower cash flow sensitivities. The paper's findings are broadly consistent with investor protection promoting accurate share prices, reducing financial constraints, and encouraging efficient investment.</description><author>McLean, R. David; Zhang, Tianyu; Zhao, Mengxin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Family-Controlled Firms and Informed Trading: Evidence from Short Sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Ronald C.; Reeb, David M.; Zhao, Wanli
We investigate the relation between organization structure and the information content of short sales, focusing on founder- and heir-controlled firms. Our analysis indicates that family-controlled firms experience substantially higher abnormal short sales prior to negative earnings shocks than nonfamily firms. Supplementary testing indicates that family control characteristics intensify informed short selling. Further analysis suggests that daily short-sale interest in family firms contains useful information in forecasting stock returns; however, we find no discernable effect for nonfamily firms. This analysis provides compelling evidence that informed trading via short sales occurs more readily in family firms than in nonfamily firms.</description><author>Anderson, Ronald C.; Reeb, David M.; Zhao, Wanli</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Power of Voice: Managerial Affective States and Future Firm Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mayew, William J.; Venkatachalam, Mohan
We measure managerial affective states during earnings conference calls by analyzing conference call audio files using vocal emotion analysis software. We hypothesize and find that, when managers are scrutinized by analysts during conference calls, positive and negative affects displayed by managers are informative about the firm's financial future. Analysts do not incorporate this information when forecasting near-term earnings. When making stock recommendation changes, however, analysts incorporate positive but not negative affect. This study presents new evidence that managerial vocal cues contain useful information about a firm's fundamentals, incremental to both quantitative earnings information and qualitative soft information conveyed by linguistic content.</description><author>Mayew, William J.; Venkatachalam, Mohan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Uncertainty and Corporate Investment Cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Julio, Brandon; Yook, Youngsuk
We document cycles in corporate investment corresponding with the timing of national elections around the world. During election years, firms reduce investment expenditures by an average of 4.8% relative to nonelection years, controlling for growth opportunities and economic conditions. The magnitude of the investment cycles varies with different country and election characteristics. We investigate several potential explanations and find evidence supporting the hypothesis that political uncertainty leads firms to reduce investment expenditures until the electoral uncertainty is resolved. These findings suggest that political uncertainty is an important channel through which the political process affects real economic outcomes.</description><author>Julio, Brandon; Yook, Youngsuk</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Credit Ratings Game</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Freixas, Xavier; Shapiro, Joel
The collapse of AAA-rated structured finance products in 2007 to 2008 has brought renewed attention to conflicts of interest in credit rating agencies (CRAs). We model competition among CRAs with three sources of conflicts: (1) CRAs conflict of understating risk to attract business, (2) issuers ability to purchase only the most favorable ratings, and (3) the trusting nature of some investor clienteles. These conflicts create two distortions. First, competition can reduce efficiency, as it facilitates ratings shopping. Second, ratings are more likely to be inflated during booms and when investors are more trusting. We also discuss efficiency-enhancing regulatory interventions.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Freixas, Xavier; Shapiro, Joel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Disclosure and Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hermalin, Benjamin E.; Weisbach, Michael S.
Public policy discussions typically favor greater corporate disclosure as a way to reduce firms agency problems. This argument is incomplete because it overlooks that better disclosure regimes can also aggravate agency problems and related costs, including executive compensation. Consequently, a point can exist beyond which additional disclosure decreases firm value. Holding all else equal, we further show that larger firms will adopt stricter disclosure rules than smaller firms and firms with better disclosure will employ more able management. We show that mandated increases in disclosure could, in part, explain recent increases in both CEO compensation and CEO turnover rates.</description><author>Hermalin, Benjamin E.; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Banks Still Special When There Is a Secondary Market for Loans?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gande, Amar; Saunders, Anthony
Secondary market trading in loans elicits a significant positive stock price response by a borrowing firms equity investors. We find the major reason for this response is the alleviation of borrowing firms financial constraints. We also find that new loan announcements are associated with a positive stock price effect even when prior loans made to the same borrower already trade on the secondary market. We conclude that the special role of banks has changed due to their ability to create an active secondary loan market while simultaneously maintaining their traditional role as information producers.</description><author>Gande, Amar; Saunders, Anthony</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Supply-Side Determinants of Loan Contract Strictness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murfin, Justin
Using a measure of contract strictness based on the probability of a covenant violation, I investigate how lender-specific shocks impact the strictness of the loan contract that a borrower receives. Banks write tighter contracts than their peers after suffering payment defaults to their own loan portfolios, even when defaulting borrowers are in different industries and geographic regions from the current borrower. The effects persist after controlling for bank capitalization, although bank equity compression is also associated with tighter contracts. The evidence suggests that recent defaults inform the lenders perception of its own screening ability, thereby impacting its contracting behavior.</description><author>Murfin, Justin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Flexibility, Bank Capital Flows, and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parlour, Christine A.; Stanton, Richard; Walden, Johan
In our parsimonious general-equilibrium model of banking and asset pricing, intermediaries have the expertise to monitor and reallocate capital. We study financial development, intraeconomy capital flows, the size of the banking sector, the value of intermediation, expected market returns, and the risk of bank crashes. Asset pricing implications include: a markets dividend yield is related to its financial flexibility, and capital flows should be important in explaining expected returns and the risk of bank crashes. Our predictions are broadly consistent with the aggregate behavior of U.S. capital markets since 1950.</description><author>Parlour, Christine A.; Stanton, Richard; Walden, Johan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Expertise as an Arms Race</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glode, Vincent; Green, Richard C.; Lowery, Richard
We show that firms intermediating trade have incentives to overinvest in financial expertise. In our model, expertise improves firms ability to estimate value when trading a security. Expertise creates asymmetric information, which, under normal circumstances, works to the advantage of the expert as it deters opportunistic bargaining by counterparties. This advantage is neutralized in equilibrium, however, by offsetting investments by competitors. Moreover, when volatility rises the adverse selection created by expertise triggers breakdowns in liquidity, destroying gains to trade and thus the benefits that firms hope to gain through high levels of expertise.</description><author>Glode, Vincent; Green, Richard C.; Lowery, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic CEO Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Gabaix, Xavier; Sadzik, Tomasz; Sannikov, Yuliy
We study optimal compensation in a dynamic framework where the CEO consumes in multiple periods, can undo the contract by privately saving, and can temporarily inflate earnings. We obtain a simple closed-form contract that yields clear predictions for how the level and performance sensitivity of pay vary over time and across firms. The contract can be implemented by escrowing the CEOs pay into a Dynamic Incentive Account that comprises cash and the firms equity. The account features state-dependent rebalancing to ensure its equity proportion is always sufficient to induce effort, and time-dependent vesting to deter short-termism.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Gabaix, Xavier; Sadzik, Tomasz; Sannikov, Yuliy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Lintner Model of Payout and Managerial Rents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Myers, Stewart C.
We develop a dynamic agency model in which payout, investment, and financing decisions are made by managers who attempt to maximize the rents they take from the firm, subject to a capital market constraint. Managers smooth payout to smooth their flow of rents. Total payout (dividends plus net repurchases) follows Lintners (1956) target adjustment model. Payout smooths out transitory shocks to current income and adjusts gradually to changes in permanent income. Smoothing is accomplished by borrowing or lending. Payout is not cut back to finance capital investment. Risk aversion causes managers to underinvest, but habit formation mitigates the degree of underinvestment.</description><author>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Myers, Stewart C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking Globalization and Monetary Transmission</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cetorelli, Nicola; Goldberg, Linda S.
Globalization of banking raises questions about banks liquidity management, their response to liquidity shocks, and the potential for international shock propagation. We conjecture that global banks manage liquidity on a global scale, actively using cross-border internal funding in response to local shocks. Having global operations insulates banks from changes in monetary policy, while banks without global operations are more affected by monetary policy than previously found. We provide direct evidence that internal capital markets are active in global banks and contribute to the international propagation of shocks. This feature was at play during the financial crisis of 20072009.</description><author>Cetorelli, Nicola; Goldberg, Linda S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory Arbitrage and International Bank Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Houston, Joel F.; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue
We study whether cross-country differences in regulations have affected international bank flows. We find strong evidence that banks have transferred funds to markets with fewer regulations. This form of regulatory arbitrage suggests there may be a destructive race to the bottom in global regulations, which restricts domestic regulators ability to limit bank risk-taking. However, we also find that the links between regulation differences and bank flows are significantly stronger if the recipient country is a developed country with strong property rights and creditor rights. This suggests that, while differences in regulations have important influences, without a strong institutional environment, lax regulations are not enough to encourage massive capital flows.</description><author>Houston, Joel F.; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incomplete-Market Equilibria Solved Recursively on an Event Tree</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dumas, Bernard; Lyasoff, Andrew
Because of non-traded human capital, real-world financial markets are massively incomplete, while the modeling of imperfect, dynamic financial markets remains a wide-open and difficult field. Some 30 years after Cox, Ross, and Rubinstein (1979) taught us how to calculate the prices of derivative securities on an event tree by simple backward induction, we show how a similar formulation can be used in computing heterogeneous-agents incomplete-market equilibrium prices of primitive securities. Extant methods work forward and backward, requiring a guess of the way investors forecast the future. In our method, the future is part of the current solution of each backward time step.</description><author>Dumas, Bernard; Lyasoff, Andrew</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Vote Is Cast: The Effect of Corporate Governance on Shareholder Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cunat, Vicente; Gine, Mireia; Guadalupe, Maria
This paper investigates whether improvements in the firms internal corporate governance create value for shareholders. We analyze the market reaction to governance proposals that pass or fail by a small margin of votes in annual meetings. This provides a clean causal estimate that deals with the endogeneity of internal governance rules. We find that passing a proposal leads to significant positive abnormal returns. Adopting one governance proposal increases shareholder value by 2.8%. The market reaction is larger in firms with more antitakeover provisions, higher institutional ownership, and stronger investor activism for proposals sponsored by institutions. In addition, we find that acquisitions and capital expenditures decline and long-term performance improves.</description><author>Cunat, Vicente; Gine, Mireia; Guadalupe, Maria</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Fire Sales and Purchases and the International Transmission of Funding Shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jotikasthira, Chotibhak; Lundblad, Christian; Ramadorai, Tarun
We identify a new channel for the transmission of shocks across international markets. Investor flows to funds domiciled in developed markets force significant changes in these funds emerging market portfolio allocations. These forced trades or fire sales affect emerging market equity prices, correlations, and betas, and are related to but distinct from effects arising purely from fund holdings or from overlapping ownership of emerging markets in fund portfolios. A simple model and calibration exercise highlight the importance to these findings of push effects from funds domicile countries and co-ownership spillover between markets with overlapping fund ownership.</description><author>Jotikasthira, Chotibhak; Lundblad, Christian; Ramadorai, Tarun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are All Ratings Created Equal? The Impact of Issuer Size on the Pricing of Mortgage-Backed Securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Jie; Qian, Jun; Strahan, Philip E.
Initial yields on both AAA-rated and non-AAA rated mortgage-backed security (MBS) tranches sold by large issuers are higher than yields on similar tranches sold by small issuers during the market boom years of 2004 to 2006. Moreover, the prices of MBS sold by large issuers drop more than those sold by small issuers, and the differences are concentrated among tranches issued during 2004 to 2006. These results suggest that investors price the risk that large issuers received more inflated ratings than small issuers, especially during boom periods.</description><author>He, Jie; Qian, Jun; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Reputation Limit Opportunistic Behavior in the VC Industry? Evidence from Litigation against VCs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanasov, Vladimir; Ivanov, Vladimir; Litvak, Kate
We examine the role of reputation in limiting opportunistic behavior by venture capitalists towards four types of counterparties: entrepreneurs, investors, other VCs, and buyers of VC-backed startups. Using a hand-collected database of lawsuits, we document that more reputable VCs (i.e., VCs that are older, have more deals and funds under management, and syndicate with larger networks of VCs) are less likely to be litigated. We also find that litigated VCs suffer declines in future business relative to matched peers. These declines are larger for more reputable VCs, and for VCs that are defendants to multiple lawsuits or sued by entrepreneurs.</description><author>Atanasov, Vladimir; Ivanov, Vladimir; Litvak, Kate</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Agency and the q Theory of Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMarzo, Peter M.; Fishman, Michael J.; He, Zhiguo; Wang, Neng
We develop an analytically tractable model integrating dynamic investment theory with dynamic optimal incentive contracting, thereby endogenizing financing constraints. Incentive contracting generates a history-dependent wedge between marginal and average q, and both vary over time as good (bad) performance relaxes (tightens) financing constraints. Financial slack, not cash flow, is the appropriate proxy for financing constraints. Investment decreases with idiosyncratic risk, and is positively correlated with past profits, past investment, and managerial compensation even with time-invariant investment opportunities. Optimal contracting involves deferred compensation, possible termination, and compensation that depends on exogenous observable persistent profitability shocks, effectively paying managers for luck.</description><author>DeMarzo, Peter M.; Fishman, Michael J.; He, Zhiguo; Wang, Neng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Equity Performance and Liquidity Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franzoni, Francesco; Nowak, Eric; Phalippou, Ludovic
Private equity has traditionally been thought to provide diversification benefits. However, these benefits may be lower than anticipated as we find that private equity suffers from significant exposure to the same liquidity risk factor as public equity and other alternative asset classes. The unconditional liquidity risk premium is about 3% annually and, in a four-factor model, the inclusion of this liquidity risk premium reduces alpha to zero. In addition, we provide evidence that the link between private equity returns and overall market liquidity occurs via a funding liquidity channel.</description><author>Franzoni, Francesco; Nowak, Eric; Phalippou, Ludovic</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Relative Pricing of Long-Maturity Index Options and Collateralized Debt Obligations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.; Yang, Fan
We investigate a structural model of market and firm-level dynamics in order to jointly price long-dated S&amp;P 500 index options and CDO tranches of corporate debt. We identify market dynamics from index option prices and idiosyncratic dynamics from the term structure of credit spreads. We find that all tranches can be well priced out-of-sample before the crisis. During the crisis, however, our model can capture senior tranche prices only if we allow for the possibility of a catastrophic jump. Thus, senior tranches are nonredundant assets that provide a unique window into the pricing of catastrophic risk.</description><author>Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.; Yang, Fan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Default and Equity Risk Across Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Favara, Giovanni; Schroth, Enrique; Valta, Philip
We show that the prospect of a debt renegotiation favorable to shareholders reduces the firms equity risk. Equity beta and return volatility are lower in countries where the bankruptcy code favors debt renegotiations and for firms with more shareholder bargaining power relative to debt holders. These relations weaken as the countrys insolvency procedure favors liquidations over renegotiations. In the limit, when debt contracts cannot be renegotiated, equity risk is independent of shareholders incentives to default strategically. We argue that these findings support the hypothesis that the threat of strategic default can reduce the firms equity risk.</description><author>Favara, Giovanni; Schroth, Enrique; Valta, Philip</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>This Time Is the Same: Using Bank Performance in 1998 to Explain Bank Performance during the Recent Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Prilmeier, Robert; Stulz, Rene M.
Are some banks prone to perform poorly during crises? If yes, why? In this paper, we show that a bank's stock return performance during the 1998 crisis predicts its stock return performance and probability of failure during the recent financial crisis. This effect is economically large. Our findings are consistent with persistence in a bank's risk culture and/or aspects of its business model that make its performance sensitive to crises. Banks that relied more on short-term funding, had more leverage, and grew more are more likely to be banks that performed poorly in both crises.</description><author>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Prilmeier, Robert; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency Problems in Public Firms: Evidence from Corporate Jets in Leveraged Buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edgerton, Jesse
This paper uses novel data to examine the fleets of corporate jets operated by both publicly traded and privately held firms. In the cross-section, firms owned by private equity funds average 40% smaller fleets than observably similar public firms. Similar fleet reductions are observed within firms that undergo leveraged buyouts. Quantile regressions indicate that these results are driven by firms in the upper 30% of the conditional jet distribution. The results thus suggest that executives in a substantial minority of public firms enjoy excessive perquisite and compensation packages.</description><author>Edgerton, Jesse</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Life Cycle Dynamics of Venture-Capital- and Non-Venture-Capital-Financed Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Puri, Manju; Zarutskie, Rebecca
We use data over 25 years to understand the life cycle dynamics of VC- and non-VC-financed firms. We find successful and failed VC-financed firms achieve larger scale but are not more profitable at exit than matched non-VC-financed firms. Cumulative failure rates of VC-financed firms are lower, with the difference driven largely by lower failure rates in the initial years after receiving VC. Our results are not driven by VCs disguising failures as acquisitions or by certain types of VCs. The performance difference between VC- and non-VC-financed firms narrows in the post-internet bubble years, but does not disappear.</description><author>Puri, Manju; Zarutskie, Rebecca</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential Address: The Corporation in Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajan, Raghuram G.
To produce significant net present value, an entrepreneur has to differentiate her enterprise from the ordinary. To take collaborators with her, she needs to have substantial ownership, and thus financing. But it is hard to raise finance against differentiated assets. So an entrepreneur has to commit to undertake a second transformation, standardization, that will make the human capital in the firm, including her own, replaceable, so that outside financiers obtain control rights that will allow them to be repaid. A vibrant stock market helps the entrepreneur commit to these two transformations. The nature of firms and financing are intimately linked.</description><author>Rajan, Raghuram G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technological Growth and Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garleanu, Nicolae; Panageas, Stavros; Yu, Jianfeng
We study the asset-pricing implications of technological growth in a model with small, disembodied productivity shocks and large, infrequent technological innovations, which are embodied into new capital vintages. The technological-adoption process leads to endogenous cycles in output and asset valuations. This process can help explain stylized asset-valuation patterns around major technological innovations. More importantly, it can help provide a unified, investment-based theory for numerous well-documented facts related to excess-return predictability. To illustrate the distinguishing features of our theory, we highlight novel implications pertaining to the joint time-series properties of consumption and excess returns.</description><author>Garleanu, Nicolae; Panageas, Stavros; Yu, Jianfeng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund Trading Pressure: Firm-Level Stock Price Impact and Timing of SEOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khan, Mozaffar; Kogan, Leonid; Serafeim, George
We use price pressure resulting from purchases by mutual funds with large capital inflows to identify overvalued equity. This is a relatively exogenous overvaluation indicator as it is associated with who is buyingbuyers with excess liquidityrather than what is being purchased. We document substantial stock price impact associated with purchases by high-inflow mutual funds, and find the probability of a seasoned equity offering (SEO), insider sales, and the probability of a stock-based acquisition increase significantly in the four quarters following the mutual fund buying pressure. These results provide new evidence that firm managers are able to identify and exploit overvalued equity.</description><author>Khan, Mozaffar; Kogan, Leonid; Serafeim, George</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund Tax Clienteles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sialm, Clemens; Starks, Laura
Mutual funds are held by investors in taxable and tax-qualified retirement accounts. We investigate whether the characteristics, investment strategies, and performance of mutual funds held by these diverse tax clienteles differ. Examining both mutual fund distributions and mutual fund holdings, we find that funds held primarily by taxable investors choose investment strategies that result in lower tax burdens than funds held primarily in tax-qualified accounts. Despite these differences, we find no evidence that any investment constraints that may arise from these tax-efficient investment strategies result in performance differences between funds held by different tax clienteles.</description><author>Sialm, Clemens; Starks, Laura</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Options, Volatility, and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grullon, Gustavo; Lyandres, Evgeny; Zhdanov, Alexei
We provide evidence that the positive relation between firm-level stock returns and firm-level return volatility is due to firms real options. Consistent with real option theory, we find that the positive volatility-return relation is much stronger for firms with more real options and that the sensitivity of firm value to changes in volatility declines significantly after firms exercise their real options. We reconcile the evidence at the aggregate and firm levels by showing that the negative relation at the aggregate level may be due to aggregate market conditions that simultaneously affect both market returns and return volatility.</description><author>Grullon, Gustavo; Lyandres, Evgeny; Zhdanov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the Editor of the Journal of Finance for the Year 2011</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harvey, Campbell R.
nan</description><author>Harvey, Campbell R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Untitled</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singleton, Kenneth J.
nan</description><author>Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncertainty about Government Policy and Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, Lubos; Veronesi, Pietro
We analyze how changes in government policy affect stock prices. Our general equilibrium model features uncertainty about government policy and a government whose decisions have both economic and noneconomic motives. The model makes numerous empirical predictions. Stock prices should fall at the announcement of a policy change, on average. The price decline should be large if uncertainty about government policy is large, and also if the policy change is preceded by a short or shallow economic downturn. Policy changes should increase volatilities and correlations among stocks. The jump risk premium associated with policy decisions should be positive, on average.</description><author>Pastor, Lubos; Veronesi, Pietro</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did Subjectivity Play a Role in CDO Credit Ratings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Tang, Dragon Yongjun
Analyzing 916 collateralized debt obligations (CDOs), we find that a top credit rating agency frequently made positive adjustments beyond its main model that amounted to increasingly larger AAA tranche sizes. These adjustments are difficult to explain by likely determinants, but exhibit a clear pattern: CDOs with smaller model-implied AAA sizes receive larger adjustments. CDOs with larger adjustments experience more severe subsequent downgrading. Additionally, prior to April 2007, 91.2% of AAA-rated CDOs only comply with the credit rating agency's own AA default rate standard. Accounting for adjustments and the criterion deviation indicates that on average AAA tranches were structured to BBB support levels.</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Tang, Dragon Yongjun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Are U.S. Stocks More Volatile?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Brown, Gregory; Stulz, Rene M.
U.S. stocks are more volatile than stocks of similar foreign firms. A firm's stock return volatility can be higher for reasons that contribute positively (good volatility) or negatively (bad volatility) to shareholder wealth and economic growth. We find that the volatility of U.S. firms is higher mostly because of good volatility. Specifically, stock volatility is higher in the United States because it increases with investor protection, stock market development, new patents, and firm-level investment in R&amp;D. Each of these factors is related to better growth opportunities for firms and better ability to take advantage of these opportunities.</description><author>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Brown, Gregory; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early Exercise of Put Options on Stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barraclough, Kathryn; Whaley, Robert E.
U.S. exchange-traded stock options are exercisable before expiration. While put options should frequently be exercised early to earn interest, they are not. In this paper, we derive an early exercise decision rule and then examine actual exercise behavior during the period January 1996 through September 2008. We find that more than 3.96 million puts that should have been exercised early remain unexercised, representing over 3.7% of all outstanding puts. We also find that failure to exercise cost put option holders $1.9 billion in forgone interest income and that this interest is systematically captured by market makers and proprietary firms.</description><author>Barraclough, Kathryn; Whaley, Robert E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Overconfident CEOs Better Innovators?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Low, Angie; Teoh, Siew Hong
Previous empirical work on adverse consequences of CEO overconfidence raises the question of why firms hire overconfident managers. Theoretical research suggests a reason: overconfidence can benefit shareholders by increasing investment in risky projects. Using options- and press-based proxies for CEO overconfidence, we find that over the 19932003 period, firms with overconfident CEOs have greater return volatility, invest more in innovation, obtain more patents and patent citations, and achieve greater innovative success for given research and development expenditures. However, overconfident managers achieve greater innovation only in innovative industries. Our findings suggest that overconfidence helps CEOs exploit innovative growth opportunities.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Low, Angie; Teoh, Siew Hong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Algorithmic Trading Improve Liquidity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendershott, Terrence; Jones, Charles M.; Menkveld, Albert J.
Algorithmic trading (AT) has increased sharply over the past decade. Does it improve market quality, and should it be encouraged? We provide the first analysis of this question. The New York Stock Exchange automated quote dissemination in 2003, and we use this change in market structure that increases AT as an exogenous instrument to measure the causal effect of AT on liquidity. For large stocks in particular, AT narrows spreads, reduces adverse selection, and reduces trade-related price discovery. The findings indicate that AT improves liquidity and enhances the informativeness of quotes.</description><author>Hendershott, Terrence; Jones, Charles M.; Menkveld, Albert J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Is a Liability Not a Liability? Textual Analysis, Dictionaries, and 10-Ks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loughran, Tim; McDonald, Bill
Previous research uses negative word counts to measure the tone of a text. We show that word lists developed for other disciplines misclassify common words in financial text. In a large sample of 10-Ks during 1994 to 2008, almost three-fourths of the words identified as negative by the widely used Harvard Dictionary are words typically not considered negative in financial contexts. We develop an alternative negative word list, along with five other word lists, that better reflect tone in financial text. We link the word lists to 10-K filing returns, trading volume, return volatility, fraud, material weakness, and unexpected earnings.</description><author>Loughran, Tim; McDonald, Bill</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Causal Impact of Media in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engelberg, Joseph E.; Parsons, Christopher A.
Disentangling the causal impact of media reporting from the impact of the events being reported is challenging. We solve this problem by comparing the behaviors of investors with access to different media coverage of the same information event. We use zip codes to identify 19 mutually exclusive trading regions corresponding with large U.S. cities. For all earnings announcements of S&amp;P 500 Index firms, we find that local media coverage strongly predicts local trading, after controlling for earnings, investor, and newspaper characteristics. Moreover, local trading is strongly related to the timing of local reporting, a particular challenge to nonmedia explanations.</description><author>Engelberg, Joseph E.; Parsons, Christopher A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage, Moral Hazard, and Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Viswanathan, S.
Financial firms raise short-term debt to finance asset purchases; this induces risk shifting when economic conditions worsen and limits their ability to roll over debt. Constrained firms de-lever by selling assets to lower-leverage firms. In turn, asset-market liquidity depends on the system-wide distribution of leverage, which is itself endogenous to future economic prospects. Good economic prospects yield cheaper short-term debt, inducing entry of higher-leverage firms. Consequently, adverse asset shocks in good times lead to greater de-leveraging and sudden drying up of market and funding liquidity.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Viswanathan, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Market Liquidity and the Business Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Naes, Randi; Skjeltorp, Johannes A.; Odegaard, Bernt Arne
In the recent financial crisis we saw liquidity in the stock market drying up as a precursor to the crisis in the real economy. We show that such effects are not new; in fact, we find a strong relation between stock market liquidity and the business cycle. We also show that investors' portfolio compositions change with the business cycle and that investor participation is related to market liquidity. This suggests that systematic liquidity variation is related to a "flight to quality" during economic downturns. Overall, our results provide a new explanation for the observed commonality in liquidity.</description><author>Naes, Randi; Skjeltorp, Johannes A.; Odegaard, Bernt Arne</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivative Pricing with Liquidity Risk: Theory and Evidence from the Credit Default Swap Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bongaerts, Dion; de Jong, Frank; Driessen, Joost
We derive an equilibrium asset pricing model incorporating liquidity risk, derivatives, and short-selling due to hedging of nontraded risk. We show that illiquid assets can have lower expected returns if the short-sellers have more wealth, lower risk aversion, or shorter horizon. The pricing of liquidity risk is different for derivatives than for positive-net-supply assets, and depends on investors' net nontraded risk exposure. We estimate this model for the credit default swap market. We find strong evidence for an expected liquidity premium earned by the credit protection seller. The effect of liquidity risk is significant but economically small.</description><author>Bongaerts, Dion; de Jong, Frank; Driessen, Joost</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance, Product Market Competition, and Equity Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giroud, Xavier; Mueller, Holger M.
This paper examines whether firms in noncompetitive industries benefit more from good governance than do firms in competitive industries. We find that weak governance firms have lower equity returns, worse operating performance, and lower firm value, but only in noncompetitive industries. When exploring the causes of the inefficiency, we find that weak governance firms have lower labor productivity and higher input costs, and make more value-destroying acquisitions, but, again, only in noncompetitive industries. We also find that weak governance firms in noncompetitive industries are more likely to be targeted by activist hedge funds, suggesting that investors take actions to mitigate the inefficiency.</description><author>Giroud, Xavier; Mueller, Holger M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Style-Related Comovement: Fundamentals or Labels?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyer, Brian H.
I find that economically meaningless index labels cause stock returns to covary in excess of fundamentals. S&amp;P/Barra follow a simple mechanical procedure to define their Value and Growth indices. In doing so, they reclassify some stocks from Value to Growth even after their book-to-market ratios have risen, and vice versa. Such stocks begin to covary more with the index they join and less with the index they leave. Backdated constituent data from Barra reveal no such label-related shifts in comovement during the 10 years prior to the actual introduction of the indices in 1992.</description><author>Boyer, Brian H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing with Garbage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savov, Alexi
A new measure of consumption, garbage, is more volatile and more correlated with stocks than the canonical measure, National Income and Product Accounts (NIPA) consumption expenditure. A garbage-based consumption capital asset pricing model matches the U.S. equity premium with relative risk aversion of 17 versus 81 and evades the joint equity premium-risk-free rate puzzle. These results carry through to European data. In a cross-section of size, value, and industry portfolios, garbage growth is priced and drives out NIPA expenditure growth.</description><author>Savov, Alexi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Decision to Privatize: Finance and Politics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dinc, I. Serdar; Gupta, Nandini
We investigate the influence of political and financial factors on the decision to privatize government-owned firms. The results show that profitable firms and firms with a lower wage bill are likely to be privatized early. We find that the government delays privatization in regions where the governing party faces more competition from opposition parties. The results also suggest that political patronage is important as no firm located in the home state of the minister in charge is ever privatized. Using political variables as an instrument for the privatization decision, we find that privatization has a positive impact on firm performance.</description><author>Dinc, I. Serdar; Gupta, Nandini</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Mutual Fund Advisory Contracts Change? Performance, Growth, and Spillover Effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Warner, Jerold B.; Wu, Joanna Shuang
We examine changes in equity mutual funds' investment advisory contracts. We find substantial advisory compensation rate changes in both directions, with typical percentage fee shifts exceeding one-fourth. Rate increases are associated with superior past market-adjusted performance, whereas rate decreases reflect economies of scale associated with growth, and are not associated with extreme poor performance. There are within-family spillover effects. Superior (e.g., star) performance for individual funds is associated with rate increases for a family's other funds. Rate reductions post-2004 by family funds involved in market timing scandals do not have large industry spillover effects.</description><author>Warner, Jerold B.; Wu, Joanna Shuang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Dividend Clienteles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Bo; Ivkovic, Zoran; Weisbenner, Scott
We exploit demographic variation to identify the effect of dividend demand on corporate payout policy. Retail investors tend to hold local stocks and older investors prefer dividend-paying stocks. Together, these tendencies generate geographically varying demand for dividends. Firms headquartered in areas in which seniors constitute a large fraction of the population are more likely to pay dividends, initiate dividends, and have higher dividend yields. We also provide indirect evidence as to why managers may respond to the demand for dividends from local seniors. Overall, these results are consistent with the notion that the investor base affects corporate policy choices.</description><author>Becker, Bo; Ivkovic, Zoran; Weisbenner, Scott</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Trade Persistence and Long-Term Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dasgupta, Amil; Prat, Andrea; Verardo, Michela
Recent studies show that single-quarter institutional herding positively predicts short-term returns. Motivated by the theoretical herding literature, which emphasizes endogenous persistence in decisions over time, we estimate the effect of multiquarter institutional buying and selling on stock returns. Using both regression and portfolio tests, we find that persistent institutional trading negatively predicts long-term returns: persistently sold stocks outperform persistently bought stocks at long horizons. The negative association between returns and institutional trade persistence is not subsumed by past returns or other stock characteristics, is concentrated among smaller stocks, and is stronger for stocks with higher institutional ownership.</description><author>Dasgupta, Amil; Prat, Andrea; Verardo, Michela</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Incentive Contracts Rigged by Powerful CEOs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morse, Adair; Nanda, Vikram; Seru, Amit
We argue that some powerful CEOs induce boards to shift the weight on performance measures toward the better performing measures, thereby rigging incentive pay. A simple model formalizes this intuition and gives an explicit structural form on the rigged incentive portion of CEO wage function. Using U.S. data, we find support for the model's predictions: rigging accounts for at least 10% of the compensation to performance sensitivity and it increases with CEO human capital and firm volatility. Moreover, a firm with rigged incentive pay that is one standard deviation above the mean faces a subsequent decrease of 4.8% in firm value and 7.5% in operating return on assets.</description><author>Morse, Adair; Nanda, Vikram; Seru, Amit</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overconfidence, Compensation Contracts, and Capital Budgeting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gervais, Simon; Heaton, J. B.; Odean, Terrance
A risk-averse manager's overconfidence makes him less conservative. As a result, it is cheaper for firms to motivate him to pursue valuable risky projects. When compensation endogenously adjusts to reflect outside opportunities, moderate levels of overconfidence lead firms to offer the manager flatter compensation contracts that make him better off. Overconfident managers are also more attractive to firms than their rational counterparts because overconfidence commits them to exert effort to learn about projects. Still, too much overconfidence is detrimental to the manager since it leads him to accept highly convex compensation contracts that expose him to excessive risk.</description><author>Gervais, Simon; Heaton, J. B.; Odean, Terrance</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overconfidence and Early-Life Experiences: The Effect of Managerial Traits on Corporate Financial Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malmendier, Ulrike; Tate, Geoffrey; Yan, Jon
We show that measurable managerial characteristics have significant explanatory power for corporate financing decisions. First, managers who believe that their firm is undervalued view external financing as overpriced, especially equity financing. Such overconfident managers use less external finance and, conditional on accessing external capital, issue less equity than their peers. Second, CEOs who grew up during the Great Depression are averse to debt and lean excessively on internal finance. Third, CEOs with military experience pursue more aggressive policies, including heightened leverage. Complementary measures of CEO traits based on press portrayals confirm the results.</description><author>Malmendier, Ulrike; Tate, Geoffrey; Yan, Jon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real and Financial Implications of Corporate Hedging</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Zou, Hong
We study the implications of hedging for corporate financing and investment. We do so using an extensive, hand-collected data set on corporate hedging activities. Hedging can lower the odds of negative realizations, thereby reducing the expected costs of financial distress. In theory, this should ease a firm's access to credit. Using a tax-based instrumental variable approach, we show that hedgers pay lower interest spreads and are less likely to have capital expenditure restrictions in their loan agreements. These favorable financing terms, in turn, allow hedgers to invest more. Our tests characterize two exact channels-cost of borrowing and investment restrictions-through which hedging affects corporate outcomes. The analysis shows that hedging has a first-order effect on firm financing and investment, and provides new insights into how hedging affects corporate value. More broadly, our study contributes novel evidence on the real consequences of financial contracting.</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Zou, Hong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Unified Theory of Tobin's q, Corporate Investment, Financing, and Risk Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Chen, Hui; Wang, Neng
We propose a model of dynamic investment, financing, and risk management for financially constrained firms. The model highlights the central importance of the endogenous marginal value of liquidity (cash and credit line) for corporate decisions. Our three main results are: (1) investment depends on the ratio of marginal q to the marginal value of liquidity, and the relation between investment and marginal q changes with the marginal source of funding; (2) optimal external financing and payout are characterized by an endogenous double-barrier policy for the firm's cash-capital ratio; and (3) liquidity management and derivatives hedging are complementary risk management tools.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Chen, Hui; Wang, Neng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In Search of Attention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Engelberg, Joseph; Gao, Pengjie
We propose a new and direct measure of investor attention using search frequency in Google (Search Volume Index (SVI)). In a sample of Russell 3000 stocks from 2004 to 2008, we find that SVI (1) is correlated with but different from existing proxies of investor attention; (2) captures investor attention in a more timely fashion and (3) likely measures the attention of retail investors. An increase in SVI predicts higher stock prices in the next 2 weeks and an eventual price reversal within the year. It also contributes to the large first-day return and long-run underperformance of IPO stocks.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Engelberg, Joseph; Gao, Pengjie</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Concentrating on Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kadyrzhanova, Dalida; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew
This paper develops a novel trade-off view of corporate governance. Using a model that integrates agency costs and bargaining benefits of management-friendly provisions, we identify the economic determinants of the resulting trade-offs for shareholder value. Consistent with the theory, our empirical analysis shows that provisions that allow managers to delay takeovers have significant bargaining effects and a positive relation with shareholder value in concentrated industries. By contrast, non-delay provisions have an unambiguously negative relation with value, particularly in concentrated industries. Our analysis suggests that there are governance trade-offs for shareholders and that industry concentration is an important determinant of their severity.</description><author>Kadyrzhanova, Dalida; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonbinding Voting for Shareholder Proposals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levit, Doron; Malenko, Nadya
Shareholder proposals are a common form of shareholder activism. Voting for shareholder proposals, however, is nonbinding since management has the authority to reject the proposal even if it received majority support from shareholders. We analyze whether nonbinding voting is an effective mechanism for conveying shareholder expectations. We show that, unlike binding voting, nonbinding voting generally fails to convey shareholder views when manager and shareholder interests are not aligned. Surprisingly, the presence of an activist investor who can discipline the manager may enhance the advisory role of nonbinding voting only if conflicts of interest between shareholders and the activist are substantial.</description><author>Levit, Doron; Malenko, Nadya</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Free Cash Flow, Issuance Costs, and Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Decamps, Jean-Paul; Mariotti, Thomas; Rochet, Jean-Charles; Villeneuve, Stephane
We develop a dynamic model of a firm facing agency costs of free cash flow and external financing costs, and derive an explicit solution for the firm's optimal balance sheet dynamics. Financial frictions affect issuance and dividend policies, the value of cash holdings, and the dynamics of stock prices. The model predicts that the marginal value of cash varies negatively with the stock price, and positively with the volatility of the stock price. This yields novel insights on the asymmetric volatility phenomenon, on risk management policies, and on how business cycles and agency costs affect the volatility of stock returns.</description><author>Decamps, Jean-Paul; Mariotti, Thomas; Rochet, Jean-Charles; Villeneuve, Stephane</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Motivating Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manso, Gustavo
Motivating innovation is important in many incentive problems. This paper shows that the optimal innovation-motivating incentive scheme exhibits substantial tolerance (or even reward) for early failure and reward for long-term success. Moreover, commitment to a long-term compensation plan, job security, and timely feedback on performance are essential to motivate innovation. In the context of managerial compensation, the optimal innovation-motivating incentive scheme can be implemented via a combination of stock options with long vesting periods, option repricing, golden parachutes, and managerial entrenchment.</description><author>Manso, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic Liquidation Risk and the Diversity-Diversification Trade-Off</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wagner, Wolf
This paper proposes a portfolio choice model in which investors are subject to liquidation risk and (endogenously) face higher costs in the event of joint liquidation (as was observed during the crisis of 2008 to 2009). The risk of joint liquidation creates an incentive for investors to choose heterogeneous portfolios and to rationally forgo diversification benefits. Joint liquidation risk is also reflected in asset prices, resulting in (1) assets with high idiosyncratic risk having low expected returns, and (2) assets that display high correlation with the portfolios of (liquidation-prone) investors having high expected returns.</description><author>Wagner, Wolf</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual Investors and Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, Thierry; Sraer, David; Thesmar, David J.
We show that retail trading activity has a positive effect on the volatility of stock returns, which suggests that retail investors behave as noise traders. To identify this effect, we use a reform of the French stock market that raises the relative cost of speculative trading for retail investors. The daily return volatility of the stocks affected by the reform falls by 20 basis points (a quarter of the sample standard deviation of the return volatility) relative to other stocks. For affected stocks, we also find a significant decrease in the magnitude of return reversals and the price impact of trades.</description><author>Foucault, Thierry; Sraer, David; Thesmar, David J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining the Magnitude of Liquidity Premia: The Roles of Return Predictability, Wealth Shocks, and State-Dependent Transaction Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lynch, Anthony W.; Tan, Sinan
Constantinides (1986) documents how the impact of transaction costs on per-annum liquidity premia in the standard dynamic allocation problem with i.i.d. returns is an order of magnitude smaller than the cost rate itself. Recent papers form portfolios sorted on liquidity measures and find spreads in expected per-annum return that are the same order of magnitude as the transaction cost spread. When we allow returns to be predictable and introduce wealth shocks calibrated to labor income, transaction costs are able to produce per-annum liquidity premia that are the same order of magnitude as the transaction cost spread.</description><author>Lynch, Anthony W.; Tan, Sinan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did Structured Credit Fuel the LBO Boom?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shivdasani, Anil; Wang, Yihui
The leveraged buyout (LBO) boom of 2004 to 2007 was fueled by growth in collateralized debt obligations (CDOs) and other forms of securitization. Banks active in structured credit underwriting lent more for LBOs, indicating that bank lending policies linked LBO and CDO markets. LBO loans originated by large CDO underwriters were associated with lower spreads, weaker covenants, and greater use of bank debt in deal financing. Loans financed through structured credit markets did not lead to worse LBOs, overpayment, or riskier deal structures. Securitization markets altered banks' access to capital, affected their lending policies, and fueled the recent LBO boom.</description><author>Shivdasani, Anil; Wang, Yihui</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Drove and Burst the Tech Bubble?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Harris, Jeffrey H.; Shu, Tao; Topaloglu, Selim
From 1997 to March 2000, as technology stocks rose more than five-fold, institutions bought more new technology supply than individuals. Among institutions, hedge funds were the most aggressive investors, but independent investment advisors and mutual funds (net of flows) actively invested the most capital in the technology sector. The technology stock reversal in March 2000 was accompanied by a broad sell-off from institutional investors but accelerated buying by individuals, particularly discount brokerage clients. Overall, our evidence supports the bubble model of Abreu and Brunnermeier (2003), in which rational arbitrageurs fail to trade against bubbles until a coordinated selling effort occurs.</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Harris, Jeffrey H.; Shu, Tao; Topaloglu, Selim</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential Address: Discount Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cochrane, John H.
Discount-rate variation is the central organizing question of current asset-pricing research. I survey facts, theories, and applications. Previously, we thought returns were unpredictable, with variation in price-dividend ratios due to variation in expected cashflows. Now it seems all price-dividend variation corresponds to discount-rate variation. We also thought that the cross-section of expected returns came from the CAPM. Now we have a zoo of new factors. I categorize discount-rate theories based on central ingredients and data sources. Incorporating discount-rate variation affects finance applications, including portfolio theory, accounting, cost of capital, capital structure, compensation, and macroeconomics.</description><author>Cochrane, John H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stressed, Not Frozen: The Federal Funds Market in the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Afonso, Gara; Kovner, Anna; Schoar, Antoinette
We examine the importance of liquidity hoarding and counterparty risk in the U.S. overnight interbank market during the financial crisis of 2008. Our findings suggest that counterparty risk plays a larger role than does liquidity hoarding: the day after Lehman Brothers' bankruptcy, loan terms become more sensitive to borrower characteristics. In particular, poorly performing large banks see an increase in spreads of 25 basis points, but are borrowing 1% less, on average. Worse performing banks do not hoard liquidity. While the interbank market does not freeze entirely, it does not seem to expand to meet latent demand.</description><author>Afonso, Gara; Kovner, Anna; Schoar, Antoinette</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rollover Risk and Market Freezes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Gale, Douglas; Yorulmazer, Tanju
The debt capacity of an asset is the maximum amount that can be borrowed using the asset as collateral. We model a sudden collapse in the debt capacity of good collateral. We assume short-term debt that must be frequently rolled over, a small transaction cost of selling collateral in the event of default, and a small probability of meeting a buy-to-hold investor. We then show that a small change in the asset's fundamental value can be associated with a catastrophic drop in the debt capacity, the kind of market freeze observed during the crisis of 2007 to 2008.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Gale, Douglas; Yorulmazer, Tanju</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public Pension Promises: How Big Are They and What Are They Worth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Novy-Marx, Robert; Rauh, Joshua
We calculate the present value of state employee pension liabilities using discount rates that reflect the risk of the payments from a taxpayer perspective. If benefits have the same default and recovery characteristics as state general obligation debt, the national total of promised liabilities based on current salary and service is $3.20 trillion. If pensions have higher priority than state debt, the value of liabilities is much larger. Using zero-coupon Treasury yields, which are default-free but contain other priced risks, promised liabilities are $4.43 trillion. Liabilities are even larger under broader concepts that account for salary growth and future service.</description><author>Novy-Marx, Robert; Rauh, Joshua</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Options on Index Futures Profitable for Risk-Averse Investors? Empirical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Constantinides, George M.; Czerwonko, Michal; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten; Perrakis, Stylianos
American options on the S&amp;P 500 index futures that violate the stochastic dominance bounds of Constantinides and Perrakis (2009) from 1983 to 2006 are identified as potentially profitable trades. Call bid prices more frequently violate their upper bound than put bid prices do, while violations of the lower bounds by ask prices are infrequent. In out-of-sample tests of stochastic dominance, the writing of options that violate the upper bound increases the expected utility of any risk-averse investor holding the market and cash, net of transaction costs and bid-ask spreads. The results are economically significant and robust.</description><author>Constantinides, George M.; Czerwonko, Michal; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten; Perrakis, Stylianos</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Interim Trading Skills of Institutional Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Puckett, Andy; Yan, Xuemin
Using a large proprietary database of institutional trades, this paper examines the interim (intraquarter) trading skills of institutional investors. We find strong evidence that institutional investors earn significant abnormal returns on their trades within the trading quarter and that interim trading performance is persistent. After transactions costs, our estimates suggest that interim trading skills contribute between 20 and 26 basis points per year to the average fund's abnormal performance. Our findings also indicate that any trading skills documented by previous studies that use quarterly data are biased downwards because of their inability to account for interim trades.</description><author>Puckett, Andy; Yan, Xuemin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Land and Credit: A Study of the Political Economy of Banking in the United States in the Early 20th Century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajan, Raghuram G.; Ramcharan, Rodney
We find that, in the early 20th century, counties in the United States where the agricultural elite had disproportionately large land holdings had significantly fewer banks per capita, even correcting for state-level effects. Moreover, credit appears to have been costlier, and access to it more limited, in these counties. The evidence suggests that elites may restrict financial development in order to limit access to finance, and they may be able to do so even in countries with well-developed political institutions.</description><author>Rajan, Raghuram G.; Ramcharan, Rodney</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory Uncertainty and Market Liquidity: The 2008 Short Sale Ban's Impact on Equity Option Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battalio, Robert; Schultz, Paul
We examine how the September 2008 short sale restrictions and the accompanying confusion and regulatory uncertainty impacted equity option markets. We find that the short sale ban is associated with dramatically increased bid-ask spreads for options on banned stocks. In addition, synthetic share prices for banned stocks become significantly lower than actual share prices during the ban. We find similar results for synthetic share prices of hard-to-borrow stocks, suggesting that the dislocation in actual and synthetic share prices is attributable to the increased hedging costs for options on banned stocks during the short sale ban.</description><author>Battalio, Robert; Schultz, Paul</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Don't U.S. Issuers Demand European Fees for IPOs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abrahamson, Mark; Jenkinson, Tim; Jones, Howard
We compare fees charged by investment banks for conducting IPOs in the United States and Europe. In recent years, the "7% solution," as documented by Chen and Ritter (2000), has become even more prevalent in the United States, and is now the norm for IPOs raising up to $250 million. The same banks dominate both markets, but European IPO fees are roughly three percentage points lower, are much more variable, and have been falling. We review explanations for the gap in spreads and find the evidence consistent with strategic pricing. U.S. issuers could have saved over $1 billion a year by paying European fees.</description><author>Abrahamson, Mark; Jenkinson, Tim; Jones, Howard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tails, Fears, and Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollerslev, Tim; Todorov, Viktor
We show that the compensation for rare events accounts for a large fraction of the average equity and variance risk premia. Exploiting the special structure of the jump tails and the pricing thereof, we identify and estimate a new Investor Fears index. The index reveals large time-varying compensation for fears of disasters. Our empirical investigations involve new extreme value theory approximations and high-frequency intraday data for estimating the expected jump tails under the statistical probability measure, and short maturity out-of-the-money options and new model-free implied variation measures for estimating the corresponding risk-neutral expectations.</description><author>Bollerslev, Tim; Todorov, Viktor</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disasters Implied by Equity Index Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Backus, David; Chernov, Mikhail; Martin, Ian
We use equity index options to quantify the distribution of consumption growth disasters. The challenge lies in connecting the risk-neutral distribution of equity returns implied by options to the true distribution of consumption growth. First, we compare pricing kernels constructed from macro-finance and option-pricing models. Second, we compare option prices derived from a macro-finance model to those we observe. Third, we compare the distribution of consumption growth derived from option prices using a macro-finance model to estimates based on macroeconomic data. All three perspectives suggest that options imply smaller probabilities of extreme outcomes than have been estimated from macroeconomic data.</description><author>Backus, David; Chernov, Mikhail; Martin, Ian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prices or Knowledge? What Drives Demand for Financial Services in Emerging Markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cole, Shawn; Sampson, Thomas; Zia, Bilal
Financial development is critical for growth, but its microdeterminants are not well understood. We test leading theories of low demand for financial services in emerging markets, combining novel survey evidence from Indonesia and India with a field experiment. We find a strong correlation between financial literacy and behavior. However, a financial education program has modest effects, increasing demand for bank accounts only for those with limited education or financial literacy. In contrast, small subsidies greatly increase demand. A follow-up survey confirms these findings, demonstrating that newly opened accounts remain open and in use 2 years after the intervention.</description><author>Cole, Shawn; Sampson, Thomas; Zia, Bilal</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Disclosure, Cognitive Biases, and Payday Borrowing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertrand, Marianne; Morse, Adair
Can psychology-guided information disclosure induce borrowers to lower their use of high-cost debt? In a field experiment at payday stores, we find that information that makes people think less narrowly (over time) about finance costs results in less borrowing. In particular, reinforcing the adding-up dollar fees incurred when rolling over loans reduces the take-up of future payday loans by 11% in the subsequent 4 months. Although we remain agnostic as to the overall sufficiency of better disclosure policy to "remedy" payday borrowing, we cast the 11% reduction in borrowing in light of the relative low cost of this policy.</description><author>Bertrand, Marianne; Morse, Adair</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguous Information, Portfolio Inertia, and Excess Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Illeditsch, Philipp Karl
I study the effects of risk and ambiguity (Knightian uncertainty) on optimal portfolios and equilibrium asset prices when investors receive information that is difficult to link to fundamentals. I show that the desire of investors to hedge ambiguity leads to portfolio inertia and excess volatility. Specifically, when news is surprising, investors may not react to price changes even if there are no transaction costs or other market frictions. Moreover, I show that small shocks to cash flow news, asset betas, or market risk premia may lead to drastic changes in the stock price and hence to excess volatility.</description><author>Illeditsch, Philipp Karl</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IQ and Stock Market Participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, Mark; Keloharju, Matti; Linnainmaa, Juhani
Stock market participation is monotonically related to IQ, controlling for wealth, income, age, and other demographic and occupational information. The high correlation between IQ and participation exists even among the affluent. Supplemental data from siblings, studied with an instrumental variables approach and regressions that control for family effects, demonstrate that IQ's influence on participation extends to females and does not arise from omitted familial and nonfamilial variables. High-IQ investors are more likely to hold mutual funds and larger numbers of stocks, experience lower risk, and earn higher Sharpe ratios. We discuss implications for policy and finance research.</description><author>Grinblatt, Mark; Keloharju, Matti; Linnainmaa, Juhani</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Poor Performance Damage the Reputation of Financial Intermediaries? Evidence from the Loan Syndication Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Nanda, Vikram; Yerramilli, Vijay
We investigate the effect of poor performance on financial intermediary reputation by estimating the effect of large-scale bankruptcies among a lead arranger's borrowers on its subsequent syndication activity. Consistent with reputation damage, such lead arrangers retain larger fractions of the loans they syndicate, are less likely to syndicate loans, and are less likely to attract participant lenders. The consequences are more severe when borrower bankruptcies suggest inadequate screening or monitoring by the lead arranger. However, the effect of borrower bankruptcies on syndication activity is not present among dominant lead arrangers, and is weak in years in which many lead arrangers experience borrower bankruptcies.</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Nanda, Vikram; Yerramilli, Vijay</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Equity and Long-Run Investment: The Case of Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lerner, Josh; Sorensen, Morten; Stroemberg, Per
A long-standing controversy is whether leveraged buyouts (LBOs) relieve managers from short-term pressures from public shareholders, or whether LBO funds themselves sacrifice long-term growth to boost short-term performance. We examine one form of long-run activity, namely, investments in innovation as measured by patenting activity. Based on 472 LBO transactions, we find no evidence that LBOs sacrifice long-term investments. LBO firm patents are more cited (a proxy for economic importance), show no shifts in the fundamental nature of the research, and become more concentrated in important areas of companies' innovative portfolios.</description><author>Lerner, Josh; Sorensen, Morten; Stroemberg, Per</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Individual Investors Have Asymmetric Information Based on Work Experience?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doskeland, Trond M.; Hvide, Hans K.
Using a novel data set covering all individual investors' stock market transactions in Norway over 10 years, we analyze whether individual investors have a preference for professionally close stocks, and whether they make excess returns on such investments. After excluding own-company stock holdings, investors hold 11% of their portfolio in stocks within their two-digit industry of employment. Given the poor hedging properties of such investments, one would expect abnormally high returns. In contrast, all estimates of abnormal returns are negative, in many cases statistically significant. Overconfidence seems the most likely explanation for the excessive trading in professionally close stocks.</description><author>Doskeland, Trond M.; Hvide, Hans K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee Stock Options and Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Babenko, Ilona; Lemmon, Michael; Tserlukevich, Yuri
Exercises of employee stock options generate substantial cash inflows to the firm. These cash inflows substitute for costly external finance in those states of the world in which the demand for investment is high. Using the fact that the proceeds from option exercises exhibit a distinct nonlinearity around the point where options fall out of the money, we estimate that firms increase investment by $0.34 for each dollar received from the exercise of stock options. Firms that face higher external financing costs allocate more of the proceeds from option exercises to investment.</description><author>Babenko, Ilona; Lemmon, Michael; Tserlukevich, Yuri</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimation and Evaluation of Conditional Asset Pricing Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagel, Stefan; Singleton, Kenneth J.
We find that several recently proposed consumption-based models of stock returns, when evaluated using an optimal set of managed portfolios and the associated model-implied conditional moment restrictions, fail to capture key features of risk premiums in equity markets. To arrive at these conclusions, we construct an optimal Generalized Method of Moments (GMM) estimator for models in which the stochastic discount factor (SDF) is a conditionally affine function of a set of priced risk factors, and we show that there is an optimal choice of managed portfolios to use in testing a null model against a proposed alternative generalized SDF.</description><author>Nagel, Stefan; Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>