<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JF5</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Can mutual fund "stars" really pick stocks? New evidence from a bootstrap analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kosowski, Robert; Timmermann, Allan; Wermers, Russ; White, Hal
We apply a new bootstrap statistical technique to examine the performance of the US. open-end, domestic equity mutual fund industry over the 1975 to 2002 period. A bootstrap approach is necessary because the cross section of mutual fund alphas has a complex nonnormal distribution due to heterogeneous risk-taking by funds as well as nonnormalities in individual fund alpha distributions. Our bootstrap approach uncovers findings that differ from many past studies. Specifically, we find that a sizable minority of managers pick stocks well enough to more than cover their costs. Moreover, the superior alphas of these managers persist.</description><author>Kosowski, Robert; Timmermann, Allan; Wermers, Russ; White, Hal</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed lending and security design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, Roman; Mueller, Holger M.
We examine the role of security design when lenders make inefficient accept or reject decisions after screening projects. Lenders may be either "too conservative," in which case they reject positive-NPV projects, or "too aggressive," in which case they accept negative-NPV projects. In the first case, the uniquely optimal security is debt. In the second case, it is levered equity. In equilibrium, profitable projects that are relatively likely to break even are financed with debt, while less profitable projects are financed with equity. Highly profitable projects are financed by uninformed arm's-length lenders.</description><author>Inderst, Roman; Mueller, Holger M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The evolution of security designs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Noe, Thomas H.; Rebello, Michael J.; Wang, Jun
We consider a competitive and perfect financial market in which agents have heterogeneous cash flow valuations. Instead of assuming that agents are endowed with rational expectations, we model their behavior as the product of adaptive learning. Our results demonstrate that adaptive learning affects security design profoundly, with securities mispriced even in the long run and optimal designs trading off underpricing against intrinsic value maximization. The evolutionary dominant security design calls for issuing securities that engender large losses with a small but positive probability, but that otherwise produce stable payoffs, almost the exact opposite of the pure state claims that are optimal in the rational expectations framework.</description><author>Noe, Thomas H.; Rebello, Michael J.; Wang, Jun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Options and the bubble</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battalio, Robert; Schultz, Paul
Many believe that a bubble existed in Internet stocks in the 1999 to 2000 period, and that short-sale restrictions prevented rational investors from driving Internet stock prices to reasonable levels. In the presence of such short-sale constraints, option and stock prices could decouple during a bubble. Using intraday options data from the peak of the Internet bubble, we find almost no evidence that synthetic stock prices diverged from actual stock prices. We also show that the general public could cheaply short synthetically using options. In summary, we find no evidence that short-sale restrictions affected Internet stock prices.</description><author>Battalio, Robert; Schultz, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value premium and the CAPM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
We examine (1) how value premiums vary with firm size, (2) whether the CAPM explains value premiums, and (3) whether, in general, average returns compensate beta in the way predicted by the CAPM. Loughran's (1997) evidence for a weak value premium among large firms is special to 1963 to 1995, U. S. stocks, and the book-to-market value-growth indicator. Ang and Chen's ( 2005) evidence that the CAPM can explain U. S. value premiums is special to 1926 to 1963. The CAPM's more general problem is that variation in beta unrelated to size and the value-growth characteristic goes unrewarded throughout 1926 to 2004.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic portfolio selection by augmentingthe asset space</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandt, Michael W.; Santa-Clara, Pedro
We present a novel approach to dynamic portfolio selection that is as easy to implement as the static Markowitz paradigm. We expand the set of assets to include mechanically managed portfolios and optimize statically in this extended asset space. We consider "conditional" portfolios, which invest in each asset an amount proportional to conditioning variables, and "timing" portfolios, which invest in each asset for a single period and in the risk-free asset for all other periods. The static choice of these managed portfolios represents a dynamic strategy that closely approximates the optimal dynamic strategy for horizons up to 5 years.</description><author>Brandt, Michael W.; Santa-Clara, Pedro</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ericsson, Jan; Renault, Olivier
We develop a structural bond valuation model to simultaneously capture liquidity and credit risk. Our model implies that renegotiation in financial distress is influenced by the illiquidity of the market for distressed debt. As default becomes more likely, the components of bond yield spreads attributable to illiquidity increase. When we consider finite maturity debt, we find decreasing and convex term structures of liquidity spreads. Using bond price data spanning 15 years, we find evidence of a positive correlation between the illiquidity and default components of yield spreads as well as support for downward-sloping term structures of liquidity spreads.</description><author>Ericsson, Jan; Renault, Olivier</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive stock options: Early exercise provisions and risk-taking incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brisley, Neil
Traditional executive stock option plans allow fixed numbers of options to vest peri-odically, independent of stock price performance. Because such options may climb deep in-the-money long before the manager can exercise them, they can exacerbate risk aversion in project selection. Making the proportion of options that vest a gradually increasing function of the stock price can ensure that appropriate numbers of options are retained while they provide risk-taking incentives, but are exercised once they have lost their convexity. "Progressive performance vesting" can allow the firm more efficiently to rebalance the manager's risk-taking incentives.</description><author>Brisley, Neil</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lending booms and lending standards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Marquez, Robert
We examine how the informational structure of loan markets interacts with banks' strategic behavior in determining lending standards, lending volume, and the aggregate allocation of credit. We show that, as banks obtain private information about borrowers and information asymmetries across banks decrease, banks may loosen their lending standards, leading to an equilibrium with deteriorated bank portfolios, lower profits, and expanded aggregate credit. These lower standards are associated with greater aggregate surplus and greater risk of financial instability. We therefore provide an explanation for the sequence of financial liberalization, lending booms, and banking crises observed in many emerging markets.</description><author>Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Marquez, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retail investor sentiment and return comovements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Alok; Lee, Charles M. C.
Using a database of more than 1.85 million retail investor transactions over 1991-1996, we show that these trades are systematically correlated-that is, individuals buy (or sell) stocks in concert. Moreover, consistent with noise trader models, we find that systematic retail trading explains return comovements for stocks with high retail concentration (i.e., small-cap, value, lower institutional ownership, and lower-priced stocks), especially if these stocks are also costly to arbitrage. Macroeconomic news and analyst earnings forecast revisions do not explain these results. Collectively, our findings support a role for investor sentiment in the formation of returns.</description><author>Kumar, Alok; Lee, Charles M. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bayesian alphas and mutual fund persistence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Busse, Jeffrey A.; Irvine, Paul J.
We use daily returns to compare the performance predictability of Bayesian estimates of mutual fund performance with standard frequentist measures. When the returns on passive nonbenchmark assets are correlated with fund holdings, incorporating histories of these returns produces a performance measure that predicts future performance better than standard measures do. Bayesian alphas based on the Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM) are particularly useful for predicting future standard CAPM alphas. Over our sample period, priors consistent with moderate to diffuse beliefs in managerial skill dominate more skeptical prior beliefs, a result that is consistent with investor cash flows.</description><author>Busse, Jeffrey A.; Irvine, Paul J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business groups and tunneling: Evidence from private securities offeringsby Korean chaebols</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baek, Jae-Seung; Kang, Jun-Koo; Lee, Inmoo
We examine whether equity-linked private securities offerings are used as a mechanism for tunneling among firms that belong to a Korean chaebol. We find that chaebol issuers involved in intragroup deals set the offering prices to benefit their controlling shareholders. We also find that chaebol issuers (member acquirers) realize an 8.8% (5.8%) higher (lower) announcement return than do other types of issuers (acquirers) if they sell private securities at a premium to other member firms, and if the controlling shareholders receive positive net gains from equity ownership in issuers and acquirers. These results are consistent with tunneling within business groups.</description><author>Baek, Jae-Seung; Kang, Jun-Koo; Lee, Inmoo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Automation versus intermediation: Evidence from treasuries going off the run</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barclay, Michael J.; Hendershott, Terrence; Kotz, Kenneth
This paper examines the choice of trading venue by dealers in U.S. Treasury securities to determine when services provided by human intermediaries are difficult to replicate in fully automated trading systems. When Treasury securities go "off the run" their trading volume drops by more than 90%. This decline in trading volume allows us to test whether intermediaries' knowledge of the market and its participants can uncover hidden liquidity and facilitate better matching of customer orders in less active markets. Consistent with this hypothesis, the market share of electronic intermediaries falls from 81% to 12% when securities go off the run.</description><author>Barclay, Michael J.; Hendershott, Terrence; Kotz, Kenneth</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and autocorrelations in individual stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun; Goyal, Amit
This paper documents a strong relationship between short-run reversals and stock illiquidity, even after controlling for trading volume. The largest reversals and the potential contrarian trading strategy profits occur in high turnover, low liquidity stocks, as the price pressures caused by non-informational demands for immediacy are accommodated. However, the contrarian trading strategy profits are smaller than the likely transactions costs. This lack of profitability and the fact that the overall findings are consistent with rational equilibrium paradigms suggest that the violation of the efficient market hypothesis due to short-term reversals is not so egregious after all.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun; Goyal, Amit</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A nonlinear factor analysis of S&amp;P 500 index option returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Christopher S.
Growing evidence suggests that extraordinary average returns may be obtained by trading equity index options, and that at least part of this abnormal performance is attributable to volatility and jump risk premia. This paper asks whether such priced risk factors are alone sufficient to explain these average returns. To provide an answer in as general as possible a setting, I estimate a flexible class of nonlinear models using all S&amp;P 500 Index futures options traded between 1986 and 2000. The results show that priced factors contribute to these expected returns but are insufficient to explain their magnitudes, particularly for short-term out-of-the-money puts.</description><author>Jones, Christopher S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are IPO allocations for sale? Evidence from mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reuter, Jonathan
Combining data on brokerage commissions that mutual fund families paid for trade execution between 1996 and 1999 with data on mutual fund holdings of initial public offerings (IPOs), I document a robust, positive correlation between commissions paid to lead underwriters and reported holdings of the IPOs they underwrite. Moreover, I find that the correlation is limited to IPOs with nonnegative first-day returns and strongest for IPOs that occur shortly before mutual funds report their holdings, when the noise introduced by flipping is smallest. Overall, the evidence suggests that business relationships with lead underwriters increase investor access to underpriced IPOs.</description><author>Reuter, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do firms rebalance their capital structures ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leary, M. T.; Roberts, M. R.
We empirically examine whether firms engage in a dynamic rebalancing of their capital structures while allowing for costly adjustment. We begin by showing that the presence of adjustment costs has significant implications for corporate financial policy and the interpretation of previous empirical results. After confirming that financing behavior is consistent with the presence of adjustment costs, we find that firms actively rebalance their leverage to stay within an optimal range. Our evidence suggests that the persistent effect of shocks on leverage observed in previous studies is more likely due to adjustment costs than indifference toward capital structure.</description><author>Leary, M. T.; Roberts, M. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal capital structure and industry dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miao, J. J.
This paper provides a competitive equilibrium model of capital structure and industry dynamics. In the model, firms make financing, investment, entry, and exit decisions subject to idiosyncratic technology shocks. The capital structure choice reflects the tradeoff between the tax benefits of debt and the associated bankruptcy and agency costs. The interaction between financing and production decisions influences the stationary distribution of firms and their survival probabilities. The analysis demonstrates that the equilibrium output price has an important feedback effect. This effect has a number of testable implications. For example, high growth industries have relatively lower leverage and turnover rates.</description><author>Miao, J. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO overconfidence and corporate investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malmendier, U.; Tate, G.
We argue that managerial overconfidence can account for corporate investment distortions. Overconfident managers overestimate the returns to their investment projects and view external funds as unduly costly. Thus, they overinvest when they have abundant internal funds, but curtail investment when they require external financing. We test the overconfidence hypothesis, using panel data on personal portfolio and corporate investment decisions of Forbes 500 CEOs. We classify CEOs as overconfident if they persistently fail to reduce their personal exposure to company-specific risk. We find that investment of overconfident CEOs is significantly more responsive to cash flow, particularly in equity-dependent firms.</description><author>Malmendier, U.; Tate, G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transparency and international portfolio holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gelos, R. G.; Wei, S. J.
Does country transparency affect international portfolio investment? We examine this question by constructing new measures of transparency and by making use of a unique microdata set on portfolio holdings of emerging market funds around the world. We distinguish between government and corporate transparency. There is clear evidence that funds systematically invest less in less transparent countries. Moreover, funds have a greater propensity to exit nontransparent countries during crises.</description><author>Gelos, R. G.; Wei, S. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial market design and the equity premium: Electronic versus floor trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jain, P. K.
We assemble the announcement and actual introduction dates of electronic trading by the leading exchanges of 120 countries to examine the impact of automation, controlling for risk factors and economic conditions. Dividend growth models and international CAPM suggest a significant decline in the equity premium, especially in emerging markets. Consistent with this reduction in the equity premium in the long run, there is a positive short-term price reaction to the switch. Further analysis of trading turnover supports the notion that electronic trading enhances the liquidity and informativeness of stock markets, leading to a reduction in the cost of capital.</description><author>Jain, P. K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial networks: Contagion, commitment, and private sector bailouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leitner, Y.
I develop a model of financial networks in which linkages not only spread contagion, but also induce private sector bailouts, where liquid banks bail out illiquid banks because of the threat of contagion. Introducing this bailout possibility, I show that linkages may be optimal ex ante because they allow banks to obtain some mutual insurance even though formal commitments are impossible. However, in some cases (e.g., when liquidity is concentrated among a small group of banks), the whole network may collapse. I also characterize the optimal network size and apply the results to joint liability arrangements and payment systems.</description><author>Leitner, Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt maturity, risk, and asymmetric information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, A. N.; Espinosa-Vega, M. A.; Frame, W. S.; Miller, N. H.
We test the implications of Flannery's (1986) and Diamond's (1991) models concerning the effects of risk and asymmetric information in determining debt maturity, and we examine the overall importance of informational asymmetries in debt maturity choices. We employ data on over 6,000 commercial loans from 53 large U.S. banks. Our results for low-risk firms are consistent with the predictions of both theoretical models, but our findings for high-risk firms conflict with the predictions of Diamond's model and with much of the empirical literature. Our findings also suggest a strong quantitative role for asymmetric information in explaining debt maturity.</description><author>Berger, A. N.; Espinosa-Vega, M. A.; Frame, W. S.; Miller, N. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance mechanisms and equity prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, K. J. M.; Nair, V. B.
We investigate how the market for corporate control (external governance) and shareholder activism (internal governance) interact. A portfolio that buys firms with the highest level of takeover vulnerability and shorts firms with the lowest level of takeover vulnerability generates an annualized abnormal return of 10% to 15% only when public pension fund (blockholder) ownership is high as well. A similar portfolio created to capture the importance of internal governance generates annualized abnormal returns of 8%, though only in the presence of "high" vulnerability to takeovers. The complementarity effect exists for firms with lower industry-adjusted leverage and is stronger for smaller firms.</description><author>Cremers, K. J. M.; Nair, V. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changing names with style: Mutual fund name changes and their effects on fund flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, M. J.; Gulen, H.; Rau, P. R.
We examine whether mutual funds change their names to take advantage of current hot investment styles, and what effects these name changes have on inflows to the funds, and to the funds' subsequent returns. We find that the year after a fund changes its name to reflect a current hot style, the fund experiences an average cumulative abnormal flow of 28%, with no improvement in performance. The increase in flows is similar across funds whose holdings match the style implied by their new name and those whose holdings do not, suggesting that investors are irrationally influenced by cosmetic effects.</description><author>Cooper, M. J.; Gulen, H.; Rau, P. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Thy neighbor's portfolio: Word-of-mouth effects in the holdings and trades of money managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, H.; Kubik, J. D.; Stein, J. C.
A mutual fund manager is more likely to buy (or sell) a particular stock in any quarter if other managers in the same city are buying (or selling) that same stock. This pattern shows up even when the fund manager and the stock in question are located far apart, so it is distinct from anything having to do with local preference. The evidence can be interpreted in terms of an epidemic model in which investors spread information about stocks to one another by word of mouth.</description><author>Hong, H.; Kubik, J. D.; Stein, J. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the benefits of concurrent lending and underwriting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drucker, S.; Puri, M.
This paper examines whether there are efficiencies that benefit issuers and underwriters when a financial intermediary concurrently lends to an issuer while also underwriting its public securities offering. We find issuers, particularly noninvestment-grade issuers for whom informational economies of scope are likely to be large, benefit through lower underwriter fees and discounted loan yield spreads. Underwriters, both commercial banks as well as investment banks, engage in concurrent lending and provide price discounts, albeit in different ways. We find concurrent lending helps underwriters build relationships, increasing the probability of receiving current and future business.</description><author>Drucker, S.; Puri, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment bank reputation and the price and quality of underwriting services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, L. H.
The relation between investment bank reputation and the price and quality of bond underwriting services is studied here. After controlling for endogeneity in issuer-underwriter matching, I find that reputable banks obtain lower yields and charge higher fees, but issuers' net proceeds are higher. These relations are pronounced in the junk-bond category, in which reputable banks' underwriting criteria are most stringent. These findings suggest that banks' underwriting decisions reflect reputation concerns, and are thus informative of issue quality. They also suggest that economic rents are earned on reputation, and thereby provide continued incentives for underwriters to maintain reputation.</description><author>Fang, L. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO compensation, change, and corporate strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dow, J.; Raposo, C. C.
CEO compensation can influence the kinds of strategies that firms adopt. We argue that performance-related compensation creates an incentive to look for overly ambitious, hard to implement strategies. At a cost, shareholders can curb this tendency by precommitting to a regime of CEO overcompensation in highly changeable environments. Alternatively shareholders can commit to low CEO pay, although this requires a commitment mechanism (either by the board of the individual company, or by the society as a whole) to counter the incentive to renegotiate upwards. We study the conditions under which the different policies for CEO compensation are preferred by shareholders.</description><author>Dow, J.; Raposo, C. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium in a dynamic limit order market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goettler, R. L.; Parlour, C. A.; Rajan, U.
We model a dynamic limit order market as a stochastic sequential game with rational traders. Since the model is analytically intractable, we provide an algorithm based on Pakes and McGuire (2001) to find a stationary Markov-perfect equilibrium. We then generate artificial time series and perform comparative dynamics. Conditional on a transaction, the midpoint of the quoted prices is not a good proxy for the true value. Further, transaction costs paid by market order submitters are negative on average, and negatively correlated with the effective spread. Reducing the tick size is not Pareto improving but increases total investor surplus.</description><author>Goettler, R. L.; Parlour, C. A.; Rajan, U.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitraging arbitrageurs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Attari, M.; Mello, A. S.; Ruckes, M. E.
This paper develops a theory of strategic trading in markets with large arbitrageurs. If arbitrageurs are not well capitalized, capital constraints make their trades predictable. Other market participants can exploit this by trading against them. Competitors may find it optimal to lend to arbitrageurs that are financially fragile; additional capital makes the arbitrageurs more viable, and lenders can reap profits from trading against them for a longer time. The strategic behavior of these market participants has implications for the functioning of financial markets. Strategic trading may produce significant price distortions, increase price manipulation, and trigger forced liquidations of large traders.</description><author>Attari, M.; Mello, A. S.; Ruckes, M. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wanna dance ? How firms and underwriters choose each other</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernando, C. S.; Gatchev, V. A.; Spindt, P. A.
We develop and test a theory explaining the equilibrium matching of issuers and underwriters. We assume that issuers and underwriters associate by mutual choice, and that underwriter ability and issuer quality are complementary. Our model implies that matching is positive assortative, and that matches are based on firms' and underwriters' relative characteristics at the time of issuance. The model predicts that the market share of top underwriters and their average issue quality varies inversely with issuance volume. Various cross-sectional patterns in underwriting spreads are consistent with equilibrium matching. We find strong empirical confirmation of our theory.</description><author>Fernando, C. S.; Gatchev, V. A.; Spindt, P. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vested interest and biased price estimates: Evidence from an auction market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mei, J. P.; Moses, M.
This study employs a new data set from art auctions to examine the relationship between auctioneer presale price estimates and the long-term performance of artworks. We find that the price estimates for expensive paintings have a consistent upward bias over a long period of 30 years. High estimates at the time of purchase are associated with adverse subsequent abnormal returns. Moreover, the estimation error for individual paintings tends to persist over time. These results are consistent with the view that auction house price estimates are affected by agency problems and that some investors are credulous.</description><author>Mei, J. P.; Moses, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Methods of payment in asset sales: Contracting with equity versus cash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Slovin, M. B.; Sushka, M. E.; Polonchek, J. A.
We analyze intercorporate asset sales where equity is the means of payment, and compare the results to cash asset sales. Equity deals are value-enhancing for both buyers, 10%, and sellers, 3%, while cash sales generate seller returns of 1.9% and buyer returns that are not significant. Combined wealth gains are large for equity deals, but modest for cash deals. Equity-based asset sales are not a precursor to consolidations between buyers and sellers, and do not affect buyer openness to the takeover market. We conclude that the use of buyer equity conveys favorable information about the value of assets and buyers.</description><author>Slovin, M. B.; Sushka, M. E.; Polonchek, J. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trends in corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hermalin, B. E.
The popular press and scholarly studies have noted a number of trends in corporate governance. This article addresses, from a theoretical perspective, whether these trends are linked. And, if so, how ? The article finds that a trend toward greater board diligence will lead, sometimes through subtle or indirect mechanisms, to trends toward more external candidates becoming CEO, shorter tenures for CEOs, more effort/less perquisite consumption by CEOs (even though such behavior is not directly monitored), and greater CEO compensation. An additional prediction is that, under plausible conditions, externally hired CEOs should have shorter tenures, on average, than internally hired CEOs.</description><author>Hermalin, B. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial stock ownership and the maturity structure of corporate debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Datta, S.; Iskandar-Datta, M.; Raman, K.
This study documents that managerial stock ownership plays an important role in determining corporate debt maturity. Controlling for previously identified determinants of debt maturity and modeling leverage and debt maturity as jointly endogenous, we document a significant and robust inverse relation between managerial stock ownership and corporate debt maturity. We also show that managerial stock ownership influences the relation between credit quality and debt maturity and between growth opportunities and debt maturity.</description><author>Datta, S.; Iskandar-Datta, M.; Raman, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic convenience yield implied from commodity futures and interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casassus, J.; Collin-Dufresne, P.
We characterize a three-factor model of commodity spot prices, convenience yields, and interest rates, which nests many existing specifications. The model allows convenience yields to depend on spot prices and interest rates. It also allows for time-varying risk premia. Both may induce mean reversion in spot prices, albeit with very different economic implications. Empirical results show strong evidence for spot-price level dependence in convenience yields for crude oil and copper, which implies mean reversion in prices under the risk-neutral measure. Silver, gold, and copper exhibit time variation in risk premia that implies mean reversion of prices under the physical measure.</description><author>Casassus, J.; Collin-Dufresne, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical analysis of the dynamic relation between investment-grade bonds and credit default swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blanco, R.; Brennan, S.; Marsh, I. W.
We test the theoretical equivalence of credit default swap (CDS) prices and credit spreads derived by Duffie (1999), finding support for the parity relation as an equilibrium condition. We also find two forms of deviation from parity. First, for three firms, CDS prices are substantially higher than credit spreads for long periods of time, arising from combinations of imperfections in the contract specification of CDSs and measurement errors in computing the credit spread. Second, we find short-lived deviations from parity for all other companies due to a lead for CDS prices over credit spreads in the price discovery process.</description><author>Blanco, R.; Brennan, S.; Marsh, I. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate yield spreads: Default risk or liquidity ? New evidence from the credit default swap market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, F. A.; Mithal, S.; Neis, E.
We use the information in credit default swaps to obtain direct measures of the size of the default and nondefault components in corporate spreads. We find that the majority of the corporate spread is due to default risk. This result holds for all rating categories and is robust to the definition of the riskless curve. We also find that the nondefault component is time varying and strongly related to measures of bond-specific illiquidity as well as to macroeconomic measures of bond market liquidity.</description><author>Longstaff, F. A.; Mithal, S.; Neis, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The optimal concentration of creditors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bris, A.; Welch, I.
Our model assumes that creditors need to expend resources to collect on claims. Consequently, because diffuse creditors suffer from mutual free-riding (Holmstrom (1982)), they fare worse than concentrated creditors (e. g., a house bank). The model predicts that measures of debt concentration relate positively to creditors' (aggregate) debt collection expenditures and positively to management's chosen expenditures to resist paying. However, collection activity is purely redistributive, so social waste is larger when creditors are concentrated. If borrower quality is not known, the best firms choose the most concentrated creditors and pay higher expected yields.</description><author>Bris, A.; Welch, I.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market impact of trends and sequences in performance: New evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durham, G. R.; Hertzel, M. G.; Martin, J. S.
Bloomfield and Hales (2002) find strong evidence that experimental market subjects are influenced by trends and patterns in a manner supportive of the shifting regimes model of Barberis, Shleifer, and Vishny (1998). We subject the model to further empirical scrutiny using the football wagering market as our price laboratory. Sports betting markets have several advantages over traditional capital markets as an empirical setting, and commonalities with traditional markets allow for useful insights. We find scant evidence that investors behave in accordance with the model.</description><author>Durham, G. R.; Hertzel, M. G.; Martin, J. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information and control in ventures and alliances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dessein, W.
This paper develops a theory of control as a signal of congruence of objectives, and applies it to financial contracting between an investor and a privately informed entrepreneur. We show that formal investor control is (i) increasing in the information asymmetries ex ante, (ii) increasing in the uncertainty surrounding the venture ex post, (iii) decreasing in the entrepreneur's resources, and (iv) increasing in the entrepreneur's incentive conflict. In contrast, real investor control-that is, actual investor interference-is decreasing in information asymmetries. Control rights are further such that control shifts to the investor in bad states of nature.</description><author>Dessein, W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade generation, reputation, and sell-side analysts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jackson, A. R.
This paper examines the trade-generation and reputation-building incentives facing sell-side analysts. Using a unique data set I demonstrate that optimistic analysts generate more trade for their brokerage firms, as do high reputation analysts. I also find that accurate analysts generate higher reputations. The analyst therefore faces a conflict between telling the truth to build her reputation versus misleading investors via optimistic forecasts to generate short-term increases in trading commissions. In equilibrium I show forecast optimism can exist, even when investment-banking affiliations are removed. The conclusions may have important policy implications given recent changes in the institutional structure of the brokerage industry.</description><author>Jackson, A. R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging or market timing? Selecting the interest rate exposure of corporate debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faulkender, M.
This paper examines whether firms are hedging or timing the market when selecting the interest rate exposure of their new debt issuances. I use a more accurate measure of the interest rate exposure chosen by firms by combining the initial exposure of newly issued debt securities with their use of interest rate swaps. The results indicate that the final interest rate exposure is largely driven by the slope of the yield curve at the time the debt is issued. These results suggest that interest rate risk management practices are primarily driven by speculation or myopia, not hedging considerations.</description><author>Faulkender, M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does idiosyncratic risk really matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, T. G.; Cakici, N.; Yan, X. M.; Zhang, Z.
Goyal and Santa-Clara (2003) find a significantly positive relation between the equal-weighted average stock volatility and the value-weighted portfolio returns on the NYSE/AMEX/Nasdaq stocks for the period of 1963:08 to 1999:12. We show that this result is driven by small stocks traded on the Nasdaq, and is in part due to a liquidity premium. In addition, their result does not hold for the extended sample of 1963:08 to 2001:12 and for the NYSE/AMEX and NYSE stocks. More importantly, we find no evidence of a significant link between the value-weighted portfolio returns and the median and value-weighted average stock volatility.</description><author>Bali, T. G.; Cakici, N.; Yan, X. M.; Zhang, Z.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal life-cycle asset allocation: Understanding the empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomes, F.; Michaelides, A.
We show that a life-cycle model with realistically calibrated uninsurable labor income risk and moderate risk aversion can simultaneously match stock market participation rates and asset allocation decisions conditional on participation. The key ingredients of the model are Epstein-Zin preferences, a fixed stock market entry cost, and moderate heterogeneity in risk aversion. Households with low risk aversion smooth earnings shocks with a small buffer stock of assets, and consequently most of them (optimally) never invest in equities. Therefore, the marginal stockholders are (endogenously) more risk averse, and as a result they do not invest their portfolios fully in stocks.</description><author>Gomes, F.; Michaelides, A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managers, workers, and corporate control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pagano, M.; Volpin, P. F.
If management has high private benefits and a small equity stake, managers and workers are natural allies against takeover threats. Two forces are at play. First, managers can transform employees into a "shark repellent" through long-term labor contracts and thereby reduce the firm's attractiveness to raiders. Second, employees can act as "white squires" for the incumbent managers. To protect their high wages, they resist hostile takeovers by refusing to sell their shares to the raider or by lobbying against the takeover. The model predicts that wages are inversely correlated with the managerial equity stake, and decline after takeovers.</description><author>Pagano, M.; Volpin, P. F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do domestic investors have an information advantage? Evidence from Indonesia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dvorak, T.
Using transaction data from Indonesia, this paper shows that domestic investors have higher profits than foreign investors. In addition, clients of global brokerages have higher long-term and smaller medium (intramonth) and short (intraday) term profits than clients of local brokerages. This suggests that clients of local brokerages have a short-lived information advantage, but that clients of global brokerages are better at picking long-term winners. Finally, domestic clients of global brokerages have higher profits than foreign clients of global brokerages, suggesting that the combination of local information and global expertise leads to higher profits.</description><author>Dvorak, T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lifting the veil: An analysis of pre-trade transparency at the NYSE</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, E.; Saar, G.; Yu, L.
We study pre-trade transparency by looking at the introduction of NYSE's OpenBook service that provides limit-order book information to traders off the exchange floor. We find that traders attempt to manage limit-order exposure: They submit smaller orders and cancel orders faster. Specialists' participation rate and the depth they add to the quote decline. Liquidity increases in that the price impact of orders declines, and we find some improvement in the informational efficiency of prices. These results suggest that an increase in pre-trade transparency affects investors' trading strategies and can improve certain dimensions of market quality.</description><author>Boehmer, E.; Saar, G.; Yu, L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wealth destruction on a massive scale? A study of acquiring-firm returns in the recent merger wave</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moeller, S. B.; Schlingemann, F. P.; Stulz, R. M.
Acquiring-firm shareholders lost 12 cents around acquisition announcements per dollar spent on acquisitions for a total loss of $240 billion from 1998 through 2001, whereas they lost $7 billion in all of the 1980s, or 1.6 cents per dollar spent. The 1998 to 2001 aggregate dollar loss of acquiring-firm shareholders is so large because of a small number of acquisitions with negative synergy gains by firms with extremely high valuations. Without these acquisitions, the wealth of acquiring-firm shareholders would have increased. Firms that make these acquisitions with large dollar losses perform poorly afterward.</description><author>Moeller, S. B.; Schlingemann, F. P.; Stulz, R. M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The geography of equity analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malloy, C. J.
I provide evidence that geographically proximate analysts are more accurate than other analysts. Stock returns immediately surrounding forecast revisions suggest that local analysts impact prices more than other analysts. These effects are strongest for firms located in small cities and remote areas. Collectively these results suggest that geographically proximate analysts possess an information advantage over other analysts, and that this advantage translates into better performance. The well-documented underwriter affiliation bias in stock recommendations is concentrated among distant affiliated analysts; recommendations by local affiliated analysts are unbiased. This finding reveals a geographic component to the agency problems in the industry.</description><author>Malloy, C. J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The stock market's reaction to unemployment news: Why bad news is usually good for stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyd, J. H.; Hu, J.; Jagannathan, R.
We find that on average, an announcement of rising unemployment is good news for stocks during economic expansions and bad news during economic contractions. Unemployment news bundles three types of primitive information relevant for valuing stocks: information about future interest rates, the equity risk premium, and corporate earnings and dividends. The nature of the information bundle, and hence the relative importance of the three effects, changes over time depending on the state of the economy. For stocks as a group, information about interest rates dominates during expansions and information about future corporate dividends dominates during contractions.</description><author>Boyd, J. H.; Hu, J.; Jagannathan, R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity shortages and banking crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diamond, D. W.; Rajan, R. G.
We show in this article that bank failures can be contagious. Unlike earlier work where contagion stems from depositor panics or contractual links between banks, we argue that bank failures can shrink the common pool of liquidity, creating, or exacerbating aggregate liquidity shortages. This could lead to a contagion of failures and a total meltdown of the system. Given the costs of a meltdown, there is a possible role for government intervention. Unfortunately, liquidity and solvency problems interact and can cause each other, making it hard to determine the cause of a crisis. We propose a robust sequence of intervention.</description><author>Diamond, D. W.; Rajan, R. G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial spawning: Public corporations and the genesis of new ventures, 1986 to 1999</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gompers, P.; Lerner, J.; Scharfstein, D.
We examine two views of the creation of venture-backed start-ups, or "entrepreneurial spawning." In one, young firms prepare employees for entrepreneurship, educating them about the process, and exposing them to relevant networks. In the other, individuals become entrepreneurs when large bureaucratic employers do not fund their ideas. Controlling for firm size, patents, and industry, the most prolific spawners are originally venture-backed companies located in Silicon Valley and Massachusetts. Undiversified firms spawn more firms. Silicon Valley, Massachusetts, and originally venture-backed firms typically spawn firms only peripherally related to their core businesses. Overall, entrepreneurial learning and networks appear important in creating venture-backed firms.</description><author>Gompers, P.; Lerner, J.; Scharfstein, D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing agency theory with entrepreneur effort and wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bitler, M. P.; Moskowitz, T. J.; Vissing-Jorgensen, A.
We develop a principal-agent model in an entrepreneurial setting and test the model's predictions using unique data on entrepreneurial effort and wealth in privately held firms. Accounting for unobserved firm heterogeneity using instrumental-variables techniques, we find that entrepreneurial ownership shares increase with outside wealth and decrease with firm risk; effort increases with ownership; and effort increases firm performance. The magnitude of the effects in the cross-section of firms suggests that agency costs may help explain why entrepreneurs concentrate large fractions of their wealth in firm equity.</description><author>Bitler, M. P.; Moskowitz, T. J.; Vissing-Jorgensen, A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can managers forecast aggregate market returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, A. W.; Grullon, G.; Weston, J. P.
Previous studies have found that the proportion of equity in total new debt and equity issues is negatively correlated with future equity market returns. Researchers have interpreted this finding as evidence that corporate managers are able to predict the systematic component of their stock returns and to issue equity when the market is overvalued. In this article we show that the predictive power of the share of equity in total new issues stems from pseudo-market timing and not from any abnormal ability of managers to time the equity markets.</description><author>Butler, A. W.; Grullon, G.; Weston, J. P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Partial privatization and firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, N.
Most privatization programs begin with a period of partial privatization in which only non-controlling shares of firms are sold on the stock market. Since management control is not transferred to private owners it is widely contended that partial privatization has little impact. This perspective ignores the role that the stock market can play in monitoring and rewarding managerial performance even when the government remains the controlling owner. Using data on Indian state-owned enterprises we find that partial privatization has a positive impact on profitability, productivity, and investment.</description><author>Gupta, N.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is debt relief efficient?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arslanalp, S.; Henry, P. B.
When developing countries announce debt relief agreements under the Brady Plan, their stock markets appreciate by an average of 60% in real dollar terms-a $42 billion increase in shareholder value. There is no significant stock market increase for a control group of countries that do not sign Brady agreements. The stock market appreciations successfully forecast higher future resource transfers, investment, and growth. Since the market capitalization of U.S. commercial banks with developing country loan exposure also rises-by $13 billion-the results suggest that both borrower and lenders can benefit from debt relief when the borrower suffers from debt overhang.</description><author>Arslanalp, S.; Henry, P. B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do behavioral biases affect prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coval, J. D.; Shumway, T.
This paper documents strong evidence for behavioral biases among Chicago Board of Trade proprietary traders and investigates the effect these biases have on prices. Our traders appear highly loss-averse, regularly assuming above-average afternoon risk to recover from morning losses. This behavior has important short-term consequences for afternoon prices, as losing traders actively purchase contracts at higher prices and sell contracts at lower prices than those that prevailed previously. However, the market appears to distinguish these risk-seeking trades from informed trading. Prices set by loss-averse traders are reversed significantly more quickly than those set by unbiased traders.</description><author>Coval, J. D.; Shumway, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider trading restrictions and analysts' incentives to follow firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bushman, R. M.; Piotroski, J. D.; Smith, A. J.
Motivated by extant finance theory predicting that insider trading crowds out private information acquisition by outsiders, we use data for 100 countries for the years 1987-2000 to study whether analyst following in a country increases following restriction of insider trading activities. We document that analyst following increases after initial enforcement of insider trading laws. This increase is concentrated in emerging market countries, but is smaller if the country has previously liberalized its capital market. We also find that analyst following responds less intensely to initial enforcement when a country has a preexisting portfolio of strong investor protections.</description><author>Bushman, R. M.; Piotroski, J. D.; Smith, A. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do professional traders exhibit myopic loss aversion? An experimental analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haigh, M. S.; List, J. A.
Two behavioral concepts, loss aversion and mental accounting, have been combined to provide a theoretical explanation of the equity premium puzzle. Recent experimental evidence supports the theory, as students' behavior has been found to be consistent with myopic loss aversion (MLA). Yet, much like certain anomalies in the realm of riskless decision-making, these behavioral tendencies may be attenuated among professionals. Using traders recruited from the CBOT, we do indeed find behavioral differences between professionals and students, but rather than discovering that the anomaly is muted, we find that traders exhibit behavior consistent with MLA to a greater extent than students.</description><author>Haigh, M. S.; List, J. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO pricing in "hot" market conditions: Who leaves money on the table?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Derrien, F.
This paper explores the impact of investor sentiment on IPO pricing. Using a model in which the aftermarket price of IPO shares depends on the information about the intrinsic value of the company and investor sentiment, I show that IPOs can be overpriced and still exhibit positive initial return. A sample of recent French offerings with a fraction of the shares reserved for individual investors supports the predictions of the model. Individual investors' demand is positively related to market conditions. Moreover, large individual investors' demand leads to high IPO prices, large initial returns, and poor long-run performance.</description><author>Derrien, F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of IPO underwriting syndicates: Pricing, information production, and underwriter competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corwin, S. A.; Schultz, P.
We examine syndicates for 1,638 IPOs from January 1997 through June 2002. We find strong evidence of information production by syndicate members. Offer prices are more likely to be revised in response to information when the syndicate has more underwriters and especially more co-managers. More co-managers also result in more analyst coverage and additional market makers following the IPO. Relationships between underwriters are critical in determining the composition of syndicates, perhaps because they mitigate free-riding and moral hazard problems. While there appear to be benefits to larger syndicates, we discuss several factors that may limit syndicate size.</description><author>Corwin, S. A.; Schultz, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading volume, information asymmetry, and timing information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chae, J.
This paper investigates trading volume before scheduled and unscheduled corporate announcements to explore how traders respond to private information. I show that cumulative trading volume decreases inversely to information asymmetry prior to scheduled announcements, while the opposite relation holds for volume after the announcement. In contrast, trading volume before unscheduled announcements increases dramatically and shows little relation to proxies for information asymmetry I investigate the behavior of market makers and find that they act appropriately by increasing price sensitivity before all announcements, implying that they extract timing information from their order books.</description><author>Chae, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric price movements and borrowing constraints: A rational expectations equilibrium model of crises, contagion, and confusion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yuan, K.
This study proposes a rational expectations equilibrium model of crises and contagion in an economy with information asymmetry and borrowing constraints. Consistent with empirical observations, the model finds: (1) Crises can be caused by small shocks to fundamentals; (2) market return distributions are asymmetric; and (3) correlations among asset returns tend to increase during crashes. The model also predicts: (1) Crises and contagion are likely to occur after small shocks in the intermediate price region; (2) the skewness of asset price distributions increases with information asymmetry and borrowing constraints; and (3) crises can spread through investor borrowing constraints.</description><author>Yuan, K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring and controlling bank risk: Does risky debt help?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnan, C. N. V.; Ritchken, P. H.; Thomson, J. B.
We examine whether mandating banks to issue subordinated debt would enhance market monitoring and control risk taking. To evaluate whether subordinated debt enhances risk monitoring, we extract the credit-spread curve for each banking firm in our sample and examine whether changes in credit spreads reflect changes in bank risk variables, after controlling for changes in market and liquidity variables. We do not find strong and consistent evidence that they do. To evaluate whether subordinated debt controls risk taking, we examine whether the first issue of subordinated debt changes the risk-taking behavior of a bank. We find that it does not.</description><author>Krishnan, C. N. V.; Ritchken, P. H.; Thomson, J. B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial analyst characteristics and herding behavior in forecasting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clement, M. B.; Tse, S. Y.
This study classifies analysts' earnings forecasts as herding or bold and finds that (1) boldness likelihood increases with the analyst's prior accuracy, brokerage size, and experience and declines with the number of industries the analyst follows, consistent with theory linking boldness with career concerns and ability; (2) bold forecasts are more accurate than herding forecasts; and (3) herding forecast revisions are more strongly associated with analysts' earnings forecast errors (actual earnings-forecast) than are bold forecast revisions. Thus, bold forecasts incorporate analysts' private information more completely and provide more relevant information to investors than herding forecasts.</description><author>Clement, M. B.; Tse, S. Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local does as local is: Information content of the geography of individual investors' common stock investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivkovic, Z.; Weisbenner, S.
Using data on the investments a large number of individual investors made through a discount broker from 1991 to 1996, we find that households exhibit a strong preference for local investments. We test whether this locality bias stems from information or from simple familiarity. The average household generates an additional annualized return of 3.2% from its local holdings relative to its nonlocal holdings, suggesting that local investors can exploit local knowledge. Excess returns to investing locally are even larger among stocks not in the S&amp;P 500 index (firms for which information asymmetries between local and nonlocal investors may be largest).</description><author>Ivkovic, Z.; Weisbenner, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distance, lending relationships, and competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degryse, H.; Ongena, S.
We study the effect on loan conditions of geographical distance between firms, the lending bank, and all other banks in the vicinity. For our study, we employ detailed contract information from more than 15,000 bank loans to small firms comprising the entire loan portfolio of a large Belgian bank. We report the first comprehensive evidence on the occurrence of spatial price discrimination in bank lending. Loan rates decrease with the distance between the firm and the lending bank and increase with the distance between the firm and competing banks. Transportation costs cause the spatial price discrimination we observe.</description><author>Degryse, H.; Ongena, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the failure of the expectations hypothesis matter for long-term investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sangvinatsos, A.; Wachter, J. A.
We solve the portfolio problem of a long-run investor when the term structure is Gaussian and when the investor has access to nominal bonds and stock. We apply our method to a three-factor model that captures the failure of the expectations hypothesis. We extend this model to account for time-varying expected inflation, and estimate the model with both inflation and term structure data. The estimates imply that the bond portfolio of a long-run investor looks very different from the portfolio of a mean-variance optimizer. In particular, time-varying term premia generate large hedging demands for long-term bonds.</description><author>Sangvinatsos, A.; Wachter, J. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial and legal constraints to growth: Does, firm size matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, T.; Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Maksimovic, V.
Using a unique firm-level survey database covering 54 countries, we investigate the effect of financial, legal, and corruption problems on firms' growth rates. Whether these factors constrain growth depends on firm size. It is consistently the smallest firms that are most constrained. Financial and institutional development weakens the constraining effects of financial, legal, and corruption obstacles and it is again the small firms that benefit the most. There is only a weak relation between firms' perception of the quality of the courts in their country and firm growth. We also provide evidence that the corruption of bank officials constrains firm growth.</description><author>Beck, T.; Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Maksimovic, V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset sales, investment opportunities, and the use of proceeds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, T. W.
This study examines the allocation of cash proceeds following 400 subsidiary sales between 1990 and 1998. Retention probabilities are increasing in the divesting firm's contemporaneous growth opportunities and expected investment. Retaining firms, however, also systematically overinvest relative to an industry benchmark. Shareholder returns to retention decisions are positively correlated with growth opportunities and benchmarked investment, but negatively correlated with benchmarked investment for firms with poor growth opportunities. Shareholder returns to debt distributions are increasing in industry-benchmarked leverage. Overall, the results of this study cohere with the hypothesized trade-off between the investment efficiencies associated with retained proceeds and the agency costs of managerial discretion and debt.</description><author>Bates, T. W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, L.
The value anomaly arises naturally in the neoclassical framework with rational expectations. Costly reversibility and countercyclical price of risk cause assets in place to be harder to reduce, and hence are riskier than growth options especially in bad times when the price of risk is high. By linking risk and expected returns to economic primitives, such as tastes and technology, my model generates many empirical regularities in the cross-section of returns; it also yields an array of new refutable hypotheses providing fresh directions for future empirical research.</description><author>Zhang, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comparison of centralized and fragmented markets with costly search</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yin, X. K.
How does quotation transparency affect financial market performance? Biais's irrelevance proposition in 1993 shows that centralized markets yield the same expected bid-ask spreads as fragmented markets, other things equal. However, de Frutos and Manzano demonstrated in 2002 that expected spreads in fragmented markets are smaller and market participants prefer to trade in fragmented markets. This paper introduces liquidity traders' costs of searching for a better quote into the Biais model and derives opposite conclusions to these previous studies: expected spreads in centralized markets are smaller and liquidity traders prefer centralized markets, while market makers prefer fragmented markets.</description><author>Yin, X. K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency returns, intrinsic value, and institutional-investor flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Froot, K. A.; Ramadorai, T.
We decompose currency returns into (permanent) intrinsic-value shocks and (transitory) expected-return shocks. We explore interactions between these shocks, currency returns, and institutional-investor currency flows. Intrinsic-value shocks are: dwarfed by expected-return shocks (yet currency returns overreact to them); unrelated to flows (although expected-return shocks correlate with flows); and related positively to forecasted cumulated-interest differentials. These results suggest flows are related to short-term currency returns, while fundamentals better explain long-term returns and values. They also rationalize the long-observed poor performance of exchange-rate models: by ignoring the distinction between permanent and transitory exchange-rate changes, prior tests obscure the connection between currencies and fundamentals.</description><author>Froot, K. A.; Ramadorai, T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What determines the domestic bias and foreign bias? Evidence from mutual fund equity allocations worldwide</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, K.; Covrig, V.; Ng, L.
We examine how mutual funds from 26 developed and developing countries allocate their investment between domestic and foreign equity markets and what factors determine their asset allocations worldwide. We find robust evidence that these funds, in aggregate, allocate a disproportionately larger fraction of investment to domestic stocks. Results indicate that the stock market development and familiarity variables have significant, but asymmetric, effects on the domestic bias (domestic investors overweighting the local markets) and foreign bias (foreign investors under or overweighting the overseas markets), and that economic development, capital controls, and withholding tax variables have significant effects only on the foreign bias.</description><author>Chan, K.; Covrig, V.; Ng, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>To steal or not to steal: Firm attributes, legal environment, and valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durnev, A.; Kim, E. H.
Data on corporate governance and disclosure practices reveal wide within-country variation that decreases with the strength of investors' legal protection. A simple model identifies three firm attributes related to that variation: investment opportunities, external financing, and ownership structure. Using firm-level governance and transparency data from 27 countries, we find that all three firm attributes are related to the quality of governance and disclosure practices, and firms with higher governance and transparency rankings are valued higher in stock markets. All relations are stronger in less investor-friendly countries, demonstrating that firms adapt to poor legal environments to establish efficient governance practices.</description><author>Durnev, A.; Kim, E. H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are firms underleveraged? An examination of the effect of leverage on default probabilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Molina, C. A.
A commonly held view in corporate finance is that firms are less leveraged than they should be, given the potentially large tax benefits of debt. In this paper, I study the effect of firms' leverage on default probabilities as represented by the firms' ratings. Using an instrumental variable approach, I find that the leverage's effect on ratings is three times stronger than it is if the endogeneity of leverage is ignored. This stronger effect results in a higher impact of leverage on the ex ante costs of financial distress, which can offset the current estimates of the tax benefits of debt.</description><author>Molina, C. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional holdings and payout policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinstein, Y.; Michaely, R.
We examine the relation between institutional holdings and payout policy in U.S. public firms. We find that payout policy affects institutional holdings. Institutions avoid firms that do not pay dividends. However, among dividend-paying firms they prefer firms that pay fewer dividends. Our evidence indicates that institutions prefer firms that repurchase shares, and regular repurchasers over nonregular repurchasers. Higher institutional holdings or a concentration of holdings do not cause firms to increase their dividends, their repurchases, or their total payout. Our results do not support models that predict that high dividends attract institutional clientele, or models that predict that institutions cause firms to increase payout.</description><author>Grinstein, Y.; Michaely, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The choice of payment method in European mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faccio, M.; Masulis, R. W.
We study merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) payment choices of European bidders for publicly and privately held targets in the 1997-2000 period. Europe is an ideal venue for studying the importance of corporate governance in making M&amp;A payment choices, given the large number of closely held firms and the wide range of capital markets, institutional settings, laws, and regulations. The tradeoff between corporate governance concerns and debt financing constraints is found to have a large bearing on the bidder's payment choice. Consistent with earlier evidence, we find that several deal and target characteristics significantly affect the method of payment choice.</description><author>Faccio, M.; Masulis, R. W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The theory of bank risk taking and competition revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyd, J. H.; De Nicolo, G.
There is a large body of literature that concludes that-when confronted with increased competition-banks rationally choose more risky portfolios. We argue that this literature has had a significant influence on regulators and central bankers. We review the empirical literature and conclude that the evidence is best described as, "mixed." We then show that existing theoretical analyses of this topic are fragile, since there exist fundamental risk-incentive mechanisms that operate in exactly the opposite direction, causing banks to become more risky as their markets become more concentrated. These mechanisms should be essential ingredients of models of bank competition.</description><author>Boyd, J. H.; De Nicolo, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demand-deposit contracts and the probability of bank runs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, I.; Pauzner, A.
Diamond and Dybvig (1983) show that while demand-deposit contracts let banks provide liquidity, they expose them to panic-based bank runs. However, their model does not provide tools to derive the probability of the bank-run equilibrium, and thus cannot determine whether banks increase welfare overall. We study a modified model in which the fundamentals determine which equilibrium occurs. This lets us compute the ex ante probability of panic-based bank runs and relate it to the contract. We find conditions under which banks increase welfare overall and construct a demand-deposit contract that trades off the benefits from liquidity against the costs of runs.</description><author>Goldstein, I.; Pauzner, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do bank relationships affect the firm's underwriter choice in the corporate-bond underwriting market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yasuda, A.
This paper studies the effect of bank relationships on underwriter choice in the US. corporate-bond underwriting market following the 1989 commercial-bank entry. I find that bank relationships have positive and significant effects on a firm's underwriter choice, over and above their effects on fees. This result is sharply stronger for junk-bond issuers and first-time issuers. I also find that there is a significant fee discount when there are relationships between firms and commercial banks. Finally, I find that serving as arranger of past loan transactions has the strongest effect on underwriter choice, whereas serving merely as participant has no effect.</description><author>Yasuda, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What explains the stock market's reaction to Federal Reserve Policy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernanke, B. S.; Kuttner, K. N.
This paper analyzes the impact of changes in monetary policy on equity prices, with the objectives of both measuring the average reaction of the stock market and understanding the economic sources of that reaction. We find that, on average, a hypothetical unanticipated 25-basis-point cut in the Federal funds rate target is associated with about a 1% increase in broad stock indexes. Adapting a methodology due to Campbell and Ammer, we find that the effects of unanticipated monetary policy actions on expected excess returns account for the largest part of the response of stock prices.</description><author>Bernanke, B. S.; Kuttner, K. N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing collateral, consumption insurance, and risk premia: An empirical perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lustig, H. N.; Van Nieuwerburgh, S. G.
In a model with housing collateral, the ratio of housing wealth to human wealth shifts the conditional distribution of asset prices and consumption growth. A decrease in house prices reduces the collateral value of housing, increases household exposure to idiosyncratic risk, and increases the conditional market price of risk. Using aggregate data for the United States, we find that a decrease in the ratio of housing wealth to human wealth predicts higher returns on stocks. Conditional on this ratio, the covariance of returns with aggregate risk factors explains 80% of the cross-sectional variation in annual size and book-to-market portfolio returns.</description><author>Lustig, H. N.; Van Nieuwerburgh, S. G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hennessy, C. A.; Whited, T. M.
We develop a dynamic trade-off model with endogenous choice of leverage, distributions, and real investment in the presence of a graduated corporate income tax, individual taxes on interest and corporate distributions, financial distress costs, and equity flotation costs. We explain several empirical findings inconsistent with the static trade-off theory. We show there is no target leverage ratio, firms can be savers or heavily levered, leverage is path dependent, leverage is decreasing in lagged liquidity, and leverage varies negatively with an external finance weighted average Q. Using estimates of structural parameters, we find that simulated model moments match data moments.</description><author>Hennessy, C. A.; Whited, T. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and the business cycle: International, inter-industry evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Braun, M.; Larrain, B.
By considering yearly production growth rates for several manufacturing industries in more than 100 countries during (roughly) the last 40 years, we show that industries that are more dependent on external finance are hit harder during recessions. The observed difference in the behavior of industries is larger when financial frictions are thought to be more prevalent, linking the result directly to the financial mechanism hypothesis. In particular, more dependent industries are more strongly affected in recessions when they are located in countries with poor financial contractibility, and when their assets are softer or less protective of financiers.</description><author>Braun, M.; Larrain, B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Judging fund managers by the company they keep</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, R. B.; Coval, J. D.; Pastor, L.
We develop a performance evaluation approach in which a fund manager's skill is judged by the extent to which the manager's investment decisions resemble the decisions of managers with distinguished performance records. The proposed performance measures use historical returns and holdings of many funds to evaluate the performance of a single fund. Simulations demonstrate that our measures are particularly useful in ranking managers. In an application that relies on such ranking, our measures reveal strong predictability in the returns of U.S. equity funds. Our measures provide information about future fund returns that is not contained in the standard measures.</description><author>Cohen, R. B.; Coval, J. D.; Pastor, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board seat accumulation by executives: A shareholder's perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perry, T.; Peyer, U.
While reformers have argued that multiple directorships for executives can destroy value, we investigate firms with executives that accept an outside directorship and find negative announcement returns only when the executive's firm has greater agency problems. When fewer agency concerns exist, additional directorships relate to increased firm value. Announcement returns are also higher when executives accept an outside directorship in a financial, high-growth, or related-industry firm. Our results suggest that outside directorships for executives can enhance firm value, which has important implications for firms employing executives nominated for outside boards and for policy recommendations restricting the number of directorships.</description><author>Perry, T.; Peyer, U.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial opportunism during corporate litigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haslem, B.
Using a large sample of litigation events involving publicly listed defendants, we document a surprising fact. The resolution of litigation through a court's decision dominates settlement of litigation from the shareholders' point of view, even when the firm loses. We develop a model using agency costs within the firm to explain why the market views settlement as a negative outcome on average and find empirical evidence supporting the implications of the model. Specifically, firms with weak corporate governance settle litigation more quickly, and the market reacts more negatively to settlements involving firms with higher agency costs.</description><author>Haslem, B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the industry concentration of actively managed equity mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kacperczyk, M.; Sialm, C.; Zheng, L.
Mutual fund managers may decide to deviate from a well-diversified portfolio and concentrate their holdings in industries where they have informational advantages. In this paper, we study the relation between the industry concentration and the performance of actively managed U.S. mutual funds from 1984 to 1999. Our results indicate that, on average, more concentrated funds perform better after controlling for risk and style differences using various performance measures. This finding suggests that investment ability is more evident among managers who hold portfolios concentrated in a few industries.</description><author>Kacperczyk, M.; Sialm, C.; Zheng, L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do insiders learn from outsiders? Evidence from mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luo, Y. Z.
I find that the market reaction to a merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) announcement predicts whether the companies later consummate the deal. The relation cannot be explained by the market's anticipation of the closing decision or its perception of the deal quality at the announcement. Merging companies appear to extract information from the market reaction and later consider it in closing the deal. Furthermore, the relation varies with deal characteristics, suggesting that companies seem to have a higher incentive to learn from the market when canceling the announced deal is easier or when the market has more information that the companies do not know.</description><author>Luo, Y. Z.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market timing and managerial portfolio decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jenter, D.
This paper provides evidence that top managers have contrarian views on firm value. Managers' perceptions of fundamental value diverge systematically from market valuations, and perceived mispricing seems an important determinant of managers' decision making. Insider trading patterns shows that low valuation firms are regarded as undervalued by their own managers relative to high valuation firms. This finding is robust to controlling for noninformation motivated trading. Further evidence links managers' private portfolio decisions to changes in corporate capital structures, suggesting that managers try to actively time the market both in their private trades and in firm-level decisions.</description><author>Jenter, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic behavior and underpricing in uniform price auctions: Evidence from Finnish Treasury auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keloharju, M.; Nyborg, K. G.; Rydqvist, K.
We contribute to the debate on the optimal design of multiunit auctions by developing and testing robust implications of the leading theory of uniform price auctions on the bid distributions submitted by individual bidders. The theory, which emphasizes market power, has little support in a data set of Finnish Treasury auctions. A reason may be that the Treasury acts strategically by determining supply after observing bids, apparently treating the auctions as a repeated game between itself and primary dealers. Bidder behavior and underpricing react to the volatility of bond returns in a way that suggests bidders adjust for the winner's curse.</description><author>Keloharju, M.; Nyborg, K. G.; Rydqvist, K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predatory trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunnermeier, M. K.; Pedersen, L. H.
This paper studies predatory trading, trading that induces and/or exploits the need of other investors to reduce their positions. We show that if one trader needs to sell, others also sell and subsequently buy back the asset. This leads to price overshooting and a reduced liquidation value for the distressed trader. Hence, the market is illiquid when liquidity is most needed. Further, a trader profits from triggering another trader's crisis, and the crisis can spill over across traders and across markets.</description><author>Brunnermeier, M. K.; Pedersen, L. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private equity performance: Returns, persistence, and capital flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplan, S. N.; Schoar, A.
This paper investigates the performance and capital inflows of private equity partnerships. Average fund returns (net of fees) approximately equal the S&amp;P 500 although substantial heterogeneity across funds exists. Returns persist strongly across subsequent funds of a partnership. Better performing partnerships are more likely to raise follow-on funds and larger funds. This relationship is concave, so top performing partnerships grow proportionally less than average performers. At the industry level, market entry and fund performance are procyclical; however, established funds are less sensitive to cycles than new entrants. Several of these results differ markedly from those for mutual funds.</description><author>Kaplan, S. N.; Schoar, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does prospect theory explain IPO market behavior ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ljungqvist, A.; Wilhelm, W. J.
We derive a behavioral measure of the IPO decision- maker's satisfaction with the underwriter's performance based on Loughran and Ritter (2002) and assess its ability to explain the decision- maker's choice among underwriters in subsequent securities offerings. Controlling for other known factors, IPO firms are less likely to switch underwriters when our behavioral measure indicates they were satisfied with the IPO underwriter's performance. Underwriters also extract higher fees for subsequent transactions involving satisfied decision- makers. Although our tests suggest that the behavioral model has explanatory power, they do not speak directly to whether deviations from expected utility maximization determine patterns in IPO initial returns.</description><author>Ljungqvist, A.; Wilhelm, W. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational IPO waves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, L.; Veronesi, P.
We argue that the number of firms going public changes over time in response to time variation in market conditions. We develop a model of optimal initial public offering (IPO) timing in which IPO waves are caused by declines in expected market return, increases in expected aggregate profitability, or increases in prior uncertainty about the average future profitability of IPOs. We test and find support for the model's empirical predictions. For example, we find that IPO waves tend to be preceded by high market returns and followed by low market returns.</description><author>Pastor, L.; Veronesi, P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time variation in the covariance between stock returns and consumption growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffee, G. R.
The conditional covariance between aggregate stock returns and aggregate consumption growth varies substantially over time. When stock market wealth is high relative to consumption, both the conditional covariance and correlation are high. This pattern is consistent with the "composition effect," where agents' consumption growth is more closely tied to stock returns when stock wealth is a larger share of total wealth. This variation can be used to test asset-pricing models in which the price of consumption risk varies. After accounting for variations in this price, the relation between expected excess stock returns and the conditional covariance is negative.</description><author>Duffee, G. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption, dividends, and the cross section of equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bansal, R.; Dittmar, R. F.; Lundblad, C. T.
We show that aggregate consumption risks embodied in cash flows can account for the puzzling differences in risk premia across book-to-market, momentum, and size-sorted portfolios. The dynamics of aggregate consumption and cash flow growth rates, modeled as a vector autoregression, are used to measure the consumption beta of discounted cash flows. Differences in these cash flow betas account for more than 60% of the cross-sectional variation in risk premia. The market price for risk in cash flows is highly significant. We argue that cash flow risk is important for interpreting differences in risk compensation across assets.</description><author>Bansal, R.; Dittmar, R. F.; Lundblad, C. T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The limits of financial globalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stulz, R. M.
Despite the dramatic reduction in explicit barriers to international investment activity over the last 60 years, the impact of financial globalization has been surprisingly limited. I argue that country attributes are still critical to financial decision- making because of "twin agency problems" that arise because rulers of sovereign states and corporate insiders pursue their own interests at the expense of outside investors. When these twin agency problems are significant, diffuse ownership is inefficient and corporate insiders must co-invest with other investors, retaining substantial equity. The resulting ownership concentration limits economic growth, financial development, and the ability of a country to take advantage of financial globalization.</description><author>Stulz, R. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of bank consolidation on commercial borrower welfare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karceski, J.; Ongena, S.; Smith, D. C.
We estimate the impact of bank merger announcements on borrowers' stock prices for publicly traded Norwegian firms. Borrowers of target banks lose about 0.8% in equity value, while borrowers of acquiring banks earn positive abnormal returns, suggesting that borrower welfare is influenced by a strategic focus favoring acquiring borrowers. Bank mergers lead to higher relationship exit rates among borrowers of target banks. Larger merger-induced increases in relationship termination rates are associated with less negative abnormal returns, suggesting that firms with low switching costs switch banks, while similar firms with high switching costs are locked into their current relationship.</description><author>Karceski, J.; Ongena, S.; Smith, D. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value-enhancing capital budgeting and firm-specific stock return variation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durnev, A.; Morck, R.; Yeung, B.
We document a robust cross-sectional positive association across industries between a measure of the economic efficiency of corporate investment and the magnitude of firm-specific variation in stock returns. This finding is interesting for two reasons, neither of which is a priori obvious. First, it adds further support to the view that firm-specific return variation gauges the extent to which information about the firm is quickly and accurately reflected in share prices. Second, it can be interpreted as evidence that more informative stock prices facilitate more efficient corporate investment.</description><author>Durnev, A.; Morck, R.; Yeung, B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond insurance: What is special about munis?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nanda, V.; Singh, R.
Close to 50% of municipal bonds are prepackaged with insurance at the time of issue. We offer a tax-based rationale for the emergence of third-party insurance of tax-exempt bonds. We argue that insurance adds value as it allows a third party to become, in a probabilistic sense, an issuer of tax-exempt securities. Insurance however reduces value by eliminating the possibility of a capital tax loss. While the net benefit from insurance increases with bond maturity, the benefit may not increase monotonically with default risk. We also provide empirical evidence supportive of the model's predictions.</description><author>Nanda, V.; Singh, R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic consumption risk and the cross section of asset returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, K.; Wang, K. Q.
This paper investigates the importance of idiosyncratic consumption risk for the cross-sectional variation in asset returns. We find that besides the rate of aggregate consumption growth, the cross-sectional variance of consumption growth is also a priced factor. This suggests that consumers are not fully insured against idiosyncratic consumption risk, and that asset returns reflect their attempts to reduce their exposure to this risk. The resulting two-factor consumption-based asset pricing model significantly outperforms the CAPM, and its performance compares favorably with that of the Fama-French three-factor model.</description><author>Jacobs, K.; Wang, K. Q.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Characteristics, contracts, and actions: Evidence from venture capitalist analyses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplan, S. N.; Stromberg, P.
We study the investment analyses of 67 portfolio investments by 11 venture capital (VC) firms. VCs describe the strengths and risks of the investments as well as expected postinvestment actions. We classify the risks into three categories and relate them to the allocation of cash flow rights, contingencies, control rights, and liquidation rights between VCs and entrepreneurs. The risk results suggest that agency and hold-up problems are important to contract design and monitoring, but that risk sharing is not. Greater VC control is associated with increased management intervention, while greater VC equity incentives are associated with increased value-added support.</description><author>Kaplan, S. N.; Stromberg, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The 52-week high and momentum investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>George, T. J.; Hwang, C. Y.
When coupled with a stock's current price, a readily available piece of information-the 52-week high price-explains a large portion of the profits from momentum investing. Nearness to the 52-week high dominates and improves upon the forecasting power of past returns (both individual and industry returns) for future returns. Future returns forecast using the 52-week high do not reverse in the long run. These results indicate that short-term momentum and long-term reversals are largely separate phenomena, which presents a challenge to current theory that models these aspects of security returns as integrated components of the market's response to news.</description><author>George, T. J.; Hwang, C. Y.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Correlated trading and location</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, L.; Seasholes, M. S.
This paper analyzes the trading behavior of stock market investors. Purchases and sales are highly correlated when we divide investors geographically. Investors who live near a firm's headquarters react in a similar manner to releases of public information. We are able to make this identification by exploiting a unique feature of individual brokerage accounts in the People's Republic of China. The data allow us to pinpoint an investor's location at the time he or she places a trade. Our results are consistent with a simple, rational expectations model of heterogeneously informed investors.</description><author>Feng, L.; Seasholes, M. S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend changes and the persistence of past earnings changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koch, A. S.; Sun, A. X.
We examine whether the market interprets changes in dividends as a signal about the persistence of past earnings changes. Prior to observing this signal, investors may believe that past earnings changes are not necessarily indicative of future earnings levels. We empirically investigate whether a change in dividends alters investors' assessments about the valuation implications of past earnings. Results confirm the hypothesis that changes in dividends cause investors to revise their expectations about the persistence of past earnings changes. This effect varies predictably with the magnitude of the dividend change and the sign of the past earnings change.</description><author>Koch, A. S.; Sun, A. X.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment-cash flow sensitivities: Constrained versus unconstrained firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moyen, N.
From the existing literature, it is not clear what effect financing constraints have on the sensitivities of firms' investment to their cash flow. I propose an explanation that reconciles the conflicting empirical evidence. I present two models: the unconstrained model, in which firms can raise external funds, and the constrained model, in which firms cannot do so. Using low dividends to identify financing constraints in my generated panel of data produces results consistent with those of Fazzari, Hubbard, and Petersen; using the constrained model produces results consistent with those of Kaplan and Zingales.</description><author>Moyen, N.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash and corporate control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faleye, O.
The takeover market is often suggested as appropriate for containing the agency problems of excessive corporate cash holdings. However, recent studies report contradictory evidence. I focus on the takeover-deterrence effects of corporate liquidity and suggest the proxy contest as an effective alternative control mechanism. I find that proxy fight targets hold 23% more cash than comparable firms, and that the probability of a contest is significantly increasing in excess cash holdings. Proxy fight announcement return also is positively related to excess cash. Following a contest, executive turnover and special cash distributions to shareholders increase, while cash holdings significantly decline.</description><author>Faleye, O.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge funds and the technology bubble</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunnermeier, M. K.; Nagel, S.
This paper documents that hedge funds did not exert a correcting force on stock prices during the technology bubble. Instead, they were heavily invested in technology stocks. This does not seem to be the result of unawareness of the bubble: Hedge funds captured the upturn, but, by reducing their positions in stocks that were about to decline, avoided much of the downturn. Our findings question the efficient markets notion that rational speculators always stabilize prices. They are consistent with models in which rational investors may prefer to ride bubbles because of predictable investor sentiment and limits to arbitrage.</description><author>Brunnermeier, M. K.; Nagel, S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictable investment horizons and wealth transfers among mutual fund shareholders\</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, W. T.
This study analyzes the distribution of investment horizons in a large, proprietary panel of all shareholders in one no-load mutual fund family. A proportional hazards model shows that there are observable shareholder characteristics that enable the fund to predict reliably on the day each account is opened whether the account will be short term or long term. Simulations show that the liquidity costs imposed on the fund by the expected short-term shareholders are significantly greater than those imposed by the expected long-term shareholders. Combining these results, the analysis argues that mutual funds do not provide equitable liquidity-risk insurance.</description><author>Johnson, W. T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecast dispersion and the cross section of expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, T. C.
Recent work by Diether, Malloy, and Scherbina (2002) has established a negative relationship between stock returns and the dispersion of analysts' earnings forecasts. I offer a simple explanation for this phenomenon based on the interpretation of dispersion as a proxy for unpriced information risk arising when asset values are unobservable. The relationship then follows from a general options-pricing result: For a levered firm, expected returns should always decrease with the level of idiosyncratic asset risk. This story is formalized with a straightforward model. Reasonable parameter values produce large effects, and the theory's main empirical prediction is supported in cross-sectional tests.</description><author>Johnson, T. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A multinational perspective on capital structure choice and internal capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, M. A.; Foley, C. F.; Hines, J. R.
This paper analyzes the capital structures of foreign affiliates and internal capital markets of multinational corporations. Ten percent higher local tax rates are associated with 2.8% higher debt/asset ratios, with internal borrowing being particularly sensitive to taxes. Multinational affiliates are financed with less external debt in countries with underdeveloped capital markets or weak creditor rights, reflecting significantly higher local borrowing costs. Instrumental variable analysis indicates that greater borrowing from parent companies substitutes for three-quarters of reduced external borrowing induced by capital market conditions. Multinational firms appear to employ internal capital markets opportunistically to overcome imperfections in external capital markets.</description><author>Desai, M. A.; Foley, C. F.; Hines, J. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank and nonbank financial intermediation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bond, P.
Conglomerates, trade credit arrangements, and banks are all instances of financial intermediation. However, these institutions differ significantly in the extent to which the projects financed absorb aggregate intermediary risk, in whether or not intermediation is carried out by a financial specialist, in the type of projects they fund and in the type of claims they issue to investors. The paper develops a simple unified model of that both accounts for the continued coexistence of these different forms of intermediation, and explains why they differ. Specific applications to conglomerate firms, trade credit, and banking are discussed.</description><author>Bond, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Moral hazard and optimal subsidiary structure for financial institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahn, C.; Winton, A.
Banks and related financial institutions often have two separate subsidiaries that make loans of similar type but differing risk, for example, a bank and a finance company, or a "good bank/bad bank" structure. Such "bipartite" structures may prevent risk shifting, in which banks misuse their flexibility in choosing and monitoring loans to exploit their debt holders. By "insulating" safer loans from riskier loans, a bipartite structure reduces risk-shifting incentives in the safer subsidiary. Bipartite structures are more likely to dominate unitary structures as the downside from riskier loans is higher or as expected profits from the efficient loan mix are lower.</description><author>Kahn, C.; Winton, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate investment and asset price dynamics: Implications for the cross-section of returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlson, M.; Fisher, A.; Giammarino, R.
We show that corporate investment decisions can explain the conditional dynamics in expected asset returns. Our approach is similar in spirit to Berk, Green, and Naik (1999), but we introduce to the investment problem operating leverage, reversible real options, fixed adjustment costs, and finite growth opportunities. Asset betas vary over time with historical investment decisions and the current product market demand. Book-to-market effects emerge and relate to operating leverage, while size captures the residual importance of growth options relative to assets in place. We estimate and test the model using simulation methods and reproduce portfolio excess returns comparable to the data.</description><author>Carlson, M.; Fisher, A.; Giammarino, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does stock return momentum explain the "Smart money" effect?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sapp, T.; Tiwari, A.
Does the "smart money" effect documented by Gruber (1996) and Zheng (1999) reflect fund selection ability of mutual fund investors? We examine the finding that investors are able to predict mutual fund performance and invest accordingly. We show that the smart money effect is explained by the stock return momentum phenomenon documented by Jegadeesh and Titman (1993). Further evidence suggests investors do not select funds based on a momentum investing style, but rather simply chase funds that were recent winners. Our finding that a common factor in stock returns explains the smart money effect offers no affirmation of investor fund selection ability.</description><author>Sapp, T.; Tiwari, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Luxury goods and the equity premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ait-Sahalia, Y.; Parker, J. A.; Yogo, M.
This paper evaluates the equity premium using novel data on the consumption of luxury goods. Specifying utility as a nonhomothetic function of both luxury and basic consumption goods, we derive pricing equations and evaluate the risk of holding equity. Household survey and national accounts data mostly reflect basic consumption, and therefore overstate the risk aversion necessary to match the observed equity premium. The risk aversion implied by the consumption of luxury goods is more than an order of magnitude less than that implied by national accounts data. For the very rich, the equity premium is much less of a puzzle.</description><author>Ait-Sahalia, Y.; Parker, J. A.; Yogo, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of banking relationships on the firm's IPO underpricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schenone, C.
This paper investigates the effects of pre-IPO banking relationships on a firm's IPO. Using a new and unique data set, which compares the firm's pre-IPO banking relationships to the underwriters managing the firm's new issue, I test whether banking relationships established before the firm's IPO ameliorate asymmetric information problems behind high IPO underpricing. The results show that firms with a pre-IPO banking relationship with a prospective underwriter face about 17% lower underpricing than firms without such banking relationships. These results are robust to controlling for the firm's endogenous selection of the pre-IPO banking institution.</description><author>Schenone, C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do initial public offering firms purchase analyst coverage with underpricing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cliff, M. L. I.; Denis, D. J.
We report that initial public offering (IPO) underpricing is positively related to analyst coverage by the lead underwriter and to the presence of an all-star analyst on the research staff of the lead underwriter. These findings are robust to controls for other determinants of underpricing and to controls for the endogeneity of underpricing and analyst coverage. In addition, we find that the probability of switching underwriters between IPO and seasoned equity offering is negatively related to the unexpected amount of post-IPO analyst coverage. These findings are consistent with the hypothesis that underpricing is, in part, compensation for expected post-IPO analyst coverage from highly ranked analysts.</description><author>Cliff, M. L. I.; Denis, D. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The choice of private versus public capital markets: Evidence from privatizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Megginson, W. L.; Nash, R. C.; Netter, J. M.; Poulsen, A. B.
We examine the impact of political, institutional, and economic factors on the choice between selling a state-owned enterprise in the public capital market through a share issue privatization (SIP) and selling it in the private capital market in an asset sale. SIPs are more likely in less developed capital markets, for more profitable state-owned enterprises, and where there are more protections of minority shareholders. Asset sales are more likely when there is less state control of the economy and when the firm is smaller. Our results suggest the importance of privatization activities in developing the equity markets of privatizing countries.</description><author>Megginson, W. L.; Nash, R. C.; Netter, J. M.; Poulsen, A. B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk and international portfolio choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, S. R.; Uppal, R.
Returns on international equities are characterized by jumps; moreover, these jumps tend to occur at the same time across countries leading to systemic risk. We capture these stylized facts using a multivariate system of jump-diffusion processes where the arrival of jumps is simultaneous across assets. We then determine an investor's optimal portfolio for this model of returns. Systemic risk has two effects: One, it reduces the gains from diversification and two, it penalizes investors for holding levered positions. We find that the loss resulting from diminished diversification is small, while that from holding very highly levered positions is large.</description><author>Das, S. R.; Uppal, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial development and intersectoral allocation: A new approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fisman, R.; Love, I.
This paper uses a new methodology based on industry comovement to examine the role of financial market development in intersectoral allocation. Based on the assumption that there exist common global shocks to growth opportunities, we hypothesize that country pairs should have, correlated patterns of sectoral growth if they are able to respond to these shocks. Consistent with financial markets promoting responsiveness to shocks, countries have more highly correlated growth rates across sectors when both countries have well-developed financial markets. This effect is stronger between country pairs at similar levels of economic development, which are more likely to experience similar growth shocks.</description><author>Fisman, R.; Love, I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How to discount cashflows with time-varying expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, A.; Liu, J.
While many studies document that the market risk premium is predictable and that betas are not constant, the dividend discount model ignores time-varying risk premiums and betas. We develop a model to consistently value cashflows with changing risk-free rates, predictable risk premiums, and conditional betas in the context of a conditional CAPM. Practical valuation is accomplished with an analytic term structure of discount rates, with different discount rates applied to expected cashflows at different horizons. Using constant discount rates can produce large misvaluations, which, in portfolio data, are mostly driven at short horizons by market risk premiums and at long horizons by time variation in risk-free rates and factor loadings.</description><author>Ang, A.; Liu, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collars and renegotiation in mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Officer, M. S.
I examine the motivation for, and effect of, including a collar in a merger agreement. The most important cross-sectional determinants of the bid structure (cash vs. stock, and whether to include a collar) are the market-related stock return standard deviations for the bidder and target. This evidence supports the hypothesis that the method of payment is dependent on the sensitivities of the bidder and target to market-related risk because either has the incentive to demand renegotiation of the merger terms if the value of the bidder's offer changes materially relative to the value of the target during the bid period.</description><author>Officer, M. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market valuation and merger waves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rhodes-Kropf, M.; Viswanathan, S.
Does valuation affect mergers? Data suggest that periods of stock merger activity are correlated with high market valuations. The naive explanation that over-valued bidders wish to use stock is incomplete because targets should not be eager to accept stock. However, we show that potential market value deviations from fundamental values on both sides of the transaction can rationally lead to a correlation between stock merger activity and market valuation. Merger waves and waves of cash and stock purchases can be rationally driven by periods of over- and undervaluation of the stock market. Thus, valuation fundamentally impacts mergers.</description><author>Rhodes-Kropf, M.; Viswanathan, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Near-sighted justice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernhardt, D.; Nosal, E.
Chapter 11 structures complex negotiations between creditors and debtors that are overseen by a bankruptcy court. We identify conditions where the court should sometimes err in determining which firms should be liquidated. Such errors affect actions by both good and bad entrepreneurs. We first characterize the optimal error rate without renegotiation. When creditors and debtors can renegotiate to circumvent an error-riven court, for one class of actions a blind court that ignores all information is optimal. For another class, the court should place the burden of proof on the entrepreneur. The robust feature is that the court should sometimes err.</description><author>Bernhardt, D.; Nosal, E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price discovery in the US treasury market: The impact of orderflow and liquidity on the yield curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandt, M. W.; Kavajecz, K. A.
We examine the role of price discovery in the U.S. Treasury market through the empirical relationship between orderflow, liquidity, and the yield curve. We find that orderflow imbalances (excess buying or selling pressure) account for up to 26% of the day-to-day variation in yields on days without major macroeconomic announcements. The effect of orderflow on yields is permanent and strongest when liquidity is low. All of the evidence points toward an important role of price discovery in understanding the behavior of the yield curve.</description><author>Brandt, M. W.; Kavajecz, K. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Remuneration, retention, and reputation incentives for outside directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yermack, D.
I study incentives received by outside directors in Fortune 500 firms from compensation, replacement, and the opportunity to obtain other directorships. Previous research has only shown these relations to apply under limited circumstances such as financial distress. Together these incentive mechanisms provide directors with wealth increases of approximately 11 cents per $1,000 rise in firm value. Although smaller than the performance sensitivities of CEOs, outside directors' incentives imply a change in wealth of about $285,000 for a 1 standard deviation (SD) change in typical firm performance. Cross-sectional patterns of director equity awards conform to agency and financial theories.</description><author>Yermack, D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bids and allocations in European IPO bookbuilding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jenkinson, T.; Jones, H.
This paper uses evidence from a data set of 27 European IPOs to analyze how investors bid and the factors that influence their allocations. We also make use of a unique ranking of investor quality, associated with the likelihood of flipping the IPO. We find that investors perceived to be long-term holders of the stock are consistently favored in allocation and in out-turn profits. In contrast to Cornelli and Goldreich (2001), we find little evidence that more informative bids receive larger allocations or higher profits. Our results cast doubt upon the extent of information production during the bookbuilding period.</description><author>Jenkinson, T.; Jones, H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The development of secondary market liquidity for NYSE-listed IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corwin, S. A.; Harris, J. H.; Lipson, M. L.
For NYSE-listed IPOs, limit order submissions and depth relative to volume are unusually low on the first trading day. Initial buy-side liquidity is higher for IPOs with high-quality underwriters, large syndicates, low insider sales, and high premarket demand, while sell-side liquidity is higher for IPOs that represent a large fraction of outstanding shares and have low premarket demand. Our results suggest that uncertainty and offer design affect initial liquidity, though order flow stabilizes quickly. We also find that submission strategies are influenced by expected underwriter stabilization and preopening order flow contains information about both initial prices and subsequent returns.</description><author>Corwin, S. A.; Harris, J. H.; Lipson, M. L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price response to S &amp; P 500 index additions and deletions: Evidence of asymmetry and a new explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, H. H.; Noronha, G.; Singal, V.
We study the price effects of changes to the S&amp;P 500 index and document an asymmetric price response: There is a permanent increase in the price of added firms but no permanent decline for deleted firms. These results are at odds with extant explanations of the effects of index changes that imply a symmetric price response to additions and deletions. A possible explanation for asymmetric price effects arises from the changes in investor awareness. Results from our empirical tests support the thesis that changes in investor awareness contribute to the asymmetric price effects of S&amp;P 500 index additions and deletions.</description><author>Chen, H. H.; Noronha, G.; Singal, V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Electricity forward prices: A high-frequency empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, F. A.; Wang, A. W.
We conduct an empirical analysis of forward prices in the PJM electricity market using a high-frequency data set of hourly spot and day-ahead forward prices. We find that there are significant risk premia in electricity forward prices. These premia vary systematically throughout the day and are directly related to economic risk factors, such as the volatility of unexpected changes in demand, spot prices, and total revenues. These results support the hypothesis that electricity forward prices in the Pennsylvania, New Jersey, and Maryland market are determined rationally by risk-averse economic agents.</description><author>Longstaff, F. A.; Wang, A. W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-selling prior to earnings announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christophe, S. E.; Ferri, M. G.; Angel, J. J.
This paper examines short-sales transactions in the five days prior to earnings announcements of 913 Nasdaq-listed firms. The tests provide evidence of informed trading in pre-announcement short-selling because they reveal that abnormal short-selling is significantly linked to post-announcement stock returns. Also, the tests indicate that short-sellers typically are more active in stocks with low book-to-market valuations or low SUEs. The levels of pre-announcement short-selling, however, mostly appear to reflect firm-specific information rather than these fundamental financial characteristics. We believe that these results should encourage financial market regulators to consider providing more extensive and timely disclosures of short-selling to investors.</description><author>Christophe, S. E.; Ferri, M. G.; Angel, J. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do entrepreneurs pay for venture capital affiliation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsu, D. H.
This study empirically evaluates the certification and value-added roles of reputable venture capitalists (VCs). Using a novel sample of entrepreneurial start-ups with multiple financing offers, I analyze financing offers made by competing VCs at the first professional round of start-up funding, holding characteristics of the start-up fixed. Offers made by VCs with a high reputation are three times more likely to be accepted, and high-reputation VCs acquire start-up equity at a 10-14% discount. The evidence suggests that VCs' ''extra-financial" value may be more distinctive than their functionally equivalent financial capital. These extra-financial services can have financial consequences.</description><author>Hsu, D. H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cash flow sensitivity of cash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, H.; Campello, M.; Weisbach, M. S.
We model a firm's demand for liquidity to develop a new test of the effect of financial constraints on corporate policies. The effect of financial constraints is captured by the firm's propensity to save cash out of cash flows (the cash flow sensitivity of cash). We hypothesize that constrained firms should have a positive cash flow sensitivity of cash, while unconstrained firms' cash savings should not be systematically related to cash flows. We empirically estimate the cash flow sensitivity of cash using a large sample of manufacturing firms over the 1971 to 2000 period and find robust support for our theory.</description><author>Almeida, H.; Campello, M.; Weisbach, M. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimation and test of a simple model of intertemporal capital asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brennan, M. J.; Wang, A. W.; Xia, Y. H.
A simple valuation model with time-varying investment opportunities is developed and estimated. The model assumes that the investment opportunity set is completely described by the real interest rate and the maximum Sharpe ratio, which follow correlated Ornstein-Uhlenbeck processes. The model parameters and time series of the state variables are estimated using US. Treasury bond yields and expected inflation from January 1952 to December 2000, and as predicted, the estimated maximum Sharpe ratio is related to the equity premium. In cross-sectional asset-pricing tests, both state variables have significant risk premia, which is consistent with Merton's ICAPM.</description><author>Brennan, M. J.; Wang, A. W.; Xia, Y. H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tobin's Q, debt overhang, and investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hennessy, C. A.
Incorporating debt in a dynamic real options framework, we show that underinvestment stems from truncation of equity's horizon at default. Debt overhang distorts both the level and composition of investment, with underinvestment being more severe for long-lived assets. An empirical proxy for the shadow price of capital to equity is derived. Use of this proxy yields a structural test for debt overhang and its mitigation through issuance of additional secured debt. Using measurement error-consistent GMM estimators, we find a statistically significant debt overhang effect regardless of firms' ability to issue additional secured debt.</description><author>Hennessy, C. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification as a public good: Community effects in portfolio choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demarzo, P. M.; Kaniel, R.; Kremer, I.
Within a rational general equilibrium model in which agents care only about personal consumption, we consider a setting in which, due to borrowing constraints, individuals endowed with local resources underparticipate in financial markets. As a result, investors compete for local resources through their portfolio choices. Even with complete financial markets and no aggregate risk, agents may herd into risky portfolios. This yields a Pareto-dominated outcome as agents introduce "community" risk unrelated to fundamentals. Moreover, if some agents are behaviorally biased, or cannot completely diversify their holdings, rational agents may choose more extreme portfolios and amplify the effect.</description><author>Demarzo, P. M.; Kaniel, R.; Kremer, I.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The timing of option repricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Callaghan, S. R.; Saly, R. J.; Subramaniam, C.
We investigate whether executive stock option repricings are systematically timed to coincide with favorable movements in the company's stock price. For a sample of 236 repricing events, we observe sharp increases in stock price in the 20-day period following the repricing date. In addition, repricing dates tend to either precede the release of good news or follow the release of bad news in the quarterly earnings announcements. Since information about stock option repricing is not generally released to the public around the repricing date, these findings suggest that CEOs opportunistically manage the timing of the option repricing date.</description><author>Callaghan, S. R.; Saly, R. J.; Subramaniam, C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms use incentives that have no incentive effects?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oyer, P.
This paper illustrates why firms might choose to implement stock option plans or other pay instruments that reward "luck." I consider a model where adjusting compensation contracts is costly and where employees' outside opportunities are correlated with their firms' performance. The model may help to explain the use and recent rise of broad-based stock option plans, as well as other financial instruments, even when these pay plans have no effect on employees' on-the-job behavior. The model suggests that agency theory's often-overlooked participation constraint may be an important determinant of some common compensation schemes, particularly for employees below the highest executive ranks.</description><author>Oyer, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee stock options, corporate taxes, and debt policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, J. R.; Lang, M. H.; Shackelford, D. A.
We find that employee stock option deductions lead to large aggregate tax savings for Nasdaq 100 and S&amp;P 100 firms and also affect corporate marginal tax rates. For Nasdaq firms, including the effect of options reduces the estimated median marginal tax rate from 31% to 5%. For S&amp;P firms, in contrast, option deductions do not affect marginal tax rates to a large degree. Our evidence suggests that option deductions are important nondebt tax shields and that option deductions substitute for interest deductions in corporate capital structure decisions, explaining in part why some firms use so little debt.</description><author>Graham, J. R.; Lang, M. H.; Shackelford, D. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information and the cost of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, D.; O'Hara, M.
We investigate the role of information in affecting a firm's cost of capital. We show that differences in the composition of information between public and private information affect the cost of capital, with investors demanding a higher return to hold stocks with greater private information. This higher return arises because informed investors are better able to shift their portfolio to incorporate new information, and uninformed investors are thus disadvantaged. In equilibrium, the quantity and quality of information affect asset prices. We show firms can influence their cost of capital by choosing features like accounting treatments, analyst coverage, and market microstructure.</description><author>Easley, D.; O'Hara, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The nature of discipline by corporate takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kini, O.; Kracaw, W.; Mian, S.
This paper provides a comprehensive examination of the disciplinary role of the corporate takeover market using a sample of US. target firms over the period 1979 to 1998. The time period spanned allows a broader study not only of the disciplinary role of the takeover market in general, but also of the interaction between the takeover market and alternative governance mechanisms during the 1980s and 1990s. Overall, our evidence is consistent with the view of the corporate takeover market as a "court of last resort," that is, it is an external source of discipline that intercedes when internal control mechanisms are relatively weak or ineffective.</description><author>Kini, O.; Kracaw, W.; Mian, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risks for the long run: A potential resolution of asset pricing puzzles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bansal, R.; Yaron, A.
We model consumption and dividend growth rates as containing (1) a small long-run predictable component, and (2) fluctuating economic uncertainty (consumption volatility). These dynamics, for which we provide empirical support, in conjunction with Epstein and Zin's (1989) preferences, can explain key asset markets phenomena. In our economy, financial markets dislike economic uncertainty and better long-run growth prospects raise equity prices. The model can justify the equity premium, the risk-free rate, and the volatility of the market return, risk-free rate, and the price-dividend ratio. As in the data, dividend yields predict returns and the volatility of returns is time-varying.</description><author>Bansal, R.; Yaron, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential address, committing to commit: Short-term debt when enforcement is costly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diamond, D. W.
In legal systems with expensive or ineffective contract enforcement, it is difficult to induce lenders to enforce debt contracts. If lenders do not enforce, borrowers will have incentives to misbehave. Lenders have incentives to enforce given bad news when debt is short-term and subject to runs caused by externalities across lenders. Lenders will not undo these externalities by negotiation. The required number of lenders increases with enforcement costs. A very high enforcement cost can exceed the ex ante incentive benefit of enforcement. Removing lenders' right to immediately enforce their debt with a "bail-in" can improve the ex ante incentives of borrowers.</description><author>Diamond, D. W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-neutral parameter shifts and derivatives pricing in discrete time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schroder, M.
We obtain a large class of discrete-time risk-neutral valuation relationships, or "preference-free" derivatives pricing models, by imposing a simple restriction on the state-price density process. The risk-neutral stock-return and forward-rate dynamics are obtained by changing only a location parameter, which can be determined independent of the preference and true location parameters. The Gaussian models of Rubinstein (1976), Brennan (1979), and C (a) over cap mera (2003), and the gamma model of Heston (1993) are all special cases. The model provides simple relationships between expected returns and state-price density parameters analogous to the diffusion case.</description><author>Schroder, M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and coalition among underwriters: The decision to join a syndicate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, W. L.
This paper studies the decision of lead investment banks to organize hybrid syndicates (commercial banks participating as co-managers) versus pure investment bank syndicates. The findings show that hybrid underwriting issues are more challenging to float. Compared to pure investment bank syndicates, hybrid syndicates serve clients that are smaller, have lower common stock rankings and less prior access to the capital markets, rely more on bank loans, and invest less capital but issue larger amounts, which indicates that commercial banks' participation enhances hybrid services. Moreover, lead investment banks tend to invite banks' participation when clients exhibit higher loyalty in reusing their services.</description><author>Song, W. L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring as a motivation for IPO underpricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arugaslan, O.; Cook, D. O.; Kieschnick, R.
Brennan and Franks (1997) and Stoughton and Zechner (1998) provide contrasting arguments for why monitoring considerations create incentives for managers to underprice their firms' IPOs (initial public offerings). Like Smart and Zutter (2003), we examine these arguments using a sample of U.S. IPOs. However, we find evidence that the determinants of initial returns, institutional shareholdings, and post-IPO likelihood of acquisition are not consistent with these arguments. Thus, we conclude that monitoring considerations are not important determinants of IPO underpricing.</description><author>Arugaslan, O.; Cook, D. O.; Kieschnick, R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous liquidity in asset markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisfeldt, A. L.
This paper analyzes a model in which long-term risky assets are illiquid due to adverse selection. The degree of adverse selection and hence the liquidity of these assets is determined endogenously by the amount of trade for reasons other than private information. I find that higher productivity leads to increased liquidity. Moreover, liquidity magnifies the effects of changes in productivity on investment and volume. High productivity implies that investors initiate larger scale risky projects which increases the riskiness of their incomes. Riskier incomes induce more sales of claims to high-quality projects, causing liquidity to increase.</description><author>Eisfeldt, A. L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price pressure around mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitchell, M.; Pulvino, T.; Stafford, E.
This paper examines the trading behavior of professional investors around 2,130 mergers announced between 1994 and 2000. We find considerable support for the existence of price pressure around mergers caused by uninformed shifts in excess demand, but that these effects are short-lived, consistent with the notion that short-run demand curves for stocks are not perfectly elastic. We estimate that nearly half of the negative announcement period stock price reaction for acquirers in stock-financed mergers reflects downward price pressure caused by merger arbitrage short selling, suggesting that previous estimates of merger wealth effects are biased downward.</description><author>Mitchell, M.; Pulvino, T.; Stafford, E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bondholder wealth effects in mergers and acquisitions: New evidence from the 1980s and 1990s</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, M. T.; King, T. H. D.; Mauer, D. C.
We examine the wealth effects of mergers and acquisitions on target and acquiring firm bondholders in the 1980s and 1990s. Consistent with a coinsurance effect, below investment grade target bonds earn significantly positive announcement period returns. By contrast, acquiring firm bonds earn negative announcement period returns. Additionally, target bonds have significantly larger returns when the target's rating is below the acquirer's, when the combination is anticipated to decrease target risk or leverage, and when the target's maturity is shorter than the acquirer's. Finally, we find that target and acquirer announcement period bond returns are significantly larger in the 1990s.</description><author>Billett, M. T.; King, T. H. D.; Mauer, D. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social interaction and stock-market participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, H.; Kubik, J. D.; Stein, J. C.
We propose that stock-market participation is influenced by social interaction. In our model, any given "social" investor finds the market more attractive when more of his peers participate. We test this theory using data from the Health and Retirement Study, and find that social households-those who interact with their neighbors, or attend church-are substantially more likely to invest in the market than non-social households, controlling for wealth, race, education, and risk tolerance. Moreover, consistent with a peer-effects story, the impact of sociability is stronger in states where stock-market participation rates are higher.</description><author>Hong, H.; Kubik, J. D.; Stein, J. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market imperfections, investment flexibility, and default spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Titman, S.; Tompaidis, S.; Tsyplakov, S.
This paper develops a structural model that determines default spreads in a setting where the debt's collateral is endogenously determined by the borrower's investment choice, and a demand variable with permanent and temporary components. We also consider the possibility that the borrower cannot commit to taking the value-maximizing investment choice, and may, in addition, be constrained in its ability to raise external capital. Based on a model calibrated to data on office buildings and commercial mortgages, we present numerical simulations that quantify the extent to which investment flexibility, incentive problems, and credit constraints affect default spreads.</description><author>Titman, S.; Tompaidis, S.; Tsyplakov, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Compensation, incentives, and the duality of risk aversion and riskiness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ross, S. A.
The common folklore that giving options to agents will make them more willing to take risks is false. In fact, no incentive schedule will make all expected utility maximizers more or less risk averse. This paper finds simple, intuitive, necessary and sufficient conditions under which incentive schedules make agents more or less risk averse. The paper uses these to examine the incentive effects of some common structures such as puts and calls, and it briefly explores the duality between a fee schedule that makes an agent more or less risk averse, and gambles that increase or decrease risk.</description><author>Ross, S. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The statistical and economic role of jumps in continuous-time interest rate models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johannes, M.
This paper analyzes the role of jumps in continuous-time short rate models. I first develop a test to detect jump-induced misspecification and, using Treasury bill rates, find evidence for the presence of jumps. Second, I specify and estimate a nonparametric jump-diffusion model. Results indicate that jumps play an important statistical role. Estimates of jump times and sizes indicate that unexpected news about the macroeconomy generates the jumps. Finally, I investigate the pricing implications of jumps. Jumps generally have a minor impact on yields, but they are important for pricing interest rate options.</description><author>Johannes, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are investors rational? Choices among index funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.; Busse, J. A.
S&amp;P 500 index funds represent one of the simplest vehicles for examining rational behavior. They hold virtually the same securities, yet their returns differ by more than 2 percent per year. Although the relative returns of alternative S&amp;P 500 funds are easily predictable, the relationship between cash flows and performance is weaker than rational behavior would lead us to expect. We show that selecting funds based on low expenses or high past returns outperforms the portfolio of index funds selected by investors. Our results exemplify the fact that, in a market where arbitrage is not possible, dominated products can prosper.</description><author>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.; Busse, J. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal consumption and investment with transaction costs and multiple risky assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, H.
We consider the optimal intertemporal consumption and investment policy of a constant absolute risk aversion (CARA) investor who faces fixed and proportional transaction costs when trading multiple risky assets. We show that when asset returns are uncorrelated, the optimal investment policy is to keep the dollar amount invested in each risky asset between two constant levels and upon reaching either of these thresholds, to trade to the corresponding optimal targets. An extensive analysis suggests that transaction cost is an important factor in affecting trading volume and that it can significantly diminish the importance of stock return predictability as reported in the literature.</description><author>Liu, H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed trading when information becomes stale</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernhardt, D.; Miao, J. J.
This paper characterizes informed trade when speculators can acquire distinct signals of varying quality about an asset's value at different dates. The most reasonable characterization of private information about stocks is that while information is long-lived, new information will arrive over time, information that may be acquired by others. Hence, while a speculator may know more than others at a moment, in the future, his information will become stale, but not valueless. In an environment that allows for arbitrary correlations among signals, we characterize equilibrium outcomes including trading, prices, and profits. We provide explicit numerical characterizations for different informational environments.</description><author>Bernhardt, D.; Miao, J. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convertible bond design and capital investment: The role of call provisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korkeamaki, T. P.; Moore, W. T.
If firms issue convertible securities to facilitate sequential investment, the securities should be engineered to give sufficient flexibility to accommodate timing of follow-on investment. We examine call provisions in convertible bonds and argue that firms with investment options expected to expire sooner (later) will offer weaker (stronger) call protection. We find that issues with weak or no call protection are offered by firms that invest greater amounts soon after issuance than those issuing convertibles with strong protection. Moreover, capital expenditure levels during the 5-year period following issuance are inversely related to the length of call-protection periods.</description><author>Korkeamaki, T. P.; Moore, W. T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option-implied risk aversion estimates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bliss, R. R.; Panigirtzoglou, N.
Using a utility function to adjust the risk-neutral PDF embedded in cross sections of options, we obtain measures of the risk aversion implied in option prices. Using FTSE 100 and S&amp;P 500 options, and both power and exponential-utility functions, we estimate the representative agent's relative risk aversion (RRA) at different horizons. The estimated coefficients of RRA are all reasonable. The RRA estimates are remarkably consistent across utility functions and across markets for given horizons. The degree of RRA declines broadly with the forecast horizon and is lower during periods of high market volatility.</description><author>Bliss, R. R.; Panigirtzoglou, N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do exchanges select stocks for option listing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mayhew, S.; Mihov, V.
We investigate the factors influencing the selection of stocks for option listing. Exchanges tend to list options on stocks with high trading volume, volatility, and market capitalization, but the relative effect of these factors has changed over time as markets have evolved. We observe a shift from volume toward volatility after the moratorium on new listings ended in 1980. Using control sample methodology designed to correct for the endogeneity of option listing, we find no evidence that volatility declines with option introduction, in contrast to previous studies that do not use control samples.</description><author>Mayhew, S.; Mihov, V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do stock prices and volatility jump? Reconciling evidence from spot and option prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eraker, B.
This paper examines the empirical performance of jump diffusion models of stock price dynamics from joint options and stock markets data. The paper introduces a model with discontinuous correlated jumps in stock prices and stock price volatility, and with state-dependent arrival intensity. We discuss how to perform likelihood-based inference based upon joint options/returns data and present estimates of risk premiums for jump and volatility risks. The paper finds that while complex jump specifications add little explanatory power in fitting options data, these models fare better in fitting options and returns data simultaneously.</description><author>Eraker, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Specification analysis of option pricing models based on time-changed Levy processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, J. Z.; Wu, L. R.
We analyze the specifications of option pricing models based on time-changed Levy processes. We classify option pricing models based on the structure of the jump component in the underlying return process, the source of stochastic volatility, and the specification of the volatility process itself. Our estimation of a variety of model specifications indicates that to better capture the behavior of the S&amp;P 500 index options, we need to incorporate a high frequency jump component in the return process and generate stochastic volatilities from two different sources, the jump component and the diffusion component.</description><author>Huang, J. Z.; Wu, L. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market states and momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, M. J.; Gutierrez, R. C.; Hameed, A.
We test overreaction theories of short-run momentum and long-run reversal in the cross section of stock returns. Momentum profits depend on the state of the market, as predicted. From 1929 to 1995, the mean monthly momentum profit following positive market returns is 0.93%, whereas the mean profit following negative market returns is -0.37%. The up-market momentum reverses in the long-run. Our results are robust to the conditioning information in macroeconomic factors. Moreover, we find that macroeconomic factors are unable to explain momentum profits after simple methodological adjustments to take account of microstructure concerns.</description><author>Cooper, M. J.; Gutierrez, R. C.; Hameed, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The foundations of freezeout laws in takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amihud, Y.; Kahan, M.; Sundaram, R. K.
We provide an economic basis for permitting freezeouts of nontendering shareholders following successful takeovers. We describe a specific freezeout mechanism based on easily verifiable information that induces desirable efficiency and welfare properties in models of both corporations with widely dispersed shareholdings and corporations with large pivotal shareholders. The mechanism dominates previous proposals along some important dimensions. We also examine takeover premia that arise in the presence of competition among raiders. Our mechanism is closely related to the practice of takeover law in the United States; thus, our analysis may be thought of as analyzing the economic foundations of current regulations.</description><author>Amihud, Y.; Kahan, M.; Sundaram, R. K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is all that talk just noise? The information content of Internet stock message boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antweiler, W.; Frank, M. Z.
Financial press reports claim that Internet stock message boards can move markets. We study the effect of more than 1.5 million messages posted on Yahoo! Finance and Raging Bull about the 45 companies in the Dow Jones Industrial Average and the Dow Jones Internet Index. Bullishness is measured using computational linguistics methods. Wall Street Journal news stories are used as controls. We find that stock messages help predict market volatility. Their effect on stock returns is statistically significant but economically small. Consistent with Harris and Raviv (1993), disagreement among the posted messages is associated with increased trading volume.</description><author>Antweiler, W.; Frank, M. Z.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed trading in stock and option markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakravarty, S.; Gulen, H.; Mayhew, S.
We investigate the contribution of option markets to price discovery, using a modification of Hasbrouck's (1995) "information share" approach. Based on five years of stock and options data for 60 firms, we estimate the option market's contribution to price discovery to be about 17% on average. Option market price discovery is related to trading volume and spreads in both markets, and stock volatility. Price discovery across option strike prices is related to leverage, trading volume, and spreads. Our results are consistent with theoretical arguments that informed investors trade in both stock and option markets, suggesting an important informational role for options.</description><author>Chakravarty, S.; Gulen, H.; Mayhew, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are judgment errors reflected in market prices and allocations? Experimental evidence based on the Monty Hall problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kluger, B. D.; Wyatt, S. B.
The question of whether individual judgment errors survive in market equilibrium is an issue that naturally lends itself to experimental analysis. Here, the Monty Hall problem is used to detect probability judgment errors both in a cohort of individuals and in a market setting. When all subjects in a cohort made probability judgment errors, market prices also reflected the error. However, competition among two bias-free subjects was sufficient to drive prices to error-free levels. Thus, heterogeneity in behavior can be an important factor in asset pricing, and further, it may take few bias-free traders to make asset prices bias-free.</description><author>Kluger, B. D.; Wyatt, S. B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal asset location and allocation with taxable and tax-deferred investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dammon, R. M.; Spatt, C. S.; Zhang, H. H.
We investigate optimal intertemporal asset allocation and location decisions for investors making taxable and tax-deferred investments. We show a strong preference for holding taxable bonds in the tax-deferred account and equity in the taxable account, reflecting the higher tax burden on taxable bonds relative to equity. For most investors, the optimal asset location policy is robust to the introduction of tax-exempt bonds and liquidity shocks. Numerical results illustrate optimal portfolio decisions as a function of age and tax-deferred wealth. Interestingly, the proportion of total wealth allocated to equity is inversely related to the fraction of total wealth in tax-deferred accounts.</description><author>Dammon, R. M.; Spatt, C. S.; Zhang, H. H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are momentum profits robust to trading costs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korajczyk, R. A.; Sadka, R.
We test whether momentum strategies remain profitable after considering market frictions induced by trading. Intraday data are used to estimate alternative measures of proportional and non-proportional (price impact) trading costs. The price impact models imply that abnormal returns to portfolio strategies decline with portfolio size. We calculate break-even fund sizes that lead to zero abnormal returns. In addition to equal- and value-weighted momentum strategies, we derive a liquidity-weighted strategy designed to reduce the cost of trades. Equal-weighted strategies perform the best before trading costs and the worst after trading costs. Liquidity-weighted and hybrid liquidity/value-weighted strategies have the largest break-even fund sizes: $5 billion or more (relative to December 1999 market capitalization) may be invested in these momentum strategies before the apparent profit opportunities vanish.</description><author>Korajczyk, R. A.; Sadka, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing the analysts: When do recommendations add value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jegadeesh, N.; Kim, J.; Krische, S. D.; Lee, C. M. C.
We show that analysts from sell-side firms generally recommend "glamour" (i.e., positive momentum, high growth, high volume, and relatively expensive) stocks. Naive adherence to these recommendations can be costly, because the level of the consensus recommendation adds value only among stocks with favorable quantitative characteristics (i.e., value stocks and positive momentum stocks). In fact, among stocks with unfavorable quantitative characteristics, higher consensus recommendations are associated with worse subsequent returns. In contrast, we find that the quarterly change in consensus recommendations is a robust return predictor that appears to contain information orthogonal to a large range of other predictive variables.</description><author>Jegadeesh, N.; Kim, J.; Krische, S. D.; Lee, C. M. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A catering theory of dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, M.; Wurgler, J.
We propose that the decision to pay dividends is driven by prevailing investor demand for dividend payers. Managers cater to investors by paying dividends when investors put a stock price premium on payers, and by not paying when investors prefer nonpayers. To test this prediction, we construct four stock price-based measures of investor demand for dividend payers. By each measure, nonpayers tend to initiate dividends when demand is high. By some measures, payers tend to omit dividends when demand is low. Further analysis confirms that these results are better explained by catering than other theories of dividends.</description><author>Baker, M.; Wurgler, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive option repricing, incentives, and retention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, M. A.
While many firms grant executive stock options that can be repriced, other firms systematically restrict or prohibit repricing. This article investigates the determinants of firms' repricing policies and the consequences of such policies for executive turnover and retention. Firms that have better internal governance, that use more powerful stock-based incentives, or that face less shareholder scrutiny are more likely to maintain repricing flexibility. Firms that restrict repricing are more vulnerable to voluntary executive turnover following stock price declines. When share price declines are severe, restricting firms appear to award unusually large numbers of new options.</description><author>Chen, M. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic news and the impact of trading on bond prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, T. C.
This paper studies the impact of trading on government bond prices surrounding the release of macroeconomic news. The results show a significant increase in the informational role of trading following economic announcements, which suggests the release of public information increases the level of information asymmetry in the government bond market. The informational role of trading is greater after announcements with a larger initial price impact, and the relation is associated with the surprise component of the announcement and the precision of the public information. The results provide evidence that government bond order flow reveals fundamental information about riskless rates.</description><author>Green, T. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk sharing and asset prices: Evidence from a natural experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chari, A.; Henry, P. B.
When countries liberalize their stock markets, firms that become eligible for foreign purchase (investible), experience an average stock price revaluation of 15.1%. Since the historical covariance of the average investible firm's stock return with the local market is roughly 200 times larger than its historical covariance with the world market, liberalization reduces the systematic risk associated with holding investible securities. Consistent with this fact: (1) the average effect of the reduction in systematic risk is 6.8 percentage points, or roughly two fifths of the total revaluation; and (2) the firm-specific revaluations are directly proportional to the firm-specific changes in systematic risk.</description><author>Chari, A.; Henry, P. B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private benefits of control: An international comparison</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dyck, A.; Zingales, L.
We estimate private benefits of control in 39 countries using 393 controlling blocks sales. On average the value of control is 14 percent, but in some countries can be as low as -4 percent, in others as high a +65 percent. As predicted by theory, higher private benefits of control are associated with less developed capital markets, more concentrated ownership, and more privately negotiated privatizations. We also analyze what institutions are most important in curbing private benefits. We find evidence for both legal and extra-legal mechanisms. In a multivariate analysis, however, media pressure and tax enforcement seem to be the dominating factors.</description><author>Dyck, A.; Zingales, L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal diversification: Reconciling theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomes, J.; Livdan, D.
In this paper we show that the main empirical findings about firm diversification and performance are consistent with the maximization of shareholder value. In our model, diversification allows a firm to explore better productive opportunities while taking advantage of synergies. By explicitly linking the diversification strategies of the firm to differences in size and productivity, our model provides a natural laboratory to investigate several aspects of the relationship between diversification and performance. Specifically, we show that our model can rationalize the evidence on the diversification discount (Lang and Stulz (1994)) and the documented relation between diversification and productivity (Schoar (2002)).</description><author>Gomes, J.; Livdan, D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks versus venture capital: Project evaluation, screening, and expropriation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ueda, M.
Why do some start-up firms raise funds from banks and others from venture capitalists? To address this question, I study a model in which the venture capitalist can evaluate the entrepreneur's project more accurately than the bank but can also threaten to steal it from the entrepreneur. Consistent with evidence regarding venture capital finance, the model implies that the characteristics of a firm financing through venture capitalists are relatively little collateral, high growth, high risk, and high profitability. The model also suggests that tighter protection of intellectual property rights encourages entrepreneurs to finance through venture capitalists.</description><author>Ueda, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An examination of long-term abnormal stock returns and operating performance following R&amp;D increases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eberhart, A. C.; Maxwell, W. F.; Siddique, A. R.
We examine a sample of 8,313 cases, between 1951 and 2001, where firms unexpectedly increase their research and development (R&amp;D) expenditures by a significant amount. We find consistent evidence of a misreaction, as manifested in the significantly positive abnormal stock returns that our sample firms' shareholders experience following these increases. We also find consistent evidence that our sample firms experience significantly positive long-term abnormal operating performance following their R&amp;D increases. Our findings suggest that R&amp;D increases are beneficial investments, and that the market is slow to recognize the extent of this benefit (consistent with investor underreaction).</description><author>Eberhart, A. C.; Maxwell, W. F.; Siddique, A. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of share repurchase programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grullon, G.; Michaely, R.
Contrary to the implications of many payout theories, we find that announcements of open-market share repurchase programs are not followed by an increase in operating performance. However, we find that repurchasing firms experience a significant reduction in systematic risk and cost of capital relative to non-repurchasing firms. Further, consistent with the free cash-flow hypothesis, we find that the market reaction to share repurchase announcements is more positive among those firms that are more likely to overinvest. Finally, we find evidence to indicate that investors under-react to repurchase announcements because they initially underestimate the decline in cost of capital.</description><author>Grullon, G.; Michaely, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity externalities and adverse selection: Evidence from trading after hours</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barclay, M. J.; Hendershott, T.
This paper examines liquidity externalities by analyzing trading costs after hours. There is less than 1/20 as many trades per unit time after hours as during the trading day. The reduced trading activity results in substantially higher trading costs: quoted and effective spreads are three to four times larger than during the trading day. The higher spreads reflect greater adverse selection and order persistence, but not higher dealer profits. Because liquidity provision remains competitive after hours, the greater adverse selection and higher trading costs provide a direct measure of the magnitude of the liquidity externalities generated during the trading day.</description><author>Barclay, M. J.; Hendershott, T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does net buying pressure affect the shape of implied volatility functions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, N. P. B.; Whaley, R. E.
This paper examines the relation between net buying pressure and the shape of the implied volatility function (IVF) for index and individual stock options. We find that changes in implied volatility are directly related to net buying pressure from public order flow. We also find that changes in implied volatility of S&amp;P 500 options are most strongly affected by buying pressure for index puts, while changes in implied volatility of stock options are dominated by call option demand. Simulated delta-neutral option-writing trading strategies generate abnormal returns that match the deviations of the IVFs above realized historical return volatilities.</description><author>Bollen, N. P. B.; Whaley, R. E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News arrival, jump dynamics, and volatility components for individual stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maheu, J. M.; McCurdy, T. H.
This paper models components of the return distribution, which are assumed to be directed by a latent news process. The conditional variance of returns is a combination of jumps and smoothly changing components. A heterogeneous Poisson process with a time-varying conditional intensity parameter governs the likelihood of jumps. Unlike typical jump models with stochastic volatility, previous realizations of both jump and normal innovations can feed back asymmetrically into expected volatility. This model improves forecasts of volatility, particularly after large changes in stock returns. We provide empirical evidence of the impact and feedback effects of jump versus normal return innovations, leverage effects, and the time-series dynamics of jump clustering.</description><author>Maheu, J. M.; McCurdy, T. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option pricing on stocks in mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Subramanian, A.
We develop an arbitrage-free and complete framework to price options on the stocks of firms involved in a merger or acquisition deal allowing for the possibility that the deal might be called off at an intermediate time, creating discontinuous impacts on the stock prices. Our model can be a normative tool for market makers to quote prices for options on stocks involved in such deals and also for traders to control risks associated with such deals using traded options. The results of tests indicate that the model performs significantly better than the Black-Scholes model in explaining observed option prices.</description><author>Subramanian, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default risk in equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vassalou, M.; Xing, Y. H.
This is the first study that uses Merton's (1974) option pricing model to compute default measures for individual firms and assess the effect of default risk on equity returns. The size effect is a default effect, and this is also largely true for the book-to-market (BM) effect. Both exist only in segments of the market with high default risk. Default risk is systematic risk. The Fama-French (FF) factors SMB and HML contain some default-related information, but this is not the main reason that the FF model can explain the cross section of equity returns.</description><author>Vassalou, M.; Xing, Y. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International evidence on institutional trading behavior and price impact</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiyachantana, C. N.; Jain, P. K.; Jiang, C.; Wood, R. A.
This study characterizes institutional trading in international stocks from 37 countries during 1997 to 1998 and 2001. We find that the underlying market condition is a major determinant of the price impact and, more importantly, of the asymmetry between price impacts of institutional buy and sell orders. In bullish markets, institutional purchases have a bigger price impact than sells; however, in the bearish markets, sells have a higher price impact. This differs from previous findings on price impact asymmetry. Our study further suggests that price impact varies depending on order characteristics, firm-specific factors, and cross-country differences.</description><author>Chiyachantana, C. N.; Jain, P. K.; Jiang, C.; Wood, R. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading activity and price volatility in the municipal bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Downing, C.; Zhang, F.
Utilizing a comprehensive database of transactions in municipal bonds, we investigate the volume-volatility relation in the municipal bond market. We find a positive relation between the number of transactions and a bond's price volatility. In contrast to previous studies, we find a negative relation between average deal size and price volatility. These results are found to be robust throughout the sample. Our results are inconsistent with current theoretical models of the volume-volatility relation. These inconsistencies may arise because current models fail to account for the effects of overall market liquidity on the costs of large transactions.</description><author>Downing, C.; Zhang, F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toward a national market system for US exchange-listed equity options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battalio, R.; Hatch, B.; Jennings, R.
In its response to the 1975 Congressional mandate to implement a national market system for financial securities, the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) initially exempted the option market. Recent dramatic changes in the structure of the option market prompted the SEC to revisit this issue. We examine a sample of actively traded, multiply listed equity options to ask whether this market's characteristics appear consistent with the goals of producing economically efficient transactions and facilitating "best execution." We find marked changes between June 2000, when quotes are often ignored, and January 2002, when the market more closely resembles a national market.</description><author>Battalio, R.; Hatch, B.; Jennings, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification discount or premium? - New evidence from the business information tracking series</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Villalonga, B.
I use the Business Information Tracking Series (BITS), a new census database that covers the whole U.S. economy at the establishment level, to examine whether the finding of a diversification discount is an artifact of segment data. BITS data allow me to construct business units that are more consistently and objectively defined than segments, and thus more comparable across firms. Using these data on a sample that yields a discount according to segment data, I find a diversification premium. The premium is robust to variations in the sample, business unit definition, and measures of excess value and diversification.</description><author>Villalonga, B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Role of speculative short sales in price formation: The case of the weekend effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, H. H.; Singal, V.
We argue that short sellers affect prices in a significant and systematic manner. In particular, we contend that speculative short sales contribute to the Weekend effect: The inability to trade over the weekend is likely to cause these short sellers to close their speculative positions on Fridays and reestablish new short positions on Mondays causing stock prices to rise on Fridays and fall on Mondays. We find evidence in support of this hypothesis based on a comparison of high short-interest stocks and low short-interest stocks, stocks with and without actively traded options, IPOs, zero short-interest stocks, and highly volatile stocks.</description><author>Chen, H. H.; Singal, V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The level and persistence of growth rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, L. K. C.; Karceski, J.; Lakonishok, J.
Expectations about long-term earnings growth are crucial to valuation models and cost of capital estimates. We analyze historical long-term growth rates across a broad cross section of stocks using several indicators of operating performance. We test for persistence and predictability in growth. While some firms have grown at high rates historically, they are relatively rare instances. There is no persistence in long-term earnings growth beyond chance, and there is low predictability even with a wide variety of predictor variables. Specifically, IBES growth forecasts are overly optimistic and add little predictive power. Valuation ratios also have limited ability to predict future growth.</description><author>Chan, L. K. C.; Karceski, J.; Lakonishok, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value spread</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, R. B.; Polk, C.; Vuolteenaho, T.
,We decompose the cross-sectional variance of firms' book-to-market ratios using both a long US. panel and a shorter international panel. In contrast to typical aggregate time-series results, transitory cross-sectional variation in expected 15-year stock returns causes only a relatively small fraction (20 to 25 percent) of the total cross-sectional variance. The remaining dispersion can be explained by expected 15-year profitability and persistence of valuation levels. Furthermore, this fraction appears stable across time and across types of stocks. We also show that the expected return on value-minus-growth strategies is atypically high at times when their spread in book-to-market ratios is wide.</description><author>Cohen, R. B.; Polk, C.; Vuolteenaho, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence of information spillovers in the production of investment banking services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benveniste, L. M.; Ljungqvist, A.; Wilhelm, W. J.; Yu, X. Y.
We provide evidence that firms attempting IPOs condition offer terms and the decision whether to carry through with an offering on the experience of their primary market contemporaries. Moreover, while initial returns and IPO volume are positively correlated in the aggregate, the correlation is negative among contemporaneous offerings subject to a common valuation factor. Our findings are-consistent with investment banks implicitly bundling offerings subject to a common valuation factor to achieve more equitable internalization of information production costs and thereby preventing coordination failures in primary equity markets.</description><author>Benveniste, L. M.; Ljungqvist, A.; Wilhelm, W. J.; Yu, X. Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-border listings and price discovery: Evidence from US-listed Canadian stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eun, C. S.; Sabherwal, S.
We examine the contribution of cross-listings to price discovery for a sample of Canadian stocks listed on both the Toronto Stock Exchange (TSE) and a U.S. exchange. We find that prices on the TSE and U.S. exchange are cointegrated and mutually adjusting. The U.S. share of price discovery ranges from 0.2 percent to 98.2 percent, with an average of 38.1 percent. The U.S. share is directly related to the U.S. share of trading and to the ratio of proportions of informative trades on the US. exchange and the. TSE, and inversely related to the ratio of bid-ask spreads.</description><author>Eun, C. S.; Sabherwal, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrenchment and severance pay in optimal governance structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almazan, A.; Suarez, J.
This paper explores how motivating an incumbent CEO to undertake actions that improve the effectiveness of his management interacts with the firm's policy on CEO replacement. Such policy depends on the presence and the size of severance pay in the CEO's compensation package and on the CEO's influence on the board of directors regarding his own replacement (i.e., entrenchment). We explain when and why the combination of some degree of entrenchment and a sizeable severance package is desirable. The analysis offers predictions about the correlation between entrenchment, severance pay, and incentive compensation.</description><author>Almazan, A.; Suarez, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pseudo market timing and the long-run underperformance of IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, P.
Numerous studies document long-run underperformance by firms following equity offerings. This paper shows that underperformance is very likely to be observed ex-post in an efficient market. The premise is that more firms issue equity at higher stock prices even though they cannot predict future returns. Ex-post, issuers seem to time the market because offerings cluster at market peaks. Simulations based on 1973 through 1997 data reveal that when ex-ante expected abnormal returns are zero, median ex-post underperformance for equity issuers will be significantly negative in event-time. Using calendar-time returns solves the problem.</description><author>Schultz, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO pricing in the dot-com bubble</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ljungqvist, A.; Wilhelm, W. J.
IPO underpricing reached astronomical levels during 1999 and 2000. We show that the regime shift in initial returns and other elements of pricing behavior can be at least partially accounted for by marked changes in pre-IPO ownership structure and insider selling behavior over the period, which reduced key decision, makers' incentives to control underpricing. After controlling for these changes, the difference in underpricing between 1999 and 2000 and the preceding three years is much reduced. Our results suggest that it was firm characteristics that were unique during the "dot-com. bubble" and that pricing behavior followed from incentives created by these characteristics.</description><author>Ljungqvist, A.; Wilhelm, W. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>