<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JF7</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Merton H. Miller: His contribution to financial economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grundy, B. D.
Merton Miller's status as a father of finance reflects the academic depth, breadth, and rigor of his writings and two important facets of his character. Merton was a man of great warmth and humor. He communicated his often challenging views via memorable phrases and anecdotes that have become part of the everyday language of the profession. Merton was also a man of great dedication. The whole profession has benefited from his devotion to his doctoral students, to his colleagues, and to his coauthors. This essay demonstrates how Merton's admiration for markets provided the foundation for all his research.</description><author>Grundy, B. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Merton H. Miller: Memories of a great mentor and leader</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scholes, M. S.
nan</description><author>Scholes, M. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do financial institutions matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, F.
In standard asset pricing theory, investors are assumed to invest directly in financial markets. The role of financial institutions is ignored. The focus in corporate finance is on agency problems. How do you ensure that managers act in shareholders' interests? There is an inconsistency in assuming that when you give your money to a financial institution there is no agency problem, but when you give it to a firm there is. It is argued that both areas need to take proper account of the role of financial institutions and markets. Appropriate concepts for analyzing particular situations should be used.</description><author>Allen, F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The equity premium and structural breaks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, L.; Stambaugh, R. F.
A long return history is useful in estimating the current equity premium even if the historical distribution has experienced structural breaks. The long series helps not only if the timing of breaks is uncertain but also if one believes that large shifts in the premium are unlikely or that the premium is associated, in part, with volatility. Our framework incorporates these features along with a belief that prices are likely to move opposite to contemporaneous shifts in the premium. The estimated premium since 1834 fluctuates between 4 and 6 percent and exhibits its sharpest drop in the last decade.</description><author>Pastor, L.; Stambaugh, R. F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mental accounting, loss aversion, and individual stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barberis, N.; Huang, M.
We study equilibrium firm-level stock returns in two economies: one in which investors are loss averse over the fluctuations of their stock portfolio, and another in which they are loss averse over the fluctuations of individual stocks that they own. Both approaches can shed light on empirical phenomena, but we find the second approach to be more successful: In that economy, the typical individual stock return has a high mean and excess volatility, and there is a large value premium in the cross section which can, to some extent, be captured by a commonly used multifactor model.</description><author>Barberis, N.; Huang, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mental accounting, loss aversion, and individual stock returns - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brennan, M. J.
nan</description><author>Brennan, M. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor psychology and asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, D.
The basic paradigm of asset pricing is in vibrant flux. The purely rational approach is being subsumed by a broader approach based upon the psychology of investors. In this approach, security expected returns are determined by both risk and misvaluation. This survey sketches a framework for understanding decision biases, evaluates the a priori arguments and the capital market evidence bearing on the importance of investor psychology for security prices, and reviews recent models.</description><author>Hirshleifer, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The bright side of internal capital markets - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sapienza, P.
nan</description><author>Sapienza, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The bright side of internal capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khanna, N.; Tice, S.
We examine capital expenditure decisions of discount firms in response to WalMart's entry into their markets. Before Wal-Mart's entry, focused incumbents and discount divisions of diversified incumbents are similar in size, geographic dispersion, and firm debt levels. However, discount divisions of diversified firms are significantly more productive. After Wal-Mart's entry, diversified firms are quicker to either "exit" the discount business or "stay and fight." Also, their capital expenditures are more sensitive to the productivity of their discount business. Internal capital markets function well, as transfers are away from the worsening discount divisions. It appears diversified firms make better investment decisions.</description><author>Khanna, N.; Tice, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Automated versus floor trading: An analysis of execution costs on the Paris and New York exchanges - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madhavan, A.
nan</description><author>Madhavan, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Automated versus floor trading: An analysis of execution costs on the Paris and New York exchanges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Venkataraman, K.
A global trend towards automated trading systems raises the important question of whether execution costs are, in fact, lower than on trading floors. This paper compares the trade execution costs of similar stocks in an automated trading structure (Paris Bourse) and a floor-based trading structure (NYSE). Results indicate that execution costs are higher in Paris than in New York after controlling for differences in adverse selection, relative tick size, and economic attributes across samples. These results suggest that the present form of the automated trading system may not be able to fully replicate the benefits of human intermediation on a trading floor.</description><author>Venkataraman, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contagion as a wealth effect - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ross, S. A.
nan</description><author>Ross, S. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contagion as a wealth effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kyle, A. S.; Xiong, W.
Financial contagion is described as a wealth effect in a continuous-time model with two risky assets and three types of traders. Noise traders trade randomly in one market. Long-term investors provide liquidity using a linear rule based on fundamentals. Convergence traders with logarithmic utility trade optimally in both markets. Asset price dynamics are endogenously determined (numerically) as functions of endogenous wealth and exogenous noise. When convergence traders lose money, they liquidate positions in both markets. This creates contagion, in that returns become more volatile and more correlated. Contagion reduces benefits from portfolio diversification and raises issues for risk management.</description><author>Kyle, A. S.; Xiong, W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectations hypotheses tests - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Richardson, M.
nan</description><author>Richardson, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectations hypotheses tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, G.; Hodrick, R. J.
We investigate the expectations hypotheses of the term structure of interest rates and of the foreign exchange market using vector autoregressive methods for U.S. dollar, Deutsche mark, and British pound interest rates and exchange rates. We examine Wald, Lagrange multiplier, and distance metric tests by iterating on approximate solutions that require only matrix inversions. Bias-corrected, constrained VARs provide Monte Carlo simulations. Wald tests grossly overreject the null, Lagrange multiplier tests slightly underreject, and distance metric tests overreject. A common interpretation emerges from the small sample statistics. The evidence against the expectations hypotheses is much less strong than under asymptotic inference.</description><author>Bekaert, G.; Hodrick, R. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variable selection for portfolio choice - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wachter, J. A.
nan</description><author>Wachter, J. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variable selection for portfolio choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ait-Sahalia, Y.; Brandt, M. W.
We study asset allocation when the conditional moments of returns are partly predictable. Rather than first model the return distribution and subsequently characterize the portfolio choice, we determine directly the dependence of the optimal portfolio weights on the predictive variables. We combine the predictors into a single index that best captures time variations in investment opportunities. This index helps investors determine which economic variables they should track and, more importantly, in what combination. We consider investors with both expected utility (mean variance and CRRA) and nonexpected utility (ambiguity aversion and prospect theory) objectives and characterize their market timing, horizon effects, and hedging demands.</description><author>Ait-Sahalia, Y.; Brandt, M. W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider trading, investment, and liquidity: A welfare analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, S.; Nicodano, G.
We compare equilibrium trading outcomes with and without participation by an informed insider, assuming inflexible ex ante aggregate investment choices by agents. Noise trading arises from aggregate uncertainty regarding other agents' intertemporal consumption preferences. The welfare levels of outsiders can thus be ascertained. The allocations without insider trading are not ex ante Pareto efficient, because our model differs from standard ones with negative exponential utility functions and normal returns. We characterize the circumstances under which the revelation of payoff-relevant information via prices - arising from insider trading-benefits outsiders with stochastic liquidity needs, by improving risk-sharing among them.</description><author>Bhattacharya, S.; Nicodano, G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do money fund managers voluntarily waive their fees?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, S. E. K.
Over half of money fund managers Voluntarily waive fees they have a contractual right to claim. Moreover, as a consequence of fee waivers, funds on average collect one half of reported expense ratios. Variation in fee waivers is significant and relates to differences in relative performance. Both low-performing retail and institutional funds waive fees to improve their net performance. More interestingly, high-performing retail, but not institutional, funds use fee waivers to strategically adjust net performance to increase expected fund flows. Despite fund flow incentives, high-performing institutional funds do not waive more because they cannot significantly improve their relative performance.</description><author>Christoffersen, S. E. K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the term structure of default premia in the swap and LIBOR markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collin-Dufresne, P.; Solnik, B.
Existing theories of the term structure of swap rates provide an analysis of the Treasury-swap spread based on either a liquidity convenience yield in the Treasury market, or default risk in the swap market. Although these models do not focus on the relation between corporate yields and swap rates (the LIBOR-swap spread), they imply that the term structure of corporate yields and swap rates should be identical. As documented previously (e.g., in Sun, Sundaresan, and Wang (1993)) this is counterfactual. Here, we propose a model of the default risk imbedded in the swap term structure that is able to explain the LIBOR-swap spread. Whereas corporate bonds carry default risk, we argue that swap contracts are free of default risk. Because swaps are indexed on "refreshed"-credit-quality LIBOR rates, the spread between corporate yields and swap rates should capture the market's expectations of the probability of deterioration in credit quality of a corporate bond issuer. We model this feature and use our model to estimate the likelihood of future deterioration in credit quality from the LIBOR-swap spread. The analysis is important because it shows that the term structure of swap rates does not reflect the borrowing cost of a standard LIBOR credit quality issuer. It also has implications for modeling the dynamics of the swap term structure.</description><author>Collin-Dufresne, P.; Solnik, B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the timing ability of mutual fund managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, N. P. B.; Busse, J. A.
Existing studies of mutual fund market timing analyze monthly returns and find little evidence of timing ability. We show that daily tests are more powerful and that mutual funds exhibit significant timing ability more often in daily tests than in monthly tests. We construct a set of synthetic fund returns in order to control for spurious results. The daily timing coefficients of the majority of funds are significantly different from their synthetic counterparts. These results suggest that mutual funds may possess more timing ability than previously documented.</description><author>Bollen, N. P. B.; Busse, J. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption, aggregate wealth, and expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lettau, M.; Ludvigson, S.
This paper studies the role of fluctuations in the aggregate consumption-wealth ratio for predicting stock returns. Using U.S, quarterly stock market data, we find that these fluctuations in the consumption-wealth ratio are strong predictors of both real stock returns and excess returns over a Treasury bill rate. We also find that this variable is a better forecaster of future returns at short and intermediate horizons than is the dividend yield, the dividend payout ratio, and several other popular forecasting variables. Why should the consumption-wealth ratio forecast asset returns? We show that a wide class of optimal models of consumer behavior imply that the log consumption-aggregate wealth (human capital plus asset holdings) ratio summarizes expected returns on aggregate wealth, or the market portfolio. Although this ratio is not observable, we provide assumptions under which its important predictive components for future asset returns may be expressed in terms of observable variables, namely in terms of consumption, asset holdings and labor income. The framework implies that these variables are cointegrated, and that deviations from this shared trend summarize agents' expectations of future returns on the market portfolio.</description><author>Lettau, M.; Ludvigson, S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How distance, language, and culture influence stockholdings and trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, M.; Keloharju, M.
This paper documents that investors are more likely to hold, buy, and sell the stocks of Finnish firms that are located close to the investor, that communicate in the investor's native tongue, and that have chief executives of the same cultural background. The influence of distance, language, and culture is less prominent among the most investment-savvy institutions than among both households and less savvy institutions. Regression analysis indicates that the marginal effect of distance is less for firms that are more nationally known, for distances that exceed 100 kilometers, and for investors with more diversified portfolios.</description><author>Grinblatt, M.; Keloharju, M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do depositors punish banks for bad behavior? Market discipline, deposit insurance, and banking crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peria, M. S. M.; Schmukler, S. L.
This paper empirically investigates two issues largely unexplored by the literature on market discipline. We evaluate the interaction between market discipline and deposit insurance and the impact of banking crises on market discipline. We focus on the experiences of Argentina, Chile, and Mexico during the 1980s and 1990s. We find that depositors discipline banks by withdrawing deposits and by requiring higher interest rates. Deposit insurance does not appear to diminish the extent of market discipline. Aggregate shocks affect deposits and interest rates during crises, regardless of bank fundamentals, and investors' responsiveness to bank risk taking increases in the aftermath of crises.</description><author>Peria, M. S. M.; Schmukler, S. L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An exploration of Neo-Austrian theory applied to financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benink, H.; Bossaerts, P.
We attempt to translate Neo-Austrian ideas about the workings of financial markets, as originally advanced by F.A. Hayek, into the standard probabilistic language of modern finance. We focus on an apparent paradox, namely the insistence of Neo-Austrians on order (i.e., stationarity) together with ever-reemerging inefficiencies. The paper's findings have implications beyond Neo-Austrian theory: They demonstrate how easy it is to reject market efficiency, but how much more difficult it is to discern the nature of the inefficiency. We illustrate our findings with price data from the U.S. Treasury bill market over the period 1962 to 1999. There is ample evidence that the price of a three-month Treasury bill is not a random walk, yet the sign of the average price change is erratic, so that inference about the nature of the inefficiency is unreliable.</description><author>Benink, H.; Bossaerts, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected option returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coval, J. D.; Shumway, T.
This paper examines expected option returns in the context of mainstream asset-pricing theory. Under mild assumptions, expected call returns exceed those of the underlying security and increase with the strike price. Likewise, expected put returns are below the risk-free rate and increase with the strike price. S&amp;P index option returns consistently exhibit these characteristics. Under stronger assumptions, expected option returns vary linearly with option betas. However, zero-beta, at-the-money straddle positions produce average losses of approximately three percent per week. This suggests that some additional factor, such as systematic stochastic volatility, is priced in option returns.</description><author>Coval, J. D.; Shumway, T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The efficient use of conditioning information in portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, W. E.; Siegel, A. F.
We study the properties of unconditional minimum-variance portfolios in the presence of conditioning information. Such portfolios attain the smallest Variance for a given mean among all possible portfolios formed using the conditioning information. We provide explicit solutions for n risky assets, either with or without a riskless asset. Our solutions provide insights into portfolio management problems and issues in conditional asset pricing.</description><author>Ferson, W. E.; Siegel, A. F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overconfidence, arbitrage, and equilibrium asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daniel, K. D.; Hirshleifer, D.; Subrahmanyam, A.
This paper offers a model in which asset prices reflect both covariance risk and misperceptions of firms' prospects, and in which arbitrageurs trade against mispricing. In equilibrium, expected returns are linearly related to both risk and mispricing measures (e.g., fundamental/price ratios). With many securities, mispricing of idiosyncratic value components diminishes but systematic mispricing does not. The theory offers untested empirical implications about volume, volatility, fundamental/price ratios, and mean returns, and is consistent with several empirical findings. These include the ability of fundamental/price ratios and market value to forecast returns, and the domination of beta by these variables in some studies.</description><author>Daniel, K. D.; Hirshleifer, D.; Subrahmanyam, A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The high-volume return premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gervais, S.; Kaniel, R.; Mingelgrin, D. H.
The idea that extreme trading activity contains information about the future evolution of stock prices is investigated. We find that stocks experiencing unusually high (low) trading volume over a day or a week tend to appreciate (depreciate) over the course of the following month. We argue that this high-volume return premium is consistent with the idea that shocks in the trading activity of a stock affect its visibility, and in turn the subsequent demand and price for that stock. Return autocorrelations, firm announcements, market risk, and liquidity do not seem to explain our results.</description><author>Gervais, S.; Kaniel, R.; Mingelgrin, D. H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underreaction, overreaction, and increasing misreaction to information in the options market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poteshman, A. M.
This paper investigates options market reaction to changes in the instantaneous Variance of the underlying asset. There are three main findings. First, options market investors underreact to individual daily changes in instantaneous variance. Second, these same investors overreact to periods of mostly increasing or mostly decreasing daily changes in instantaneous variance. Third, they tend to underreact (overreact) to current daily changes in instantaneous variance that are preceded mostly by daily changes of the opposite (same) sign. The third finding can reconcile the first two and is also consistent with well-established cognitive biases.</description><author>Poteshman, A. M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal portfolio choice for long-horizon investors with nontradable labor income</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Viceira, L. M.
This paper examines how risky labor income and retirement affect optimal portfolio choice. With idiosyncratic labor income risk, the optimal allocation to stocks is unambiguously larger for employed investors than for retired investors, consistent with the typical recommendations of investment advisors. Increasing idiosyncratic labor income risk raises investors' willingness to save and reduces their stock portfolio allocation towards the level of retired investors. Positive correlation between labor income and stock returns has a further negative effect and can actually reduce stockholdings below the level of retired investors.</description><author>Viceira, L. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The expiration of IPO share lockups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Field, L. C.; Hanka, G.
We examine 1,948 share lockup agreements that prevent insiders from selling their shares in the period immediately after the IPO (typically 180 days). While lockups are in effect, there is little selling by insiders. When lockups expire, we find a permanent 40 percent increase in average trading volume, and a statistically prominent three-day abnormal return of -1.5 percent. The abnormal return and volume are much larger when the firm is financed by venture capital, and we find that venture capitalists sell more aggressively than executives and other shareholders. We find limited support for several hypotheses that may explain the abnormal return, but no complete explanation.</description><author>Field, L. C.; Hanka, G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market liquidity and trading activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, T.; Roll, R.; Subrahmanyam, A.
Previous studies of liquidity span short time periods and focus on the individual security. In contrast, we study aggregate market spreads, depths, and trading activity for U.S. equities over an extended time sample. Daily changes in market averages of liquidity and trading activity are highly volatile and negatively serially dependent. Liquidity plummets significantly in down markets. Recent market volatility induces a decrease in trading activity and spreads. There are strong day-of-the-week effects; Fridays accompany a significant decrease in trading activity and liquidity, while Tuesdays display the opposite pattern. Long- and short-term interest rates influence liquidity. Depth and trading activity increase just prior to major macroeconomic announcements.</description><author>Chordia, T.; Roll, R.; Subrahmanyam, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Investors Profit from the Prophets? Security Analyst Recommendations and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, B.; Lehavy, R.; McNichols, M.; Trueman, B.
We document that purchasing (selling short) stocks with the most (least) favorable consensus recommendations, in conjunction with daily portfolio rebalancing and a timely response to recommendation changes, yield annual abnormal gross returns greater than four percent. Less frequent portfolio rebalancing or a delay in reacting to recommendation changes diminishes these returns; however, they remain significant for the least favorably rated stocks. We also show that high trading levels are required to capture the excess returns generated by the strategies analyzed, entailing substantial transactions costs and leading to abnormal net returns for these strategies that are not reliably greater than zero.</description><author>Barber, B.; Lehavy, R.; McNichols, M.; Trueman, B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation and control in venture finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kirilenko, A. A.
This paper presents the model of a relationship between a venture capitalist and an entrepreneur engaged in the formation of a new firm. I assume that the entrepreneur derives private nonpecuniary benefits from having some control over the firm. I show that to separate the entrepreneur's value of control from the firm's expected payoff, the venture capitalist demands disproportionately higher control rights than the size of his equity investment. The entrepreneur is compensated for a greater loss of control through better terms of financing, ability to extract higher rents from asymmetric information, and improved risk sharing.</description><author>Kirilenko, A. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What makes investors trade?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, M.; Keloharju, M.
A unique data set allows us to monitor the buys, sells, and holds of individuals and institutions in the Finnish stock market on a daily basis. With this data set, we employ Logit regressions to identify the determinants of buying and selling activity over a two-year period. We find evidence that investors are reluctant to realize losses, that they engage in tax-loss selling activity, and that past returns and historical price patterns, such as being at a monthly high or low, affect trading. There also is modest evidence that life-cycle trading plays a role in the pattern of buys and sells.</description><author>Grinblatt, M.; Keloharju, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking market structure, financial dependence and growth: International evidence from industry data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cetorelli, N.; Gambera, M.
This paper explores the empirical relevance of banking market structure on growth. There is substantial evidence of a positive relationship between the level of development of the banking sector of an economy and its long-run output growth. Little is known, however, about the role played by the market structure of the banking sector on the dynamics of capital accumulation. This paper provides evidence that bank concentration promotes the growth of those industrial sectors that are more in need of external finance by facilitating credit access to younger firms. However, we also find evidence of a general depressing effect on growth associated with a concentrated banking industry, which impacts all sectors and all firms indiscriminately.</description><author>Cetorelli, N.; Gambera, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme correlation of international equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longin, F.; Solnik, B.
Testing the hypothesis that international equity market correlation increases in volatile times is a difficult exercise and misleading results have often been reported in the past because of a spurious relationship between correlation and volatility. Using "extreme value theory" to model the multivariate distribution tails, we derive the distribution of extreme correlation for a wide class of return distributions. Empirically, we reject the null hypothesis of multivariate normality for the negative tail, but not for the positive tail. We also find that correlation is not related to market volatility per se but to the market trend. Correlation increases in bear markets, but not in bull markets.</description><author>Longin, F.; Solnik, B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate bond trading costs: a peek behind the curtain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, P.
In this paper, I use institutional corporate bond trade data to estimate transactions costs in the over-the-counter bond market. I find average round-trip trading costs to be about $0.27 per $100 of par value. Trading costs are lower for larger trades. Small institutions pay more to trade than large institutions, all else being equal. Small bond dealers charge more than large ones. I find no evidence that trading costs more for lower-rated bonds.</description><author>Schultz, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Profitability of momentum strategies: An evaluation of alternative explanations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jegadeesh, N.; Titman, S.
This paper evaluates various explanations for the profitability of momentum strategies documented in Jegadeesh and Titman (1993). The evidence indicates that momentum profits have continued in the 1990s, suggesting that the original results were not a product of data snooping bias. The paper also examines the predictions of recent behavioral models that propose that momentum profits are due to delayed overreactions that are eventually reversed. Our evidence provides support for the behavioral models, but this support should be tempered with caution.</description><author>Jegadeesh, N.; Titman, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing for mean-variance spanning with short sales constraints and transaction costs: the case of emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Roon, F. A.; Nijman, T. E.; Werker, B. J. M.
We propose regression-based tests for mean-variance spanning in the case where investors face market frictions such as short sales constraints and transaction costs. We test whether U.S. investors can extend their efficient set by investing in emerging markets when accounting for such frictions. For the period after the major liberalizations in the emerging markets, we find strong evidence for diversification benefits when market frictions are excluded, but this evidence disappears when investors face short sales constraints or small transaction costs. Although simulations suggest that there is a possible small-sample bias, this bias appears to be too small to affect our conclusions.</description><author>De Roon, F. A.; Nijman, T. E.; Werker, B. J. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining the cross-section of stock returns in Japan: Factors or characteristics?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daniel, K.; Titman, S.; Wei, K. C. J.
Japanese stock returns are even more closely related to their hook-to-market ratios than are their U.S. counterparts, and thus provide a good setting for testing whether the return premia associated with these characteristics arise because the characteristics are proxies for covariance with priced factors. Our tests, which replicate the Daniel and Titman (1997) tests on a Japanese sample, reject the Fama and French (1993) three-factor model, but fail to reject the characteristic model.</description><author>Daniel, K.; Titman, S.; Wei, K. C. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the perils of financial intermediaries setting security prices: The mutual fund wild card option</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chalmers, J. M. R.; Edelen, R. M.; Kadlec, G. B.
Economic distortions can arise when financial claims trade at prices set by an intermediary rather than direct negotiation between principals. We demonstrate the problem in a specific context, the exchange of open-end mutual fund shares. Mutual funds typically set fund share price (NAV) using an algorithm that fails to account for nonsynchronous trading in the fund's underlying securities. This results in predictable changes in NAV, which lead to exploitable trading opportunities. A modification to the pricing algorithm that corrects for nonsynchronous trading eliminates much of the predictability. However, there are many other potential sources of distortion when intermediaries set prices.</description><author>Chalmers, J. M. R.; Edelen, R. M.; Kadlec, G. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Characteristics of risk and return in risk arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitchell, M.; Pulvino, T.
This paper analyzes 4,750 mergers from 1963 to 1998 to characterize the risk and return in risk arbitrage. Results indicate that risk arbitrage returns are positively correlated with market returns in severely depreciating markets but uncorrelated with market returns in flat and appreciating markets. This suggests that returns to risk arbitrage are similar to those obtained from selling uncovered index put options. Using a contingent claims analysis that controls for the nonlinear relationship with market returns, and after controlling for transaction costs, we find that risk arbitrage generates excess returns of four percent per year.</description><author>Mitchell, M.; Pulvino, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend changes and future profitability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nissim, D.; Ziv, A.
We investigate the relation between dividend changes and future profitability, measured in terms of either future earnings or future abnormal earnings. Supporting "the information content of dividends hypothesis," we find that dividend changes provide information about the level of profitability in subsequent years, incremental to market and accounting data. We also document that dividend changes are positively related to earnings changes in each of the two years after the dividend change.</description><author>Nissim, D.; Ziv, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relative valuation of caps and swaptions: Theory and empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, F. A.; Santa-Clara, P.; Schwartz, E. S.
Although traded as distinct products, caps and swaptions are linked by no-arbitrage relations through the correlation structure of interest rates. Using a string market model, we solve for the correlation matrix implied by swaptions and examine the relative valuation of caps and swaptions. We find that swaption prices are generated by four factors and that implied correlations are lower than historical correlations. Long-dated swaptions appear mispriced and there were major pricing distortions during the 1998 hedge-fund crisis. Cap prices periodically deviate significantly from the no-arbitrage values implied by the swaptions market.</description><author>Longstaff, F. A.; Santa-Clara, P.; Schwartz, E. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market for corporate assets: Who engages in mergers and asset sales and are there efficiency gains?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maksimovic, V.; Phillips, G.
We analyze the market for corporate assets. There is an active market for corporate assets, with close to seven percent of plants changing ownership annually through mergers, acquisitions, and asset sales in peak expansion years. The probability of asset sales and whole-firm transactions is related to firm organization and ex ante efficiency of buyers and sellers. The timing of sales and the pattern of efficiency gains suggests that the transactions that occur, especially through asset sales of plants and divisions, tend to improve the allocation of resources and are consistent with a simple neoclassical model of profit maximizing by firms.</description><author>Maksimovic, V.; Phillips, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limit orders, depth, and volatility: Evidence from the stock exchange of Hong Kong</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, H. J.; Bae, K. H.; Chan, K.
We investigate the role of limit orders in the liquidity provision in a pure order-driven market. Results show that market depth rises subsequent to an increase in transitory volatility, and transitory volatility declines subsequent to an increase in market depth. We also examine how transitory volatility affects the mix between limit orders and market orders. When transitory volatility arises from the ask (bid) side, investors will submit more limit sell (buy) orders than market sell (buy) orders. This result is consistent with the existence of limit-order traders who enter the market and place orders when liquidity is needed.</description><author>Ahn, H. J.; Bae, K. H.; Chan, K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of options illiquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brenner, M.; Eldor, R.; Hauser, S.
The purpose of this paper is to examine the effect of illiquidity on the value of currency options. We use a unique dataset that allows us to explore this issue in special circumstances where options are issued by a central bank and are not traded prior to maturity. The value of these options is compared to similar options traded on the exchange. We find that the nontradable options are priced about 21 percent less than the exchange-traded options. This gap cannot be arbitraged away due to transactions costs and the risk that the exchange rate will change during the bidding process.</description><author>Brenner, M.; Eldor, R.; Hauser, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of credit spread changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collin-Dufresne, P.; Goldstein, R. S.; Martin, J. S.
Using dealer's quotes and transactions prices on straight industrial bonds, we investigate the determinants of credit spread changes. Variables that should in theory determine credit spread changes have rather limited explanatory power. Further, the residuals from this regression are highly cross-correlated, and principal components analysis implies they are mostly driven by a single common factor. Although we consider several macroeconomic and financial variables as candidate proxies, we cannot explain this common systematic component. Our results suggest that monthly credit spread changes are principally driven by local supply/demand shocks that are independent of both credit-risk factors and standard proxies for liquidity.</description><author>Collin-Dufresne, P.; Goldstein, R. S.; Martin, J. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of the syndicate: Form follows function</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pichler, P.; Wilhelm, W.
We relate the organizational form of investment banking syndicates to moral hazard in team production. Although syndicates are dissolved upon deal completion, membership stability across deals represents a barrier to entry that enables the capture of quasi-rents. This improves incentives for individual bankers to cultivate investor relationships that translate into greater expected proceeds. Reputational concerns of lead bankers amplify the effect. We derive conditions under which restricted entry and designation of a lead banker strictly Pareto dominate, in which case it is also strictly Pareto dominant for the syndicate's fee to be greater than members' cost of participation.</description><author>Pichler, P.; Wilhelm, W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal monitoring mechanisms and CEO turnover: A long-term perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huson, M. R.; Parrino, R.; Starks, L. T.
We report evidence on chief executive officer (CEO) turnover during the 1971 to 1994 period. We find that the nature of CEO turnover activity has changed over time. The frequencies of forced CEO turnover and outside succession both increased. However, the relation between the likelihood of forced CEO turnover and firm performance did not change significantly from the beginning to the end of the period we examine, despite substantial changes in internal governance mechanisms. The evidence also indicates that changes in the intensity of the takeover market are not associated with changes in the sensitivity of CEO turnover to firm performance.</description><author>Huson, M. R.; Parrino, R.; Starks, L. T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating mutual fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kothari, S. P.; Warner, J. B.
We study standard mutual fund performance measures, using simulated funds whose characteristics mimic actual funds. We find that performance measures used in previous mutual fund research have little ability to detect economically large magnitudes (e.g., three percent per year) of abnormal fund performance, particularly if a fund's style characteristics differ from those of the value-weighted market portfolio. Power can be substantially improved, however, using event-study procedures that analyze a fund's stock trades. These procedures are feasible using time-series data sets on mutual fund portfolio holdings.</description><author>Kothari, S. P.; Warner, J. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Location matters: An examination of trading profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hau, H.
The electronic trading system Xetra of the German Security Exchange provides a unique data source on the equity trades of 756 professional traders located in 23 different cities and eight European countries. We explore informational asymmetries across the trader population: Traders located outside Germany in non-German-speaking cities show lower proprietary trading profit. Their underperformance is not only statistically significant, it is also of economically significant magnitude and occurs for the 11 largest German blue-chip stocks. We also examine whether a trader location in Frankfurt as the financial center, or local proximity of the trader to the corporate headquarters of the traded stock, or affiliation with a large financial institution results in superior trading performance, The data provide no evidence for a financial center advantage or of increasing institutional scale economies in proprietary trading. However, we find evidence for an information advantage due to corporate headquarters proximity for high-frequency (intraday) trading.</description><author>Hau, H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do credit spreads reflect stationary leverage ratios?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collin-Dufresne, P.; Goldstein, R. S.
Most structural models of default preclude the firm from altering its capital structure. In practice, firms adjust outstanding debt levels in response to changes in firm value, thus generating mean-reverting leverage ratios. We propose a structural model of default with stochastic interest rates that captures this mean reversion. Our model generates credit spreads that are larger for low-leverage firms, and less sensitive to changes in firm value, both of which are more consistent with empirical findings than predictions of extant models. Further, the term structure of credit spreads can be upward sloping for speculative-grade debt, consistent with recent empirical findings.</description><author>Collin-Dufresne, P.; Goldstein, R. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Massively confused investors making conspicuously ignorant choices (MCI-MCIC)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rashes, M. S.
This paper examines the comovement of stocks with similar ticker symbols. For one such pair of firms, there is a significant correlation between returns, volume, and volatility at short frequencies. Deviations from "fundamental value" tend to be reversed within several days, although there is some evidence that the return comovement persists for longer horizons. Arbitrageurs appear to be limited in their ability to eliminate these deviations from fundamentals. This anomaly allows the observation of noise traders and their effect on stock prices independent of changes in information and expectations.</description><author>Rashes, M. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is sound just noise?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coval, J. D.; Shumway, T.
We analyze the information content of the ambient noise level in the Chicago Board of Trade's 30-year Treasury Bond futures trading pit. Controlling for a variety of other variables, including lagged price changes, trading volumes, and news announcements, we find that the sound level conveys information which is highly economically and statistically significant. Specifically, changes in the sound level forecast changes in the cost of transacting. Following a rise in the sound level, prices become more volatile, depth declines, and information asymmetry increases. Our results offer important implications for the future of open outcry and floor-based trading mechanisms.</description><author>Coval, J. D.; Shumway, T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Careers and survival: Competition and risk in the hedge fund and CTA industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, S. J.; Goetzmann, W. N.; Park, J.
Investors in hedge funds and commodity trading advisors (CTAs) are concerned with risk as well as return. We investigate the volatility of hedge funds and CTAs in light of managerial career concerns. We find an association between past performance and risk levels consistent with previous findings for mutual fund managers. Variance shifts depend upon relative rather than absolute fund performance. The importance of relative rankings points to the importance of reputation costs in the investment industry. Our analysis of factors contributing to fund disappearance shows that survival depends on absolute and relative performance, excess volatility, and on fund age.</description><author>Brown, S. J.; Goetzmann, W. N.; Park, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>LAPM: A liquidity-based asset pricing model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holmstrom, B.; Tirole, J.
The intertemporal CAPM predicts that an asset's price is equal to the expectation of the product of the asset's payoff and a representative consumer's intertemporal marginal rate of substitution. This paper develops an alternative approach to asset pricing based on corporations' desire to hoard liquidity. Our corporate finance approach suggests new determinants of asset prices such as the distribution of wealth within the corporate sector and between the corporate sector and the consumers. Also, leverage ratios, capital adequacy requirements, and the composition of savings affect the corporate demand for liquid assets and, thereby, interest rates.</description><author>Holmstrom, B.; Tirole, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>True spreads and equilibrium prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ball, C. A.; Chordia, T.
Stocks and other financial assets are traded at prices that lie on a fixed grid determined by the minimum tick size. Observed prices and quoted spreads do not correspond to the equilibrium prices and true spreads that would exist in a market with no minimum tick size, Using Monte Carlo Markov Chain methods, this paper estimates the equilibrium prices and true spreads. For large stocks, most of the quoted spread is attributable to the rounding of prices and the adverse selection component is small. The true spread and the adverse selection component are greater for mid-sized stocks.</description><author>Ball, C. A.; Chordia, T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Counterparty risk and the pricing of defaultable securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jarrow, R. A.; Yu, F.
Motivated by recent financial crises in East Asia and the United States where the downfall of a small number of firms had an economy-wide impact, this paper generalizes existing reduced-form models to include default intensities dependent on the default of a counterparty. In this model, firms have correlated defaults due not only to an exposure to common risk factors, but also to firm-specific risks that are termed "counterparty risks." Numerical examples illustrate the effect of counterparty risk on the pricing of defaultable bonds and credit derivatives such as default swaps.</description><author>Jarrow, R. A.; Yu, F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Excessive extrapolation and the allocation of 401(k) accounts to company stock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benartzi, S.
About a third of the assets in large retirement savings plans are invested in company stock, and about a quarter of the discretionary contributions are invested in company stock. From a diversification perspective, this is a dubious strategy. This paper explores the role of excessive extrapolation in employees' company stock holdings. I find that employees of firms that experienced the worst stock performance over the last 10 years allocate 10.37 percent of their discretionary contributions to company stock, whereas employees whose firms experienced the best stock performance allocate 39.70 percent. Allocations to company stock, however, do not predict future performance.</description><author>Benartzi, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Upstairs market for principal and agency trades: Analysis of adverse information and price effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smith, B. F.; Turnbull, D. A. S.; White, R. W.
This paper directly tests the hypothesis that upstairs intermediation lowers adverse selection cost. We find upstairs market makers effectively screen out information-motivated orders and execute large liquidity-motivated orders at a lower cost than the downstairs market. Upstairs markets do not cannibalize or free ride off the downstairs market. In one-quarter of the trades, the upstairs market offers price improvement over the limit orders available in the consolidated limit order book, Trades are more likely to be executed upstairs at times when liquidity is lower in the downstairs market.</description><author>Smith, B. F.; Turnbull, D. A. S.; White, R. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The diversification discount: Cash flows versus returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lamont, O. A.; Polk, C.
Diversified firms have different values from comparable portfolios of single-segment firms. These value differences must be due to differences in either future cash flows or future returns. Expected security returns on diversified firms vary systematically with relative value. Discount firms have significantly higher subsequent returns than premium firms. Slightly more than half of the cross-sectional variation in excess values is due to variation in expected future cash flows, with the remainder due to variation in expected future returns and to covariation between cash flows and returns.</description><author>Lamont, O. A.; Polk, C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is it inefficient investment that causes the diversification discount?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Whited, T. M.
Diversified conglomerates are valued less than matched portfolios of pure-play firms. Recent studies find that this diversification discount results from conglomerates' inefficient allocation of capital expenditures across divisions. Much of this work uses Tobin's q as a proxy for investment opportunities, therefore hypothesizing that q is a good proxy. This paper treats measurement error in q. Using a measurement-error consistent estimator on the sorts regressions in the literature, I find no evidence of inefficient allocation of investment. The results in the literature appear to be artifacts of measurement error and of the correlation between investment opportunities and liquidity.</description><author>Whited, T. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity premia as low as three percent? Evidence from analysts' earnings forecasts for domestic and international stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claus, J.; Thomas, J.
The returns earned by U.S. equities since 1926 exceed estimates derived from theory, from other periods and markets, and from surveys of institutional investors. Rather than examine historic experience, we estimate the equity premium from the discount rate that equates market valuations with prevailing expectations of future flows. The accounting flows we project are isomorphic to projected dividends but use more available information and narrow the range of reasonable growth rates. For each year between 1985 and 1998, we find that the equity premium is around three percent (or less) in the United States and five other markets.</description><author>Claus, J.; Thomas, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The stock market valuation of research and development expenditures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, L. K. C.; Lakonishok, J.; Sougiannis, T.
We examine whether stock prices fully value firms' intangible assets, specifically research and development (R&amp;D). Under current U.S. accounting standards, financial statements do not report intangible assets and R&amp;D spending is expensed. Nonetheless, the average historical stock returns of firms doing R&amp;D matches the returns of firms without R&amp;D. However, the market is apparently too pessimistic about beaten-down R&amp;D-intensive technology stocks' prospects. Companies with high R&amp;D to equity market value (which tend to have poor past returns) earn large excess returns. A similar relation exists between advertising and stock returns. R&amp;D intensity is positively associated with return volatility.</description><author>Chan, L. K. C.; Lakonishok, J.; Sougiannis, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A first look at the accuracy of the CRSP mutual fund database and a comparison of the CRSP and morningstar mutual fund databases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.; Blake, C. R.
This paper examines problems in the CRSP Survivor Bias Free U.S. Mutual Fund Database (CRSP, 1998) and compares returns contained in it to those in Morning-star. The CRSP database has an omission bias that has the same effects as survivorship bias. Although all mutual funds are listed in CRSP, return data is missing for many and the characteristics of these funds differ from the populations. The CRSP return data is biased upward and merger months are inaccurately recorded about half the time. Differences in returns in Morningstar and CRSP are a problem for older data and small funds.</description><author>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.; Blake, C. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Feedback from stock prices to cash flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Subrahmanyam, A.; Titman, S.
Feedback from financial market prices to cash flows arises when a firm's non-financial stakeholders, for example, its customers, employees, and suppliers, make decisions that are contingent on the information revealed by the price. Complementarities across stakeholders result in cascades, wherein relatively small stock price moves trigger substantial changes in asset values. This paper analyzes the relation between such feedback effects and parameters such as the information cost, the volatility of existing projects, the risk aversion of liquidity suppliers, and the precision of managerial information.</description><author>Subrahmanyam, A.; Titman, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A rose.com by any other name</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, M. J.; Dimitrov, O.; Rau, P. R.
We document a striking positive stock price reaction to the announcement of corporate name changes to Internet-related dotcom names. This "dotcom" effect produces cumulative abnormal returns on the order of 74 percent for the 10 days surrounding the announcement day. The effect does not appear to be transitory; there is no evidence of a postannouncement negative drift. The announcement day effect is also similar across all firms, regardless of the firm's level of involvement with the Internet. A mere association with the Internet seems enough to provide a firm with a large and permanent value increase.</description><author>Cooper, M. J.; Dimitrov, O.; Rau, P. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bookbuilding and strategic allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornelli, F.; Goldreich, D.
In the bookbuilding procedure, an investment banker solicits bids for shares from institutional investors prior to pricing an equity issue. The banker then prices the issue and allocates shares at his discretion to the investors. We examine the books for 39 international equity issues. We find that the investment banker awards more shares to bidders who provide information in their bids. Regular investors receive favorable allocations, especially when the issue is heavily oversubscribed. The investment banker also favors revised bids and domestic investors.</description><author>Cornelli, F.; Goldreich, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive compensation and corporate acquisition decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Datta, S.; Iskandar-Datta, M.; Raman, K.
By examining how executive compensation structure determines corporate acquisition decisions, we document a strong positive relation between acquiring managers' equity-based compensation (EBC) and stock price performance around and following acquisition announcements. This relation is highly robust when we control for acquisition mode (mergers), means of payment, managerial ownership, and previous option grants. Compared to low EBC managers, high EBC managers pay lower acquisition premiums, acquire targets with higher growth opportunities, and make acquisitions engendering larger increases in firm risk. EBC significantly explains postacquisition stock price performance even after controlling for acquisition mode, means of payment, and "glamour" versus "value" acquirers.</description><author>Datta, S.; Iskandar-Datta, M.; Raman, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selection editor's introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, F.
nan</description><author>Allen, F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Friction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoll, H. R.
The sources of trading friction are studied, and simple, robust empirical measures of friction are provided. Seven distinct measures of trading friction are computed from transactions data for 1,706 NYSE/AMSE stocks and 2,184 Nasdaq stocks. The measures provide insights into the magnitude of trading costs, the importance of informational versus real frictions, and the role of market structure. The degree to which the various measures are associated with each other and with trading characteristics of stocks is examined.</description><author>Stoll, H. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing at the millennium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, J. Y.
This paper surveys the field of asset pricing. The emphasis is on the interplay between theory and empirical work and on the trade-off between risk and return. Modern research seeks to understand the behavior of the stochastic discount factor (SDF) that prices all assets in the Economy. The behavior of the term structure of real interest rates restricts the conditional mean of the SDF, whereas patterns of risk premia restrict its conditional volatility and factor structure. Stylized facts about interest rates, aggregate stock prices, and cross-sectional patterns in stock returns have stimulated new research on optimal portfolio choice, intertemporal equilibrium models, and behavioral finance.</description><author>Campbell, J. Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Continuous-time methods in finance: A review and an assessment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sundaresan, S. M.
I survey and assess the development of continuous-time methods in finance during the last 30 years, The subperiod 1969 to 1980 saw a dizzying pace of development with seminal ideas in derivatives securities pricing, term structure theory, asset pricing, and optimal consumption and portfolio choices. During the period 1981 to 1999 the theory has been extended and modified to better explain empirical regularities in various subfields of finance. This latter subperiod has seen significant progress in econometric theory, computational and estimation methods to test and implement continuous-time models. Capital market frictions and bargaining issues are being increasingly incorporated in continuous-time theory.</description><author>Sundaresan, S. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In search of new foundations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zingales, L.
In this paper I argue that corporate finance theory, empirical research, practical applications, and policy recommendations are deeply rooted in an underlying theory of the firm. I also argue that although the existing theories have delivered very important and useful insights, they seem to be quite ineffective in helping us cope with the new type of firms that is emerging. I outline the characteristics that a new theory of the firm should satisfy and how such a theory could change the way we do corporate finance, both theoretically and empirically.</description><author>Zingales, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund performance: An empirical decomposition into stock-picking talent, style, transactions costs, and expenses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wermers, R.
We use a new database to perform a comprehensive analysis of the mutual fund industry. We find that funds hold stocks that outperform the market by 1.3 percent per year, but their net returns underperform by one percent. Of the 2.3 percent difference between these results, 0.7 percent is due to the underperformance of nonstock holdings, whereas 1.6 percent is due to expenses and transactions costs. Thus, funds Dick stocks well enough to cover their costs. Also, high-turnover funds beat the Vanguard Index 500 fund on a net return basis. Our evidence supports the value of active mutual fund management.</description><author>Wermers, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund performance: An empirical decomposition into stock-picking talent, style, transactions costs, and expenses - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moskowitz, T. J.
nan</description><author>Moskowitz, T. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foundations of technical analysis: Computational algorithms, statistical inference, and empirical implementation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lo, A. W.; Mamaysky, H.; Wang, J.
Technical analysis, also known as "charting," has been a part of financial practice for many decades, but this discipline has not received the same level of academic scrutiny and acceptance as more traditional approaches such as fundamental analysis. One of the main obstacles is the highly subjective nature of technical analysis-the presence of geometric shapes in historical price charts is often in the eyes of the: beholder. In this paper, we propose a systematic and automatic approach to technical pattern recognition using nonparametric kernel regression, and we apply this method to a large number of U.S. stocks from 1962 to 1996 to evaluate the effectiveness of technical analysis. By comparing the unconditional empirical distribution of daily stock returns to the conditional distribution-conditioned on specific technical indicators such as head-and-shoulders or double-bottoms-we find that over the 31-year sample period, several technical indicators do provide incremental information and may have some practical value.</description><author>Lo, A. W.; Mamaysky, H.; Wang, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foundations of technical analysis: Computational algorithms, statistical inference, and empirical implementation - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jegadeesh, N.
nan</description><author>Jegadeesh, N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order flow and liquidity around NYSE trading halts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corwin, S. A.; Lipson, M. L.
We study order flow and liquidity around NYSE trading halts. We find that market and limit order submissions and cancellations increase significantly during trading halts, that a large proportion of the limit order book at the reopen is composed of orders submitted during the halt, and that the market-clearing price at the reopen is a good predictor of future prices. Depth near the quotes is unusually low around trading halts, though specialists and/or floor traders appear to provide additional liquidity at these times. Finally, specialists appear to "spread the quote" prior to imbalance halts to convey information to market participants.</description><author>Corwin, S. A.; Lipson, M. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order flow and liquidity around NYSE trading halts - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weaver, D. G.
nan</description><author>Weaver, D. G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate reorganizations and non-cash auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rhodes-Kropf, M.; Viswanathan, S.
This paper extends the theory of non-cash auctions by considering the revenue and efficiency of using different securities. Research on bankruptcy and privatization suggests using non-cash auctions to increase cash-constrained bidder participation. We examine this proposal and demonstrate that securities may lead to higher revenue. However, bidders pool unless bids include debt, which results in possible repossession by the seller. This suggests all-equity outcomes are unlikely and explains the high debt of reorganized firms. Securities also inefficiently determine bidders' incentive contracts and the firm's capital structure. Therefore, we recommend a new cash auction for an incentive contract.</description><author>Rhodes-Kropf, M.; Viswanathan, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate reorganizations and non-cash auctions - Discussion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marquez, R.
nan</description><author>Marquez, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of bank capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diamond, D. W.; Rajan, R. G.
Banks can create liquidity precisely because deposits are fragile and prone to runs. Increased uncertainty makes deposits excessively fragile, creating a role for outside bank capital. Greater bank capital reduces the probability of financial distress but also reduces liquidity creation. The quantity of capital influences the amount that banks can induce borrowers to pay. Optimal bank capital structure trades off effects on liquidity creation, costs of bank distress, and the ability to force borrower repayment. The model explains the decline :in bank capital over the last two centuries. It identifies overlooked consequences of having regulatory capital requirements and deposit insurance.</description><author>Diamond, D. W.; Rajan, R. G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time and the price impact of a trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dufour, A.; Engle, R. F.
We use Hasbrouck's (1991) vector autoregressive model for prices and trades to empirically test and assess the role played by the waiting time between consecutive transactions in the process of price formation. We find that as the time duration between transactions decreases, the price impact of trades, the speed of price adjustment to trade-related information, and the positive autocorrelation of signed trades all increase. This suggests that times when markets are most active are times when there is an increased presence of informed traders; we interpret such markets as having reduced liquidity.</description><author>Dufour, A.; Engle, R. F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of dividends based on tax clienteles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, F.; Bernardo, A. E.; Welch, I.
This paper explains why some firms prefer to pay dividends rather than repurchase shares. When institutional investors are relatively less taxed than individual investors, dividends induce "ownership clientele" effects. Firms paying dividends attract relatively more institutions, which have a relative advantage in detecting high firm quality and in ensuring firms are well managed. The theory is consistent with some documented regularities, specifically both the presence and stickiness of dividends, and offers novel empirical implications, e.g., a prediction that it; is the tax difference between institutions and retail investors that determines dividend payments, not the absolute tax payments.</description><author>Allen, F.; Bernardo, A. E.; Welch, I.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dark side of internal capital markets: Divisional rent-seeking and inefficient investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scharfstein, D. S.; Stein, J. C.
We develop a two-tiered agency model that shows how rent-seeking behavior on the part of division managers can subvert the workings of an internal capital market. By rent-seeking, division managers can raise their bargaining power and extract greater overall compensation from the CEO. And because the CEO is herself an agent of outside investors, this extra compensation may take the form not of cash wages, but rather of preferential capital budgeting allocations. One interesting feature of our model is that it implies a kind of "socialism" in internal capital allocation, whereby weaker divisions get subsidized by stronger ones.</description><author>Scharfstein, D. S.; Stein, J. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition on the Nasdaq and the impact of recent market reforms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weston, J. P.
This paper examines the effect of recent market reforms on the competitive structure of the Nasdaq. Our results show that changes in inventory and information costs cannot explain the post-reform decrease in bid-ask spreads. We interpret this as evidence that the reforms have reduced Nasdaq dealers' rents. Additionally, we find that the difference between NYSE and Nasdaq spreads have been greatly diminished with the new rules. Further, the reforms have resulted in an exit, ceteris paribus, from the industry for market making. Overall, our results provide strong evidence that the reforms have improved competition on the Nasdaq.</description><author>Weston, J. P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hostility in takeovers: In the eyes of the beholder?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. W.
This paper examines whether hostile takeovers can be distinguished from friendly takeovers, empirically, based on accounting and stock performance data. Much has been made of this distinction in both the popular and the academic literature, where gains from hostile takeovers result from replacing incumbent managers and gains from friendly takeovers result from strategic synergies. Alternatively, hostility could reflect strategic choices made by the bidder or the target. Empirical tests show that most deals described as hostile in the press are not distinguishable from friendly deals in economic terms, except that hostile transactions involve publicity as part of the bargaining process.</description><author>Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflicts of interest and market illiquidity in bankruptcy auctions: Theory and tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stromberg, P.
I develop and estimate a model of cash auction bankruptcy using data on 205 Swedish firms, The results challenge arguments that cash auctions, as compared to reorganizations, are immune to conflicts of interest between claimholders but lead to inefficient liquidations. I show that a sale of the assets back to incumbent management is a common bankruptcy outcome. Sale-backs are more likely when they favor the bank at the expense of other creditors. On the other hand, inefficient liquidations are frequently avoided through sale-backs when markets are illiquid, that is, when industry indebtedness is high and the firm has few nonspecific assets.</description><author>Stromberg, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Depositary Receipts, country funds, and the Peso crash: The intraday evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bailey, W.; Chan, K. L.; Chung, Y. P.
We study the intraday impact of exchange rate news on emerging market American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) and closed-end country funds during the 1994 Mexican peso crisis. Peso exchange-rate changes affect prices and trading volumes of Latin American equities, and some closed-end fund behavior is consistent with "noise trader" theories of small investors. However, there is no evidence that peso depreciation triggers a significant sell-off of non-Mexican securities or that other non-Mexican trading patterns change at times of high peso news flow. Thus, the "Tequila Effect" is largely confined to price changes.</description><author>Bailey, W.; Chan, K. L.; Chung, Y. P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment plans and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lamont, O. A.
When the discount rate falls, investment should rise. Thus with time-varying discount rates and instantly changing investment, investment should positively covary with current stock returns and negatively covary with future stock returns. Aggregate nonresidential U.S. investment contradicts both these implications, probably because of investment lags. Investment plans, however, satisfy both implications. These investment plans, from a U.S. government survey of firms, are highly informative measures of expected investment and explain more than three-quarters of the variation in real annual aggregate investment growth. Plans have substantial forecasting power for excess stock returns, showing that time-varying risk premia affect investment.</description><author>Lamont, O. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry, R&amp;D, and insider gains</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aboody, D.; Lev, B.
Although researchers have documented gains from insider trading, the sources of private information leading to information asymmetry and insider gains have not been comprehensively investigated. We focus on research and development (R&amp;D)-an increasingly important yet poorly disclosed productive input-as a potential source of insider gains. Our findings, for the period from 1985 to 1997 indicate that insider gains in R&amp;D-intensive firms are substantially larger than insider gains in firms without R&amp;D. Insiders also take advantage of information on planned changes in R&amp;D budgets. R&amp;D is thus a major contributor to information asymmetry and insider gains, raising issues concerning management compensation, incentives, and disclosure policies.</description><author>Aboody, D.; Lev, B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of global equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaplinsky, S.; Ramchand, L.
This article examines the impact of U.S. firms issuing equity in multiple markets. We compare the stock price reactions to announcements of global equity offers to a control group of issues offered exclusively in the domestic U.S. market. All else equal, the adverse price reaction that typically accompanies equity issuance is reduced by 0.8 percent when some shares are sold abroad. The overall evidence suggests global offers are effective in expanding demand and reducing the price pressure effects associated with share issuance. The benefits of global offers appear to be associated with an increase in the number of foreign shareholders.</description><author>Chaplinsky, S.; Ramchand, L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate equity ownership, strategic alliances, and product market relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, J. W.; Phillips, G. M.
This paper examines long-term block ownership by corporations and performance changes in firms with corporate block owners. We also examine potential reasons for corporate ownership including benefits in product market relationships, alleviation of financing constraints, and board monitoring by corporate owners. We find the largest significant increases in targets' stock prices, investment, and operating profitability when ownership is combined with alliances, joint ventures, and other product market relationships between purchasing and target firms, especially in industries with high research and development. Our findings are consistent with the conclusion that block ownership by corporations has significant benefits in product market relationships.</description><author>Allen, J. W.; Phillips, G. M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relation between stock market movements and NYSE seat prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keim, D. B.; Madhavan, A.
Exchange seat prices are widely reported and followed as measures of market sentiment. This paper analyzes the information content of NYSE seat prices using: (1) annual seat prices from 1869 to 1998, and (2) the complete record of trades, bids and offers for the seat market from 1973 to 1994. Seat market volumes have predictive power regarding future stock market returns, consistent with a model where seat market activity is a proxy for unobserved factors affecting expected returns. We find abnormally large price movements in seats prior to October 1987, consistent with the hypothesis that seat prices capture market sentiment.</description><author>Keim, D. B.; Madhavan, A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reduction of constraints on arbitrage trading and market efficiency: An examination of ex-day returns in Hong Kong after introduction of electronic settlement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kadapakkam, P. R.
Previous research documents positive ex-dividend day returns in excess of one percent in the unique institutional setting of Hong Kong, where neither dividends nor capital gains are taxed. Short-term arbitrage trades around the ex-day were hampered by physical settlement procedures. After the recent switch to an electronic settlement system, which enables such trades, ex-day abnormal returns have declined to an insignificant 0.17 percent. This drop is more pronounced fbr high-yield stocks, which are more likely to attract dividend capture trading. The evidence points to the crucial role of short-term traders in ensuring the pricing efficiency of financial markets.</description><author>Kadapakkam, P. R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining the poor performance of consumption-based asset pricing models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, J. Y.; Cochrane, J. H.
We show that the external habit-formation model economy of Campbell and Cochrane (1999) can explain why the Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM) and its extensions are better approximate asset pricing models than is the standard consumption-based model. The model economy produces time-varying expected returns, tracked by the dividend-price ratio. Portfolio-based models capture some of this variation in state variables, which a state-independent function of consumption cannot capture. Therefore, though the consumption-based model and CAPM are both perfect conditional asset pricing models, the portfolio-based models are better approximate unconditional asset pricing models.</description><author>Campbell, J. Y.; Cochrane, J. H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information value of bond ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kliger, D.; Sarig, O.
We test whether bond ratings contain pricing-relevant information by examining security price reactions to Moody's refinement of its rating system, which was not accompanied by any fundamental change in issuers' risks, was not preceded by any announcement, and was carried simultaneously for all bonds. We find that rating information does not affect firm value, but that debt value increases (decreases) and equity value falls (rises) when Moody's announces better- (worse-) than-expected ratings. We also find that when Moody's announces better- (worse-) than-expected ratings, the volatilities implied by prices of options on the fine-rated issuers' shares decline (rise).</description><author>Kliger, D.; Sarig, O.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price discovery in initial public offerings and the role of the lead underwriter</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, R.; Conroy, P.
We examine the price discovery process of initial public offerings (IPOs) using a unique dataset. The first quote entered by the lead underwriter in the five-minute preopening window explains a large proportion of initial returns even for hot IPOs. Significant learning and price discovery continues to take place during these five minutes with hundreds of quotes being entered. The lead underwriter observes the quoting behavior of other market makers, particularly the wholesalers, and accordingly revises his own quotes. There is a strong positive relationship between initial returns and the time of day when trading starts in an IPO.</description><author>Aggarwal, R.; Conroy, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crossing networks and dealer markets: Competition and performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendershott, T.; Mendelson, H.
This paper studies the interaction between dealer markets and a relatively new form of exchange, passive crossing networks, where buyers and sellers trade directly with one another We find that the crossing network is characterized by both positive ("liquidity") and negative ("crowding") externalities, and we analyze the effects of its introduction on the dealer market. Traders who use the dealer market as a "market of last resort" can induce dealers to widen their spread and can lead to more efficient subsequent prices, but traders who only use the crossing network can provide a counterbalancing effect by reducing adverse selection and inventory holding costs.</description><author>Hendershott, T.; Mendelson, H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Imperfect competition among informed traders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Back, K.; Cao, C. H.; Willard, G. A.
We analyze competition among informed traders in the continuous-time Kyle (1985) model, as Foster and Viswanathan (1996) do in discrete time. We explicitly describe the unique linear equilibrium when signals are imperfectly correlated and confirm the conjecture of Holden and Subrahmanyam (1992) that there is no linear equilibrium when signals are perfectly correlated. One result is that at some date, and at all dates thereafter, the market would have buen more informationally efficient had there been a monopolist informed trader instead of competing traders. The relatively large amount of private information remaining. near the end of trading causes the market to approach complete illiquidity.</description><author>Back, K.; Cao, C. H.; Willard, G. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring and structure of debt contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, C.
This paper presents a theory of optimal debt structure when the moral hazard problem is severe. The main idea is that the optimal debt contract delegates monitoring. to a single senior lender and that seniority allows the monitoring senior lender to appropriate the full return from his monitoring activities. The theory explains (i) why debt contracts are prioritized, (ii) why short-term debt is senior to long-term debt, and (iii) why financial intermediaries usually hold short-term senior debt whereas long-term junior debt is widely held. Another implication of the theory is that covenant and maturity structures will be set to conform to the seniority structure.</description><author>Park, C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of bank relations on investment decisions: An investigation of Japanese takeover bids</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, J. K.; Shivdasani, A.; Yamada, T.
We study 154 domestic mergers in Japan during 1977 to 1993. In contrast to U.S. evidence, mergers are viewed favorably by investors of acquiring firms. We document a two-day acquirer abnormal return of 1.2 percent and a mean cumulative abnormal return of 5.4 percent for the duration of the takeover. Announcement returns display a strong positive association with the strength of acquirer's relationships with hanks. The benefits of bank relations appear to be greater For firms with poor investment opportunities and when the banking sector is healthy. We conclude that close ties with informed creditors, such as banks, facilitate investment policies that enhance shareholder wealth.</description><author>Kang, J. K.; Shivdasani, A.; Yamada, T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The equity share in new issues and aggregate stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, M.; Wurgler, J.
The share of equity issues in total new equity and debt issues is a strong predictor of U.S. stock market returns between 1928 and 1997. In particular, firms issue relatively more equity than debt just before periods of low market returns. The equity share in new issues has stable predictive power in both halves of the sample period and after controlling for other known predictors. We do not find support For efficient market explanations of the results. Instead, the fact that the equity share sometimes predicts significantly negative market returns suggests inefficiency and that firms time the market component of their returns when issuing securities.</description><author>Baker, M.; Wurgler, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order flow, transaction clock, and normality of asset returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ane, T.; Geman, H.
The goal of this paper is to show that normality of asset returns can be recovered through a stochastic time change. Clark (1973) addressed this issue by representing the price process as a subordinated process with volume as the lognormally distributed subordinator. We extend Clark's results and find the following: (i) stochastic time chang-es are mathematically much less constraining than subordinators; (ii) the cumulative number of trades is a better stochastic clock than the volume for generating virtually perfect normality in returns; (iii) this clock can be modeled nonparametrically, allowing both the time-change and price processes to take the form of jump diffusions.</description><author>Ane, T.; Geman, H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictability and transaction costs: The impact on rebalancing rules and behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lynch, A. W.; Balduzzi, P.
Recent papers show that predictability calibrated to U.S. data has a large effect on the rebalancing behavior of a multiperiod investor. We find that this continues to he true in the presence of realistic transaction costs. In particular, predictability causes the no-trade region for the risky-asset holding to become state dependent and, on average, wider and higher. Predictability also motivates the investor to spend considerably more on rebalancing and to rebalance more often. In other results, we find that introducing costly liquidation of the risky asset for consumption lowers the average allocation to the risky asset, though only marginally early in life. Our experiments also vary the nature of the return predictability and introduce return heteroskedasticity.</description><author>Lynch, A. W.; Balduzzi, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does option compensation increase managerial risk appetite?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carpenter, J. N.
This paper solves the dynamic investment problem of a risk averse manager compensated with a call option on the assets he controls. Under the manager's optimal policy, the option ends up either deep in or deep out of the money. As the asset value goes to zero, volatility goes to infinity. However, the option compensation does not strictly lead to greater risk seeking. Sometimes, the manager's optimal volatility is less with the option than it would be if he were trading his own account. Furthermore, giving the manager more options causes him to reduce volatility.</description><author>Carpenter, J. N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The American put option and its critical stock price</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bunch, D. S.; Johnson, H.
We derive an expression for the critical stock price for the American put. We start by expressing the put price as an integral involving first-passage probabilities. This approach yields intuition for Merton's result for the perpetual put. We then consider the finite-lived case. Using (1) the fact that the put value ceases to depend on time when the critical stock price is reached and (2) the result that an American put equals a European put plus an early-exercise premium, we derive the critical stock price. We approximate the critical-stock-price function to compute accurate put prices.</description><author>Bunch, D. S.; Johnson, H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time variation of ex-dividend day stock returns and corporate dividend capture: A reexamination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Naranjo, A.; Nimalendran, M.; Ryngaert, M.
This paper documents some empirical facts about ex-day abnormal returns to high dividend yield stocks that are potentially subject to corporate dividend capture. We find that average abnormal ex-dividend day returns are uniformly negative in each year after the introduction of negotiated commission rates and that time variation in ex-day returns during the negotiated commission rates era is consistent with corporate tax-based dividend capture. Ex-day returns are more negative when the tax advantage to corporate dividend capture is greatest and more positive when increases in transaction costs and risk reduce incentives to engage in corporate tax-based dividend capture.</description><author>Naranjo, A.; Nimalendran, M.; Ryngaert, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock repurchases in Canada: Performance and strategic trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ikenberry, D.; Lakonishok, J.; Vermaelen, T.
During the 1980s, U.S. firms announcing stock repurchases earned favorable long-run returns. Recently, concerns have been raised over the robustness of these findings. This concern comes at a time of explosive growth in repurchase programs. Thus, we study new evidence from the 1990s for 1,060 Canadian repurchase programs. Moreover, because of Canadian law, we can carefully track repurchase activity monthly. Similarly to the situation in the United States, the Canadian stock market discounts the information in repurchase announcements, particularly for value stocks. Completion rates in Canada are sensitive to mispricing. Trades also appear linked to price movements; managers buy more shares when prices fall.</description><author>Ikenberry, D.; Lakonishok, J.; Vermaelen, T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity undervaluation and decisions related to repurchase tender offers: An empirical investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Mello, R.; Shroff, P. K.
This paper tests whether managers repurchase stock when their assessment of the firm's economic value exceeds the market value. Using the forecasts managers would have if they had perfect foresight, we estimate economic value using an earnings-based valuation model. The major findings are as follows: (1) 74 percent of the firms that repurchase shares via fixed-price tender offers are undervalued relative to their preannouncement economic value; this percentage is significantly lower for a control sample, (2) the tender premium is highly correlated with the magnitude of undervaluation, and (3) the decision to satisfy oversubscription demand is influenced significantly by the magnitude of undervaluation.</description><author>D'Mello, R.; Shroff, P. K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price momentum and trading volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, C. M. C.; Swaminathan, B.
This study shows that past trading volume provides an important link between "momentum" and "value" strategics. Specifically, we find that firms with high (low) past turnover ratios exhibit many glamour (value) characteristics, earn lower (higher) future returns, and have consistently more negative (positive) earnings surprises over the next eight quarters. Past trading volume also predicts both the magnitude and persistence of price momentum. Specifically price momentum effects reverse over the next five years, and high (low) volume winners (losers) experience faster reversals. Collectively, our findings show that past volume helps to reconcile intermediate-horizon "underreaction" and long-horizon "overreaction" effects.</description><author>Lee, C. M. C.; Swaminathan, B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inference in long-horizon event studies: A Bayesian approach with application to initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, A.
Statistical inference in long-horizon event studies has been hampered by the fact that abnormal returns are neither normally distributed nor independent. This study presents a new approach to inference that overcomes these difficulties and dominates other popular testing methods. I illustrate the use of the methodology by examining the long-horizon returns of initial public offerings (IPOs). I find that the Fama and French (1993) three-factor model is inconsistent with the observed long-horizon price performance of these IPOs, whereas a characteristic-based model cannot be rejected.</description><author>Brav, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Specification analysis of affine term structure models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Q.; Singleton, K. J.
This paper explores the structural differences and relative goodness-of-fits of affine term structure models (ATSMs). Within the family of ATSMs there is a tradeoff between flexibility in modeling the conditional correlations and volatilities of the risk factors. This trade-off is formalized by our classification of N-factor affine family into N + 1 non-nested subfamilies of models. Specializing to three-factor ATSMs, our analysis suggests, based on theoretical considerations and empirical evidence, that some subfamilies of ATSMs are butter suited than others to explaining historical interest rate behavior.</description><author>Dai, Q.; Singleton, K. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How big are the tax benefits of debt?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, J. R.
I integrate under firm-specific benefit functions to estimate that the capitalized tax benefit of debt equals 9.7 percent of firm value (or as low as 4.3 percent, net of personal taxes). The typical firm could double tax benefits by issuing debt until the marginal tax benefit begins to decline. I infer how aggressively a firm uses debt by observing the shape of its tax benefit Function. Paradoxically, large, liquid, profitable Firms with low expected distress costs use debt conservatively. Product market factors, growth options, low asset collateral, and planning for future expenditures lead to conservative debt usage. Conservative debt policy is persistent.</description><author>Graham, J. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency problems and dividend policies around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>La Porta, R.; Lopez-de-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A.; Vishny, R. W.
This paper outlines and tests two agency models of dividends. According to the "outcome model," dividends are paid because minority shareholders pressure corporate insiders to disgorge cash. According to the "substitute model," insiders interested in issuing equity in the future pay dividends to establish a reputation for decent treatment of minority shareholders. The first model predicts that stronger minority shareholder rights should be associated with higher dividend payouts; the second model predicts the opposite. Tests on a cross section of 4,000 companies from 33 countries with different levels of minority shareholder rights support the outcome agency model of dividends.</description><author>La Porta, R.; Lopez-de-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A.; Vishny, R. W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cost of diversity: The diversification discount and inefficient investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajan, R.; Servaes, H.; Zingales, L.
We model the distortions that internal power struggles can generate in the allocation of resources between divisions of a diversified firm. The model predicts that if divisions are similar in the level of their resources and opportunities, funds will be transferred from divisions with poor opportunities to divisions with good opportunities. When diversity in resources and opportunities increases, however, resources can flow toward the most inefficient division, leading to more inefficient investment and less valuable firms. We test these predictions on a panel of diversified U.S. firms during the period from 1980 to 1993 and find evidence consistent with them.</description><author>Rajan, R.; Servaes, H.; Zingales, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency costs and ownership structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, J. S.; Cole, R. A.; Lin, J. W.
We provide measures of absolute and relative equity agency costs for corporations under different ownership and management structures. Our base case is Jensen and Meckling's (1976) zero agency-cast firm, where the manager is the firm's sole shareholder We utilize a sample of 1,708 small corporations from the FRB/NSSBF database and find that agency costs (i) are significantly higher when an outsider rather than an insider manages the firm; (ii) are inversely related to the manager's ownership share; (iii) increase with the number of nonmanager shareholders, and (iv) to a lesser extent, are lower with greater monitoring by banks.</description><author>Ang, J. S.; Cole, R. A.; Lin, J. W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing policy, basis risk, and corporate hedging: Evidence from oil and gas producers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haushalter, G. D.
This paper studies the hedging policies of oil and gas producers between 1992 and 1994. My evidence shows that the extent of hedging is related to financing costs. In particular, companies with greater financial leverage manage price risks more extensively. My evidence also shows that the likelihood of hedging is related to economies of scale in hedging costs and to the basis risk associated with hedging instruments. Larger companies and companies whose production is located primarily in regions where prices have a high correlation with the prices on which exchange-traded derivatives are based are more likely to manage risks.</description><author>Haushalter, G. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The exploitation of relationships in financial distress: The case of trade credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wilner, B. S.
This paper develops optimal pricing, lending, and renegotiation strategies for companies in relationships where one firm is highly dependent on the other. Long-term trade-creditor firm relationships induce dependent trade creditors to grant more concessions in debt renegotiations than nondependent creditors. Anticipating these larger renegotiation concessions, not only do less financially stable firms prefer trade credit, but all firms agree to pay a higher interest rate for trade credit. The model also explains the existence of "teaser" interest rates and convenience classes. Findings are consistent with those of the relationship-lending literature.</description><author>Wilner, B. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio selection and asset pricing models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, L.
Finance theory can be used to form informative prior beliefs in financial decision making. This paper approaches portfolio selection in a Bayesian framework that incorporates a prior degree of belief in an asset pricing model. Sample evidence on home bias and Value and size effects is evaluated from an asset-allocation perspective. U.S. investors' belief in the domestic CAPM must be very strong to justify the home bias observed in their equity holdings. The same strong prior belief results in large and stable optimal positions in the Fama-French boob-to-market portfolio in combination with the market since the 1940s.</description><author>Pastor, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing for the long run when returns are predictable</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barberis, N.
We examine how the evidence of predictability in asset returns affects optimal portfolio choice for investors with long horizons. Particular attention is paid to estimation risk, or uncertainty about the true values of model parameters. We find that even after incorporating parameter uncertainty, there is enough predictability in returns to make investors allocate substantially more to stocks, the longer their horizon. Moreover, the weak statistical significance of the evidence for predictability makes it important to take estimation risk into account; a long-horizon investor who ignores it may overallocate to stocks by a sizeable amount.</description><author>Barberis, N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bad news travels slowly: Size, analyst coverage, and the profitability of momentum strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, H.; Lim, T.; Stein, J. C.
Various theories have been proposed to explain momentum in stock returns. We test the gradual-information-diffusion model of Hong and Stein (1999) and establish three key results. First, once one moves past the very smallest stocks, the profitability of momentum strategies declines sharply with firm size. Second, holding size fixed, momentum strategies work better among stacks with low analyst coverage. Finally, the effect of analyst coverage is greater for stocks that are past losers than for past winners. These findings are consistent with the hypothesis that firm-specific information, especially negative information, diffuses only gradually across the investing public.</description><author>Hong, H.; Lim, T.; Stein, J. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the short rate drift actually nonlinear?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chapman, D. A.; Pearson, N. D.
Ait-Sahalia (1996) and Stanton (1997) use nonparametric estimators applied to short-term interest rate data to conclude that the drift function contains important nonlinearities. We study the finite-sample properties of their estimators by applying them to simulated sample paths of a square-root diffusion. Although the drift function is linear, both estimators suggest nonlinearities of the type and magnitude reported in Ait-Sahalia (1996) and Stanton (1997). Combined with the results of a weighted least squares estimator, this evidence implies that nonlinearity of the short rate drift is not a robust stylized fact.</description><author>Chapman, D. A.; Pearson, N. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading and returns under periodic market closures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, H.; Wang, J.
This paper studies how market closures affect investors' trading policies and the resulting return-generating process. It shows that closures generate rich patterns of time variation in trading and returns, including those consistent with empirical findings: (1) U-shaped patterns in the mean and volatility of returns over trading periods, (2) higher trading activity around the close and open, (3) more volatile open-to-open returns than close-to-close returns, (4) higher returns over trading periods than over nontrading periods, (5) more volatile returns over trading periods than over nontrading periods. It also shows that closures can make prices more informative about future payoffs.</description><author>Hong, H.; Wang, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Characteristics, covariances, and average returns: 1929 to 1997</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, J. L.; Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.
The Value premium in U.S. stock returns is robust. The positive relation between average return and beak-to-market equity is as strong for 1929 to 1963 as for the subsequent period studied in previous papers. A three-factor risk model explains the value premium better than the hypothesis that the book-to-market characteristic is compensated irrespective of risk loadings.</description><author>Davis, J. L.; Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sorting out sorts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berk, J. B.
In this paper we analyze the theoretical implications of sorting data into groups and then running asset pricing tests within each group. We show that the way this procedure is implemented introduces a bias in favor of rejecting the model under consideration. By simply picking enough groups to sort into, the true asset pricing model can be shown to have no explanatory power within each group.</description><author>Berk, J. B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock splits, tick size, and sponsorship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, P.
A traditional explanation for stock splits is that they increase the number of small shareholders who own the stock. A possible reason for the increase is that the minimum bid-ask spread is wider after a split and brokers have more incentive to promote a stock. I document a large number of small buy orders following Nasdaq and NYSE/AMEX splits during 1993 to 1994. I also find strong evidence that trading costs increase, and weak evidence that costs of market making decline following splits. This is consistent with splits acting as an incentive to brokers to promote stocks.</description><author>Schultz, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effectiveness of capital regulation at US commercial banks, 1985 to 1994</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hovakimian, A.; Kane, E. J.
Unless priced and administered appropriately, a governmental safety net enhances risk-shifting opportunities far banks. This paper quantifies regulatory efforts to use capital requirements to control risk-shifting by U.S. banks during 1985 to 1994 and investigates how much risk-based capital requirements and other deposit-insurance reforms improved this control. We find that capital discipline did not prevent large banks from shifting risk onto the safety net. Banks with low capital and debt-to-deposits ratios overcame outside discipline better than other banks. Mandates introduced by 1991 legislation have improved but did not establish full regulatory control over bank risk-shifting incentives.</description><author>Hovakimian, A.; Kane, E. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and liquidation: Evidence from real estate investment trusts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, D. T.
This study provides evidence that highly leveraged owner-managed properties liquidated assets during the commercial real estate decline of the late 1980s, and that this provided buying opportunities for better capitalized buyers. The analysis documents significant financial distress costs far highly leveraged firms during an industry-wide downturn and shows that these costs are particularly large for owner-managed firms.</description><author>Brown, D. T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of options on stock prices: 1973 to 1995</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sorescu, S. M.
I show that the effect of option introductions on underlying stock prices is best described by a two-regime switching means model whose optimal switch date occurs in 1981. In accordance with previous studies, I find positive abnormal returns for options listed during 1973 to 1980. By contrast, I find negative abnormal returns for options listed in 1981 and later. Possible causes for this switch include the introduction of index options in 1982, the implementation of regulatory changes in 1981, and the possibility that options expedite the dissemination of negative information.</description><author>Sorescu, S. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A non-random walk down Wall Street.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, J.
nan</description><author>Conrad, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage theory in continuous times.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Protter, P.
nan</description><author>Protter, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Outside equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Myers, S. C.
Equity financing is modeled when cash flows and asset values are not verifiable. Investors have enforceable property rights to the firm's assets, but cannot prevent insiders (managers or entrepreneurs) from capturing cash flow Insiders must co-invest and pay in each period a dividend sufficient to ensure outside investors' participation for at least one more period. Intervention by the investors must be limited by an agreement with insiders or by costs of collective action. Basic models are extended to show why firms go public and why agency costs necessarily arise when the act of investment is not immediately verifiable.</description><author>Myers, S. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When the underwriter is the market maker: An examination of trading in the IPO aftermarket</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, K.; Michaely, R.; O'Hara, M.
This paper examines aftermarket trading of underwriters and unaffiliated market makers in the three-month period after an IPO. We find that the lead underwriter is always the dominant market maker; he takes substantial inventory positions in the aftermarket trading, and co-managers play a negligible role in aftermarket trading. The lead underwriter engages in stabilization activity for less successful IPOs, and uses the overallotment option to reduce his inventory risk. Compensation to the underwriter arises primarily from fees, but aftermarket trading does generate positive profits, which are positively related to the degree of underpricing.</description><author>Ellis, K.; Michaely, R.; O'Hara, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stabilization activities by underwriters after initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, R.
Prior research has assumed that underwriters post a stabilizing bid in the aftermarket. We find instead that aftermarket activities are less transparent and include stimulating demand through short covering and restricting supply by penalizing the flipping of shares. In more than half of IPOs, a short position of an average 10.75 percent of shares offered is covered in 22 transactions over 16.6 days in the aftermarket, resulting in a loss of 3.61 percent of underwriting fees. Underwriters manage price support activities by using a combination of aftermarket short covering, penalty bids, and the selective use of the overallotment option.</description><author>Aggarwal, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The seven percent solution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, H. C.; Ritter, J. R.
Gross spreads received by underwriters on initial public offerings (IPOs) in the United States are much higher than in other countries. Furthermore, in recent years more than 90 percent of deals raising $20-80 million have spreads of exactly seven percent, three times the proportion of a decade earlier. Investment bankers readily admit that the IPO business is very profitable, and that they avoid competing on fees because they "don't want to turn it into ct commodity business." We examine several features of the IPO underwriting business that result in a market structure where spreads are high.</description><author>Chen, H. C.; Ritter, J. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple versus single banking relationships: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Detragiache, E.; Garella, P.; Guiso, L.
A theory of the optimal number of banking relationships is developed and tested using matched bank-firm data. According to the theory, relationship banks may be unable to continue funding profitable projects owing to internal problems and a firm may thus have to refinance from nonrelationship banks. The latter, however, face an adverse selection problem, as they do not know the quality of the project, and may refuse to lend. In these circumstances, multiple banking can reduce the probability of an early liquidation of the project. The empirical evidence supports the predictions of the model.</description><author>Detragiache, E.; Garella, P.; Guiso, L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio choice and asset prices: The importance of entrepreneurial risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heaton, J.; Lucas, D.
Using cross-sectional data from the SCF and Tax Model, we show that entrepreneurial income risk has a significant influence on portfolio choice and asset prices. We find that households with high and variable business income hold less wealth in stocks than other similarly wealthy households, although they constitute a significant fraction of the stockholding population. Similarly for nonentrepreneurs, holding stock in the firm where one works reduces the portfolio share of other common stocks. Finally, we show that adding proprietary income to a linear asset pricing model improves its performance over a similar model that includes only wage income.</description><author>Heaton, J.; Lucas, D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A test of the relative pricing effects of dividends and earnings: Evidence from simultaneous announcements in Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conroy, R. M.; Eades, K. M.; Harris, R. S.
We study the pricing effects of dividend and earnings announcements by taking advantage of the unique setting in Japan where managers simultaneously announce the current year's dividends and earnings as well as forecasts of next year's dividends and earnings. Defining surprises as deviations from analysts' forecasts, we find that share price reactions are significantly affected by earnings surprises, especially management forecasts of next year's earnings. The information content of dividends is marginal and is restricted to announcements of next year's dividends. Consistent with Modigliani and Miller's dividend irrelevance proposition, current dividend surprises have no material impact on stock prices in Japan.</description><author>Conroy, R. M.; Eades, K. M.; Harris, R. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm size and cyclical variations in stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perez-Quiros, G.; Timmermann, A.
Recent imperfect capital market theories predict the presence of asymmetries in the Variation of small and large firms' risk over the economic cycle. Small firms with little collateral should be more strongly affected by tighter credit market conditions in a recession state than large, better collateralized ones. This paper adopts a flexible econometric model to analyze these implications empirically. Consistent with theory, small firms display the highest degree of asymmetry in their risk across recession and expansion states, which translates into a higher sensitivity of their expected stock returns with respect to variables that measure credit market conditions.</description><author>Perez-Quiros, G.; Timmermann, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional skewness in asset pricing tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harvey, C. R.; Siddique, A.
If asset returns have systematic skewness, expected returns should include rewards for accepting this risk. We formalize this intuition with an asset pricing model that incorporates conditional skewness. Our results show that conditional skewness helps explain the cross-sectional Variation of expected returns across assets and is significant even when factors based on size and book-to-market are included. Systematic skewness is economically important and commands a risk premium, on average, of 3.60 percent per year. Our results suggest that the momentum effect is related to systematic skewness. The low expected return momentum portfolios have higher skewness than high expected return portfolios.</description><author>Harvey, C. R.; Siddique, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium forward curves for commodities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Routledge, B. R.; Seppi, D. J.; Spatt, C. S.
We develop an equilibrium model of the term structure of forward prices for storable commodities. As a consequence of a nonnegativity constraint on inventory, the spot commodity has an embedded timing option that is absent in forward contracts. This option's value changes over time due to both endogenous inventory and exogenous transitory shocks to supply and demand. Our model makes predictions about Volatilities of forward prices at different horizons and shows how conditional violations of the "Samuelson effect" occur. We extend the model to incorporate a permanent second factor and calibrate the model to crude oil futures data.</description><author>Routledge, B. R.; Seppi, D. J.; Spatt, C. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price discovery without trading: Evidence from the Nasdaq preopening</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, C.; Ghysels, E.; Hatheway, F.
This paper studies Nasdaq market makers' activities during the one and one-half hour preopening period. Price discovery during the preopening is conducted via price signaling as opposed to the auction used to open the NYSE or the continuous market used during trading. In the absence of trades, Nasdaq dealers use crossed and locked inside quotes to signal to other market makers which direction the price should move. Furthermore, we find evidence of price leadership among market makers that bears little resemblance to their IPO/SEO lead underwriter participation.</description><author>Cao, C.; Ghysels, E.; Hatheway, F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taking stock: Equity-based compensation and the evolution of managerial ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ofek, E.; Yermack, D.
We investigate the impact of stock-based compensation on managerial ownership. We find that equity compensation succeeds in increasing incentives of lower-ownership managers, but higher-ownership managers negate much of its impact by selling previously owned shares. When executives exercise options to acquire stock, nearly all of the shares are sold. Our results illuminate dynamic aspects of managerial ownership arising from divergent goals of boards of directors, who use equity compensation for incentives, and managers, who respond by selling shares for diversification. The findings cast doubt on the frequent and important theoretical assumption that managers cannot hedge the risks of these awards.</description><author>Ofek, E.; Yermack, D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund advisor compensation in closed-end funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coles, J. L.; Suay, J.; Woodbury, D.
This paper examines the relation between the premium on closed-end funds and organizational features of the funds and advisors, including the compensation scheme of the investment advisor. We find that the fund premium is larger when: (a) the advisor's compensation is more sensitive to fund performance; (b) the assets managed by the advisor are concentrated in the fund in question; (c) the advisor manages other funds with low compensation sensitivity to performance and with low concentration of assets managed by the advisor; and (d) the advisor's compensation contract evaluates performance relative to a benchmark.</description><author>Coles, J. L.; Suay, J.; Woodbury, D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial innovation and the role of derivative securities: An empirical analysis of the treasury STRIPS program</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, M.; Longstaff, F. A.
The role that financial innovation plays in financial markets is very controversial. To provide insight into this role, we examine how market participants use the highly successful Treasury STRIPS program. We find that investors use the option to create Treasury-derivative STRIPS primarily to make markets more complete and take advantage of tax and accounting asymmetries. Although liquidity-related factors help explain differences in the prices of Treasury bonds and STRIPS, we find little evidence that the option to strip and reconstitute securities is used for speculative or arbitrage-related purposes.</description><author>Grinblatt, M.; Longstaff, F. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging pressure effects in futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Roon, F. A.; Nijman, T. E.; Veld, C.
We present a simple model implying that futures risk premia depend on both own-market and cross-market hedging pressures. Empirical evidence from 20 futures markets, divided into four groups (financial, agricultural, mineral, and currency) indicates that, after controlling for systematic risk, both the futures own hedging pressure and cross-hedging pressures from within the group significantly affect futures returns. These effects remain significant after controlling for a measure of price pressure. Finally, we show that hedging pressure also contains explanatory power for returns on the underlying asset, as predicted by the model.</description><author>de Roon, F. A.; Nijman, T. E.; Veld, C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of finance journal impact factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borokhovich, K. A.; Bricker, R. J.; Simkins, B. J.
This paper provides an analysis of the citation counts of articles published in the leading finance journals. It identifies the determinants of the most prevalent measure of influence for finance journals, the Social Sciences Citation Index impact factors. It finds that impact factors are affected by citations outside the finance field, are not affected by the distribution of published articles across subfields, and are good predictors of the long-term citation counts of articles. The citation impact factors are reduced for both the Journal of Financial Economics and The Journal of Finance by their publication of other than regular articles.</description><author>Borokhovich, K. A.; Bricker, R. J.; Simkins, B. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market liberalization, economic reform, and emerging market equity prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henry, P. B.
A stock market liberalization is a decision by a country's government to allow foreigners to purchase shares in that country's stock market. On average, a country's aggregate equity price index experiences abnormal returns of 3.3 percent per month in real dollar terms during an eight-month window leading up to the implementation of its initial stock market liberalization. This result is consistent with the prediction of standard international asset pricing models that stock market liberalization may reduce the liberalizing country's cost of equity capital by allowing for risk sharing between domestic and foreign agents.</description><author>Henry, P. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign speculators and emerging equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, G.; Harvey, C. R.
We propose a cross-sectional time-series model to assess the impact of market liberalizations in emerging equity markets on the cost of capital, volatility, beta, and correlation with world market returns. Liberalizations are defined by regulatory changes, the introduction of depositary receipts and country funds, and structural breaks in equity capital flows to the emerging markets. We control for other economic events that might confound the impact of foreign speculators on local equity markets. Across a range of specifications, the cost of capital always decreases after a capital market liberalization with the effect varying between 5 and 75 basis points.</description><author>Bekaert, G.; Harvey, C. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Going public without governance: Managerial reputation effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomes, A.
This paper addresses the agency problem between controlling shareholders and minority shareholders. This problem is common among public firms in many countries where the legal system does not effectively protect minority shareholders against oppression by controlling shareholders. We show that even without any explicit corporate governance mechanisms protecting minority shareholders, controlling shareholders can implicitly commit not to expropriate them. Stock prices of such companies are significantly higher and firms are more likely go public because of this reputation effect. Moreover, insiders divest shares gradually over time, at a rate that is negatively related to the degree of moral hazard.</description><author>Gomes, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency conflicts in public and negotiated transfers of corporate control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burkart, M.; Gromb, D.; Panunzi, F.
We analyze control transfers in firms with a dominant minority blockholder and otherwise dispersed owners, and show that the transaction mode is important. Negotiated block trades preserve a low level of ownership concentration, inducing more inefficient extraction of private benefits. In contrast, public acquisitions increase ownership concentration, resulting in fewer private benefits and higher firm value. Within our model, the incumbent and new controlling party prefer to trade the block because of the dispersed shareholders' free-riding behavior. We also explore the regulatory implications of this agency problem and its impact on the terms of block trades.</description><author>Burkart, M.; Gromb, D.; Panunzi, F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can relationship banking survive competition?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boot, A. W. A.; Thakor, A. V.
How will banks evolve as competition increases from other banks and from the capital market? Will banks become more like capital market underwriters and offer passive transaction loans or return to their roots as relationship lending experts? These are the questions we address. Our key result is that as interbank competition increases, banks make more relationship loans, but each has lower added value for borrowers. Capital market competition reduces relationship lending land bank lending shrinks), but each relationship loan has greater added value for borrowers. In both cases, welfare increases for some borrowers but not necessarily for all.</description><author>Boot, A. W. A.; Thakor, A. V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Some evidence on the uniqueness of initial public debt offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Datta, S.; Iskandar-Datta, M.; Patel, A.
Debt initial public offerings (IPOs) represent a major shift in a firm's financing policy by both extending debt maturity and altering the public-private debt mix. In contrast to findings for seasoned debt offerings, we document a significantly negative stock price response to debt IPO announcements. This result is consistent with debt maturity and debt ownership structure theories. The equity wealth effect is negatively related to the offer's maturity, and positively related to the degree of bank monitoring. We find that firms with less information asymmetry and firms with higher growth opportunities experience a less adverse stock price response.</description><author>Datta, S.; Iskandar-Datta, M.; Patel, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mean reversion across national stock markets and parametric contrarian investment strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balvers, R.; Wu, Y. R.; Gilliland, E.
For U.S. stock prices, evidence of mean reversion over long horizons is mixed, possibly due to lack of a reliable long time series. Using additional cross-sectional power gained from national stock index data of 18 countries during the period 1969 to 1996, we find strong evidence of mean reversion in relative stock index prices. Our findings imply a significantly positive speed of reversion with a half-life of three to three and one-half years. This result is robust to alternative specifications and data. Parametric contrarian investment strategies that fully exploit mean reversion across national indexes outperform buy-and-hold and standard contrarian strategies.</description><author>Balvers, R.; Wu, Y. R.; Gilliland, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading is hazardous to your wealth: The common stock investment performance of individual investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, B. M.; Odean, T.
Individual investors who hold common stocks directly pay a tremendous performance penalty for active trading. Of 66,465 households with accounts at a large discount broker during 1991 to 1996, those that trade most earn an annual return of 11.4 percent, while the market returns 17.9 percent. The average household earns an annual return of 16.4 percent, tilts its common stock investment toward high-beta, small, value stocks, and turns over 75 percent of its portfolio annually. Overconfidence can explain high trading levels and the resulting poor performance of individual investors. Our central message is that trading is hazardous to your wealth.</description><author>Barber, B. M.; Odean, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does information quality affect stock returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Veronesi, P.
Using a simple dynamic asset pricing model, this paper investigates the relationship between the precision of public information about economic growth and stock market returns. After fully characterizing expected returns and conditional volatility, I show that (i) higher precision of signals tends to increase the risk premium, (ii) when signals are imprecise the equity premium is bounded above independently of investors' risk aversion, (iii) return volatility is U-shaped with respect to investors' risk aversion, and (iv) the relationship between conditional expected returns and conditional variance is ambiguous.</description><author>Veronesi, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option prices, implied price processes, and stochastic volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Britten-Jones, M.; Neuberger, A.
This paper characterizes all continuous price processes that are consistent with current option prices. This extends Derman and Kani (1994), Dupire (1994, 1997), and Rubinstein (1994), who only consider processes with deterministic volatility. Our characterization implies a volatility forecast that does not require a specific model, only current option prices. We show how arbitrary volatility processes can be adjusted to fit current option prices exactly, just as interest rate processes can be adjusted to fit bond prices exactly. The procedure works with many volatility models, is fast to calibrate, and can price exotic options efficiently using familiar lattice techniques.</description><author>Britten-Jones, M.; Neuberger, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is group affiliation profitable in emerging markets? An analysis of diversified Indian business groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khanna, T.; Palepu, K.
Emerging markets like India have poorly functioning institutions, leading to severe agency and information problems. Business groups in these markets have the potential both to offer benefits to member firms, and to destroy value. We analyze the performance of affiliates of diversified Indian business groups relative to unaffiliated firms. We find that accounting and stock market measures of firm performance initially decline with group diversification and subsequently increase once group diversification exceeds a certain level. Unlike U.S. conglomerates' lines of business, and similar to the affiliates of U.S. LBO associations, affiliates of the most diversified business groups outperform unaffiliated firms.</description><author>Khanna, T.; Palepu, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demand curves for stocks do slope down: New evidence from an index weights adjustment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaul, A.; Mehrotra, V.; Morck, R.
Weights in the Toronto Stock Exchange 300 index are determined by the market values of the included stocks' public floats. In November 1996, the exchange implemented a previously announced revision of its definition of the public float. This revision, which increased the floats and the index weights of 31 stocks, conveyed no information and had no effect on the legal duties of shareholders. Affected stocks experienced statistically significant excess returns of 2.3 percent during the event week, and no price reversal occurred as trading volume returned to normal levels. These findings support downward sloping demand curves for stocks.</description><author>Kaul, A.; Mehrotra, V.; Morck, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading volume and cross-autocorrelations in stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, T.; Swaminathan, B.
This paper finds that trading volume is a significant determinant of the lead-lag patterns observed in stock returns. Daily and weekly returns on high volume port folios lead returns on low volume portfolios, controlling for firm size. Nonsynchronous trading or low volume portfolio autocorrelations cannot explain these findings. These patterns arise because returns on low volume portfolios respond more slowly to information in market returns. The speed of adjustment of individual stocks confirms these findings. Overall, the results indicate that differential speed of adjustment to information is a significant source of the cross-autocorrelation patterns in short-horizon stock returns.</description><author>Chordia, T.; Swaminathan, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Truth in mutual fund advertising: Evidence on future performance and fund flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jain, P. C.; Wu, J. S.
We examine a sample of 294 mutual funds that are advertised in Barren's or Money magazine. The preadvertisement performance of these funds is significantly higher than that of the benchmarks. We test whether the Sponsors select funds to signal continued superior performance or they use the past superior :performance to attract more money into the funds. Our analysis shows that there is no superior performance in the postadvertisement period. Thus, the results do not support the signaling hypothesis. On the other hand, we find that the advertised funds attract significantly more money in comparison with a group of control funds.</description><author>Jain, P. C.; Wu, J. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A model of returns and trading in futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, H.
This paper develops an equilibrium model of a competitive futures market in which investors trade to hedge positions and to speculate on their private information. Equilibrium return and trading patterns are examined. (1) In markets where the information asymmetry among investors is small, the return volatility of a futures contract decreases with time-to-maturity (i.e., the Samuelson effect holds). (2) However, in markets where the information asymmetry among investors is large, the Samuelson effect need not hold. (3) Additionally, the model generates rich time-to-maturity patterns in open interest and spot price volatility that are consistent with empirical findings.</description><author>Hong, H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage and the expectations hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, F. A.
This paper shows that all traditional forms of the expectations hypothesis can be consistent with the absence of arbitrage if markets are incomplete. A key implication is that the validity of the expectations hypothesis is purely an empirical issue; the expectations hypothesis cannot be ruled out on a priori theoretical grounds.</description><author>Longstaff, F. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mathematics of financial markets.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cvitanic, J.
nan</description><author>Cvitanic, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Thinking about Prices versus Thinking about Returns in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glaser, Markus; Iliewa, Zwetelina; Weber, Martin
Prices and returns are alternative ways to present information and to elicit expectations in financial markets. But do investors think of prices and returns in the same way? We present three studies in which subjects differ in the level of expertise, amount of information, and type of incentive scheme. The results are consistent across all studies: asking subjects to forecast returns as opposed to prices results in higher expectations, whereas showing them return charts rather than price charts results in lower expectations. Experience is not a useful remedy but cognitive reflection mitigates the impact of format changes.</description><author>Glaser, Markus; Iliewa, Zwetelina; Weber, Martin</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Investors Value Sustainability? A Natural Experiment Examining Ranking and Fund Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Sussman, Abigail B.
Examining a shock to the salience of the sustainability of the U.S. mutual fund market, we present causal evidence that investors marketwide value sustainability: being categorized as low sustainability resulted in net outflows of more than $12 billion while being categorized as high sustainability led to net inflows of more than $24 billion. Experimental evidence suggests that sustainability is viewed as positively predicting future performance, but we do not find evidence that high-sustainability funds outperform low-sustainability funds. The evidence is consistent with positive affect influencing expectations of sustainable fund performance and nonpecuniary motives influencing investment decisions.</description><author>Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Sussman, Abigail B.</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Dynamic Model of Characteristic-Based Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alti, Aydogan; Titman, Sheridan
We present a dynamic model that links characteristic-based return predictability to systematic factors that determine the evolution of firm fundamentals. In the model, an economy-wide disruption process reallocates profits from existing businesses to new projects and thus generates a source of systematic risk for portfolios of firms sorted on value, profitability, and asset growth. If investors are overconfident about their ability to evaluate the disruption climate, these characteristic-sorted portfolios exhibit persistent mispricing. The model generates predictions about the conditional predictability of characteristic-sorted portfolio returns and illustrates how return persistence increases the likelihood of observing characteristic-based anomalies.</description><author>Alti, Aydogan; Titman, Sheridan</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Brokers and Order Flow Leakage: Evidence from Fire Sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barbon, Andrea; Di Maggio, Marco; Franzoni, Francesco; Landier, Augustin
Using trade-level data, we study whether brokers play a role in spreading order flow information in the stock market. We focus on large portfolio liquidations that result in temporary price drops, and identify the brokers who intermediate these trades. These brokers' clients are more likely to predate on the liquidating funds than to provide liquidity. Predation leads to profits of about 25 basis points over 10 days and increases the liquidation costs of the distressed fund by 40%. This evidence suggests a role of information leakage in exacerbating fire sales.</description><author>Barbon, Andrea; Di Maggio, Marco; Franzoni, Francesco; Landier, Augustin</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Revelation in Decentralized Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hagstromer, Bjoern; Menkveld, Albert J.
How does information get revealed in decentralized markets? We test several hypotheses inspired by recent dealer-network theory. To do so, we construct an empirical map of information revelation where two dealers are connected based on the synchronicity of their quote changes. The tests, based on the euro to Swiss franc spot rate (EUR/CHF) quote data including the 2015 crash, largely support theory: strongly connected (i.e., central) dealers are more informed. Connections are weaker when there is less to be learned. The crash serves to identify how a network forms when dealers are transitioned from no-learning to learning, that is, from a fixed to a floating rate.</description><author>Hagstromer, Bjoern; Menkveld, Albert J.</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where Is the Risk in Value? Evidence from a Market-to-Book Decomposition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golubov, Andrey; Konstantinidi, Theodosia
We study the value premium using the multiples-based market-to-book decomposition of Rhodes-Kropf, Robinson, and Viswanathan (2005). The market-to-value component drives all of the value strategy return, while the value-to-book component exhibits no return predictability in either portfolio sorts or firm-level regressions. Existing results linking market-to-book to operating leverage, duration, exposure to investment-specific technology shocks, and analysts' risk ratings derive from the unpriced value-to-book component. In contrast, results on expectation errors, limits to arbitrage, and certain types of cash flow risk and consumption risk exposure are due to the market-to-value component. Overall, our evidence casts doubt on several value premium theories.</description><author>Golubov, Andrey; Konstantinidi, Theodosia</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonfinancial Firms as Cross-Market Arbitrageurs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ma, Yueran
I demonstrate that nonfinancial corporations act as cross-market arbitrageurs in their own securities. Firms use one type of security to replace another in response to shifts in relative valuations, inducing negatively correlated financing flows in different markets. Net equity repurchases and net debt issuance both increase when expected excess returns on debt are particularly low, or when expected excess returns on equity are relatively high. Credit valuations affect equity financing as much as equity valuations do, and vice versa. Cross-market corporate arbitrage is most prevalent among large, unconstrained firms, and helps account for aggregate financing patterns.</description><author>Ma, Yueran</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Words Speak Louder without Actions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levit, Doron
Information and control rights are central aspects of leadership, management, and corporate governance. This paper studies a principal-agent model that features both communication and intervention as alternative means to exert influence. The main result shows that a principal's power to intervene in an agent's decision limits the ability of the principal to effectively communicate her private information. The perverse effect of intervention on communication can harm the principal, especially when the cost of intervention is low or the underlying agency problem is severe. These novel results are applied to managerial leadership, corporate boards, private equity, and shareholder activism.</description><author>Levit, Doron</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning from Coworkers: Peer Effects on Individual Investment Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ouimet, Paige; Tate, Geoffrey
Using unique data on employee stock purchase plans (ESPPs), we examine the influence of networks on investment decisions. Comparing employees within a firm during the same election window with metro area fixed effects, we find that the choices of coworkers in the firm's ESPP exert a significant influence on employees' own decisions to participate and trade. Moreover, we find that the presence of high-information employees magnifies the effects of peer networks. Given participation in an ESPP is value-maximizing, our analysis suggests the potential of networks and targeted investor education to improve financial decision-making.</description><author>Ouimet, Paige; Tate, Geoffrey</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Funding Liquidity without Banks: Evidence from a Shock to the Cost of Very Short-Term Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Restrepo, Felipe; Cardona-Sosa, Lina; Strahan, Philip E.
In 2011, Colombia instituted a tax on repayment of bank loans, which increased the cost of short-term bank credit more than long-term credit. Firms responded by cutting short-term loans for liquidity management purposes and increasing the use of cash and trade credit. In industries in which trade credit is more accessible (based on U.S. Compustat firms), we find substitution into accounts payable and little effect on cash and investment. Where trade credit is less available, firms increase cash and cut investment. Thus, trade credit provides an alternative source of liquidity that can insulate some firms from bank liquidity shocks.</description><author>Restrepo, Felipe; Cardona-Sosa, Lina; Strahan, Philip E.</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pledgeability, Industry Liquidity, and Financing Cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diamond, Douglas W.; Hu, Yunzhi; Rajan, Raghuram G.
Why do firms choose high debt when they anticipate high valuations, and underperform subsequently? We propose a theory of financing cycles where the importance of creditors' control rights over cash flows ("pledgeability") varies with industry liquidity. The market allows firms take on more debt when they anticipate higher future liquidity. However, both high anticipated liquidity and the resulting high debt limit their incentives to enhance pledgeability. This has prolonged adverse effects in a downturn. Because these effects are hard to contract upon, higher anticipated liquidity can also reduce a firm's current access to finance.</description><author>Diamond, Douglas W.; Hu, Yunzhi; Rajan, Raghuram G.</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diagnostic Expectations and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bordalo, Pedro; Gennaioli, Nicola; La Porta, Rafael; Shleifer, Andrei
We revisit La Porta's finding that returns on stocks with the most optimistic analyst long-term earnings growth forecasts are lower than those on stocks with the most pessimistic forecasts. We document the joint dynamics of fundamentals, expectations, and returns of these portfolios, and explain the facts using a model of belief formation based on the representativeness heuristic. Analysts forecast fundamentals from observed earnings growth, but overreact to news by exaggerating the probability of states that have become more likely. We find support for the model's predictions. A quantitative estimation of the model accounts for the key patterns in the data.</description><author>Bordalo, Pedro; Gennaioli, Nicola; La Porta, Rafael; Shleifer, Andrei</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Women's Liberation as a Financial Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hazan, Moshe; Weiss, David; Zoabi, Hosny
In one of the greatest extensions of property rights in human history, common law countries began giving rights to married women in the 1850s. Before this "women's liberation," the doctrine of coverture strongly incentivized parents of daughters to hold real estate, rather than financial assets such as money, stocks, or bonds. We exploit the staggered nature of coverture's demise across U.S. states to show that women's rights led to shifts in household portfolios, a positive shock to the supply of credit, and a reallocation of labor toward nonagriculture and capital-intensive industries. Investor protection thus deepened financial markets, aiding industrialization.</description><author>Hazan, Moshe; Weiss, David; Zoabi, Hosny</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>YOLO: Mortality Beliefs and Household Finance Puzzles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heimer, Rawley Z.; Myrseth, Kristian Ove R.; Schoenle, Raphael S.
We study the effect of subjective mortality beliefs on life-cycle behavior. With new survey evidence, we document that survival is underestimated (overestimated) by the young (old). We calibrate a canonical life-cycle model to elicited beliefs. Relative to calibrations using actuarial probabilities, the young undersave by 26%, and retirees draw down their assets 27% slower, while the model's fit to consumption data improves by 88%. Cross-sectional regressions support the model's predictions: Distorted mortality beliefs correlate with savings behavior while controlling for risk preferences, cognitive, and socioeconomic factors. Overweighting the likelihood of rare events contributes to mortality belief distortions.</description><author>Heimer, Rawley Z.; Myrseth, Kristian Ove R.; Schoenle, Raphael S.</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Over-the-Counter Market Frictions and Yield Spread Changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friewald, Nils; Nagler, Florian
We empirically study whether systematic over-the-counter (OTC) market frictions drive the large unexplained common factor in yield spread changes. Using transaction data on U.S. corporate bonds, we find that marketwide inventory, search, and bargaining frictions explain 23.4% of the variation in the common component. Systematic OTC frictions thus substantially improve the explanatory power of yield spread changes and account for one-third of their total explained variation. Search and bargaining frictions combined explain more in the common dynamics of yield spread changes than inventory frictions. Our findings support the implications of leading theories of intermediation frictions in OTC markets.</description><author>Friewald, Nils; Nagler, Florian</author><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>