<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFE1</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Board diversity, firm risk, and corporate policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernile, Gennaro; Bhagwat, Vineet; Yonker, Scott
We examine the effects of diversity in the board of directors on corporate policies and risk. Using a multidimensional measure, we find that greater board diversity leads to lower volatility and better performance. The lower risk levels are largely due to diverse boards adopting more persistent and less risky financial policies. However, consistent with diversity fostering more efficient (real) risk-taking, firms with greater board diversity also invest persistently more in research and development (R&amp;D) and have more efficient innovation processes. Instrumental variable tests that exploit exogenous variation in firm access to the supply of diverse nonlocal directors indicate that these relations are causal. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bernile, Gennaro; Bhagwat, Vineet; Yonker, Scott</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Network centrality and delegated investment performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rossi, Alberto G.; Blake, David; Timmermann, Allan; Tonks, Ian; Wermers, Russ
We show a positive relation between network centrality and risk-adjusted performance in a delegated investment management setting. More connected managers take more portfolio risk and receive higher investor flows, consistent with these managers improving their ability to exploit investment opportunities through their network connections. Greater network connections are shown to be particularly important in reducing the diseconomies of scale for large managers who are well connected. We also use the exogenous merger of two investment consultants, which creates a sudden change in the network connections of the managers they oversee, to provide evidence that a greater number of connections translates into better portfolio performance. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rossi, Alberto G.; Blake, David; Timmermann, Allan; Tonks, Ian; Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The customer knows best: The investment value of consumer opinions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Jiekun
This paper investigates whether consumer opinions convey value-relevant information to financial markets. Using a data set of more than 14.5 million customer product reviews on Amazon.com from 2004 through 2015, I find evidence that consumer opinions contain information for stock pricing. A spread portfolio that is long on stocks with high abnormal customer ratings and short on stocks with low abnormal customer ratings delivers an abnormal return of around 55.7 to 73.0 basis points per month. There is no evidence of return reversals in the subsequent year. The return predictability of customer ratings continues to hold after controlling for firm characteristics such as gross profitability, advertising, research and development expenses, and trading volume. Furthermore, abnormal customer ratings positively predict revenues and earnings surprises. These results suggest that consumer opinions contain novel information about firms' fundamentals and stock pricing. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Jiekun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agnostic fundamental analysis works</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Sohnke M.; Grinblatt, Mark
To assess stock market informational efficiency with minimal data snooping, we take the view of a statistician with little knowledge of finance. The statistician uses techniques such as least squares to estimate peer-implied fair values from the market values of replicating portfolios with the same accounting statements as the company being valued. Divergence of a company's peer-implied value estimate from its market value represents mispricing, motivating a convergence trade that earns risk-adjusted returns of up to 10% per year and is economically significant for both large and small cap firms. The rate of convergence decays to zero over the subsequent 34 months. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bartram, Sohnke M.; Grinblatt, Mark</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantitative easing auctions of Treasury bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, Zhaogang; Zhu, Haoxiang
The Federal Reserve uses (reverse) auctions to implement its purchases of Treasury bonds in quantitative easing (QE). To evaluate dealers' offers across multiple bonds, the Fed relies on its internal yield curve model, fitted to secondary market bond prices. From November 2010 to September 2011, a one standard deviation increase in the cheapness of a Treasury bond (how much the market price of the bond is below a model-implied value) increases the Fed's purchase quantity of that bond by 276 million and increases the auction costs on that bond by 2.6 cents per $100 par value, controlling for standard covariates. Our results suggest that the Fed harvests gains from trades by purchasing undervalued bonds, but strategic dealers extract some profits because the Fed's relative values can be partly inferred from price data. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Song, Zhaogang; Zhu, Haoxiang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tradability of output, business cycles and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Mary
I examine the effect of a firm's tradability, the proportion of output that is exported abroad, on its stock returns over business cycles from 1947-2015. Firms with higher tradability have more cyclical asset returns, even after controlling for the real exchange rate. Returns of a portfolio long on firms with the highest tradability and short on firms with the lowest tradability can predict changes in the real dollar exchange rate and trade volumes. The empirical patterns are consistent with the relative price adjustment of tradable and non-tradable goods to business cycles primarily driven by supply shocks. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Tian, Mary</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do universal banks finance riskier but more productive firms?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neuhann, Daniel; Saidi, Farzad
Using variation in bank scope generated by the stepwise repeal of the Glass-Steagall Act in the US, we show that the deregulation of universal banks allowed them to finance firms with 14% higher volatility. This increase in risk is compensated by lasting improvements in firms' total factor productivity of 3%. Using bank scope-expanding mergers to identify shocks to universal banks' private information about borrower firms, we provide evidence that informational economies of scope across loans and non-loan products account for the firm-level real effects of universal banking. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Neuhann, Daniel; Saidi, Farzad</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Busy directors and firm performance: Evidence from mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hauser, Roie
This paper studies whether director appointments to multiple boards impact firm outcomes. To overcome endogeneity of board appointments, I exploit variation generated by mergers that terminate entire boards and thus shock the appointments of those terminated directors. Reductions of board appointments are associated with higher profitability, market-to-book, and likelihood of directors joining board committees. The performance gains are particularly stark when directors are geographically far from firm headquarters. I conclude that the effect of the shocks to board appointments is: (i) evidence that boards matter; and (ii) plausibly explained by a workload channel: when directors work less elsewhere, their companies benefit. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hauser, Roie</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Absolving beta of volatility's effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Jianan; Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yuan, Yu
The beta anomaly, negative (positive) alpha on stocks with high (low) beta, arises from beta's positive correlation with idiosyncratic volatility (IVOL). The relation between IVOL and alpha is positive among underpriced stocks but negative and stronger among overpriced stocks (Stambaugh, Yu, and Yuan, 2015). That stronger negative relation combines with the positive IVOL-beta correlation to produce the beta anomaly. The anomaly is significant only within overpriced stocks and only in periods when the beta-IVOL correlation and the likelihood of overpricing are simultaneously high. Either controlling for IVOL or simply excluding overpriced stocks with high IVOL renders the beta anomaly insignificant. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Jianan; Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yuan, Yu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment, Tobin's q, and interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Xiaoji; Wang, Chong; Wang, Neng; Yang, Jinqiang
We study the impact of stochastic interest rates and capital illiquidity on investment and firm value by incorporating a widely used arbitrage-free term structure model of interest rates into a standard g theoretic framework. Our generalized q model informs us to use corporate credit-risk information to predict investments when empirical measurement issues of Tobin's average q are significant (e.g., equity is much more likely to be mis-priced than debt), as in Philippon (2009). We find, consistent with our theory, that credit spreads and bond q have significant predictive powers on micro-level and aggregate investments corroborating the recent empirical work of Gilchrist and Zakrajgek (2012). We also show that the quantitative effects of the stochastic interest rates and capital illiquidity on investment, Tobin's average q, the duration and user cost of capital, and the value of growth opportunities are substantial. These findings are particularly important in today's low interest rate environment. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Xiaoji; Wang, Chong; Wang, Neng; Yang, Jinqiang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>One fundamental and two taxes: When does a Tobin tax reduce financial price volatility?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deng, Yongheng; Liu, Xin; Wei, Shang-Jin
We aim to make two contributions to the literature on the effects of transaction costs on financial price volatility. First, by augmenting a double differencing approach with a research design with three ingredients (a common set of companies simultaneously listed on two stock exchanges, binding capital controls, and different timing of changes in transaction costs), we obtain a control group that has identical corporate fundamentals as the treatment group. We apply the research design to Chinese stocks that are cross-listed in Hong Kong and Mainland China. Second, we allow transaction costs to have different effects in markets with different maturity. We find a significantly negative relationship, on average, between stamp duty increase and price volatility. However, this average effect masks some important heterogeneity. In particular, when institutional investors have become a significant part of the traders' pool, we find an opposite effect. Overall, our results suggest that a Tobin tax could work in an immature market, but can backfire in a more developed market. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Deng, Yongheng; Liu, Xin; Wei, Shang-Jin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government guarantees and the two-way feedback between banking and sovereign debt crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leonello, Agnese
This paper studies the effects of government guarantees on the interconnection between banking and sovereign debt crises in a framework where both the banks and the government are fragile and the credibility and feasibility of the guarantees are determined endogenously. The analysis delivers some new results on the role of guarantees in the bank sovereign nexus. First, guarantees emerge as a key channel linking banks' and sovereign stability, even in the absence of banks' holdings of sovereign bonds. Second, depending on the specific characteristics of the economy and the nature of banking crises, an increase in the size of guarantees can be beneficial for the bank-sovereign nexus in that it enhances financial stability without undermining sovereign solvency. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leonello, Agnese</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum in Imperial Russia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goetzmann, William N.; Huang, Simon
Some of the leading theories of momentum have different empirical predictions that depend on market composition and structure. The institutional theory predicts lower momentum profits in markets with less agency. Behavioral theories predict lower profits in markets with more sophisticated investors. In this paper, we use a dataset from a major 19th century equity market to test these predictions. We find no evidence to support the institutional theory due to the lack of delegated management. We exploit a regulatory change in the middle of our sample period to test behavioral theories. We find evidence consistent with overreaction theories of momentum. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goetzmann, William N.; Huang, Simon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When do CDS spreads lead? Rating events, private entities, and firm-specific information flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Jongsub; Naranjo, Andy; Velioglu, Guner
We find that credit default swap (CDS) spreads contribute significantly to price discovery in financial markets when firm-specific credit information is prominent. Using 3,470 S&amp;P rating notch and watch changes for US public and private entities from 2001-2013, we show that CDS prices contain unique firm credit risk information that is not captured by the prices of other related securities such as stocks and bonds of the same firm. Credit information unidirectionally flows from CDS to bonds, particularly for private entities whose stocks are not concurrently trading in markets. We further find that CDS returns significantly predict stock returns, particularly their idiosyncratic components. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Jongsub; Naranjo, Andy; Velioglu, Guner</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home away from home? Foreign demand and London house prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Badarinza, Cristian; Ramadorai, Tarun
Identifying the effects of "flights to safety" on asset prices using pure time-series methods is difficult because crises are infrequent. We develop a new cross-sectional identification approach, motivated by the insight that investors may differ in their "preferred habitats" within a broad asset class. We apply the method to the question of whether foreign capital is responsible for residential real estate price movements in global cities such as London and New York, especially during crises. Using large data sets of housing transactions, we find that foreign risk strongly affects London house prices. The effects are long-lasting, and are associated with both safe-haven effects and immigration. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Badarinza, Cristian; Ramadorai, Tarun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing and ambiguity: Empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brenner, Menachem; Izhakian, Yehuda
We introduce ambiguity in conjunction with risk to study the relation between risk, ambiguity, and expected returns. Distinguishing between ambiguity and attitudes toward ambiguity, we develop an empirical methodology for measuring the degree of ambiguity and for assessing attitudes toward ambiguity from market data. The main findings indicate that ambiguity in the equity market is priced. Introducing ambiguity alongside risk provides stronger evidence on the role of risk in explaining expected returns in the equity markets. The findings also indicate that investors' level of aversion to or love for ambiguity is contingent on the expected probability of favorable returns. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brenner, Menachem; Izhakian, Yehuda</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate debt maturity profiles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Jaewon; Hackbarth, Dirk; Zechner, Josef
We study a novel aspect of a firm's capital structure, namely, the profile of its debt maturity dates. In a simple theoretical framework we show that the dispersion of debt maturities constitutes an important dimension of capital structure choice, driven by firm characteristics and debt rollover risk. Guided by these predictions we establish two main empirical results. First, using an exogenous shock to rollover risk, we document a significant increase in maturity dispersion for firms that need to roll over maturing debt. Second, we find strong support that maturities of newly issued debt are influenced by pre-existing maturity profiles. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choi, Jaewon; Hackbarth, Dirk; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fintech, regulatory arbitrage, and the rise of shadow banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buchak, Greg; Matvos, Gregor; Piskorski, Tomasz; Seru, Amit
Shadow bank market share in residential mortgage origination nearly doubled from 2007 to 2015, with particularly dramatic growth among online "fintech" lenders. We study how two forces, regulatory differences and technological advantages, contributed to this growth. Difference in difference tests exploiting geographical heterogeneity induced by four specific increases in regulatory burden capital requirements, mortgage servicing rights, mortgage related lawsuits, and the movement of supervision to Office of Comptroller and Currency following closure of the Office of Thrift Supervision all reveal that traditional banks contracted in markets where they faced more regulatory constraints; shadow banks partially filled these gaps. Relative to other shadow banks, fintech lenders serve more creditworthy borrowers and are more active in the refinancing market. Fintech lenders charge a premium of 14-16 basis points and appear to provide convenience rather than cost savings to borrowers. They seem to use different information to set interest rates relative to other lenders. A quantitative model of mortgage lending suggests that regulation accounts for roughly 60% of shadow bank growth, while technology accounts for roughly 30%. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buchak, Greg; Matvos, Gregor; Piskorski, Tomasz; Seru, Amit</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, reach for yield, and money market funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>La Spada, Gabriele
Do asset managers reach for yield because of competitive pressures in a low rate environment? I propose a tournament model of money market funds (MMFs) to study this question. When funds care about relative performance, an increase in the risk premium leads funds with lower default costs to increase risk taking, while funds with higher default costs decrease risk taking. Without changes in the premium, lower risk-free rates reduce the risk taking of all funds. I show that these predictions are consistent with MMF risk taking during the 2002-2008 period and that rank-based performance is a key determinant of money flows to MMFs. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>La Spada, Gabriele</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are institutional investors with multiple blockholdings effective monitors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Jun-Koo; Luo, Juan; Na, Hyun Seung
We examine whether institutions' monitoring effectiveness is related to the number of their blockholdings. We find that the number of blocks that a firm's large institutions hold is positively associated with forced chief executive officer (CEO) turnover-performance sensitivity, abnormal returns around forced CEO turnover announcements and 13D filings, and changes in firm value. These results are particularly evident when institutions have multiple blockholdings in the same industry, when they have activism experience, or when they have long-term blockholdings in their portfolio firms. Our results suggest that information advantages and governance experience obtained from multiple blockholdings are important channels through which institutions perform effective monitoring. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kang, Jun-Koo; Luo, Juan; Na, Hyun Seung</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The unintended consequences of divestment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davies, Shaun William; Van Wesep, Edward Dickersin
A divestment campaign aims to depress share prices to induce managers to change firm behavior. Assuming that managers make profit-maximizing decisions in the absence of a campaign, firms that accede to divestors' demands raise short-run share prices but depress long-run profits. Managers who are more interested in short-run prices are therefore more motivated by divestment than managers who care about long-run profits. We show that, as most managerial compensation contracts reward long-run profitability and stock returns, divestment can be ineffective at best, and perhaps counterproductive, rewarding managers who attract divestment campaigns. In a quantification exercise, we show that the wealth of most executives running likely divestment targets in 2015 would be unaffected by even large movements in share prices. Of those affected, a substantial majority would benefit from divestment. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Davies, Shaun William; Van Wesep, Edward Dickersin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing with beliefs-dependent risk aversion and learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berrada, Tony; Detemple, Jerome; Rindisbacher, Marcel
This paper studies equilibrium in a pure exchange economy with unobservable Markov switching growth regimes and beliefs-dependent risk aversion (BDRA). Risk aversion is stochastic and depends nonlinearly on consumption and beliefs. Equilibrium is obtained in closed form. The market price of risk, the interest rate, and the stock return volatility acquire new components tied to fluctuations in beliefs. A three-regime specification is estimated using the generalized method of moments (GMM). Model moments match their empirical counterparts for a variety of unconditional moments, including the equity premium, stock returns volatility, and the correlations between stock returns and consumption and dividends. Dynamic features of the data, such as the countercyclical behaviors of the equity premium and volatility, are also captured. Model volatility provides a good fit for realized volatility. A new factor, the information risk premium, is found to be a strong predictor of future excess returns. These results are obtained with an estimated risk aversion fluctuating between 1.44 and 1.93. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berrada, Tony; Detemple, Jerome; Rindisbacher, Marcel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash flow duration and the term structure of equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weber, Michael
The term structure of equity returns is downward-sloping: stocks with high cash flow duration earn 1.10% per month lower returns than short-duration stocks in the cross-section. I create a measure of cash flow duration at the firm level using balance sheet data to show this novel fact. Factor models can explain only 50% of the return differential, and the difference in returns is three times larger after periods of high investor sentiment. Analysts extrapolate from past earnings growth into the future and predict high returns for high-duration stocks following high-sentiment periods, contrary to ex-post realizations. I use institutional ownership as a proxy for short-sale constraints, and find the negative cross-sectional relationship between cash flow duration and returns is only contained within short-sale constrained stocks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Weber, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cost of experimentation and the evolution of venture capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ewens, Michael; Nanda, Ramana; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew
We study how technological shocks to the cost of starting new businesses have led the venture capital model to adapt in fundamental ways over the prior decade. We both document and provide a framework to understand the changes in the investment strategy of venture capitalists (VCs) in recent years - an increased prevalence of a "spray and pray" investment approach - where investors provide a little funding and limited governance to an increased number of startups that they are more likely to abandon, but where initial experiments significantly inform beliefs about the future potential of the venture. This adaptation and related entry by new financial intermediaries has led to a disproportionate rise in innovations where information on future prospects is revealed quickly and cheaply, and reduced the relative share of innovation in complex technologies where initial experiments cost more and reveal less. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ewens, Michael; Nanda, Ramana; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of media slant on firm behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baloria, Vishal P.; Heese, Jonas
The media can impose reputational costs on firms because of its important role as an information intermediary and its ability to negatively slant coverage. We exploit a quasi-natural experiment that holds constant the information event across firms but varies the availability of a major news outlet in local markets. We find that firms subject to the threat of slanted coverage suppress the release of negative information before the event and release it subsequently. Our results are consistent with theory on the active role firms can play in managing their reputational capital through anticipatory actions to avoid negative media coverage. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baloria, Vishal P.; Heese, Jonas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pilot CEOs and corporate innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sunder, Jayanthi; Sunder, Shyam V.; Zhang, Jingjing
We find evidence that chief executive officers' (CEOs') hobby of flying airplanes is associated with significantly better innovation outcomes, measured by patents and citations, greater innovation effectiveness, and more diverse and original patents. We rule out alternative explanations, leading us to conclude that CEO pilot credentials capture the personality trait of sensation seeking. Sensation seeking combines risk taking with a desire to pursue novel experiences and has been associated with creativity. Our evidence highlights sensation seeking as a valuable personality trait that can be used to identify CEOs who are likely to drive innovation success. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sunder, Jayanthi; Sunder, Shyam V.; Zhang, Jingjing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio concentration and performance of institutional investors worldwide</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Nicole; Fedenia, Mark; Skiba, Hilla; Sokolyk, Tatyana
Using data on security holdings for 10,771 institutional investors from 72 countries, we test whether concentrated investment strategies result in excess risk-adjusted returns. We examine several measures of portfolio concentration with respect to countries and industries and find that portfolio concentration is directly related to risk-adjusted returns for institutional investors worldwide. Results suggest, in contrast to traditional asset pricing theory and in support of information advantage theory, that concentrated investment strategies in international markets can be optimal. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Choi, Nicole; Fedenia, Mark; Skiba, Hilla; Sokolyk, Tatyana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How collateral laws shape lending and sectoral activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calomiris, Charles W.; Larrain, Mauricio; Liberti, Jose; Sturgess, Jason
We demonstrate the central importance of creditors' ability to use movable assets as collateral (as distinct from immovable real estate) when borrowing from banks. Using a unique cross-country micro-level loan data set containing loan-to-value ratios for different assets, we find that loan-to-values of loans collateralized with movable assets are lower in countries with weak collateral laws, relative to immovable assets, and that lending is biased toward the use of immovable assets. Using sector-level data, we find that weak movable collateral laws create distortions in the allocation of resources that favor immovable-based production and investment. An analysis of Slovakia's collateral law reform confirms our findings. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calomiris, Charles W.; Larrain, Mauricio; Liberti, Jose; Sturgess, Jason</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dealer financial conditions and lender-of-last-resort facilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Fleming, Michael J.; Hrung, Warren B.; Sarkar, Asani
We examine the financial conditions of dealers that participated in two of the Federal Reserve's lender-of-last-resort (LOLR) facilities the Term Securities Lending Facility (TSLF) and the Primary Dealer Credit Facility (PDCF) that provided liquidity against a range of assets during 2008-2009. Dealers with lower equity returns and greater leverage prior to borrowing from the facilities were more likely to participate in the programs, borrow more, and, in the case of the TSLF, at higher bidding rates. Dealers with less liquid collateral on their balance sheets before the facilities were introduced also tended to borrow more. The results suggest that both financial performance and balance sheet liquidity play a role in LOLR utilization. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Fleming, Michael J.; Hrung, Warren B.; Sarkar, Asani</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The unintended consequences of the zero lower bound policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Di Maggio, Marco; Kacperczyk, Marcin
We study the impact of the zero lower bound interest rate policy on the industrial organization of the U.S. money fund industry. We find that in response to policies that maintain low interest rates, money funds: change their product offerings by investing in riskier asset classes; are more likely to exit the market; and reduce the fees they charge their investors. The consequence of fund closures resulting from interest rate policy is the relocation of resources in affected fund families and in the asset management industry in general, as well as decline in capital of issuers borrowing from money funds. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Di Maggio, Marco; Kacperczyk, Marcin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systematic mistakes in the mortgage market and lack of financial sophistication</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Ben-David, Itzhak; Yao, Vincent
Institutions often offer a menu of contracts to consumers in an attempt to create a separating equilibrium that reveals borrower types and provides better pricing. We test the effectiveness of a specific set of contracts in the mortgage market: mortgage points. Points allow borrowers to exchange an upfront amount for a decrease in the mortgage rate. We document that, on average, points takers lose about $700. Also, points takers are less financially savvy (less educated, older), and they make mistakes on other dimensions (e.g., inefficiently refinancing their mortgages). Overall, our results show that borrowers overestimate how long they will stay with the mortgage. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Ben-David, Itzhak; Yao, Vincent</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt enforcement, investment, and risk taking across countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Favara, Giovanni; Morellec, Erwan; Schroth, Enrique; Valta, Philip
We argue that the prospect of an imperfect enforcement of debt contracts in default reduces shareholder-debtholder conflicts and induces leveraged firms to invest more and take on less risk as they approach financial distress. To test these predictions, we use a large panel of firms in 41 countries with heterogeneous debt enforcement characteristics. Consistent with our model, we find that the relation between debt enforcement and firms' investment and risk depends on the firm-specific probability of default. A differences-indifferences analysis of firms' investment and risk taking in response to bankruptcy reforms that make debt more renegotiable confirms the cross-country evidence. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Favara, Giovanni; Morellec, Erwan; Schroth, Enrique; Valta, Philip</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tail risk in hedge funds: A unique view from portfolio holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Ruenzi, Stefan; Weigert, Florian
We develop a new systematic tail risk measure for equity-oriented hedge funds to examine the impact of tail risk on fund performance and to identify the sources of tail risk. We find that tail risk affects the cross-sectional variation in fund returns and that investments in both tail-sensitive stocks and options drive tail risk. Moreover, leverage and exposure to funding liquidity shocks are important determinants of tail risk. We find evidence of some funds being able to time tail risk exposure prior to the 2008-2009 financial crisis. (c) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Ruenzi, Stefan; Weigert, Florian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are foreign investors locusts? The long-term effects of foreign institutional ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bena, Jan; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro; Pires, Pedro
This paper challenges the view that foreign investors lead firms to adopt a short-term orientation and forgo long-term investment. Using a comprehensive sample of publicly listed firms in 30 countries over the period 2001-2010, we find instead that greater foreign institutional ownership fosters long-term investment in tangible, intangible, and human capital. Foreign institutional ownership also leads to significant increases in innovation output. We identify these effects by exploiting the exogenous variation in foreign institutional ownership that follows the addition of a stock to the MSCI indexes. Our results suggest that foreign institutions exert a disciplinary role on entrenched corporate insiders worldwide. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bena, Jan; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro; Pires, Pedro</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt correlations in the wake of the financial crisis: What are appropriate default correlations for structured products?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nickerson, Jordan; Griffin, John M.
This paper proposes several frameworks to estimate the appropriate default correlations for structured products, each of which jointly considers the role of co-movements in modeled risk characteristics and unmodeled systematic risk, or 'frailty.' We contrast our estimates with credit rating agencies' default correlation assumptions, which were only 0.01 for Collateralized Loan Obligations (CLOs) pre-crisis and have increased to 0.03 post-crisis. In contrast, the joint consideration of observable risk factors and frailty leads to substantially higher estimates of 0.12. We show that this translates into CLOs with credit risk understated by 26%, suggesting caution for the post-crisis structured finance market. (c) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nickerson, Jordan; Griffin, John M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reexamining staggered boards and shareholder value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Alma; Wang, Charles C. Y.
Cohen and Wang (2013) (CW2013) provide evidence consistent with market participants perceiving staggered boards to be value reducing. Amihud and Stoyanov (2016) (AS2016) contests these findings, reporting some specifications under which the results are not statistically significant. We show that the results retain their significance under a wide array of robustness tests that address the concerns expressed by AS2016. Our empirical findings reinforce the conclusions of CW2013. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cohen, Alma; Wang, Charles C. Y.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Maximum likelihood estimation of the equity premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avdis, Efstathios; Wachter, Jessica A.
xThe equity premium the expected return on the aggregate stock market less the government bill rate - is of central importance to the portfolio allocation of individuals, to the investment decisions of firms, and to model calibration and testing. This quantity is usually estimated from the sample average excess return. We propose an alternative estimator, based on maximum likelihood, that takes into account information contained in dividends and prices. Applied to the postwar sample, our method leads to an economically significant reduction from 6.4% to 5.1%. Simulation results show that our method produces more reliable estimates under a wide range of specifications. (c) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avdis, Efstathios; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed trading and price discovery before corporate events</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baruch, Shmuel; Panayides, Marios; Venkataraman, Kumar
Stock prices incorporate less news before negative events than positive events. Further, informed agents use less price aggressive (limit) orders before negative events and more price aggressive (market) orders before positive events (buy-sell asymmetry). Motivated by these patterns, we model the execution risk that informed agents impose on each other and relate the asymmetry to costly short selling. When investor base is narrow, security borrowing is difficult, or the magnitude of the event is small, buy-sell asymmetry is pronounced and price discovery before negative events is lower. Overall, we show that the strategies of informed traders influence the process of price formation in financial markets, as predicted by theory. (c) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baruch, Shmuel; Panayides, Marios; Venkataraman, Kumar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of innovation: Evidence from corporate bond exchange-traded funds (ETFs)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dannhauser, Caitlin D.
Using distinct features of corporate bond exchange-traded funds (ETFs), I find that financial innovation has a significant and long-term positive valuation impact on the systemically important underlying securities. A one standard deviation increase in ETF ownership reduces high-yield and investment-grade bond spreads by 20.3 and 9.2 basis points, respectively, implying an average monthly price increase of 1.03% and 0.75%. Two novel quasi-natural experiments exploit exogenous changes in ETF eligibility to confirm the effect. Examining theoretical explanations for the effect, I find that ETFs decrease liquidity trader participation, increase institutional ownership, and insignificantly or negatively impact the liquidity of individual bonds. (c) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dannhauser, Caitlin D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk in clearing houses: Evidence from the European repo market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boissel, Charles; Derrien, Francois; Ors, Evren; Thesmar, David
We study how crises affect Central Clearing Counterparties (CCPs). We focus on a large and safe segment of the CCP-cleared repo market during the Eurozone sovereign debt crisis. We develop a simple model to infer CCP stress, which is measured as repo rates' sensitivity to sovereign credit default swaps (CDS) spreads and jointly captures (1) the effectiveness of haircut policies, (2) CCP-member default risk (conditional on sovereign default), and (3) CCP default risk (conditional on both sovereign and CCP-member default). During 2011, repo rates strongly respond to sovereign risk, particularly for Greece, Italy, Ireland, Portugal and Spain (GIIPS): Repo investors behaved as if the conditional probability of CCP default was substantial. (c) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boissel, Charles; Derrien, Francois; Ors, Evren; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility of aggregate volatility and hedge fund returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Arisoy, Y. Eser; Naik, Narayan Y.
This paper investigates empirically whether uncertainty about equity market volatility can explain hedge fund performance both in the cross section and over time. We measure uncertainty via volatility of aggregate volatility (VOV) and construct an investable version through returns on lookback straddles on the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE) volatility index, VIX. We find that VOV exposure is a significant determinant of hedge fund returns. After controlling for fund characteristics, we find a robust and significant negative risk premium for VOV exposure in the cross section of hedge fund returns. We corroborate our results using statistical and parameterized proxies of VOV over a longer sample period. (c) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Arisoy, Y. Eser; Naik, Narayan Y.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fire sale discount: Evidence from the sale of minority equity stakes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dinc, Serdar; Erel, Isil; Liao, Rose
Most empirical studies estimate the impact of fire sales either without the benefit of market prices from frequent trades, as with aircraft sales, or without observing transaction prices, as with the forced sales of equity securities by mutual funds facing outflows. We observe both by studying firms' sales of minority equity stakes in publicly listed third parties. We estimate the distressed sale discount to be about 8% while controlling for liquidity and for industry, or about double the 4% estimated for equity sales by distressed mutual funds. The discount becomes 13-14% if the stake sold is more than 5% of the firm or is sold as a block. Prices recover after distressed sales. (c) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Dinc, Serdar; Erel, Isil; Liao, Rose</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interbank networks in the National Banking Era: Their purpose and their role in the Panic of 1893</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calomiris, Charles W.; Carlson, Mark
The unit banking structure of the United States produced a uniquely important interbank correspondent network. During the National Banking Era, this network normally provided banks with access to money markets, facilitated payment processing, and helped banks meet legal reserve requirements. In crises, network connections could be a source of liquidity risk. That risk became evident during the Panic of 1893, when New York suspended convertibility. Banks with high two-sided liquidity risk (those holding more of their liquid assets with their correspondents and funded to a greater extent by deposits of other banks) were particularly exposed and more likely to close. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Calomiris, Charles W.; Carlson, Mark</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity and the corporation: Group disagreement and underinvestment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Giammarino, Ron; Lazrak, Ali
We study a dynamic corporate investment problem where decisions have to be made collectively by a group of agents holding heterogeneous beliefs and adhering to a "utilitarian" governance mechanism in which each agent has a given influence in the decision. In this setting we show that: (i)group decisions are typically dynamically inconsistent, (ii)dynamic inconsistency leads to inefficient underinvestment, and (iii)the ability to trade securities among insiders or with outsiders may restore efficient investment decisions but it may, in some cases, lead to inefficient overinvestment. Our theory can help explain the empirical evidence on the effect of diversity of groups, such as corporate boards, on firms' outcomes and, more generally, on the difference between group and individual behavior. (c) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Giammarino, Ron; Lazrak, Ali</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option repricing, corporate governance, and the effect of shareholder empowerment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gulen, Huseyin; O'Brien, William J.
We use the practice of employee option repricing to investigate how shareholder involvement in firm compensation policies affects the quality of firm governance. We find that a 2003 reform that empowered shareholders to approve or reject repricing proposals led to value increases in previous repricers. The likelihood of repricing becomes less sensitive to poor manager performance, but remains similarly sensitive to bad luck, after the reform. Average post-repricing changes in firm performance are positive only after the reform. Overall, our results suggest that shareholder empowerment improves the governance of repricing and can transform repricing into a value-creating tool. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gulen, Huseyin; O'Brien, William J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employment protection and takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dessaint, Olivier; Golubov, Andrey; Volpin, Paolo
Labor restructuring is a key driver of takeovers and the associated synergy gains worldwide. In a difference-in-differences research design, we show that major increases in employment protection reduce takeover activity by 14-27% and the combined firm gains (synergies) by over half. Consistent with the labor channel behind these effects, deals with greater potential for workforce restructuring show a greater reduction in volume, number, and synergies. Increases in employment protection impede layoffs, resulting in wage costs that match the magnitude of synergy losses. Offer prices are not fully adjusted, with both bidders and targets exhibiting lower returns following the reforms. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dessaint, Olivier; Golubov, Andrey; Volpin, Paolo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Moral hazard in active asset management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, David C.; Davies, Shaun William
We consider a model of active asset management in which mutual fund managers exert unobservable effort to earn excess returns. Investors allocate capital to actively managed funds and passively managed products. In equilibrium, investors are indifferent between investing an additional dollar with an active manager or with a passively managed product. As passively managed products become more attractive to investors, active managers' revenues froin portfolio-management services fall, reducing their effort incentives. More-severe decreasing-returns-to-scale are also associated with reduced incentives and increased moral hazard. Performance-based fees and holdings-based data are all unlikely to mitigate moral hazard. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, David C.; Davies, Shaun William</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impacts of political uncertainty on asset prices: Evidence from the Bo scandal in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Laura Xiaolei; Shu, Haibing; Wei, K. C. John
Models of political risk predict that increases in political uncertainty cause stock prices to fall, especially for politically sensitive firms. We use the event of the Bo Xilai political scandal in 2012 in China as an exogenous shock to identify the impact of political uncertainty on asset prices. We document that the Bo scandal caused a significant drop in stock prices, especially for firms that are more politically sensitive. Further analysis shows that the stock price drop is mainly driven by a change in discount rate, providing strong support for the existence of priced political risk. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Laura Xiaolei; Shu, Haibing; Wei, K. C. John</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal consumption, portfolio and life insurance rules for an uncertain lived individual in a continuous time model (vol 2, pg 187, 1975)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Richard, Scott F.
nan</description><author>Richard, Scott F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US multinationals and cash holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gu, Tiantian
U.S. multinational firms hold significantly more cash than domestic firms. I study this cash differential using a dynamic model featuring corporate physical and intangible investment, cross-border decisions, and financial policies. I find that the cash differential diminishes by 42% if repatriation costs are set to zero. Hence, costly repatriation induces cash accumulation offshore. Further, firms that invest overseas have different ex ante cash policies from firms that do not. I examine this self-selection effect by elimiriating heterogeneous intangibility across multinational and domestic firms, which reduces the cash differential by 28%. 1 also examine the likelihood of corporate inversion under federal regulations. The estimated annual tax loss to the U.S. Treasury from inversions is reduced from $2.2 billion to $1.3 billion if the requirements for foreign ownership are tightened from 20% to 50%. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gu, Tiantian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm characteristics, consumption risk, and firm-level risk exposures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, Robert F.; Lundblad, Christian T.
We propose a novel approach to measuring firm-level risk exposures and costs of equity. Using a simple consumption-based asset pricing model that explains nearly two-thirds of the variation in average returns across 55 anomaly portfolios, we map the relation between exposures to consumption risk and portfolio-level characteristics. We use this relation to calculate exposures to consumption risk at the firm level and show that the calculated consumption risk exposures yield portfolios with large differences in average returns and ex post consumption risk exposures consistent with those predicted by our calculated betas. Further, industry betas and risk premia implied by our procedure display economically intuitive variation over time. Finally, Fama-MacBeth regressions suggest that risk exposures calculated using our procedure dominate those from alternative factor models at explaining cross-sectional variation in returns. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dittmar, Robert F.; Lundblad, Christian T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank capital, liquid reserves, and insolvency risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hugonnier, Julien; Morellec, Erwan
We develop a dynamic model of banking to assess the effects of liquidity and leverage requirements on banks' financing decisions and insolvency risk. In this model, banks face taxation, issuance costs of securities, and default costs and maximize shareholder value by choosing their debt-to-asset ratio, deposits-to-debt ratio, liquid asset holdings, equity issuance and default policies in response to these frictions as well as regulatory requirements. Our analytic characterization of the bank policy choices shows that imposing liquidity requirements leads to lower bank losses in default at the cost of an increased likelihood of default. Combining liquidity and leverage requirements reduces both the likelihood of default and the magnitude of bank losses in default. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hugonnier, Julien; Morellec, Erwan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reputation and signaling in asset sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartman-Glaser, Barney
Static adverse selection models of security issuance show that informed issuers can perfectly reveal their private information by maintaining a costly stalce in the securities they issue. This paper shows that allowing an issuer to both signal current security quality via retention and build a reputation for honesty leads that issuer to misreport quality even when owning a positive stake, that is, the equilibrium is neither separating nor pooling. An issuer retains less as reputation improves and prices are more sensitive to retention when the issuer has a worse reputation. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hartman-Glaser, Barney</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Offshore activities and financial vs operational hedging</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoberg, Gerard; Moon, S. Katie
A key question is why many multinational firms forgo foreign exchange derivative (FX) hedging and instead use operational hedging. We propose an explanation based on illiquidity and the unique advantages of operational hedges. We use 10-K filings to construct dynamically updated text-based measures of the offshore sale of output, purchase of input, and ownership of assets. We find that firms use FX derivatives when they are liquid and generally available. Otherwise, they often favor purchasing input from the same nations they sell output to, an operational hedge. Quasi-natural experiments based on new derivative product launches suggest a likely causal relation. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hoberg, Gerard; Moon, S. Katie</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shaped by their daughters: Executives, female socialization, and corporate social responsibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cronqvist, Henrik; Yu, Frank
Corporate executives managing some of the largest public companies in the U.S. are shaped by their daughters. When a firm's chief executive officer (CEO) has a daughter, the corporate social responsibility rating (CSR) is about 9.1% higher, compared to a median firm. The results are robust to confronting several sources of endogeneity, e.g., examining first-born CEO daughters and CEO changes. The relation is strongest for diversity, but significant also for broader pro-social practices related to the environment and employee relations. Our study contributes to research on female socialization, heterogeneity in CSR policies, and plausibly exogenous determinants of CEOs' styles. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cronqvist, Henrik; Yu, Frank</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are corporate inversions good for shareholders?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Babkin, Anton; Glover, Brent; Levine, Oliver
Corporate inversion, the process of redomiciling for tax purposes, reduces corporate income taxes, but it imposes a personal tax cost that is shareholder-specific. We develop a model, incorporating the corporate tax benefits and personal tax costs, to quantify the return to inversion for different shareholders. Foreign and tax-exempt investors, along with the chief executive officer, disproportionately benefit. We show that an inversion simultaneously reduces the wealth of many taxable shareholders. The model illustrates an agency conflict in which heterogeneity in personal taxes generates a wealth transfer between shareholders. Furthermore, personal taxes offset the loss in government revenue by 39%. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Babkin, Anton; Glover, Brent; Levine, Oliver</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital utilization, market power, and the pricing of investment shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Song, Zhongzhi
Capital utilization and market power crucially affect asset prices in an economy exposed to shocks that improve real investment opportunities through capital-embodied technological innovations. We embed these two mechanisms in a standard general equilibrium model and show that (i) the price of risk for investment shocks is negative under fixed capital utilization, but positive under sufficiently flexible capital utilization, and (ii) the equity return exposure to investment shocks is negative under perfect competition, but positive under high market power. We further show that, high market power, persistent components in technology growth, and a strong preference for early resolution of uncertainty are jointly important to quantitatively match the observed equity risk premium. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Song, Zhongzhi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is economic uncertainty priced in the cross-section of stock returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Tang, Yi
We investigate the role of economic uncertainty in the cross-sectional pricing of individual stocks and equity portfolios. We estimate stock exposure to an economic uncertainty index and show that stocks in the lowest uncertainty beta decile generate 6% more annualized risk-adjusted return compared to stocks in the highest uncertainty beta decile. We find that the uncertainty premium is driven by the outperformance (underperformance) by stocks with negative (positive) uncertainty beta. Our results indicate that uncertainty averse investors demand extra compensation to hold stocks with negative uncertainty beta and they are willing to pay high prices for stocks with positive uncertainty beta. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Tang, Yi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Opportunism as a firm and managerial trait: Predicting insider trading profits and misconduct</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ali, Usman; Hirshleifer, David
We show that opportunistic insiders can be identified through the profitability of their trades prior to quarterly earnings announcements (QEAs) and that opportunistic trading is associated with various kinds of firm or managerial misconduct. A value-weighted trading strategy based on (not necessarily pre-QEA) trades of opportunistic insiders earns monthly four-factor alphas of over 1%, which is much higher than in past insider trading literature and substantial and significant even on the short side. Firms with opportunistic insiders have higher levels of earnings management, restatements, US Securities and Exchange Commission enforcement actions, shareholder litigation, and executive compensation. These findings suggest that opportunism is a domain-general trait. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ali, Usman; Hirshleifer, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Offshore schemes and tax evasion: The role of banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernykh, Lucy; Mityakov, Sergey
We use mandatory Russian banks' reports to the Central Bank to construct a novel measure of offshore-banking. Individual bank involvement in offshore operations is calculated as a fraction of total transactions with foreign countries that go through offshore financial centers. We find that offshore-active banks perform less financial intermediation and focus more on international wire transfers. We show a positive relation between banks' offshore activities and tax evasion of companies doing business through these banks. Finally, we show that the Central Bank eventually responds to this behavior: offshore-active banks have higher likelihood of license revocation and criminal investigation against top management. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chernykh, Lucy; Mityakov, Sergey</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic co-jumps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caporin, Massimiliano; Kolokolov, Aleksey; Reno, Roberto
The simultaneous occurrence of jumps in several stocks can be associated with major financial news, triggers short-term predictability in stock returns, is correlated with sudden spikes of the variance risk premium, and determines a persistent increase (decrease) of stock variances and correlations when they come along with bad (good) news. These systemic events and their implications can be easily overlooked by traditional univariate jump statistics applied to stock indices. They are instead revealed in a clearly cut way by using a novel test procedure applied to individual assets, which is particularly effective on high volume stocks. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caporin, Massimiliano; Kolokolov, Aleksey; Reno, Roberto</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax uncertainty and retirement savings diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, David C.; Cederburg, Scott; O'Doherty, Michael S.
We investigate the optimal savings decisions for investors with access to pre-tax (traditional) and post-tax (Roth) versions of tax-advantaged retirement accounts. The model features a progressive tax schedule and uncertainty over future tax rates. Traditional accounts are valuable for hedging retirement account performance and managing current income near tax-bracket cutoffs, whereas Roth accounts allow investors to mitigate uncertainty over future tax schedules. The optimal asset location policy for most households involves diversifying between traditional and Roth vehicles. Contrary to conventional advice, the substantial economic benefits from Roth investments are not limited to investors with low current income. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, David C.; Cederburg, Scott; O'Doherty, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Confidence, bond risks, and equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhao, Guihai
I show that investor confidence (size of ambiguity) about future consumption growth is driven by past consumption growth and inflation. The impact of inflation on confidence has moved considerably over time and switched on average from negative to positive in 1997. Motivated by this evidence, I develop and estimate a model in which the confidence process has discrete regime shifts, and I find that the time-varying impact of inflation on confidence enables the model to match bond risks over different subperiods. The model can also account for stock and bond return predictability, and correlation between price dividend ratios and inflation, among other features of the data. Crown Copyright (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhao, Guihai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Designated market makers still matter: Evidence from two natural experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clark-Joseph, Adam D.; Ye, Mao; Zi, Chao
Independent technological glitches forced two separate trading halts on different U.S. exchanges during the week of July 6, 2015. During each halt, all other exchanges remained open. We exploit exogenous variation provided by this unprecedented coincidence, in conjunction with a proprietary data set, to identify the causal impact of Designated Market Maker (DMM) participation on liquidity. When the voluntary liquidity providers on one exchange were removed, liquidity remained unchanged; when DMMs were removed, liquidity decreased market-wide. We find evidence consistent with the idea that these DMMs, despite facing only mild formal obligations, significantly improve liquidity in the modern electronic marketplace. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Clark-Joseph, Adam D.; Ye, Mao; Zi, Chao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank rescues and bailout expectations: The erosion of market discipline during the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hett, Florian; Schmidt, Alexander
We design a novel test for changes in market discipline based on the relation between firm-specific risk, credit spreads, and equity returns. We use our method to analyze the evolution of bailout expectations during the recent financial crisis. We find that bailout expectations peaked in reaction to government interventions following the failure of Lehman Brothers, and returned to pre-crisis levels following the initiation of the Dodd-Frank Act. We do not find such changes in market discipline for nonfinancial firms. Finally, market discipline is weaker for government-sponsored enterprises (GSEs) and systemically important banks (SIBs) than for investment banks. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hett, Florian; Schmidt, Alexander</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advising shareholders in takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levit, Doron
This paper studies the advisory role of the board of directors in takeovers. I develop a model in which the takeover premium and the ability of the target board to resist the takeover are endogenous. The analysis relates the influence of the board on target shareholders and the reaction of the market to its recommendations to various characteristics of the acquirer and the target. I also show that the expected target shareholder value can decrease with the expertise of the board and it is maximized when the board is biased against the takeover. Generally, uninformative and ignored recommendations are not necessarily evidence that the target board has no influence on the outcome of the takeover. Perhaps surprisingly, under the optimal board structure, target shareholders ignore the recommendations of the board, which are never informative in equilibrium. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Levit, Doron</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor flows and fragility in corporate bond funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Hao; Ng, David T.
This paper explores flow patterns in corporate bond mutual funds. We show that corporate bond funds exhibit a concave flow-to-performance relationship: their outflows are sensitive to bad performance more than their inflows are sensitive to good performance. Moreover, corporate bond funds tend to have greater sensitivity of outflows to bad performance when they have more illiquid assets and when the overall market illiquidity is high. These results point to the possibility of fragility in the fast-growing corporate bond market. The illiquidity of corporate bonds may generate a first-mover advantage among investors in corporate bond funds, amplifying their response to bad performance. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Hao; Ng, David T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rollover risk as market discipline: A two-sided inefficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisenbach, Thomas M.
Why does the market discipline that financial intermediaries face seem too weak during booms and too strong during crises? This paper shows in a general equilibrium setting that rollover risk as a disciplining device is effective only if all intermediaries face purely idiosyncratic risk. However, if assets are correlated, a two-sided inefficiency arises: Good aggregate states have intermediaries taking excessive risks, while bad aggregate states suffer from costly fire sales. The driving force behind this inefficiency is an amplifying feedback loop between asset values and market discipline. In equilibrium, financial intermediaries inefficiently amplify both positive and negative aggregate shocks. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eisenbach, Thomas M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Merger activity in industry equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimopoulos, Theodosios; Sacchetto, Stefano
We quantify the impact of merger activity on productive efficiency. We develop and calibrate a dynamic industry-equilibrium model that features mergers, entry, and exit by heterogeneous firms. Mergers affect productivity directly through realized synergies, and indirectly through firms' incentives to enter or exit the industry. Merger activity increases average firm productivity by 4.8%, of which 4.1% reflects the accumulation of synergies, and 0.7% the interaction between merger options and firms' entry and exit decisions. We show that ignoring the implications of merger activity for public policies that promote entry can reverse the expected impact of these policies on productivity. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dimopoulos, Theodosios; Sacchetto, Stefano</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of institutional investor objectives on firm valuation and governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borochin, Paul; Yang, Jie
We find that ownership by different types of institutional investors has varying implications for future firm misvaluation and governance characteristics. Dedicated institutional investors decrease future firm misvaluation, in both direction and magnitude, relative to fundamentals. In contrast, transient institutional investors have the opposite effect. Using the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) Regulation FD as an exogenous shock to information dissemination, we find evidence consistent with dedicated institutions having an information advantage. Similarly, dedicated investors are associated with better future governance characteristics, while transient investors are not. The valuation effects are primarily driven by institutional portfolio concentration while the governance effects are driven by portfolio turnover. These results imply a more nuanced relationship between institutional ownership and firm value and corporate governance. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Borochin, Paul; Yang, Jie</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An extrapolative model of house price dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glaeser, Edward L.; Nathanson, Charles G.
A model in which homebuyers make a modest approximation leads house prices to display three features present in the data but usually missing from rational models: momentum at one-year horizons, mean reversion at five-year horizons, and excess longer-term volatility relative to fundamentals. Approximating buyers assume that past prices reflect only contemporaneous demand, just like professional economists who use trends in housing prices to infer trends in housing demand. Consistent with survey evidence, this approximation leads buyers to expect increases in the market value of their homes after recent house price increases. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Glaeser, Edward L.; Nathanson, Charles G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do managers overreact to salient risks? Evidence from hurricane strikes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dessaint, Olivier; Matray, Adrien
We study how managers respond to hurricane events when their firms are located in the neighborhood of the disaster area. We find that the sudden shock to the perceived liquidity risk leads managers to increase corporate cash holdings and to express more concerns about hurricane risk in 10-Ks/10-Qs, even though the actual risk remains unchanged. Both effects are temporary. Over time, the perceived risk decreases, and the bias disappears. The distortion between perceived and actual risk is large, and the increase in cash is suboptimal. Overall, managerial reaction to hurricanes is consistent with salience theories of choice. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dessaint, Olivier; Matray, Adrien</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The source of information in prices and investment-price sensitivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Jayaraman, Sudarshan; Schneemeier, Jan
This paper shows that real decisions depend not only on the total amount of information in prices, but the source of this information-a manager learns from prices when they contain information not possessed by him. We use the staggered enforcement of insider trading laws across 27 countries as a shock to the source of information that leaves total information unchanged: enforcement reduces (increases) managers' (outsiders') contribution to the stock price. Consistent with the predictions of our theoretical model, enforcement increases investment-q sensitivity, even when controlling for total price informativeness. The effect is larger in industries where learning is likely to be stronger, and in emerging countries where outsider information acquisition rises most post-enforcement. Enforcement does not increase the sensitivity of investment to cash flow, a non-price measure of investment opportunities. These findings suggest that extant measures of price efficiency should be rethought when evaluating real efficiency. More broadly, our paper provides causal evidence that managers learn from prices, by using a shock to price informativeness. (C) 2017 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Jayaraman, Sudarshan; Schneemeier, Jan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Activism mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyson, Nicole M.; Gantchev, Nickolay; Shivdasani, Anil
Shareholder value creation from hedge fund activism occurs primarily by influencing takeover outcomes for targeted firms. Controlling for selection decisions, activist interventions substantially increase the probability of a takeover offer. Third-party bids for targets have higher returns, premia, and completion rates, but these patterns reverse when the activist is the bidder. Failed bids for activism targets lead to improvements in operating performance, financial policy, and positive long-term abnormal returns, suggesting that activism enhances value. The positive long-term performance from hedge fund activism arises from monitoring target management during merger and acquisition contests and not from target undervaluation or bidder overpayment. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boyson, Nicole M.; Gantchev, Nickolay; Shivdasani, Anil</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of portfolio disclosure on hedge fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shi, Zhen
Consistent with the argument that portfolio disclosure reveals trade secrets, a difference in-differences estimation suggests a drop in fund performance after a hedge fund begins filing Form 13F as well as an increase in return correlations with other funds in the same investment style. The drop in performance is concentrated among funds with larger expected proprietary costs of disclosure, for instance, funds that disclose a greater fraction of their assets or hold more illiquid stocks. The drop in performance cannot be fully explained by alternative explanations such as decreasing returns to scale or mean reversion in fund returns. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shi, Zhen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intermediary asset pricing: New evidence from many asset classes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo; Kelly, Bryan; Manela, Asaf
We find that shocks to the equity capital ratio of financial intermediaries Primary Dealer counterparties of the New York Federal Reserve possess significant explanatory power for cross-sectional variation in expected returns. This is true not only for commonly studied equity and government bond market portfolios, but also for other more sophisticated asset classes such as corporate and sovereign bonds, derivatives, commodities, and currencies. Our intermediary capital risk factor is strongly procyclical, implying countercyclical intermediary leverage. The price of risk for intermediary capital shocks is consistently positive and of similar magnitude when estimated separately for individual asset classes, suggesting that financial intermediaries are marginal investors in many markets and hence key to understanding asset prices. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Zhiguo; Kelly, Bryan; Manela, Asaf</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International correlation risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mueller, Philippe; Stathopoulos, Andreas; Vedolin, Andrea
We show that the cross-sectional dispersion of conditional foreign exchange (FX) correlation is countercyclical and that currencies that perform badly (well) during periods of high dispersion yield high (low) average excess returns. We also find a negative cross-sectional association between average FX correlations and average option-implied FX correlation risk premiums. Our findings show that while investors in spot currency markets require a positive risk premium for exposure to high dispersion states, FX option prices are consistent with investors being compensated for the risk of low dispersion states. To address our empirical findings, we propose a no-arbitrage model that features unspanned FX correlation risk. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mueller, Philippe; Stathopoulos, Andreas; Vedolin, Andrea</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board reforms and firm value: Worldwide evidence (vol 125, pg 120, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fauver, Larry; Hung, Mingyi; Li, Xi; Taboada, Alvaro G.
nan</description><author>Fauver, Larry; Hung, Mingyi; Li, Xi; Taboada, Alvaro G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Precautionary savings, retirement planning and misperceptions of financial literacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Anders; Baker, Forest; Robinson, David T.
We measure financial literacy among Linkedln members, complementing standard questions with additional questions that allow us to gauge self-perceptions of financial literacy. Average financial literacy is surprisingly low given the demographics of our sample: fewer than two-thirds of chief financial officers, chief executive officers, and chief operating officers complete the test correctly. Financial literacy, precautionary savings and retirement planning are positively correlated, but this is mostly driven by perceived, not actual, literacy: controlling for self-perceptions, actual literacy has low predictive power. Perceptions drive decision-making among low-literacy respondents and are associated with mistaken beliefs about financial products and less willingness to accept financial advice. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Anderson, Anders; Baker, Forest; Robinson, David T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of credit default swap trading on information asymmetry in syndicated loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amiram, Dan; Beaver, William H.; Landsman, Wayne R.; Zhao, Jianxin
This study shows that initiation of credit default swap (CDS) trading for an entity's debt increases the share of loans retained by loan syndicate lead arrangers and increases loan spread. These findings are consistent with CDS initiation reducing the effectiveness of a lead arranger's stake in the loan to serve as a mechanism to address the adverse selection and moral hazard problems in the loan syndicate. Additional findings corroborate this interpretation by revealing a moderating effect for firms with greater transparency, for loans originated by a lead arranger with a strong reputation in this market, and for firms with relatively illiquid CDS markets. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amiram, Dan; Beaver, William H.; Landsman, Wayne R.; Zhao, Jianxin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee bargaining power, inter-firm competition, and equity-based compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bova, Francesco; Yang, Liyan
We develop a model to illustrate that equity-based compensation for non-executive employees and product market decisions are related. When the product market is competitive and employees have low bargaining power, the unique equilibrium is for each firm's owners to offer equity-based compensation to their employees. In this setting, equity-based compensation leads to a lower wage rate, which makes each firm more competitive with its rival. However, this unique equilibrium is a Prisoner's Dilemma for the firms' original owners. Our results are consistent with several empirical regularities and provide predictions on when firms will offer equity-based compensation to their employees. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bova, Francesco; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic risk and the manager</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glover, Brent; Levine, Oliver
We develop a model to characterize and quantify the effects of stock, option, and fixed compensation on a manager's risk-taking incentive and investment choice. We find the average chief executive officer's (CEO) compensation contract incentivizes overinvestment by 1.3 percentage points per year, with significant variation across firms and over time. We estimate a value of CEO effort implied by compensation contracts and find it to be strongly related to firm intangibility. Finally, we assess the effects on investment of FAS 123R and a hypothetical ban on option grants and find heterogeneous responses that depend on firm volatility and the prior structure of compensation. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Glover, Brent; Levine, Oliver</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Acquiring growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levine, Oliver
I develop a model of mergers in which M&amp;A deals are used to reallocate investment opportunities. In equilibrium, acquirers lack internal growth options and seek out projects from targets in the M&amp;A market. The model is able to reconcile many features of the merger data that I document, including the high productivity, investment, and valuation of target firms. Furthermore, in my model, profitability is highly predictive of acquisition, and merger transactions naturally lead to a substantial drop in profitability despite creating value for the acquirer. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Levine, Oliver</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early peek advantage? Efficient price discovery with tiered information disclosure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Grace Xing; Pan, Jun; Wang, Jiang
From 2007 to June 2013, a small group of fee-paying, high-speed traders receive the Michigan Index of Consumer Sentiment two seconds before its broader release. Within this early peek window, we find highly concentrated trading and a fast price discovery of less than 200 milliseconds. Outside this narrow window, general investors trade at fully adjusted prices. We further establish a causal relationship between the early peek mechanism and the fast price discovery by isolating the impact of the early peek arrangement along two dimensions. In cross section, we use other news releases without the early peek (as controls); in time series, we use the sudden suspension of the early peek arrangement in July 2013 (as the treatment). Our difference-in-difference tests directly connect the early peek arrangement to more efficient price discovery - it results in faster price discovery, lower volatility, and faster resolution of uncertainty. These results show that contrary to the common perception, tiered information release may help to reduce, rather than enhance, the informational advantage of faster traders and improve the efficiency of the price discovery process in financial markets. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hu, Grace Xing; Pan, Jun; Wang, Jiang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Staggered boards and long-term firm value, revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Litov, Lubomir P.; Sepe, Simone M.
This paper revisits the staggered board debate focusing on the long-term association of firm value with changes in board structure. We find no evidence that staggered board changes are negatively related to firm value. However, we find a positive relation for firms engaged in innovation and where stakeholder relationships matter more. This suggests that staggered boards promote value creation for some firms by committing the firm to undertaking long-term projects and bonding it to the relationship-specific investments of its stakeholders. Our results are robust to matching procedures and an exogenous change in Massachusetts corporate law that mandated staggered boards. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Litov, Lubomir P.; Sepe, Simone M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Well-connected short-sellers pay lower loan fees: A market-wide analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chague, Fernando; De-Losso, Rodrigo; De Genaro, Alan; Giovannetti, Bruno
High loan fees generate short-selling constraints and, therefore, reduce price efficiency. Despite the importance of loan fees, empirical evidence on their determinants is scarce. Using a market-wide deal-by-deal data set on the Brazilian equity lending market which uniquely identifies borrowers, brokers, and lenders, we are able to construct a proxy of search costs at the borrower-stock-day level. We find that for the same stock, on the same day borrowers with higher search costs pay significantly higher loan fees. Our results suggest that regulators should encourage the use of a centralized lending platform to reduce search costs in the lending market. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chague, Fernando; De-Losso, Rodrigo; De Genaro, Alan; Giovannetti, Bruno</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information percolation, momentum and reversal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrei, Daniel; Cujean, Julien
We propose a joint theory of time -series momentum and reversal based on a rational expectations model. We show that a necessary condition for momentum to arise in this framework is that information flows at an increasing rate. We focus on word-ofmouth communication as a mechanism that enforces this condition and generates shortterm momentum and long-term reversal. Investors with heterogeneous trading strategies contrarian and momentum traders coexist in the marketplace. Although a significant proportion of investors are momentum traders, momentum is not completely eliminated. Word-of-mouth communication spreads rumors and generates price run-ups and reversals. Our theoretical predictions are in line with empirical findings. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andrei, Daniel; Cujean, Julien</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited disclosure and hidden orders in asset markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Monnet, Cyril; Quintin, Erwan
Opacity assumes at least two prominent forms in asset markets. Dark exchanges and over-the-counter markets enable expert investors to hide their orders while originators carefully control the disclosure of fundamental information about the assets they source. We describe a simple model in which both forms of opacity- hidden orders and limited disclosure - complement one another. Costly investor expertise gives originators incentives to deliver assets of good quality. Keeping expert orders hidden generates the rents investors need to justify investing in expertise in the first place. Limiting disclosure mitigates the resulting adverse selection issues. Originators prefer to restrict the information they can convey to experts because it encourages the participation of non experts. This optimal organization of asset markets can be decentralized using standard financial arrangements. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Monnet, Cyril; Quintin, Erwan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification and cash dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakke, Tor-Erik; Gu, Tiantian
Why do diversified firms hold significantly less cash than focused firms? We study this question using a dynamic model of corporate investment, saving, and diversification decisions. We find that investment dynamics are more important in explaining the cash differences than financing frictions. More efficient internal capital markets increase cash differences and are especially valuable when a firm diversifies or refocuses. Contrary to static models, more diverse conglomerates have lower cash differences. Endogenous selection (diversifying firms are larger and have better growth opportunities) accounts for 68% of the cash difference, and the diversification event itself reduces cash holdings by 32%. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bakke, Tor-Erik; Gu, Tiantian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining CEO retention in misreporting firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beneish, Messod D.; Marshall, Cassandra D.; Yang, Jun
We propose a framework that advances our understanding of Chief Executive Officer (CEO) retention decisions in misreporting firms. Consistent with economic intuition, outside directors are more likely to fire (retain) CEOs when retention (replacement) costs are high relative to replacement (retention) costs. When the decision is ambiguous because neither cost dominates, outside directors are more likely to retain the CEO when they both benefit from selling stock in the misreporting period. We show that joint abnormal selling captures director-CEO alignment incrementally to biographical overlap. This new proxy operationalizes information sharing and trust, making it useful for studying economic decision making embedded in social relationships. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beneish, Messod D.; Marshall, Cassandra D.; Yang, Jun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The US listing gap</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Stulz, Rene M.
Relative to other countries, the U.S. now has abnormally few listed firms. This "U.S. listing gap" is consistent with a decrease in the net benefit of a listing for U.S. firms. Since the listing peak in 1996, the propensity to be listed is lower for all firm size categories and industries, the new list rate is low, and the delist rate is high. The high delist rate accounts for 46% of the listing gap and the low new list rate for 54%. The high delist rate is explained by an unusually high rate of acquisitions of publicly listed firms. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Independent boards and innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balsmeier, Benjamin; Fleming, Lee; Manso, Gustavo
Much research has suggested that independent boards of directors are more effective in reducing agency costs and improving firm governance. How they influence innovation is less clear. Relying on regulatory changes, we show that firms that transition to independent boards focus on more crowded and familiar areas of technology. They patent and claim more and receive more total future citations to their patents. However, the citation increase comes mainly from incremental patents in the middle of the citation distribution; the numbers of uncited and highly cited patents arguably associated with riskier innovation strategies do not change significantly. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balsmeier, Benjamin; Fleming, Lee; Manso, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of director experience on acquisition performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Field, Laura Casares; Mkrtchyan, Anahit
Prior research finds that firms hire directors for their acquisition experience, regardless of acquisition quality (whether their prior acquisitions earned positive or negative announcement returns). Using several short- and long-run measures, we examine the effects of directors' acquisition experience on the acquisition performance of firms hiring them. We find that board acquisition experience is positively related to subsequent acquisition performance, demonstrating that firms appropriately value experience. Beyond experience itself, however, the quality of directors' prior acquisitions is also important. Our results suggest that firms may be better served to select directors based upon both past acquisition experience and acquisition performance. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Field, Laura Casares; Mkrtchyan, Anahit</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International tests of a five-factor asset pricing model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
Average stock returns for North America, Europe, and Asia Pacific increase with the book-to-market ratio (B/M) and profitability and are negatively related to investment. For Japan, the relation between average returns and B/M is strong, but average returns show little relation to profitability or investment. A five-factor model that adds profitability and investment factors to the three-factor model of Fama and French (1993) largely absorbs the patterns in average returns. As in Fama and French (2015, 2016), the model's prime problem is failure to capture fully the low average returns of small stocks whose returns behave like those of low profitability firms that invest aggressively. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do corporate taxes hinder innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mukherjee, Abhiroop; Singh, Manpreet; Zaldokas, Alminas
We exploit staggered changes in state-level corporate tax rates to show that an increase in taxes reduces future innovation. A variety of tests, including those based on policy discontinuity at contiguous counties straddling borders of politically similar states, show that local economic conditions do not drive our results. The effect we document is consistent across the innovation spectrum: taxes affect not only patenting and R&amp;D investment but also new product introductions, which we measure using textual analysis. Our empirical results are consistent with models that highlight the role of higher corporate taxes in reducing innovator incentives and discouraging risk-taking. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mukherjee, Abhiroop; Singh, Manpreet; Zaldokas, Alminas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interim fund performance and fundraising in private equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, Brad M.; Yasuda, Ayako
General partners (GPs) in private equity (PE) report the performance of an existing fund while raising capital for a follow-on fund. Interim performance has large effects on fundraising outcomes. The impact is greatest when backed by exits and for low reputation GPs. Faced with these incentives, GPs time their fundraising to coincide with periods of peak performance through two strategies: (1) exit and fundraise and (2) net asset value (NAV) management. Consistent with the former, performance peaks are greatest for funds with high realization rates. Consistent with the latter, low reputation GPs with low realization rates experience performance peaks and erosions in performance after fundraising. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barber, Brad M.; Yasuda, Ayako</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who is internationally diversified? Evidence from the 401(k) plans of 296 firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, Geert; Hoyem, Kenton; Hu, Wei-Yin; Ravina, Enrichetta
Drawing on a novel database of the 401(k) plans of 296 firms, we examine the international equity allocations of 3.8 million individuals over the 2005-2011 period. We find enormous cross-individual variation, ranging from zero to more than 75%, and strong cohort effects, with younger cohorts investing more internationally than older ones and each cohort investing more internationally over time. Access to financial advice, lower fees, and more international fund choices are associated with higher international allocations, suggesting a role for plan design and policy. Education, financial literacy, and the fraction of foreign-born population in the ZIP code also have positive effects on international diversification, consistent with explanations based on familiarity bias and information barriers. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Hoyem, Kenton; Hu, Wei-Yin; Ravina, Enrichetta</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Shocks and Short-Term Market Underreaction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, George J.; Zhu, Kevin X.
Using jumps in stock prices as a proxy for large information shocks, we provide evidence consistent with short-term underreaction in the US equity market. Strategies long (short) stocks with positive (negative) lagged jump returns earn significantly positive returns over the next one-to three-month horizons. The results based on intraday jumps, especially overnight jumps, provide further evidence consistent with underreaction. The underreaction is robust to controlling for other firm characteristics, extends stock return momentum over intermediate to short horizons, and captures market underreaction to information shocks beyond earnings surprises. We further show that limited investor attention contributes to short-term underreaction. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, George J.; Zhu, Kevin X.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of returns: Facts and theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Koijen, Ralph S. J.
We summarize and extend the new literature on the term structure of equity. Short-term equity claims, or dividend strips, have higher average returns and Sharpe ratios than the aggregate stock market. The returns on short-term dividend claims are risky as measured by volatility, but safe as measured by market beta. These facts are hard to reconcile with traditional macro-finance models and we provide an overview of new models that can reproduce some of these facts. We relate our evidence on dividend strips to facts about other asset classes such as nominal and corporate bonds, volatility, and housing. We discuss the broader economic implications of our findings by linking the term structure of returns to real economic decisions such as hiring and investment. We conclude with an outline of empirical and theoretical extensions that we consider interesting avenues for future research. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Koijen, Ralph S. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do loans contain covenants? Evidence from lending relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prilmeier, Robert
Despite the importance of banks' role as delegated monitors, little is known about how non-price terms of loan contracts are structured to optimize information production in a lending relationship. Using a large sample of corporate loans, this paper examines the effect of relationship lending on covenant choice. Consistent with information asymmetry theories, covenant tightness is relaxed over the duration of a relationship, especially for opaque borrowers. In contrast, the effect of lending relationship intensity on the number of covenants included in a loan follows an inverted U shape. I discuss potential explanations for this finding. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Prilmeier, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage and strategic preemption: Lessons from entry plans and incumbent investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cookson, J. Anthony
This paper empirically investigates the effect of leverage on strategic preemption. Using new data on entry plans and incumbent investments from the American casino industry, I find that high leverage prevents incumbents from responding to entry threats. Facing the same set of entry plans, low-leverage incumbents expand physical capacity (by 30%), whereas high-leverage incumbents do not. This difference in investment matters because capacity installations preempt eventual entry. Stock market reactions to withdrawn plans imply that effective preemption increases incumbent firm value by 5%. My findings suggest that leverage matters for industry composition, not just firm-level investment. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cookson, J. Anthony</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do staggered boards harm shareholders?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amihud, Yakov; Stoyanov, Stoyan
We examine the Cohen and Wang (2013) conclusion that a staggered board lowers firm value based on the stock price reaction to two 2010 Delaware court rulings in the Air gas, Inc. case. The first ruling weakened the potency of a staggered board and the second restored it. We find that the Cohen and Wang results, for their sample, become insignificant after excluding a few penny stocks, stocks with value below $10 million, or over-the-counter (non-exchange) stocks. The effects of the rulings are also insignificant for an alternative sample. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Amihud, Yakov; Stoyanov, Stoyan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information disclosure, firm growth, and the cost of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dutta, Sunil; Nezlobin, Alexander
We study how information disclosure affects the cost of equity capital and investor welfare in a dynamic setting. We show that a firm's cost of capital decreases (increases) in the precision of public disclosure if the firm's growth rate is below (above) a certain threshold. The threshold growth rate is higher when the firm's cash flows are more persistent, or when other firms in the economy are growing at low rates. While current shareholders always prefer maximum public disclosure, future shareholders' welfare decreases (increases) in the precision of public disclosure if the firm's growth rate is below (above) the threshold. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dutta, Sunil; Nezlobin, Alexander</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reference-dependent preferences and the risk-return trade-off</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Huijun; Yan, Jinghua; Yu, Jianfeng
This paper studies the cross-sectional risk-return trade-off in the stock market. A fundamental principle in finance is the positive relation between risk and expected return. However, recent empirical evidence suggests the opposite. Using several intuitive risk measures, we show that the negative risk-return relation is much more pronounced among firms in which investors face prior losses, but the risk-return relation is positive among firms in which investors face prior gains. We consider a number of possible explanations for this new empirical finding and conclude that reference-dependent preference is the most promising explanation. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Huijun; Yan, Jinghua; Yu, Jianfeng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Customer-supplier relationships and corporate tax avoidance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cen, Ling; Maydew, Edward L.; Zhang, Liandong; Zuo, Luo
We investigate whether firms in close customer supplier relationships are better able to identify and implement tax avoidance strategies via supply chains. Consistent with our prediction, we find that both principal customers and their dependent suppliers avoid more taxes than other firms. Further analysis suggests that principal customers and dependent suppliers likely engage in tax strategies involving shifting profits to tax haven subsidiaries. Moreover, tax benefits appear to explain both principal customer firms' and dependent supplier firms' organizational decisions. Overall, our study provides evidence of the importance of tax avoidance as a source of gains from these relationships. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cen, Ling; Maydew, Edward L.; Zhang, Liandong; Zuo, Luo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of asymmetric information on product market outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, Matthew T.; Garfinkel, Jon A.; Yu, Miaomiao
We explore how asymmetric information in financial markets affects outcomes in product markets. Difference-in-difference tests around brokerage house merger/closure events (which increase asymmetric information through reductions in analyst coverage) indicate worse industry-adjusted sales growth for shocked firms than for their peers. Our results are consistent with Bolton and Scharfstein's (1990) tradeoff between investor agency concerns and predation risk. Further support is found in stronger treatment effects among firms with ex ante greater agency concerns, financing constraints, asymmetric information, and those operating in ex ante more competitive (fluid) product market spaces. Our results are concentrated in industries where we can clearly identify either net firm entry or exit. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Billett, Matthew T.; Garfinkel, Jon A.; Yu, Miaomiao</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News implied volatility and disaster concerns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manela, Asaf; Moreira, Alan
We construct a text-based measure of uncertainty starting in 1890 using front-page articles of the Wall Street Journal. News implied volatility (NVIX) peaks during stock market crashes, times of policy-related uncertainty, world wars, and financial crises. In US postwar data, periods when NVIX is high are followed by periods of above average stock returns, even after controlling for contemporaneous and forward-looking measures of stock market volatility. News coverage related to wars and government policy explains most of the time variation in risk premia our measure identifies. Over the longer 1890-2009 sample that includes the Great Depression and two world wars, high NVIX predicts high future returns in normal times and rises just before transitions into economic disasters. The evidence is consistent with recent theories emphasizing time variation in rare disaster risk as a source of aggregate asset prices fluctuations. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Manela, Asaf; Moreira, Alan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Customer concentration and loan contract terms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Gao, Janet
We study pricing and non-pricing features of loan contracts to gauge how the credit market evaluates a firm's customer-base profile and supply-chain relations. Higher customer concentration increases interest rate spreads and the number of restrictive covenants featured in newly initiated as well as renegotiated bank loans. Customer concentration also abbreviates the maturity of those loans as well as the relationship between firms and their banks. These effects are intensified by customers' financial distress, the level of relationship-specific investments, and the use of trade credit in customer-supplier relations. Our evidence shows that a deeper exposure to a small set of large customers bears negative consequences for a firm's relations with its creditors, revealing limits to integration along the supply chain. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Gao, Janet</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth through rigidity: An explanation for the rise in CEO pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shue, Kelly; Townsend, Richard R.
The dramatic rise in CEO compensation during the 1990s and early 2000s is a long-standing puzzle. In this paper, we show that much of the rise can be explained by a tendency of firms to grant the same number of options each year. Number-rigidity implies that the grant-date value of option awards will grow with firm equity returns, which were very high on average during the tech boom. Further, other forms of CEO compensation did not adjust to offset the dramatic growth in the value of option pay. Number-rigidity in options can also explain the increased dispersion in pay, the difference in growth between the US and other countries, and the increased correlation between pay and firm-specific equity returns. We present evidence that number-rigidity arose from a lack of sophistication about option valuation that is akin to money illusion. We show that regulatory changes requiring transparent expensing of the grant-date value of options led to a decline in number-rigidity and helps explain why executive pay increased less with equity returns during the housing boom in the mid-2000s. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shue, Kelly; Townsend, Richard R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intangible capital and the investment-q relation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peters, Ryan H.; Taylor, Lucian A.
The neoclassical theory of investment has mainly been tested with physical investment, but we show that it also helps explain intangible investment. At the firm level, Tobin's q explains physical and intangible investment roughly equally well, and it explains total investment even better. Compared with physical capital, intangible capital adjusts more slowly to changes in investment opportunities. The classic q theory performs better in firms and years with more intangible capital: Total and even physical investment are better explained by Tobin's q and are less sensitive to cash flow. At the macro level, Tobin's q explains intangible investment many times better than physical investment. We propose a simple, new Tobin's q proxy that accounts for intangible capital, and we show that it is a superior proxy for both physical and intangible investment opportunities. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Peters, Ryan H.; Taylor, Lucian A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of firm prestige on executive compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Focke, Florens; Maug, Ernst; Niessen-Ruenzi, Alexandra
We show that chief executive officers (CEOs) of prestigious firms earn less. Total compensation is on average 8% lower for firms listed in Fortune's ranking of America's most admired companies. We suggest that CEOs are willing to trade off status and career benefits from working for a publicly admired company against additional monetary compensation. Our identification strategy is based on matched sample analyses, difference-in-differences regressions, and a regression discontinuity design. We perform several robustness checks and exclude many alternative explanations, including that firm prestige just proxies for better corporate governance or for increased exposure of the pay-setting process to media attention. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Focke, Florens; Maug, Ernst; Niessen-Ruenzi, Alexandra</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>WSJ Category Kings - The impact of media attention on consumer and mutual fund investment decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaniel, Ron; Parham, Robert
We exploit a novel natural experiment to establish a causal relation between media attention and consumer investment behavior, independent of the conveyed information. Our findings indicate a 31% local average increase in quarterly capital flows into mutual funds mentioned in a prominent Wall Street Journal "Category Kings" ranking list, compared to those funds which just missed making the list. This flow increase is about seven times larger than extra flows due to the well-documented performance-flow relation. Other funds in the same fund complex receive substantial extra flows as well, especially in smaller complexes. There is no increase in flows when the Wall Street Journal publishes similar lists absent the prominence of the Category Kings labeling. We show mutual fund managers react to the incentive created by the media effect in a strategic way predicted by theory, and present evidence for the existence of propagation mechanisms including increased fund complex advertising subsequent to having a Category King and increased efficacy of subsequent fund media mentions. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaniel, Ron; Parham, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How persistent is private equity performance? Evidence from deal-level data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Braun, Reiner; Jenkinson, Tim; Stoff, Ingo
The persistence of returns is a critical issue for investors in their choice of private equity managers. In this paper, we analyse buyout performance persistence in new ways, using a unique database containing cash flow data on 13,523 portfolio company investments by 865 buyout funds. We focus on unique realized deals and find that persistence of fund managers has substantially declined as the private equity sector has matured and become more competitive. Private equity has, therefore, largely conformed to the pattern found in most other asset classes in which past performance is a poor predictor of the future. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Braun, Reiner; Jenkinson, Tim; Stoff, Ingo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of variance risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dew-Becker, Ian; Giglio, Stefano; Le, Anh; Rodriguez, Marius
Between 1996 and 2014, it was costless on average to hedge news about future variance at horizons ranging from 1 quarter to 14 years. Only unexpected, transitory realized variance was significantly priced. These results present a challenge to many structural models of the variance risk premium, such as the intertemporal CAPM and recent models with Epstein-Zin preferences and long-run risks. The results are also difficult to reconcile with macro models in which volatility affects investment decisions. At the same time, the data allows us to distinguish between different disaster models; a model in which the stock market has a time-varying exposure to disasters and investors have power utility fits the major features of the variance term structure. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dew-Becker, Ian; Giglio, Stefano; Le, Anh; Rodriguez, Marius</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political uncertainty and investment: Causal evidence from US gubernatorial elections</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jens, Candace E.
I examine the link between political uncertainty and firm investment using U.S. gubernatorial elections as a source of plausibly exogenous variation in uncertainty. Investment declines 5% before all elections and up to 15% for subsamples of firms particularly susceptible to political uncertainty. I use term limits as an instrumental variable (IV) for election closeness. Because close elections are related to economic downturns, I find that the effect of close elections on investment is understated by more than half by ordinary least squares (OLS). Post-election rebounds in investment depend on whether an incumbent is re-elected. Finally, I provide evidence that firms delay equity and debt issuances tied to investments before elections. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jens, Candace E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skill and luck in private equity performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korteweg, Arthur; Sorensen, Morten
Private equity (PE) performance is persistent, with PE firms consistently producing high (or low) net-of-fees returns. We use a new variance decomposition model to isolate three components of persistence. We find high long-term persistence: the spread in expected net-of-fee future returns between top and bottom quartile PE firms is 7-8 percentage points annually. This spread is estimated controlling for spurious persistence, which arises mechanically from the overlap of contemporaneous funds. Performance is noisy, however, making it difficult for investors to identify the PE funds with top quartile expected future performance and leaving little investable persistence. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Korteweg, Arthur; Sorensen, Morten</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock liquidity and default risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brogaard, Jonathan; Li, Dan; Xia, Ying
This paper examines the impact of stock liquidity on firm bankruptcy risk. Using the Securities and Exchange Commission decimalization regulation as a shock to stock liquidity, we establish that enhanced liquidity decreases default risk. Stocks with the highest default risk experience the largest improvements. We find two mechanisms through which stock liquidity reduces firm default risk: improving stock price informational efficiency and facilitating corporate governance by blockholders. Of the two mechanisms, the informational efficiency channel has higher explanatory power than the corporate governance channel. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brogaard, Jonathan; Li, Dan; Xia, Ying</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment banking relationships and analyst affiliation bias: The impact of the global settlement on sanctioned and non-sanctioned banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corwin, Shane A.; Larocque, Stephannie A.; Stegemoller, Mike A.
We examine the impact of the Global Settlement on affiliation bias in analyst recommendations. Using a broad measure of investment bank-firm relationships, we find a substantial reduction in analyst affiliation bias following the settlement for sanctioned banks. In contrast, we find strong evidence of bias both before and after the settlement for affiliated analysts at non-sanctioned banks. Our results suggest that the settlement led to an increase in the expected costs of issuing biased coverage at sanctioned banks, while concurrent self-regulatory organization rule changes were largely ineffective at reducing the influence of investment banking on analyst research at large non-sanctioned banks. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Corwin, Shane A.; Larocque, Stephannie A.; Stegemoller, Mike A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt maturity and the liquidity of secondary debt markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruche, Max; Segura, Anatoli
We model the debt maturity choice of firms in the presence of fixed issuance costs in the primary market and search frictions in the secondary market for debt. In the secondary market, short maturities improve the bargaining position of sellers, which reduces the required issuance yield. Long maturities reduce reissuance costs. The optimally chosen maturity trades off both considerations. Equilibrium exhibits inefficiently short maturity choices. An individual firm does not internalize that a longer maturity increases expected gains from trade in the secondary market, which attracts more buyers and, hence, facilitates the sale of debt issued by other firms. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bruche, Max; Segura, Anatoli</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of removing barriers to equity issuance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gustafson, Matthew T.; Iliev, Peter
We study the consequences of a US deregulation allowing small firms to accelerate their public equity issuance. Post-deregulation, affected firms double their reliance on public equity and transition away from private investments in public equity compared to similar untreated firms. The net effect is a 5.7 percentage point or 49% increase in the annual probability of raising equity. This is accompanied by a reduction in equity issuance costs, an increase in investment, and a decrease in leverage. Our findings provide evidence that reducing equity issuance barriers benefits issuers even in highly developed markets. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gustafson, Matthew T.; Iliev, Peter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shades of darkness: A pecking order of trading venues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkveld, Albert J.; Yueshen, Bart Zhou; Zhu, Haoxiang
We characterize the dynamic fragmentation of U.S. equity markets using a unique data set that disaggregates dark transactions by venue types. The "pecking order" hypothesis of trading venues states that investors "sort" various venue types, putting low-cost-low-immediacy venues on top and high-cost-high-immediacy venues at the bottom. Hence, midpoint dark pools on top, non-midpoint dark pools in the middle, and lit markets at the bottom. As predicted, following VIX shocks, macroeconomic news, and firms' earnings surprises, changes in venue market shares become progressively more positive (or less negative) down the pecking order. We further document heterogeneity across dark venue types and stock size groups. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Menkveld, Albert J.; Yueshen, Bart Zhou; Zhu, Haoxiang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do takeover laws matter? Evidence from five decades of hostile takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cain, Matthew D.; McKeon, Stephen B.; Solomon, Steven Davidoff
This study evaluates the relation between hostile takeovers and 17 takeover laws from 1965 to 2014. Using a data set of largely exogenous legal changes, we find that certain takeover laws, such as poison pill and business combination laws, have no discernible impact on hostile activity, while others such as fair price laws have reduced hostile takeovers. We construct a Takeover Index from the laws and find that higher takeover protection is associated with lower firm value, consistent with entrenchment and agency costs. However, conditional on a bid, firms with more protection achieve higher premiums, consistent with increased bargaining power. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cain, Matthew D.; McKeon, Stephen B.; Solomon, Steven Davidoff</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changes in corporate effective tax rates over the past 25 years</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dyreng, Scott D.; Hanlon, Michelle; Maydew, Edward L.; Thornock, Jacob R.
We investigate systematic changes in corporate effective tax rates over the past 25 years and find that effective tax rates have decreased significantly. Contrary to conventional wisdom, the decline in effective tax rates is not concentrated in multinational firms; effective tax rates have declined at approximately the same rate for both multinational and domestic firms. Moreover, within multinational firms, both foreign and domestic effective rates have decreased. Finally, changes in firm characteristics and declining foreign statutory tax rates explain little of the overall decrease in effective rates. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dyreng, Scott D.; Hanlon, Michelle; Maydew, Edward L.; Thornock, Jacob R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board reforms and firm value: Worldwide evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fauver, Larry; Hung, Mingyi; Li, Xi; Taboada, Alvaro G.
We examine the impact of corporate board reforms on firm value in 41 countries. Using a difference-in-differences design, we find that board reforms increase firm value. Reforms involving board and audit committee independence, but not reforms involving separation of chairman and chief executive officer positions, drive the valuation increases. In addition, while comply-or-explain reforms result in a greater increase in firm value than rule-based reforms, the effects of reforms are similar across civil law and common law countries. Further investigation shows that the subsequent change in board independence plays an important role in explaining the effectiveness of the reforms. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fauver, Larry; Hung, Mingyi; Li, Xi; Taboada, Alvaro G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining the negative returns to volatility claims: An equilibrium approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eraker, Bjorn; Wu, Yue
We study the returns to investing in VIX futures, VIX Exchange Traded Notes (ETNs), and variance swaps. We document substantial negative return premia for these assets. For example, the constant maturity portfolio of 1-month VIX futures loses about 30% per year over our sample period (2006-2013). We investigate if these findings are consistent with dynamic equilibrium. We derive a model based on present value computation that endogenizes stock prices, the VIX index, and its associated derivative contracts. The model explains the negative return premia as well as several other stylized features of the VIX futures, ETNs, and variance swap data. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Eraker, Bjorn; Wu, Yue</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO talent, CEO compensation, and product market competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jung, Hae Won; Subramanian, Ajay
We develop a structural industry equilibrium model to show how competitive chief executive officer (CEO)-firm matching and product markets jointly determine firm value and CEO pay. We analytically derive testable implications for the effects of product market characteristics on firm size, CEO pay, and CEO impact on firm value. CEO talent matters more in more competitive markets with greater product substitutabilities. Our CEO impact estimates are much higher than those obtained by previous structural approaches that abstract away from CEO market segmentation. The estimates differ across industries primarily due to variation in product market competition, rather than variation in the CEO talent distribution. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jung, Hae Won; Subramanian, Ajay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous intermediation in over-the-counter markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Babus, Ana; Hu, Tai-Wei
We provide a theory of trading through intermediaries in over-the-counter markets. The role of intermediaries is to sustain trade. In our model, traders are connected through an informational network. Agents observe their neighbors' actions and can trade with their counterparty in a given period through a path of intermediaries in the network. Nevertheless, agents can renege on their obligations. We show that trading through an informational network is essential to support trade when agents infrequently meet the same counteparty. However, intermediaries must receive fees to implement trades. Concentrated intermediation, as represented by a star network, is both constrained efficient and stable when agents incur linking costs. The center agent in a star can receive higher fees as well. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Babus, Ana; Hu, Tai-Wei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tracing out capital flows: How financially integrated banks respond to natural disasters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cortes, Kristle Romero; Strahan, Philip E.
Multi-market banks reallocate capital when local credit demand increases after natural disasters. Using property damage as an instrument for lending growth, we find credit in unaffected but connected markets declines by a little less than 50 cents per dollar of additional lending in shocked areas. However, banks shield their core markets because most of the decline comes from loans in areas where banks do not own branches. Moreover, banks increase sales of more-liquid loans and they bid up the rate on deposits in the connected markets. These actions help lessen the impact of the demand shock on credit supply. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cortes, Kristle Romero; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The advantages of using excess returns to model the term structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golinski, Adam; Spencer, Peter
We advocate the use of excess returns rather than yields or log prices in analysing the risk neutral dynamics of the term structure. We show that under standard assumptions, excess returns are affine in the risk neutral innovations in the factors. This framework has several important advantages. First, it allows for an easy estimation of models that are more flexible than the AR(1). Indeed, we estimate models with more general dynamics, like ARFIMA(p, d, q), almost as easily as AR(1). Second, within our framework the dimension of the unrestricted model is the same for the AR(1) as it is for the richer models, and does not expand in line with the state vector as it does in a yield or log price framework. This makes it appropriate to test all of these risk neutral dynamic specifications against the same OLS unrestricted alternative. Our results for the US Treasury bond market show that the unrestricted model is preferred to the AR(1) by the Bayesian Information Criterion, but the opposite conclusion is reached for more flexible models. A final advantage of the excess returns framework is that the pricing errors are much lower than for the equivalent log price system. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Golinski, Adam; Spencer, Peter</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do measures of real-time corporate sales say about earnings surprises and post-announcement returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Froot, Kenneth; Kang, Namho; Ozik, Gideon; Sadka, Ronnie
We develop real-time proxies of retail corporate sales from multiple sources, including similar to 50 million mobile devices. These measures contain information from both the earnings quarter ("within quarter") and the period between the quarter-end and the earnings announcement date ("post quarter"). Our within-quarter measure is powerful in explaining quarterly sales growth, revenue surprises, and earnings surprises, generating average excess announcement returns of 3.4%. However, our post-quarter measure is related negatively to announcement returns and positively to post-announcement returns. When post-quarter private information is positive, managers, at announcement, provide pessimistic guidance and use negative language. This effect is more pronounced when, post-announcement, management insiders trade. We conclude that managers do not fully disclose their private information and instead bias their disclosures down when in possession of positive private information. The data suggest that they could be motivated in part by subsequent personal stock-trading opportunities. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Froot, Kenneth; Kang, Namho; Ozik, Gideon; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The bright side of financial derivatives: Options trading and firm innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blanco, Ivan; Wehrheim, David
Do financial derivatives enhance or impede innovation? We answer this question by examining the relationship between equity options markets and standard measures of firm innovation. We find that firms with more options trading activity generate more patents and patent citations per dollar invested in research and development (R&amp;D), after accounting for other confounding factors. These results are confirmed when we use a propensity score matching procedure and an instrumental variable approach to control for the potential endogeneity of options trading. The evidence is consistent with the notion that the enhanced informational efficiency induced by options leads to an improved allocation of corporate resources. We further discuss possible underlying economic mechanisms through which more active options markets boost innovation and show that the effect remains substantial even after controlling for these mechanisms. Considering the average increase in the dollar volume of options traded for our sample firms, we conclude that a 200% move in options volume increases firm innovation by about 31%. 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blanco, Ivan; Wehrheim, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information networks: Evidence from illegal insider trading tips</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahern, Kenneth R.
This paper exploits a novel hand-collected data set to provide a comprehensive analysis of the social relationships that underlie illegal insider trading networks. I find that inside information flows through strong social ties based on family, friends, and geographic proximity. On average, inside tips originate from corporate executives and reach buy-side investors after three links in the network. Inside traders earn prodigious returns of 35% over 21 days, with more central traders earning greater returns, as information conveyed through social networks improves price efficiency. More broadly, this paper provides some of the only direct evidence of person-to-person communication among investors. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahern, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking integration and house price co-movement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Landier, Augustin; Sraer, David; Thesmar, David
The correlation in house price growth across US states increased steadily between 1976 and 2000. This paper shows that the contemporaneous geographic integration of the US banking market, via the emergence of large banks, was a primary driver of this phenomenon. To this end, we first theoretically derive an appropriate measure of banking integration across state pairs and show that house price growth correlation is strongly related to this measure of financial integration. Our instrumental variable estimates suggest that banking integration can explain up to one-fourth of the rise in house price correlation over this period. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Landier, Augustin; Sraer, David; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large shareholders and credit ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kedia, Simi; Rajgopal, Shivaram
This paper addresses regulatory concerns that large shareholders of credit rating agencies can influence the rating process. Unlike Standard &amp; Poor's, which is a privately held division of McGraw-Hill, Moody's is a public company listed on the NYSE. From 2001 to 2010, Moody's has two shareholders, Berkshire Hathaway and Davis Selected Advisors, which collectively own about 23.5% of Moody's. Moody's ratings on bonds issued by important investee firms of these two stable large shareholders are more favorable relative to S&amp;P, as well as Fitch, ratings. We exploit Moody's initial public offering in 2000 to address endogeneity and to mitigate concerns that the results are driven by issuer characteristics or by the greater informativeness of Moody's ratings. S&amp;P's parent, McGraw-Hill, has a large shareholder for much less time, and some weak evidence exists that S&amp;P ratings are relatively more favorable toward the owners of McGraw-Hill. These findings are consistent with regulatory concerns about the ownership and governance of rating agencies, especially those that are publicly listed. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kedia, Simi; Rajgopal, Shivaram</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It pays to write well</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun; Kim, Hugh Hoikwang
We quantify the effects of easy-to-read disclosure documents on firm value by analyzing shareholder reports of closed-end investment companies in which the company's value can be estimated separately from the value of the company's underlying assets. Using a copy-editing software application that counts the pervasiveness of the most important 'writing faults' that make a document harder to read, our analysis provides evidence that issuing financial disclosure documents with low readability causes firms to trade at significant discounts relative to the value of their fundamentals. Our estimates suggest that a one-standard-deviation decrease in readability decreases firm value by a full 2.5%. In situations in which investors are more likely to rely on annual reports, the readability effect on firm value increases to 3.3%. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun; Kim, Hugh Hoikwang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncovering expected returns: Information in analyst coverage proxies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Charles M. C.; So, Eric C.
We show that analyst coverage proxies contain information about expected returns. We decompose analyst coverage into abnormal and expected components using a simple characteristic-based model and show that firms with abnormally high analyst coverage subsequently outperform firms with abnormally low coverage by approximately 80 basis points per month. We also show abnormal coverage rises following exogenous shocks to underpricing and predicts improvements in firms' fundamental performance, suggesting that return predictability stems from analysts more heavily covering underpriced stocks. Our findings highlight the usefulness of analysts' actions in expected return estimations, and a potential inference problem when coverage proxies are used to study information asymmetry and dissemination. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Charles M. C.; So, Eric C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of credit spreads, firm fundamentals, and expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Bing; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Zhou, Yi
We explore the link between credit and equity markets by considering the informational content of the term structure of credit spreads. A shallower credit term structure predicts decreases in default risk and increases in future profitability, as well as favorable earnings surprises. Further, the slope of the credit term structure negatively predicts future stock returns. While systematic slope risk is priced, information diffusion from the credit market to equities, particularly in less visible stocks, plays an additional role in accounting for return predictability from credit slopes. That is, such predictability is less evident in stocks with high institutional ownership, analyst coverage, and liquidity, and vice versa. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Han, Bing; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Zhou, Yi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency and stability of a financial architecture with too-interconnected-to-fail institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gofman, Michael
The regulation of large interconnected financial institutions has become a key policy issue. To improve financial stability, regulators have proposed limiting banks' size and interconnectedness. I estimate a network-based model of the over-the-counter interbank lending market in the US and quantify the efficiency-stability implications of this policy. Trading efficiency decreases with limits on interconnectedness because the intermediation chains become longer. While restricting the interconnectedness of banks improves stability, the effect is non-monotonic. Stability also improves with higher liquidity requirements, when banks have access to liquidity during the crisis, and when failed banks' depositors maintain confidence in the banking system. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gofman, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk, ambiguity, and the exercise of employee stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Izhakian, Yehuda; Yermack, David
We investigate the importance of ambiguity, or Knightian uncertainty, in executives' stock option exercise decisions. We develop an empirical estimate of ambiguity and include it in regression models alongside the traditional measure of risk, equity volatility. We show that each variable has a significant effect on the timing of option exercises, with volatility causing executives to hold options longer to preserve option value, and ambiguity increasing the tendency for executives to exercise early. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Izhakian, Yehuda; Yermack, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High frequency trading and the 2008 short-sale ban</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brogaard, Jonathan; Hendershott, Terrence; Riordan, Ryan
We examine the effects of high-frequency traders (HFTs) on liquidity using the September 2008 short sale-ban. To disentangle the separate impacts of short selling by HFTs and non-HFTs, we use an instrumental variables approach exploiting differences in the ban's cross-sectional impact on HFTs and non-HFTs. Non-HFTs' short selling improves liquidity, as measured by bid-ask spreads. HFTs' short selling has the opposite effect by adversely selecting limit orders, which can decrease liquidity supplier competition and reduce trading by non-HFTs. The results highlight that some HFTs' activities are harmful to liquidity during the extremely volatile short-sale ban period. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brogaard, Jonathan; Hendershott, Terrence; Riordan, Ryan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Compensation goals and firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennett, Benjamin; Bettis, J. Carr; Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Milbourn, Todd
Using a large data set of performance goals employed in executive incentive contracts, we find that a disproportionately large number of firms exceed their goals by a small margin as compared to the number that fall short of the goal by a similar margin. This asymmetry is particularly acute for earnings goals, when compensation is contingent on a single goal, when the pay-performance relationship around the goal is concave-shaped, and for grants with non-equity-based payouts. Firms that exceed their compensation target by a small margin are more likely to beat the target the next period and CEOs of firms that miss their targets are more likely to experience a forced turnover. Firms that just exceed their Earnings Per Share (EPS) goals have higher abnormal accruals and lower Research and Development (R&amp;D) expenditures, and firms that just exceed their profit goals have lower Selling, General and Administrative (SG&amp;A) expenditures. Overall, our results highlight some of the costs of linking managerial compensation to specific compensation targets. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bennett, Benjamin; Bettis, J. Carr; Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Milbourn, Todd</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of trading relations in turbulent times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Di Maggio, Marco; Kermani, Amir; Song, Zhaogang
This paper investigates how dealers' trading relations shape their trading behavior in the corporate bond market. Dealers charge lower spreads to dealers with whom they have the strongest ties and more so during periods of market turmoil. Systemically important dealers exploit their connections at the expense of peripheral dealers as well as clients, charging higher markups than to other core dealers. Also, intermediation chains lengthened by 20% following the collapse of a flagship dealer in 2008 and even more for institutions strongly connected to this dealer. Finally, dealers drastically reduced their inventory during the crisis. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Di Maggio, Marco; Kermani, Amir; Song, Zhaogang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dark pool trading strategies, market quality and welfare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butia, Sabrina; Rindi, Barbara; Werner, Ingrid M.
We show that when a continuous dark pool is added to a limit order book that opens illiquid, book and consolidated fill rates and volume increase, but spread widens, depth declines, and welfare deteriorates. The adverse effects on market quality and welfare are mitigated when book-liquidity builds but so are the positive effects on trading activity. All effects are stronger when traders' valuations are less dispersed, access to the dark pool is greater, horizon is longer, and relative tick size larger. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Butia, Sabrina; Rindi, Barbara; Werner, Ingrid M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial dependence and innovation: The case of public versus private firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral; Xu, Zhaoxia
In this paper, we examine the relation between innovation and a firm's financial dependence using a sample of privately held and publicly traded US firms. We find that public firms in external finance dependent industries spend more on research and development and generate a better patent portfolio than their private counterparts. However, public firms in internal finance dependent industries do not have a better innovation profile than private firms. The results are robust to various empirical strategies that address selection bias. The findings indicate that the influence of public listing on innovation depends on the need for external capital. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral; Xu, Zhaoxia</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do exogenous changes in passive institutional ownership affect corporate governance and firm value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmidt, Cornelius; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger
We investigate whether corporations and their executives react to an exogenous change in passive institutional ownership and alter their corporate governance structure. We find that exogenous increases in passive ownership lead to increases in CEO power and fewer new independent director appointments. Consistent with these changes not being beneficial for shareholders, we observe negative announcement returns to the appointments of new independent directors. We also show that firms carry out worse mergers and acquisitions after exogenous increases in passive ownership. These results suggest that the changed ownership structure causes higher agency costs. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schmidt, Cornelius; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Socioeconomic status and learning from financial information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuhnen, Camelia M.; Miu, Andrei C.
The majority of lower socioeconomic status (SES) households in the U.S. and Europe do not have stock investments, which is detrimental to wealth accumulation. Here, we examine one explanation for this puzzling fact, namely, that economic adversity may influence how people learn from financial information. Using experimental and survey data from the U.S. and Romania, we find that lower SES individuals form more pessimistic beliefs about the distribution of stock returns and. are less likely to invest in stocks when these investments are likely to have good outcomes. SES-related differences in pessimism may help explain variation in investments across households. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kuhnen, Camelia M.; Miu, Andrei C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit default swaps, exacting creditors and corporate liquidity management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Tang, Dragon Yongjun; Wang, Sarah Qian
We investigate the liquidity management of firms following the inception of credit default swaps (CDS) markets on their debt, which allow hedging and speculative trading on credit risk to be carried out by creditors and other parties. We find that reference firms hold more cash after CDS trading commences on their debt. The increase in cash holdings is more pronounced for CDS firms that do not pay dividends and have a higher marginal value of liquidity. For CDS firms with higher cash flow volatility, these increased cash holdings do not entail higher leverage. Overall, our findings are consistent with the view that CDS-referenced firms adopt more conservative liquidity policies to avoid negotiations with more exacting creditors. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Tang, Dragon Yongjun; Wang, Sarah Qian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variance risk premiums and the forward premium puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Londono, Juan M.; Zhou, Hao
We provide new empirical evidence that world currency and U.S. stock variance risk premiums have nonredundant and significant predictive power for the appreciation rates of 22 with respect to the U.S. dollar, especially at the four-month and one-month horizons, respectively. The heterogeneous exposures of currencies to the currency variance risk premium are systematically rising along the line of inflation risk. We rationalize these findings in a consumption-based asset pricing model, with local consumption uncertainty and global inflation uncertainty characterized, respectively, by the stock and currency variance risk premiums. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Londono, Juan M.; Zhou, Hao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revolving doors on Wall Street</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornaggia, Jess; Cornaggia, Kimberly J.; Xia, Han
Credit analysts often leave rating agencies to work at firms they rate. We use benchmark rating agencies as counterfactuals to measure rating inflation in a difference-in-differences framework and find that transitioning analysts award inflated ratings to their future employers before switching jobs. We find no evidence that analysts inflate ratings of other firms they rate. Market based measures of hiring firms' credit quality further indicate that transitioning analysts' inflated ratings become less informative. We conclude that conflicts of interest at the analyst level distort credit ratings. More broadly, our results shed light on the economic consequences of revolving doors. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cornaggia, Jess; Cornaggia, Kimberly J.; Xia, Han</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sentiments, financial markets, and macroeconomic fluctuations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benhabib, Jess; Liu, Xuewen; Wang, Pengfei
This paper studies how financial information frictions can generate sentiment-driven fluctuations in asset prices and self-fulfilling business cycles. In our model economy, exuberant financial market sentiments of high output and high demand for capital increase the price of capital, which signals strong fundamentals of the economy to the real side and consequently leads to an actual boom in real output and employment. The model further derives implications for asymmetric nonlinear asset prices and for economic contagion and co-movement across countries. In the extension to the dynamic overlapping generations (OLG) setting, our model demonstrates that sentiment shocks can generate persistent output, employment, and business cycle fluctuations, and it offers some new implications for asset prices over business cycles. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benhabib, Jess; Liu, Xuewen; Wang, Pengfei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing volatility risk and risk premium in option contracts: A new theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren
We develop a new option pricing framework that tightly integrates with how institutional investors manage options positions. The framework starts with the near-term dynamics of the implied volatility surface and derives no-arbitrage constraints on its current shape. Within this framework, we show that just like option implied volatilities, realized and expected volatilities can also be constructed specific to, and different across, option contracts. Applying the new theory to the S&amp;P 500 index time series and options data, we extract volatility risk and risk premium from the volatility surfaces, and find that the extracted risk premium significantly predicts future stock returns. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discerning information from trade data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; de Prado, Marcos Lopez; O'Hara, Maureen
How best to discern trading intentions from market data? We examine the accuracy of three methods for classifying trade data: bulk volume classification (BVC), tick rule and aggregated tick rule. We develop a Bayesian model of inferring information from trade executions and "show the conditions under which tick rules or bulk volume classification predominates. Empirically, we find that tick rule approaches and BVC are relatively good classifiers of the aggressor side of trading, but bulk volume classifications are better linked to proxies of information-based trading. Thus, BVC would appear to be a useful tool for discerning trading intentions from market data. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Easley, David; de Prado, Marcos Lopez; O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rethinking reversals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Timothy C.
High-frequency reversals are an economically important characteristic of the returns to tradeable claims to the market portfolio. This paper demonstrates that short-horizon negative autocorrelation can arise in a tractable model of agents with tournament-type preferences. Intuitively, investors act as if they are averse to missing out on a trend, causing the risk premium to move strongly counter to realized returns. The model features fully rationalizing agents, complete markets, and no exogenous transaction demand. Plausible parameterizations can match the autocorrelation in the data. Supporting evidence on novel first and second moment implications is presented. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Johnson, Timothy C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local financial capacity and asset values: Evidence from bank failures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajan, Raghuram; Ramcharan, Rodney
Using differences in regulation as a means of identification, we find that a reduction in local financial intermediation capacity reduces the recovery rates on assets of failing banks. It also depresses local land prices and is associated with subsequent distress in nearby banks. Fire sales appear to be one channel through which lower local intermediation capacity reduces the recovery rates on failed banks' assets. The paper provides a rationale for why bank failures are contagious, and why the value of specialized financial assets could depend on the size of the intermediary market that is available to buy it. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rajan, Raghuram; Ramcharan, Rodney</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder nonparticipation in valuable rights offerings: New findings for an old puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holderness, Clifford G.; Pontiff, Jeffrey
Shareholder participation in valuable domestic rights offerings averages only 64%, which is considerably lower than previously asserted. This causes wealth transfers from nonparticipating to participating shareholders that average 7% of the offering. Wealth transfers are larger in nontransferable and bigger offerings. The stock market reacts more negatively to larger wealth transfers. Offerings with lower shareholder participation also fall short in raising publicly stated capital goals. Rights offerings are far more common in countries with institutional practices that limit nonparticipating shareholders' wealth losses. These findings suggest that agency conflicts influence the use of rights offers. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Holderness, Clifford G.; Pontiff, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adverse selection, slow-moving capital, and misallocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuchs, William; Green, Brett; Papanikolaou, Dimitris
We embed adverse selection into a dynamic, general equilibrium model with heterogeneous capital and study its implications for aggregate dynamics. The friction leads to delays in firms' divestment decisions and thus slow recoveries from shocks, even when these shocks do not affect the economy's potential output. The impediments to reallocation increase with the dispersion in productivity and decrease with the interest rate, the frequency of sectoral shocks, and households' consumption smoothing motives. When households are risk averse, delaying reallocation serves as a hedge against future shocks, which can lead to persistent misallocation. Our model also provides a micro-foundation for convex adjustment costs and a link between the nature of these costs and the underlying economic environment. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fuchs, William; Green, Brett; Papanikolaou, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset allocation and monetary policy: Evidence from the eurozone</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hau, Harald; Lai, Sandy
The eurozone has a single short-term nominal interest rate, but monetary policy conditions measured by real short-term interest rates varied substantially across countries in the period 2003-2010. We use this cross-country variation in the (local) tightness of monetary policy to examine its influence on equity and money market flows. In line with a powerful risk-shifting channel, we find that fund investors in countries with decreased real interest rates shift their portfolio investment out of the money market and into the riskier equity market, causing significant equity price inflation in countries where investment home bias is the strongest. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hau, Harald; Lai, Sandy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-to-produce, inventory, and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhanhui
Time-to-build, time-to-produce, and inventory have important implications for asset prices and quantity dynamics in a general equilibrium model with recursive preferences. Time to -build captures the delay in transforming new investments into productive capital, and time-to-produce captures the delay in transforming productive capital into output. Both delays increase risks in that time-to-build generates procyclical payouts, whereas the time to -produce amplifies this procyclicality. Inventory smooths consumption and helps capture interest rate volatility even when the elasticity of intertemporal substitution is small. The model is consistent with a high equity premium, a high stock return volatility, and lead-lag relations between asset prices and macroeconomic quantities. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Zhanhui</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the geographic expansion of banks reduce risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goetz, Martin R.; Laeven, Luc; Levine, Ross
We develop a new identification strategy to evaluate the impact of the geographic expansion of a bank holding company (BHC) across US metropolitan statistical areas (MSAs) on BHC risk. For the average BHC, the instrumental variable results suggest that geographic expansion materially reduces risk. Geographic diversification does not affect loan quality. The results are consistent with arguments that geographic expansion lowers risk by reducing exposure to idiosyncratic local risks and inconsistent with arguments that expansion, on net, increases risk by reducing the ability of BHCs to monitor loans and manage risks. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goetz, Martin R.; Laeven, Luc; Levine, Ross</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy law and bank financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rodano, Giacomo; Serrano-Velarde, Nicolas; Tarantino, Emanuele
Exploiting the timing of the 2005-2006 Italian bankruptcy law reforms, we disentangle the effects of reorganization and liquidation in bankruptcy on bank financing and firm investment. A 2005 reform introduces reorganization procedures facilitating loan renegotiation. The 2006 reform subsequently strengthens creditor rights in liquidation. The first reform increases interest rates and reduces investment. The second reform reduces interest rates and spurs investment. Our results highlight the importance of identifying the distinct effects of liquidation and reorganization, as these procedures differently address the tension in bankruptcy law between the continuation of viable businesses and the preservation of repayment incentives. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Rodano, Giacomo; Serrano-Velarde, Nicolas; Tarantino, Emanuele</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underwriter deal pipeline and the pricing of IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boeh, Kevin K.; Dunbar, Craig
This study examines how initial public offering (IPO) pricing is affected by the pipeline of deals in registration, measured at the underwriter level. Examining IPOs from 2002 to 2013, we find evidence that measures of the IPO bookrunner's pipeline significantly affect pricing decisions. The evidence is mostly consistent with market power and agency theories, which argue that underwriters use a young or growing pipeline to push for higher IPO first day returns. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boeh, Kevin K.; Dunbar, Craig</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility risk premia and exchange rate predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Della Corte, Pasquale; Ramadorai, Tarun; Sarno, Lucio
We discover a new currency strategy with highly desirable return and diversification properties, which uses the predictive ability of currency volatility risk premia for currency returns. The volatility risk premium the difference between expected realized volatility and model-free implied volatility reflects the costs of insuring against currency volatility fluctuations. The strategy sells high insurance-cost currencies and buys low insurance-cost currencies. A distinctive feature of the strategy's returns is that they are mainly generated by movements in spot exchange rates instead of interest rate differentials. We explore explanations for the profitability of the strategy, which cannot be understood using traditional risk factors. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Della Corte, Pasquale; Ramadorai, Tarun; Sarno, Lucio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Redacting proprietary information at the initial public offering</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boone, Audra L.; Floros, Loannis V.; Johnson, Shane A.
Nearly 40% of IPO firms redact information from their SEC registration filings. These firms exhibit characteristics consistent with the need to shield proprietary information from potential rivals. They experience greater underpricing, but pre-IPO insiders reduce underpricing-related wealth transfers by selling proportionately less of the firm's shares at the IPO, raising more equity financing in later seasoned equity offerings, and selling their own holdings at a relatively slow pace. The information environment of redacting firms reflects proportionately more private information than that of non-redacting firms post-IPO, but this difference abates by the fourth year. Consistent with the view that redacted proprietary information provides competitive advantages, redacting firms exhibit superior financial performance post-IPO. The results illustrate tradeoffs in balancing a firm's needs to protect proprietary information with its capital needs, investor needs for information to price securities, and pre-IPO owner liquidity needs. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Boone, Audra L.; Floros, Loannis V.; Johnson, Shane A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The expected returns and valuations of private and public firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Ilan; Priestley, Richard
Characteristics play a similar role in describing returns in private firms as in public firms. This evidence suggests a causal effect of optimal investment underlying the role of characteristics, as private firms do not have stock prices to over-or under-react on. Common factor models largely describe the cross section of investment returns of both types of firms, suggesting that the common factors are likely aggregate risk factors. Finally, the cost of capital and firm valuations are similar across private and public firms. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cooper, Ilan; Priestley, Richard</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dual ownership, returns, and voting in mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Rossi, Marco
In Mergers and Acquisitions (M&amp;As) a significant proportion of targets' equity is owned by financial institutions that simultaneously own targets' bonds ("dual holders"). Targets with larger equity ownership by dual holders have lower M&amp;A equity premia and larger abnormal bond returns, particularly when dual holders stand to benefit more from appreciation of their bond stakes, e.g., when their bond ownership in the target is large and the target credit rating is non-investment grade. Dual holders are more likely to vote in favor of the merger proposal. Our results suggest the presence of coordination of decisions within dual holding financial conglomerates in M&amp;A targets. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Rossi, Marco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spare tire? Stock markets, banking crises, and economic recoveries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levine, Ross; Lin, Chen; Xie, Wensi
Do stock markets act as a spare tire during banking crises, providing an alternative corporate financing channel and mitigating the economic severity of these crises? Using firm level data in 36 countries from 1990 through 2011, we find that the adverse consequences of banking crises on equity issuances, firm profitability, employment, and investment efficiency are smaller in countries with stronger shareholder protection laws. These findings are not explained by the development of stock markets or financial institutions prior to the crises, the severity of the banking crisis, or overall economic, legal, and institutional development. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Levine, Ross; Lin, Chen; Xie, Wensi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On secondary buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degeorge, Francois; Martin, Jens; Phalippou, Ludovic
Private equity firms increasingly sell companies to each other in secondary buyouts (SBOs), raising concerns which we examine using novel data sets. Our evidence paints a nuanced picture. SBOs underperform and destroy value for investors when they are made by buyers under pressure to spend. Investors then reduce their capital allocation to the firms doing those transactions. But not all SBOs are money-burning devices. SBOs made under no pressure to spend perform as well as other buyouts. When buyer and seller have complementary skill sets, SBOs outperform other buyouts. Investors do not pay higher total transaction costs as a result of SBOs, even if they have a stake in both the buying fund and the selling fund. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Degeorge, Francois; Martin, Jens; Phalippou, Ludovic</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are retail traders compensated for providing liquidity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barrot, Jean-Noel; Kaniel, Ron; Sraer, David
This paper examines the extent to which individual investors provide liquidity to the stock market and whether they are compensated for doing so. We show that the ability of aggregate retail order imbalances, contrarian in nature, to predict short-term future returns is significantly enhanced during times of market stress, when market liquidity provisions decline. While a weekly rebalanced portfolio long in stocks purchased and short in stocks sold by retail investors delivers 19% annualized excess returns over a four-factor model from 2002 to 2010, it delivers up to 40% annualized returns in periods of high uncertainty. Despite this high aggregate performance, individual investors do not reap the rewards from liquidity provision because they experience a negative return on the day of their trade and they reverse their trades long after the excess returns from liquidity provision are dissipated. During the financial crisis, French active retail stock traders stepped up to the plate, increased stock holdings, and provided liquidity. In contrast, mutual fund investors fled from delegation by selling their mutual funds. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barrot, Jean-Noel; Kaniel, Ron; Sraer, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using options to measure the full value-effect of an event: Application to Obamacare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borochin, Paul; Golec, Joseph
Many event studies only measure a fraction of an event's full value effect because they do not adjust for market anticipation of the event. We present a method based on stock and options prices to measure the full effect that accounts for market anticipation. We apply the method to the passage of Obamacare. Our method estimates the full value effect of Obamacare on the healthcare sector as $55 billion, compared to $16 billion when market anticipation is ignored. The method is applicable to most major events because it only requires that some affected firms have traded stock options. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Borochin, Paul; Golec, Joseph</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO overconfidence and financial crisis: Evidence from bank lending and leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ho, Po-Hsin; Huang, Chia-Wei; Lin, Chih-Yung; Yen, Ju-Fang
Over a period that includes the 1998 Russian crisis and 2007-2009 financial crisis, banks with overconfident chief executive officers (CEOs) were more likely to weaken lending standards and increase leverage than other banks in advance of a crisis, making them more vulnerable to the shock of the crisis. During crisis years, they generally experienced more increases in loan defaults, greater drops in operating and stock return performance, greater increases in expected default probability, and higher likelihood of CEO turnover or failure than other banks. CEO overconfidence thus can explain the cross-sectional heterogeneity in risk-taking behavior among banks. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ho, Po-Hsin; Huang, Chia-Wei; Lin, Chih-Yung; Yen, Ju-Fang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of creditor control in corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldhutter, Peter; Hotchkiss, Edith; Karakas, Oguzhan
This paper introduces a measure that captures the premium in bond prices that is due to the value of creditor control. We estimate the premium as the difference in the bond price and an equivalent synthetic bond without control rights that is constructed using credit default swap (CDS) contracts. We find empirically that this premium increases as firm credit quality decreases and around important credit events such as defaults, bankruptcies, and covenant violations. The increase is greatest for bonds most pivotal to changes in control. Changes in bond and CDS liquidity do not appear to drive increases in the premium. (c) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Feldhutter, Peter; Hotchkiss, Edith; Karakas, Oguzhan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accruals, cash flows, and operating profitability in the cross section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ball, Ray; Gerakos, Joseph; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Nikolaev, Valeri
Accruals are the non-cash component of earnings. They represent adjustments made to cash flows to generate a profit measure largely unaffected by the timing of receipts and payments of cash. Prior research uncovers two anomalies: expected returns increase in profitability and decrease in accruals. We show that cash-based operating profitability (a measure that excludes accruals) outperforms measures of profitability that include accruals. Further, cash-based operating profitability subsumes accruals in predicting the cross section of average returns. An investor can increase a strategy's Sharpe ratio more by adding just a cash-based operating profitability factor to the investment opportunity set than by adding both an accruals factor and a profitability factor that includes accruals. (c) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ball, Ray; Gerakos, Joseph; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Nikolaev, Valeri</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short interest and aggregate stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rapach, David E.; Ringgenberg, Matthew C.; Zhou, Guofu
We show that short interest is arguably the strongest known predictor of aggregate stock returns. It outperforms a host of popular return predictors both in and out of sample, with annual R-2 statistics of 12.89% and 13.24%, respectively. In addition, short interest can generate utility gains of over 300 basis points per annum for a mean-variance investor. A vector autoregression decomposition shows that the economic source of short interest's predictive power stems predominantly from a cash flow channel. Overall, our evidence indicates that short sellers are informed traders who are able to anticipate future aggregate cash flows and associated market returns. (c) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rapach, David E.; Ringgenberg, Matthew C.; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Under new management: Equity issues and the attribution of past returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Malcolm; Xuan, Yuhai
There is a strong link between measures of stock market performance and subsequent equity issues. We find that management turnover weakens the link between equity issues and the returns that preceded the new chief executive officer (CEO). Moreover, there is a discontinuity in the distribution of equity issues around the specific share price that the CEO inherited, while there is no discontinuity around salient share prices prior to turnover. The evidence suggests that capital allocation involves an attribution of past returns not only to the firm but also to its CEO. A corollary is that a firm with poor stock market performance may be better able to raise new capital if its current CEO is replaced. (c) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baker, Malcolm; Xuan, Yuhai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity, resiliency and market quality around predictable trades: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Carrion, Allen; Tuttle, Laura; Venkataraman, Kumar
We extend the theory of strategic trading around a predictable liquidation by considering the role of market resiliency. Our model predicts that even a monopolist strategic trader improves market quality and increases liquidator proceeds if trades' temporary price impacts are quickly reversed, and that competition among strategic traders strictly improves market quality. We provide related empirical evidence by studying prices, liquidity, and individual account trading activity around the large and predictable "roll" trades undertaken by a large exchange-traded fund (ETF). The evidence indicates narrower bid-ask spreads, greater order book depth, and improved resiliency on roll dates. We find that a larger number of individual trading accounts provide liquidity on roll dates, and do not find evidence of the systematic use of predatory strategies. On balance, the theory and evidence imply that traders supply liquidity to rather than exploit predictable trades in resilient markets. (c) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Carrion, Allen; Tuttle, Laura; Venkataraman, Kumar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Have we solved the idiosyncratic volatility puzzle?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hou, Kewei; Loh, Roger K.
We propose a simple methodology to evaluate a large number of potential explanations for the negative relation between idiosyncratic volatility and subsequent stock returns (the idiosyncratic volatility puzzle). Surprisingly, we find that many existing explanations explain less than 10% of the puzzle. On the other hand, explanations based on investors' lottery preferences and market frictions show some promise in explaining the puzzle. Together, all existing explanations account for 29-54% of the puzzle in individual stocks and 78-84% of the puzzle in idiosyncratic volatility-sorted portfolios. Our methodology can be applied to evaluate competing explanations for other asset pricing anomalies. (c) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hou, Kewei; Loh, Roger K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How costly is corporate bankruptcy for the CEO?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckbo, B. Espen; Thorburn, Karin S.; Wang, Wei
We examine chief executive officer (CEO) career and compensation changes for large firms filing for Chapter 11. One-third of the incumbent CEOs maintain executive employment, and these CEOs experience a median compensation change of zero. However, incumbent CEOs leaving the executive labor market suffer a compensation loss with a median present value until age 65 of $7 million (five times pre-departure compensation). The likelihood of leaving decreases with profitability and CEO share ownership. Furthermore, creditor control rights during bankruptcy (through debtor-in-possession financing and large trade credits) are associated with CEO career change. Despite large equity losses (median $11 million for incumbents who stay until filing), the median incumbent does not reduce his stock ownership as the firm approaches bankruptcy. (c) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eckbo, B. Espen; Thorburn, Karin S.; Wang, Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does rating analyst subjectivity affect corporate debt pricing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fracassi, Cesare; Petry, Stefan; Tate, Geoffrey
We find evidence of systematic optimism and pessimism among credit analysts, comparing contemporaneous ratings of the same firm across rating agencies. These differences in perspectives carry through to debt prices and negatively predict future changes in credit spreads, consistent with mispricing. Moreover, the pricing effects are the largest among firms that are the most opaque, likely exacerbating financing constraints. We find that masters of business administration (MBAs) provide higher quality ratings. However, optimism increases and accuracy decreases with tenure covering the firm. Our analysis demonstrates the role analysts play in shaping investor expectations and its effect on corporate debt markets. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fracassi, Cesare; Petry, Stefan; Tate, Geoffrey</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Roughing up beta: Continuous versus discontinuous betas and the cross section of expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollerslev, Tim; Li, Sophia Zhengzi; Todorov, Viktor
We investigate how individual equity prices respond to continuous and jumpy market price moves and how these different market price risks, or betas, are priced in the cross section of expected stock returns. Based on a novel high-frequency data set of almost 1,000 stocks over two decades, we find that the two rough betas associated with intraday discontinuous and overnight returns entail significant risk premiums, while the intraday continuous beta does not. These higher risk premiums for the discontinuous and overnight market betas remain significant after controlling for a long list of other firm characteristics and explanatory variables. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bollerslev, Tim; Li, Sophia Zhengzi; Todorov, Viktor</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of a good credit reputation: Evidence from credit card renegotiations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liberman, Andres
I exploit a natural experiment to estimate borrowers' willingness to pay for a good credit reputation. A lender in Chile offered lower installments to borrowers who were in default. Those who owed more than a fixed arbitrary cutoff were additionally offered a clean public repayment record. Using the cutoff in a fuzzy regression discontinuity design, I show that borrowers are willing to pay the equivalent of 11% of their monthly income for a good reputation. Borrowers use their reputation to take on more debt with other banks, but default more. Thus, renegotiations may impose informational externalities on other lenders. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liberman, Andres</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms use high discount rates?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, Ravi; Matsa, David A.; Meier, Iwan; Tarhan, Vefa
We present evidence consistent with operational constraints leading firms to use high discount rates that average twice the firms' cost of financial capital. Based on a survey of Chief Financial Officers matched to archival data, we find that firms with abundant access to capital but limited qualified management or manpower appear to forgo profitable projects in preparation for more profitable future investment opportunities. Consistent with this explanation, firms that use high discount rates have strong balance sheets, low leverage, and large cash holdings. In addition, firms appear to increase discount rates to account for idiosyncratic risk. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jagannathan, Ravi; Matsa, David A.; Meier, Iwan; Tarhan, Vefa</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The leverage externalities of credit default swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Jay Yin; Tang, Dragon Yongjun
This paper provides the first empirical evidence of the externalities of credit default swaps (CDS). We find that a firm's leverage is lower when a larger proportion of its revenue is derived from CDS-referenced customers. This finding is robust to alternative samples and measures, placebo tests, and the selection of customers by suppliers. Moreover, firms affected by customer CDS trading issue equity to lower leverage, and their equity issuance costs are lower. These findings are consistent with the view that CDS trading on customers improves the information environment for suppliers. Therefore, while many firms are not directly linked to CDS trading, CDS trading on their customers has spillover effects on these firms' financial policies. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Jay Yin; Tang, Dragon Yongjun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indexing and and active fund management: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, Martijn; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro; Starks, Laura
We examine the relation between indexing and active management in the mutual fund industry worldwide. Explicit indexing and closet indexing by active funds are associated with countries' regulatory and financial market environments. We find that actively managed funds are more active and charge lower fees when they face more competitive pressure from low-cost explicitly indexed funds. A quasi-natural experiment using the exogenous variation in indexed funds generated by the passage of pension laws supports a causal interpretation of the results. Moreover, the average alpha generated by active management is higher in countries with more explicit indexing and lower in countries with more closet indexing. Overall, our evidence suggests that explicit indexing improves competition in the mutual fund industry. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cremers, Martijn; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro; Starks, Laura</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The commitment problem of secured lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fabbri, Daniela; Menichini, Anna Maria C.
The paper presents a new theory of trade credit in which firms buy inputs on credit from suppliers to restore the benefits of secured bank financing impaired by contract incompleteness. In a setting where investment is endogenous and unobservable to financiers, we show that a bank-secured credit contract is time-inconsistent. Upon being granted credit, the entrepreneur has an incentive to alter the original input combination, jeopardizing the bank's revenues. Anticipating the entrepreneur's opportunism, the bank offers an unsecured credit contract, reducing the surplus from the venture. One way for the entrepreneur to commit to the contract terms is to purchase inputs on credit from the supplier. The supplier observes the input investment and acts as a guarantor that inputs will be purchased as contracted, thus facilitating access to secured bank financing. The commitment role of trade credit still holds in a multi-period extension that investigates the impact of bank relationship lending on secured debt and trade credit. Our model provides novel testable predictions on optimal financial contracts in both one-period and repeated lending relationships. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Fabbri, Daniela; Menichini, Anna Maria C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes and bank capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schepens, Glenn
This paper shows that a reduction in tax discrimination between debt and equity funding leads to better capitalized financial institutions. The paper exploits exogenous variation in the tax treatment of debt and equity created by the introduction of a tax shield for equity. The results demonstrate that a more equal treatment of debt and equity increases bank capital ratios, driven by an increase in common equity. The change also leads to a significant reduction in risk taking for ex-ante low capitalized banks. Overall, the findings suggest that tax shields could be a valuable and innovative policy tool for bank regulators. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schepens, Glenn</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why does the option to stock volume ratio predict stock returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ge, Li; Lin, Tse-Chun; Pearson, Neil D.
We use data on signed option volume to study which components of option volume predict stock returns and resolve the seemingly inconsistent results in the literature. We find no evidence that trades related to synthetic short positions in the underlying stocks contain more information than trades related to synthetic long positions. Purchases of calls that open new positions are the strongest predictor of returns, followed by call sales that close out existing purchased call positions. Overall, our results indicate that the role of options in providing embedded leverage is the most important channel why option trading predicts stock returns. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ge, Li; Lin, Tse-Chun; Pearson, Neil D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The causal effect of option pay on corporate risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakke, Tor-Erik; Mahmudi, Hamed; Fernando, Chitru S.; Salas, Jesus M.
This study provides strong evidence of a causal effect of risk-taking incentives provided by option compensation on corporate risk management. We utilize the passage of Financial Accounting Standard (FAS) 123R, which required firms to expense options, to investigate how chief executive officer option compensation affects the hedging behavior of oil and gas firms. Firms that did not expense options before FAS 123R significantly reduced option pay, which resulted in a large increase in their hedging intensity compared with firms that did not use options or expensed their options voluntarily prior to FAS 123R. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bakke, Tor-Erik; Mahmudi, Hamed; Fernando, Chitru S.; Salas, Jesus M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The expected cost of default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glover, Brent
The sample of observed defaults significantly understates the average firm's true expected cost of default due to a sample selection bias. I use a dynamic capital structure model to estimate firm-specific expected default costs and quantify the selection bias. The average firm expects to lose 45% of firm value in default, a cost higher than existing estimates. However, the average cost among defaulted firms in the estimated model is only 25%, a value consistent with existing empirical estimates from observed defaults. This substantial selection bias helps to reconcile the levels of leverage and default costs observed in the data. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Glover, Brent</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross-sectional variation of volatility risk premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gonzalez-Urteaga, Ana; Rubio, Gonzalo
This paper analyzes the determinants of the cross-sectional variation of the average volatility risk premia for a representative set of portfolios sorted by volatility risk premium beta. The market volatility risk premium and, especially, the default premium are shown to be key risk factors in the cross-sectional variation of average volatility risk premium payoffs. The cross-sectional variation of risk premia seems to reflect a very different behavior of the underlying components of our sample portfolios with respect to credit or financial stress that generates a significant dispersion of the volatility swap pricing of these securities. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gonzalez-Urteaga, Ana; Rubio, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product market competition, R&amp;D investment, and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gu, Lifeng
A standard real options model predicts a strong positive interaction effect between research and development (R&amp;D) investment and product market competition. R&amp;D-intensive firms tend to be riskier and earn higher expected returns than R&amp;D-weak firms, particularly in competitive industries. Also, firms in competitiye industries earn higher expected returns than firms in concentrated industries, especially among R&amp;D-intensive firms. Intuitively, R&amp;D projects are more likely to fail in the presence of more competition because rival firms could win the innovation race. Empirical evidence largely supports the model's predictions. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gu, Lifeng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The product market effects of hedge fund activism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aslan, Hadiye; Kumar, Praveen
We examine the product market spillover effects of hedge fund activism (HFA) on the industry rivals of target firms. HFA has negative real and stockholder wealth effects on the average rival firm. The effects on rivals' product market performance is commensurate with post-activism improvements in target's productivity, cost and capital allocation efficiency, and product differentiation. Financially constrained rivals accommodate these improvements but those facing high intervention threat respond effectively to them. The spillover effects are strengthened in less concentrated and low entry barrier industries. The results are robust to the alternative hypothesis of strategic target selection by hedge funds. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aslan, Hadiye; Kumar, Praveen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The influence of political bias in state pension funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, Daniel; Pantzalis, Christos; Yuan, Xiaojing
Using a sample of state pension funds' equity holdings, we find evidence of not only local bias, but also bias towards politically-connected stocks. Political bias is detrimental to fund performance. State pension funds have longer holding durations of politically-connected local firms and display disposition behavior in these positions. Political bias is positively related to the percentage of politically-affiliated trustees on the board and Congressional connections. The more politically-affiliated trustees on the board, the more the fund shifts toward risky asset allocations. Overall, our results imply that political bias is likely costly to taxpayers and pension beneficiaries. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bradley, Daniel; Pantzalis, Christos; Yuan, Xiaojing</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Target revaluation after failed takeover attempts: Cash versus stock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malmendier, Ulrike; Opp, Marcus M.; Saidi, Farzad
Cash- and stock-financed takeover bids induce strikingly different target revaluations. We exploit detailed data on unsuccessful takeover bids between 1980 and 2008, and we show that targets of cash offers are revalued on average by 15% after deal failure, whereas stock targets return to their pre-announcement levels. The differences in revaluation do not revert over longer horizons. We find no evidence that future takeover activities or operational changes explain these differences. While the targets of failed cash and stock offers are both more likely to be acquired over the following eight years than matched control firms, no differences exist between cash and stock targets, either in the timing or in the value of future offers. Similarly, we cannot detect differential operational policies following the failed bid. Our results are most consistent with cash bids revealing prior undervaluation of the target We reconcile our findings with the opposite conclusion in earlier literature (Bradley, Desai, and Kim, 1983) by identifying a look-ahead bias built into their sample construction. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malmendier, Ulrike; Opp, Marcus M.; Saidi, Farzad</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do CEOs see their roles? Management philosophies and styles in family and non-family firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mullins, William; Schoar, Antoinette
Using a survey of 800 Chief Executive Officers (CEOs) in 22 emerging economies, we show that CEOs' management styles and philosophies vary with the ownership and governance structure of their firms. Founders and CEOs of firms with greater family involvement display a greater stakeholder focus, and feel more accountable to employees and banks than to shareholders. They also have a more hierarchical management approach, and see their role as maintaining the status quo rather than bringing about change. In contrast, CEOs of non-family firms emphasize shareholder-value-maximization. Finally, firm-level variation in ownership is as important in explaining management philosophies as cross-country or industry-level differences. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mullins, William; Schoar, Antoinette</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing asset pricing models using revealed preference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berk, Jonathan B.; van Binsbergen, Jules H.
We propose a new method of testing asset pricing models that relies on quantities rather than just prices or returns. We use the capital flows into and out of mutual funds to infer which risk model investors use. We derive a simple test statistic that allows us to infer, from a set of candidate models, the risk model that is closest to the model that investors use in making their capital allocation decisions. Using our method, we assess the performance of the most commonly used asset pricing models in the literature. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berk, Jonathan B.; van Binsbergen, Jules H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quadratic variance swap models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Filipovic, Damir; Gourier, Elise; Mancini, Loriano
We introduce a novel class of term structure models for variance swaps. The multivariate state process is characterized by a quadratic diffusion function. The variance swap curve is quadratic in the state variable and available in closed form, greatly facilitating empirical analysis. Various goodness-of-fit tests show that quadratic models fit variance swaps on the S&amp;P 500 remarkably well, and outperform affine models. We solve a dynamic optimal portfolio problem in variance swaps, index option, stock index and bond. An empirical analysis uncovers robust features of the optimal investment strategy. (C) 2015 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Filipovic, Damir; Gourier, Elise; Mancini, Loriano</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price and volatility co-jumps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bandi, F. M.; Reno, R.
The nature of the dependence between discontinuities in prices and contemporaneous discontinuities in volatility (co-jumps) has been reported by many as being elusive, in terms of sign, magnitude, and statistical significance. Using a novel identification strategy in continuous time relying on trade-level information for spot variance estimation, as well as infinitesimal cross-moments, we document that a sizeable proportion of discontinuous changes in prices are associated with strongly anti-correlated, contemporaneous, discontinuous changes in volatility. Assuming a possibly nonmonotonic pricing kernel, we illustrate the equilibrium implications of price and volatility co-jumps for return and variance risk premia. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bandi, F. M.; Reno, R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating the impact of unconventional monetary policy measures: Empirical evidence from the ECB's Securities Markets Programme</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eser, Fabian; Schwaab, Bernd
We assess the yield impact of asset purchases within the European Central Bank's (ECB) Securities Markets Programme (SMP) in five euro area sovereign bond markets from 2010-11. In addition to large announcement effects, we find an impact of approximately -3 basis points at the five-year maturity for purchases of 1/1000 of the outstanding debt. Bond yield volatility and tail risk are lower on intervention days for most SMP countries. A dynamic specification points to both transitory and long-run effects. Purchases improved liquidity conditions and reduced default-risk premia, while the signaling of future low interest rates did not play a role. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eser, Fabian; Schwaab, Bernd</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The real effects of share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor; Fos, Vyacheslav; Kronlund, Mathias
We employ a regression discontinuity design to identify the real effects of share repurchases on other firm outcomes. The probability of share repurchases that increase earnings per share (EPS) is sharply higher for firms that would have just missed the EPS forecast in the absence of the repurchase, when compared with firms that "just beat" the EPS forecast. We use this discontinuity to show that EPS-motivated repurchases are associated with reductions in employment and investment, and a decrease in cash holdings. Our evidence suggests that managers are willing to trade off investments and employment for stock repurchases that allow them to meet analyst EPS forecasts. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Fos, Vyacheslav; Kronlund, Mathias</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock repurchases and liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hillert, Alexander; Maug, Ernst; Obernberger, Stefan
We analyze the impact of share repurchases on liquidity based on a new comprehensive data set of realized share repurchases in the US, which covers 50,204 repurchase months between 2004 and 2010. Using instrumental variable analysis, we show that repurchases unequivocally improve liquidity and suggest that endogenous controls have confounded results in earlier studies. Liquidity also influences how firms execute repurchase programs. Repurchases provide liquidity when other investors sell the firm's stock or in times of crisis. No evidence exists that firms reduce liquidity when they trade on private information. (C) 2015 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hillert, Alexander; Maug, Ernst; Obernberger, Stefan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>