<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFE4</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>The US left behind? Financial globalization and the rise of IPOs outside the US</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Stulz, Rene M.
From 1990 to 2011, the share of world IPO activity by non-U.S. firms increased because of financial globalization and because of a decrease in U.S. IPO activity. Financial globalization reduces the impact of national institutions on domestic IPO activity and enables more non-U.S. firms from countries with weak institutions to go public with a global IPO. U.S. IPO activity does not benefit from financial globalization. Compared to other countries, the rate of small-firm IPO activity in the U.S. is abnormally low in the 2000s. This abnormally low rate cannot be explained by the regulatory changes of the early 2000s. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do staggered boards affect shareholder value? Evidence from a natural experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Alma; Wang, Charles C. Y.
The well-established negative correlation between staggered boards (SBs) and firm value could be due to SBs leading to lower value or a reflection of low-value firms' greater propensity to maintain SBs. We analyze the causal question using a natural experiment involving two Delaware court rulings separated by several weeks and going in opposite directions that affected the antitakeover force of SBs. We contribute to the long-standing debate on staggered boards by presenting empirical evidence consistent with the market viewing SBs as leading to lower firm value for the affected firms. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cohen, Alma; Wang, Charles C. Y.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of options-implied inflation probability density functions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kitsul, Yuriy; Wright, Jonathan H.
Recently a market in options based on consumer price index inflation (inflation caps and floors) has emerged in the US. This paper uses quotes on these derivatives to construct probability densities for inflation. We study how these probability density functions respond to news announcements and find that the implied odds of deflation are sensitive to certain macroeconomic news releases. We also estimate empirical pricing kernels using these option prices along with time series models fitted to inflation. The options-implied densities assign considerably more mass to extreme inflation outcomes (either deflation or high inflation) than do their time series counterparts. This yields a U-shaped empirical pricing kernel, with investors having high marginal utility in states of the world characterized by either deflation or high inflation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kitsul, Yuriy; Wright, Jonathan H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Binsbergen, Jules; Hueskes, Wouter; Koijen, Ralph; Vrugt, Evert
We study a new data set of dividend futures with maturities up to ten years across three world regions: the US, Europe, and Japan. We use these asset prices to construct equity yields, analogous to bond yields. We decompose the equity yields to obtain a term structure of expected dividend growth rates and a term structure of risk premia, which decomposes the equity risk premium by maturity. We find that the slope of the term structure of risk premia is pro-cyclical, whereas the slope of the term structure of expected dividend growth rates is counter-cyclical. The comovement of yields across regions is, on average, higher for long-maturity yields than for short-maturity yields, whereas the variation in this comovement is much higher for short-maturity yields. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>van Binsbergen, Jules; Hueskes, Wouter; Koijen, Ralph; Vrugt, Evert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Legislating stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren; Diether, Karl; Malloy, Christopher
We demonstrate that legislation has a simple, yet previously undetected, impact on stock prices. Exploiting the voting record of legislators whose constituents are the affected industries, we show that the votes of these "interested" legislators capture important information seemingly ignored by the market. A long-short portfolio based on these legislators' views earns abnormal returns of over 90 basis points per month following the passage of legislation. Industries that we classify as beneficiaries of legislation experience significantly more positive earnings surprises and positive analyst revisions in the months following passage of the bill, as well as significantly higher future sales and profitability. We show that the more complex the legislation, the more difficulty the market has in assessing the impact of these bills. Further, the more concentrated the legislator's interest in the industry, the more informative are her votes for future returns. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cohen, Lauren; Diether, Karl; Malloy, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quiet bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Sraer, David
Motivated by the recent subprime mortgage crisis, we explore whether speculative bubble models of equity based on investor disagreement and short-sales constraints can also provide an explanation for the overvaluation of debt contracts. We find that this is unlikely. Equity bubbles are loud: price and volume go together as investors speculate on capital gains from reselling to more optimistic investors. But this resale option is limited for debt since its upside payoff is bounded. Debt bubbles then require an optimism bias among investors. But greater optimism leads to less speculative trading as investors view the debt as safe and having limited upside. Debt bubbles are hence quiet high price comes with low volume. We find the predicted price-volume relationship of credits over the 2003-2007 credit boom. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Sraer, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contracting under asymmetric information: Evidence from lockup agreements in seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Lee, Gemma; Masulis, Ronald W.
We document the frequent use of lockup agreements in seasoned equity offerings (SEOs) and examine the determinants of their use, duration, and early release. We find that the likelihood of an SEO lockup and its duration are positively related to issuer information asymmetry measures. Lockup duration is negatively related to underwriter spreads and underpricing, indicating that lockups lower expected flotation costs. Lockups are frequently released early following share prices rises. We conclude that lockups represent a contracting solution to asymmetric information and agency problems that plague equity issues by helping to insure SEO quality and deter opportunistic insider trading. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Lee, Gemma; Masulis, Ronald W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reputational contagion and optimal regulatory forbearance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morrison, Alan D.; White, Lucy
Existing studies suggest that systemic crises may arise because banks either hold correlated assets, or are connected by interbank lending. This paper shows that common regulation is also a conduit for interbank contagion. One bank's failure may undermine confidence in the banking regulator's competence, and, hence, in other banks chartered by the same regulator. As a result, depositors withdraw funds from otherwise unconnected banks. The optimal regulatory response to this behavior can be privately to exhibit forbearance to a failing bank. We show that regulatory transparency improves confidence ex ante but impedes regulators' ability to stem panics ex post. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morrison, Alan D.; White, Lucy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of firm-initiated clawback provisions on bank loan contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Lilian H.; Chen, Kevin C. W.; Chen, Tai-Yuan
Although firm-initiated clawbacks reduce accounting manipulation, they also induce managers to engage in suboptimal activities (e.g., reduce research and development (R&amp;D) expenses) to achieve earnings targets. To assess the effectiveness of clawback provisions, we examine their impact from debtholders' point of view. We find that banks use more financial covenants and performance pricing provisions in the loan contracts and decrease interest rates after firms initiate clawbacks. Moreover, we also find that loan maturity increases and loan collateral decreases subsequent to clawback adoption. Taken together, our findings indicate that firm-initiated clawback provisions enhance financial reporting quality, thereby reducing the information uncertainty that financing providers face. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Lilian H.; Chen, Kevin C. W.; Chen, Tai-Yuan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Boards, CEO entrenchment, and the cost of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dow, James
Existing research on chief executive officer (CEO) turnover focuses on CEO ability. This paper argues that board ability is also important. Corporate boards are reluctant to replace CEOs, as this makes financing expensive by sending a negative signal about board ability. Entrenchment in this model does not result from CEO power, or from agency problems. Entrenchment is mitigated when there are more assets-in-place relative to investment opportunities. The paper also compares public and private equity. Private ownership eliminates CEO entrenchment, but market signals improve investment decisions. Finally, the model implies that board choice in publicly listed firms will be conservative. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dow, James</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Word power: A new approach for content analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jegadeesh, Narasimhan; Wu, Di
We present a new approach for content analysis to quantify document tone. We find a significant relation between our measure of the tone of 10-Ks and market reaction for both negative and positive words. We also find that the appropriate choice of term weighting in content analysis is at least as important as, and perhaps more important than, a complete and accurate compilation of the word list. Furthermore, we show that our approach circumvents the need to subjectively partition words into positive and negative word lists. Our approach reliably quantifies the tone of IPO prospectuses as well, and we find that the document score is negatively related to IPO underpricing. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jegadeesh, Narasimhan; Wu, Di</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>General equilibrium pricing of currency and currency options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Du
This paper presents a consumption-based general equilibrium model for valuing foreign exchange contingent claims. The model identifies a novel economic mechanism by exploiting highly but imperfectly shared consumption disaster with variable intensities which are the concerns to the representative investor under recursive utility. When applied to the data, the model simultaneously replicates (i) the moderate option-implied volatilities; (ii) substantial variations in the risk-neutral skewness of currency returns; (iii) the uncovered interest rate parity puzzle; and (iv) the first two moments of carry trade returns. Furthermore, the model rationalizes salient features of the aggregate stock, government bonds, and equity index options. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Du, Du</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market timing, investment, and risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Chen, Hui; Wang, Neng
The 2008 financial crisis exemplifies significant uncertainties in corporate financing conditions. We develop a unified dynamic q-theoretic framework where firms have both a precautionary-savings motive and a market-timing motive for external financing and payout decisions, induced by stochastic financing conditions. The model predicts (1) cuts in investment and payouts in bad times and equity issues in good times even without immediate financing needs; (2) a positive correlation between equity issuance and stock repurchase waves. We show quantitatively that real effects of financing shocks may be substantially smoothed out as a result of firms' adjustments in anticipation of future financial crises. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Chen, Hui; Wang, Neng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm characteristics and long-run stock returns after corporate events</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Zhang, Feng
The well-documented abnormal long-run buy-and-hold returns to firms issuing equity in initial public offerings and seasoned equity offerings, firms bidding in mergers, and firms initiating dividends can be attributed to imperfect control-firm matching. In addition to firm size and market-to-book ratio, event firms on average differ from control firms in terms of idiosyncratic volatility, liquidity, return momentum, and capital investment, each of which also explains returns. We propose a simple regression-based approach to control for differences in firm characteristics across event and control firms, and we show that long-run abnormal returns do not differ significantly from zero for event firms in the 1980 to 2005 period. The returns to event firms are, therefore, consistent with patterns known to exist for the broad stock market and do not require event-specific explanations. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Zhang, Feng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Worldwide reach of short selling regulations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jain, Archana; Jain, Pankaj K.; McInish, Thomas H.; McKenzie, Michael
We characterize legality and incidence of short selling in a worldwide, multimarket framework. Home country short selling restrictions curtail home market stock borrowing by 45% and reduce short selling of the country's American Depository Receipts (ADRs) by 68% due to regulatory reach. Also, the 2008 US ban on short selling of financial firms reduced borrowing in foreign locations. These findings are robust to controls for option availability, enforcement, returns, firm size, trading volume, dividends, ADR level, volatility, days-to-cover, and industry sector. Further, we show that investor conduct resulting from adherence to professional standards is a more powerful mechanism of regulatory reach than intergovernment cooperation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jain, Archana; Jain, Pankaj K.; McInish, Thomas H.; McKenzie, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sharing information in the credit market: Contract-level evidence from</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doblas-Madrid, Antonio; Minetti, Raoul
We investigate the impact of lenders' information sharing on firms' performance in the credit market using rich contract-level data from a U.S. credit bureau. The staggered entry of lenders into the bureau offers a natural experiment to identify the effect of lenders' improved access to information. Consistent with the predictions of Padilla and Pagano (1997, 2000) and Pagano and Jappelli (1993), we find that information sharing reduces contract delinquencies and defaults, especially when firms are informationally opaque. The results also reveal that information sharing does not reduce the use of guarantees, that is, it may not loosen lending standards. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doblas-Madrid, Antonio; Minetti, Raoul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The leverage effect puzzle: Disentangling sources of bias at high frequency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ait-Sahalia, Yacine; Fan, Jianqing; Li, Yingying
The leverage effect refers to the generally negative correlation between an asset return and its changes of volatility. A natural estimate consists in using the empirical correlation between the daily returns and the changes of daily volatility estimated from high frequency data. The puzzle lies in the fact that such an intuitively natural estimate yields nearly zero correlation for most assets tested, despite the many economic reasons for expecting the estimated correlation to be negative. To better understand the sources of the puzzle, we analyze the different asymptotic biases that are involved in high frequency estimation of the leverage effect, including biases due to discretization errors, to smoothing errors in estimating spot volatilities, to estimation error, and to market microstructure noise. This decomposition enables us to propose novel bias correction methods for estimating the leverage effect. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ait-Sahalia, Yacine; Fan, Jianqing; Li, Yingying</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Productivity, restructuring, and the gains from takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xiaoyang
This paper investigates how takeovers create value. Using plant-level data, I show that acquirers increase targets' productivity through more efficient use of capital and labor. Acquirers reduce capital expenditures, wages, and employment in target plants, though output is unchanged. Acquirers improve targets' investment efficiency through reallocating capital to industries with better investment opportunities. Moreover, changes in productivity help explain the merging firms' announcement returns. The combined announcement returns are driven by improvements in target's productivity. Targets with greater productivity improvements receive higher premiums. These results provide some first empirical evidence on the relation between productivity and stock returns in takeovers. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Xiaoyang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firms as liquidity providers: Evidence from the 2007-2008 financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia-Appendini, Emilia; Montoriol-Garriga, Judit
Using a supplier-client matched sample, we study the effect of the 2007-2008 financial crisis on between-firm liquidity provision. Consistent with a causal effect of a negative shock to bank credit, we find that firms with high precrisis liquidity levels increased the trade credit extended to other corporations and subsequently experienced better performance as compared with ex ante cash-poor firms. Trade credit taken by constrained firms increased during this period. These findings are consistent with firms providing liquidity insurance to their clients when bank credit is scarce and offer an important precautionary savings motive for accumulating cash reserves. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garcia-Appendini, Emilia; Montoriol-Garriga, Judit</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do personal taxes affect capital structure? Evidence from the 2003 tax cut</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Leming; Flannery, Mark J.
Because the personal tax treatments of interest and dividend income likely affect the relative cost of debt and equity financing, a sharp change in tax treatment could affect firms' optimal leverage. This paper examines the effect of the 2003 equity income tax cut on firms' debt usage. Because this tax cut affected only individual investors, we can use a difference-in-differences method to identify the effect of personal tax on firms' leverage. Previous research has found that the 2003 tax cut encouraged dividend payouts and reduced the cost of equity, but it provides no link to equilibrium leverage ratios. We estimate that the tax cut causes the affected firms' leverage to decrease by about 5 percentage points. Furthermore, we show that the effects of the tax cut are stronger for firms with lower marginal corporate tax rates and for firms that are not financially constrained, consistent with our theoretical predictions. Overall, we find strong evidence that personal tax is an important determinant of firms' optimal leverage. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Leming; Flannery, Mark J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate ownership structure and the choice between bank debt and public debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Malatesta, Paul; Xuan, Yuhai
This article examines the relation between a borrowing firm's ownership structure and its choice of debt source using a novel data set on corporate ownership, control, and debt structures for 9,831 firms in 20 countries from 2001 to 2010. We find that the divergence between the control rights and cash-flow rights of a borrowing firm's largest ultimate owner has a significant negative impact on the firm's reliance on bank debt financing. In addition, we show that the control-ownership divergence affects other aspects of debt structure including debt maturity and security. Our results indicate that firms controlled by large shareholders with excess control rights may choose public debt financing over bank debt as a way of avoiding scrutiny and insulating themselves from bank monitoring. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Malatesta, Paul; Xuan, Yuhai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relation between equity incentives and misreporting: The role of risk-taking incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armstrong, Christopher S.; Larcker, David F.; Ormazabal, Gaizka; Taylor, Daniel J.
Prior research argues that a manager whose wealth is more sensitive to changes in the firm's stock price has a greater incentive to misreport. However, if the manager is risk-averse and misreporting increases both equity values and equity risk, the sensitivity of the manager's wealth to changes in stock price (portfolio delta) will have two countervailing incentive effects: a positive "reward effect" and a negative "risk effect." In contrast, the sensitivity of the manager's wealth to changes in risk (portfolio vega) will have an unambiguously positive incentive effect. We show that jointly considering the incentive effects of both portfolio delta and portfolio vega substantially alters inferences reported in prior literature. Using both regression and matching designs, and measuring misreporting using discretionary accruals, restatements, and enforcement actions, we find strong evidence of a positive relation between vega and misreporting and that the incentives provided by vega subsume those of delta. Collectively, our results suggest that equity portfolios provide managers with incentives to misreport when they make managers less averse to equity risk. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Armstrong, Christopher S.; Larcker, David F.; Ormazabal, Gaizka; Taylor, Daniel J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does risk management matter? Evidence from the US agricultural industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornaggia, Jess
This article constructs triple-difference tests around shifts in the supply of risk management instruments available to agricultural producers to reveal a positive relation between risk management and productivity. This relation is more robust when producers adopt instruments with payoffs linked to group performance and weaker when payoffs are linked to individual performance. Additionally, productivity is particularly high among risk-managing producers in counties containing high levels of bank deposits, a proxy for access to finance. Overall, this article illuminates the relation between hedging and real firm outcomes as well as the interaction between access to finance and firms' risk management choices. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cornaggia, Jess</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can hedge funds time market liquidity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Charles; Chen, Yong; Liang, Bing; Lo, Andrew W.
We explore a new dimension of fund managers' timing ability by examining whether they can time market liquidity through adjusting their portfolios' market exposure as aggregate liquidity conditions change. Using a large sample of hedge funds, we find strong evidence of liquidity timing. A bootstrap analysis suggests that top-ranked liquidity timers cannot be attributed to pure luck. In out-of-sample tests, top liquidity timers outperform bottom timers by 4.0-5.5% annually on a risk-adjusted basis. We also find that it is important to distinguish liquidity timing from liquidity reaction, which primarily relies on public information. Our results are robust to alternative explanations, hedge fund data biases, and the use of alternative timing models, risk factors, and liquidity measures. The findings highlight the importance of understanding and incorporating market liquidity conditions in investment decision making. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cao, Charles; Chen, Yong; Liang, Bing; Lo, Andrew W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Feedback effects of credit ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manso, Gustavo
Rating agencies are often criticized for being biased in favor of borrowers, for being too slow to downgrade following credit quality deterioration, and for being oligopolists. Based on a model that takes into account the feedback effects of credit ratings, I show that: (i) rating agencies should focus not only on the accuracy of their ratings but also on the effects of their ratings on the probability of survival of the borrower; (ii) even when rating agencies pursue an accurate rating policy, multi-notch downgrades or immediate default may occur in response to small shocks to fundamentals; (iii) increased competition between rating agencies can lead to rating downgrades, increasing default frequency and reducing welfare. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Manso, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading frenzies and their impact on real investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, Itay; Ozdenoren, Emre; Yuan, Kathy
We study a model in which a capital provider learns from the price of a firm's security in deciding how much capital to provide for new investment. This feedback effect from the financial market to the investment decision gives rise to trading frenzies, in which speculators all wish to trade like others, generating large pressure on prices. Coordination among speculators is sometimes desirable for price informativeness and investment efficiency, but speculators' incentives push in the opposite direction, so that they coordinate exactly when it is undesirable. We analyze the effect of various market parameters on the likelihood of trading frenzies to arise. Crown Copyright (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goldstein, Itay; Ozdenoren, Emre; Yuan, Kathy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A production-based model for the term structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jermann, Urban J.
This paper considers the term structure of interest rates implied by a production-based asset pricing model in which the fundamental drivers are investment in equipment and structures as well as inflation. The model matches the average yield curve up to five-year maturity almost perfectly. Longer term yields are roughly as volatile as in the data. The model also generates time-varying bond risk premiums. In particular, when running Fama-Bliss regressions of excess returns on forward premiums, the model produces slope coefficients of roughly half the size of the empirical counterparts. Closed-form expressions highlight the importance of the capital depreciation rates for interest rate dynamics. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jermann, Urban J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO first-day returns, offer price revisions, volatility, and form S-1 language</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loughran, Tim; McDonald, Bill
Form S-1 is the first SEC filing in the initial public offering (IPO) process. The tone of the S-1, in terms of its definitiveness in characterizing the firm's business strategy and operations, should affect investors' ability to value the IPO. We find that IPOs with high levels of uncertain text have higher first-day returns, absolute offer price revisions, and subsequent volatility. Our findings provide empirical evidence for the theoretical models of uncertainty, bookbuilding, and prospect theory. (C) 2013 Elsevier BAT. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loughran, Tim; McDonald, Bill</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO turnover in a competitive assignment framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisfeldt, Andrea L.; Kuhnen, Camelia M.
There is widespread concern about whether Chief Executive Officers (CEOs) are appropriately punished for poor performance. While CEOs are more likely to be forced out if their performance is poor relative to the industry average, overall industry performance also matters. This seems puzzling if termination is disciplinary, however, we show that both absolute and relative performance-driven turnover can be natural and efficient outcomes in a competitive assignment model in which CEOs and firms form matches based on multiple characteristics. The model also has new predictions about replacement managers' equilibrium pay and performance. We document CEO turnover events during 1992-2006 and provide empirical support for our model. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eisfeldt, Andrea L.; Kuhnen, Camelia M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The timing of pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parsons, Christopher A.; Van Wesep, Edward D.
There exists large and persistent variation in not only how, but when employees are paid, a fact unexplained by existing theory. This paper develops a simple model of optimal pay timing for firms. When workers have self-control problems, they under-save and experience volatile consumption between paychecks. Thus, pay whose delivery matches the timing of workers' consumption needs will reduce wage costs. The model also explains why pay timing should be regulated (as it is in practice): although the worker benefits from a timing profile that smoothes her consumption, her lack of self-control induces her to attempt to undo the arrangement, either by renegotiating with her employer or by taking out payday loans. Regulation of pay timing and consumer borrowing is required to counter these efforts, helping the worker help herself. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Parsons, Christopher A.; Van Wesep, Edward D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring and corporate disclosure: Evidence from a natural experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Irani, Rustom M.; Oesch, David
Using an experimental design that exploits exogenous reductions in coverage resulting from brokerage house mergers, we find that a reduction in coverage causes a deterioration in financial reporting quality. The effect of coverage on disclosure is more pronounced for firms with weak shareholder rights, consistent with a substitution effect between analyst monitoring and other corporate governance mechanisms. The effects we uncover using our experimental design are an order of magnitude larger than estimates from ordinary least squares regressions that do not account for the endogeneity of coverage. Overall, our results suggest that security analysts monitor managers and entrenched managers adopt less informative disclosure policies in the absence of such scrutiny. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Irani, Rustom M.; Oesch, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limits to arbitrage and hedging: Evidence from commodity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Lochstoer, Lars A.; Ramadorai, Tarun
We build an equilibrium model of commodity markets in which speculators are capital constrained, and commodity producers have hedging demands for commodity futures. Increases in producers' hedging demand or speculators' capital constraints increase hedging costs via price-pressure on futures. These in turn affect producers' equilibrium hedging and supply decision inducing a link between a financial friction in the futures market and the commodity spot prices. Consistent with the model, measures of producers' propensity to hedge forecasts futures returns and spot prices in oil and gas market data from 1979 to 2010. The component of the commodity futures risk premium associated with producer hedging demand rises when speculative activity reduces. We conclude that limits to financial arbitrage generate limits to hedging by producers, and affect equilibrium commodity supply and prices. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Lochstoer, Lars A.; Ramadorai, Tarun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral and capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rampini, Adriano A.; Viswanathan, S.
We develop a dynamic model of investment, capital structure, leasing, and risk management based on firms' need to collateralize promises to pay with tangible assets. Both financing and risk management involve promises to pay subject to collateral constraints. Leasing is strongly collateralized costly financing and permits greater leverage. More constrained firms hedge less and lease more, both cross-sectionally and dynamically. Mature firms suffering adverse cash flow shocks may cut risk management and sell and lease back assets. Persistence of productivity reduces the benefits to hedging low cash flows and can lead firms not to hedge at all. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rampini, Adriano A.; Viswanathan, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate social responsibility and stakeholder value maximization: Evidence from mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deng, Xin; Kang, Jun-koo; Low, Buen Sin
Using a large sample of mergers in the US, we examine whether corporate social responsibility (CSR) creates value for acquiring firms' shareholders. We find that compared with low CSR acquirers, high CSR acquirers realize higher merger announcement returns, higher announcement returns on the value-weighted portfolio of the acquirer and the target, and larger increases in post-merger long-term operating performance. They also realize positive long-term stock returns, suggesting that the market does not fully value the benefits of CSR immediately. In addition, we find that mergers by high CSR acquirers take less time to complete and are less likely to fail than mergers by low CSR acquirers. These results suggest that acquirers' social performance is an important determinant of merger performance and the probability of its completion, and they support the stakeholder value maximization view of stakeholder theory. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Deng, Xin; Kang, Jun-koo; Low, Buen Sin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The European Union, the Euro, and equity market integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, Geert; Harvey, Campbell R.; Lundblad, Christian T.; Siegel, Stephan
We use industry valuation differentials across European countries to study the impact of membership in the European Union as well as the Eurozone on both economic and financial integration. In integrated markets, discount rates and expected growth opportunities should be similar within one industry, irrespective of the country, implying narrowing valuation differentials as countries become more integrated. Our analysis of the 1990-2007 period shows that membership in the EU significantly lowered discount rate and expected earnings growth differentials across countries. In contrast, the adoption of the Euro was not associated with increased integration. Our results do not change when the sample is extended to include the recent crisis period. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Harvey, Campbell R.; Lundblad, Christian T.; Siegel, Stephan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Gaussian macro-finance term structure models are (nearly) unconstrained factor-VARs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joslin, Scott; Le, Anh; Singleton, Kenneth J.
This paper explores the implications of filtering and no-arbitrage for the maximum likelihood estimates of the entire conditional distribution of the risk factors and bond yields in Gaussian macro-finance term structure model (MTSM) when all yields are priced imperfectly. For typical yield curves and macro-variables studied in this literature, the estimated joint distribution within a canonical MTSM is nearly identical to the estimate from an economic-model-free factor vector-autoregression (factor-VAR), even when measurement errors are large. It follows that a canonical MTSM offers no new insights into economic questions regarding the historical distribution of the macro risk factors and yields, over and above what is learned from a factor-VAR These results are rotation-invariant and, therefore, apply to many of the specifications in the literature. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Joslin, Scott; Le, Anh; Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Controlling shareholders and market timing in share issuance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larrain, Borja; Urzua, Francisco I.
We examine market timing in the equity issuance of firms controlled by large shareholders using a hand-collected data set of controlling shareholders' ownership stakes in Chile between 1990 and 2009. When a firm issues shares, the controlling shareholder can either maintain or change his ownership stake depending on how many of the new shares he subscribes. Issuance predicts poor future returns and is preceded by high returns, but only when the controlling shareholder's stake is significantly reduced. Consistent with market timing, the results are stronger in the absence of institutional investors and in hot issuance markets. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Larrain, Borja; Urzua, Francisco I.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Externalities of public firm presence: Evidence from private firms' investment decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Badertscher, Brad; Shroff, Nemit; White, Hal D.
Public firms provide a large amount of information through their disclosures. In addition, information intermediaries publicly analyze, discuss, and disseminate these disclosures. Thus, greater public firm presence in an industry should reduce uncertainty in that industry. Following the theoretical prediction of investment under uncertainty, we hypothesize and find that private firms are more responsive to their investment opportunities when they operate in industries with greater public firm presence. Further, we find that the effect of public firm presence is greater in industries with better information quality and in industries characterized by a greater degree of investment irreversibility. Our results suggest that public firms generate positive externalities by reducing industry uncertainty and facilitating more efficient private firm investment. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Badertscher, Brad; Shroff, Nemit; White, Hal D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploring uncharted territories of the hedge fund Industry: Empirical characteristics of mega hedge fund firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edelman, Daniel; Fung, William; Hsieh, David A.
This paper investigates mega hedge fund management companies that collectively manage over 50% of the industry's assets, incorporating previously unavailable data from those that do not report to commercial databases. We find similarities among mega firms that report performance to commercial databases compared with those that do not. We show that the largest divergences between the performance of reporting and nonreporting mega firms can be traced to differential exposure to credit markets. Thus, the performance of hard-to-observe mega firms can be inferred from observable data. This conclusion is robust to delisting bias and the presence of serially correlated returns. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Edelman, Daniel; Fung, William; Hsieh, David A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking deregulation and innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Oettl, Alexander; Subramanian, Ajay; Subramanian, Krishnamurthy V.
We document empirical support for a key micro-level channel-innovation by young, private firms-through which financial sector deregulation affects economic growth. We find that intrastate banking deregulation, which increased the local market power of banks, decreased the level and risk of innovation by young, private firms. In contrast, interstate banking deregulation, which decreased the local market power of banks, increased the level and risk of innovation by young, private firms. These contrasting effects on innovation also translated into contrasting effects on economic growth. Our study suggests that the nature of financial sector deregulation crucially affects its potential benefits to the real economy. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Oettl, Alexander; Subramanian, Ajay; Subramanian, Krishnamurthy V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why does junior put all his eggs in one basket? A potential rational explanation for holding concentrated portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roche, Herve; Tompaidis, Stathis; Yang, Chunyu
Empirical studies of household portfolios show that young households, with little financial wealth, hold underdiversified portfolios that are concentrated in a small number of assets, a fact often attributed to behavioral biases. We present a potential rational alternative: we show that investors with little financial wealth, who receive labor income, rationally limit the number of assets they invest in when faced with financial constraints such as margin requirements and restrictions on borrowing. We provide theoretical and numerical support for our results and identify the ratio of financial wealth to labor income as a useful control variable for household portfolio studies. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roche, Herve; Tompaidis, Stathis; Yang, Chunyu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Undisclosed orders and optimal submission strategies in a limit order market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buti, Sabrina; Rindi, Barbara
Reserve orders enable traders to hide a portion of their orders and now appear in most electronic limit order markets. This paper outlines a theory to determine an optimal submission strategy in a limit order book, in which traders choose among limit, market, and reserve orders and simultaneously set price, quantity, and exposure. We show that reserve orders help traders compete for the provision of liquidity and reduce the friction generated by exposure costs. Therefore, total gains from trade increase. Large traders always benefit from reserve orders, whereas small traders benefit only when the tick size is large. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buti, Sabrina; Rindi, Barbara</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit supply and corporate innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amore, Mario Daniele; Schneider, Cedric; Zaldokas, Alminas
We present evidence that banking development plays a key role in technological progress. We focus on manufacturing firms' innovative performance, measured by patent-based metrics, and employ exogenous variations in banking development arising from the staggered deregulation of banking activities across US states during the 1980s and 1990s. We find that interstate banking deregulation had significant beneficial effects on the quantity and quality of innovation activities, especially for firms highly dependent on external capital and located closer to entering banks. Furthermore, we find that these results are strongly driven by a greater ability of deregulated banks to geographically diversify credit risk. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amore, Mario Daniele; Schneider, Cedric; Zaldokas, Alminas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of interbank risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Filipovic, Damir; Trolle, Anders B.
We infer a term structure of interbank risk from spreads between rates on interest rate swaps indexed to the London Interbank Offered Rate (LIBOR) and overnight indexed swaps. We develop a tractable model of interbank risk to decompose the term structure into default and non-default (liquidity) components. From August 2007 to January 2011, the fraction of total interbank risk due to default risk, on average, increases with maturity. At short maturities, the non-default component is important in the first half of the sample period and is correlated with measures of funding and market liquidity. The model also provides a framework for pricing, hedging, and risk management of interest rate swaps in the presence of significant basis risk. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Filipovic, Damir; Trolle, Anders B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of corporate cash policy: Insights from private firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Huasheng; Harford, Jarrad; Li, Kai
We provide one of the first large sample comparisons of cash policies in public and private U.S. firms. We first show that despite higher financing frictions, private firms hold, on average, about half as much cash as public firms do. By examining the drivers of cash policies for each group, we are able to attribute the difference to the much higher agency costs in public firms. By combining evidence from across public and private firms as well as within public firms across different qualities of governance, we are able to reconcile existing mixed evidence on the effects of agency problems on cash policies. Specifically, agency problems affect not only the target level of cash, but also how managers react to cash in excess of the target. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gao, Huasheng; Harford, Jarrad; Li, Kai</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dividend month premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.
We find an asset pricing anomaly whereby companies have positive abnormal returns in months when they are predicted to issue a dividend. Abnormal returns in predicted dividend months are high relative to other companies and relative to dividend-paying companies in months without a predicted dividend, making risk-based explanations unlikely. The anomaly is as large as the value premium, but less volatile. The premium is consistent with price pressure from dividend-seeking investors. Measures of liquidity and demand for dividends are associated with larger price increases in the period before the ex-day (when there is no news about the dividend) and larger reversals afterward. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Company name fluency, investor recognition, and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, T. Clifton; Jame, Russell
Research from psychology suggests that people evaluate fluent stimuli more favorably than similar information that is harder to process. Consistent with fluency affecting investment decisions, we find that companies with short, easy to pronounce names have higher breadth of ownership, greater share turnover, lower transaction price impacts, and higher valuation ratios. Corporate name changes increase fluency on average, and fluency-improving name changes are associated with increases in breadth of ownership, liquidity, and firm value. Name fluency also affects other investment decisions, with fluently named closed-end funds trading at smaller discounts and fluent mutual funds attracting greater fund flows. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Green, T. Clifton; Jame, Russell</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dark side of analyst coverage: The case of innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Jie; Tian, Xuan
We examine the effects of financial analysts on the real economy in the case of innovation. Our baseline results show that firms covered by a larger number of analysts generate fewer patents and patents with lower impact. To establish causality, we use a difference-indifferences approach that relies on the variation generated by multiple exogenous shocks to analyst coverage, as well as an instrumental variable approach. Our identification strategies suggest a negative causal effect of analyst coverage on firm innovation. The evidence is consistent with the hypothesis that analysts exert too much pressure on managers to meet short-term goals, impeding firms investment in long-term innovative projects. We further discuss possible underlying mechanisms through which analysts impede innovation and show that there is a residual effect of analysts on innovation even after controlling for these mechanisms. Our paper offers novel evidence on a previously under-explored adverse consequence of analyst coverage-its hindrance to firm innovation. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Jie; Tian, Xuan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction: A special issue on investor sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wurgler, Jeffrey
nan</description><author>Wurgler, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Realization utility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barberis, Nicholas; Xiong, Wei
A number of authors have suggested that investors derive utility from realizing gains and losses on assets that they own. We present a model of this "realization utility," analyze its predictions, and show that it can shed light on a number of puzzling facts. These include the disposition effect, the poor trading performance of individual investors, the higher volume of trade in rising markets, the effect of historical highs on the propensity to sell, the individual investor preference for volatile stocks, the low average return of volatile stocks, and the heavy trading associated with highly valued assets. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barberis, Nicholas; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Chasing noise</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mendel, Brock; Shleifer, Andrei
We present a simple model in which rational but uninformed traders occasionally chase noise as if it were information, thereby amplifying sentiment shocks and moving prices away from fundamental values. In the model, noise traders can have an impact on market equilibrium disproportionate to their size in the market. The model offers a partial explanation for the surprisingly low market price of financial risk in the spring of 2007. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mendel, Brock; Shleifer, Andrei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer performance and stock market entry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaustia, Markku; Knuepfer, Samuli
Peer performance can influence the adoption of financial innovations and investment styles. We present evidence of this type of social influence: recent stock returns that local peers experience affect an individual's stock market entry decision, particularly in areas with better opportunities for social learning. The likelihood of entry does not decrease as returns fall below zero, consistent with people not talking about decisions that have produced inferior outcomes. Market returns, media coverage, local stocks, omitted local variables, short sales constraints, and stock purchases within households do not seem to explain these results. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaustia, Markku; Knuepfer, Samuli</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring investor sentiment with mutual fund flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Kandel, Shmuel; Wohl, Avi
We investigate a proxy for monthly shifts between bond funds and equity funds in the USA: aggregate net exchanges of equity funds. This measure (which is negatively related to changes in VIX) is positively contemporaneously correlated with aggregate stock market excess returns: One standard deviation of net exchanges is related to 1.95% of market excess return. Our main new finding is that 85% (all) of the contemporaneous relation is reversed within four (ten) months. The effect is stronger in smaller stocks and in growth stocks. These findings support the notion of "noise" in aggregate market prices induced by investor sentiment. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Kandel, Shmuel; Wohl, Avi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Complicated firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren; Lou, Dong
We exploit a novel setting in which the same piece of information affects two sets of firms: one set of firms requires straightforward processing to update prices, while the other set requires more complicated analyses to incorporate the same piece of information into prices. We document substantial return predictability from the set of easy-to-analyze firms to their more complicated peers. Specifically, a simple portfolio strategy that takes advantage of this straightforward vs. complicated information processing classification yields returns of 118 basis points per month before transaction costs. Consistent with processing complexity driving the return relation, we further show that the more complicated the firm, the more pronounced the return predictability. In addition, we find that sell-side analysts are subject to these same information processing constraints, as their forecast revisions of easy-to-analyze firms predict their future revisions of more complicated firms. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cohen, Lauren; Lou, Dong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of board structure on firm value: A multiple identification strategies approach using Korean data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Black, Bernard; Kim, Woochan
Outside directors and audit committees are widely considered to be central elements of good corporate governance. We use a 1999 Korean law as an exogenous shock to assess whether and how board structure affects firm market value. The law mandates 50% outside directors and an audit committee for large public firms, but not smaller firms. We study this shock using event study, difference-in-differences, and instrumental variable methods, within an overall regression discontinuity approach. The legal shock produces economically large share price increases for large firms, relative to mid-sized firms; their share prices jump in 1999 when the reforms are announced. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Black, Bernard; Kim, Woochan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate ownership structure and bank loan syndicate structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Malatesta, Paul; Xuan, Yuhai
Using a novel data set on corporate ownership and control, we show that the divergence between the control rights and cash-flow rights of a borrowing firm's largest ultimate owner has a significant impact on the concentration and composition of the firm's loan syndicate. When the control-ownership divergence is large, lead arrangers form syndicates with structures that facilitate enhanced due diligence and monitoring efforts. These syndicates tend to be relatively concentrated and composed of domestic banks that are geographically close to the borrowing firms and that have lending expertise related to the industries of the borrowers. We also examine factors that influence the relation between ownership structure and syndicate structure, including lead arranger reputation, prior lending relationship, borrowing firm informational opacity, presence of multiple large owners, laws and institutions, and financial crises. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Malatesta, Paul; Xuan, Yuhai</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The flight home effect: Evidence from the syndicated loan market during financial crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Laeven, Luc
This paper shows that the collapse of the global market for syndicated loans during financial crises can in part be explained by a flight home effect whereby lenders rebalance their loan portfolios in favor of domestic borrowers. The home bias of lenders' loan origination increases by approximately 20% if the bank's home country experiences a banking crisis. This flight home effect is distinct from flight to quality because borrowers of different quality are equally affected. The results indicate that the home bias in capital allocation tends to increase when adverse economic shocks reduce the wealth of international investors. (C) 2012 International Monetary Fund. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Laeven, Luc</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive stock options, differential risk-taking incentives, and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armstrong, Christopher S.; Vashishtha, Rahul
The sensitivity of stock options' payoff to return volatility, or vega, provides risk-averse CEOs with an incentive to increase their firms' risk more by increasing systematic rather than idiosyncratic risk. This effect manifests because any increase in the firm's systematic risk can be hedged by a CEO who can trade the market portfolio. Consistent with this prediction, we find that vega gives CEOs incentives to increase their firms' total risk by increasing systematic risk but not idiosyncratic risk. Collectively, our results suggest that stock options might not always encourage managers to pursue projects that are primarily characterized by idiosyncratic risk when projects with systematic risk are available as an alternative. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Armstrong, Christopher S.; Vashishtha, Rahul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>(Interstate) Banking and (interstate) trade: Does real integration follow financial integration?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michalski, Tomasz; Ors, Evren
We conjecture that banks present in two regions charge the appropriate risk premiums for trade-related projects between these markets, whereas higher rates are charged for projects involving shipments to markets where they are absent. These differences affect regional trade flows. US interstate banking deregulation serves as a natural experiment to test our model's implication with the Commodity Flow Survey data. Difference-indifferences estimates suggest that the trade share of state-pairs that allowed pairwise interstate entry increased by 14% over 10 years relative to non-integrated state-pairs. Instrumental variables estimates suggest that an actual increase in bank integration from zero to 2.28% (the mean) increases trade 17% to 25%. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Michalski, Tomasz; Ors, Evren</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reputation penalties for poor monitoring of executive pay: Evidence from option backdating</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ertimur, Yonca; Ferri, Fabrizio; Maber, David A.
We study whether outside directors are held accountable for poor monitoring of executive compensation by examining the reputation penalties to directors of firms involved in the option backdating (BD) scandal of 2006-2007. We find that, at firms involved in BD, significant penalties accrued to compensation committee members (particularly those who served during the BD period) both in terms of votes withheld when up for election and in terms of turnover, especially in more severe cases of BD. However, directors of BD firms did not suffer similar penalties at non-BD firms, raising the question of whether reputation penalties for poor oversight of executive pay are large enough to affect the ex ante incentives of directors. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ertimur, Yonca; Ferri, Fabrizio; Maber, David A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local investors, price discovery, and market efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shive, Sophie
This study examines the effect of locally informed investors on market efficiency and stock prices using large power outages, which are exogenous events that constrain trading. Turnover in stocks headquartered in an outage area with 0.5% of U.S. electrical customers drops by 3-7% on the first full day of the outage, and bid-ask spreads narrow by 2.5%. Firm-specific price volatility is 2.3% lower on blackout dates. This effect is larger for smaller, lesser-known stocks and in higher income areas. Consistent with a valuation discount and higher expected returns for stocks with more informed traders, firms with a one-standard-deviation higher local trading propensity have market-to-book values that are 5% lower, Tobin's Q that is 6% lower, annualized four-factor alphas that are 1.2% higher, and average spreads that are 6.5% higher. Together, the evidence suggests that informed investors contribute disproportionately to both liquidity and price discovery, and that these contributions are reflected in valuations and expected returns. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shive, Sophie</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash holdings, risk, and expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Palazzo, Berardino
In this paper I develop and empirically test a model that highlights how the correlation between cash flows and a source of aggregate risk affects a firm's optimal cash holding policy. In the model, riskier firms (i.e., firms with a higher correlation between cash flows and the aggregate shock) are more likely to use costly external funding to finance their growth option exercises and have higher optimal savings. This precautionary savings motive implies a positive relation between expected equity returns and cash holdings. In addition, this positive relation is stronger for firms with less valuable growth options. Using a data set of US pubic companies, I find evidence consistent with the model's predictions. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Palazzo, Berardino</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal securitization with moral hazard</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartman-Glaser, Barney; Piskorski, Tomasz; Tchistyi, Alexei
We consider the optimal design of mortgage-backed securities (MBS) in a dynamic setting in which a mortgage underwriter with limited liability can engage in costly hidden effort to screen borrowers and can sell loans to investors. We show that (i) the timing of payments to the underwriter is the key incentive mechanism, (ii) the maturity of the optimal contract can be short, and that (iii) bundling mortgages is efficient as it allows investors to learn about underwriter effort more quickly, an information enhancement effect. Finally, we demonstrate that the optimal contract can be closely approximated by the "first loss piece." (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hartman-Glaser, Barney; Piskorski, Tomasz; Tchistyi, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal corporate governance, CEO turnover, and earnings management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hazarika, Sonali; Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Nahata, Rajarishi
The likelihood and speed of forced CEO turnover - but not voluntary turnover - are positively related to a firm's earnings management. These patterns persist in tests that consider the effects of earnings restatements, regulatory enforcement actions, and the possible endogeneity of CEO turnover and earnings management. The relation between earnings management and forced turnover occurs both in firms with good and bad performance, and when the accruals work to inflate or deflate reported earnings. These results indicate that boards tend to act proactively to discipline managers who manage earnings aggressively, before the manipulations lead to costly external consequences. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hazarika, Sonali; Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Nahata, Rajarishi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitized banking and the run on repo</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, Gary; Metrick, Andrew
The panic of 2007-2008 was a run on the sale and repurchase market (the repo market), which is a very large, short-term market that provides financing for a wide range of securitization activities and financial institutions. Repo transactions are collateralized, frequently with securitized bonds. We refer to the combination of securitization plus repo finance as "securitized banking" and argue that these activities were at the nexus of the crisis. We use a novel data set that includes credit spreads for hundreds of securitized bonds to trace the path of the crisis from subprime-housing related assets into markets that had no connection to housing. We find that changes in the LIB-OIS spread, a proxy for counterparty risk, were strongly correlated with changes in credit spreads and repo rates for securitized bonds. These changes implied higher uncertainty about bank solvency and lower values for repo collateral. Concerns about the liquidity of markets for the bonds used as collateral led to increases in repo haircuts, that is the amount of collateral required for any given transaction. With declining asset values and increasing haircuts, the US banking system was effectively insolvent for the first time since the Great Depression. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gorton, Gary; Metrick, Andrew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Neglected risks, financial innovation, and financial fragility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gennaioli, Nicola; Shleifer, Andrei; Vishny, Robert
We present a standard model of financial innovation, in which intermediaries engineer securities with cash flows that investors seek, but modify two assumptions. First, investors (and possibly intermediaries) neglect certain unlikely risks. Second, investors demand securities with safe cash flows. Financial intermediaries cater to these preferences and beliefs by engineering securities perceived to be safe but exposed to neglected risks. Because the risks are neglected, security issuance is excessive. As investors eventually recognize these risks, they fly back to the safety of traditional securities and markets become fragile, even without leverage, precisely because the volume of new claims is excessive. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gennaioli, Nicola; Shleifer, Andrei; Vishny, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Econometric measures of connectedness and systemic risk in the finance and insurance sectors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billio, Monica; Getmansky, Mila; Lo, Andrew W.; Pelizzon, Loriana
We propose several econometric measures of connectedness based on principal-components analysis and Granger-causality networks, and apply them to the monthly returns of hedge funds, banks, broker/dealers, and insurance companies. We find that all four sectors have become highly interrelated over the past decade, likely increasing the level of systemic risk in the finance and insurance industries through a complex and time-varying network of relationships. These measures can also identify and quantify financial crisis periods, and seem to contain predictive power in out-of-sample tests. Our results show an asymmetry in the degree of connectedness among the four sectors, with banks playing a much more important role in transmitting shocks than other financial institutions. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Billio, Monica; Getmansky, Mila; Lo, Andrew W.; Pelizzon, Loriana</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market institutions, financial market risks, and the financial crisis Introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carey, Mark; Kashyap, Anil K.; Rajan, Raghuram; Stulz, Rene M.
nan</description><author>Carey, Mark; Kashyap, Anil K.; Rajan, Raghuram; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage crashes and the speed of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitchell, Mark; Pulvino, Todd
The imminent failure of prime brokers during the 2008 financial crisis caused a sudden decrease in the leverage afforded hedge funds. This decrease resulted from the asymmetrical payoff to rehypothecation lenders-the ultimate financiers, through prime brokers, to hedge funds. Seemingly long-term debt capital became short-term capital creating a duration mismatch between left-hand side arbitrage opportunities and right-hand side liabilities. Consequently, arbitrageurs became unable to maintain similar prices of similar assets. Mispricing magnitudes, and the time required to correct them, reflect the role of arbitrageurs in maintaining accurate prices during normal times and offer an estimate of discounts at which assets transact during crises. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mitchell, Mark; Pulvino, Todd</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of institutional investors in propagating the crisis of 2007-2008</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manconi, Alberto; Massa, Massimo; Yasuda, Ayako
Using novel data on investors' bond portfolios, we study the contagion of the crisis from securitized bonds to corporate bonds. When securitized bonds became "toxic" in August 2007, mutual funds retained the now illiquid securitized bonds and sold corporate bonds. Funds with negative flows or high liquidity needs liquidated more than others. Yield spreads increased more for corporate bonds whose pre-crisis bondholders were more heavily exposed to securitized bonds, compared to same-issuer bonds held by unexposed investors. The findings suggest that liquidity-constrained investors with exposure to securitized bonds played a role in propagating the crisis from securitized to corporate bonds. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Manconi, Alberto; Massa, Massimo; Yasuda, Ayako</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset commonality, debt maturity and systemic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Babus, Ana; Carletti, Elena
We develop a model in which asset commonality and short-term debt of banks interact to generate excessive systemic risk. Banks swap assets to diversify their individual risk. Two asset structures arise. In a clustered structure, groups of banks hold common asset portfolios and default together. In an unclustered structure, defaults are more dispersed. Portfolio quality of individual banks is opaque but can be inferred by creditors from aggregate signals about bank solvency. When bank debt is short-term, creditors do not roll over in response to adverse signals and all banks are inefficiently liquidated. This information contagion is more likely under clustered asset structures. In contrast, when bank debt is long-term, welfare is the same under both asset structures. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Babus, Ana; Carletti, Elena</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time series momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Ooi, Yao Hua; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
We document significant "time series momentum" in equity index, currency, commodity, and bond futures for each of the 58 liquid instruments we consider. We find persistence in returns for one to 12 months that partially reverses over longer horizons, consistent with sentiment theories of initial under-reaction and delayed over-reaction. A diversified portfolio of time series momentum strategies across all asset classes delivers substantial abnormal returns with little exposure to standard asset pricing factors and performs best during extreme markets. Examining the trading activities of speculators and hedgers, we find that speculators profit from time series momentum at the expense of hedgers. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Ooi, Yao Hua; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global, local, and contagious investor sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Malcolm; Wurgler, Jeffrey; Yuan, Yu
We construct investor sentiment indices for six major stock markets and decompose them into one global and six local indices. In a validation test, we find that relative sentiment is correlated with the relative prices of dual-listed companies. Global sentiment is a contrarian predictor of country-level returns. Both global and local sentiment are contrarian predictors of the time-series of cross-sectional returns within markets: When sentiment is high, future returns are low on relatively difficult to arbitrage and difficult to value stocks. Private capital flows appear to be one mechanism by which sentiment spreads across markets and forms global sentiment. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baker, Malcolm; Wurgler, Jeffrey; Yuan, Yu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The short of it: Investor sentiment and anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yu, Jianfeng; Yuan, Yu
This study explores the role of investor sentiment in a broad set of anomalies in cross-sectional stock returns. We consider a setting in which the presence of market-wide sentiment is combined with the argument that overpricing should be more prevalent than underpricing, due to short-sale impediments. Long-short strategies that exploit the anomalies exhibit profits consistent with this setting. First, each anomaly is stronger (its long-short strategy is more profitable) following high levels of sentiment. Second, the short leg of each strategy is more profitable following high sentiment. Finally, sentiment exhibits no relation to returns on the long legs of the strategies. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yu, Jianfeng; Yuan, Yu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IQ, trading behavior, and performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, Mark; Keloharju, Matti; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.
We analyze whether IQ influences trading behavior, performance, and transaction costs. The analysis combines equity return, trade, and limit order book data with two decades of scores from an intelligence (IQ) test administered to nearly every Finnish male of draft age. Controlling for a variety of factors, we find that high-IQ investors are less subject to the disposition effect, more aggressive about tax-loss trading, and more likely to supply liquidity when stocks experience a one-month high. High-IQ investors also exhibit superior market timing, stock-picking skill, and trade execution. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grinblatt, Mark; Keloharju, Matti; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor attention, psychological anchors, and stock return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Jun; Yu, Jianfeng
Motivated by psychological evidence on limited investor attention and anchoring, we propose two proxies for the degree to which traders under- and overreact to news, namely, the nearness to the Dow 52-week high and the nearness to the Dow historical high, respectively. We find that nearness to the 52-week high positively predicts future aggregate market returns, while nearness to the historical high negatively predicts future market returns. We further show that our proxies contain information about future market returns that is not captured by traditional macroeconomic variables and that our results are robust across G7 countries. Comprehensive Monte Carlo simulations and comparisons with the NYSE/Amex market cap index confirm the significance of these findings. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Jun; Yu, Jianfeng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment-cash flow sensitivity cannot be a good measure of financial constraints: Evidence from the time series</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Huafeng; Chen, Shaojun
Investment-cash flow sensitivity has declined and disappeared, even during the 2007-2009 credit crunch. If one believes that financial constraints have not disappeared, then investment-cash flow sensitivity cannot be a good measure of financial constraints. The decline and disappearance are robust to considerations of R&amp;D and cash reserves, and across groups of firms. The information content in cash flow regarding investment opportunities has declined, but measurement error in Tobin's q does not completely explain the patterns in investment-cash flow sensitivity. The decline and disappearance cannot be explained by changes in sample composition, corporate governance, or market power and remain a puzzle. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Huafeng; Chen, Shaojun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tournament incentives, firm risk, and corporate policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kini, Omesh; Williams, Ryan
This paper tests the proposition that higher tournament incentives will result in greater risk-taking by senior managers in order to increase their chance of promotion to the rank of CEO. Measuring tournament incentives as the pay gap between the CEO and the next layer of senior managers, we find a significantly positive relation between firm risk and tournament incentives. Further, we find that greater tournament incentives lead to higher R&amp;D intensity, firm focus, and leverage, but lower capital expenditures intensity. Our results support the hypothesis that option-like features of intra-organizational CEO promotion tournaments provide incentives to senior executives to increase firm risk by following riskier policies. Finally, the compensation levels and structures of executives of financial institutions have received a great deal of scrutiny after the financial crisis. In a separate examination of financial firms, we again find a significantly positive relation between firm risk and tournament incentives. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kini, Omesh; Williams, Ryan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board connections and M&amp;A transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Ye; Sevilir, Merih
We examine M&amp;A transactions between firms with current board connections and find that acquirers obtain higher announcement returns in transactions with a first-degree connection where the acquirer and the target share a common director. Acquirer returns are also higher in transactions with a second-degree connection where one acquirer director and one target director serve on the same third board. Our results suggest that first-degree connections benefit acquirers with lower takeover premiums while second-degree connections benefit acquirers with greater value creation. Overall, we provide new evidence that board connectedness plays important roles in corporate investments and leads to greater value creation. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cai, Ye; Sevilir, Merih</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The high volume return premium: Cross-country evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaniel, Ron; Ozoguz, Arzu; Starks, Laura
We examine the high volume return premium across 41 different countries and find it to be a phenomenon found in both developed and emerging markets. The premium is not caused by systematic differences in risk or liquidity. Using Merton's (1987) investor recognition hypothesis as a guide, we find the magnitude of the premium is generally associated with country and firm characteristics hypothesized to affect returns subsequent to a change in a stock's visibility. We also characterize the time-series properties of the premium and consider economic trading strategies. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaniel, Ron; Ozoguz, Arzu; Starks, Laura</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Counterparty credit risk and the credit default swap market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arora, Navneet; Gandhi, Priyank; Longstaff, Francis A.
Counterparty credit risk has become one of the highest-profile risks facing participants in the financial markets. Despite this, relatively little is known about how counterparty credit risk is actually priced. We examine this issue using an extensive proprietary data set of contemporaneous CDS transaction prices and quotes by 14 different CDS dealers selling credit protection on the same underlying firm. This unique cross-sectional data set allows us to identify directly how dealers' credit risk affects the prices of these controversial credit derivatives. We find that counterparty credit risk is priced in the CDS market. The magnitude of the effect, however, is vanishingly small and is consistent with a market structure in which participants require collateralization of swap liabilities by counterparties. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arora, Navneet; Gandhi, Priyank; Longstaff, Francis A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Delegated trading and the speed of adjustment in security prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edelen, Roger M.; Kadlec, Gregory B.
Institutional trading arrangements often involve the portfolio manager delegating the task of trade execution to a separate division within the firm. We model the agency conflict that arises in this setting and show that optimal performance benchmarks often create an incentive to execute orders contrary to concurrent information flow. We hypothesize that aggregate contrarian trading resulting from widespread application of such benchmarks leads to delays in the assimilation of information in security prices. Using institutional trading data, we document the hypothesized contrarian trading pattern and relate the pattern to price-adjustment delays in the response of individual stocks to index futures returns. The evidence supports the assertion that delegated institutional trading contributes to these delays. (C) 2011 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Edelen, Roger M.; Kadlec, Gregory B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disclosure and agency conflict: Evidence from mutual fund commission bundling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edelen, Roger M.; Evans, Richard B.; Kadlec, Gregory B.
This study provides empirical evidence on the role of disclosure in resolving agency conflicts in delegated investment management. For certain expenditures, fund managers have alternative means of payment which differ greatly in their opacity: payments can be expensed (relatively transparent): or bundled with brokerage commissions (relatively opaque). We find that the return impact of opaque payments is significantly more negative than that of transparent payments. Moreover, we find a differential flow reaction that confirms the opacity of commission bundling. Collectively, our results demonstrate the importance of transparency in addressing agency costs of delegated investment management. (C) 2011 Elsevier By. All rights reserved.</description><author>Edelen, Roger M.; Evans, Richard B.; Kadlec, Gregory B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Difference in interim performance and risk taking with short-sale constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, Suleyman; Makarov, Dmitry
Absent much theory, empirical works often rely on the following informal reasoning when looking for evidence of a mutual fund tournament: If there is a tournament, interim winners have incentives to decrease their portfolio volatility as they attempt to protect their lead, while interim losers are expected to increase their volatility so as to catch up with winners. We consider a rational model of a mutual fund tournament in the presence of short-sale constraints and find the opposite: Interim winners choose more volatile portfolios in equilibrium than interim losers. Several empirical works present evidence consistent with our model. However, based on the above informal argument, they appear to conclude against the tournament behavior. We argue that this conclusion is unwarranted. We also demonstrate that tournament incentives lead to differences in interim performance for otherwise identical managers and that mid-year trading volume is inversely related to mid-year stock return. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Basak, Suleyman; Makarov, Dmitry</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous technological progress and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Xiaoji
I study the cross-sectional variation of stock returns and technological progress using a dynamic equilibrium model with production. Technological progress is endogenously driven by research and development (R&amp;D) investment and is composed of two parts. One part is devoted to product innovation; the other, to increasing the productivity of physical investment. The latter is embodied in new tangible capital. The model breaks the symmetry assumed in standard models between tangible and intangible capital, in which the accumulation processes of tangible and intangible capital stock do not affect each other. Qualitatively and, in many cases, quantitatively, the model explains well-documented empirical regularities. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Xiaoji</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Litigation risk, strategic disclosure and the underpricing of initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanley, Kathleen Weiss; Hoberg, Gerard
Using word content analysis on the time-series of IPO prospectuses, we show that issuers tradeoff underpricing and strategic disclosure as potential hedges against litigation risk. This tradeoff explains a significant fraction of the variation in prospectus revision patterns, IPO underpricing, the partial adjustment phenomenon, and litigation outcomes. We find that strong disclosure is an effective hedge against all types of lawsuits. Underpricing, however, is an effective hedge only against Section 11 lawsuits, those lawsuits which are most damaging to the underwriter. Underwriters who fail to adequately hedge litigation risk experience economically large penalties, including loss of market share. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanley, Kathleen Weiss; Hoberg, Gerard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Red and blue investing: Values and finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Kostovetsky, Leonard
Using data on the political contributions and stock holdings of U.S. investment managers, we find that mutual fund managers who make campaign donations to Democrats hold less of their portfolios (relative to non-donors or Republican donors) in companies that are deemed socially irresponsible (e.g., tobacco, guns, or defense firms or companies with bad employee relations or diversity records). Although explicit socially responsible investing (SRI) funds are more likely to be managed by Democratic managers, this result holds for non-SRI funds and after controlling for other fund and manager characteristics. The effect is more than one-half of the underweighting observed for SRI funds. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Kostovetsky, Leonard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When do high stock returns trigger equity issues?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alti, Aydogan; Sulaeman, Johan
One of the most prominent stylized facts in corporate finance is that equity issues tend to follow periods of high stock returns. We document that firms exhibit such timing behavior only in response to high returns that coincide with strong institutional investor demand. When not accompanied by institutional purchases, stock price increases have little impact on the likelihood of equity issuance. The results highlight the importance of market reception for the timing of equity issues. (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Alti, Aydogan; Sulaeman, Johan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional determinants of capital structure adjustment speeds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oeztekin, Oezde; Flannery, Mark J.
Many authors relate a firm's performance to legal and political features and the regulatory environment in which it operates. This article compares firms' capital structure adjustments across countries and investigates whether institutional differences help explain the variance in estimated adjustment speeds. We find that legal and financial traditions significantly correlate with firm adjustment speeds. More narrowly, institutional features also relate to adjustment speeds, consistent with the hypothesis that better institutions lower the transaction costs associated with adjusting a firm's leverage. Such associations between institutional arrangements and leverage adjustment speeds are consistent with the dynamic trade-off theory of capital structure choice. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oeztekin, Oezde; Flannery, Mark J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expropriation risk and technology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Opp, Marcus M.
This paper develops a unified framework to analyze the dynamics of firm investment in countries with poor legal enforcement. The firm's technology edge over the government generates endogenous property rights. Industry variation in the technology gap predicts a sectoral pecking-order of expropriations. Long-run investment distortions may be Pareto superior relative to persistent investment at the static optimum. The dynamics of investment and transfers depend on whether incentives (backloading) or efficiency (frontloading) concerns dominate at the initial division of surplus. An increase in government efficiency may reduce its welfare. The model provides a technology-driven rationale for the widespread use of conglomerate structures in emerging market countries. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Opp, Marcus M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives to innovate and financial crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thakor, Anjan V.
In this paper I develop a model of a competitive financial system with unrestricted but costly entry and an endogenously determined number of competing financial institutions ("banks" for short). Banks can make standard loans on which plentiful historical data are available and unanimous agreement exists on default probabilities. Or banks can innovate and make new loans on which limited historical data are available, leading to possible disagreement over default probabilities. In equilibrium, banks make zero profits on standard loans and positive profits on innovative loans, which engenders innovation incentives for banks. But innovation brings with it the risk that investors could disagree with the bank that the loan is worthy of continued funding and hence could Withdraw funding at an interim stage, precipitating a financial crisis. The degree of innovation in the financial system is determined by this trade-off. Welfare implications of financial innovation and mechanisms to reduce the probability of crises are discussed. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Friends with money</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engelberg, Joseph; Gao, Pengjie; Parsons, Christopher A.
When banks and firms are connected through interpersonal linkages - such as their respective management having attended college or previously worked together interest rates are markedly reduced, comparable with single shifts in credit ratings. These rate concessions do not appear to reflect sweetheart deals. Subsequent firm performance, such as future credit ratings or stock returns, improves following a connected deal, suggesting that social networks lead to either better information flow or better monitoring. (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Engelberg, Joseph; Gao, Pengjie; Parsons, Christopher A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal clearing arrangements for financial trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koeppl, Thorsten; Monnet, Cyril; Temzelides, Ted
Clearinghouses support financial trades by keeping records of transactions and by providing liquidity through short-term credit that participants clear periodically. We study efficient clearing arrangements for exchanges, where traders must clear with a clearinghouse, and for over-the-counter (OTC) markets, where traders can clear bilaterally. When clearing is costly, it can be efficient to subsidize OTC clearing by charging a higher clearing price for transactions conducted on exchanges. The clearinghouse then operates across both markets. Since clearinghouses offer credit, intertemporal incentives are needed to ensure settlement. When liquidity costs increase, concerns about default lead to a tightening of liquidity provision. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koeppl, Thorsten; Monnet, Cyril; Temzelides, Ted</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CAPM for estimating the cost of equity capital: Interpreting the empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Guo, Re-Jin; Jagannathan, Ravi
We argue that the empirical evidence against the capital asset pricing model (CAPM) based on stock returns does not invalidate its use for estimating the cost of capital for projects in making capital budgeting decisions. Because stocks are backed not only by projects in place, but also by the options to modify current projects and undertake new ones, the expected returns on stocks need not satisfy the CAPM even when expected returns of projects do. We provide empirical support for our arguments by developing a method for estimating firms' project CAPM betas and project returns. Our findings justify the continued use of the CAPM by firms in spite of the mounting evidence against it based on the cross section of stock returns. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Guo, Re-Jin; Jagannathan, Ravi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavioral consistency in corporate finance: CEO personal and corporate leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cronqvist, Henrik; Makhija, Anil K.; Yonker, Scott E.
We find that firms behave consistently with how their CEOs behave personally in the context of leverage choices. Analyzing data on CEOs' leverage in their most recent primary home purchases, we find a positive, economically relevant, robust relation between corporate and personal leverage in the cross-section and when examining CEO turnovers. The results are consistent with an endogenous matching of CEOs to firms based on preferences, as well as with CEOs imprinting their personal preferences on the firms they manage, particularly when governance is weaker. Besides enhancing our understanding of the determinants of corporate capital structures, the broader contribution of the paper is to show that CEOs' personal behavior can, in part, explain corporate financial behavior of the firms they manage. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cronqvist, Henrik; Makhija, Anil K.; Yonker, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How much of the diversification discount can be explained by poor corporate governance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoechle, Daniel; Schmid, Markus; Walter, Ingo; Yermack, David
We investigate whether the diversification discount occurs partly as an artifact of poor corporate governance. In panel data models, we find that the discount narrows by 16% to 21% when we add governance variables as regression controls. We also estimate Heckman selection models that account for the endogeneity of diversification and dynamic panel generalized method of moments models that account for the endogeneity of both diversification and governance. We find that the diversification discount persists even with these controls for endogeneity. However, in selection models the discount disappears entirely when we introduce governance variables in the second stage, and in dynamic panel GMM models the discount narrows by 37% when we include governance variables. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hoechle, Daniel; Schmid, Markus; Walter, Ingo; Yermack, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural models and endogeneity in corporate finance: The link between managerial ownership and corporate performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coles, Jeffrey L.; Lemmon, Michael L.; Meschke, J. Felix
This paper presents a parsimonious, structural model that isolates primary economic determinants of the level and dispersion of managerial ownership, firm scale, and performance and the empirical associations among them. In particular, variation across firms and through time of estimated productivity parameters for physical assets and managerial input and corresponding variation in optimal compensation contract and firm size combine to deliver the well-known hump-shaped relation between Tobin's Q and managerial ownership. To assess the effectiveness of standard econometric approaches to the endogeneity problem, we apply those remedies to panel data generated from the model. The unfortunate conclusion is that, at least in the ownership-performance context, proxy variables, fixed effects, and instrumental variables do not generally provide reliable solutions to simultaneity bias. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coles, Jeffrey L.; Lemmon, Michael L.; Meschke, J. Felix</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust and delegation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Stephen; Goetzmann, William; Liang, Bing; Schwarz, Christopher
This paper studies operational risk in the hedge fund industry using due diligence reports. Many funds suffer from operational problems, including limited disclosure of legal and regulatory issues. We use direct evidence of inadequate or failed internal processes to derive a canonical correlation-based measure for operational risk consistent with the Basel definition. It controls for selection bias using an extension of Heckman's (1979) procedure. Operational risk increases the likelihood of subsequent poor performance and fund disappearance, but does not influence investors' return-chasing behavior. Our study emphasizes the importance of information verification in the context of financial intermediation. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Stephen; Goetzmann, William; Liang, Bing; Schwarz, Christopher</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry contagion in loan spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hertzel, Michael G.; Officer, Micah S.
Spreads on new and renegotiated corporate loans are significantly higher when the loan originates (or is renegotiated) in the two years surrounding bankruptcy filings by industry rivals. This industry-specific contagion is particularly severe in the middle of industry bankruptcy waves. Furthermore, this contagion in loan spreads is mitigated in concentrated industries, consistent with the hypothesis and evidence in Lang and Stulz (1992) that bankruptcy filings in concentrated industries can have positive consequences for rivals (increased market share and/or power). There is also some evidence that contagion affects non-spread terms in loan contracts. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hertzel, Michael G.; Officer, Micah S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is momentum really momentum?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Novy-Marx, Robert
Momentum is primarily driven by firms' performance 12 to seven months prior to portfolio formation, not by a tendency of rising and falling stocks to keep rising and falling. Strategies based on recent past performance generate positive returns but are less profitable than those based on intermediate horizon past performance, especially among the largest, most liquid stocks. These facts are not particular to the momentum observed in the cross section of US equities. Similar results hold for momentum strategies trading international equity indices, commodities, and currencies. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Novy-Marx, Robert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate bond liquidity before and after the onset of the subprime crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dick-Nielsen, Jens; Feldhutter, Peter; Lando, David
We analyze liquidity components of corporate bond spreads during 2005-2009 using a new robust illiquidity measure. The spread contribution from illiquidity increases dramatically with the onset of the subprime crisis. The increase is slow and persistent for investment grade bonds while the effect is stronger but more short-lived for speculative grade bonds. Bonds become less liquid when financial distress hits a lead underwriter and the liquidity of bonds issued by financial firms dries up under crises. During the subprime crisis, flight-to-quality is confined to AAA-rated bonds. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dick-Nielsen, Jens; Feldhutter, Peter; Lando, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seeking safety: The relation between CEO inside debt holdings and the riskiness of firm investment and financial policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cassell, Cory A.; Huang, Shawn X.; Sanchez, Juan Manuel; Stuart, Michael D.
CEO inside debt holdings (pension benefits and deferred compensation) are generally unsecured and unfunded liabilities of the firm. Because these characteristics of inside debt expose the CEO to default risk similar to that faced by outside creditors, theory predicts that CEOs with large inside debt holdings will display lower levels of risk-seeking behavior (Jensen and Meckling, 1976). Consistent with the theoretical predictions, we find a negative association between CEO inside debt holdings and the volatility of future firm stock returns, R&amp;D expenditures, and financial leverage, and a positive association between CEO inside debt holdings and the extent of diversification and asset liquidity. Collectively, our results provide empirical evidence suggesting that CEOs with large inside debt holdings prefer investment and financial policies that are less risky. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cassell, Cory A.; Huang, Shawn X.; Sanchez, Juan Manuel; Stuart, Michael D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do arbitrageurs amplify economic shocks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Kubik, Jeffrey D.; Fishman, Tal
We test the hypothesis that arbitrageurs amplify economic shocks in equity markets. The ability of speculators to hold short positions depends on asset values. Shorts are often reduced following good news about a stock. Therefore, the prices of highly shorted stocks are excessively sensitive to shocks compared with stocks with little short interest. We confirm this hypothesis using several empirical strategies including two quasi-experiments. In particular, we establish that the price of highly shorted stocks overshoots after good earnings news due to short covering compared with other stocks. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Kubik, Jeffrey D.; Fishman, Tal</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Longevity risk, retirement savings, and financial innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cocco, Joao F.; Gomes, Francisco J.
Over the last couple of decades unprecedented increases in life expectancy have raised important concerns for retirement savings. We solve a life-cycle model with longevity risk, which can be hedged through endogenous saving and retirement decisions. We investigate the benefits of financial assets designed to hedge the shocks to survival probabilities. When longevity risk is calibrated to match forward-looking projections, those benefits are substantial. This lends support to the idea that such hedging should be pursued by defined benefit pension plans on behalf of their beneficiaries. Finally, we draw implications for optimal security design. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cocco, Joao F.; Gomes, Francisco J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bargaining power and industry dependence in mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahern, Kenneth R.
In contrast to the widely held belief that targets capture the lion's share of merger gains, I show that the average dollar gains to targets are only modestly more than the dollar gains to acquirers. To help explain the variation in merger outcomes, I present empirical evidence in support of a new hypothesis that a target's relative scarcity (proxied by its market power) and product market dependence (proxied by customer-supplier relations) help to explain its share of the total merger gains. These results provide new evidence for an unexplored role of product markets on bargaining outcomes in mergers. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahern, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy spillover effects on strategic alliance partners</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boone, Audra L.; Ivanov, Vladimir I.
This paper examines whether a party to a strategic alliance or joint venture suffers from spillover effects when the other partner files for bankruptcy. We find that the non-bankrupt strategic alliance partners, on average, experience a negative stock price reaction around their partner firm's bankruptcy filing announcement. This negative effect is strongest for longer partnerships and those with higher returns at the announcement of the initial alliance formation. Furthermore, horizontal alliance firms in declining industries have lower returns, indicating that industry conditions can exacerbate expected problems for the non-bankrupt firm. Non-bankrupt partners also experience drops in profit margins and investment levels in the subsequent two years with the worst performance concentrated among the longer-term agreements. There is very little impact on the returns or performance for joint venture partners, which suggests that these agreements are more insulating for the partner firm. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boone, Audra L.; Ivanov, Vladimir I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge funds as liquidity providers: Evidence from the Lehman bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aragon, George O.; Strahan, Philip E.
Hedge funds using Lehman as prime broker faced a decline in funding liquidity after the September 15, 2008 bankruptcy. We find that stocks held by these Lehman-connected funds experienced greater declines in market liquidity following the bankruptcy than other stocks; the effect was larger for ex ante illiquid stocks and persisted into the beginning of 2009. We find no similar effects surrounding the Bear Stearns failure, suggesting that disruptions surrounding bankruptcy explain the liquidity effects. We conclude that shocks to traders' funding liquidity reduce the market liquidity of the assets that they trade. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aragon, George O.; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous liquidity in credit derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qiu, Jiaping; Yu, Fan
We study study the determination of liquidity provision in the single-name credit default swap (CDS) market as measured by the number of distinct dealers providing quotes. We find that liquidity is concentrated among large obligors and those near the investment-grade/speculative-grade cutoff. Consistent with endogenous liquidity provision by informed financial institutions, more liquidity is associated with obligors for which there is a greater information flow from the CDS market to the stock market ahead of major credit events. Furthermore, the level of information heterogeneity plays an important role in how liquidity provision responds to transaction demand and how liquidity is priced into the CDS premium. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Qiu, Jiaping; Yu, Fan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash flows and leverage adjustments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faulkender, Michael; Flannery, Mark J.; Hankins, Kristine Watson; Smith, Jason M.
Recent research has emphasized the impact of transaction costs on firm leverage adjustments. We recognize that cashflow realizations can provide opportunities to adjust leverage at relatively low marginal cost. We find that a firm's cashflow features affect not only the leverage target, but also the speed of adjustment toward that target. Heterogeneity in adjustment speeds is driven by an economically meaningful concept: adjustment costs. Accounting for this fact produces adjustment speeds that are significantly faster than previously estimated in the literature. We also analyze how both financial constraints and market timing variables affect adjustments toward a leverage target. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faulkender, Michael; Flannery, Mark J.; Hankins, Kristine Watson; Smith, Jason M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The seeds of a crisis: A theory of bank liquidity and risk taking over the business cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral; Naqvi, Hassan
We examine how the banking sector could ignite the formation of asset price bubbles when there is access to abundant liquidity. Inside banks, to induce effort, loan officers are compensated based on the volume of loans. Volume-based compensation also induces greater risk taking; however, due to lack of commitment, loan officers are penalized ex post only if banks suffer a high enough liquidity shortfall. Outside banks, when there is heightened macroeconomic risk, investors reduce direct investment and hold more bank deposits. This 'flight to quality' leaves banks flush with liquidity, lowering the sensitivity of bankers' payoffs to downside risks and inducing excessive credit volume and asset price bubbles. The seeds of a crisis are thus sown. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral; Naqvi, Hassan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of inflation expectations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernov, Mikhail; Mueller, Philippe
We use information in the term structure of survey-based forecasts of inflation to estimate a factor hidden in the nominal yield curve. We construct a model that accommodates forecasts over multiple horizons from multiple surveys and Treasury real and nominal yields by allowing for differences between risk-neutral, subjective, and objective probability measures. We establish that model-based inflation expectations are driven by inflation, output, and one latent factor. We find that this factor affects inflation expectations at all horizons but has almost no effect on the nominal yields; that is, the latent factor is hidden. We show that this hidden factor is not related to either current and past inflation or the standard set of macro variables studied in the literature. Consistent with the theoretical property of a hidden factor, our model outperforms a standard macro-finance model in its forecasting of inflation and yields. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chernov, Mikhail; Mueller, Philippe</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are banks happy when managers go long? The information content of managers' vested option holdings for loan pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dezso, Cristian L.; Ross, David Gaddis
While traditional finance theory holds that managers with option-laden incentive contracts may favor equity at the expense of debt, a risk-averse manager may be more likely to retain vested in-the-money options if the manager has private information that the firm's risk-adjusted performance will be better. It follows that vested option holdings should be positively associated with credit quality. In support of this, we find that vested option holdings have a strong negative association with loan pricing, especially for informationally sensitive loans, and also predict higher cash flows and credit ratings, a greater distance to default, and lower equity volatility. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dezso, Cristian L.; Ross, David Gaddis</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Profitability and capital structure: Evidence from import penetration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Jin
Firms experiencing increases in import competition significantly reduce their leverage ratios by issuing equity and selling assets to repay debt. Using import tariffs and foreign exchange rates as instrumental variables for import penetration, I show that these results are not manifestations of endogenous relations between import competition and leverage. The results are consistent with traditional trade-off models of capital structure that predict a positive relation between book leverage and expected future profitability. Further evidence suggests that import competition affects leverage through changes in the trade-off between the tax benefits of debt and the costs of financial distress. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xu, Jin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do option markets undo restrictions on short sales? Evidence from the 2008 short-sale ban</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grundy, Bruce D.; Lim, Bryan; Verwijmeren, Patrick
The effectiveness of any sanction depends on the costs of avoiding its restrictions. We examine whether bearish option strategies were substitutes for short sales during the September 2008 short-sale ban. We find a significant diminution in option volumes and a significant increase in option bid-ask spreads for banned stock relative to unbanned stock during the ban period. Apparent violations of the put-call parity bound became significantly more frequent for banned stocks during the ban period. We conclude that the ban acted as an effective restriction on trading in options. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grundy, Bruce D.; Lim, Bryan; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information effect of entry into credit ratings market: The case of insurers' ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doherty, Neil A.; Kartasheva, Anastasia V.; Phillips, Richard D.
The paper analyzes the effect of competition between credit rating agencies (CRAs) on the information content of ratings. We show that a monopolistic CRA pools sellers into multiple rating classes and has partial market coverage. This provides an opportunity for market entry. The entrant designs a rating scale distinct from that of the incumbent. It targets higher-than-average companies in each rating grade of the incumbent's rating scale and employs more stringent rating standards. We use Standard and Poor's (S&amp;P) entry into the market for insurance ratings previously covered by a monopolist, A.M. Best, to empirically test the impact of entry on the information content of ratings. The empirical analysis reveals that S&amp;P required higher standards to assign a rating similar to the one assigned by A.M. Best and that higher-than-average quality insurers in each rating category of AM. Best chose to receive a second rating from S&amp;P. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doherty, Neil A.; Kartasheva, Anastasia V.; Phillips, Richard D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The option to stock volume ratio and future returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Travis L.; So, Eric C.
We examine the information content of option and equity volumes when trade direction is unobserved. In a multimarket asymmetric information model, equity short-sale costs result in a negative relation between relative option volume and future firm value. In our empirical tests, firms in the lowest decile of the option to stock volume ratio (O/S) outperform the highest decile by 0.34% per week (19.3% annualized). Our model and empirics both indicate that O/S is a stronger signal when short-sale costs are high or option leverage is low. O/S also predicts future firm-specific earnings news, consistent with O/S reflecting private information. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Johnson, Travis L.; So, Eric C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The sources of value destruction in acquisitions by entrenched managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Powell, Ronan
Prior work has established that entrenched managers make value-decreasing acquisitions. In this study, we determine how they destroy that value. Overall, we find that value destruction by entrenched managers comes from a combination of factors. First, they disproportionately avoid private targets, which have been shown to be generally associated with value creation. Second, when they do buy private targets or public targets with blockholders, they tend not to use all-equity offers, which has the effect of avoiding the transfer of a valuable blockholder to the bidder. We further test whether entrenched managers simply overpay for good targets or choose targets with lower synergies. We find that while they overpay, they also choose low synergy targets in the first place, as shown by combined announcement returns and post-merger operating performance. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Powell, Ronan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial risk, investment, and innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caggese, Andrea
I estimate the effect of uncertainty on risky innovation using a panel of 11,417 manufacturing firms. I find that an increase in uncertainty has a large negative effect on the risky innovation of entrepreneurial firms, while it does not have any significant impact on other firms. This negative effect is stronger for the less diversified entrepreneurial firms in the sample. The estimation results are consistent with the innovation dynamics generated in a model in which entrepreneurs are risk averse and cannot diversify the risk of their business. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caggese, Andrea</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal capital structure, bargaining, and the supplier market structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chu, Yongqiang
This paper studies the relationship between firm leverage and supplier market structure. We find that firm leverage decreases with the degree of competition between suppliers. Specifically, leverage decreases with the elasticity of substitution between suppliers. Leverage also decreases with the number of suppliers when the elasticity of substitution is high, and increases with the number of suppliers when the elasticity is low. We also provide empirical evidence that is consistent with the model predictions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chu, Yongqiang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Doing battle with short sellers: The conflicted role of blockholders in bear raids</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khanna, Naveen; Mathews, Richmond D.
If short sellers can destroy firm value by manipulating prices down, an informed blockholder has a powerful natural incentive to protect the value of his stake by trading against them. However, he also has a potentially conflicting incentive to use his information to generate trading profits. We show that a speculator can exploit this conflict and force the blockholder to buy a disproportionately large amount to prevent value destruction. This is costly for the blockholder because the trades must sometimes be executed at inflated prices. Given reasonable constraints on short sellers, a sufficiently large blockholder will have the incentive to absorb these losses and prevent a bear raid. However, conditions exist under which outside intervention may be warranted. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khanna, Naveen; Mathews, Richmond D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of reference point prices on mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Malcolm; Pan, Xin; Wurgler, Jeffrey
Prior stock price peaks of targets affect several aspects of merger and acquisition activity. Offer prices are biased toward recent peak prices although they are economically unremarkable. An offer's probability of acceptance jumps discontinuously when it exceeds a peak price. Conversely, bidder shareholders react more negatively as the offer price is influenced upward toward a peak. Merger waves occur when high returns on the market and likely targets make it easier for bidders to offer a peak price. Parties thus appear to use recent peaks as reference points or anchors to simplify the complex tasks of valuation and negotiation. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baker, Malcolm; Pan, Xin; Wurgler, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public market staging: The timing of capital infusions in newly public firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hertzel, Michael G.; Huson, Mark R.; Parrino, Robert
We examine financing activities of newly public firms for evidence on capital staging in the public equity market. Staging (sequential financing) can increase issuance costs but can limit costs associated with overinvestment. We find evidence consistent with the hypothesis that staging is employed to help control the overinvestment problem in public firms. Initial public offering (IPO) proceeds, relative to external financing requirements, are smaller for firms with more intangible assets and more research and development (R&amp;D)-intensive firms. Asset intangibility and R&amp;D intensity are also both negatively related to the length of time from a firm's IPO to its first post-IPO capital infusion. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hertzel, Michael G.; Huson, Mark R.; Parrino, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization without adverse selection: The case of CLOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benmelech, Efraim; Dlugosz, Jennifer; Ivashina, Victoria
In this paper, we investigate whether securitization was associated with risky lending in the corporate loan market by examining the performance of individual loans held by collateralized loan obligations. We employ two different data sets that identify loan holdings for a large set of CLOs and find that adverse selection problems in corporate loan securitizations are less severe than commonly believed. Using a battery of performance tests, we find that loans securitized before 2005 performed no worse than comparable unsecuritized loans originated by the same bank. Even loans originated by the bank that acts as the CLO underwriter do not show under-performance relative to the rest of the CLO portfolio. While some evidence exists of under-performance for securitized loans originated between 2005 and 2007, it is not consistent across samples, performance measures, and horizons. Overall, we argue that the securitization of corporate loans is fundamentally different from securitization of other assets classes because securitized loans are fractions of syndicated loans. Therefore, mechanisms used to align incentives in a lending syndicate are likely to reduce adverse selection in the choice of CLO collateral. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Benmelech, Efraim; Dlugosz, Jennifer; Ivashina, Victoria</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systematic risk and the cross section of hedge fund returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Caglayan, Mustafa Onur
This paper investigates the extent to which market risk, residual risk, and tail risk explain the cross-sectional dispersion in hedge fund returns. The paper introduces a comprehensive measure of systematic risk (SR) for individual hedge funds by breaking up total risk into systematic and fund-specific or residual risk components. Contrary to the popular understanding that hedge funds are market neutral, we find that systematic risk is a highly significant factor explaining the dispersion of cross-sectional returns while at the same time measures of residual risk and tail risk seem to have little explanatory power. Funds in the highest SR quintile generate 6% more average annual returns compared with funds in the lowest SR quintile. After controlling for a large set of fund characteristics and risk factors, systematic risk remains positive and highly significant, whereas the relation between residual risk and future fund returns continues to be insignificant. Hence, systematic risk is a powerful determinant of the cross-sectional differences in hedge fund returns. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Caglayan, Mustafa Onur</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political geography and stock returns: The value and risk implications of proximity to political power</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Chansog; Pantzalis, Christos; Park, Jung Chul
We show that political geography has a pervasive effect on the cross-section of stock returns. We collect election results over a 40-year period and use a political alignment index (PAI) of each state's leading politicians with the ruling (presidential) party to proxy for local firms' proximity to political power. Firms whose headquarters are located in high PAI states outperform those located in low PAI states, both in terms of raw returns, and on a risk-adjusted basis. Overall, although we cannot rule out indirect political connectedness advantages as an explanation of the PAI effect, our results are consistent with the notion that proximity to political power has stock return implications because it reflects firms' exposure to policy risk. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Chansog; Pantzalis, Christos; Park, Jung Chul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A unified model of entrepreneurship dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Chong; Wang, Neng; Yang, Jinqiang
We develop an incomplete-markets q-theoretic model to study entrepreneurship dynamics. Precautionary motive, borrowing constraints, and capital illiquidity lead to underinvestment, conservative debt use, under-consumption, and less risky portfolio allocation. The endogenous liquid wealth-illiquid capital ratio w measures time-varying financial constraint. The option to accumulate wealth before entry is critical for entrepreneurship. Flexible exit option is important for risk management purposes. Investment increases and the private marginal value of liquidity decreases as w decreases and exit becomes more likely, contrary to predictions of standard financial constraint models. We show that the idiosyncratic risk premium is quantitatively significant, especially for low w. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Chong; Wang, Neng; Yang, Jinqiang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing conditional factor models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Kristensen, Dennis
Using nonparametric techniques, we develop a methodology for estimating and testing conditional alphas and betas and long-run alphas and betas, which are the averages of conditional alphas and betas, respectively, across time. The estimators and tests can be implemented for a single asset or jointly across portfolios. The traditional Gibbons, Ross, and Shanken (1989) test arises as a special case of no time variation in the alphas and factor loadings and homoskedasticity. As applications of the methodology, we estimate conditional CAPM and multifactor models on book-to-market and momentum decile portfolios. We reject the null that long-run alphas are equal to zero even though there is substantial variation in the conditional factor loadings of these portfolios. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Kristensen, Dennis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictive regressions with time-varying coefficients</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dangl, Thomas; Hailing, Michael
We evaluate predictive regressions that explicitly consider the time-variation of coefficients in a comprehensive Bayesian framework. For monthly returns of the S&amp;P 500 index, we demonstrate statistical as well as economic evidence of out-of-sample predictability: relative to an investor using the historic mean, an investor using our methodology could have earned consistently positive utility gains (between 1.8% and 5.8% per year over different time periods). We also find that predictive models with constant coefficients are dominated by models with time-varying coefficients. Finally, we show a strong link between out-of-sample predictability and the business cycle. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dangl, Thomas; Hailing, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial finance, credit cards, and race</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chatterji, Aaron K.; Seamans, Robert C.
This paper examines the impact of financial deregulation on entrepreneurship. We assess the impact of credit card deregulation on transitions into self-employment using state-level removal of credit card interest rate ceilings following the US Supreme Court's 1978 Marquette decision as a quasi-natural experiment. We find that credit card deregulation increases the probability of entrepreneurial entry, with a particularly strong effect for black entrepreneurs. We demonstrate that these effects are magnified in states with a history of racial discrimination and link the results to discrimination-based barriers to entry. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chatterji, Aaron K.; Seamans, Robert C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The politics of government investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duchin, Ran; Sosyura, Denis
This paper investigates the relation between corporate political connections and government investment. We study various forms of political influence, ranging from passive connections between firms and politicians, such as those based on politicians' voting districts, to active forms, such as lobbying, campaign contributions, and employment of connected directors. Using hand-collected data on firm applications for capital under the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP), we find that politically connected firms are more likely to be funded, controlling for other characteristics. Yet investments in politically connected firms underperform those in unconnected firms. Overall, we show that connections between firms and regulators are associated with distortions in investment efficiency. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duchin, Ran; Sosyura, Denis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>'Deja vol': Predictive regressions for aggregate stock market volatility using macroeconomic variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paye, Bradley S.
Aggregate stock return volatility is both persistent and countercyclical. This paper tests whether it is possible to improve volatility forecasts at monthly and quarterly horizons by conditioning on additional macroeconomic variables. I find that several variables related to macroeconomic uncertainty, time-varying expected stock returns, and credit conditions Granger cause volatility. It is more difficult to find evidence that forecasts exploiting macroeconomic variables outperform a univariate benchmark out-of-sample. The most successful approaches involve simple combinations of individual forecasts. Predictive power associated with macroeconomic variables appears to concentrate around the onset of recessions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Paye, Bradley S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pinning in the S&amp;P 500 futures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golez, Benjamin; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten
We show that Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P) 500 futures are pulled toward the at-the-money strike price on days when serial options on the S&amp;P 500 futures expire (pinning) and are pushed away from the cost-of-carry adjusted at-the-money strike price right before the expiration of options on the S&amp;P 500 index (anti-cross-pinning). These effects are driven by the interplay of market makers' rebalancing of delta hedges due to the time decay of those hedges as well as in response to reselling (and early exercise) of in-the-money options by individual investors. The associated shift in notional futures value is at least $115 million per expiration day. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Golez, Benjamin; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multifactor models and their consistency with the ICAPM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maio, Paulo; Santa-Clara, Pedro
Can any multifactor model be interpreted as a variant of the Intertemporal CAPM (ICAPM)? The ICAPM places restrictions on time-series and cross-sectional behavior of state variables and factors. If a state variable forecasts positive (negative) changes in investment opportunities in time-series regressions, its innovation should earn a positive (negative) risk price in the cross-sectional test of the respective multifactor model. Second, the market (covariance) price of risk must be economically plausible as an estimate of the coefficient of relative risk aversion (RRA). We apply our ICAPM criteria to eight popular multifactor models and the results show that most models do not satisfy the ICAPM restrictions. Specifically, the "hedging" risk prices have the wrong sign and the estimates of RRA are not economically plausible. Overall, the Fama and French (1993) and Carhart (1997) models perform the best in consistently meeting the ICAPM restrictions. The remaining models, which represent some of the most relevant examples presented in the empirical asset pricing literature, can still empirically explain the size, value, and momentum anomalies, but they are generally inconsistent with the ICAPM. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maio, Paulo; Santa-Clara, Pedro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technical trading revisited: False discoveries, persistence tests, and transaction costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bajgrowicz, Pierre; Scaillet, Olivier
We revisit the apparent historical success of technical trading rules on daily prices of the Dow Jones Industrial Average index from 1897 to 2011, and we use the false discovery rate (FDR) as a new approach to data snooping. The advantage of the FDR over existing methods is that it selects more outperforming rules, which allows diversifying against model uncertainty. Persistence tests show that, even with the more powerful FDR technique, an investor would never have been able to select ex ante the future best-performing rules. Moreover, even in-sample, the performance is completely offset by the introduction of low transaction costs. Overall, our results seriously call into question the economic value of technical trading rules that has been reported for early periods. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bajgrowicz, Pierre; Scaillet, Olivier</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Geographic dispersion and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia, Diego; Norli, Oyvind
This paper shows that stocks of truly local firms have returns that exceed the return on stocks of geographically dispersed firms by 70 basis points per month. By extracting state name counts from annual reports filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) on Form 10-K, we distinguish firms with business operations in only a few states from firms with operations in multiple states. Our findings are consistent with the view that lower investor recognition for local firms results in higher stock returns to compensate investors for insufficient diversification. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Garcia, Diego; Norli, Oyvind</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank valuation and accounting discretion during a financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huizinga, Harry; Laeven, Luc
This paper shows that banks overstate the value of distressed assets and their regulatory capital during the US mortgage crisis. Real estate-related assets are overvalued in banks' balance sheets, especially those of bigger banks, compared to the market value of these assets. Banks with large exposure to mortgage-backed securities also provision less for bad loans. Furthermore, distressed banks use discretion over the classification of mortgage-backed securities to inflate their books. Our results indicate that banks' balance sheets offer a distorted view of the financial health of the banks and provide suggestive evidence of regulatory forbearance and noncompliance with accounting rules. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huizinga, Harry; Laeven, Luc</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock returns after major price shocks: The impact of information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savor, Pavel G.
This paper focuses on stocks that experience major price changes. Using analyst reports as a proxy. I find that price events accompanied by information are followed by drift, while no-information ones result in reversals. One interpretation of these results is that investors underreact to news about fundamentals and overreact to other shocks that move stock prices. Consistent with this hypothesis, information-based price changes are more strongly correlated with future earnings surprises than no-information ones. Furthermore, drift exists only when the direction of the price move and of the change in analyst recommendations have the same sign. Finally, the ratio of no-information to information-based price shocks is strongly correlated with aggregate implied volatility and also forecasts momentum returns. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Savor, Pavel G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency momentum strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkhoff, Lukas; Sarno, Lucio; Schmeling, Maik; Schrimpf, Andreas
We provide a broad empirical investigation of momentum strategies in the foreign exchange market. We find a significant cross-sectional spread in excess returns of up to 10% per annum (p.a.) between past winner and loser currencies. This spread in excess returns is not explained by traditional risk factors, it is partially explained by transaction costs and shows behavior consistent with investor under- and overreaction. Moreover, cross-sectional currency momentum has very different properties from the widely studied carry trade and is not highly correlated with returns of benchmark technical trading rules. However, there seem to be very effective limits to arbitrage that prevent momentum returns from being easily exploitable in currency markets. (C) 2012 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Menkhoff, Lukas; Sarno, Lucio; Schmeling, Maik; Schrimpf, Andreas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock option vesting conditions, CEO turnover, and myopic investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Laux, Volker
Corporations have been criticized for providing executives with excessive incentives to focus on short-term performance. This paper shows that investment in short-term projects has beneficial effects in that it provides early feedback about Chief Executive Officer (CEO) talent, which leads to more efficient replacement decisions. Due to the threat of CEO turnover, the optimal design of stock option vesting conditions in executive compensation is more subtle than conventional views suggest. For example, I show that long vesting periods can backfire and induce excessive short-term investments. The study generates new empirical predictions regarding the determinants and impacts of stock option vesting terms in optimal contracting. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Laux, Volker</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market for new issues of municipal bonds: The roles of transparency and limited access to retail investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, Paul
I examine how transparency and interdealer trading affects prices investors pay in municipal bond offerings. Real-time trade reporting for municipal bonds started January 31, 2005. The dispersion of purchase prices fell sharply at that time. There was little impact on average markups for most trades, but they increased for purchases of more than $100,000. Bonds often pass through a series of dealers before being placed with a buy-and-hold investor. As the interdealer trades progress, trade sizes decline and trade prices rise. Markups on investor purchases increase with the amount of interdealer trading before the trade. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schultz, Paul</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic jump intensities and risk premiums: Evidence from S&amp;P500 returns and options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Ornthanalai, Chayawat
We build a new class of discrete-time models that are relatively easy to estimate using returns and/or options. The distribution of returns is driven by two factors: dynamic volatility and dynamic jump intensity. Each factor has its own risk premium. The models significantly outperform standard models without jumps when estimated on S&amp;P500 returns. We find very strong support for time-varying jump intensities. Compared to the risk premium on dynamic volatility, the risk premium on the dynamic jump intensity has a much larger impact on option prices. We confirm these findings using joint estimation on returns and large option samples. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Ornthanalai, Chayawat</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Illiquidity or credit deterioration: A study of liquidity in the US corporate bond market during financial crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friewald, Nils; Jankowitsch, Rainer; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.
We investigate whether liquidity is an important price factor in the US corporate bond market. In particular, we focus on whether liquidity effects are more pronounced in periods of financial crises, especially for bonds with high credit risk, using a unique data set covering more than 20,000 bonds, between October 2004 and December 2008. We employ a wide range of liquidity measures and find that liquidity effects account for approximately 14% of the explained market-wide corporate yield spread changes. We conclude that the economic impact of the liquidity measures is significantly larger in periods of crisis, and for speculative grade bonds. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V, All rights reserved.</description><author>Friewald, Nils; Jankowitsch, Rainer; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing of commercial real estate securities during the 2007-2009 financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Driessen, Joost; Van Hemert, Otto
We study the relative and absolute pricing of CMBX contracts (commercial real estate derivatives) during the recent financial crisis. Using a structural CMBX pricing model, we find little systematic mispricing relative to REIT equity and options. We do find short-term deviations from this relative pricing relationship that are statistically and economically significant. In particular, the CMBX market temporarily overreacts to news announcements. We provide evidence that this temporary mispricing is caused by price pressure due to hedging activities. Finally, an absolute pricing analysis provides no substantial evidence that CMBX contracts traded at fire sale levels during the crisis. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Driessen, Joost; Van Hemert, Otto</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vertical integration to avoid contracting with potential competitors: Evidence from bankers' banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brickley, James A.; Linck, James S.; Smith, Clifford W.
We examine a vertical integration decision within the commercial banking industry. During the last quarter of the 20th century, some community banks reduced their traditional reliance on correspondent banks for upstream products and services by joining bankers' banks, a form of business cooperative. Research on vertical integration focuses primarily on firm-specific investment, market power, and government regulation. However, this case is difficult to explain in terms of these standard vertical integration motives. Our evidence suggests that bankers' banks are a response to technological change and deregulation that results in increased costs faced by community banks in dealing with correspondent banks as both suppliers and potential competitors. For instance, loan participations require sharing proprietary information about major loan customers, something a community bank would not want to provide to a potential competitor. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brickley, James A.; Linck, James S.; Smith, Clifford W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payout yield, risk, and mispricing: A Bayesian analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shanken, Jay; Tamayo, Ane
We develop a simple parametric model in which hypotheses about predictability, mispricing, and the risk-return tradeoff can be evaluated simultaneously, while allowing for time variation in both risk and expected return. Most of the return predictability based on aggregate payout yield is unrelated to market risk. We consider a range of Bayesian prior beliefs about the risk-return tradeoff and the extent to which predictability is driven by mispricing. The impact of these beliefs on an investor's certainty-equivalent return when choosing between a market index and riskless T-bills is economically significant, in both ex ante and out-of-sample analyses. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shanken, Jay; Tamayo, Ane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting fraud by investment managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimmock, Stephen G.; Gerken, William C.
We test the predictability of investment fraud using a panel of mandatory disclosures filed with the SEC. We find that disclosures related to past regulatory and legal violations, conflicts of interest, and monitoring have significant power to predict fraud. Avoiding the 5% of firms with the highest ex ante predicted fraud risk would allow an investor to avoid 29% of fraud cases and over 40% of the total dollar losses from fraud. We find no evidence that investors receive compensation for fraud risk through superior performance or lower fees. We examine the barriers to implementing fraud prediction models and suggest changes to the SEC's data access policies that could benefit investors. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dimmock, Stephen G.; Gerken, William C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock options and managerial incentives for risk taking: Evidence from FAS 123R</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hayes, Rachel M.; Lemmon, Michael; Qiu, Mingming
We provide new evidence on the relation between option-based compensation and risk-taking behavior by exploiting the change in the accounting treatment of stock options following the adoption of FAS 123R in 2005. The implementation of FAS 123R represents an exogenous change in the accounting benefits of stock options that has no effect on the economic costs and benefits of options for providing managerial incentives. Our results do not support the view that the convexity inherent in option-based compensation is used to reduce risk-related agency problems between managers and shareholders. We show that all firms dramatically reduce their usage of stock options (convexity) after the adoption of FAS 123R and that the decline in option use is strongly associated with a proxy for accounting costs. Little evidence exists that the decline in option usage following the accounting change results in less risky investment and financial policies. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hayes, Rachel M.; Lemmon, Michael; Qiu, Mingming</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variance bounds on the permanent and transitory components of stochastic discount factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Chabi-Yo, Fousseni
In this paper, we develop lower bounds on the variance of the permanent component and the transitory component, and on the variance of the ratio of the permanent to the transitory components of SDFs. Exactly solved eigenfunction problems are then used to study the empirical attributes of asset pricing models that incorporate long-run risk, external habit persistence, and rare disasters. Specific quantitative implications are developed for the variance of the permanent and the transitory components, the return behavior of the long-term bond, and the comovement between the transitory and the permanent components of SDFs. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Chabi-Yo, Fousseni</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>U.S. stock market crash risk, 1926-2010</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, David S.
This paper examines how well alternate time-changed Levy processes capture stochastic volatility and the substantial outliers observed in U.S. stock market returns over the past 85 years. The autocorrelation of daily stock market returns varies substantially over time, necessitating an additional state variable when analyzing historical data. I estimate various one- and two-factor stochastic volatility/Levy models with time-varying autocorrelation via extensions of the Bates (2006) methodology that provide filtered daily estimates of volatility and autocorrelation. The paper explores option pricing implications, including for the Volatility Index (VIX) during the recent financial crisis. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bates, David S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did securitization affect the cost of corporate debt?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nadauld, Taylor D.; Weisbach, Michael S.
This paper investigates whether the securitization of corporate bank loan facilities had an impact on the price of corporate debt. Our results suggest that loan facilities that are subsequently securitized are associated with a 17 basis point lower spread than that of facilities that are not subsequently securitized. We consider facility characteristics that are associated with the likelihood of securitization and estimate the extent to which these characteristics are related to spreads. We document that Term Loan B facilities, facilities of B-rated firms, and facilities originated by banks that originate CLOs are securitized more frequently than other facilities. Spreads on facilities estimated to be more likely to be subsequently securitized have lower spreads than otherwise similar facilities. The results are consistent with the view that securitization caused a reduction in the cost of capital. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nadauld, Taylor D.; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual political contributions and firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ovtchinnikov, Alexei V.; Pantaleoni, Eva
We present evidence that individuals make political contributions strategically by targeting politicians with power to affect their economic well-being. Individuals in Congressional districts with greater industry clustering choose to support politicians with jurisdiction over the industry. Importantly, individual political contributions are associated with improvements in operating performance of firms in industry clusters. The relation between contributions and firm performance is strongest for poorly performing firms, firms closer to financial distress, and for contributions in close elections. The results imply that individual political contributions are valuable to firms, especially during bad economic times. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ovtchinnikov, Alexei V.; Pantaleoni, Eva</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How (not) to pay for advice: A framework for consumer financial protection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, Roman; Ottaviani, Marco
This paper investigates the determinants of the compensation structure for brokers who advise customers regarding the suitability of financial products. Our model explains why brokers are commonly compensated indirectly through contingent commissions paid by product providers, even though this compensation structure could lead to biased advice. When customers are wary of the adviser's incentives, contingent commissions can be an effective incentive tool to induce the adviser to learn which specialized product is most suitable for the specific needs of customers. If, instead, customers naively believe they receive unbiased advice, high product prices and correspondingly high commissions become a tool of exploitation. Policy intervention that mandates disclosure of commissions can protect naive consumers and increase welfare. However, prohibiting or capping commissions could have the unintended consequence of stifling the adviser's incentive to acquire information. More vigorous competition benefits consumers and reduces exploitation, but firms have limited incentives to educate naive customers. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Inderst, Roman; Ottaviani, Marco</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do controlling shareholders' expropriation incentives imply a link between corporate governance and firm value? Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, Kee-Hong; Baek, Jae-Seung; Kang, Jun-Koo; Liu, Wei-Lin
We develop and test a model that investigates how controlling shareholders' expropriation incentives affect firm values during crisis and subsequent recovery periods. Consistent with the prediction of our model, we find that, during the 1997 Asian financial crisis, Asian firms with weaker corporate governance experience a larger drop in their share values but, during the post-crisis recovery period, such firms experience a larger rebound in their share values. We also find consistent evidence for Latin American firms during the 2001 Argentine economic crisis. Our results support the view that controlling shareholders' expropriation incentives imply a link between corporate governance and firm value. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bae, Kee-Hong; Baek, Jae-Seung; Kang, Jun-Koo; Liu, Wei-Lin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A darker side to decentralized banks: Market power and credit rationing in SME lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Canales, Rodrigo; Nanda, Ramana
We use loan-level data to study how the organizational structure of banks impacts small business lending. We find that decentralized banks-where branch managers have greater autonomy over lending decisions-give larger loans to small firms and those with "soft information." However, decentralized banks are also more responsive to their own competitive environment. They are more likely to expand credit when faced with competition but also cherry pick customers and restrict credit when they have market power. This "darker side" to decentralized banks in concentrated markets highlights that the level of local banking competition is key to determining which organizational structure provides better lending terms for small businesses. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Canales, Rodrigo; Nanda, Ramana</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The credit crisis around the globe: Why did some banks perform better?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beltratti, Andrea; Stulz, Rene M.
Though overall bank performance from July 2007 to December 2008 was the worst since the Great Depression, there is significant variation in the cross-section of stock returns of large banks across the world during that period. We use this variation to evaluate the importance of factors that have been put forth as having contributed to the poor performance of banks during the credit crisis. The evidence is supportive of theories that emphasize the fragility of banks financed with short-term capital market funding. The better-performing banks had less leverage and lower returns immediately before the crisis. Differences in banking regulations across countries are generally uncorrelated with the performance of banks during the crisis, except that large banks from countries with more restrictions on bank activities performed better and decreased loans less. Our evidence poses a substantial challenge to those who argue that poor bank governance was a major cause of the crisis because we find that banks with more shareholder-friendly boards performed significantly worse during the crisis than other banks, were not less risky before the crisis, and reduced loans more during the crisis. (C) 2012 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Beltratti, Andrea; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cost and timing of financial distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elkamhi, Redouane; Ericsson, Jan; Parsons, Christopher A.
Assessments of the trade-off theory have typically compared the present value of tax benefits to the present value of bankruptcy costs. We verify that this comparison overwhelmingly favors tax benefits, suggesting that firms are under-leveraged. However, when we allow firms to experience even modest (e.g., 1-2% annualized) financial distress costs prior to bankruptcy, the cumulative present value of such costs can easily offset the tax benefits. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elkamhi, Redouane; Ericsson, Jan; Parsons, Christopher A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding commonality in liquidity around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karolyi, G. Andrew; Lee, Kuan-Hui; van Dijk, Mathijs A.
We examine how commonality in liquidity varies across countries and over time in ways related to supply determinants (funding liquidity of financial intermediaries) and demand determinants (correlated trading behavior of international and institutional investors, incentives to trade individual securities, and investor sentiment) of liquidity. Commonality in liquidity is greater in countries with and during times of high market volatility (especially, large market declines), greater presence of international investors, and more correlated trading activity. Our evidence is more reliably consistent with demand-side explanations and challenges the ability of the funding liquidity hypothesis to help us understand important aspects of financial market liquidity around the world, even during the recent financial crisis. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Karolyi, G. Andrew; Lee, Kuan-Hui; van Dijk, Mathijs A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do foreigners facilitate information transmission in emerging markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, Kee-Hong; Ozoguz, Arzu; Tan, Hongping; Wirjanto, Tony S.
Using the degree of accessibility of foreign investors to emerging stock markets, or investibility, as a proxy for the extent of foreign investments, we assess whether investibility has a significant influence on the diffusion of global market information across stocks in emerging markets. We show that greater investibility reduces price delay to global market information. We also find that returns of highly investible stocks lead those of noninvestible stocks because they incorporate global information more quickly. These results are consistent with the idea that financial liberalization in the form of greater investibility yields informationally more efficient stock prices in emerging markets. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bae, Kee-Hong; Ozoguz, Arzu; Tan, Hongping; Wirjanto, Tony S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A unique view of hedge fund derivatives usage: Safeguard or speculation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aragon, George O.; Martin, J. Spencer
We study the common equity and equity option positions of hedge fund investment advisors over the 1999-2006 period. We find that hedge funds' stock positions predict future returns and that option positions predict both volatility and returns on the underlying stock. A quarterly tracking portfolio of stocks based on publicly observable hedge fund option holdings earns abnormal returns of 1.55% through the end of the quarter. Net of fees, hedge funds using options deliver higher benchmark-adjusted portfolio returns and lower risk than nonusers. The results suggest that hedge fund positions reflect significant timing and selectivity skill. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aragon, George O.; Martin, J. Spencer</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial constraints and share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Wang, Yanzhi
We examine how the financial constraints of repurchasing firms affect their post-buyback performance. By every constraint measure we use, a set of constrained firms repurchase. They display significantly poorer post-buyback abnormal return and operating performance than unconstrained firms. Financial constraints are more important in explaining the performance of share buybacks for firms with high actual repurchase ratios. Constrained firms, especially those with high actual repurchase ratios, experience a significantly greater increase in post-buyback distress risk than unconstrained firms. Managerial hubris could explain why constrained firms buy back shares even if the buybacks do not improve shareholder wealth. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Wang, Yanzhi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size, value, and momentum in international stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
In the four regions (North America, Europe, Japan, and Asia Pacific) we examine, there are value premiums in average stock returns that, except for Japan, decrease with size. Except for Japan, there is return momentum everywhere, and spreads in average momentum returns also decrease from smaller to bigger stocks. We test whether empirical asset pricing models capture the value and momentum patterns in international average returns and whether asset pricing seems to be integrated across the four regions. Integrated pricing across regions does not get strong support in our tests. For three regions (North America, Europe, and Japan), local models that use local explanatory returns provide passable descriptions of local average returns for portfolios formed on size and value versus growth. Even local models are less successful in tests on portfolios formed on size and momentum. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogeneity and the dynamics of internal corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wintoki, M. Babajide; Linck, James S.; Netter, Jeffry M.
We use a well-developed dynamic panel generalized method of moments (GMM) estimator to alleviate endogeneity concerns in two aspects of corporate governance research: the effect of board structure on firm performance and the determinants of board structure. The estimator incorporates the dynamic nature of internal governance choices to provide valid and powerful instruments that address unobserved heterogeneity and simultaneity. We re-examine the relation between board structure and performance using the GMM estimator in a panel of 6,000 firms over a period from 1991 to 2003, and find no causal relation between board structure and current firm performance. We illustrate why other commonly used estimators that ignore the dynamic relationship between current governance and past firm performance may be biased. We discuss where it may be appropriate to consider the dynamic panel GMM estimator in corporate governance research, as well as caveats to its use. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wintoki, M. Babajide; Linck, James S.; Netter, Jeffry M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does it matter who pays for bond ratings? Historical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, John; Stanford, Mary Harris; Xie, Yuan
We test whether Standard and Poor's (S&amp;P) assigns higher bond ratings after it switches from investor-pay to issuer-pay fees in 1974. Using Moody's rating for the same bond as a benchmark, we find that when S&amp;P charges investors and Moody's charges issuers, S&amp;P's ratings are lower than Moody's. Once S&amp;P adopts issuer-pay, its ratings increase and no longer differ from Moody's. More importantly, S&amp;P only assigns higher ratings for bonds that are subject to greater conflicts of interest, measured by higher expected rating fees or lower credit quality. These findings suggest that the issuer-pay model leads to higher ratings. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, John; Stanford, Mary Harris; Xie, Yuan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and the cost of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Valta, Philip
This paper empirically shows that the cost of bank debt is systematically higher for firms that operate in competitive product markets. Using various proxies for product market competition, and reductions of import tariff rates to capture exogenous changes to a firm's competitive environment, I find that competition has a significantly positive effect on the cost of bank debt. Moreover, the analysis reveals that the effect of competition is greater in industries in which small firms face financially strong rivals, in industries with intense strategic interactions between firms, and in illiquid industries. Overall, these findings suggest that banks price financial contracts by taking into account the risk that arises from product market competition. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Valta, Philip</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What does futures market interest tell us about the macroeconomy and asset prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Yogo, Motohiro
Economists have traditionally viewed futures prices as fully informative about future economic activity and asset prices. We argue that open interest could be more informative than futures prices in the presence of hedging demand and limited risk absorption capacity in futures markets. We find that movements in open interest are highly pro-cyclical, correlated with both macroeconomic activity and movements in asset prices. Movements in commodity market interest predict commodity returns, bond returns, and movements in the short rate even after controlling for other known predictors. To a lesser degree, movements in open interest predict returns in currency, bond, and stock markets. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Yogo, Motohiro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Properties of foreign exchange risk premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarno, Lucio; Schneider, Paul; Wagner, Christian
We study the properties of foreign exchange risk premiums that can explain the forward bias puzzle, defined as the tendency of high-interest rate currencies to appreciate rather than depreciate. These risk premiums arise endogenously from the no-arbitrage condition relating the term structure of interest rates and exchange rates. Estimating affine (multi-currency) term structure models reveals a noticeable tradeoff between matching depreciation rates and accuracy in pricing bonds. Risk premiums implied by our global affine model generate unbiased predictions for currency excess returns and are closely related to global risk aversion, the business cycle, and traditional exchange rate fundamentals. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sarno, Lucio; Schneider, Paul; Wagner, Christian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Displacement risk and asset returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garleanu, Nicolae; Kogan, Leonid; Panageas, Stavros
We study asset-pricing implications of innovation in a general-equilibrium overlapping-generations economy. Innovation increases the competitive pressure on existing firms and workers, reducing the profits of existing firms and eroding the human capital of older workers. Due to the lack of inter-generational risk sharing, innovation creates a systematic risk factor, which we call "displacement risk" This risk helps explain several empirical patterns, including the existence of the growth-value factor in returns, the value premium, and the high equity premium. We assess the magnitude of displacement risk using estimates of inter-cohort consumption differences across households and find support for the model. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garleanu, Nicolae; Kogan, Leonid; Panageas, Stavros</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and the cross section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burlacu, Radu; Fontaine, Patrice; Jimenez-Garces, Sonia; Seasholes, Mark S.
This paper mathematically transforms unobservable rational expectation equilibrium model parameters (information precision and supply uncertainty) into a single variable that is correlated with expected returns and that can be estimated with recently observed data. Our variable can be used to explain the cross section of returns in theoretical, numerical, and empirical analyses. Using Center for Research in Security Prices data, we show that a -1 sigma to +1 sigma change in our variable is associated with a 0.31% difference in average returns the following month (equaling 3.78% per annum). The results are statistically significant at the 1% level. Our results remain economically and statistically significant after controlling for stocks' market capitalizations, book-to-market ratios, liquidities, and the probabilities of information-based trading. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Burlacu, Radu; Fontaine, Patrice; Jimenez-Garces, Sonia; Seasholes, Mark S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How are shorts informed? Short sellers, news, and information processing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engelberg, Joseph E.; Reed, Adam V.; Ringgenberg, Matthew C.
We find that a substantial portion of short sellers' trading advantage comes from their ability to analyze publicly available information. Using a database of short sales combined with a database of news releases, we show that the well-documented negative relation between short sales and future returns is twice as large on news days and four times as large on days with negative news. Further, we find that the most informed short sales are not from market makers but rather from clients, and we find only weak evidence that short sellers anticipate news events. Overall, the evidence suggests that public news provides valuable trading opportunities for short sellers who are skilled information processors. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Engelberg, Joseph E.; Reed, Adam V.; Ringgenberg, Matthew C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited arbitrage between equity and credit markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kapadia, Nikunj; Pu, Xiaoling
We document that short-horizon pricing discrepancies across firms' equity and credit markets are common and that an economically significant proportion of these are anomalous, indicating a lack of integration between the two markets. Proposing a statistical measure of market integration, we investigate whether equity-credit market integration is related to impediments to arbitrage. We find that time variation in integration across a firm's equity and credit markets is related to firm-specific impediments to arbitrage such as liquidity in equity and credit markets and idiosyncratic risk. Our evidence provides a potential resolution to the puzzle of why Merton model hedge ratios match empirically observed stock-bond elasticities (Schaefer and Strebulaev, 2008) and yet the model is limited in its ability to explain the integration between equity and credit markets (Collin-Dufresne, Goldstein, and Martin, 2001). (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kapadia, Nikunj; Pu, Xiaoling</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sell-order liquidity and the cross-section of expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brennan, Michael J.; Chordia, Tarun; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Tong, Qing
We estimate buy- and sell-order illiquidity measures (lambdas) for a comprehensive sample of NYSE stocks. We show that sell-order liquidity is priced more strongly than buy-order liquidity in the cross-section of equity returns. Indeed, our analysis indicates that the liquidity premium in equities emanates predominantly from the sell-order side. We also find that the average difference between sell and buy lambdas is generally positive throughout our sample period. Both buy and sell lambdas are significantly positively correlated with measures of funding liquidity such as the TED spread as well option implied volatility. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brennan, Michael J.; Chordia, Tarun; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Tong, Qing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market fragility and international market crashes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Dave; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara
We extend the Pukthuanthong and Roll (2009) measure of integration to provide an estimate of systemic risk within international equity markets. Our measure indicates an increasing likelihood of market crashes. The conditional probability of market crashes increases substantially following increases of our risk measure. High levels of our risk measure indicate the probability of a global crash is greater than the probability of a local crash. That is, conditional on high levels of systemic risk, the probability of a severe crash across multiple markets is larger than the probability of a crash within a smaller number of markets. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Dave; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging labor income risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Betermier, Sebastien; Jansson, Thomas; Parlour, Christine; Walden, Johan
We use a detailed panel data set of Swedish households to investigate the relation between their labor income risk and financial investment decisions. In particular, we relate changes in wage volatility to changes in the portfolio holdings for households that switched industries between 1999 and 2002. We find that households do adjust their portfolio holdings when switching jobs, which is consistent with the idea that households hedge their human capital risk in the stock market. The results are statistically and economically significant. A household going from an industry with low wage volatility to one with high volatility ceteris paribus decreases its portfolio share of risky assets by up to 35%, or $15,575. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Betermier, Sebastien; Jansson, Thomas; Parlour, Christine; Walden, Johan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adverse selection in mortgage securitization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Chang, Yan; Yavas, Abdullah
Using several large data sets of mortgage loans originated between 2004 and 2007, we find that in the prime mortgage market, banks generally sold low-default-risk loans into the secondary market while retaining higher-default-risk loans in their portfolios. In contrast, these lenders retained loans with lower prepayment risk relative to loans they sold. Securitization strategy of lenders changed dramatically in 2007 as the crisis set in with most unwilling to retain higher-default-risk loans in return for lower prepayment risk. Contrary to the prime market, the subprime market does not exhibit any clear pattern of adverse selection. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Chang, Yan; Yavas, Abdullah</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do time-varying risk premiums explain labor market performance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Long; Zhang, Lu
Within the standard search and matching model, time-to-build implies that high aggregate risk premiums should forecast low employment growth in the short run but high employment growth in the long run. If there is also time-to-plan, high risk premiums should forecast low net hiring rates in the short run but high net hiring rates in the long run. Our evidence indicates two-quarter time-to-build in the aggregate payroll data, no time-to-plan in the aggregate hiring data, but two-quarter time-to-plan in the job creation data for manufacturing firms. High payroll growth and high net job creation rate in manufacturing also forecast low stock market excess returns at business cycle frequencies. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Long; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Maxing out: Stocks as lotteries and the cross-section of expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret; Whitelaw, Robert F.
Motivated by existing evidence of a preference among investors for assets with lottery-like payoffs and that many investors are poorly diversified, we investigate the significance of extreme positive returns in the cross-sectional pricing of stocks. Portfolio-level analyses and firm-level cross-sectional regressions indicate a negative and significant relation between the maximum daily return over the past one month (MAX) and expected stock returns. Average raw and risk-adjusted return differences between stocks in the lowest and highest MAX deciles exceed 1% per month. These results are robust to controls for size, book-to-market, momentum, short-term reversals, liquidity, and skewness. Of particular interest, including MAX reverses the puzzling negative relation between returns and idiosyncratic volatility recently shown in Ang, Hodrick, Xing, and Zhang (2006, 2009). (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret; Whitelaw, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure dynamics and transitory debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, Harry; DeAngelo, Linda; Whited, Toni M.
Firms deliberately but temporarily deviate from permanent leverage targets by issuing transitory debt to fund investment. Leverage targets conservatively embed the option to issue transitory debt, with the evolution of leverage reflecting the sequence of investment outlays. We estimate a dynamic capital structure model with these features and find that it replicates industry leverage very well, explains debt issuances/repayments better than extant tradeoff models, and accounts for the leverage changes accompanying investment "spikes." It generates leverage ratios with slow average speeds of adjustment to target, which are dampened by intentional temporary movements away from target, not debt issuance costs. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeAngelo, Harry; DeAngelo, Linda; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empty voting and the efficiency of corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, Alon; Mathews, Richmond D.
We model corporate voting outcomes when an informed trader, such as a hedge fund, can establish separate positions in a firm's shares and votes (empty voting). The positions are separated by borrowing shares on the record date, hedging economic exposure, or trading between record and voting dates. We find that the trader's presence can improve efficiency overall despite the fact that it sometimes ends up selling to a net short position and then voting to decrease firm value. An efficiency improvement is likely if other shareholders' votes are not highly correlated with the correct decision or if it is relatively expensive to separate votes from shares on the record date. On the other hand, empty voting will tend to decrease efficiency if it is relatively inexpensive to separate votes from shares and other shareholders are likely to vote the right way. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brav, Alon; Mathews, Richmond D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Frequent issuers' influence on long-run post-issuance returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, Matthew T.; Flannery, Mark J.; Garfinkel, Jon A.
Prior studies conclude that firms' equity underperforms following many individual sorts of external financing. These conclusions naturally raise significant questions about market efficiency and/or about the techniques used to measure long-run "abnormal returns." Rather than concentrating on a single security type or issuance, we examine long-run performance following any and all sorts of security issuances. Initial financing events do not associate with underperformance; however, subsequent financings do. Our results suggest that negative post-issuance returns have nothing to do with the specific type of security issued, and everything to do with the number of types of securities issued. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Billett, Matthew T.; Flannery, Mark J.; Garfinkel, Jon A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The structure and formation of business groups: Evidence from Korean chaebols</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor; Park, Sang Yong; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Wolfenzon, Daniel
We study the evolution of Korean chaebols (business groups) using ownership data. Chaebols grow vertically (as pyramids) when the controlling family uses well-established group firms ("central firms") to acquire firms with low pledgeable income and high acquisition premiums. Chaebols grow horizontally (through direct ownership) when the family acquires firms with high pledgeable income and low acquisition premiums. Central firms trade at a relative discount, due to shareholders' anticipation of value-destroying acquisitions. Our evidence is consistent with the selection of firms into different positions in the chaebol and ascribes the underperformance of pyramidal firms to a selection effect rather than tunneling. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Park, Sang Yong; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Wolfenzon, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simple formulas for standard errors that cluster by both firm and time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thompson, Samuel B.
When estimating finance panel regressions, it is common practice to adjust standard errors for correlation either across firms or across time. These procedures are valid only if the residuals are correlated either across time or across firms, but not across both. This paper shows that it is very easy to calculate standard errors that are robust to simultaneous correlation along two dimensions, such as firms and time. The covariance estimator is equal to the estimator that clusters by firm, plus the estimator that clusters by time, minus the usual heteroskedasticity-robust ordinary least squares (OLS) covariance matrix. Any statistical package with a clustering command can be used to easily calculate these standard errors. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thompson, Samuel B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank CEO incentives and the credit crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Stulz, Rene M.
We investigate whether bank performance during the recent credit crisis is related to chief executive officer (CEO) incentives before the crisis. We find some evidence that banks with CEOs whose incentives were better aligned with the interests of shareholders performed worse and no evidence that they performed better. Banks with higher option compensation and a larger fraction of compensation in cash bonuses for their CEOs did not perform worse during the crisis. Bank CEOs did not reduce their holdings of shares in anticipation of the crisis or during the crisis. Consequently, they suffered extremely large wealth losses in the wake of the crisis. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional cross-holdings and their effect on acquisition decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Jenter, Dirk; Li, Kai
Cross-holdings are created when a shareholder of one firm holds shares in other firms as well, and cross-holdings alter shareholder preferences over corporate decisions that affect those other firms. Prior evidence suggests that such cross-holdings explain the puzzle of why shareholders allow acquisitions that reduce the value of the bidder. Conducting a shareholder-level analysis of cross-holdings, we instead find that cross-holdings are too small to matter in most acquisitions and that bidders do not bid more aggressively even in the few cases in which cross-holdings are large. We conclude that cross-holdings do not explain value-reducing acquisitions. Beyond acquisitions, we find that institutional cross-holdings between large firms have, in fact, increased rapidly over the last 20 years, but mostly due to indexing and quasi-indexing. As in acquisitions, cross-holdings by active investors are typically too small to matter. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Jenter, Dirk; Li, Kai</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition among mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wahal, Sunil; Wang, Albert
We examine the impact of the entry of new mutual funds on incumbents using the overlap in their portfolio holdings as a measure of competitive intensity. This simple metric delivers powerful economic results. Incumbents that have a high overlap with entrants subsequently engage in price competition by reducing management fees. Distribution fees, however, rise so that investors do not benefit as much from price competition. Funds with high overlap also experience quantity competition through lower investor flows, have lower alphas, and higher attrition rates. These effects only appear after the late 1990s, at which point there appears to be an endogenous structural shift in the competitive environment. We conclude that the mutual fund market has evolved into one that displays the hallmark features of a competitive market. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wahal, Sunil; Wang, Albert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculative capital and currency carry trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jylha, Petri; Suominen, Matti
In this paper, we study a two-country general equilibrium model with partially segmented financial markets, where hedge funds emerge endogenously. Empirically, we show that the hedge fund investment strategy predicted by our model, which we call the "risk-adjusted carry trade" strategy, explains more than 16% of the overall hedge fund index returns and more than 33% of the fixed income arbitrage sub-index returns. The flow of new money to hedge funds affects market interest rates, exchange rates, and both the hedge funds' contemporaneous and expected future returns as predicted by the model. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jylha, Petri; Suominen, Matti</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of governance reform on performance and transparency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Price, Richard; Roman, Francisco J.; Rountree, Brian
This study examines the influence of Mexico's efforts to improve corporate governance on firm performance and transparency. We utilize compliance data from the Code of 'Best' Corporate Practices, disclosed annually by public firms in Mexico, as a measure of corporate governance strength. We document a significant increase in compliance over 2000-2004 indicating Mexican companies view non-compliance as costly. However, we find no association between the governance index and firm performance, nor is there a relation with transparency. Instead, we find firms with greater compliance resort to the more costly mechanism of making dividend payments (higher propensity to pay and greater yield) to reduce agency conflicts. We conclude these associations are the direct result of the institutional features of the Mexican business environment, which is characterized by concentrated ownership of insiders, interlocked boards of directors, a lack of insider trading enforcement, and generally poor protection of minority investors. Our results show that monitoring mechanisms alone are not enough to fundamentally change economic behavior. (C) 2010 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Price, Richard; Roman, Francisco J.; Rountree, Brian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Horizontal acquisitions and buying power: A product market analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharyya, Sugato; Nain, Amrita
Horizontal mergers exert price pressure on dependent suppliers and adversely affect their performance. Consistent with the theory of countervailing power, concentrated suppliers and those with greater barriers to entry experience larger price declines after consolidation downstream. Time-series results suggest that consolidation in dependent supplier industries follows mergers in main customer industries, indicating that consolidation activity travels up the supply chain. The findings are broadly consistent with pervasive beliefs in the business community about the buying power effects of horizontal mergers. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhattacharyya, Sugato; Nain, Amrita</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of banking crisis on bank-dependent borrowers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh
We provide causal evidence that adverse capital shocks to banks affect their borrowers' performance negatively. We use an exogenous shock to the U.S. banking system during the Russian crisis of Fall 1998 to separate the effect of borrowers' demand of credit from the supply of credit by the banks. Firms that primarily relied on banks for capital suffered larger valuation losses during this period and subsequently experienced a higher decline in their capital expenditure and profitability as compared to firms that had access to the public-debt market. Consistent with an adverse shock to the supply of credit, crisis-affected banks decreased the quantity of their lending and increased loan interest rates in the post-crisis period significantly more than the unaffected banks. Our results suggest that the global integration of the financial sector can contribute to the propagation of financial shocks from one economy to another through the banking channel. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The world price of liquidity risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Kuan-Hui
This paper empirically tests the liquidity-adjusted capital asset pricing model of Acharya and Pedersen (2005) on a global level. Consistent with the model, I find evidence that liquidity risks are priced independently of market risk in international financial markets. That is, a security's required rate of return depends on the covariance of its own liquidity with aggregate local market liquidity, as well as the covariance of its own liquidity with local and global market returns. I also show that the US market is an important driving force of global liquidity risk. Furthermore, I find that the pricing of liquidity risk varies across countries according to geographic, economic, and political environments. The findings show that the systematic dimension of liquidity provides implications for international portfolio diversification. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Kuan-Hui</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disagreement and return predictability of stock portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Jialin
This paper provides evidence that portfolio disagreement measured bottom-up from individual-stock analyst forecast dispersions has a number of asset pricing implications. For the market portfolio, market disagreement mean-reverts and is negatively related to ex post expected market return. Contemporaneously, an increase in market disagreement manifests as a drop in discount rate. For book-to-market sorted portfolios, the value premium is stronger among high disagreement stocks. The underperformance by high disagreement stocks is stronger among growth stocks. Growth stocks are more sensitive to variations in disagreement relative to value stocks. These findings are consistent with asset pricing theory incorporating belief dispersion. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd All rights reserved.</description><author>Yu, Jialin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does access to external finance improve productivity? Evidence from a natural experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, Alexander W.; Cornaggia, Jess
We study the relation between access to finance and productivity. Our contribution to the literature is a clean identification of a causal effect of access to finance on productivity. Specifically, we exploit an exogenous shift in demand for a product to expose how producers adapt their productivity in the presence of varying levels of access to finance. We use a triple differences testing approach and find that production increases the most over the sample period in areas with relatively strong access to finance, even in comparison with a control group. This result is statistically significant and robust to a variety of controls, alternative variables, and tests. The causal effect of access to finance on productivity that we find speaks to the larger role of finance in economic growth. (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Butler, Alexander W.; Cornaggia, Jess</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markowitz meets Talmud: A combination of sophisticated and naive diversification strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tu, Jun; Zhou, Guofu
The modern portfolio theory pioneered by Markowitz (1952) is widely used in practice and extensively taught to MBAs. However, the estimated Markowitz portfolio rule and most of its extensions not only underperform the naive 1/N rule (that invests equally across N assets) in simulations, but also lose money on a risk-adjusted basis in many real data sets. In this paper, we propose an optimal combination of the naive 1/N rule with one of the four sophisticated strategies the Markowitz rule, the Jorion (1986) rule, the MacKinlay and Pastor (2000) rule, and the Kan and Zhou (2007) rule as a way to improve performance. We find that the combined rules not only have a significant impact in improving the sophisticated strategies, but also outperform the 1/N rule in most scenarios. Since the combinations are theory-based, our study may be interpreted as reaffirming the usefulness of the Markowitz theory in practice. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tu, Jun; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jump risk, stock returns, and slope of implied volatility smile</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yan, Shu
In the presence of jump risk, expected stock return is a function of the average jump size, which can be proxied by the slope of option implied volatility smile. This implies a negative predictive relation between the slope of implied volatility smile and stock return. For more than four thousand stocks ranked by slope during 1996-2005, the difference between the risk-adjusted average returns of the lowest and highest quintile portfolios is 1.9% per month. Although both the systematic and idiosyncratic components of slope are priced, the idiosyncratic component dominates the systematic component in explaining the return predictability of slope. The findings are robust after controlling for stock characteristics such as size, book-to-market, leverage, volatility, skewness, and volume. Furthermore, the results cannot be explained by alternative measures of steepness of implied volatility smile in previous studies. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yan, Shu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does governance travel around the world? Evidence from institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Reena; Erel, Isil; Ferreira, Miguel; Matos, Pedro
We examine whether institutional investors affect corporate governance by analyzing portfolio holdings of institutions in companies from 23 countries during the period 2003-2008. We find that firm-level governance is positively associated with international institutional investment. Changes in institutional ownership over time positively affect subsequent changes in firm-level governance, but the opposite is not true. Foreign institutions and institutions from countries with strong shareholder protection play a role in promoting governance improvements outside of the U.S. Institutional investors affect not only which corporate governance mechanisms are in place, but also outcomes. Firms with higher institutional ownership are more likely to terminate poorly performing Chief Executive Officers (CEOs) and exhibit improvements in valuation over time. Our results suggest that international portfolio investment by institutional investors promotes good corporate governance practices around the world. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, Reena; Erel, Isil; Ferreira, Miguel; Matos, Pedro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee treatment and firm leverage: A test of the stakeholder theory of capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, Kee-Hong; Kang, Jun-Koo; Wang, Jin
We investigate the stakeholder theory of capital structure from the perspective of a firm's relations with its employees. We find that firms that treat their employees fairly (as measured by high employeefriendly ratings) maintain low debt ratios. This result is robust to a variety of model specifications and endogeneity issues. The negative relation between leverage and a firm's ability to treat employees fairly is also evident when we measure its ability by whether it is included in the Fortune magazine list, "100 Best Companies to Work For." These results suggest that a firm's incentive or ability to offer fair employee treatment is an important determinant of its financing policy. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved,</description><author>Bae, Kee-Hong; Kang, Jun-Koo; Wang, Jin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market aversion? Political preferences and stock market participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaustia, Markku; Torstila, Sami
We find that left-wing voters and politicians are less likely to invest in stocks, controlling for income, wealth, education, and other relevant factors. This finding from unique data sets in Finland is robust both at the zip code and at the individual level. A moderate left voter is 17-20% less likely to own stocks than a moderate right voter. The results are consistent with the idea that personal values are a factor in important investment decisions, in this case leading to "stock market aversion." The results are inconsistent with alternative explanations such as wealth effects, risk aversion, reverse causality, return expectations, or social capital. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaustia, Markku; Torstila, Sami</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional tax clienteles and payout policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, Mihir A.; Jin, Li
This paper employs heterogeneity in institutional shareholder tax characteristics to identify the relation between firm payout policy and tax incentives. Analysis of a panel of firms matched with the tax characteristics of the clients of their institutional shareholders indicates that "dividend-averse" institutions are significantly less likely to hold shares in firms with larger dividend payouts. This relation between the tax preferences of institutional shareholders and firm payout policy may reflect dividend-averse institutions gravitating towards low dividend paying firms or managers adapting their payout policies to the interests of their institutional shareholders. Evidence is provided that both effects are operative. Plausibly exogenous changes in payout policy result in shifting institutional ownership patterns. Similarly, exogenous changes in the tax cost of institutional investors receiving dividends results in changes in firm dividend policy. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Desai, Mihir A.; Jin, Li</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership structure and the cost of corporate borrowing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Malatesta, Paul; Xuan, Yuhai
This article identifies an important channel through which excess control rights affect firm value. Using a new, hand-collected data set on corporate ownership and control of 3,468 firms in 22 countries during the 1996-2008 period, we find that the cost of debt financing is significantly higher for companies with a wider divergence between the largest ultimate owner's control rights and cash-flow rights and investigate factors that affect this relation. Our results suggest that potential tunneling and other moral hazard activities by large shareholders are facilitated by their excess control rights. These activities increase the monitoring costs and the credit risk faced by banks and, in turn, raise the cost of debt for the borrower. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Malatesta, Paul; Xuan, Yuhai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The liquidity risk of liquid hedge funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Teo, Melvyn
This paper evaluates hedge funds that grant favorable redemption terms to investors. Within this group of purportedly liquid funds, high net inflow funds subsequently outperform low net inflow funds by 4.79% per year after adjusting for risk. The return impact of fund flows is stronger when funds embrace liquidity risk, when market liquidity is low, and when funding liquidity, as measured by the Treasury-Eurodollar spread, aggregate hedge fund flows, and prime broker stock returns, is tight. In keeping with an agency explanation, funds with strong incentives to raise capital, low manager option deltas, and no manager capital co-invested are more likely to take on excessive liquidity risk. These results resonate with the theory of funding liquidity by Brunnermeier and Pedersen (2009). (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Teo, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic IPOs and product market competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chod, Jiri; Lyandres, Evgeny
We examine firms' incentives to go public in the presence of product market competition. As a result of their greater ability to diversify idiosyncratic risk in the capital market, public firms' owners tolerate higher profit variability than owners of private firms. Consequently, public firms adopt riskier and more aggressive output market strategies than private firms, which improves the competitive position of the former vis-a-vis the latter. This strategic benefit of being public, and thus, the proportion of public firms in an industry, is shown to be positively related to the degree of competitive interaction among firms in the output market, to demand uncertainty, and to the idiosyncratic port ion of this uncertainty. Additional empirical predictions concern the effect of a firm's initial public offering on its market share and on its rivals' valuations. We test the model's predictions and find empirical support for most of them. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chod, Jiri; Lyandres, Evgeny</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>