<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFE6</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>The role of private equity group reputation in LBO financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher M.
This paper investigates whether the reputation of acquiring private equity groups (PEGs) is related to the financing structure of leveraged buyouts (LBOs). Using a sample of 180 public-to-private LBOs in the US between January 1, 1997 and August 15, 2007, we find that reputable PEGs are more active in the LBO market when credit risk spreads are low and lending standards in the credit markets are lax. We also find that reputable PEGs pay narrower bank and institutional loan spreads, have longer loan maturities, and rely more on institutional loans. In addition, while we find that PEG reputation is positively related to buyout leverage (i.e., LBO debt divided by pre-LBO earnings before interest, taxes, and amortization (EBITDA) of the target), and leverage is significantly positively related to buyout pricing, we do not find any direct relation between PEG reputation and buyout valuations. The evidence suggests that PEG reputation is related to LBO financing structure not only because reputable PEGs are more likely to take advantage of market timing in credit markets and but also because PEG reputation reduces agency costs of LBO debt. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Sarbanes-Oxley act and corporate investment: A structural assessment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Qiang; Liu, Qiao; Qi, Rong
We assess the impact of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 on corporate investment in an investment Euler equation framework. We allow a dummy for the passage of the Act to affect the rate at which managers discount future investment payoffs. Using generalized method of moments estimators, we find that the rate U.S. firm managers apply to discount investment projects rises significantly after 2002, while the discount rate for U.K. firms remains unchanged. The effects of the legislation on corporate investment are asymmetric, and are much more significant among relatively small firms. We also find that well-governed firms, firms with a credit rating, and accelerated filers of Section 404 of the Act have become more cautious about investment. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kang, Qiang; Liu, Qiao; Qi, Rong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting jumps from Levy jump diffusion processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Suzanne S.; Hannig, Jan
Recent asset-pricing models incorporate jump risk through Levy processes in addition to diffusive risk. This paper studies how to detect stochastic arrivals of small and big Levy jumps with new nonparametric tests. The tests allow for robust analysis of their separate characteristics and facilitate better estimation of return dynamics. Empirical evidence of both small and big jumps based on these tests suggests that models for individual equities and overall market indices require incorporating Levy-type jumps. The evidence of small jumps also helps explain why jumps in the market index are uncorrelated with jumps in its component equities. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Suzanne S.; Hannig, Jan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inside the black box: The role and composition of compensation peer groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faulkender, Michael; Yang, Jun
This paper considers the features of the newly disclosed compensation peer groups and demonstrates their significant role in explaining variations in chief executive officer (CEO) compensation beyond that of other benchmarks such as the industry-size peers. After controlling for industry, size, visibility, CEO responsibility, and talent flows, we find that firms appear to select highly paid peers to justify their CEO compensation and this effect is stronger in firms where the compensation peer group is smaller, where the CEO is the chairman of the board of directors, where the CEO has longer tenure, and where directors are busier serving on multiple boards. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faulkender, Michael; Yang, Jun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of emerging hedge funds and managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Rajesh K.; Jorion, Philippe
This paper provides the first systematic analysis of performance patterns for emerging funds and managers in the hedge fund industry. Emerging funds and managers have particularly strong financial incentives to create investment performance and, because of their size, may be more nimble than established ones. Performance measurement, however, needs to control for the usual biases afflicting hedge fund databases. After adjusting for such biases and using a novel event time approach, we find strong evidence of outperformance during the first two to three years of existence. Each additional year of age decreases performance by 42 basis points, on average. Cross-sectionally, early performance by individual funds is quite persistent, with early strong performance lasting for up to five years. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, Rajesh K.; Jorion, Philippe</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity biases in asset pricing tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asparouhova, Elena; Bessembinder, Hendrik; Kalcheva, Ivalina
Microstructure noise in security prices biases the results of empirical asset pricing specifications, particularly when security-level explanatory variables are cross-sectionally correlated with the amount of noise. We focus on tests of whether measures of illiquidity, which are likely to be correlated with the noise, are priced in the cross-section of stock returns, and show a significant upward bias in estimated return premiums for an array of illiquidity measures in Center for Research in Security Prices (CRSP) monthly return data. The upward bias is larger when illiquid securities are included in the sample, but persists even for NYSE/Amex stocks after decimalization. We introduce a methodological correction to eliminate the biases that simply involves weighted least squares (WLS) rather than ordinary least squares (OLS) estimation, and find evidence of smaller, but still significant, return premiums for illiquidity after implementing the correction. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asparouhova, Elena; Bessembinder, Hendrik; Kalcheva, Ivalina</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When are outside directors effective?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duchin, Ran; Matsusaka, John G.; Ozbas, Oguzhan
This paper uses recent regulations that have required some companies to increase the number of outside directors on their boards to generate estimates of the effect of board independence on performance that are largely free from endogeneity problems. Our main finding is that the effectiveness of outside directors depends on the cost of acquiring information about the firm: when the cost of acquiring information is low, performance increases when outsiders are added to the board, and when the cost of information is high, performance worsens when outsiders are added to the board. The estimates provide some of the cleanest estimates to date that board independence matters, and the finding that board effectiveness depends on information cost supports a nascent theoretical literature emphasizing information asymmetry. We also find that firms compose their boards as if they understand that outsider effectiveness varies with information costs. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duchin, Ran; Matsusaka, John G.; Ozbas, Oguzhan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A skeptical appraisal of asset pricing tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewellen, Jonathan; Nagel, Stefan; Shanken, Jay
It has become standard practice in the cross-sectional asset pricing literature to evaluate models based on how well they explain average returns on size-B/M portfolios, something many models seem to do remarkably well. In this paper, we review and critique the empirical methods used in the literature. We argue that asset pricing tests are often highly misleading, in the sense that apparently strong explanatory power (high cross-sectional R(2)s and small pricing errors) can provide quite weak support for a model. We offer a number of suggestions for improving empirical tests and evidence that several proposed models do not work as well as originally advertised. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lewellen, Jonathan; Nagel, Stefan; Shanken, Jay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A resolution of the distress risk and leverage puzzles in the cross section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>George, Thomas J.; Hwang, Chuan-Yang
We revisit findings that returns are negatively related to financial distress intensity and leverage. These are puzzles under frictionless capital markets assumptions but are consistent with optimizing firms that differ in their exposure to financial distress costs. Firms with high costs choose low leverage to avoid distress, but they retain exposure to the systematic risk of bearing such costs in low states. Empirical results are consistent with this explanation. The return premiums to low leverage and low distress are significant in raw returns, and even stronger in risk-adjusted returns. When in distress, low-leverage firms suffer more than high-leverage firms as measured by a deterioration in accounting operating performance and heightened exposure to systematic risk. The connection between return premiums and distress costs is apparent in subperiod evidence. Both are small or insignificant prior to 1980 and larger and significant thereafter. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>George, Thomas J.; Hwang, Chuan-Yang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional investors, intangible information, and the book-to-market effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Hao
This paper establishes a robust link between the trading behavior of institutions and the book-to-market effect. Building on work by Daniel and Titman (2006), who argue that the book-to-market effect is driven by the reversal of intangible returns, I find that institutions tend to buy (sell) shares in response to positive (negative) intangible information and that the reversal of the intangible return is most pronounced among stocks for which a large proportion of active institutions trade in the direction of intangible information. Furthermore, the book-to-market effect is large and significant in stocks with intense past institutional trading but nonexistent in stocks with moderate institutional trading. This influence of institutional trading on the book-to-market effect is distinct from that of firm size. These results are consistent with the view that the tendency of institutions to trade in the direction of intangible information exacerbates price overreaction, thereby contributing to the value premium. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Hao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does law affect finance? An examination of equity tunneling in Bulgaria</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanasov, Vladimir; Black, Bernard; Ciccotello, Conrad; Gyoshev, Stanley
We model and test the mechanisms through which law affects tunneling and tunneling affects firm valuation. In 2002, Bulgaria adopted legal changes which limit equity tunneling through dilutive equity offerings and freezeouts. Following the changes, minority shareholders participate equally in equity offerings, where before they Suffered severe dilution; freezeout offer price ratios quadruple; and Tobin's q rises sharply for firms at high risk of tunneling. The paper shows the importance of legal rules in limiting equity tunneling, the role of equity tunneling risk as a factor in determining equity prices, and substitution by controlling shareholders between different forms of tunneling. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Atanasov, Vladimir; Black, Bernard; Ciccotello, Conrad; Gyoshev, Stanley</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public trust, the law, and financial investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Dorobantu, Florin; Viswanathan, S.
How does trust evolve in markets? What is the optimal level of regulation and how does this affect trust formation and economic growth? In a theoretical model, we analyze these questions, given the value of social capital and the potential for growth in the market. When social capital is valuable, regulation and trustfulness are substitutes. In this case, regulation may cause lower aggregate investment and decreased economic growth. When the social capital is less valuable, regulation and trustfulness may be complements. In the paper, we analyze the optimal level of regulation and highlight the novel predictions of the model. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Dorobantu, Florin; Viswanathan, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial ownership dynamics and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Stulz, Rene M.
From 1988 to 2003, the average change in managerial ownership is significantly negative every year for American firms. We find that managers are more likely to significantly decrease their ownership when their firms are performing well and more likely to increase their ownership when their firms become financially constrained. When controlling for past stock returns, we find that large increases in managerial ownership increase Tobin's q. This result is driven by increases in shares held by officers, while increases in shares held by directors appear unrelated to changes in firm value. There is no evidence that large decreases in ownership have an adverse impact on firm value. We rely on the dynamics of the managerial ownership/firm value relation to mitigate concerns in the literature about the endogeneity of managerial ownership. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor activism and takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Schor, Michael
Recent work documents large positive abnormal returns when a hedge fund announces activist intentions regarding a publicly listed firm. We show that these returns are largely explained by the ability of activists to force target firms into a takeover. For a comprehensive sample of 13D filings by portfolio investors between 1993 and 2006, announcement returns and long-term abnormal returns are high for targets that are ultimately acquired, but not detectably different from zero for firms that remain independent. Firms targeted by activists are more likely than control firms to get acquired. Finally, activist investors' portfolios perform poorly during a period in which market wide takeover interest declined. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Schor, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sell on the news: Differences of opinion, short-sales constraints, and returns around earnings announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, Henk; Dimitrov, Valentin; Jain, Prem C.; Koch, Paul D.; Tice, Sheri
Miller [1977. Risk, uncertainty, and divergence of opinion. journal of Finance 32, 1151-1168] hypothesizes that prices of stocks subject to high differences of opinion and short-sales constraints are biased upward. We expect earnings announcements to reduce differences of opinion among investors, and consequently, these announcements should reduce overvaluation. Using five distinct proxies for differences of opinion, we find that high differences of opinion stocks earn significantly lower returns around earnings announcements than low differences of opinion stocks. In addition, the returns on high differences of opinion stocks are more negative within the subsample of stocks that are most difficult for investors to sell short. These results are robust when we control for the size effect and the market-to-book effect and when we examine alternative explanations such as financial leverage, earnings announcement premium, post-earnings announcement drift, return momentum, and potential biases in analysts' forecasts. Also consistent with Miller's theory, we find that stocks subject to high differences of opinion and more binding short-sales constraints have a price run-up just prior to earnings announcements that is followed by an even larger decline after the announcements. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berkman, Henk; Dimitrov, Valentin; Jain, Prem C.; Koch, Paul D.; Tice, Sheri</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor control rights and firm investment policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nini, Greg; Smith, David C.; Sufi, Amir
We present novel empirical evidence that conflicts of interest between creditors and their borrowers have a significant impact on firm investment policy. We examine a large sample of private credit agreements between banks and public firms and find that 32% of the agreements contain an explicit restriction on the firm's capital expenditures. Creditors are more likely to impose a capital expenditure restriction as a borrower's credit quality deteriorates, and the use of a restriction appears at least as sensitive to borrower credit quality as other contractual terms, such as interest rates, collateral requirements, or the use of financial covenants. We find that capital expenditure restrictions cause a reduction in firm investment and that firms obtaining contracts with a new restriction experience subsequent increases in their market value and operating performance. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nini, Greg; Smith, David C.; Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The strategic use of corporate cash holdings in collective bargaining with labor unions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klasa, Sandy; Maxwell, William F.; Ortiz-Molina, Hernan
We provide evidence that firms in more unionized industries strategically hold less cash to gain bargaining advantages over labor unions and shelter corporate income from their demands. Specifically, we show that corporate cash holdings are negatively related with unionization. We also find that this relation is stronger for firms that are likely to place a higher value on gaining a bargaining advantage over unions and weaker for those firms in which lower cash holdings provide less credible evidence that a firm is unable to concede to union demands. Additionally, we show that for unionized firms increases in cash holdings raise the probability of a strike. Finally, we show that unionization decreases the market value of a dollar of cash holdings. Overall, our findings indicate that firms trade-off the benefits of corporate cash holdings with the costs resulting from a weaker bargaining position with labor. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Klasa, Sandy; Maxwell, William F.; Ortiz-Molina, Hernan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technical analysis: An asset allocation perspective on the use of moving averages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Yingzi; Zhou, Guofu
In this paper, we analyze the usefulness of technical analysis, specifically the widely employed moving average trading rule from an asset allocation perspective. We show that, when stock returns are predictable, technical analysis adds value to commonly used allocation rules that invest fixed proportions of wealth in stocks. When uncertainty exists about predictability, which is likely in practice, the fixed allocation rules combined with technical analysis can outperform the prior-dependent optimal learning rule when the prior is not too informative. Moreover, the technical trading rules are robust to model specification, and they tend to substantially outperform the model-based optimal trading strategies when the model governing the stock price is uncertain. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhu, Yingzi; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underinvestment vs. overinvestment: Evidence from price reactions to pension contributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franzoni, Francesco
Mandatory contributions to defined benefit pension plans provide a unique identification strategy to estimate the market's assessment of the value of internal resources controlling for investment opportunities. The price decrease following a pension-induced drop in cash is magnified for firms that appear a priori more financially constrained, suggesting a negative effect of financing frictions on investment. In contrast, low control on managerial discretion attenuates the negative price reaction to contributions consistent with empire-building theories. While overinvestment seems to be the prevalent distortion in a panel of large firms, underinvestment appears to dominate in a sample that is more representative of the cross-section of listed companies. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Franzoni, Francesco</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial risk-taking behavior and equity-based compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Low, Angie
Equity-based compensation affects managers' risk-taking behavior, which in turn has an impact on shareholder wealth. In response to an exogenous increase in takeover protection in Delaware during the mid-1990s, managers lower firm risk by 6%. This risk reduction is concentrated among firms with low managerial equity-based incentives, in particular firms with low chief executive officer portfolio sensitivity to stock return volatility. Furthermore, the risk reduction is value-destroying. Finally, firms respond to the increased protection accorded by the regime shift by providing managers with greater incentives for risk-taking. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Low, Angie</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seasoned equity offerings: Quality of accounting information and expected flotation costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Gemma; Masulis, Ronald W.
Flotation costs represent a significant loss of capital to firms and are positively related to information asymmetry between managers and outside investors. We measure a firm's information asymmetry by its accounting information quality based on two extensions of the Dechow and Dichev [2002. The quality of accruals and earnings: the role of accrual estimation errors. Accounting Review 77, 35-59] earnings accruals model, which is a more direct approach to assessing the information available to outside investors than the more commonly used proxies. Our main hypothesis is that poor accounting information quality raises uncertainty about a firm's financial condition for outside investors, though not necessarily for insiders. This accounting effect lowers demand for a firm's new equity, thereby raising underwriting costs and risk. Using a large sample of seasoned equity offerings (SEOs), we show that poor accounting information quality is associated with higher flotation costs in terms of larger underwriting fees, larger negative SEO announcement effects, and a higher probability of SEO withdrawals. These results are robust to joint determination of offer size and flotation cost components and to adjustments for sample selection bias. (C) 2009 published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Lee, Gemma; Masulis, Ronald W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price-based return comovement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, T. Clifton; Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun
Similarly priced stocks move together. Stocks that undergo splits experience an increase in comovement with low-priced stocks and a decrease in their comovement with high-priced stocks. Price-based comovement is not explained by economic fundamentals, firm size, or changes in liquidity or information diffusion. The shift in comovement following splits is greater for large stocks, high-priced stocks, and when investor sentiment is high. In the full cross-section, price-based portfolios explain variation in stock-level returns after controlling for movements in the market and industry portfolios as well as portfolios based on size, book-to-market, transaction costs, and return momentum. The results suggest that investors categorize stocks based on price. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Green, T. Clifton; Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do firms have leverage targets? Evidence from acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Klasa, Sandy; Walcott, Nathan
In the context of large acquisitions, we provide evidence on whether firms have target capital structures. We examine how deviations from these targets affect how bidders choose to finance acquisitions and how they adjust their capital structure following the acquisitions. We show that when a bidder's leverage is over its target level, it is less likely to finance the acquisition with debt and more likely to finance the acquisition with equity. Also, we find a positive association between the merger-induced changes in target and actual leverage, and we show that bidders incorporate more than two-thirds of the change to the merged firm's new target leverage. Following debt-financed acquisitions, managers actively move the firm back to its target leverage, reversing more than 75% of the acquisition's leverage effect within five years. Overall, our results are consistent with a model of capital structure that includes a target level and adjustment costs. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Klasa, Sandy; Walcott, Nathan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of sin: The effects of social norms on markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Kacperczyk, Marcin
We provide evidence for the effects of social norms on markets by studying "sin" stocks-publicly traded companies involved in producing alcohol, tobacco, and gaming. We hypothesize that there is a societal norm against funding operations that promote vice and that some investors, particularly institutions subject to norms, pay a financial cost in abstaining from these stocks. Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that sin stocks are less held by norm-constrained institutions such as pension plans as compared to mutual or hedge funds that are natural arbitrageurs, and they receive less coverage from analysts than do stocks of otherwise comparable characteristics. Sin stocks also have higher expected returns than otherwise comparable stocks, consistent with them being neglected by norm-constrained investors and facing greater litigation risk heightened by social norms. Evidence from corporate financing decisions and the performance of sin stocks outside the US also suggest that norms affect stock prices and returns. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Kacperczyk, Marcin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The underpricing of private targets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooney, John W.; Moeller, Thomas; Stegemoller, Mike
We examine acquisitions of private firms with valuation histories and find a positive relation between acquirer announcement returns and target valuation revisions. Similar to other studies, acquirer announcement returns are positive, on average. However, positive acquirer announcement returns are mainly driven by targets that are acquired for more than their prior valuation. This relation is consistent with pricing effects associated with target valuation uncertainty and behavioral biases in negotiation outcomes. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cooney, John W.; Moeller, Thomas; Stegemoller, Mike</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed traders and limit order markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goettler, Ronald L.; Parlour, Christine A.; Rajan, Uday
We consider a dynamic limit order market in which traders optimally choose whether to acquire information about the asset and the type of order to submit. We numerically solve for the equilibrium and demonstrate that the market is a "volatility multiplier": prices are more volatile than the fundamental value of the asset. This effect increases when the fundamental value has high volatility and with asymmetric information across traders. Changes in the microstructure noise are negatively correlated with changes in the estimated fundamental value, implying that asset betas estimated from high-frequency data will be incorrect. (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Goettler, Ronald L.; Parlour, Christine A.; Rajan, Uday</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It pays to have friends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun; Kim, Seoyoung
Currently. a director is classified as independent if he or she has neither financial nor familial ties to the CEO or to the firm. We add another dimension: social ties. Using a unique data set, we find that 87% of boards are conventionally independent but that only 62% are conventionally and socially independent. Furthermore, firms whose boards are conventionally and socially independent award a significantly lower level of compensation. exhibit stronger pay-performance sensitivity, and exhibit stronger turnover-performance sensitivity than firms whose boards are only conventionally independent. Our results suggest that social ties do matter and that, consequently, a considerable percentage of the conventionally independent boards are substantively not. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun; Kim, Seoyoung</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Affiliated mutual funds and analyst optimism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mola, Simona; Guidolin, Massimo
This paper extends the literature on analyst optimism. Our analysis of a large sample of recommendations issued from 1995 through 2006 indicates that sell-side analysts are likely to assign frequent and favorable ratings to a stock after the analysts' affiliated mutual funds invest in that stock. Controlling for a number of variables, including the ties between analysts and investment banks, we find that the greater the portfolio weight of a stock in the fund family, the more optimistic the stock ratings from affiliated analysts become. Since 2002, analysts' optimism on stocks held by affiliated mutual funds has declined. However, an analyst's decision of upgrading a stock to a "strong buy" rating is still significantly associated with the portfolio weight of that stock in the fund family. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mola, Simona; Guidolin, Massimo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payout policy and cash-flow uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chay, J. B.; Suh, Jungwon
The importance of cash-flow uncertainty in payout policy has received little attention in empirical studies, while survey studies such as [Lintner, J., 1956. Distribution of incomes of operations among dividends, retained earnings, and taxes. American Economic Review 46, 97-113.] and [Brav. A., Graham, J., Harvey C., Michaely, R., 2005. Payout policy in the 21st century. journal of Financial Economics 77, 483-527.] indicate its importance. With worldwide firm-level data, we present evidence that cash-flow uncertainty is an important cross-sectional determinant of corporate payout policy. Our results show that across countries, cash-flow uncertainty, as proxied by stock return volatility, has a negative impact on the amount of dividends as well as the probability of paying dividends. The impact of cash-flow uncertainty on dividends is generally stronger than the impact of other potential determinants of payout policy-such as the earned/contributed capital mix, agency conflicts, and investment opportunities. We also find that the effect of cash-flow uncertainty on dividends is distinct from the effect of a firm's financial life-cycle stage. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chay, J. B.; Suh, Jungwon</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employment risk, compensation incentives, and managerial risk taking: Evidence from the mutual fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kempf, Alexander; Ruenzi, Stefan; Thiele, Tanja
We examine the influence on managerial risk taking of incentives due to employment risk and due to compensation. Our empirical investigation of the risk taking behavior of mutual fund managers indicates that managerial risk taking crucially depends on the relative importance of these incentives. When employment risk is more important than compensation incentives, fund managers with a poor midyear performance tend to decrease risk relative to leading managers to prevent potential job loss. When employment risk is low, compensation incentives become more relevant and fund managers with a poor midyear performance increase risk to catch up with the midyear winners. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kempf, Alexander; Ruenzi, Stefan; Thiele, Tanja</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Neighborhood matters: The impact of location on broad based stock option plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kedia, Simi; Rajgopal, Shiva
We find that fixed effects related to the location of firms' headquarters explain variation in broad based option grants after controlling for industry effects and firm characteristics traditionally known to affect option granting. Location matters because of local labor market conditions and social interaction with neighboring firms. Broad based option grants are higher: (i) when a firm's stock prices co-move more with stock prices of other firms located in that Metropolitan Statistical Area (MSA): (ii) in states that are less likely to enforce non-compete agreements; and (iii) in MSAs where employees prefer options because stocks there experience abnormally high returns. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kedia, Simi; Rajgopal, Shiva</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the reversal of return and dividend growth predictability: A tale of two periods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Long
A disconcerting, albeit generally accepted, finding is that aggregate stock returns are predictable by dividend yield but dividend growth is unpredictable. I show that part of this lack of dividend growth predictability stems from how dividend growth is constructed. I then show a dramatic reversal of predictability in the 134 years during 1872-2005: stock returns are largely unpredictable in the first seven decades, but become predictable in the postwar period; dividend growth is strongly predictable in the prewar years but this predictability disappears in the postwar years. New evidence on the predictability of long-run returns and dividend growth is also shown. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Long</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Caught on tape: Institutional trading, stock returns, and earnings announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John Y.; Ramadorai, Tarun; Schwartz, Allie
Many questions about institutional trading can only be answered if one tracks high-frequency changes in institutional ownership. In the United States, however, institutions are only required to report their ownership quarterly in 13-F filings. We infer daily institutional trading behavior from the "tape", the Transactions and Quotes database of the New York Stock Exchange, using a sophisticated method that best predicts quarterly 13-F data from trades of different sizes. We find that daily institutional trades are highly persistent and respond positively to recent daily returns but negatively to longer-term past daily returns. Institutional trades, particularly sells, appear to generate short-term losses-possibly reflecting institutional demand for liquidity-but longer-term profits. One source of these profits is that institutions anticipate both earnings surprises and post-earnings announcement drift. These results are different from those obtained using a standard size cutoff rule for institutional trades. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campbell, John Y.; Ramadorai, Tarun; Schwartz, Allie</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product market advertising and new equity issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas; Yan, An
We analyze the interaction between a firm's product market advertising and its corporate financing decisions. We consider a firm that faces asymmetric information in both the product and financial markets and that needs to raise external financing to fund its growth opportunity (new project). Any product market advertising undertaken by the firm is visible to the financial market as well. In equilibrium, the firm uses a combination of product market advertising, equity underpricing, and underfinancing (raising a smaller amount of external capital than the full information optimum) to convey its true product quality and the intrinsic value of its projects to consumers and investors. The following two predictions arise from our theoretical analysis for the relation between product market advertising and equity underpricing around new equity issues. First, firms choose a higher level of product market advertising when they are planning to issue new equity, compared with situations in which they have no immediate plans to do so. Second, product market advertising and equity underpricing are substitutes for a firm issuing new equity. We empirically test the above two predictions and find supporting evidence in the context of firms making initial public offerings and seasoned equity offerings. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas; Yan, An</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance evaluation and self-designated benchmark indexes in the mutual fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sensoy, Berk A.
Almost one-third of actively managed, diversified U.S. equity mutual funds specify a size and value/growth benchmark index in the fund prospectus that does not match the fund's actual style. Nevertheless, these "mismatched" benchmarks matter to fund investors. Performance relative to the specified benchmark is a significant determinant of a fund's subsequent cash inflows, even controlling for performance measures that better capture the fund's style. These incremental flows appear unlikely to be rational responses to abnormal returns. The evidence is consistent with the notion that mismatched self-designated benchmarks result from strategic fund behavior driven by the incentive to improve flows. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sensoy, Berk A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The on-the-run liquidity phenomenon</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pasquariello, Paolo; Vega, Clara
We test the implications of a model of multi-asset speculative trading in which liquidity differentials between on-the-run and off-the-run U.S. Treasury bonds ensue from endowment shocks in the presence of two realistic market frictions-information heterogeneity and imperfect competition among informed traders-and a public signal. Cur evidence suggests that (i) off/on-the-run liquidity differentials are economically and statistically significant, even after controlling for several of the bonds' intrinsic characteristics (such as duration, convexity, repo rates, or term premiums), and (ii) off/on-the-run liquidity differentials are smaller immediately following bond auction dates, and larger when the uncertainty surrounding the ensuing auction allocations is high, when the dispersion of beliefs across informed traders is high, and when macroeconomic announcements are noisy, consistent with our model. (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Pasquariello, Paolo; Vega, Clara</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage timing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Van Hemert, Otto; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn
We study how the term structure of interest rates relates to mortgage choice at both household and aggregate levels. A simple utility framework of mortgage choice points to the long-term bond risk premium as distinct from the yield spread and the long yield as a theoretical determinant of mortgage choice: when the bond risk premium is high, fixed-rate mortgage payments are high, making adjustable-rate mortgages more attractive. We confirm empirically that the bulk of the time variation in both aggregate and loan-level mortgage choice can be explained by time variation in the bond risk premium, whether bond risk premia are measured using forecasters' data, a vector autoregressive (VAR) term structure model, or a simple household decision rule based on adaptive expectations. The household decision rule moves in lock-step with mortgage choice. lending credibility to a theory of strategic mortgage timing by households. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Van Hemert, Otto; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accruals, cash flows, and aggregate stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Hou, Kewei; Teoh, Siew Hong
This paper examines whether the firm-level accrual and cash flow effects extend to the aggregate stock market. In sharp contrast to previous firm-level findings, aggregate accruals is a strong positive time series predictor of aggregate stock returns, and cash flows is a negative predictor. In addition, innovations in accruals are negatively contemporaneously correlated with aggregate returns, and innovations in cash flows are positively correlated with returns. These findings suggest that innovations in accruals and cash flows contain information about changes in discount rates, or that firms manage earnings in response to marketwide undervaluation. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Hou, Kewei; Teoh, Siew Hong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corruption in bank lending to firms: Cross-country micro evidence on the beneficial role of competition and information sharing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barth, James R.; Lin, Chen; Lin, Ping; Song, Frank M.
Building on the important study by Beck, Demirguc-Kunt, and Levine [2006. Bank supervision and corruption in lending. journal of Monetary Economics 53, 2131-2163], we examine the effects of both borrower and lender competition as well as information sharing via credit bureaus/registries on corruption in bank lending. Using the unique World Bank data set (WBES) covering more than 4,000 firms across 56 countries with information on credit bureaus/registries, assembled by Djankov, McLiesh, and Shleifer [2007. Private credit in 129 countries. journal of Financial Economics 84, 299-329], and bank regulation data collected by Barth, Caprio, and Levine [2006. Rethinking Bank Regulation: Till Angels Govern. Cambridge University Press, New York] to measure bank competition and information sharing, we find strong evidence that both banking competition and information sharing reduce lending corruption, and that information sharing also helps enhance the positive effect of competition in curtailing lending corruption. We also find that the ownership structure of firms and banks, legal environment, and firm competition all exert significant impacts on lending corruption. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barth, James R.; Lin, Chen; Lin, Ping; Song, Frank M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benmelech, Efraim; Bergman, Nittai K.
We examine how collateral affects the cost of debt capital. Using a novel data set of secured debt issued by U.S. airlines, we construct industry-specific measures of collateral redeployability. We show that debt tranches that are secured by more redeployable collateral exhibit lower credit spreads, higher credit ratings, and higher loan-to-value ratios-an effect which our estimates show to be economically sizeable. Our results suggest that the ability to pledge collateral, and in particular redeployable collateral, lowers the cost of external financing and increases debt capacity. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benmelech, Efraim; Bergman, Nittai K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic order submission strategies with competition between a dealer market and a crossing network</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degryse, Hans; Van Achter, Mark; Wuyts, Gunther
We analyze a dynamic microstructure model in which a dealer market (DM) and a crossing network (CN) interact for three informational settings. A key result is that coexistence of trading systems generates systematic patterns in order flow, which depend on the degree of transparency. Further, we study overall welfare, measured by the gains from trade of all agents, and compare it with the maximum overall welfare. The discrepancy between both measures is attributable to two inefficiencies. Due to these inefficiencies, introducing a CN next to a DM, as well as increasing the transparency level, not necessarily produces greater overall welfare. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Degryse, Hans; Van Achter, Mark; Wuyts, Gunther</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional volatility in affine term-structure models: Evidence from Treasury and swap markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, Kris; Karoui, Lotfi
We study the ability of three-factor affine term-structure models to extract conditional volatility using interest rate swap yields for 1991-2005 and Treasury yields for 1970-2003. For the Treasury sample, the correlation between model-implied and EGARCH volatility is between 60% and 75%. For the swap sample, this correlation is rather low or negative. We find that these differences in model performance are primarily due to the timing of the swap sample, and not to institutional differences between swap and Treasury markets. We conclude that the ability of multifactor affine models to extract conditional volatility depends on the sample period, but that overall these models perform better than has been argued in the literature. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacobs, Kris; Karoui, Lotfi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic price complexity in retail financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlin, Bruce I.
There is mounting empirical evidence to suggest that the law of one price is violated in retail financial markets: there is significant price dispersion even when products are homogeneous. Also, despite the large number of firms in the market, prices remain above marginal cost and may even rise as more firms enter. in a non-cooperative oligopoly pricing model, I show that these anomalies arise when firms add complexity to their price structures. Complexity increases the market power of the firms because it prevents some consumers from becoming knowledgeable about prices in the market. In the model, as competition increases, firms tend to add more complexity to their prices as a best response, rather than make their disclosures more transparent. Because this may substantially decrease consumer surplus in these markets, such practices have important welfare implications. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carlin, Bruce I.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Has New York become less competitive than London in global markets? Evaluating foreign listing choices over time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Stulz, Rene M.
We study the determinants and consequences of cross-listings on the New York and London stock exchanges from 1990 to 2005. This investigation enables us to evaluate the relative benefits of New York and London exchange listings and to assess whether these relative benefits have changed over time, perhaps as a result of the passage of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act in 2002. We find that cross-listings have been falling on US exchanges as well as on the Main Market in London. This decline in cross-listings is explained by changes in firm characteristics instead of by changes in the benefits of cross-listing. We show that after controlling for firm characteristics there is no deficit in cross-listing counts on US exchanges related to SOX. Investigating the valuation differential between listed and non-listed firms (the cross-listing premium) from 1990 to 2005, we find that there is a significant premium for US exchange listings every year, that the premium has not fallen significantly in recent years, and that it persists when allowing for time-invariant unobservable firm characteristics. In contrast, no premium exists for listings on London's Main Market in any year. Firms increase their capital-raising activities at home and abroad following a cross-listing on a major US exchange but not following a cross-listing in London. Our evidence is consistent with the theory that an exchange listing in New York has unique governance benefits for foreign firms. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Untitled</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Founders, heirs, and corporate opacity in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Ronald C.; Duru, Augustine; Reeb, David M.
We argue that information about firm activities can vary substantially in the presence of founder or heir ownership, thereby influencing the risks borne by minority investors. We explore two hypotheses with regard to these controlling shareholders and corporate transparency, focusing on their role as monitor in-place and their potential to exploit firm opacity to accrue private benefits of control. To test these notions, we create an opacity index that ranks the relative transparency of the two thousand largest industrial US firms and find founder and heir ownership in 22% and 25% of these firms, respectively. Our analysis indicates that, in large, publicly traded companies, both founder and heir firms are significantly more opaque than diffuse shareholder firms. We also find that founder and heir-controlled firms exhibit a negative relation to performance in all but the most transparent firms. Surprisingly, additional tests reveal that concerns about divergences it) ownership versus control (management type, dual class shares, and board influence) appear to be Substantially less important than corporate opacity in explaining the performance impacts of founder and heir control. Finally, we decompose corporate opacity into disclosure and market scrutiny components, finding that the disclosure quality component appears to be of greater importance to investors. However, irrespective of whether these controlling shareholders create or stay in the firm because of corporate opacity, our analysis suggests that founders and heirs in large, publicly traded firms exploit opacity to extract private benefits at the expense of minority investors. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anderson, Ronald C.; Duru, Augustine; Reeb, David M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do liquidity measures measure liquidity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyenko, Ruslan Y.; Holden, Craig W.; Trzcinka, Charles A.
Given the key role of liquidity in finance research, identifying high quality proxies based oil daily (as opposed to intraday) data Would permit liquidity to be studied over relatively long timeframes and across many countries. Using new measures and widely employed measures in the literature, we run horseraces of annual and monthly estimates of each measure against liquidity benchmarks. Our benchmarks are effective spread, realized spread, and price impact based on both Trade and Quote (TAQ) and Rule 605 data. We find that the new effective/realized spread measures win the majority of horseraces, while the Amihud [2002. Illiquidity and stock returns: cross-section and time-series effects. Journal of Financial Markets 5, 31-56] measure does well measuring price impact. (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Goyenko, Ruslan Y.; Holden, Craig W.; Trzcinka, Charles A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Synchronicity and firm interlocks in an emerging market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khanna, Tarun; Thomas, Catherine
Stock price synchronicity has been attributed to poor corporate governance and a lack of firm-level transparency. This paper investigates the association between different kinds of firm interlocks, control groups, and synchronicity in Chile. A unique data set containing equity cross-holdings, common individual owners, and director interlocks is used to map out firm ties and control groups. While there is a correlation between synchronicity and share ownership and equity ties, synchronicity is more strongly correlated with interlocking directorates. The presence of share directors is associated with either reduced firm-level transparency or increased correlation in firm fundamentals-due, for example, to joint resource allocation across the firms. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.Stock price synchronicity has been attributed to poor corporate governance and a lack of firm-level transparency. This paper investigates the association between different kinds of firm interlocks, control groups, and synchronicity in Chile. A unique data set containing equity cross-holdings, common individual owners, and director interlocks is used to map out firm ties and control groups. While there is a correlation between synchronicity and share ownership and equity ties, synchronicity is more strongly correlated with interlocking directorates. The presence of share directors is associated with either reduced firm-level transparency or increased correlation in firm fundamentals-due, for example, to joint resource allocation across the firms. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khanna, Tarun; Thomas, Catherine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual investor mutual fund flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivkovic, Zoran; Weisbenner, Scott
This paper studies the relation between individuals mutual fund flows and fund characteristics, establishing three key results. First, consistent with tax motivations, individual investors are reluctant to sell mutual funds that have appreciated in value and are willing to sell losing funds. Second, individuals pay attention to investment costs as redemption decisions are sensitive to both expense ratios and loads. Third, individuals fund-level inflows and outflows are sensitive to performance, but in different ways. Inflows are related only to "relative" performance, suggesting that new money chases the best performers in air objective. Outflows are related only to "absolute" fund performance, the relevant benchmark for taxes. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ivkovic, Zoran; Weisbenner, Scott</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital expenditures, financial constraints, and the use of options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adam, Tim
This paper analyzes why gold mining firms use options instead of linear strategies to hedge their gold price risk. Consistent with financial constraints based theories, the largest and least financially constrained firms are the most likely to hedge with insurance strategies (Put options), while more constrained firms finance the purchase of puts by selling calls (collars). The most financially constrained firms use strategies that involve selling calls. Firms with large investment programs are also more likely to use insurance rather than linear strategies. Firms' hedging instrument choices are also correlated with current market conditions, suggesting that managers' market views partially drive hedging instrument choices. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adam, Tim</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>City size and fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Sarkissian, Sergei
The literature predicts that the average skill level and productivity are higher in larger cities. Prior studies use workers' wage or education differentials to indirectly link city size and output. This article relates city size and productivity directly, using performance data of U.S. equity mutual funds. On average, funds in financial centers perform better than other funds in terms of both gross and risk-adjusted returns, but this difference is driven only by more experienced managers. Among funds in financial centers there is strong evidence of a positive relation between performance and manager experience in a given city, especially among New York funds. More importantly, we observe performance improvements of the same manager at the same fund in financial centers but not elsewhere. Our tests provide novel evidence of knowledge spillovers and learning in cities. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Sarkissian, Sergei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend policy, creditor rights, and the agency costs of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, Paul; Unlu, Emre
We show that country-level creditor rights influence dividend policies around the world by establishing the balance of power between debt and equity claimants. Creditors demand and managers consent to a more restrictive Payout policy as a substitute for weak creditor rights in an effort to minimize the firm's agency costs of debt. Using a sample of 120,507 firm-years from 52 countries, we find that both the probability and amount of dividend payouts are significantly lower in countries with poor creditor rights. A reduction in the creditor rights index from its highest value to its lowest value implies a 41% reduction in the probability of paying a dividend, and a 60% reduction in dividend payout ratios. These results are robust to numerous control variables, sample variations, model specifications, and alternative hypotheses. We also show that the agency costs of debt play a more decisive role in determining dividend policies than the previously documented agency costs of equity. Overall, our findings contribute to the growing literature arguing that creditors exert significant influence over corporate decision-making outside of bankruptcy. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brockman, Paul; Unlu, Emre</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric information effects on loan spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivashina, Victoria
This paper estimates the cost arising from information asymmetry between the lead bank and members of the lending syndicate. In a lending syndicate, the lead bank retains only a fraction of the loan but acts as the intermediary between the borrower and the syndicate participants. Theory predicts that asymmetric information will cause participants to demand a higher interest rate and that a large loan ownership by the lead bank should reduce this effect. In equilibrium, however, the asymmetric information premium demanded by participants is offset by the diversification premium demanded by the lead. Using shifts in the idiosyncratic credit risk of the lead bank's loan portfolio as an instrument, I measure the asymmetric information effect of the lead's share on the loan spread and find that it accounts for approximately 4% of the total cost of credit. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ivashina, Victoria</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry and firms' credit market access: Evidence from Moody's credit rating format refinement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tang, Tony T.
I exploit Moody's 1982 credit rating refinement to examine its effects on firms' credit market access, financing decisions, and investment policies. While firms' ex ante yield spread can partially predict the direction of refinement changes, firms with refinement upgrades experience an additional decrease in their ex post borrowing cost compared with firms with downgrades. The former subsequently also issue more debt and rely more on debt financing over equity than the latter. Lastly, upgraded firms have more capital investments, less cash accumulation, and faster asset growth than downgraded firms. These findings show that credit market information asymmetry significantly affects firms' real outcomes. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tang, Tony T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early-stage financing and firm growth in new industries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, Roman; Mueller, Holger M.
This paper shows that active investors, such as venture capitalists, can affect the speed at which new ventures grow. in the absence of product market competition, new ventures financed by active investors grow faster initially, though in the long run those financed by passive investors are able to catch up. By contrast, in a competitive product market, new ventures financed by active investors may prey on rivals that are financed by passive investors by "strategically overinvesting" early on, resulting in long-run differences in investment, profits, and firm growth. The value of active investors is greater in highly competitive industries as well as in industries with learning curves, economies of scope, and network effects, as is typical for many "new economy" industries. For such industries, our model predicts that start-ups with access to venture capital may dominate their industry peers in the long run. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Inderst, Roman; Mueller, Holger M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option markets and implied volatility: Past versus present</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mixon, Scott
Traders in the nineteenth century appear to have priced options the same way that twenty-first-century traders price options. Empirical regularities relating implied volatility to realized volatility, stock prices, and other implied volatilities (including the volatility skew) are qualitatively the same in both eras. Modern pricing models and centralized exchanges have not fundamentally altered pricing behavior, but they have generated increased trading volume and a much closer conformity in the level of observed and model prices. The major change in pricing is the sharp decline in implied volatility relative to realized volatility, evident immediately upon the opening of the CBOE. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mixon, Scott</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives volatility persistence in the foreign exchange market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, David; Chaboud, Alain; Hjalmarsson, Erik
We propose a new empirical specification of volatility that links volatility to the information flow, measured as the order flow in the market, and to the price sensitivity to that information. The time-varying market sensitivity to information is estimated from high-frequency data, and movements in volatilitycanthereforebedirectlyrelated to movements in order flow and market sensitivity. Empirically, the model explains a large share of the long-run variation involatility. Importantly, the time variation in the market's sensitivity to information is atleast as relevant in explaining the persistence of volatility as the rate of information arrival itself. This may be evidence of a link between changes over time in the aggregate behavior of market participants and the time-series properties of realized volatility. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Berger, David; Chaboud, Alain; Hjalmarsson, Erik</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global market integration: An alternative measure and its application</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Roll, Richard
Global markets seem to be increasingly integrated but there is no well-accepted measure of integration. We show that the correlation across markets is a poor measure; perfectly integrated markets can exhibit weak correlation. We derive a new integration measure based on the explanatory power of a multi-factor model and use it empirically to investigate recent trends in global integration. For most countries, there has been a marked increase in measured integration over the past three decades, but this is not indicated by correlations among country indexes. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of risk and uncertainty on expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Evan W.; Ghysels, Eric; Juergens, Jennifer L.
We study asset pricing in economies featuring both risk and uncertainty. In our empirical analysis, we measure risk via return volatility and uncertainty via the degree of disagreement of professional forecasters, attributing different weights to each forecaster. We empirically model the typical risk-return trade-off and augment these models with our measure of uncertainty. We find stronger empirical evidence for an uncertainty-return trade-off than for the traditional risk-return trade-off. Finally, we investigate the performance of a two-factor model with risk and uncertainty in the cross section. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anderson, Evan W.; Ghysels, Eric; Juergens, Jennifer L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technological innovations and aggregate risk premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsu, Po-Hsuan
In this paper, I propose that technological innovations increase expected stock returns and premiums at the aggregate level. I use aggregate patent data and research and development (R&amp;D) data to measure technological innovations in the U.S., and find that patent shocks and R&amp;D shocks have positive and distinct predictive power for U.S. market returns and premiums. Similar patterns are also found in international data including other G7 countries, China, and India. These findings are consistent with previous empirical studies based on firm-level data, and call for further theoretical explanations. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hsu, Po-Hsuan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO pay and the Lake Wobegon Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hayes, Rachel M.; Schaefer, Scott
The "Lake Wobegon Effect,'' which is widely cited as a potential cause for rising CEO pay, is said to occur because no firm wants to admit to having a CEO who is below average, and so no firm allows its CEO's pay package to lag market expectations. We develop a game-theoretic model of this Effect. In our model, a CEO's wage may serve as a signal of match surplus, and therefore affect the value of the firm. We compare equilibria of our model to a full-information case and derive conditions under which equilibrium wages are distorted upward. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hayes, Rachel M.; Schaefer, Scott</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Women in the boardroom and their impact on governance and performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Renee B.; Ferreira, Daniel
We show that female directors have a significant impact on board inputs and firm outcomes. In a sample of US firms, we find that female directors have better attendance records than male directors, male directors have fewer attendance problems the more gender-diverse the board is, and women are more likely to join monitoring committees. These results suggest that gender-diverse boards allocate more effort to monitoring. Accordingly, we find that chief executive officer turnover is more sensitive to stock performance and directors receive more equity-based compensation in firms with more gender-diverse boards. However, the average effect of gender diversity on firm performance is negative. This negative effect is driven by companies with fewer takeover defenses. Our results suggest that man dating gender quotas for directors can reduce firm value for well-governed firms. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, Renee B.; Ferreira, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-section of option returns and volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyal, Amit; Saretto, Alessio
We study the cross-section of stock option returns by sorting stocks on the difference between historical realized volatility and at-the-money implied volatility. We find that a zero-cost trading strategy that is long (short) in the portfolio with a large positive (negative) difference between these two volatility measures produces an economically and statistically significant average monthly return. The results are robust to different market conditions, to stock risks-characteristics, to various industry groupings, to option liquidity characteristics, and are not explained by usual risk factor models. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goyal, Amit; Saretto, Alessio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subsidiary debt, capital structure and internal capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolasinski, Adam C.
I study external debt issued by operating subsidiaries of diversified firms. Consistent with Kahn and Winton's [2004. Moral hazard and optimal subsidiary structure for financial institutions. Journal of Finance 59,2537-2575] model, where subsidiary debt mitigates asset substitution, I find firms are more likely to use subsidiary debt when their divisions vary more in risk. Consistent with subsidiary debt mitigating the free cash flow problem, I find that subsidiaries are more likely to have their own external debt when they have fewer growth options and higher cash flow than the rest of the firm. Finally, I find that subsidiary debt mitigates the "corporate socialism" and "poaching" problems modeled in theories of internal capital markets. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kolasinski, Adam C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank governance, regulation and risk taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Laeven, Luc; Levine, Ross
This paper conducts the first empirical assessment of theories concerning risk taking by banks, their ownership structures, and national bank regulations. We focus on conflicts between bank managers and owners over risk, and we show that bank risk taking varies positively with the comparative power of shareholders within the corporate governance structure of each bank. Moreover, we show that the relation between bank risk and capital regulations, deposit insurance policies, and restrictions on bank activities depends critically on each bank's ownership structure, such that the actual sign of the marginal effect of regulation on risk varies with ownership concentration. These findings show that the same regulation has different effects on bank risk taking depending on the bank's corporate governance structure. (C) 2009 L. Laeven. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Laeven, Luc; Levine, Ross</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging and competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Tingjun; Parlour, Christine A.
We consider firms that, all else equal, wish to minimize variability in their internal capital(due to convex costs of raising external funds). The firms can hedge the cash flow risk of the project, but not that of winning or losing the auction. We characterize optimal hedging and bidding strategies in this competition framework. We show that access to financial markets makes firms bid more aggressively, possibly even above their valuation for the project. In addition, hedging increases the variance of bids and makes firm values more dispersed. Further, with hedging, the covariance of internal capital changes with the risk factor is negative, and is more negative, the higher the correlation of the hedging instrument with the risk factor. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Tingjun; Parlour, Christine A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional industry herding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Nicole; Sias, Richard W.
We examine whether institutional investors follow each other into and out of the same industries. Our empirical results reveal strong evidence of institutional industry herding. The cross-sectional correlation between the fraction of institutional traders buying an industry this quarter and the fraction buying last quarter, for example, averages 40%. Additional tests suggest that correlated signals primarily drive institutional industry herding. Our results also provide empirical support for "style investing'' models. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Choi, Nicole; Sias, Richard W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cashflow risk, systematic earnings revisions, and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Warachka, Mitchell Craig
The returns of stocks are partially driven by changes in their expected cashflow. Using revisions in analyst earnings forecasts, we construct an analyst earnings beta that measures the covariance between the cashflow innovations of an asset and those of the market. A higher analyst earnings beta implies greater sensitivity to market wide revisions in expected cashflow, and therefore higher systematic risk. Our analyst earnings beta captures exposure to macroeconomic fluctuations and has a positive risk premium that provides a partial explanation for the value premium, size premium, and long-term return reversals. From 1984 to 2005, 55.1% of the return variation across book-to-market, size, and long-term return reversal portfolios is captured by their analyst earnings betas. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Warachka, Mitchell Craig</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk sharing, finance, and institutions in international portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fratzscher, Marcel; Imbs, Jean
We develop a standard model to show how transaction costs in international investment affect conventional tests of consumption risk sharing, both in a multilateral and a bilateral setting. We implement the tests in a novel international data set on bilateral holdings of equity, bonds, foreign direct investment (FDI) and bank loans. In our data, high foreign capital holdings are associated with international consumption risk sharing as implied by our theory. This is especially true of investment in equity or bonds, but not of foreign direct investment or bank loans. In our model, the implication is that transaction costs are higher for FDI and international loans. The discrepancy could reflect technological differences, but also the prospect of expropriation, perhaps most stringent for FDI or loans. We argue that expropriation risk is endogenous to both the borrower's institutions and its openness to international markets. The detrimental impact of poor institutions is muted in open economies , where the possibility of subsequent exclusion from world markets deters expropriation of foreign capital. We show the implied effects of institutions prevail in both the cross-section of consumption risk sharing and in observed international investment patterns. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fratzscher, Marcel; Imbs, Jean</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predatory mortgage lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bond, Philip; Musto, David K.; Yilmaz, Bilge
Regulators express growing concern over predatory loans, which we take to mean loans that borrowers should decline. Using a model of consumer credit in which such lending is possible, we identify the circumstances in which it arises both with and without competition. We find that predatory lending is associated with highly collateralized loans, inefficient refinancing of subprime loans, lending without due regard to ability to pay, prepayment penalties, balloon payments, and poorly informed borrowers. Under most circumstances competition among lenders attenuates predatory lending. We use our model to analyze the effects of legislative interventions. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bond, Philip; Musto, David K.; Yilmaz, Bilge</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of institutional investors in seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; He, Shan; Hu, Gang
Do institutional investors possess private information about seasoned equity offerings (SEOs)? If so, do they use this private information to trade in a direction opposite to this information (a manipulative trading role) or in the same direction (an information production role)? We use a large sample of transaction-level institutional trading data to distinguish between these two roles of institutional investors. We explicitly identify institutional SEO allocations for the first time in the literature. We analyze the consequences of the private information possessed by institutional investors for SEO share allocation, institutional trading before and after the SEO and realized trading profitability, and the SEO discount. We find that institutions are able to identify and obtain more allocations in SEOs with better long-run stock returns, they trade in the same direction as their private information, and their post-SEO trading significantly outperforms a naive buy-and-hold trading strategy. Further, more pre-offer institutional net buying and larger institutional SEO allocations are associated with a smaller SEO discount. Overall, our results are consistent with institutions possessing private information about SEOs and with an information production instead of a manipulative trading role for institutional investors in SEOs. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; He, Shan; Hu, Gang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hidden liquidity: An analysis of order exposure strategies in electronic stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Panayides, Marios; Venkataraman, Kumar
Many stock exchanges choose to reduce market transparency by allowing traders to hide some or all of their order size. We study the costs and benefits of order exposure and test hypotheses regarding hidden order usage using a sample of Euronext-Paris stocks, where hidden orders represent 44% of the sample order volume. Our results support the hypothesis that hidden orders are associated with a decreased probability of full execution and increased average time to completion, and fail to support the alternate hypothesis that order exposure causes defensive traders to withdraw from the market. However, exposing rather than hiding order size increases average execution costs. We assess the extent to which non-displayed size is truly hidden and document that the presence and magnitude of hidden orders can be predicted to a significant, but imperfect, degree based on observable order attributes, firm characteristics, and market conditions. Overall, the results indicate that the option to hide order size is valuable, in particular, to patient traders. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Panayides, Marios; Venkataraman, Kumar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Options trading activity and firm valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roll, Richard; Schwartz, Eduardo; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
Options may have an effect on firm value because they help complete markets and stimulate informed trades. However, these benefits are likely to manifest themselves in active, rather than inactive, options markets. Supporting this observation, we find that firms with more options trading have higher values of Tobin's q, after accounting for other determinants of value. Corporate investment in firms with greater options trading is more sensitive to stock prices. Options trading affects firm valuation more strongly in stocks with greater information asymmetry. These results indicate that options trading is positively associated with firm values as well as information production. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roll, Richard; Schwartz, Eduardo; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inexperienced investors and bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Nagel, Stefan
We use mutual fund manager data from the technology bubble to examine the hypothesis that inexperienced investors play a role in the formation of asset price bubbles. Using age as a proxy for managers' investment experience, we find that around the peak of the technology bubble, mutual funds run by younger managers are more heavily invested in technology stocks, relative to their style benchmarks, than their older colleagues. Furthermore, young managers, but not old managers, exhibit trend-chasing behavior in their technology stock investments. As a result, young managers increase their technology holdings during the run-up, and decrease them during the downturn. Both results are in line with the behavior of inexperienced investors in experimental asset markets. The economic significance of young managers' actions is amplified by large inflows into their funds prior to. the peak in technology stock prices. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Nagel, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public and private enforcement of securities laws: Resource-based evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jackson, Howell E.; Roe, Mark J.
Ascertaining which enforcement mechanisms work to protect investors has been both a focus of recent work in academic finance and an issue for policy-making at international development agencies. According to recent academic work, private enforcement of investor protection via both disclosure and private liability rules goes hand in hand with financial market development, but public enforcement fails to correlate with financial development and, hence, is unlikely to facilitate it. Our results confirm the disclosure result but reverse the results on both liability standards and public enforcement. We use securities regulators' resources to proxy for regulatory intensity of the securities regulator. When we do, financial depth regularly, significantly, and robustly correlates with stronger public enforcement. In horse races between these resource-based measures of public enforcement intensity and the most common measures of private enforcement, public enforcement is overall as important as disclosure in explaining financial market outcomes around the world and more important than private liability rules. Hence, policymakers who reject public enforcement as useful for financial market development are ignoring the best currently available evidence. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jackson, Howell E.; Roe, Mark J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do banks price their informational monopoly?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hale, Galina; Santos, Joao A. C.
Theory suggests that banks' private information lets them hold up borrowers for higher interest rates. Since new information about a firm is revealed at the time of its bond IPO, it follows that banks will be forced to adjust their loan interest rates downwards after firms undertake their bond IPO. We test this hypothesis and find that firms are able to borrow at lower interest rates after their bond IPO. Importantly, firms that get their first credit rating at the time of their bond IPO benefit from larger interest rate savings than those that already had a credit rating. These findings provide support for the hypothesis that banks price their informational monopoly. We also find that it is costly for firms to enter the public bond market. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hale, Galina; Santos, Joao A. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Renegotiation of financial contracts: Evidence from private credit agreements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roberts, Michael R.; Sufi, Amir
Using a large sample of private credit agreements between U.S. publicly traded firms and financial institutions, we show that over 90% of long-term debt contracts are renegotiated prior to their stated maturity. Renegotiations result in large changes to the amount, maturity, and pricing of the contract, occur relatively early in the life of the contract, and are rarely a consequence of distress or default. The accrual of new information concerning the credit quality, investment opportunities, and collateral of the borrower, as well as macroeconomic fluctuations in credit and equity market conditions, are the primary determinants of renegotiation and its outcomes. The terms of the initial contract (e.g., contingencies) also play an important role in renegotiations; by altering the structure of the contract in a state contingent manner, renegotiation is partially controlled by the contractual assignment of bargaining power. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roberts, Michael R.; Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Democratizing entry: Banking deregulations, financing constraints, and entrepreneurship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kerr, William R.; Nanda, Ramana
We examine entrepreneurship and creative destruction following US banking deregulations using US Census Bureau data. US banking reforms brought about exceptional growth in both entrepreneurship and business closures. Most of the closures, however, were the new ventures themselves. Although we find evidence for the standard story of creative destruction, the most pronounced impact was a massive increase in churning among new entrants. We argue that creative destruction requires many business failures along with the few great successes. The successes are difficult to identify ex ante, which is why democratizing entry is an import ant trait of well-functioning capital markets. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kerr, William R.; Nanda, Ramana</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market liquidity and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Vivian W.; Noe, Thomas H.; Tice, Sheri
This paper investigates the relation between stock liquidity and firm performance. The study shows that firms with liquid stocks have better performance as measured by the firm market-to-book ratio. This result is robust to the inclusion of industry or firm fixed effects, a control for idiosyncratic risk, a control for endogenous liquidity using two-stage least squares, and the use of alternative measures of liquidity. To identify the causal effect of liquidity on firm performance, we study an exogenous shock to liquidity-the decimalization of stock trading-and show that the increase in liquidity around decimalization improves firm performance. The causes of liquidity's beneficial effect are investigated: Liquidity increases the information content of market prices and of performance-sensitive managerial compensation. Finally, momentum trading, analyst coverage, investor overreaction, and the effect of liquidity on discount rates or expected returns do not appear to drive the results. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fang, Vivian W.; Noe, Thomas H.; Tice, Sheri</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deductio' ad absurdum: CEOs donating their own stock to their own family foundations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yermack, David
I study large charitable stock gifts by Chairmen and Chief Executive Officers (CEOs) of public companies. These gifts, which are not subject to insider trading law, often occur just before sharp declines in their companies' share prices. This timing is more pronounced when executives donate their own shares to their own family foundations. Evidence related to reporting delays and seasonal patterns suggests that some CEOs fraudulently backdate stock gifts to increase personal income tax benefits. CEOs' family foundations hold donated stock for long periods rather than diversifying, permitting CEOs to continue voting the shares. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yermack, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictability and the earnings-returns relation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sadka, Gil; Sadka, Ronnie
This paper studies the effects of predictability on the earnings-returns relation for individual firms and for the aggregate. We demonstrate that prices better anticipate earnings growth at the aggregate level than at the firm level, which implies that random-walk models are inappropriate for gauging aggregate earnings expectations. Moreover, we show that the contemporaneous correlation of earnings growth and stock returns decreases with the ability to predict future earnings. Our results may therefore help explain the apparently conflicting recent evidence that the earnings - returns relation is negative at the aggregate level but positive at the firm level. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sadka, Gil; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Opaque financial reports, R-2, and crash risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hutton, Amy P.; Marcus, Alan J.; Tehranian, Hassan
We investigate the relation between the transparency of financial statements and the distribution of stock returns. Using earnings management as a measure of opacity, we find that opacity is associated with higher R(2)s, indicating less revelation of firm-specific information. Moreover, opaque firms are more prone to stock price crashes, consistent with the prediction of the Jin and Myers [2006. R-2 around the world: new theory and new tests. Journal of Financial Economics 79, 257-292] model. However, these relations seem to have dissipated since the passage of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act, suggesting that earnings management has decreased or that firms can hide less information in the new regulatory environment. (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hutton, Amy P.; Marcus, Alan J.; Tehranian, Hassan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can interest rate volatility be extracted from the cross section of bond yields?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.; Jones, Christopher S.
Most affine models of the term structure with stochastic volatility predict that the variance of the short rate should play a 'dual role' in that it should also equal a linear combination of yields. However, we find that estimation of a standard affine three-factor model results in a variance state variable that, while instrumental in explaining the shape of the yield curve, is essentially unrelated to GARCH estimates of the quadratic variation of the spot rate process or to implied variances from options. We then investigate four-factor affine models. Of the models tested, only the model that exhibits 'unspanned stochastic volatility' (USV) generates both realistic short rate volatility estimates and a good cross-sectional fit. Our findings suggest that short rate volatility cannot be extracted from the cross-section of bond prices. In particular, short rate volatility and convexity are only weakly correlated. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.; Jones, Christopher S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global private information in international equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Bauer, Gregory H.; Schneider, Martin
This paper studies international equity markets when some investors have private information that is valuable for trading in many countries simultaneously. We use a dynamic model of equity trading to show that global private information helps explain US investors' trading behavior and performance. In particular, the model predicts global return chasing (positive co-movement of US investors' net purchases with returns in many countries) which we show to be present in the data. Return chasing in our model can be due to superior performance of US investors, not inferior knowledge or naive trend-following. We also show that trades due to private information are strongly correlated across countries. A common (global) factor accounts for about half their variation. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Bauer, Gregory H.; Schneider, Martin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Share issuance and cross-sectional returns: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McLean, R. David; Pontiff, Jeffrey; Watanabe, Akiko
Share issuance predicts cross-sectional returns in a non-U.S. sample of stocks from 41 different countries. Issuance predictability has greater statistical significance than either size or momentum, and is similar to book-to-market. As in the U.S., the international issuance effect is robust across both small and large firms. Unlike the U.S., the effect is driven more by low returns after share creation rather than positive returns following share repurchases. Issuance return predictability is stronger in countries with greater issuance activity, greater stock market development, and stronger investor protection. The results suggest that the share issuance effect is related to the ease with which firms can issue and repurchase their shares. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McLean, R. David; Pontiff, Jeffrey; Watanabe, Akiko</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt, bargaining, and credibility in firm-supplier relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Livdan, Dmitry
We examine optimal leverage for a downstream firm relying on implicit (self-enforcing) contracts with a supplier. Performing a leveraged recapitalization prior to bargaining increases the firm's share of total surplus. However, the resulting debt overhang limits the range of credible bonuses, resulting in low input quality. Optimal financial structure trades off bargaining benefits of debt within efficiency resulting from overhang. Consistent with empirical evidence, the model predicts that leverage increases with supplier bargaining power (e. g., unionization rates) and decreases with utilization of non-verifiable inputs (e. g., human capital). (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Livdan, Dmitry</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market for corporate control and the cost of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qiu, Jiaping; Yu, Fan
How do bond holders view the existence of an open market for corporate control? Between 1985 and 1991,30 states in the U.S. enacted business combination (BC) laws, raising the cost of corporate takeovers. Relying on these exogenous events, we estimate the influence of the market for corporate control on the cost of debt. We identify different channels through which an open market for corporate control can benefit or harm bondholders: a reduction in managerial slack or the "quiet life," resulting in higher profitability and firm value; a coinsurance effect, in which firms become less risky after being acquired; and an increasing leverage effect, in which bond holder wealth is expropriated through leverage-increasing takeovers. Consistent with the first two mechanisms, we find that the cost of debt rose after the passage of the BC laws; moreover, it rose sharply for firms in non-competitive industries, and for firms rated speculative-grade. In contrast, there is virtually no effect for firms in competitive industries, or firms rated investment-grade. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Qiu, Jiaping; Yu, Fan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity risk and syndicate structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gatev, Evan; Strahan, Philip E.
We decompose syndicated loan risk into credit, market, and liquidity risk and test how these shape syndicate structure. Commercial banks dominate relative to non-banks in loan syndicates that expose lenders to liquidity risk. This dominance is most pronounced when borrowers have high levels of creditor market risk. We then tie commercial banks' advantage in liquidity risk to access to transactions deposits by comparing investments a cross-banks. The results suggest that risk-management considerations matter most for participants relative to lead arrangers. Links from transactions deposits to liquidity exposure, for instance, are more than 50% larger at participants than at lead arrangers. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gatev, Evan; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock splits, trading continuity, and the cost of equity capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Ji-Chai; Singh, Ajai K.; Yu, Wen
We hypothesize that managers use stock splits to attract more uninformed trading so that market makers can provide liquidity services at lower costs, there by increasing investors' trading propensity and improving liquidity. We examine a large sample of stock splits and find that, consistent with our hypothesis, the incidence of no trading decreases and liquidity risk is lower following splits, implying a decline in latent trading costs and a reduced cost of equity capital. Further, split announcement returns are correlated with the improvements in both liquidity levels and liquidity risk. Our analysis suggests nontrivial economic benefits from liquidity improvements, with less liquid firms benefiting more from stock splits. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Ji-Chai; Singh, Ajai K.; Yu, Wen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does religion matter in corporate decision making in America?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hilary, Gilles; Hui, Kai Wai
We examine how corporate culture influences firm behavior. Prior research suggests a link between individual religiosity and risk a version. We find that this relationship also influences organizational behavior. Firms located in counties with higher levels of religiosity display lower degrees of risk exposure, as measured by variances in equity returns or returns on assets. They exhibit a lower investment rate and less growth, but generate a more positive market reaction, when they announce new investments. Finally, chief executive officers are more likely to join a firm with a similar religious environment as in their previous firm when they switch employers. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hilary, Gilles; Hui, Kai Wai</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cost of capital effects and changes in growth expectations around US cross-listings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hail, Luzi; Leuz, Christian
This paper examines whether cross-listing in the U.S. reduces firms' costs of capital. We estimate cost of capital effects implied by market prices and analyst forecasts, which accounts for changes in growth expectations around cross-listings. Firms with cross-listings on U.S. exchanges experience a decrease in their cost of capital between 70 and 120 basis points. These effects are sustained and exist after the Sarbanes-Oxley Act. We find smaller reductions for cross-listings in the over-the-counter market and for exchange-listings from countries with stronger legal institutions. For exchange-traded cross-listings, the cost of capital reduction accounts for over half of the increase in firm value, where as for other types of cross-listings the valuation effects are primarily attributable to contemporaneous revisions in growth expectations. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hail, Luzi; Leuz, Christian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cosmetic mergers: The effect of style investing on the market for corporate control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Zhang, Lei
We study the impact of "style investing'' on the market for corporate control. We argue that the choice of the bidder is influenced by the fact that the merge with a firm that belongs to an investment style more popular with the market may boost the bidder's value. By using data on the flows in mutual funds, we construct a measure of popularity, which relies directly on the identification of sentiment-induced investor demand, rather than being a direct transformation of stock market data. We show that differences in popularity between bidder and target help to explain their pairing. The merger with a more popular target generates a halo effect from the target to the bidder that induces the market to evaluate the assets of the less popular bidder at the (inflated) market value of the more popular target. Both bidder and target premiums are positively related to the difference in popularity between the target and the bidder. However, the target's ability to appropriate the gain is reduced by the fact that its bargaining position is weaker when the bidder's potential for asset appreciation is higher. We document a better short- and medium-term performance of less popular firm staking over more popular firms. The bidder managers engaging in these cosmetic mergers take advantage of the window of opportunity induced by the deal to reduce their stake in the firm under convenient conditions. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Zhang, Lei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are elite universities losing their competitive edge?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, E. Han; Morse, Adair; Zingales, Luigi
We study the location-specific component of research productivity for economics and finance faculty over the last three decades. We find that there was a positive effect of being affiliated with a top 25 university in the 1970s; this effect weakened in the 1980s and disappeared in the 1990s. The decline in elite university fixed effect is due to the reduced importance of physical access to productive research colleagues, which in turn seems due to innovations in communication technology. One implication is that knowledge-based organizations should find it more difficult to capture rents vis-a-vis workers. We find that faculty salaries increased the most where the estimated spillover dropped the most. Despite the loss in local spillovers, elite universities still enjoy an edge in average productivity because of agglomeration of top researchers in prestigious institutions with high long-term research reputations. (C) 2009 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kim, E. Han; Morse, Adair; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Merger negotiations and the toehold puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Betton, Sandra; Eckbo, B. Espen; Thorburn, Karin S.
The substantial control premium typically observed in corporate takeovers makes a compelling case for acquiring target shares (a toehold) in the market prior to launching a bid. Moreover, auction theory suggests that toehold bidding may yield a competitive advantage over rival bidders. Nevertheless. with a sample exceeding 10,000 initial control bids for US public targets, we show that toehold bidding has declined steadily since the early 1980s and is now surprisingly rare. At the same time, the average toehold is large when it occurs (20%), and toeholds are the norm in hostile bids. To explain these puzzling observations, we develop and test a two-stage takeover model where attempted merger negotiations are followed by open auction. With optimal bidding, a toehold imposes a cost on target management, causing some targets to (rationally) reject merger negotiations. Optimal toeholds are therefore either zero (to avoid rejection costs) or greater than a threshold (so that toehold benefits offset rejection costs). The toehold threshold estimate averages 9% across initial bidders, reflecting in part the bidder's opportunity loss of a merger termination agreement. In the presence of market liquidity costs, a threshold of this size may well induce a broad range of bidders to select zero toehold. As predicted, the probability of toehold bidding decreases, and the toehold size increases, with the threshold estimate. The model also predicts a relatively high frequency of toehold bidding in hostile bids, as observed. Overall, our test results are consistent with rational bidder behavior with respect to the toehold decision. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Betton, Sandra; Eckbo, B. Espen; Thorburn, Karin S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convertible bond arbitrage, liquidity externalities, and stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Darwin; Getmansky, Mila; Tookes, Heather
In the context of convertible bond issuance, we examine the impact of arbitrage activity on underlying equity markets. In particular, we use changes in equity short interest following convertible bond issuance to identify convertible bond arbitrage activity and analyze its impact on stock market liquidity and prices for the period 1993 to 2006. There is considerable evidence of arbitrage-induced short selling resulting from issuance. Moreover, we find strong evidence that this activity is systematically related to liquidity improvements in the stock. These results are robust to controlling for the potential endogeneity of arbitrage activity. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choi, Darwin; Getmansky, Mila; Tookes, Heather</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does investor recognition predict returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Ostberg, Per
Merton [1987. A simple model of capital market equilibrium with incomplete information. Journal of Finance 42, 483-510] shows that stocks about which not all investors are informed should yield a return premium. This premium depends on the shadow cost of incomplete information which in turn depends on the shareholder base, relative market size, and idiosyncratic risk. Utilizing a comprehensive database of Swedish shareholdings, we demonstrate that stock returns are positively related to the shadow cost. We also find that the shareholder base is negatively related to returns when controlling for size and idiosyncratic risk. Zero-cost portfolios based on the shadow cost/shareholder base yield substantial trading profits that are never positively correlated with the market and are only modestly explained by the four-factor model. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Ostberg, Per</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are fairness opinions fair? The case of mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kisgen, Darren J.; Qian, Jun Qj; Song, Weihong
Over the period 1994-2003. 80% of targets and 37% of acquirers obtain a third-party assessment of the fairness of a merger or acquisition. These fairness opinions do not affect deal outcomes when used by targets, but they affect deal outcomes when used by acquirers. The deal premium is lower in transactions if the acquirer obtains a fairness opinion, and is further reduced if multiple advisors provide an opinion. However, the acquirer's announcement-period return is 2.3% lower if the acquirer has a fairness opinion, especially if the acquirer pays a high premium, indicating that investors are skeptical of these transactions. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kisgen, Darren J.; Qian, Jun Qj; Song, Weihong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of reverse leveraged buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Jerry; Lerner, Josh
Reverse leveraged buyouts (RLBOs) have received increased public scrutiny but attracted little systematic study. We collect a comprehensive sample of 526 RLBOs between 1981 and 2003 and examine the three-year and five-year stock performance of these offerings. RLBOs appear to perform as well as or better than other initial public offerings and the stock market as a whole, depending on the specification. Evidence exists of a deterioration of returns over time. (C) 2008 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cao, Jerry; Lerner, Josh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why is PIN priced?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duarte, Jefferson; Young, Lance
Recent empirical work suggests that a proxy for the probability of informed trading (PIN) is an important determinant of the cross-section of average returns. This paper examines whether PIN is priced because of information asymmetry or because of other liquidity effects that are unrelated to information asymmetry. Our starting point is a model that decomposes PIN into two components, one related to asymmetric information and one related to illiquidity. In a two-pass Fama-MacBeth [1973. Risk, return, and equilibrium: empirical tests. Journal of Political Economy 81, 607-636] regression, we show that the PIN component related to asymmetric information is not priced, while the PIN component related to illiquidity is priced. We conclude, therefore, that liquidity effects unrelated to information asymmetry explain the relation between PIN and the cross-section of expected returns. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duarte, Jefferson; Young, Lance</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A market-clearing role for inefficiency on a limit order book</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Large, Jeremy
Limit order markets with stationary dynamics attract equal volumes of market orders and uncanceled limit orders, equalizing the supply and demand for liquidity and immediacy. To maintain this balance, market orders must share any benefit obtained by limit order traders from more efficient trading conditions, such as better order queuing policies. Therefore an efficient market places a low price on immediacy, producing small bid-ask spreads. Furthermore, when price-discreteness leads to a mainly constant spread, cutting the price tick raises surplus. This is modeled with a stochastic sequential game, using stationarity considerations to bypass direct analysis of traders' intricate market forecasts. (C) 2008 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Large, Jeremy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dispersion in analysts' earnings forecasts and credit rating</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun; Jostova, Gergana; Philipov, Alexander
This paper shows that the puzzling negative cross-sectional relation between dispersion in analysts' earnings forecasts and future stock returns may be explained by financial distress, as proxied by credit rating downgrades. Focusing on a sample of firms rated by Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P), we show that the profitability of dispersion-based trading strategies concentrates in a small number of the worst-rated firms and is significant only during periods of deteriorating credit conditions. In such periods, the negative dispersion-return relation emerges as low-rated firms experience substantial price drop along with considerable increase in forecast dispersion. Moreover, even for this small universe of worst-rated firms, the dispersion-return relation is non-existent when either the dispersion measure or return is adjusted by credit risk. The results are robust to previously proposed explanations for the dispersion effect such as short-sale constraints and leverage. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun; Jostova, Gergana; Philipov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk, uncertainty, and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, Geert; Engstrom, Eric; Xing, Yuhang
We identify the relative importance of changes in the conditional variance of fundamentals (which we call "uncertainty") and changes in risk aversion in the determination of the term structure, equity prices, and risk premiums. Theoretically, we introduce persistent time-varying uncertainty about the fundamentals in an external habit model. The model matches the dynamics of dividend and consumption growth, including their volatility dynamics and many salient asset market phenomena. While the variation in price-dividend ratios and the equity risk premium is primarily driven by risk aversion, uncertainty plays a large role in the term structure and is the driver of countercyclical volatility of asset returns. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Engstrom, Eric; Xing, Yuhang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Redistribution by insurance market regulation: Analyzing a ban on gender-based retirement annuities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Finkelstein, Amy; Poterba, James; Rothschild, Casey
We illustrate how equilibrium screening models can be used to evaluate the economic consequences of insurance market regulation. We calibrate and solve a model of the United Kingdom's compulsory annuity market and examine the impact of gender-based pricing restrictions. We find that the endogenous adjustment of annuity contract menus in response to such restrictions can undo up to half of the redistribution from men to women that would occur with exogenous Social Security-like annuity contracts. Our findings indicate the importance of endogenous contract responses and illustrate the feasibility of employing theoretical insurance market equilibrium models for quantitative policy analysis. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Finkelstein, Amy; Poterba, James; Rothschild, Casey</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic risk and the cross-section of expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fu, Fangjian
Theories such as Merton [1987. A simple model of capital market equilibrium with incomplete information. Journal of Finance 42, 483-510] predict a positive relation between idiosyncratic risk and expected return when investors do not diversify their portfolio. Ang, Hodrick, Xing, and Zhang [2006. The cross-section of volatility and expected returns. Journal of Finance 61, 259-299], however, find that monthly stock returns are negatively related to the one-month lagged idiosyncratic volatilities. I show that idiosyncratic volatilities are time-varying and thus, their findings should not be used to imply the relation between idiosyncratic risk and expected return. Using the exponential GARCH models to estimate expected idiosyncratic volatilities, I find a significantly positive relation between the estimated conditional idiosyncratic volatilities and expected returns. Further evidence suggests that Ang et al.'s findings are largely explained by the return reversal of a subset of small stocks with high idiosyncratic volatilities. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fu, Fangjian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High idiosyncratic volatility and low returns: International and further</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Hodrick, Robert J.; Xing, Yuhang; Zhang, Xiaoyan
Stocks with recent past high idiosyncratic volatility have low future average returns around the world. Across 23 developed markets, the difference in average returns between the extreme quintile portfolios sorted on idiosyncratic volatility is -1.31% per month, after controlling for world market, size, and value factors. The effect is individually significant in each G7 country. In the United States, we rule out explanations based on trading frictions, information dissemination, and higher moments. There is strong covariation in the low returns to high-idiosyncratic-volatility stocks across countries, suggesting that broad, not easily diversifiable factors lie behind this phenomenon. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Hodrick, Robert J.; Xing, Yuhang; Zhang, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Export incentives, financial constraints, and the (mis)allocation of credit: Micro-level evidence from subsidized export loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zia, Bilal H.
This paper combines an exogenous shock to the supply of subsidized credit with unique loan-level data from the export sector in Pakistan to identify the impact and allocation of such financial incentives. The removal of subsidized credit causes a significant decline in the exports of privately owned firms, while the exports of large, publicly listed, and group network firms are unaffected. Publicly listed firms make no significant adjustments to their balance sheets, and only their profits are reduced, indicating that they are financially unconstrained. Nearly half of all subsidized loans are assigned to such firms, implying a substantial misallocation of credit and an output loss to privately owned firms of 0.75% of GDP. Productivity differences do not explain the heterogeneous effects across firms. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zia, Bilal H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing limits to policy reversal: Evidence from Indian privatizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dastidar, Siddhartha G.; Fisman, Raymond; Khanna, Tarun
We examine the effect of regime change on privatization. In the 2004 Indian election, the pro-reform BJP was unexpectedly defeated by a less reformist coalition. Stock prices of government-controlled companies that had been slated for privatization by the BJP dropped 3.5% relative to private firms. Government-controlled companies that were under study for possible privatization fell 7.5% relative to private firms. This is consistent with investor belief of a "point of no return," where advanced reforms are more difficult to reverse. Further analysis suggests that layoffs, combined with the privatization announcement, served as a credible commitment to privatize. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dastidar, Siddhartha G.; Fisman, Raymond; Khanna, Tarun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who are the active investors? Evidence from venture capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bottazzi, Laura; Da Rin, Marco; Hellmann, Thomas
This paper examines the determinants and consequences of investor activism in venture capital. Using a hand-collected sample of European venture capital deals, it shows the importance of human capital. Venture capital firms with partners that have prior business experience are more active recruiting managers and directors. helping with fundraising, and interacting more frequently with their portfolio companies. Independent venture capital firms are also more active than 'captive' (bank-, corporate-, or government-owned) firms. After controlling for endogeneity, investor activism is shown to be positively related to the success of portfolio companies. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bottazzi, Laura; Da Rin, Marco; Hellmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing patterns around the world: Are small firms different?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Demirguec-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav
Using a firm-level survey database covering 48 countries, we investigate how financial and institutional development affects financing of large and small firms. our database is not limited to large firms but includes small and medium-size firms and data on a broad spectrum of financing sources, including leasing, supplier, development, and informal finance. Small firms and firms in countries with poor institutions use less external finance, especially bank finance. Protection of property rights increases external financing of small firms significantly more than of large firms, mainly due to its effect on bank finance. Small firms do not use disproportionately more leasing or trade finance compared with larger firms, so these financing sources do not compensate for lower access to bank financing of small firms. We also find that larger firms more easily expand external financing when they are constrained than small firms. Finally, we find suggestive evidence that the pecking order holds across countries. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Demirguec-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The divergence of liquidity commonality in the cross-section of stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamara, Avraham; Lou, Xiaoxia; Sadka, Ronnie
This paper demonstrates that the cross-sectional variation of liquidity commonality has increased over the period 1963-2005. The divergence of systematic liquidity can be explained by patterns in institutional ownership over the sample period. We document that our findings are associated with similar patterns in systematic risk. Our analysis also indicates that the ability to diversify systematic risk and aggregate liquidity shocks by holding large-cap stocks has declined. The evidence suggests that the fragility of the US equity market to unanticipated events has increased over the past few decades. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kamara, Avraham; Lou, Xiaoxia; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment frictions and leverage dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsyplakov, Sergey
The paper examines the effect of investment frictions on leverage dynamics, using a model of a firm whose investment projects are (1) indivisible and lumpy, and (2) subject to time-to-build. Regressions on the model-simulated data demonstrate that investment frictions can provide alternative interpretations of the observed leverages shown in the empirical literature. Cross-sectional analysis of firms in the oil and gas extraction industries, as well as analysis across all industries, reveals the evidence that small firms have more volatile investments and longer time-to-build, which may explain the observed differences in leverage dynamics across small and large firms. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tsyplakov, Sergey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Automatic bankruptcy auctions and fire-sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckbo, B. Espen; Thorburn, Karin S.
We test for fire-sale tendencies in automatic bankruptcy auctions. We find evidence consistent with fire-sale discounts when the auction leads to piecemeal liquidation, but not when the bankrupt firm is acquired as a going concern. Neither industry-wide distress nor the industry affiliation of the buyer affect prices in going-concern sales. Bids are often structured as leveraged buyouts, which relaxes liquidity constraints and reduces bidder underinvestment incentives in the presence of debt overhang. Prices ill "prepack" auctions (sales agreements negotiated prior to bankruptcy filing) are on average lower than for in-auction going-concern sales, suggesting that prepacks may help preempt excessive liquidation when the auction is expected to be illiquid. Prepack targets have a greater industry-adjusted probability of refiling for bankruptcy, indicating that liquidation preemption is a risky strategy. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eckbo, B. Espen; Thorburn, Karin S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-ownership, returns, and voting in mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Matvos, Gregor; Ostrovsky, Michael
We show that institutional shareholders of acquiring companies on average do not lose money around public merger announcements, because they hold substantial stakes in the targets and make up for the losses from the acquirers with the gains from the targets. Depending on their holdings in the target, acquirer shareholders generally realize different returns from the same merger, some losing money and others gaining. This conflict of interest is reflected in the mutual fund voting behavior: In mergers with negative acquirer announcement returns, cross-owners are significantly more likely to vote for the merger. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Matvos, Gregor; Ostrovsky, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do private acquirers pay so little compared to public acquirers?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bargeron, Leonce L.; Schlingemann, Frederik P.; Stulz, Rene M.; Zutter, Chad J.
Using the longest event window, we find that public target shareholders receive a 63% (14%) higher premium when the acquirer is a public firm rather than a private equity firm (private operating firm). The premium difference holds with the usual controls for deal and target characteristics, and it is highest (lowest) when acquisitions by private bidders are compared to acquisitions by public companies with low (high) managerial ownership. Further, the premium paid by public bidders (not private bidders) increases with target managerial and institutional ownership. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bargeron, Leonce L.; Schlingemann, Frederik P.; Stulz, Rene M.; Zutter, Chad J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cycles in the IPO market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yung, Chris; Colak, Goenuel; Wang, Wei
We develop a model in which time-varying real investment opportunities lead to time-varying adverse selection in the market for IPOs. The model is consistent with several stylized facts known about the IPO market: economic expansions are associated with a dramatic increase in the number of firms going public, which is in turn positively correlated with underpricing. Adverse selection is procyclical in the sense that dispersion in unobservable quality across firms should be more pronounced during booms. Taking the premise that uncertainty is resolved (and thus private information revealed) over time, we test this hypothesis by looking at long-rum abnormal returns and delisting rates. Consistent with the model, we find (a) greater cross-sectional return variance, and (b) higher incidence of delisting for hot-market IPOs. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All Rights reserved.</description><author>Yung, Chris; Colak, Goenuel; Wang, Wei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Voluntary disclosures around share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, Paul; Khurana, Inder K.; Martin, Xiumin
Managers increase the frequency and magnitude of bad news announcements during the 1-month period prior to repurchasing shares. To a lesser extent, they also increase the frequency and magnitude of good news announcements during the 1-month period following their repurchases. These results are consistent with Barclay and Smith's [1988. Corporate payout policy: Cash dividends versus open-market repurchases. journal of Financial Economics 22, 64-82.] conjecture that share repurchases, unlike dividends, create incentives for managers to manipulate information flows. We further show that managers provide downward-biased earnings forecasts before repurchases and that managers' propensity to alter information flows prior to share repurchases increases with their ownership interest in the firm. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brockman, Paul; Khurana, Inder K.; Martin, Xiumin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The expectation hypothesis of the term structure of very short-term rates: Statistical tests and economic value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Della Corte, Pasquale; Sarno, Lucio; Thornton, Daniel L.
This paper reexamines the validity of the expectation hypothesis (EH) of the term structure of US repo rates ranging in maturity from overnight to 3 months. We extend the work of Longstaff [2000b. The term Structure of very short term rates: new evidence for the expectations hypothesis. journal of Financial Economics 58, 397-415] in two directions: (1) we implement statistical tests designed to increase test power in this context; (2) more important, we assess the economic value of departures from the EH based on criteria of profitability and economic significance in the context of a simple trading strategy. The EH is rejected throughout the term structure examined on the basis of the statistical tests. However, the results Of Our economic analysis are favorable to the EH, suggesting that the statistical rejections of the EH in the repo market are economically insignificant. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Della Corte, Pasquale; Sarno, Lucio; Thornton, Daniel L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification to mitigate expropriation in the tobacco industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beneish, Messod D.; Jansen, Ivo Ph; Lewis, Melissa F.; Stuart, Nathan V.
While it is well established that diversifying acquisitions by large, cash-rich firms destroy shareholder wealth, we document positive abnormal returns to such acquisitions in the tobacco industry. We show that these abnormal returns are associated with proxies for lower expected expropriation costs. Specifically, we show that wealth creation increases in the degree of domestic geographic expansion afforded by the acquisition (increasing tobacco firms' influence in more political districts) and in the liquidity of tobacco firms' assets (converting cash to harder-to-expropriate operating assets). We also show that the threat of expropriation constrains payments to shareholders before expropriation becomes certain in 1998. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beneish, Messod D.; Jansen, Ivo Ph; Lewis, Melissa F.; Stuart, Nathan V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creative destruction and firm-specific performance heterogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chun, Hyunbae; Kim, Jung-Wook; Morck, Randall; Yeung, Bernard
Traditional U.S. industries with higher firm-specific stock return and fundamentals performance heterogeneity use information technology (IT) more intensively and post faster productivity growth in the late 20th century. We argue that this mechanically reflects a wave of Schumpeter's creative destruction disrupting a wide swath of industries, with successful IT adopters unpredictably undermining established firms. This validates endogenous growth theory models of creative destruction and suggests intensified creative destruction as explaining findings associating greater firm-specific performance variation with higher per capita GDPs, economy growth rates, accounting standards, financial system development, and property right protection. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chun, Hyunbae; Kim, Jung-Wook; Morck, Randall; Yeung, Bernard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Big business stability and economic growth: Is what's good for General Motors good for America?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fogel, Kathy; Morck, Randall; Yeung, Bernard
What is good for a country may not be good for its big businesses, at least recently. More turnover in top businesses correlates with faster per capita gross domestic product, productivity, and capital growth; supporting Schumpeter's [1942. Capitalism, Socialism and Democracy, third ed., Harper &amp; Bros., New York, NY] theory of "creative destruction"-innovative firms blooming as stagnant ones wither. These correlations are greater in more developed economies, supporting Aghion and Howitt's [1992. A model of growth through creative destruction. Econometrica 60, 323-351] thesis that creative destruction matters more to economies nearer the technological frontier. More big business turnover also correlates with smaller government, common law, less bank-dependence, stronger shareholder Fights, and greater openness. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fogel, Kathy; Morck, Randall; Yeung, Bernard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms pay dividends? International evidence on the determinants of dividend policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, David J.; Osobov, Igor
In the US, Canada, UK, Germany, France, and Japan, the propensity to pay dividends is higher among larger, more profitable firms, and those for which retained earnings comprise a large fraction of total equity. Although there are hints of reductions in the propensity to pay dividends in most of the sample countries over the 1994-2002 period, they are driven by a failure of newly listed firms to initiate dividends when expected to do so. Dividend abandonment and the failure to initiate by existing nonpayers are economically unimportant except in Japan. Moreover, in each country, aggregate dividends have not declined and are concentrated among the largest. most profitable firms. Finally, outside of the US there is little evidence of a systematic positive relation between relative prices of dividend paying and non-paying firms and the propensity to pay dividends. Overall, these findings cast doubt on signaling, clientele. and catering explanations for dividends, but support agency cost-based lifecycle theories. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Denis, David J.; Osobov, Igor</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate misreporting and bank loan contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, John R.; Li, Si; Qiu, Jiaping
This paper is the first to study the effect of financial restatement on bank loan contracting. Compared with loans initiated before restatement, loans initiated after restatement have significantly higher spreads, shorter maturities, higher likelihood of being secured, and More covenant restrictions. The increase in loan spread is significantly larger for fraudulent restating firms than other restating firms. We also find that after restatement, the number of lenders per loan declines and firms pay higher upfront and annual fees. These results are consistent with banks using tighter loan contract terms to overcome risk and information problems arising from financial restatements. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All Rights reserved.</description><author>Graham, John R.; Li, Si; Qiu, Jiaping</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who makes acquisitions? CEO overconfidence and the market's reaction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malmendier, Ulrike; Tate, Geoffrey
Does CEO overconfidence help to explain merger decisions? Overconfident CEOs overestimate their ability to generate returns. As a result, they overpay for target companies and undertake value-destroying mergers. The effects are strongest if they have access to internal financing. We test these predictions using two proxies for overconfidence: CEOs' personal over-investment in their company and their press portrayal. We find that the odds of making an acquisition are 65% higher if the CEO is classified as overconfident. The effect is largest if the merger is diversifying and does not require external financing. The market reaction at merger announcement (-90 basis points) is significantly more negative than for non-overconfident CEOs (-12 basis points). We consider alternative interpretations including inside information, signaling, and risk tolerance. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malmendier, Ulrike; Tate, Geoffrey</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do auctions induce a winner's curse? New evidence from the corporate takeover market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boone, Audra L.; Mulherin, J. Harold
We contrast the winner's curse hypothesis and the competitive market hypothesis as potential explanations for the observed returns to bidders in corporate takeovers. The winner's curse hypothesis posits suboptimal behavior in which winning bidders fail to adapt their strategies to the level of competition and the amount of uncertainty in the takeover environment and predicts that bidder returns are inversely related to the level of competition in a given deal and to the uncertainty in the value of the target. Our measure of takeover competition comes from a unique data set on the auction process that occurs prior to the announcement of a takeover. In our empirical estimation, we control for the endogeneity between bidder returns and the level of competition in takeover deals. Controlling for endogeneity, we find that the returns to bidders are not significantly related to takeover competition. We also find that uncertainty in the value of the target does not reduce bidder returns. Related analysis indicates that prestigious investment banks do not promote overbidding. Analysis of post-takeover operating performance also fails to find any negative effects of takeover competition. As a whole, the results indicate that the breakeven returns to bidders in corporate takeovers stem not from the winner's curse but from the competitive market for targets that occurs predominantly prior to the public announcement of bids. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boone, Audra L.; Mulherin, J. Harold</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividends and share repurchases in the European Union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Eije, Henk; Megginson, William L.
We examine cash dividends and share repurchases from 1989 to 2005 in the 15 nations that were members of the European Union before May 2004. As ill the United States, the fraction of European firms paying dividends declines, while total real dividends paid increase and share repurchases surge. We also show that financial reporting frequency is associated with higher payout, and that privatized companies account for almost one-quarter of total cash dividends and share repurchases. Our regression analyses indicate that increasing fractions of retained earnings to equity do not increase the likelihood of cash payouts, whereas company age does. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>von Eije, Henk; Megginson, William L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rights offerings, takeup, renounceability, and underwriting status</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balachandran, Balasingham; Faff, Robert; Theobald, Michael
Rights offerings in Australia provide valuable choices to the issuer in terms of both underwriting and renounceability. We formulate a set of hypotheses from a quality signaling perspective, affording an analysis of the key interrelations between quality, underwriting status, renounceability, takeup, and subscription price discount. We analyse rights offerings from two perspectives: market reaction to rights announcements and identification of the factors driving the choice of issue type. Evidence strongly supports the relation between quality signals and issue type. Using a robustly constructed takeup variable, we establish empirical relations between takeup, underwriting status, and renounceability that differ significantly from those previously reported, but which are consistent with the hypotheses developed in this paper. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balachandran, Balasingham; Faff, Robert; Theobald, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Striking oil: Another puzzle?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Driesprong, Gerben; Jacobsen, Ben; Maat, Benjamin
Changes in oil prices predict stock market returns worldwide. We find significant predictability in both developed and emerging markets. These results cannot be explained by time-varying risk premia as oil price changes also significantly predict negative excess returns. Investors seem to underreact to information in the price of oil. A rise in oil prices drastically lowers future stock returns. Consistent with the hypothesis of a delayed reaction by investors, the relation between monthly stock returns and lagged monthly oil price changes strengthens once we introduce lags of several trading days between monthly stock returns and lagged monthly oil price changes. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Driesprong, Gerben; Jacobsen, Ben; Maat, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information flows within financial conglomerates: Evidence from the banks-mutual funds relation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Rehman, Zahid
We study how information flows within financial conglomerates by analyzing the relations between mutual funds and banks that belong to the same financial group. We investigate the effect that the lending behavior of affiliated banks has on the portfolio choice of the mutual funds that are part of the same group. We show that funds (fund families) increase their stakes in the firms that borrow from their affiliated banks in the period following the deal by far greater amounts than other unaffiliated funds (fund families). We provide evidence that this strategy is information-driven. The performance of the positions of affiliated funds in the stocks of borrowing firms exceeds that of their other positions in nonborrowing stocks located in the same industry as well as that of other stocks having similar characteristics by up to 1.6% per month. Funds increase (decrease) their stock holdings in those borrowing stocks that subsequently provide positive (negative) abnormal returns, suggesting that they exploit privileged inside information not available to other market participants. This behavior is prevalent largely in funds located in close geographic proximity to their lending banks. Furthermore, it is exhibited mostly by young, small, and poorly performing fund families. Our evidence points to information flows within conglomerates through informal channels such as personal acquaintances. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Rehman, Zahid</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advisors and asset prices: A model of the origins of bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Scheinkman, Jose; Xiong, Wei
We develop a model of asset price bubbles based on the communication process between advisors and investors. Advisors are well-intentioned and want to maximize the welfare of their advisees (like a parent treats a child). But only some advisors understand the new technology (the tech-savvies): others do not and can only make a downward-biased recommendation (the old-fogies). While smart investors recognize the heterogeneity in advisors, naive ones mistakenly take whatever is said at face value. Tech-savvies innate their forecasts to signal that they are not old-fogies, since more accurate information about their type improves the welfare of investors in the future. A bubble arises for a wide range of parameters, and its size is maximized when there is a mix of smart and naive investors in the economy. Our model suggests an alternative Source for stock over-valuation in addition to investor overreaction to news and sell-side bias. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Scheinkman, Jose; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the importance of retail banking relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Puri, Manju; Rocholl, Joerg
We use proprietary data to analyze the importance of retail banking relationships to commercial banks and their depositors when banks underwrite securities. We find lead underwriters' retail customers benefit as they demand and end up with significantly more of the highly underpriced issues. We find it is actual underpricing beyond that predicted by grey markets that drive the differential demand from the lead bank retail clientele, suggesting that banks pass on information about underpriced initial public offerings to their retail depositors. We analyze banks' incentives for such behavior and find evidence of banks benefiting through retail cross-selling-both brokerage accounts and consumer loans increase significantly. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Puri, Manju; Rocholl, Joerg</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can real options explain financing behavior?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tserlukevich, Yuri
Trade-off models commonly invoke financial transaction costs in order to explain observed leverage fluctuations. This paper offers an alternative explanation based on real options. The model is frictionless on the financing side but incorporates irreversibility and fixed costs of investment. Results obtained from Simulating the model are broadly consistent with observed financing patterns. Market leverage ratios are negatively related to profitability, mean-reverting, and depend on past stock returns. The gradual and lumpy leverage adjustments can occur in the absence of financial transaction costs. This evidence shows that incorporating real frictions into structural models increases their explanatory power. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tserlukevich, Yuri</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt and managerial rents in a real-options model of the firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Myers, Stewart C.
We present a theory of capital investment and debt and equity financing in a real-options model of a public corporation. The theory assumes that managers maximize the present value of their future compensation (managerial rents), subject to constraints imposed by outside shareholders' property rights to the firm's assets. Absent bankruptcy costs, managers follow an optimal debt policy that generates efficient investment and disinvestment. We show how bankruptcy Costs can distort both investment and disinvestment. We also show how managers' personal wealth constraints can lead to delayed investment and increased reliance on debt financing. Changes in cash flow can cause changes in investment by tightening or loosening the wealth constraints. Firms with weaker investor protection adopt higher debt levels. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Myers, Stewart C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How common are common return factors across the NYSE and Nasdaq?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyal, Amit; Perignon, Christophe; Villa, Christophe
We entertain the possibility of pervasive factors that are not common across two (or more) groups of securities. We propose and implement a general procedure to estimate the space spanned by common and group-specific pervasive factors. In our empirical analysis, we study the factor structure of excess returns on stocks traded on the NYSE and Nasdaq using our methodology. We find that there are only two common pervasive factors that govern the returns for both NYSE and Nasdaq. At the same time, the NYSE and Nasdaq each have one more group-specific factor that is not the same across the two exchanges. Our results point to the absence of complete similarity between the factors driving the returns on these exchanges. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goyal, Amit; Perignon, Christophe; Villa, Christophe</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why firms purchase property insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aunon-Nerin, Daniel; Ehling, Paul
We investigate whether corporate finance incentives affect the extent of corporate hedging with property insurance. Using a database that contains detailed insurance information, we document a positive relation between the expected costs of distress and property insurance coverage. We also show that the dividend payout ratio is negatively associated with property insurance coverage, consistent with the view that firms with high payout ratios insure a smaller fraction of properties due to cash flows in excess of investment needs, easy access to capital markets, or both. Different incentives are important for the insurance deductible and limit of coverage, and the deductible and limit of coverage are substitutes. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aunon-Nerin, Daniel; Ehling, Paul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option valuation with long-run and short-run volatility components</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Ornthanalai, Chayawat; Wang, Yintian
This paper presents a new model for the valuation of European options, in which the volatility of returns consists of two components. One is a long-run component and can be modeled as fully persistent. The other is short-run and has a zero mean. Our model can be viewed as an affine version of Engle and Lee [ 1999. A permanent and transitory component model of stock return volatility. In: Engle, R., White, H. (Eds.), Cointegration, Causality, and Forecasting: A Festschrift in Honor of Clive WJ. Granger. Oxford University Press, New York, pp. 475-497], allowing for easy valuation of European options. The model substantially outperforms a benchmark single-component volatility model that is well established in the literature, and it fits options better than a model that combines conditional heteroskedasticity and Poisson-normal jumps. The component model's superior performance is partly due to its improved ability to model the smirk and the path of spot volatility, but its most distinctive feature is its ability to model the volatility term structure. This feature enables the component model to jointly model long-maturity and short-maturity options. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Ornthanalai, Chayawat; Wang, Yintian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do investors value smooth performance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rountree, Brian; Weston, James P.; Allayannis, George
This paper presents empirical evidence that cash-flow volatility is negatively valued by investors. The magnitude of the effect is substantial with a 1% increase in cash-flow volatility, resulting in approximately a 0.15% decrease in firm value. We show that this increase, however, is not associated with earnings smoothing resulting from managers' accrual estimates, Our results are consistent with a preference by the market for less volatile cash flows and suggest that managers' efforts to produce smooth financial statements add Value, but only via the cash component of earnings. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rountree, Brian; Weston, James P.; Allayannis, George</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of the transition to secondary market trading of IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhaohui; Wilhelm, William J.
We develop a model in which investment banks and institutional investors collaborate in smoothing an initial public offering's (IPOs) transition to secondary market trading. Their intervention promotes welfare under the assumption that significant new information arrives in the market in the immediate aftermath of the IPO. Under this assumption, it is optimal to stage the offering and suboptimal to commit to selling shares at a uniform price. The optimal strategy yields an economic rationale for secondary market price stabilization for IPOs carried out via a well-coordinated network of repeat institutional investors. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Zhaohui; Wilhelm, William J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does firm value move too much to be justified by subsequent changes in cash flow?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larrain, Boria; Yogo, Motohiro
The appropriate measure of cash flow for valuing corporate assets is net payout, which is the sum of dividends, interest, and net repurchases of equity and debt. Variation in net payout yield, the ratio of net payout to asset value, is mostly driven by movements in expected cash flow growth, instead of movements in discount rates. Net payout yield is less persistent than dividend yield and implies much smaller variation in long-horizon discount rates. Therefore, movements in the value of corporate assets can be justified by changes in expected future cash flow. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Larrain, Boria; Yogo, Motohiro</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural models of credit risk are useful: Evidence from hedge ratios on corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schaefer, Stephen M.; Strebulaev, Ilya A.
Structural models of credit risk provide poor predictions of bond prices. We show that, despite this, they provide quite accurate predictions of the sensitivity of corporate bond returns to changes in the value of equity (hedge ratios). This is important since it suggests that the poor performance of structural models may have more to do with the influence of non-credit factors rather than their failure to capture the credit exposure of corporate debt. The main result of this paper is that even the simplest of the structural models [Merton, R., 1974. On the pricing of corporate debt: the risk structure of interest rates. Journal of Finance 29, 449-470] produces hedge ratios that are not rejected in time-series tests. However, we find that the Merton model (with or without stochastic interest rates) does not capture the interest rate sensitivity of corporate debt, which is substantially lower than would be expected from conventional duration measures. The paper also shows that corporate bond prices are related to a number of rnarket-wide factors such as the Farna-French SMB (small minus big) factor in a way that is not predicted by structural models. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved</description><author>Schaefer, Stephen M.; Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do boards pay attention when institutional investor activists "just vote no"?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Del Guercio, Diane; Seery, Laura; Woidtke, Tracie
We examine "just vote no" campaigns, a recent innovation in low-cost shareholder activist tools whereby activists encourage their fellow shareholders to withhold votes toward a director's election to express dissatisfaction with management performance or the firm's corporate governance structure. Grundfest [1993. Just vote no: a minimalist strategy for dealing with barbarians inside the gates. Stanford Law Review 45, 857-937] argues that a substantial withheld vote motivates directors to take immediate action to avoid further embarrassment. We find a variety of supportive evidence, including operating performance improvements and abnormal disciplinary chief executive officer (CEO) turnover, indicating that such campaigns induce boards to take actions in shareholders' interests. Furthermore, abnormal turnover is robust to controlling for concurrent events and firm- and CEO-specific controls. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Del Guercio, Diane; Seery, Laura; Woidtke, Tracie</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The timing of financing decisions: An examination of the correlation in financing waves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, Amy K.; Dittmar, Robert F.
Why do corporate financing events occur in waves? We challenge recent evidence of the importance of valuation cycles in driving financing waves by documenting that the aggregate pattern of stock repurchases mirrors that of equity issuance and mergers, despite repurchases involving an opposite transaction. We then show that trends in financing decisions result from differing responses to the same economic stimulus: growth in GDP. Specifically, economic expansion reduces the cost of equity relative to the cost of debt, inducing firms to issue equity, and increases cash flow and also causes varying degrees of uncertainty, increasing stock repurchases. We document similar trends and provide similar motivation for merger waves. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dittmar, Amy K.; Dittmar, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The importance of IRS monitoring to debt pricing in private firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guedhami, Omrane; Pittman, Jeffrey
We examine the link between Internal Revenue Service (IRS) monitoring and yield spreads on private firms' 144A bond issues. After controlling for security-specific and other firm-specific determinants, we provide evidence that debt financing is cheaper when the probability of a face-to-face IRS audit is higher. Consistent with another prediction, we find that IRS oversight has a stronger impact on bond pricing for private firms with high ownership concentration, which suffer worse agency problems between controlling shareholders and outside investors. Collectively, our research implies that IRS monitoring plays a valuable corporate governance role by reducing information asymmetry evident in borrowing costs. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guedhami, Omrane; Pittman, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The only game in town: Stock-price consequences of local bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Kubik, Jeffrey D.; Stein, Jeremy C.
Theory suggests that, in the presence of local bias, the price of a stock should be decreasing in the ratio of the aggregate book value of firms in its region to the aggregate risk tolerance of investors in its region. Using data on U.S. states and Census regions, we find clear-cut support for this proposition. Most of the variation in the ratio of interest comes from differences across regions in aggregate book value Per capita. Regions with low population density-e.g., the Deep South-are home to relatively few firms per capita, which leads to higher stock prices via an "only-game-in-town" effect. (c) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Kubik, Jeffrey D.; Stein, Jeremy C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks and innovation: Microeconometric evidence on Italian firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benfratello, Luigi; Schiantarelli, Fabio; Sembenelli, Alessandro
In this paper we investigate the effect of local banking development on firms' innovative activities, using a rich data set on innovation for a large number of Italian firms over the 1990s. There is evidence that banking development affects the probability Of Process innovation, particularly for firms in high-tech sectors, in Sectors more dependent upon external finance, and for firms that are small. The evidence for product innovation is much weaker and not robust. There is also some evidence that banking development reduces the cash flow sensitivity of fixed investment spending, particularly for small firms, and that it increases the probability they will engage in R&amp;D. (C) 2008 Elsevier B,V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benfratello, Luigi; Schiantarelli, Fabio; Sembenelli, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can hedging tell the full story? Reconciling differences in United States aggregate- and industry-level exchange rate risk premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Hunter, Delroy M.
While the importance of currency movements to industry competitiveness is theoretically well established, there is little evidence that Currency risk impacts US industries. Applying a conditional asset pricing model to 36 US industries, we find that all industries have a Significant Currency premium that adds about 2.47 percentage points to the cost of equity and accounts for approximately 11.7% of total risk premium in absolute Value. Cross-industry Variation in the Currency premium is explained by foreign income, industry competitiveness, leverage, liquidity, and other industry characteristics, while its time variation is explained by US aggregate foreign trade, monetary Policy, growth Opportunities, and other macro variables. The results indicate that methodological weakness, not hedging, explains the insignificant industry currency risk premium found in previous work, thus resolving the puzzle that currency risk premium is important at the aggregate stock market level, but not at the industry level. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Hunter, Delroy M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the use of peer groups contribute to higher pay and less efficient compensation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bizjak, John M.; Lemmon, Michael L.; Naveen, Lalitha
We provide empirical evidence on how the practice of competitive benchmarking affects chief executive officer (CEO) pay. We find that the use of benchmarking is widespread and has a significant impact on CEO compensation. One view is that benchmarking is inefficient because it can lead to increases in executive pay not tied to firm performance. A contrasting view is that benchmarking is a practical and efficient mechanism used to gauge the market wage necessary to retain valuable human capital. Our empirical results generally support the latter view. Our findings also suggest that the documented asymmetry in the relationship between CEO pay and luck is explained by the firm's desire to adjust pay for retention purposes and is not the result of rent-seeking behavior oil the part of the CEO. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bizjak, John M.; Lemmon, Michael L.; Naveen, Lalitha</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture capital reputation and investment performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nahata, Rajarishi
I propose a new measure of venture capital (VC) firm reputation and analyze its performance implications on private companies. Controlling for portfolio company quality and other VC-specific factors including experience, connectedness, syndication, industry competition, exit conditions, and investment environment, I find companies backed by more reputable VCs by initial public offering (IPO) capitalization share (based on cumulative market capitalization of IPCs backed by the VC), are more likely to exit successfully, access public markets faster, and have higher asset productivity at IPOs. Further tests suggest VCs' IPO Capitalization share effectively captures both VC screening and monitoring expertise. My findings have financial implications for limited partners and entrepreneurs regarding their VC-sorting activities. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nahata, Rajarishi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, sell-side research, and market making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madureira, Leonardo; Underwood, Shane
The interaction between an investment bank's research and market making arms may have important implications for the trading of a firm's stock. We investigate the impact that research has on the liquidity provided by the bank's market maker. Utilizing a large sample of Nasdaq firms, we show that market makers whose banks also provide research coverage provide more liquidity and contribute more to price discovery than do market makers without such research coverage. Finally, we show that such "affiliated" market makers are less affected by uncertainty following earnings announcements. Our results provide new evidence on the Sources of liquidity improvements for Nasdaq firms, and Suggest that the information produced by banks in the sell-side research process is beneficial to their market makers. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Madureira, Leonardo; Underwood, Shane</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reply to: Dividend policy: Reconciling DD with MM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, Harry; DeAngelo, Linda
nan</description><author>DeAngelo, Harry; DeAngelo, Linda</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend policy: Reconciling DD with MM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Handley, John C.
Miller and Modigliani [1961. Dividend policy, growth and the valuation of shares. Journal of Business 34, 411-433] establish the irrelevance of dividend policy in a perfect capital market. DeAngelo and DeAngelo [2006. The irrelevance of the MM dividend irrelevance theorem. Journal of Financial Economics 79, 293-315.] suggest the Miller-Modigliani analysis is flawed and consequently their central conclusion is incorrect. The purpose of this paper is to show the vital role played by stock repurchases and agency costs in reconciling the two opposing views. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Handley, John C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate asset purchases and sales: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Warusawitharana, Missaka
Purchases and sales of operating assets by firms generated $162 billion for shareholders over the past 20 years. This contrasts sharply with the evidence on mergers. This paper characterizes the behavior of value-maximizing firms, which could grow organically, purchase existing assets, or sell assets. The approach yields an endogenous selection model that links asset purchases and sales to fundamental properties of the firm. Empirical tests confirm the predictions of the model. In particular, return on assets and size strongly predict when firms purchase or sell assets, and the transaction size covaries with the value of capital employed by the firm. These findings indicate that corporate asset purchases and sales are consistent with efficient investment decisions. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Warusawitharana, Missaka</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How and why do small firms manage interest rate risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vickery, James
Although small firms are particularly sensitive to interest rates and other shocks, empirical work on corporate risk management has focused instead on large public companies. This paper studies fixed-rate and adjustable-rate loans to see how small firms manage their exposure to interest rate risk. Credit-constrained firms are found to match significantly more often with fixed-rate loans, consistent with prior research that shows the supply of credit shrinks during periods of rising interest rates. Banks originate a higher share of adjustable-rate loans than other lenders, ameliorating maturity mismatch and exposure to the lending channel of monetary policy. Time-series patterns in the fixed-rate share are consistent with recent evidence on debt market timing. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vickery, James</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seasonality in the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heston, Steven L.; Sadka, Ronnie
This paper presents a new pattern in the cross-section of expected stock returns. Stocks tend to have relatively high (or low) returns every year in the same calendar month. We recognize the annual cross-sectional autocorrelation pattern documented in Jegadeesh [1990. Evidence of predictable behavior of security returns. Journal of Finance 45, 881-898] at lags of 12, 24, and 36 months as part of a general pattern that lasts up to 20 annual lags, superimposed on the general momentum/reversal patterns. This pattern explains an economically and statistically significant magnitude of the crosssectional variation in average stock returns. Volume and volatility exhibit similar seasonal patterns but they do not explain the seasonality in returns. The pattern is independent of size, industry, earnings announcements, dividends, and fiscal year. The results are consistent with the existence of a persistent seasonal effect in stock returns. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heston, Steven L.; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volume, liquidity, and liquidity risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Timothy C.
Many classes of microstructure models, as well as intuition, suggest that it should be easier to trade when markets are more active. In the data, however, volume and liquidity seem unrelated over time. This paper offers an explanation for this fact based on a simple frictionless model in which liquidity reflects the average risk-bearing capacity of the economy and volume reflects the changing contribution of individuals to that average. Volume and liquidity are unrelated in the model, but volume is positively related to the variance of liquidity, or liquidity risk. Empirical evidence from the U.S. government bond and stock markets supports this new prediction. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Johnson, Timothy C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inter-firm linkages and the wealth effects of financial distress along the supply chain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hertzel, Michael G.; Li, Zhi; Officer, Micah S.; Rodgers, Kimberly J.
Extant research examines the extent to which bankruptcy has intra-industry valuation consequences. This study broadens the investigation by examining the wealth effects of distress and bankruptcy filing for suppliers and customers of filing firms. On average, important wealth effects occur prior to and at bankruptcy filings and extend beyond industry competitors along the supply chain. Specifically, distress related to bankruptcy filings is associated with negative and significant stock price effects for suppliers. Supplier wealth effects are more negative when intra-industry contagion is more severe. We also investigate the importance of industry structure, specialized product nature, and leverage on supply chain effects. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hertzel, Michael G.; Li, Zhi; Officer, Micah S.; Rodgers, Kimberly J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and pay-for-performance: The impact of earnings management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornett, Marcia Millon; Marcus, Alan J.; Tehranian, Hassan
We ask whether the apparent impact of governance structure and incentive-based compensation on firm performance stands up when measured performance is adjusted for the effects of earnings management. Institutional ownership of shares, institutional investor representation on the board of directors, and the presence of independent outside directors on the board all reduce the use of discretionary accruals. These factors largely offset the impact of option compensation, which strongly encourages earnings management. Adjusting for the impact of earnings management substantially increases the measured importance of governance variables and dramatically decreases the impact of incentive-based compensation on corporate performance. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cornett, Marcia Millon; Marcus, Alan J.; Tehranian, Hassan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Boards: Does one size fit all?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coles, Jeffrey L.; Daniel, Naveen D.; Naveen, Lalitha
This paper reexamines the relation between firm value and board structure. We find that complex firms, which have greater advising requirements than simple firms, have larger boards with more outside directors. The relation between Tobin's Q and board size is U-shaped, which, at face value, suggests that either very small or very large boards are optimal. This relation, however, arises from differences between complex and simple firms. Tobin's Q increases (decreases) in board size for complex (simple) firms, and this relation is driven by the number of outside directors. We find some evidence that R&amp;D-intensive firms, for which the firm-specific knowledge of insiders is relatively important, have a higher fraction of insiders on the board and that, for these firms, Q increases with the fraction of insiders on the board. Our findings challenge the notion that restrictions on board size and management representation on the board necessarily enhance firm value. (c) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Coles, Jeffrey L.; Daniel, Naveen D.; Naveen, Lalitha</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of board structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linck, James S.; Netter, Jeffry M.; Yang, Tina
Using a comprehensive sample of nearly 7,000 firms from 1990 to 2004, we examine the corporate board structure, trends, and determinants. Guided by recent theoretical work, we find that board structure across firms is consistent with the costs and benefits of the board's monitoring and advising roles. Our models explain as much as 45% of the observed variation in board structure. Further, small and large firms have dramatically different board structures. For example, board size fell in the 1990s for large firms, a trend that reversed at the time of mandated reforms, while board size was relatively flat for small and medium-sized firms. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V All rights reserved.</description><author>Linck, James S.; Netter, Jeffry M.; Yang, Tina</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Motivations for public equity offers: An international perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Woojin; Weisbach, Michael S.
This paper examines the motivations for public equity offers, using a sample of 17,226 initial public offerings and 13,142 seasoned equity offerings from 38 countries between 1990 and 2003. We estimate the uses of funds raised in both initial and seasoned offerings. Firms appear to spend incremental dollars on both R&amp;D and capital expenditures, consistent with the investment financing explanation of equity issues. However, consistent with the mispricing explanation, high market to book firms tend to save more cash and offer a higher fraction of secondary shares in SEOs than low market to book firms. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Woojin; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The expected value premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Long; Petkova, Ralitsa; Zhang, Lu
Fama and French [2002. The equity premium. Journal of Finance 57, 637-659] estimate the equity premium using dividend growth rates to measure expected rates of capital gain. We apply their method to study the value premium. From 1945 to 2005, the expected value premium is on average 6.1% per annum, consisting of an expected dividend growth component of 4.4% and an expected dividend price ratio component of 1.7%. Unlike the equity premium, the value premium has been largely stable over the last half century. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Long; Petkova, Ralitsa; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and market efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, Tarun; Roll, Richard; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
Short-horizon return predictability from order flows is an inverse indicator of market efficiency. We find that such predictability is diminished when bid-ask spreads are narrower, and has declined over time with the minimum tick size. Variance ratio tests suggest that prices were closer to random walk benchmarks in the more liquid decimal regime than in other ones. These findings indicate that liquidity stimulates arbitrage activity, which, in turn, enhances market efficiency. Further, as the tick size decreased, open-close/close-open return variance ratios increased, while return autocorrelations decreased. This suggests an increased incorporation of private information into prices during more liquid regimes. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chordia, Tarun; Roll, Richard; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial distress and corporate risk management: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Purnanandam, Amiyatosh
This paper extends the current theoretical models of corporate risk-management in the presence of financial distress costs and tests the model's predictions using a comprehensive data set. I show that the shareholders optimally engage in ex-post (i.e., after the debt issuance) risk-management activities even without a pre-commitment to do so. The model predicts a positive (negative) relation between leverage and hedging for moderately (highly) leveraged firms. Consistent with the theory, empirically I find a non-monotonic relation between leverage and hedging. Further, the effect of leverage on hedging is higher for firms in highly concentrated industries. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Purnanandam, Amiyatosh</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating the real effect of bank branching deregulation: Comparing contiguous counties across US state borders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Rocco R.
This paper proposes a new methodology to evaluate the economic effect of state-specific policy changes, using bank-branching deregulations in the US as an example. The new method compares economic performance of pairs of contiguous counties separated by state borders, where on one side restrictions on statewide branching were removed relatively earlier, to create a natural "regression discontinuity" setup. The study uses a total of 285 pairs of contiguous counties along 38 segments of such regulation change borders to estimate treatment effects for 23 separate deregulation events taking place between 1975 and 1990. To distinguish real treatment effects from those created by data-snooping and spatial correlations, fictitious placebo deregulations are randomized (permutated) on another 32 segments of non-event borders to establish empirically a statistical table of critical values for the estimator. The method determines that statistically significant growth accelerations can be established at a &gt; 90% confidence level in five (and none prior to 1985) out of the 23 deregulation events examined. "Hinterland counties" within the still-regulated states, but farther away from the state borders, are used as a second control group to consider and reject the possibility that cross-border spillover of deregulation effects may invalidate the empirical design. (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Huang, Rocco R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board classification and managerial entrenchment: Evidence from the market for corporate control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, Thomas W.; Becher, David A.; Lemmon, Michael L.
This paper considers the relation between board classification, takeover activity, and transaction outcomes for a panel of firms between 1990 and 2002. Target board classification does not change the likelihood that a firm, once targeted, is ultimately acquired. Moreover, shareholders of targets with a classified board realize bid returns that are equivalent to those of targets with a single class of directors, but receive a higher proportion of total bid surplus. Board classification does reduce the likelihood of receiving a takeover bid, however, the economic effect of bid deterrence on the value of the firm is quite small. Overall, the evidence is inconsistent with the conventional wisdom that board classification is an antitakeover device that facilitates managerial entrenchment. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bates, Thomas W.; Becher, David A.; Lemmon, Michael L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm-specific information and the efficiency of investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chari, Anusha; Henry, Peter Blair
In the three-year period following stock market liberalizations, the growth rate of the typical firm's capital stock exceeds its pre-liberalization mean by an average of 4.1 percentage points. Cross-sectional changes in investment are significantly correlated with the signals about fundamentals embedded in the stock price changes that occur upon liberalization. Panel-data estimations show that a 10-percentage point increase in a firm's expected future sales growth predicts a 2.9- to 3.5-percentage point increase in the growth rate of its capital stock. Country-specific changes in the cost of capital drive changes in investment but firm-specific changes in the cost of capital do not. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chari, Anusha; Henry, Peter Blair</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Second time lucky? Withdrawn IPOs that return to the market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dunbar, Craig G.; Foerster, Stephen R.
We investigate issuers withdrawing an IPO (after security regulation filings) that return later for a successful offering. Venture capital backing and reputation of the lead underwriter are key factors in predicting successful return. The possibility of returning has a significant impact on the decision to withdraw and the pricing of offerings that succeed. Our sample of returning IPOs also provides a unique setting to investigate underwriter switching after a withdrawal but before a successful IPO. We find that switching occurs in response to poor bank performance and when switching firms "graduate" to banks that have high industry market shares. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dunbar, Craig G.; Foerster, Stephen R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The evolving relation between earnings, dividends, and stock repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Skinner, Douglas J.
This paper examines how the relation between earnings and payout policy has evolved over the last three decades. Three principal groups of payers have emerged: firms that pay dividends and make regular repurchases, firms that make regular repurchases, and firms that make occasional repurchases. Firms that only pay dividends are largely extinct. Repurchases are increasingly used in place of dividends, even for firms that continue to pay dividends. While other factors help explain the timing of repurchases, the overall level of repurchases is fundamentally determined by earnings. The results suggest that repurchases are now the dominant form of payout. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Skinner, Douglas J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing and takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morellec, Erwan; Zhdanov, Alexel
This paper analyzes the interaction between financial leverage and takeover activity. We develop a dynamic model of takeovers in which the financing strategies of bidding firms and the timing and terms of takeovers are jointly determined. In the paper, capital structure plays the role of a commitment device, and determines the outcome of the acquisition contest. We demonstrate that there exists an asymmetric equilibrium in financing policies with endogenous leverage, bankruptcy, and takeover terms, in which the bidder with the lowest leverage wins the takeover contest. Based on the resulting equilibrium, the model generates a number of new predictions. In particular, the model predicts that the leverage of the winning bidder is below the industry average and that acquirers should lever up after the takeover consummation. The model also relates the dispersion in leverage ratios to various industry characteristics, such as cash flow volatility or bankruptcy costs. (C) 2008 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Morellec, Erwan; Zhdanov, Alexel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and firm cash holdings in the US</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Mansi, Sattar A.; Maxwell, William F.
Using governance metrics based on antitakeover provisions and inside ownership, we find that firms with weaker corporate governance structures actually have smaller cash reserves. When distributing cash to shareholders, firms with weaker governance structures choose to repurchase instead of increasing dividends, avoiding future payout commitments. The combination of excess cash and weak shareholder rights leads to increases in capital expenditures and acquisitions. Firms with low shareholder rights and excess cash have lower profitability and valuations. However, there is only limited evidence that the presence of excess cash alters the overall relation between governance and profitability. In the US, weakly controlled managers choose to spend cash quickly on acquisitions and capital expenditures, rather than hoard it. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Mansi, Sattar A.; Maxwell, William F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The probability and magnitude of information events</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Odders-White, Elizabeth R.; Ready, Mark J.
Models of adverse selection risk generally assume that market makers offset expected losses to informed traders with expected gains from the uninformed. We recognize that the expected loss captures a combination of two effects: (1) the probability that some traders have private information, and (2) the likely magnitude of that information. We use a maximum-likelihood approach to separately estimate the probability and magnitude of private information events for NYSE-listed stocks from 1993 through 2003. The results shed light on the price discovery process and have implications for many areas of finance. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Odders-White, Elizabeth R.; Ready, Mark J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial incentives, capital reallocation, and the business cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisfeldt, Andrea L.; Rampini, Adriano A.
We argue that when managers have private information about the productivity of assets under their control and receive private benefits, substantial bonuses are required to induce less productive managers to declare that capital should be reallocated. The need to provide incentives for managers to relinquish control links executive compensation to capital reallocation and managerial turnover over the business cycle, rendering them procyclical if expected managerial compensation increases when more managers are hired. Moreover, capital is less productively deployed in downturns because agency costs make reallocation more costly. Empirically, we find that both CEO turnover and executive compensation are remarkably procyclical. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eisfeldt, Andrea L.; Rampini, Adriano A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board size and the variability of corporate performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Shijun
This study provides empirical evidence that firms with larger boards have lower variability of corporate performance. The results indicate that board size is negatively associated with the variability of monthly stock returns, annual accounting return on assets, Tobin's Q, accounting accruals, extraordinary items, analyst forecast inaccuracy, and R&amp;D spending, the level of R&amp;D expenditures, and the frequency of acquisition and restructuring activities. The results are consistent with the view that it takes more compromises for a larger board to reach consensus, and consequently, decisions of larger boards are less extreme, leading to less variable corporate performance. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cheng, Shijun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic risk premiums, stochastic skewness in currency options, and stochastic discount factors in international economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren
We develop models of stochastic discount factors in international economies that produce stochastic risk premiums and stochastic skewness in currency options. We estimate the models using time-series returns and option prices on three currency pairs that form a triangular relation. Estimation shows that the average risk premium in Japan is larger than that in the US or the UK, the global risk premium is more persistent and volatile than the country-specific risk premiums, and investors respond differently to different shocks. We also identify high-frequency jumps in each economy but find that only downside jumps are priced. Finally, our analysis shows that the risk premiums are economically compatible with movements in stock and bond market fundamentals. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The intertemporal relation between expected returns and risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.
This paper explores the time-series relation between expected returns and risk for a large cross section of industry and size/book-to-market portfolios. I use a bivariate generalized autoregressive conditional heteroskedasticity (GARCH) model to estimate a portfolio's conditional covariance with the market and then test whether the conditional covariance predicts time-variation in the portfolio's expected return. Restricting the slope to be the same across assets, the risk-return coefficient is highly significant with a risk-aversion coefficient (slope) between one and five. The results Lire robust to different portfolio formations, alternative GARCH specifications, additional state variables, and small sample biases. When conditional covariances are replaced by conditional betas, the risk premium on beta is estimated to be in the range of 3% to 5% per annum and is statistically significant. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dominant shareholders, corporate boards, and corporate value: A cross-country analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahya, Jay; Dimitrov, Orlin; McConnell, John J.
We investigate the relation between corporate Value and the proportion of the board made up of independent directors in 799 firms with a dominant shareholder across 22 Countries. We find a positive relation, especially in Countries with weak legal protection for shareholders. The findings suggest that a dominant shareholder, were he so inclined, could offset, at least in part, the documented value discount associated with weak country-level shareholder protection by appointing an 'independent' board. The cost to the dominant shareholder of doing so is the loss in perquisites associated with being a dominant shareholder. Thus, not all dominant shareholders choose independent boards. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dahya, Jay; Dimitrov, Orlin; McConnell, John J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing the commonality across alternative measures of liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korajczyk, Robert A.; Sadka, Ronnie
We estimate latent factor models of liquidity, aggregated across various liquidity measures. Shocks to assets' liquidity have a common component across measures which accounts for most of the explained variation in individual liquidity measures. We find that across-measure systematic liquidity is a priced factor while within-measure systematic liquidity does not exhibit additional pricing information. Controlling for across-measure systematic liquidity risk, there is some evidence that liquidity, as a characteristic of assets, is priced in the cross-section. Our results are robust to the inclusion of other equity characteristics and risk factors, such as market capitalization, book-to-market, and momentum. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Korajczyk, Robert A.; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry, information dissemination and the effect of regulation FD on the cost of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duarte, Jefferson; Han, Xi; Harford, Jarrad; Young, Lance
This paper considers the impact of Regulation Fair Disclosure (FD) on firms' information environments and costs of capital. For NYSE/Amex firms we find little evidence of a change in the cost of capital attributable to Regulation FD. For Nasdaq firms we find that Regulation FD increased firms' costs of capital by 10-19 basis points per annum though the statistical significance of this change is modest for some of our models. We also show substantial cross-sectional variation in the cost If capital changes. We find that cost of capital changes were negatively related to both pre-regulation firm size and PIN. In addition to the findings regarding Regulation FD, this research contributes to a growing literature that documents links between firms' information environments and their costs of capital. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duarte, Jefferson; Han, Xi; Harford, Jarrad; Young, Lance</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture capital investment cycles: The impact of public markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gompers, Paul; Kovner, Anna; Lerner, Josh; Scharfstein, David
It is well documented that the venture capital industry is highly volatile and that much of this volatility is associated with shifting valuations and activity in Public equity markets. This paper examines how changes in public market signals affected venture capital investing between 1975 and 1998. We find that venture capitalists with the most industry experience increase their investments the most when public market signals become more favorable. Their reaction to an increase is greater than the reaction of venture capital organizations with relatively little industry experience and those with considerable experience but in other industries. The increase in investment rates does not affect the success of these transactions adversely to a significant extent. These findings are consistent with the view that venture capitalists rationally respond to attractive investment Opportunities signaled by public market shifts. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gompers, Paul; Kovner, Anna; Lerner, Josh; Scharfstein, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst coverage and earnings management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Fang
What is the role of information intermediaries in corporate governance? This paper examines equity analysts' influence on managers' earnings management decisions. Do analysts serve as external monitors to managers, or do they put excessive pressure on managers? Using multiple measures of earnings management, I find that firms followed by more analysts manage their earnings less. To address the potential endogencity problem of analyst coverage, I use two instrumental variables based on change in broker size and on firm's inclusion in the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index, and I find that the results are robust. Finally, given the number of covering analysts, analysts from top brokers and more experienced analysts have stronger effects against earnings management. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yu, Fang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The consequences to managers for financial misrepresentation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Lee, D. Scott; Martin, Gerald S.
We track the fortunes of all 2,206 individuals identified as responsible parties for all 788 Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and Department of Justice (DOJ) enforcement actions for financial misrepresentation from January 1, 1978 through September 30, 2006. Fully 93% lose their jobs by the end of the regulatory enforcement period. Most are explicitly fired. The likelihood of ouster increases with the cost of the misconduct to shareholders and the quality of the firm's governance. Culpable managers also bear substantial financial losses through restrictions on their future employment, their shareholdings in the firm, and SEC fines. A sizeable minority (28%) face criminal charges and penalties, including jail sentences that average 4.3 years. These results indicate that the individual perpetrators of financial misconduct face significant disciplinary action. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Lee, D. Scott; Martin, Gerald S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incumbents and protectionism: The political economy of foreign entry liberalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chari, Anusha; Gupta, Nandini
This paper investigates the influence of incumbent firms on the decision to allow foreign direct investment into an industry. Using data from India's economic reforms, the results show that firms in concentrated industries are more successful at preventing foreign entry, state-owned firms are more successful at stopping foreign entry than privately-owned firms, and profitable state-owned firms are more successful at stopping foreign entry than unprofitable state-owned firms. The pattern of foreign entry liberalization supports the private interest view of policy implementation and suggests that it may be necessary to reduce the influence of state-owned firms to optimally enact reforms. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chari, Anusha; Gupta, Nandini</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internationalization and the evolution of corporate valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gozzi, Juan Carlos; Levine, Ross; Schmukler, Sergio L.
By documenting the evolution of Tobin's g before, during, and after firms internationalize, this paper provides evidence on the bonding, segmentation, and market-timing theories of internationalization. We find that Tobin's g does not rise after internationalization, even relative to domestic firms. Instead, g rises significantly before and during the internationalization year, but then falls sharply in the following year, quickly relinquishing the increases of the previous years. In decomposing these dynamics, we find that market capitalization rises before internationalization and remains high, while corporate assets increase during internationalization. The evidence supports the theory that financial internationalization facilitates corporate expansion, but challenges the theory that internationalization produces an enduring effect on g by bonding firms to a better corporate governance system. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gozzi, Juan Carlos; Levine, Ross; Schmukler, Sergio L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do local analysts know more? A cross-country study of the performance of local analysts and foreign analysts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, Kee-Hong; Stulz, Rene M.; Tan, Hongping
This paper examines whether analysts resident in a country make more precise earnings forecasts for firms in that country than non-resident analysts. Using a sample of 32 countries, we find an economically and statistically significant local analyst advantage even after controlling for firm and analyst characteristics. The local advantage is high in countries where earnings are smoothed more, less information is disclosed by firms, and firm idiosyncratic information explains a smaller fraction of stock returns. It is negatively related to whether a firm has foreign assets and to market participation by foreign investors and by institutions, and positively related to holdings by insiders. The extent to which U.S. investors underweight a country's stocks is positively related to that country's local analyst advantage. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bae, Kee-Hong; Stulz, Rene M.; Tan, Hongping</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political connections and preferential access to finance: The role of campaign contributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claessens, Stijn; Feijen, Erik; Laeven, Luc
Using novel indicators of political connections constructed from campaign contribution data, we show that Brazilian firms that provided contributions to (elected) federal deputies experienced higher stock returns than firms that did not around the 1998 and 2002 elections. This suggests that contributions help shape policy on a firm-specific basis. Using a firm fixed effects framework to mitigate the risk that unobserved firm characteristics distort the results, we find that contributing firms substantially increased their bank financing relative to a control group after each election, indicating that access to bank finance is an important channel through which political connections operate. We estimate the economic costs of this rent seeking over the two election cycles to be at least 0.2% oh gross domestic product per annum. (C) 2007 Elsevier Ltd All rights reserved.</description><author>Claessens, Stijn; Feijen, Erik; Laeven, Luc</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The colors of investors' money: The role of institutional investors around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro
We study the role of institutional investors around the world using a comprehensive data set of equity holdings from 27 countries. We find that all institutional investors have a strong preference for the stock of large firms and firms with good governance, while foreign institutions tend to overweight firms that are cross-listed in the U.S. and members of the Morgan Stanley Capital International World Index. Firms with higher ownership by foreign and independent institutions have higher firm valuations, better operating performance, and lower capital expenditures. Our results indicate that foreign and independent institutions, with potentially fewer business ties to firms, are involved in monitoring corporations worldwide. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mixing family with business: A study of Thai business groups and the families behind them</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertrand, Marianne; Johnson, Simon; Samphantharak, Krislert; Schoar, Antoinette
How does the structure of the families behind business groups affect the group's organization, governance, and performance? We construct a unique dataset of family trees and business groups for 93 of the largest business families in Thailand. We find a strong positive association between family size and family involvement in the ownership and control of the family businesses. The founders' sons play a central role in both ownership and board membership, especially when the founder of the group is dead. Greater involvement by sons is also associated with lower firm-level performance, especially when the founder is dead. One hypothesis that emerges from our analysis is that part of the decay of family-run groups over time is due to the dilution of ownership and control across a set of equally powerful descendants of the founder, which creates a "race to the bottom" in tunneling resources out of the group firms. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bertrand, Marianne; Johnson, Simon; Samphantharak, Krislert; Schoar, Antoinette</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The law and economics of self-dealing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Djankov, Simeon; La Porta, Rafael; Lopez-de-Silanes, Florencio; Shleifer, Andrei
We present a new measure of legal protection of minority shareholders against expropriation by corporate insiders: the anti-self-dealing index. Assembled with the help of Lex Mundi law firms, the index is calculated for 72 countries based on legal rules prevailing in 2003, and focuses on private enforcement mechanisms, such as disclosure, approval, and litigation, that govern a specific self-dealing transaction. This theoretically grounded index predicts a variety of stock market outcomes, and generally works better than the previously introduced index of anti-director rights. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Djankov, Simeon; La Porta, Rafael; Lopez-de-Silanes, Florencio; Shleifer, Andrei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Darden conference issue: Capital raising in emerging economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harvey, Campbell R.; Lipson, Marc L.; Warnock, Francis E.
nan</description><author>Harvey, Campbell R.; Lipson, Marc L.; Warnock, Francis E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does international cross-listing improve the information environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandes, Nuno; Ferreira, Miguel A.
We investigate whether cross-listing in the U.S. affects the information environment for non-U.S. stocks. Our findings suggest cross-listing has an asymmetric impact on stock price informativeness around the world, as measured by firm-specific stock return variation. Cross-listing improves price informativeness for developed market firms. For firms in emerging markets, however, cross-listing decreases price informativeness. The added analyst coverage associated with cross-listing likely explains the findings in emerging markets, rather than changes in liquidity, ownership, or accounting quality. Our results indicate that the added analyst coverage fosters the production of marketwide information, rather than firm-specific information. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fernandes, Nuno; Ferreira, Miguel A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure with risky foreign investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, Mihir A.; Foley, C. Fritz; Hines, Jannes R.
Firms facing significant business risks have incentives to mitigate the costs of these risks by adjusting their capital structures. This paper investigates this link by analyzing the exposures of multinational firms to political risk. The evidence indicates that returns on investment in politically risky countries are more volatile than returns elsewhere. Multinational firms reduce their leverage in response to these political risks: a one standard deviation increase in foreign political risk is associated with 3.5% reduced leverage. The effect of foreign political risks on leverage is most pronounced for firms in industries whose returns are most susceptible to political influence. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Desai, Mihir A.; Foley, C. Fritz; Hines, Jannes R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Latent liquidity: A new measure of liquidity, with an application to corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mahanti, Sriketan; Nashikkar, Amrut; Subrahmanyam, Marti; Chacko, George; Mallik, Gaurav
We present a new measure of liquidity known as "latent liquidity" and apply it to a unique corporate bond database. Latent liquidity is defined as the weighted average turnover of investors who hold a bond, in which the weights are the fractional investor holdings. It can be used to measure liquidity in markets with sparse transactions data. For bonds that trade frequently, our measure has predictive power for both transaction costs and the price impact of trading, over and above trading activity and bond-specific characteristics thought to be related to liquidity. Additionally, this measure exhibits relationships with bond characteristics similar to those of other trade-based measures. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mahanti, Sriketan; Nashikkar, Amrut; Subrahmanyam, Marti; Chacko, George; Mallik, Gaurav</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ultimate ownership and control in Russia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernykh, Lucy
I investigate ultimate control and ownership patterns in Russian publicly traded companies. I show that these companies are controlled either by the state or by anonymous private owners. Federal and regional governments' control is exercised through extensive use of pyramids. Private owners widely exploit legal loopholes that allow them to mask their holdings and identities through nominee and foreign offshore arrangements. The comparison of formal and informal ownership disclosure reveals that the typical anonymous owners are insiders and that in virtually all cases the market participants "know" who the real owners are. Collectively, the evidence suggests that the legal weaknesses in disclosure requirements are important determinants of country-specific ownership and control structures. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chernykh, Lucy</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock price informativeness, cross-listings, and investment decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, Thierry; Gehrig, Thomas
We show that a cross-listing enables firms to obtain, from the stock market, more precise information about the value of their growth opportunities. Thus, cross-listed firms make better investment decisions and trade at a premium. This theory of cross-listings implies that the sensitivity of investment to stock prices is larger for cross-listed firms. Moreover, the cross-listing premium is positively related to the size of growth opportunities and negatively related to the quality of managerial information. The sensitivity of the premium to the size of growth opportunities increases with factors that strengthen the impact of the cross-listing on price informativeness. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Foucault, Thierry; Gehrig, Thomas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firms as buyers of last resort</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Wang, Jiang; Yu, Jialin
We develop a model to explore the asset pricing implications of firms being buyers of last resort for their own stocks. Those with more ability to repurchase shares when prices drop far below fundamental value (i.e., less financially constrained firms) should have lower short-horizon return variances (controlling for fundamental variance) than other firms. Using standard proxies for financing constraints such as past repurchases and firm age, we find strong Support for this predicted relation. We also find that this relation is stronger in the U.S. after 1982 when regulatory reforms lowered the legal cost of conducting repurchases as well as in countries where share repurchases are legally easier to execute. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Wang, Jiang; Yu, Jialin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure and international debt shifting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huizinga, Harry; Laeven, Luc; Nicodeme, Gaetan
This paper presents a model of a multinational firm's optimal debt policy that incorporates international taxation factors. The model yields the prediction that a multinational firm's indebtedness in a country depends on a weighted average of national tax rates and differences between national and foreign tax rates. These differences matter as multinationals have an incentive to shift debt to high-tax countries. The predictions of the model are tested using a novel firm-level dataset for European multinationals and their subsidiaries, combined with newly collected data on the international tax treatment of dividend and interest streams. Our empirical results show that a foreign subsidiary's capital structure reflects local corporate tax rates as well as tax rate differences vis-A-vis the parent firm and other foreign subsidiaries, although the overall economic effect of taxes on leverage appears to be small. Ignoring the international debt shifting arising from differences in national tax rates would understate the impact of national taxes on debt policies by about 25%. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huizinga, Harry; Laeven, Luc; Nicodeme, Gaetan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial finance: Banks versus venture capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Winton, Andrew; Yerramilli, Vijay
We analyze how entrepreneurial firms choose between two funding institution: banks, which monitor less intensively and face liquidity demands from their own investors, and venture capitalists, who can monitor more intensively but face a higher cost of capital because of the liquidity constraints that they impose on their own investors. Because the firm's manager prefers continuing the firm over liquidating it and aggressive (risky) continuation strategies over conservative (safe) continuation strategies, the institution must monitor the firm and exercise some control over its decisions. Bank finance takes the form of debt, whereas venture capital finance often resembles convertible debt. Venture capital finance is optimal only when the aggressive continuation strategy is not too profitable, ex ante; the uncertainty associated with the risky continuation strategy (strategic uncertainty) is high; and the firm's cash flow distribution is highly risky and positively skewed, with low probability of success, low liquidation value, and high returns if successful. A decrease in venture capitalists' cost of capital encourages firms to switch from safe strategies and bank finance to riskier strategies and venture capital finance, increasing the average risk of firms in the economy. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Winton, Andrew; Yerramilli, Vijay</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How is macro news transmitted to exchange rates?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evans, Martin D. D.; Lyons, Richard K.
Macro news can affect currency prices directly and indirectly via order flow. Past research shows that the direct effects of scheduled macro news account for less than 10% of daily price variance. This paper shows that the arrival of macro news can account for more than 30% of daily price variance. Two features of our analysis account for this finding: (1) We consider the broad spectrum of macro news items that market participants observe, not just scheduled announcements. (2) We allow the arrival of news to affect prices indirectly via its impact on the volatility of order flow. Our analysis shows that order flow variations contribute more to currency price dynamics following the arrival of public macro news than at other times. This is not consistent with news effects being common knowledge that is impounded in price directly. Roughly two-thirds of the total effect of macro news on the DM/$ exchange rate is transmitted via order flow. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Evans, Martin D. D.; Lyons, Richard K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The power of the pen and executive compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Core, John E.; Guay, Wayne; Larcker, David F.
We examine the press' role in monitoring and influencing executive compensation practice using more than 11,000 press articles about CEO compensation from 1994 to 2002. Negative press coverage is more strongly related to excess annual pay than to raw annual pay, suggesting a sophisticated approach by the media in selecting CEOs to cover. However, negative coverage is also greater for CEOs with more option exercises, suggesting the press engages in some degree of "sensationalism." We find little evidence that firms respond to negative press coverage by decreasing excess CEO compensation or increasing CEO turnover. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Core, John E.; Guay, Wayne; Larcker, David F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dumb money: Mutual fund flows and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frazzini, Andrea; Lamont, Owen A.
We use mutual fund flows as a measure of individual investor sentiment for different stocks, and find that high sentiment predicts low future returns. Fund flows are dumb money-by reallocating across different mutual funds, retail investors reduce their wealth in the long run. This dumb money effect is related to the value effect: high sentiment stocks tend to be growth stocks. High sentiment also is associated with high corporate issuance, interpretable as companies increasing the supply of shares in response to investor demand. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frazzini, Andrea; Lamont, Owen A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading imbalances, predictable reversals, and cross-stock price pressure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrade, Sandro C.; Chang, Charles; Seasholes, Mark S.
We test the implications of a multi-asset equilibrium model in which a finite number of risk-averse liquidity providers accommodate non-informational trading imbalances. These imbalances generate predictable reversals in stock returns. An imbalance in one stock also affects the prices of other stocks. The magnitude of the cross-stock price pressure depends on the correlations of the stocks' underlying cash flows. The model implies that non-informational trading increases the volatility of stock returns. We confirm the model's implications using data from the Taiwan Stock Exchange. (C) 2008 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Andrade, Sandro C.; Chang, Charles; Seasholes, Mark S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>