<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFE7</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Financial expertise of directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guner, A. Burak; Malmendier, Ulrike; Tatec, Geoffrey
We analyze how directors with financial expertise affect corporate decisions. Using a novel panel data set, we find that financial experts exert significant influence, though not necessarily in the interest of shareholders. When commercial bankers join boards, external funding increases and investment-cash flow sensitivity decreases. However, the increased financing flows to firms with good credit but poor investment opportunities. Similarly, investment bankers on boards are associated with larger bond issues but worse acquisitions. We find little evidence that financial experts affect compensation policy. The results suggest that increasing financial expertise on boards may not benefit shareholders if conflicting interests (e.g., bank profits) are neglected. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guner, A. Burak; Malmendier, Ulrike; Tatec, Geoffrey</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decomposing swap spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldhutter, Peter; Lando, David
We analyze a six-factor model for Treasury bonds, corporate bonds, and swap rates and decompose swap spreads into three components: a convenience yield from holding Treasuries, a credit risk element from the underlying LIBOR rate, and a factor specific to the swap market. The convenience yield is by far the largest component of spreads. There is a discernible contribution from credit risk as well as from a swap-specific factor with higher variability which in certain periods is related to hedging activity in the mortgage-backed security market. The model also sheds light on the relation between AA hazard rates and the spread between LIBOR rates and General Collateral repo rates and on the level of the riskless rate compared to swap and Treasury rates. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Feldhutter, Peter; Lando, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ex-dividend day trading: Who, how, and why? Evidence from the Finnish market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rantapuska, Elias
This study examines the ex-dividend day trading behavior of all investors in the Finnish stock market. Consistent with dynamic dividend clientele theories, investors with a preference for dividend income buy shares cum-dividend and sell ex-dividend; the reverse is true for investors with the opposite preference. Investors also engage in overnight arbitrage, earning on average a 2% overnight return on their invested capital. Trades at the investor-level reveal that idiosyncratic risk is an important determinant in the choice of stock for short-term ex-day trading. Furthermore, transaction costs and dividend yield jointly determine whether the volume of short-term trading activity is nonzero. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rantapuska, Elias</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reaching out: Access to and use of banking services across countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Demirguc-Kunt, Ash; Martinez Peria, Maria Soledad
This paper is a first attempt at measuring financial sector outreach and investigating its determinants. First, we present new indicators of banking sector outreach across 99 countries, constructed from aggregate data provided by bank regulators. Second, we show that our indicators closely predict harder-to-collect micro-level statistics of household and firm use of banking services, and are associated with measures of firm financing obstacles in the expected way. Finally, we explore the association between our outreach indicators and standard determinants of financial sector depth. We find many similarities but also some differences in the determinants of outreach and depth. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Demirguc-Kunt, Ash; Martinez Peria, Maria Soledad</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do managers intentionally use repurchase tender offers to signal private information? Evidence from firm financial reporting behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Louis, Henock; White, Hal
Signaling is the most commonly cited explanation for stock repurchases in the academic literature. Yet, there is little evidence on whether managers intentionally use repurchases as signaling devices. Using a firm's financial reporting behavior to infer managerial intent, we find evidence suggesting that managers intentionally use fixed-price repurchase tender offers to signal undervaluation. In contrast, we find no evidence that managers use Dutch-auction tender offers to signal undervaluation. Instead, firms engaging in Dutch-auction repurchases act as if they are trying to deflate their earnings prior to the repurchases to further reduce the repurchasing price. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Louis, Henock; White, Hal</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio manager ownership and fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khorana, Ajay; Servaes, Henri; Wedge, Lei
This paper documents the range of portfolio manager ownership in the funds they manage and examines whether higher ownership is associated with improved future performance. Almost half of all managers have ownership stakes in their funds, though the absolute investment is modest. Future risk-adjusted performance is positively related to managerial ownership, with performance improving by about 3 basis points for each basis point of managerial ownership. These findings persist after controlling for various measures of fund board effectiveness. Fund manager ownership is higher in funds with better past performance, lower front-end loads, smaller size, longer managerial tenure, and funds affiliated with smaller families. It is also higher in funds with higher board member compensation and in equity funds relative to bond funds. Future performance is positively related to the component of ownership that can be predicted by other variables, as well as the unpredictable component. Our findings support the notion that managerial ownership has desirable incentive alignment attributes for mutual fund investors and indicate that the disclosure of this information is useful in making portfolio allocation decisions. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khorana, Ajay; Servaes, Henri; Wedge, Lei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Geographical segmentation of US capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Bo
Demographic variation in savings behavior can be exploited to provide evidence on segmentation in US bank loan markets. Cities with a large fraction of seniors have higher volumes of bank deposits. Since many banks rely heavily on deposit financing, this affects local loan supply and economic activity. I show a positive effect of local deposit supply on local outcomes, including the number of firms, the number of manufacturing firms, and the number of new firms started. The effect is stronger in industries that are heavily dependent on external finance. The deregulation of intrastate branching reduced the effect of local deposit supply by approximately a third. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Becker, Bo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The risk return tradeoff in the long run: 1836-2003</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lundblad, Christian
Previous studies typically find a statistically insignificant relation between the market risk premium and its expected volatility. Further, several of these studies estimate a negative risk return tradeoff, contrary to the predictions of mainstream theory. Using simulations, I demonstrate that even 100 years of data constitute a small sample that may easily lead to this finding even though the true risk return tradeoff is positive. Small-sample inference is plagued by the fact that conditional volatility has almost no explanatory power for realized returns. Using the nearly two century history of U.S. equity market returns from Schwert [1990. Indexes of United States stock prices from 1802 to 1987. Journal of Business 63, 399-426], 1 estimate a positive and statistically significant risk return tradeoff. Finally, exploratory analysis suggests a role for a time-varying relation linked to the changing nature of the U.S. economy. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lundblad, Christian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Laddering in initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hao, Grace Qing
Laddering is a practice whereby the allocating underwriter requires the ladderer to buy additional shares of the issuer in the aftermarket as a condition for receiving shares at the offer price. This paper identifies factors that create incentives to engage in this type of manipulation and models the effect of laddering on initial public offering (IPO) pricing. I show that laddering has a bigger effect on the market price of IPOs with greater expected underpricing (without laddering) and greater expected momentum in the aftermarket; laddering increases the IPO offer price, the aftermarket price, and the money left on the table but does not necessarily increase the percentage underpricing; laddering contributes to long-run underperformance and creates a negative correlation between short-run and long-run returns; and profit-sharing increases the extent of laddering and the percentage underpricing. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hao, Grace Qing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of corporate board size and composition: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boone, Audra L.; Field, Laura Casares; Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Raheja, Charu G.
Using a unique panel dataset that tracks corporate board development from a firm's IPO through 10 years later, we find that: (i) board size and independence increase as firms grow and diversify over time; (ii) board size-but not board independence-reflects a tradeoff between the firm-specific benefits and costs of monitoring; and (iii) board independence is negatively related to the manager's influence and positively related to constraints on that influence. These results indicate that economic considerations-in particular, the specific nature of the firm's competitive environment and managerial team-help explain cross-sectional variation in corporate board size and composition. Nonetheless, much of the variation in board structures remains unexplained, suggesting that idiosyncratic factors affect many individual boards' characteristics. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boone, Audra L.; Field, Laura Casares; Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Raheja, Charu G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive stock options and IPO underpricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lowry, Michelle; Murphy, Kevin J.
In about one-third of US IPOs between 1996 and 2000, executives received stock options with an exercise price equal to the IPO offer price rather than a market-determined price. Among firms with such "IPO options", 58% of top executives realize a net benefit from underpricing: the gain from the options exceeds the loss from the dilution of their pre-IPO shareholdings. If executives can influence either the IPO offer price or the timing and terms of their stock option grants, there should be a positive relation between IPO option grants and underpricing. We find no evidence of such a relation. Our results contrast sharply with the emerging literature on managerial self-dealing at shareholder expense. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lowry, Michelle; Murphy, Kevin J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk, return, and dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Liu, Jun
Using only the definition of returns, together with a transversality assumption, we demonstrate that given a dividend process, any one of three variables-expected return, return volatility, and the price-dividend ratio-completely determines the other two. By parameterizing only one of these processes, common empirical specifications place strong, and sometimes counter-factual, restrictions on the dynamics of the other variables. Our findings lend insight into the nature of the risk-return relation and the predictability of stock returns. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Liu, Jun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Untitled</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stulz, Rene M.
nan</description><author>Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of conflicts of interest in financial institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mehran, Hamid; Stulz, Rene M.
A conflict of interest exists when a party to a transaction can gain by taking actions that are detrimental to its counterparty. This paper examines the growing empirical literature on the economics of conflicts of interest in financial institutions. Economic analysis shows that, although conflicts of interest are omnipresent when contracting is costly and parties are imperfectly informed, there are important factors that mitigate their impact and, strikingly, it is possible for customers of financial institutions to benefit from the existence of such conflicts. The empirical literature reaches conclusions that differ across types of conflicts of interest but are overall more ambivalent and certainly more benign than the conclusions drawn by journalists and politicians from mostly anecdotal evidence. (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Mehran, Hamid; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflicts of interest, information provision, and competition in the financial services industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Freixas, Xavier; Shapiro, Joel
In some markets sellers have better information than buyers over which products best serve a buyer's needs. Depending on the market structure, this may lead to conflicts of interest in the provision of information by sellers. This paper studies this issue in the market for financial services. The analysis presents a new model of competition between banks, where price competition influences the ensuing incentives for truthful information revelation. We also compare conflicts of interest in two different firm structures, specialized banking and one-stop banking. (C) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Freixas, Xavier; Shapiro, Joel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board structure, mergers, and shareholder wealth: A study of the mutual fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khorana, Ajay; Tufano, Peter; Wedge, Lei
We study mutual fund mergers between 1999 and 2001 to understand the role and effectiveness of fund boards. Some fund mergers-typically across-family mergers-benefit target shareholders but are costly to target fund directors. Such mergers are more likely when funds underperform and their boards have a larger percentage of independent trustees, suggesting that more-independent boards tolerate less underperformance before initiating across-family mergers. This effect is most pronounced when all of the fund's directors are independent, not the 75% level of independence required by the SEC. Higher-paid target fund boards are less likely to approve across-family mergers that cause substantial reductions in their compensation. (C) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khorana, Ajay; Tufano, Peter; Wedge, Lei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business ties and proxy voting by mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, Gerald F.; Kim, E. Han
The magnitude of mutual funds' business ties with their portfolio firms is documented and is linked to funds' proxy votes at specific firms and to overall voting practices. Aggregate votes at the fund family level indicate a positive relation between business ties and the propensity to vote with management. Votes at specific firms, however, reveal that funds are no more likely to vote with management of client firms than of non-clients. Because the votes took place when funds knew their votes would be publicly scrutinized, fund families with a larger client base may have adopted voting policies that led to less frequent opposition to management at all firms. (C) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Davis, Gerald F.; Kim, E. Han</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are IPO investors net buyers through lead underwriters?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Harris, Jeffrey H.; Topaloglu, Selim
In Nasdaq initial public offerings (IPOs) issued between 1997 and 2002, purchases of lead underwriter clients exceed sales by an amount equal to 8.79% of the total issue. We find that lead underwriter clients do not buy to build larger long-term positions, capitalize on superior execution quality, or because of clientele effects. However, characteristics of net buying that are at odds with these explanations and other behaviors (like institutional purchases of cold IPOs) are all consistent with lead underwriters engaging in quid pro quo arrangements with clients. Price contribution analysis shows that such client buying activity contributes significantly to first-day price increases. (C) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Harris, Jeffrey H.; Topaloglu, Selim</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparing the stock recommendation performance of investment banks and independent research firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, Brad M.; Lehavy, Reuven; Trueman, Brett
From January 1996 through June 2003, the average daily abnormal return to independent research firm buy recommendations exceeds that of investment bank buy recommendations by 3.1 basis points (almost 8 percentage points annualized). Investment bank buy recommendation underperformance is more pronounced following the NASDAQ market peak (March 10, 2000) and strikingly so for buy recommendations on firms that recently conducted equity offerings. In contrast, investment bank hold and sell recommendations outperform those of independent research firms by 1.8 basis points daily (4 1/2 percentage points annualized). These results suggest reluctance by investment banks to downgrade stocks whose prospects dimmed during the bear market of the early 2000s, as claimed in the SEC's Global Research Analyst Settlement. (C) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barber, Brad M.; Lehavy, Reuven; Trueman, Brett</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are small investors naive about incentives?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malmendier, Ulrike; Shanthikumar, Devin
Security analysts tend to bias stock recommendations upward, particularly if they are affiliated with the underwriter. We analyze how investors account for such distortions. Using the NYSE Trades and Quotations database, we find that large traders adjust their trading response downward. While they exert buy pressure following strong buy recommendations, they display no reaction to buy recommendations and selling pressure following hold recommendations. This "discounting" is even more pronounced when the analyst is affiliated with the underwriter. Small traders, instead, follow recommendations literally. They exert positive pressure following both buy and strong buy recommendations and zero pressure following hold recommendations. We discuss possible explanations for the differences in trading response, including information costs and investor naivete. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malmendier, Ulrike; Shanthikumar, Devin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflicts of interest in sell-side research and the moderating role of institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ljungqvist, Alexander; Marston, Felicia; Starks, Laura T.; Wei, Kelsey D.; Yan, Hong
Because sell-side analysts are dependent on institutional investors for performance ratings and trading commissions, we argue that analysts are less likely to succumb to investment banking or brokerage pressure in stocks highly visible to institutional investors. Examining a comprehensive sample of analyst recommendations over the 1994-2000 period, we find that analysts' recommendations relative to consensus are positively associated with investment banking relationships and brokerage pressure but negatively associated with the presence of institutional investor owners. The presence of institutional investors is also associated with more accurate earnings forecasts and more timely re-ratings following severe share price falls. (C) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Ljungqvist, Alexander; Marston, Felicia; Starks, Laura T.; Wei, Kelsey D.; Yan, Hong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>So what do I get? The bank's view of lending relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bharath, Sreedhar; Dahiya, Sandeep; Saunders, Anthony; Srinivasan, Anand
While many empirical studies document borrower benefits of lending relationships, less is known about lender benefits. A relationship tender's informational advantage over a non-relationship lender may generate a higher probability of selling information-sensitive products to its borrowers. Our results show that the probability of a relationship lender providing a future loan is 42%, while for a non-relationship lender, this probability is 3%. Consistent with theory, we find that borrowers with greater information asymmetries are significantly likely to obtain future loans from their relationship lenders. Relationship lenders are likely to be chosen to provide debt/equity underwriting services, but this effect is economically small. (C) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bharath, Sreedhar; Dahiya, Sandeep; Saunders, Anthony; Srinivasan, Anand</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is there a diversification discount in financial conglomerates?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Laeven, Luc; Levine, Ross
This paper investigates whether the diversity of activities conducted by financial institutions influences their market valuations. We find that there is a diversification discount: The market values of financial conglomerates that engage in multiple activities, e.g., lending and non-lending financial services, are lower than if those financial conglomerates were broken into financial intermediaries that specialize in the individual activities. While difficult to identify a single causal factor, the results are consistent with theories that stress intensified agency problems in financial conglomerates engaged in multiple activities and indicate that economics of scope are not sufficiently large to produce a diversification premium. (C) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Laeven, Luc; Levine, Ross</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disclosure frequency and earnings management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jo, Hoje; Kim, Yongtae
We examine the relation between disclosure frequency and earnings management, and the impact of this relation on post-issue performance, for a sample of seasoned equity offerings (SEOs). We contend that firms with extensive disclosure are less likely to face information problems, leading to less earnings management and better post-issue performance. Our results confirm that disclosure frequency is inversely related to earnings management and positively associated with post-issue performance. We also find that transparency-reducing disclosure is concentrated in firms that substantially, but temporarily, increase disclosure prior to the offering. Such firms exhibit more earnings management and poorer post-SEO stock performance, on average. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jo, Hoje; Kim, Yongtae</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arrogance can be a virtue: Overconfidence, information acquisition, and market efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ko, K. Jeremy; Huang, Zhijian
In behavioral finance, overconfidence has been established as a prevalent psychological bias, which can make markets less efficient by creating mispricing in the form of excess volatility and return predictability. In this paper, we develop a model in which overconfidence causes investors to overinvest in information acquisition when this information could improve market efficiency by driving prices closer to true values. We study the impact of overconfidence on mispricing and information acquisition, comparing their net effect on prices. We derive several novel implications. First, overconfidence generally improves market pricing provided the level of overconfidence is not too high. Pricing can also improve even when overconfidence is arbitrarily high, depending on the amount of private information acquired relative to publicly available information. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ko, K. Jeremy; Huang, Zhijian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign entry and bank competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sengupta, Rajdeep
Foreign entry and bank competition are modeled as the interaction between asymmetrically informed principals: The entrant uses collateral as a screening device to contest the incumbent's informational advantage. Both better information ex ante and stronger legal protection ex post are shown to facilitate the entry of low-cost outside competitors into credit markets. The entrant's success in gaining borrowers of higher quality by offering cheaper loans increases with its efficiency (cost) advantage. This paper accounts for evidence suggesting that foreign banks tend to lend more to large firms thereby neglecting small and medium enterprises. The results also explain why this observed bias is stronger in emerging markets. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sengupta, Rajdeep</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Drexel Burnham Lambert's bankruptcy and the subsequent decline in underwriter fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Livingston, Miles; Williams, Glenn
In the 1980s, Drexel Burnham Lambert dominated the underwriting of junk bonds with close to a 50% market share. In 1990, Drexel went bankrupt and was liquidated, and the percentage underwriting fees for junk bonds subsequently dropped dramatically. We present strong evidence that the exit of Drexel Burnham Lambert and the resulting increase in competition for market share were major contributing factors to the decline in junk bond underwriter fees. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Livingston, Miles; Williams, Glenn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of trade-size clustering and its relation to stealth trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Gordon J.; Peterson, Mark A.
NYSE and Nasdaq trades increasingly cluster on multiples of 500, 1,000, and 5,000 shares. Such clustering varies over time and across stocks, and tends to increase with the level of trading activity. Furthermore, rounded trades tend to have more persistence both in occurrence and in trade initiation. Finally, medium-sized rounded trades tend to have greater relative price impact than large rounded trades. From these observations we surmise that trade-size clustering is consistent, at least in part, with the actions of stealth traders who tend to use medium-sized rounded transactions in an attempt to disguise their trades. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, Gordon J.; Peterson, Mark A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm-specific attributes and the cross-section of momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sagi, Jacob S.; Seasholes, Mark S.
This paper identifies observable firm-specific attributes that drive momentum. We find that a firm's revenues, costs, and growth options combine to determine the dynamics of its return autocorrelation. We use these insights to implement momentum strategies (buying winners and selling losers) with both numerically simulated returns and CRSP/Cornpustat data. In both sets of data, momentum strategies that use firms with high revenue growth volatility, low costs, or valuable growth options Outperform traditional momentum strategies by approximately 5% per-year. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sagi, Jacob S.; Seasholes, Mark S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm-specific risk and equity market development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Gregory; Kapadia, Nishad
We show that the increase in firm-specific risk in the US stock market is the result of new listings by riskier companies. In addition, our results explain why prior researchers have found that growth opportunities, profit margin, firm size, and industry composition (among other factors) are related to increases in firm-specific risk. The new listing effect is not driven by small companies becoming riskier but instead by a riskier sub-sample of the economy becoming publicly traded. These results are consistent with prior research that documents time trends in financial market development. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Gregory; Kapadia, Nishad</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Politically connected CEOs, corporate governance, and Post-IPO performance of China's newly partially privatized firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, Joseph P. H.; Wong, T. J.; Zhang, Tianyu
Almost 27% of the CEOs in a sample of 790 newly partially privatized firms in China are former or current government bureaucrats. Firms with politically connected CEOs underperform those without politically connected CEOs by almost 18% based on three-year post-IPO stock returns and have poorer three-year post-IPO earnings growth, sales growth, and change in returns on sales. The negative effect of the CEO's political ties also show up in the first-day stock return. Finally, firms led by politically connected CEOs are more likely to appoint other bureaucrats to the board of directors rather than directors with relevant professional backgrounds. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fan, Joseph P. H.; Wong, T. J.; Zhang, Tianyu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private credit in 129 countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Djankov, Simeon; McLiesh, Caralee; Shleifer, Andrei
We investigate cross-country determinants of private credit, using new data on legal creditor rights and private and public credit registries in 129 countries. Both creditor protection through the legal system and information-sharing institutions are associated with higher ratios of private credit to gross domestic product, but the former is relatively more important in the richer countries. An analysis of legal reforms shows that credit rises after improvements in creditor rights and in information sharing. Creditor rights are remarkably stable over time, contrary to the hypothesis that legal rules are converging. Finally, legal origins are an important determinant of both creditor rights and informationsharing institutions. The analysis suggests that public credit registries, which are primarily a feature of French civil law countries, benefit private credit markets in developing countries. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Djankov, Simeon; McLiesh, Caralee; Shleifer, Andrei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate financing decisions when investors take the path of least resistance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Malcolm; Coval, Joshua; Stein, Jeremy C.
We argue that inertial behavior on the part of investors can have significant consequences for corporate financial policy. One implication of investor inertia is that it improves the terms for the acquiring firm in a stock-for-stock merger, because acquirer shares are placed in the hands of investors, who, independent of their beliefs, do not resell these shares on the open market. In the presence of a downward-sloping demand curve, this leads to a reduction in price pressure and, hence, to cheaper equity financing. We develop a simple model to illustrate this idea and present supporting empirical evidence. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baker, Malcolm; Coval, Joshua; Stein, Jeremy C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider trading in credit derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Johnson, Timothy C.
Insider trading in the credit derivatives market has become a significant concern for regulators and participants. This paper attempts to quantify the problem. Using news reflected in the stock market as a benchmark for public information, we find significant incremental information revelation in the credit default swap market under circumstances consistent with the use of non-public information by informed banks. The information revelation occurs only for negative credit news and for entities that subsequently experience adverse shocks, and increases with the number of a firm's relationship banks. We find no evidence, however, that the degree of asymmetric information adversely affects prices or liquidity in either the equity or credit markets. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Johnson, Timothy C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do today's trades affect tomorrow's IPO allocations?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nimalendran, M.; Ritter, Jay R.; Zhang, Donghang
Underwriters using bookbuilding can allocate shares of initial public offerings (IPOs) on the basis of, among other things, commissions paid by investors. In testing the hypothesis that investors trade liquid stocks in order to affect their IPO allocations, we find that money left on the table by IPOs is related to the trading volume of the 50 most liquid stocks near the offer date. For an IPO that leaves $1 billion on the table, there is abnormal volume of 2.7% to 4.1 % in the 50 most liquid stocks over the six days ending on the day that trading commences in that IPO, although only during the internet bubble period is this volume increase statistically significant. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nimalendran, M.; Ritter, Jay R.; Zhang, Donghang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating and testing beta pricing models: Alternative methods and their performance in simulations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shanken, Jay; Zhou, Guofu
We conduct a simulation analysis of the Fama and MacBeth[1973. Risk, returns and equilibrium: empirical tests. Journal of Political Economy 71, 607-636.] two-pass procedure, as well as maximum likelihood (ML) and generalized method of moments estimators of cross-sectional expected return models. We also provide some new analytical results on computational issues, the relations between estimators, and asymptotic distributions under model misspecification. The generalized least squares estimator is often much more precise than the usual ordinary least squares (OLS) estimator, but it displays more bias as well. A "truncated" form of ML performs quite well overall in terms of bias and precision, but produces less reliable inferences than the OLS estimator. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shanken, Jay; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment under uncertainty and time-inconsistent preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grenadier, Steven R.; Wang, Neng
While standard real options models assume that agents possess a constant rate of time preference, there is substantial evidence that agents are impatient about choices in the short term but are patient when choosing between long-term alternatives. We extend the real options framework to model the investment-timing decisions of entrepreneurs with time-inconsistent preferences. The impact on investment-timing depends on such factors as whether entrepreneurs are sophisticated or naive in their expectations regarding their future time-inconsistent behavior, and whether the payoff from investment occurs all at once or over time. The model is extended to the case of a competitive equilibrium. (c) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Grenadier, Steven R.; Wang, Neng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good and bad credit contagion: Evidence from credit default swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jorion, Philippe; Zhang, Gaiyan
This study examines the intra-industry information transfer effect of credit events, as captured in the credit default swaps (CDS) and stock markets. Positive correlations across CDS spreads imply that contagion effects dominate, whereas negative correlations indicate competition effects. We find strong evidence of contagion effects for Chapter 11 bankruptcies and competition effects for Chapter 7 bankruptcies. We also introduce a purely unanticipated event, in the form of a large jump in a company's CDS spread, and find that this leads to the strongest evidence of credit contagion across the industry. These results have important implications for the construction of portfolios with credit-sensitive instruments. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jorion, Philippe; Zhang, Gaiyan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A lender-based theory of collateral</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, Roman; Mueller, Holger M.
We consider an imperfectly competitive loan market in which a local relationship lender has an information advantage vis--vis distant transaction lenders. Competitive pressure from the transaction lenders prevents the local lender from extracting the full surplus from projects. As a result, the local lender inefficiently rejects marginally profitable projects. Collateral mitigates the inefficiency by increasing the local lender's payoff from precisely those marginally profitable projects that she inefficiently rejects. The model predicts that, controlling for observable borrower risk, collateralized loans are more likely to default ex post, which is consistent with the empirical evidence. The model also predicts that borrowers for whom local lenders have a relatively smaller information advantage face higher collateral requirements, and that technological innovations that narrow the information advantage of local lenders, such as small business credit scoring, lead to a greater use of collateral in lending relationships. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Inderst, Roman; Mueller, Holger M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The influence of product market dynamics on a firm's cash holdings and hedging behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haushalter, David; Klasa, Sandy; Maxwell, William F.
Prior work suggests that if a firm shares a larger proportion of its growth opportunities with rivals, an inability to fully invest in these opportunities leads to predatory behavior on the part of rivals and losses in market share. We examine whether firms manage this predation risk. We find inter- and intra-industry evidence that the extent of the interdependence of a firm's investment opportunities with rivals is positively associated with its use of derivatives and the size of its cash holdings. Moreover, an analysis of investment behavior provides evidence that if this interdependence is high, the management of predation risk provides strategic benefits. Our results indicate that predation risk is an important determinant of corporate financial policy choices and investment behavior. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Haushalter, David; Klasa, Sandy; Maxwell, William F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Chapter 11 costly?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalay, Avner; Singhal, Rajeev; Tashjian, Elizabeth
We examine a sample of 459 firms filing for Chapter 11 during the period 1991-1998 and find that our sample firms experience significant improvements in their operating performance during Chapter 11. Our evidence is consistent with the hypothesis that Chapter 11, if anything, provides net benefits to bankrupt firms. In the cross section, firms with higher debt ratios experience greater improvements in operating performance, and the complexity of the renegotiation process negatively affects the improvement. We find no relationship between Chapter 11 outcome and changes in risk-adjusted firm value in Chapter 11. (c) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kalay, Avner; Singhal, Rajeev; Tashjian, Elizabeth</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection and the Coasian view</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergman, Nittai K.; Nicolaievsky, Daniel
The corporate charters of a sample of Mexican firms show that private firms often significantly enhance the legal protection offered to investors, but public firms rarely do so. We construct a model that endogenizes the degree of investor protection that firms provide, using as a springboard the assumption that legal regimes differ in their ability to enforce precisely filtering contracts that provide protection only in those cases where expropriation can occur. Our model generates predictions about the types of contracts that would be employed and the levels of investor protection that would prevail across different legal regimes in both private and public firms. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bergman, Nittai K.; Nicolaievsky, Daniel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of all-star analyst job changes on their coverage choices and investment banking deal flow</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, Jonathan; Khorana, Ajay; Patel, Ajay; Rau, P. Raghavendra
Using a sample of all-star analysts who switch investment banks, we examine (1) whether analyst behavior is influenced by banking relationships and (2) whether analyst behavior affects investment banking deal flow. Although the stock coverage decision depends on the relationship with the client firms, we find no evidence that analysts change their optimism or recommendation levels when joining a new firm. Investment banking deal flow is related to analyst reputation only for equity transactions. For debt and M&amp;A transactions, analyst reputation does not matter. There is no evidence that issuing optimistic earnings forecasts or recommendations affects investment banking deal flow. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Clarke, Jonathan; Khorana, Ajay; Patel, Ajay; Rau, P. Raghavendra</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee sentiment and stock option compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergman, Nittai K.; Jenter, Dirk
The use of equity-based compensation for rank-and-file employees is a puzzle. We analyze whether the popularity of option compensation may be driven by employee optimism, and show that optimism by itself is insufficient to make option compensation optimal. The crucial insight is that firms compete with financial markets as suppliers of equity to employees and that employees' access to the equity market restricts firms' ability to profit from employee optimism. Firms must be able to extract some of the implied rents even though employees can purchase company equity in the financial markets. Such rent extraction becomes feasible if employees prefer the stock options offered by firms to the equity offered by the market, or if the traded equity is overvalued. We provide empirical evidence that firms use broad-based option compensation when boundedly rational employees are likely to be excessively optimistic about company stock, and when employees are likely to strictly prefer options over stock. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bergman, Nittai K.; Jenter, Dirk</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mimicking repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Rehman, Zahid; Vermaelen, Theo
We study the tendency of firms to mimic the repurchase announcements of their industry counterparts. We argue that a firm, by repurchasing its shares, sends a positive signal about itself and a negative one about its competitors. This induces the competing firms to mimic the behavior of the repurchasing firm by repurchasing themselves. Using a broad sample of US firms from the period 1984-2002, we show that, in concentrated industries, a repurchase announcement lowers the stock price of the other firms in the same industry. The other firms react by repurchasing themselves to undo these negative effects. Repurchases are chosen as a strategic reaction to other firms' repurchase decisions and are not motivated by the desire to time the market, i.e., to take advantage of a significantly undervalued stock price. Therefore, repurchasing firms in more concentrated industries experience a lower increase in value in comparison with their counterparts in less concentrated industries in the post-announcement era. Alternative methodologies used to estimate long-term performance confirm that it is only the repurchasing firms in low concentration industries that outperform the market, their non-repurchasing peers, and their counterparts in more concentrated industries by amounts that are economically and statistically significant. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V .All rights reserved.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Rehman, Zahid; Vermaelen, Theo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Theft and taxes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, Mihir A.; Dyck, Alexander; Zingales, Luigi
This paper analyzes the interaction between corporate taxes and corporate governance. We show that the design of the corporate tax system affects the amount of private benefits extracted by company insiders and that the quality of the corporate governance system affects the sensitivity of tax revenues to tax changes. Analyses of a tax enforcement crackdown in Russia and cross-country data on tax changes support this two-way interaction between corporate governance and corporate taxation. (c) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Desai, Mihir A.; Dyck, Alexander; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Productivity-based asset pricing: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balvers, Ronald J.; Huang, Dayong
In a general real business cycle model, we derive a pricing kernel that involves only production function arguments. The productivity shock is the single factor and the capital stock relative to a productivity measure is the conditioning variable. The model compares favorably with the complementary consumption-based and market-based approaches and with the Fama-French three-factor model. A size premium arises from differences in unconditional sensitivities-small firms are more sensitive to productivity shocks-and a value premium from differences in conditional sensitivities to productivity shocks-growth firms are more sensitive to productivity shocks when the productivity risk premium is low. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balvers, Ronald J.; Huang, Dayong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank relationships and underwriter competition: Evidence from Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yasuda, Ayako
I examine the effects of bank relationships on underwriter choice in the Japanese corporate bond market following the 1993 deregulation. Bank relationships have significant positive effects on a firm's underwriter choice. Relationship firms receive a small but significant fee discount and, consistent with the mitigating effect of competition on hold-up costs, multiple-relationship firms receive a significantly deeper discount than single-relationship firms. Bank shareholding alone negatively affects underwriter choice, whereas shareholding together with loans has significantly more positive effects than loans alone. Finally, existing relationships reduce a Japanese firm's switching probability by 32%, in contrast to only 6% for U.S. firms. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yasuda, Ayako</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Affiliated mutual funds and the allocation of initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ritter, Jay R.; Zhang, Donghang
We examine how investment banks use initial public offerings (IPOs) in relation to their affiliated mutual funds. The dumping ground hypothesis predicts that the lead underwriter allocates cold IPOs to its affiliated funds so that more deals can be completed when demand for these IPOs is weak. Affiliated funds could also receive more cold IPOs because the lead underwriter uses allocations of hot IPOs to unaffiliated funds to gain trading commission business. The nepotism hypothesis predicts that the lead underwriter allocates hot IPOs to its affiliated funds to boost their performance and thus attract more money. We find little evidence supporting the dumping ground hypothesis, although some evidence supports the nepotism hypothesis, especially during the internet bubble period of 1999-2000. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ritter, Jay R.; Zhang, Donghang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial fraud, director reputation, and shareholder wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fich, Eliezer M.; Shivdasani, Anil
We investigate the reputational impact of financial fraud for outside directors based on a sample of firms facing shareholder class action lawsuits. Following a financial fraud lawsuit, outside directors do not face abnormal turnover on the board of the sued firm but experience a significant decline in other board seats held. This decline in other directorships is greater for more severe allegations of fraud and when the outside director bears greater responsibility for monitoring fraud. Interlocked firms that share directors with the sued firm also exhibit valuation declines at the lawsuit filing. Fraud-affiliated directors are more likely to lose directorships at firms with stronger corporate,governance and their departure is associated with valuation increases for these firms. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fich, Eliezer M.; Shivdasani, Anil</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring: Which institutions matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Xia; Harford, Jarrad; Li, Kai
Within a cost benefit framework, we hypothesize that independent institutions with long-term investments will specialize in monitoring and influencing efforts rather than trading. Other institutions will not monitor. Using acquisition decisions to reveal monitoring, we show that only concentrated holdings by independent long-term institutions are related to post-merger performance. Further, the presence of these institutions makes withdrawal of bad bids more likely. These institutions make long-term portfolio adjustments rather than trading for short-term gain and only sell in advance of very bad outcomes. Examining total institutional holdings or even concentrated holdings by other types of institutions masks important variation in the subset of monitoring institutions. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Xia; Harford, Jarrad; Li, Kai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Untitled</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. William
nan</description><author>Schwert, G. William</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric stock market volatility and the cyclical behavior of expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mele, Antonio
Recent explanations of aggregate stock market fluctuations suggest that countercyclical stock market volatility is consistent with rational asset evaluations. In this paper, I develop a framework to study the causes of countercyclical stock market volatility. I find that countercyclical risk premia do not imply countercyclical return volatility. Instead, countercyclical stock volatility occurs if risk premia increase more in bad times than they decrease in good times, thereby inducing price-dividend ratios to fluctuate more in bad times than in good. The business cycle asymmetry in the investors' attitude toward discounting future cash flows plays a novel and critical role in many rational explanations of asset price fluctuations. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mele, Antonio</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset fire sales (and purchases) in equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coval, Joshua; Stafford, Erik
This paper examines institutional price pressure in equity markets by studying mutual fund transactions caused by capital flows from 1980 to 2004. Funds experiencing large outflows tend to decrease existing positions, which creates price pressure in the securities held in common by distressed funds. Similarly, the tendency among funds experiencing large inflows to expand existing positions creates positive price pressure in overlapping holdings. Investors who trade against constrained mutual funds earn significant returns for providing liquidity. In addition, future flow-driven transactions are predictable, creating an incentive to front-run the anticipated forced trades by funds experiencing extreme capital flows. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coval, Joshua; Stafford, Erik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Affirmative obligations and market making with inventory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Panayides, Marios A.
Existing empirical studies provide little support for the theoretical prediction that market makers rebalance their inventory through revisions of quoted prices. This study provides evidence that the NYSE's specialist does engage in significant inventory rebalancing, but only when not constrained by the affirmative obligation to provide liquidity imposed by the Price Continuity rule. The evidence also suggests that such obligations are associated with better market quality, but impose significant costs on the specialist. The specialist mitigates these costs through discretionary trading when the rule is not binding. These findings shed light on how exchange rules affect market makers' behavior and market quality. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Panayides, Marios A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International asset pricing under segmentation and PPP deviations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaieb, Ines; Errunza, Vihang
We analyze the impact of both purchasing power parity (PPP) deviations and market segmentation on asset pricing and investor's portfolio holdings. The freely traded securities command a world market risk premium and an inflation risk premium. The securities that can be held by only a subset of investors command two additional premiums: a conditional market risk premium and a segflation risk premium. Our model is empirically supported with important implications for tests of international asset pricing. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chaieb, Ines; Errunza, Vihang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating systemic risk in the international financial system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Brown, Gregory W.; Hund, John E.
This paper develops three distinct methods to quantify the risk of a systemic failure in the global banking system. We examine a sample of 334 banks (representing 80% of global bank equity) in 28 countries around five global financial crises. Our results suggest statistically significant, but economically small, increases in systemic risk. Although policy responses are endogenous, the low estimated probabilities suggest that the distress of central bankers, regulators and politicians about the events we study could be overstated and that current policy responses to financial crises could be adequate to handle major macroeconomic events. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Brown, Gregory W.; Hund, John E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparative advantage, demand for external finance, and financial development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Do, Quy-Toan; Levchenko, Andrei A.
This paper analyzes the effect of comparative advantage in international trade on a country's level of financial development. Countries with comparative advantage in financially intensive goods experience a higher demand for external finance, and therefore financial development. By contrast, financial development is lower in countries that primarily export goods which do not rely on external finance. We use disaggregated trade data to develop a measure of a country's external finance need of exports, and demonstrate this effect empirically. In order to overcome the simultaneity problem, we develop a novel instrumentation strategy based on the exogenous geographic determinants of trade patterns. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Do, Quy-Toan; Levchenko, Andrei A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Affiliated firms and financial support: Evidence from Indian business groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Nanda, Vikram; Seru, Amit
We investigate the functioning of internal capital markets in Indian Business Groups. We document that intragroup loans are an important means of transferring cash across group firms and are typically used to support financially weaker firms. Evidence suggests that an important reason for providing support may be to avoid default by a group firm and consequent negative spillovers to the rest of the group. Consistent with such spillovers, the first bankruptcy in a group is followed by significant drops in external financing, investments and profits of other firms in the group and an increase in their bankruptcy probability. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Nanda, Vikram; Seru, Amit</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do mutual funds time the market? Evidence from portfolio holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, George J.; Yao, Tong; Yu, Tong
Previous research finds insignificant market-timing ability for mutual funds using tests based on fund returns. The return-based tests, however, are subject to the "artificial timing" bias. In this paper, we propose and implement new measures of market timing based on mutual fund holdings. Our holdings-based measures do not suffer from the artificial timing bias. We find that, on average, actively managed U.S. domestic equity funds have positive timing ability. Market timing funds use non-public information to predict market returns, tend to have high industry concentration, large fund size, a tilt toward small-cap stocks, and are active in industry rotation. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, George J.; Yao, Tong; Yu, Tong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing financing constraints on firm investment using variable capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caggese, Andrea
We consider a dynamic multifactor model of investment with financing imperfections, adjustment costs and fixed and variable capital. We use the model to derive a test of financing constraints based on a reduced form variable capital equation. Simulation results show that this test correctly identifies financially constrained firms even when the estimation of firms' investment opportunities is very noisy. In addition, the test is well specified in the presence of both concave and convex adjustment costs of fixed capital. We confirm empirically the validity of this test on a sample of small Italian manufacturing companies. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caggese, Andrea</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dealer intermediation and price behavior in the aftermarket for new bond issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, Richard C.; Hollifield, Burton; Schuerhoff, Norman
Municipal bonds trade in decentralized broker-dealer markets, and are underpriced when issued, but unlike equities the average price rises slowly over several days. Newly issued municipal bonds have high levels of price dispersion and the average price rises because the mix of trade sizes changes over time. While large trades occur close to the reoffering price, small trades occur between the reoffering price to as much as 5% above the reoffering price. Using a mixed-distribution model we quantify the losses uninformed traders or issuers give up to broker-dealers. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Green, Richard C.; Hollifield, Burton; Schuerhoff, Norman</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment, consumption, and hedging under incomplete markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miao, Jianjun; Wang, Neng
Entrepreneurs often face undiversifiable idiosyncratic risks from their business investments. We extend the standard real options approach to an incomplete markets environment and analyze the joint decisions of business investments, consumption/savings, and portfolio selection. For a lumpsum investment payoff and an agent with a sufficiently strong precautionary savings motive, an increase in volatility can accelerate investment, contrary to the standard real options analysis. When the agent can trade the market portfolio to partially hedge against investment risk, the systematic volatility is compensated via the standard CAPM argument, and the idiosyncratic volatility generates a private equity premium. Finally, when the investment payoff is a series of flows, the agent's idiosyncratic risk exposure alters both the implied option value and the implied project value, causing a reversal of the results in the lump-sum payoff case. (c) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Miao, Jianjun; Wang, Neng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms hold so much cash? A tax-based explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foley, C. Fritz; Hartzell, Jay C.; Titman, Sheridan; Twite, Garry
US corporations hold significant amounts of cash on their balance sheets. This paper develops and tests the hypothesis that the magnitude of US multinational cash holdings are, in part, a consequence of the tax costs associated with repatriating foreign income. Consistent with this hypothesis, firms facing higher repatriation taxes hold higher levels of cash, hold this cash abroad, and hold this cash in affiliates that trigger high tax costs when repatriating earnings. In addition, less financially constrained firms and those that are more technology intensive exhibit a higher sensitivity of affiliate cash holdings to repatriation tax burdens. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Foley, C. Fritz; Hartzell, Jay C.; Titman, Sheridan; Twite, Garry</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order flow, dealer profitability, and price formation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Locke, Peter; Onayev, Zhan
We analyze the dynamics of the S&amp;P 500 futures price, finding both short- and long-run effects of order flow on price. While price moves strongly with the order flow in the short-run, the long-run impact is slightly negative, attributable to costly slippage from a hedging propensity in futures markets. We find strong evidence of a state dependence in the relation between price and order flow, using both volume and floor trader income measures as states. We also find that both the long- and short-run impacts of order flow are greater when dealer income is higher. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Locke, Peter; Onayev, Zhan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>SV mixture models with application to S&amp;P 500 index returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durham, Garland B.
Understanding both the dynamics of volatility and the shape of the distribution of returns conditional on the volatility state is important for many financial applications. A simple single-factor stochastic volatility model appears to be sufficient to capture most of the dynamics. It is the shape of the conditional distribution that is the problem. This paper examines the idea of modeling this distribution as a discrete mixture of normals. The flexibility of this class of distributions provides a transparent look into the tails of the returns distribution. Model diagnostics suggest that the model, SV-mix, does a good job of capturing the salient features of the data. In a direct comparison against several affine-jump models, SV-mix is strongly preferred by Akaike and Schwarz information criteria. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Durham, Garland B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does industry-wide distress affect defaulted firms? Evidence from creditor recoveries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Srinivasan, Arland
Using data on defaulted firms in the United States over the period 1982-1999, we show that creditors of defaulted firms recover significantly lower amounts in present-value terms when the industry of defaulted firms is in distress. We investigate whether this is purely an economic-downturn effect or also a fire-sales effect along the lines of Shleifer and Vishny [1992. Liquidation values and debt capacity: a market equilibrium approach. Journal of Finance 47, 1343-1366]. We find the fire-sales effect to be also at work: Creditors recover less if the industry is in distress and non-defaulted firms in the industry are illiquid, particularly if the industry is characterized by assets that are specific, that is, not easily redeployable by other industries, and if the debt is collateralized by such specific assets. The interaction effect of industry-level distress and asset-specificity is strongest for senior unsecured creditors, is economically significant, and robust to contract-specific, firm-specific, macroeconomic, and bond-market supply effects. We also document that defaulted firms in distressed industries are more likely to emerge as restructured firms than to be acquired or liquidated, and spend longer time in bankruptcy. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Srinivasan, Arland</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of the floating-to-fixed rate debt structure of firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh
We analyze the effects of managerial incentive, firm characteristics and market timing on floating-to-fixed rate debt structure of firms. We find that chief financial officer's (CFO's), not chief executive officer's (CEO's), incentive has a strong influence on firm's debt structure. When CFOs have incentives to increase (decrease) firm risk, firms obtain volatility-increasing (-decreasing) debt structure. These effects are present only for CFOs who are not subject to high monitoring by board members, CEOs, or corporate control market. Our findings suggest that agency problems at the level of non-CEO executives could be an important driver of various corporate decisions. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technological innovation and real investment booms and busts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMarzo, Peter; Kaniel, Ron; Kremer, Ilan
We investigate why new, high-risk technologies can attract excessive and often unprofitable investment. We develop an equilibrium model in which rational, risk-averse agents overinvest in a risky technology, possibly to the point that its expected return is negative. Overinvestment results from relative wealth concerns which arise endogenously from the imperfect tradability of future endowments. Competition over future consumption leads to an indirect utility for wealth with "keeping up with the Joneses" properties that can induce herding. Because overinvestment increases with the risk of the technology, our model can explain why new, risky technological innovations may promote investment bubbles. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeMarzo, Peter; Kaniel, Ron; Kremer, Ilan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral, debt capacity, and corporate investment: Evidence from a natural experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gan, Jie
This paper examines how a shock to collateral value influences firms' debt capacities and investments. Using a source of exogenous variation in collateral value provided by the land market collapse in Japan, I find that collateral has a statistically and economically significant impact on corporate investments. I also provide direct evidence on the workings of such a collateral channel. Exploiting a unique dataset of matched bank-firm lending, I show that firms with greater collateral losses are less likely to sustain their banking relationships and tend to obtain a smaller amount of bank credit. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gan, Jie</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do corporate managers misstate financial statements? The role of option compensation and other factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Efendi, Jap; Srivastava, Anup; Swanson, Edward P.
We investigate the incentives that led to the rash of restated financial statements at the end of the 1990s market bubble. We find that the likelihood of a misstated financial statement increases greatly when the CEO has very sizable holdings of in-the-money stock options. Misstatements are also more likely for firms that are constrained by an interest-coverage debt covenant, that raise new debt or equity capital, or that have a CEO who serves as board chair. Our results indicate that agency costs increased [Jensen, M.C., 2005a, Agency costs of overvalued equity. Financial Management 34, 5-19] as substantially overvalued equity caused managers to take actions to support the stock price. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Efendi, Jap; Srivastava, Anup; Swanson, Edward P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are IPOs underpriced? Evidence from Japan's hybrid auction-method offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kerins, Frank; Kutsuna, Kenji; Smith, Richard
We document discretionary underpricing and partial adjustment of IPO prices in the public offer tranche of Japan's hybrid auction regime, in which investor information differences are not important, there are no roadshows, preferential allocations are negligible, institutional investing is low, and the public offer tranche cannot fail. The magnitude and variation of underpricing in our sample, which spans relatively hot and cold markets, are similar to those reported for US IPOs. The evidence is most consistent with underpricing arising from an implicit contract to allocate risk related to initial mispricing where, in exchange for guaranteeing a minimum price, the underwriter participates indirectly in upside performance. The results raise important questions about interpretations of IPO underpricing in the US. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kerins, Frank; Kutsuna, Kenji; Smith, Richard</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How much of the corporate bond spread is due to personal taxes?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Sheen; Shi, Jian; Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi
Existing term structure models of defaultable bonds have often underestimated corporate bond spreads. A potential problem is that investors' taxes are ignored in these models. We propose a pricing model that accounts for stochastic default probability and differential tax treatments for discount and premium bonds. By estimating parameters directly from bond data, we obtain significantly positive estimates for the income tax rate of a marginal corporate bond investor after 1986. This contrasts sharply with the previous finding that the implied tax rates for Treasury bonds are close to zero. Results show that taxes explain a substantial portion of corporate bond spreads. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Sheen; Shi, Jian; Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit-spread determinants and interlocking contracts: A study of the Ras Gas project</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dallami, Mansoor; Hauswald, Robert
This paper provides an in-depth study of the allocation of a firm's residual risks not explicitly managed through interlocking contracts in the context of project finance. Focusing on the Ras Gas project, we relate its credit spreads as a measure of investor risk perceptions to firm-specific risk factors in the context of 25year supply agreements, debt covenants, and a debt-service guarantee contingent on output prices. Consistent with theoretical predictions, we find that unmanaged risk factors affecting the supply agreement drive Ras Gas' credit spreads, whereas managed ones have no effect. Interpreting our findings as evidence for the nexus-of-contracts view of the firm, we discuss some implications for financial design and valuation. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dallami, Mansoor; Hauswald, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic skew in currency options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren
We analyze the behavior of over-the-counter currency option prices across moneyness, maturity, and calendar time on two of the most actively traded currency pairs over the past eight years. We find that, on any given date, the conditional risk-neutral distribution of currency returns can show strong asymmetry. This asymmetry varies greatly over time and often switches signs. We develop and estimate a class of models that captures this stochastic skew behavior. Model estimation shows that our stochastic skew models significantly outperform traditional jump-diffusion stochastic volatility models both in sample and out of sample. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multifrequency news and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calvet, Laurent E.; Fisher, Adial J.
Equity prices are driven by shocks with persistence levels ranging from intraday horizons to several decades. To accommodate this diversity, we introduce a parsimonious equilibrium model with regime shifts of heteroaeneous durations in fundamentals, and estimate specifications with up to 256 states on daily aggregate returns. The multifrequency equilibrium has higher likelihood than the Campbell and Hentschel [1992. No news is good news: an asymmetric model of changing volatility in stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics 31, 281-318] specification, while producing volatility feedback 10 to 40 times larger. Furthermore. Bayesian learning about volatility generates a novel trade-off between skewness and kurtosis as information quality varies, complementing the uncertainty channel [e.g., Veronesi, 1999. Stock market overreaction to bad news in good times: a rational expectations equilibrium model. Review of Financial Studies 12, 975-1007]. Economies with intermediate information best match daily returns. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calvet, Laurent E.; Fisher, Adial J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign currency-denominated borrowing in the absence of operating incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McBrady, Matthew R.; Schill, Michael J.
It is well known that corporations issue foreign currency-denominated debt to hedge foreign currency cash flows with offsetting interest payments. We test an alternative "opportunistic" motive for foreign currency-denominated borrowing. We do so by constructing a comprehensive sample of foreign currency-denominated bonds issued by sovereign government and agency issuers with no foreign currency cash flows or foreign operations. We find strong and consistent evidence that the borrowers in our sample consider cross-currency differences in covered and uncovered interest yields in choosing the currency in which to denominate their international debt. We estimate the average gains to opportunistic covered yield borrowing to be 4 to 18 basis points. Interestingly, we also find that the average bond offering in our sample precedes a large and beneficial depreciation of the issue currency over the course of the following year. These results support what has been a frequent conjecture in the foreign debt market. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McBrady, Matthew R.; Schill, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Was there too little entry during the Dot Com Era?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldfarb, Brent; Kirsch, David; Miller, David A.
We present four stylized facts about the Dot Corn Era: (1) there was a widespread belief in a Get Big Fast business strategy, (2) the increase and decrease in public and private equity investment was most prominent in the Internet and information technology sectors, (3) the survival rate of dot com firms is on par with or higher than other emerging industries, and (4) firm survival is independent of private equity funding. To connect these findings we offer a herding model that accommodates a diveraence between the information and incentives of venture capitalists and their investors. A Get Bia Fast belief cascade could have led to overly focused investment in too few Internet startups and, as a result, too little entry. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goldfarb, Brent; Kirsch, David; Miller, David A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimism and economic choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Puri, Manju; Robinson, David T.
We create a novel measure of optimism using the Survey of Consumer Finance by comparing selfreported life expectancy to that implied by statistical tables. This measure of optimism correlates with positive beliefs about future economic conditions and with psychometric tests of optimism. Optimism is related to numerous work/life choices: more optimistic people work harder, expect to retire later, are more likely to remarry, invest more in individual stocks, and save more. Interestingly, however, moderate optimists display reasonable financial behavior, whereas extreme optimists display financial habits and behavior that are generally not considered prudent. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Puri, Manju; Robinson, David T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks and bubbles: How good are bankers at spotting winners?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gonzalez, Laura; James, Christopher
This paper examines the bank lending relations of a large sample of technology and nontechnology firms that went public during the 1996-2000 period. We use a unique hand-collected data set to examine the characteristics of firms that establish pre- Initial Public Offering (IPO) bank lending relations and whether post-IPO performance is related to the existence and size of pre-IPO banking relations. We find that the majority of IPO firms have banking relations before they go public. Firms with banking relations are older, more profitable or, in the case of tech firms, have lower losses, and are More likely to have funding front venture capitalists than firms without banking relations. We also find that banks lent aggressively to technology firms in the sense that current earnings and cash flows were significantly less important in determining banking relations for technology firms than for nontechnology firms. Consistent with the importance of so-called soft information in lending decisions, we find that, controlling for ex ante observable risk measures, there is a positive and significant relation between improvements in post-IPO operating performance and the existence and size of pre-IPO banking relations. Overall, our results indicate that firms with the best current and future prospects establish banking relations. Our findings provide an explanation as to why investors could interpret lending relations as a positive signal of firm quality. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gonzalez, Laura; James, Christopher</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do countries matter so much for corporate governance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Stulz, Ren M.
This paper develops and tests a model of how country characteristics, such as legal protections for minority investors and the level of economic and financial development, influence firms' costs and benefits in implementing measures to improve their own governance and transparency. We find that country characteristics explain much more of the variance in governance ratings (ranging from 39% to 73%) than observable firm characteristics (ranging from 4% to 22%). Further, we show that firm characteristics explain almost none of the variation in governance ratings in less-developed countries and that access to global capital markets sharpens firms' incentives for better governance. (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Stulz, Ren M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is universal banking justified? Evidence from bank underwriting of corporate bonds in Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Jun-Koo; Liu, Wei-Lin
We examine the extent to which universal banking in Japan creates conflicts of interest. We find that as banks enter the securities business, they discount the price of the corporate bonds they underwrite significantly in an effort to attract investors, thereby generating conflicts of interest that are harmful to issuers. Further, we find that close prior lending relationships between banks and their client issuers is the driving force behind such conflicts and that competition from investment houses limits but does not eliminate these conflicts. Our results contrast sharply with the evidence for the US, which largely shows a certification role for banks. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kang, Jun-Koo; Liu, Wei-Lin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking crises, financial dependence, and growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kroszner, Randall S.; Laeven, Luc; Klingebiel, Daniela
This paper contributes to the literature that analyzes the mechanisms linking financial shocks and real activity. In particular, we investigate the growth impact of banking crises on industries with different levels of dependence on external finance. If banks are the key institutions allowing credit constraints to be relaxed, then a sudden loss of these intermediaries in a system in which such intermediaries are important should have a disproportionately contractionary impact on the sectors that flourished due to their reliance on banks. Using data from 38 developed and developing countries that experienced financial crises during the last quarter century, we find that those sectors that are highly dependent on external finance tend to experience a substantially greater contraction of value added during a banking crisis in countries with deeper financial systems than in countries with shallower financial systems. Our results do not suggest, however, that on net the externally dependent firms fare worse in deep financial systems. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kroszner, Randall S.; Laeven, Luc; Klingebiel, Daniela</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do hedge funds deliver alpha? A Bayesian and bootstrap analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kosowski, Robert; Naik, Narayan Y.; Teo, Melvyn
Using a robust bootstrap procedure, we find that top hedge fund performance cannot be explained by luck, and hedge fund performance persists at annual horizons. Moreover, we show that Bayesian measures, which help overcome the short-sample problem inherent in hedge fund returns, lead to superior performance predictability. Sorting on Bayesian alphas, relative to OLS alphas, yields a 5.5% per year increase in the alpha of the spread between the top and bottom hedge fund deciles. Our results are robust and relevant to investors as they are neither confined to small funds, nor driven by incubation bias, backfill bias, or serial correlation. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kosowski, Robert; Naik, Narayan Y.; Teo, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade credit and bank credit: Evidence from recent financial crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Love, Inessa; Preve, Lorenzo A.; Sarria-Allende, Virginia
This paper studies the effect of financial crises on trade credit for a sample of 890 firms in six emerging economies. Although the provision of trade credit increases right after a crisis, it contracts in the following months and years. Firms that are financially more vulnerable to crises extend less trade credit to their customers. We argue that the decline in aggregate trade credit ratios is driven by the reduction in the supply of trade credit that follows a bank credit crunch, consistent with the "redistribution view" of trade credit provision, whereby bank credit is redistributed via trade credit from financially stronger firms to weaker firms. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Love, Inessa; Preve, Lorenzo A.; Sarria-Allende, Virginia</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extending quadrature methods to value multi-asset and complex path dependent options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andricopoulos, Ari D.; Widdicks, Martin; Newton, David P.; Duck, Peter W.
The exposition of the quadrature (QUAD) method (Andricopoulos, Widdicks, Duck, and Newton, 2003. Universal option valuation using quadrature methods. Journal of Financial Economics 67, 447-471 (see also Corrigendum, Journal of Financial Economics 73, 603 (2004)) is significantly extended to cover notably more complex and difficult problems in option valuations involving one or more underlyings. Trials comparing several techniques in the literature, adapted from standard lattice, grid and Monte Carlo methods to tackle particular types of problem, show that QUAD offers far greater flexibility, superior convergence, and hence, increased accuracy and considerably reduced computational times. The speed advantage of QUAD means that, even under the curse of dimensionality, it is not necessary to resort to Monte Carlo methods (certainly for options involving up to five underlying assets). Given the universality and flexibility of the method, it should be the method of choice for pricing options involving multiple underlying assets, in the presence of many features, such as early exercise or path dependency. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andricopoulos, Ari D.; Widdicks, Martin; Newton, David P.; Duck, Peter W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Classified boards, firm value, and managerial entrenchment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faleye, Olubunmi
This paper shows that classified boards destroy value by entrenching management and reducing director effectiveness. First, I show that classified boards are associated with a significant reduction in firm value and that this holds even among complex firms, although such firms are often regarded as most likely to benefit from staggered board elections. I then examine how classified boards entrench management by focusing on CEO turnover, executive compensation, proxy contests, and shareholder proposals. My results indicate that classified boards significantly insulate management from market discipline, thus suggesting that the observed reduction in value is due to managerial entrenchment and diminished board accountability. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faleye, Olubunmi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do asset prices reflect fundamentals? Freshly squeezed evidence from the</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boudoukh, Jacob; Richardson, Matthew; Shen, YuQing; Whitelaw, Robert F.
The behavioral finance literature cites the frozen concentrated orange juice (FCOJ) futures market as a prominent example of the failure of prices to reflect fundamentals. In contrast, we show that when theory clearly identifies the fundamental, e.g., at temperatures close to or below freezing, a close link exists between FCOJ prices and that fundamental. Using a simple, theoretically motivated, nonlinear, state dependent model, we can explain approximately 50% of the return variation on days with freezing temperatures. Moreover, while these observations represent less than 4.5% of the winter sample, they account for two-thirds of the entire winter return variability. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boudoukh, Jacob; Richardson, Matthew; Shen, YuQing; Whitelaw, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Maximum likelihood estimation of stochastic volatility models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ait-Sahalia, Yacine; Kimmel, Robert
We develop and implement a method for maximum likelihood estimation in closed-form of stochastic volatility models. Using Monte Carlo simulations, we compare a full likelihood procedure, where an option price is inverted into the unobservable volatility state, to an approximate likelihood procedure where the volatility state is replaced by proxies based on the implied volatility of a short-dated at-the-money option. The approximation results in a small loss of accuracy relative to the standard errors due to sampling noise. We apply this method to market prices of index options for several stochastic volatility models, and compare the characteristics of the estimated models. The evidence for a general CEV model, which nests both the affine Heston model and a GARCH model, suggests that the elasticity of variance of volatility lies between that assumed by the two nested models. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ait-Sahalia, Yacine; Kimmel, Robert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do industries lead stock markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Torous, Walter; Valkanov, Rossen
We investigate whether the returns of industry portfolios predict stock market movements. In the US, a significant number of industry returns, including retail, services, commercial real estate, metal, and petroleum, forecast the stock market by up to two months. Moreover, the propensity of an industry to predict the market is correlated with its propensity to forecast various indicators of economic activity. The eight largest non-US stock markets show remarkably similar patterns. These findings suggest that stock markets react with a delay to information contained in industry returns about their fundamentals and that information diffuses only gradually across markets. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Torous, Walter; Valkanov, Rossen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate capital structure and the characteristics of suppliers and customers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kale, Jayant R.; Shahrur, Husayn
We investigate the link between a firm's leverage and the characteristics of its suppliers and customers. Specifically, we examine whether firms use decreased leverage as a commitment mechanism to induce suppliers/customers to undertake relationship-specific investments. We find that the firm's leverage is negatively related to the R&amp;D intensities of its suppliers and customers. We also find lower debt levels for firms operating in industries in which strategic alliances and joint ventures with firms in supplier and customer industries are more prevalent. Consistent with a bargaining role for debt, we find a positive relation between firm debt level and the degree of concentration in supplier/customer industries. (c) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kale, Jayant R.; Shahrur, Husayn</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does backdating explain the stock price pattern around executive stock option grants?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heron, Randall A.; Lie, Erik
Extant studies show that stock returns are abnormally negative before executive option grants and abnormally positive afterward. We find that this return pattern is much weaker since August 29, 2002, when the Securities and Exchange Commission requirement that option grants must be reported within two business days took effect. Furthermore, in those cases in which grants are reported within one day of the grant date, the pattern has completely vanished, but it continues to exist for grants reported with longer lags, and its magnitude tends to increase with the reporting delay. We interpret these findings as evidence that most of the abnormal return pattern around option grants is attributable to backdating of option grant dates. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heron, Randall A.; Lie, Erik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of state laws on capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wald, John K.; Long, Michael S.
US manufacturing firms incorporated in states with stronger payout restrictions use less debt, while antitakeover statutes do not significantly reduce long-run leverage. Correcting for the endogenously determined choice of where to incorporate, we find that firms sort themselves according to state laws and capital structure needs. After accounting for self-selection, state antitakeover laws are positively associated with debt as a fraction of market value, possibly due to lower market values for these firms. Payout restrictions appear to reduce leverage for firms that have not reincorporated outside their home states. These constraints explain part of the negative relation between profitability and leverage. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wald, John K.; Long, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firms' histories and their capital structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kayhan, Ayla; Titman, Sheridan
This paper examines how cash flows, investment expenditures, and stock price histories affect debt ratios. Consistent with earlier work, we find that these variables have a substantial influence on changes in capital structure. Specifically, stock price changes and financial deficits (i.e., the amount of external capital raised) have strong influences on capital Structure changes, but in contrast to previous conclusions, we find that over long horizons their effects are partially reversed. These results indicate that although firms' histories strongly influence their capital structures, over time their capital structures tend to move towards target debt ratios that are consistent with the tradeoff theories of capital structure. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kayhan, Ayla; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Share restrictions and asset pricing: Evidence from the hedge fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aragon, George O.
This paper presents evidence on the relation between hedge fund returns and restrictions imposed by funds that limit the liquidity of fund investors. The excess returns of funds with lockup restrictions are approximately 4-7% per year higher than those of nonlockup funds. The average alpha of all funds is negative or insignificant after controlling for lockups and other share restrictions. Also, a negative relation is found between share restrictions and the liquidity of the fund's portfolio. This suggests that share restrictions allow funds to efficiently manage illiquid assets, and these benefits are captured by investors as a share illiquidity premium. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aragon, George O.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of commercial paper rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Downing, Chris; Oliner, Stephen
This paper tests a generalized version of the expectations hypothesis in the market for commercial paper. Our main data set, which is new to the literature, consists of daily yield indexes constructed from the market yields for nearly all commercial paper issued by US corporations between 1998 and 2004. We show that term premia for commercial paper often rise dramatically at year-end. However, once we control for these year-end effects, we find considerable support for the generalized expectations hypothesis in the market for commercial paper. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Downing, Chris; Oliner, Stephen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Saving and investing for early retirement: A theoretical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farhi, Emmanuel; Panageas, Stavros
We Study optimal consumption and portfolio choice in a framework where investors adjust their labor Supply through an irreversible choice of their retirement time. We show that investing for early retirement tends to increase savings and reduce an agent's effective relative risk aversion, thus increasing her stock market exposure. Contrary to common intuition, an investor might find it optimal to increase the proportion of financial wealth held in stocks as she ages and accumulates assets, even when her income and the investment opportunity set are constant. The model predicts a decrease in risk aversion following strong market gains like those observed in the nineties. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Farhi, Emmanuel; Panageas, Stavros</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market price of risk specifications for affine models: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheridito, Patrick; Filipovic, Damir; Kimmel, Robert L.
We extend the standard specification of the market price of risk for affine yield models, and apply it to U.S. Treasury data. Our specification often provides better fit, sometimes with very high statistical significance. The improved fit comes from the time-series rather than cross-sectional features of the yield curve. We derive conditions under which our specification does not admit arbitrage opportunities. The extension has extremely strong statistical significance For affine yield models with multiple square-root type variables. Although we focus on affine yield models, our specification can be used with other asset pricing models as well. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cheridito, Patrick; Filipovic, Damir; Kimmel, Robert L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The empirical risk-return relation: A factor analysis approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ludvigson, Sydney C.; Ng, Serena
Existing empirical literature on the risk-return relation uses relatively small amount of conditioning information to model the conditional mean and conditional volatility of excess stock market returns. We use dynamic Factor analysis for large data sets, to summarize a large amount of economic information by few estimated factors, and find that three new factors-termed "volatility," "risk premium," and "real" factors-contain important information about one-quarter-ahead excess returns and volatility not contained in commonly used predictor variables. Our specifications predict 16-20% of the one-quarter-ahead variation in excess stock market returns, and exhibit stable and statistically significant out-of-sample forecasting power. We also find a positive conditional risk-return correlation. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ludvigson, Sydney C.; Ng, Serena</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed finance and technological change: Evidence from credit relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herrera, Ana Maria; Minetti, Raoul
This paper empirically investigates the effect of "informed finance" on technological change. The theoretical literature offers conflicting predictions on whether the information of financiers fosters or inhibits firms' innovation. Using data from a sample of Italian manufacturing firms, we find that the information of firms' main banks, proxied by the duration of credit relationships, promotes innovation. This positive effect is economically and statistically more significant for product than for process innovations. Nonetheless, the role of relationship banks in innovation is quite unsophisticated: they do not foster internal research but rather fund the relevant investments that the introduction and acquisition of new technologies entails. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Herrera, Ana Maria; Minetti, Raoul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multi-period corporate default prediction with stochastic covariates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffie, Darrell; Saita, Leandro; Wang, Ke
We provide maximum likelihood estimators of term structures of conditional probabilities of corporate default, incorporating the dynamics of firm-specific and macroeconomic covariates. For US Industrial firms, based on over 390,000 firm-months of data spanning 1980 to 2004, the term structure of conditional future default probabilities depends on a firm's distance to default (a volatility-adjusted measure of leverage), on the firm's trailing stock return, on trailing S&amp;P 500 returns, and on US interest rates. The out-of-sample predictive performance of the model is an improvement over that of other available models. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duffie, Darrell; Saita, Leandro; Wang, Ke</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of corporate liquidity: Acquisition discounts for unlisted targets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Officer, Micah S.
This paper documents average acquisition discounts for stand-alone private firms and subsidianes of other firms (unlisted targets) of 15% to 30% relative to acquisition multiples for comparable publicly traded targets. My results are strongly consistent with the notion that sale prices for unlisted targets are affected by both the need for, and availability of, the liquidity provided by the buyi.r. Corporate parents are significantly liquidity-constraincd prior to the sale of a subsidiary, particularly when the subsidiary is being sold for cash. Furthermore, acquisition discounts are significandy greater when debt capital is relatively more expensive to obtain, and when the parent firm has belowmarket stock returns in the 12 months prior to the sale. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Officer, Micah S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing, consumption and asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piazzesi, Monika; Schneider, Martin; Tuzel, Selale
This paper considers a consumption-based asset pricing model where housing is explicitly modeled both as an asset and as a consumption good. Nonseparable preferences describe households' concern with composition risk, that is, fluctuations in the relative share of housing in their consumption basket. Since the housing share moves slowly, a concern with composition risk induces low frequency movements in stock prices that are not driven by news about cash flow. Moreover, the model predicts that the housing share can be used to forecast excess returns on stocks. We document that this indeed true in the data. The presence of composition risk also implies that the riskless rate is low which further helps the model improve on the standard CCAPM. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Piazzesi, Monika; Schneider, Martin; Tuzel, Selale</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disagreement, tastes, and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
Standard asset pricing models assume that: (i) there is complete agreement among investors about probability distributions of future payoffs on assets; and (ii) investors choose asset holdings based solely on anticipated payoffs-, that is, investment assets are not also consumption goods. Both assumptions are unrealistic. We provide a simple framework for studying how disagreement and tastes for assets as consumption goods can affect asset prices. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing Q theory with financing frictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Levy, Amnon; Whited, Toni M.
We develop a Q theory of investment under financing constraints. The firm invests and saves optimally facing convex costs of external equity, overhang from outstanding debt, and collateial constraints on new borrowing. Overhang and costs of external equity discourage investment. Conversely, firms anticipating collateral constraints experience a side benefit from investing as installed capital relaxes future constraints. Empirical tests support the model. Conditional on average Q, investment is lower for equity issuers and for firms with large debt overhang. The Kaplan and Zingales and the Whited and Wu indices are used as proxies for future collateral constraints. Consistent with the model, both indices enter investment regressions positively. (c) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Levy, Amnon; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneous preferences and equilibrium trading volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berrada, Tony; Hugonnier, Julien; Rindisbacher, Marcel
The representative-agent Lucas model stresses aggregate risk and hence does not allow us to study the impact of agents' heterogeneity on the dynamics of equilibrium trading volume. In this paper, we investigate under what conditions non-informational heterogeneity, i.e., differences in preferences and endowments, leads to nontrivial trading volume in equilibrium. We present a non-informational no-trade theorem that provides necessary and sufficient conditions for zero equilibrium trading volume in a continuous-time Lucas market model with heterogeneous agents, multiple goods, and multiple securities. We explain in detail how no-trade equilibria are related to autarky equilibria, portfolio autarky equilibria, and peculiar financial market equilibria, which play an important role in the literature on international risk sharing. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berrada, Tony; Hugonnier, Julien; Rindisbacher, Marcel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local ownership as private information: Evidence on the monitoring-liquidity trade-off</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaspar, Jose-Miguel; Massa, Massimo
We investigate how ownership patterns affect the way the firm is monitored, the liquidity of its shares, and its stock price. We show that informed ownership improves governance and induces value-enhancing decisions (less over-investment and fewer but better acquisitions). At the same time, it increases the adverse selection discount required by less informed investors to trade, reducing the firm's liquidity. Both effects are impounded in the stock price. This explains why ownership seems to be unrelated to performance. Informed investors affect prices in opposite directions: monitoring would raise prices, but the lower liquidity induced by their presence would reduce them. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gaspar, Jose-Miguel; Massa, Massimo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and the value of cash holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, Amy; Mahrt-Smith, Jan
We investigate how corporate governance impacts firm value by comparing the value and use of cash holdings in poorly and well-governed firms. We show that governance has a substantial impact on value through its impact on cash: $1.00 of cash in a poorly governed firm is valued at only $0.42 to $0.88. Good governance approximately doubles this value. Furthermore, we show that firms with poor corporate governance dissipate cash quickly in ways that significantly reduce operating performance. This negative impact of large cash holdings on future operating performance is cancelled out if the firm is well governed. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dittmar, Amy; Mahrt-Smith, Jan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Partial adjustment toward target capital structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flannery, M. J.; Rangan, K. P.
The empirical literature provides conflicting assessments about how firms choose their capital structures. Distinguishing among the three main hypotheses ("tradeoff", pecking order, and market timing) requires that we know whether firms have long-run leverage targets and (if so) how quickly they adjust toward them. Yet many previous researchers have applied empirical specifications that fail to recognize the potential for incomplete adjustment. A more general, partial-adjustment model of firm leverage indicates that firms do have target capital structures. The typical firm closes about one-third of the gap between its actual and its target debt ratios each year. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Flannery, M. J.; Rangan, K. P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility in an era of reduced uncertainty: Lessons from Pax Britannica</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, W. O.; Burdekin, R. C. K.; Weidenmier, M. D.
Although it has been well established that financial volatility is related to news and macroeconomic shocks, less emphasis has been placed on the importance of underlying economic and political stability. In this paper we study the behavior of consol returns since 1729 and identify a greater-than-50% decline in volatility from the end of the Napoleonic Wars in 1815 until the First World War. News events and macroeconomic variables cannot account for this extended period of reduced volatility. Underlying political stability under Pax Britannica seems to be a more likely explanation. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, W. O.; Burdekin, R. C. K.; Weidenmier, M. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Separating microstructure noise from volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bandi, F. M.; Russell, J. R.
There are two variance components embedded in the returns constructed using high frequency asset prices: the time-varying variance of the unobservable efficient returns that would prevail in a frictionless economy and the variance of the equally unobservable microstructure noise. Using sample moments of high frequency return data recorded at different frequencies, we provide a simple and robust technique to identify both variance components. In the context of a volatility-timing trading strategy, we show that careful (optimal) separation of the two volatility components of the observed stock returns yields substantial utility gains. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bandi, F. M.; Russell, J. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trades outside the quotes: Reporting delay, trading option, or trade size?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoll, H. R.; Schenzler, C.
In the period 1993 through 2002 examined in this study, quoted and effective spreads declined substantially on Nasdaq and to a lesser degree on the NYSE. At the same time, however, trades outside the quotes increased dramatically on Nasdaq. Because investors would prefer to trade at the quotes rather than outside the quotes, we examine why trades outside the quotes are observed. We focus on how the continuous market mechanism itself influences the outcome of orders and the reporting of trades, and we conclude that slippage exists in the market mechanism. Outside-trades occur on Nasdaq, first, because of delays in reporting trades, second, because the ability of dealers to delay execution of trades creates a look-back option, which when exercised results in outside-trades, and third, because large trades can take place at prices outside the quotes. Outside-trades are rarely observed on the NYSE because the market is more centralized. While the pattern of trading on the NYSE is not inconsistent with the presence of a look-back option, our tests provide no direct evidence that specialists are exercising such an option. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stoll, H. R.; Schenzler, C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A general approach to integrated risk management with skewed, fat-tailed risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosenberg, J. V.; Schuermann, T.
Integrated risk management for financial institutions requires an approach for aggregating risk types (market, credit, and operational) whose distributional shapes vary considerably. We construct the joint risk distribution for a typical large, internationally active bank using the method of copulas. This technique allows us to incorporate realistic marginal distributions that capture essential empirical features of these risks such as skewness and fat-tails while allowing for a rich dependence structure. We explore the impact of business mix and inter-risk correlations on total risk. We then compare the copula-based method with several conventional approaches to computing risk. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rosenberg, J. V.; Schuermann, T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock returns, aggregate earnings surprises, and behavioral finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kothari, S. P.; Lewellen, J.; Warner, J. B.
We study the stock market's reaction to aggregate earnings news. Prior research shows that, for individual firms, stock prices react positively to earnings news but require several quarters to fully reflect the information in earnings. We find a substantially different pattern in aggregate data. First, returns are unrelated to past earnings, suggesting that prices neither underreact nor overreact to aggregate earnings news. Second, aggregate returns correlate negatively with concurrent earnings; over the last 30 years, for example, stock prices increased 5.7% in quarters with negative earnings growth and only 2.1% otherwise. This finding suggests that earnings and discount rates move together over time and provides new evidence that discount-rate shocks explain a significant fraction of aggregate stock returns. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kothari, S. P.; Lewellen, J.; Warner, J. B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term structure estimation without using latent factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffee, G. R.
A combination of observed and unobserved (latent) factors capture term structure dynamics. Information about these dynamics is extracted from observed factors using restrictions implied by no-arbitrage, without specifying or estimating any of the parameters associated with latent factors. Estimation is equivalent to fitting the moment conditions of a set of regressions, where no-arbitrage imposes cross-equation restrictions on the coefficients. The methodology is applied to the dynamics of inflation and yields. Outside of the disinflationary period of 1979 through 1983, short-term rates move one-for-one with expected inflation, while bond risk premia are insensitive to inflation. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duffee, G. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are perks purely managerial excess?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajan, R. G.; Wulf, J.
A widespread view is that executive perks exemplify agency-problems-they are a route through which managers misappropriate a firm's surplus. Accordingly,. firms with high free cash flow, operating in industries with limited investment prospects, should offer more perks, and firms subject to more external monitoring should offer fewer perks. The evidence for agency as an explanation of perks is, at best, mixed. Perks are, however, offered in situations in which they enhance managerial productivity. While we cannot rule out the occasional aberration, and while we have little to say on the overall level of perks, our findings suggest that treating perks purely as managerial excess is incorrect. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rajan, R. G.; Wulf, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of performance-based compensation on misreporting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burns, N.; Kedia, S.
This paper examines the effect of CEO compensation contracts on misreporting. We find that the sensitivity of the CEO's option portfolio to stock price is significantly positively related to the propensity to misreport. We do not find that the sensitivity of other components of CEO compensation, i.e., equity, restricted stock, long-term incentive payouts, and salary plus bonus have any significant impact on the propensity to misreport. Relative to other components of compensation, stock options are associated with stronger incentives to misreport because convexity in CEO wealth introduced by stock options limits the downside risk on detection of the misreporting. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Burns, N.; Kedia, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crushed by a rational stampede: Strategic share dumping and shareholder insurrections</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Attari, M.; Banerjee, S.; Noe, T. H.
In this paper, we develop a dynamic model of institutional share dumping surrounding control events. Institutional investors sometimes dump shares, despite trading losses, in order to manipulate share prices and trigger activism by "relationship" investors. These institutional investors are motivated to trade not only by trading profits but also by a desire to protect the value of their inventory and to disguise the quality of their own information. Relationship investor profit from targeting firms both by improving firm performance and by generating private information. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Attari, M.; Banerjee, S.; Noe, T. H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate tax avoidance and high-powered incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, M. A.; Dharmapala, D.
This paper analyzes the links between corporate tax avoidance and the growth of high-powered incentives for managers. A simple model demonstrates the role of feedback effects between tax sheltering and managerial diversion in determining how high-powered incentives influence tax sheltering decisions. A novel measure of corporate tax avoidance (the component of the book-tax gap not attributable to accounting accruals) allows for an investigation of the link between tax avoidance and incentive compensation. Increases in incentive compensation tend to reduce the level of tax sheltering, in a manner consistent with a complementary relationship between diversion and sheltering. In addition, this negative effect is driven primarily by firms with relatively weak governance arrangements., confirming a central prediction of the model. These results can help explain the growing cross-sectional variation among firms in their levels of tax avoidance, the undersheltering puzzle, and why large book-tax gaps are associated with subsequent negative abnormal returns. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Desai, M. A.; Dharmapala, D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should business groups be dismantled? The equilibrium costs of efficient internal capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, H.; Wolfenzon, D.
We analyze the relationship between conglomerates' internal capital markets and the efficiency of economy-wide capital allocation, and we identify a novel cost of conglomeration that arises from an equilibrium framework. Because of financial market imperfections engendered by imperfect investor protection, conglomerates that engage in winner-picking (Stein, 1997 [Internal capital markets and the completion for corporate resources. Journal of Finance 52, 111-133]) find it optimal to allocate scarce capital internally to mediocre projects, even when other firms in the economy have higher-productivity projects that are in need of additional capital. This bias for internal capital allocation can decrease allocative efficiency even when conglomerates have efficient internal capital markets, because a substantial presence of conglomerates might make it harder for other firms in the economy to raise capital. We also argue that the negative externality associated with conglomeration is particularly costly for countries that are at intermediary levels of financial development. In such countries, a high degree of conglomeration, generated, for example, by the control of the corporate sector by family business groups, could decrease the efficiency of the capital market. Our theory generates novel empirical predictions that cannot be derived in models that ignore the equilibrium effects of conglomerates. These predictions are consistent with anecdotal evidence that the presence of business groups in developing countries inhibits the growth of new independent firms because of a lack of finance. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Almeida, H.; Wolfenzon, D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should corporate debt include a rating trigger?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhanot, K.; Mello, A. S.
Recent corporate debt offerings have included a covenant specifying a pre-determined payment to debtholders when the debt is downgraded. We examine the incentive for equityholders to increase firm risk (and the associated costs) when debt includes a "rating trigger." Equityholders of firms with a low-risk profile and operating flexibility choose debt with a trigger, while equityholders of firms with a high-risk profile and less flexibility choose regular debt. A trigger that requires an equity infusion better mitigates conflicts between equityholders and debtholders than a trigger paid by liquidating assets. A trigger that increases the coupon rate is not optimal. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhanot, K.; Mello, A. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial incentives and risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coles, J. L.; Daniel, N. D.; Naveen, L.
We provide empirical evidence of a strong causal relation between managerial compensation and investment policy, debt policy, and firm risk. Controlling for CEO pay-performance sensitivity (delta) and the feedback effects of firm policy and risk on the managerial compensation scheme, we find that higher sensitivity of CEO wealth to stock volatility (vega) implements riskier policy choices, including relatively more investment in R&amp;D, less investment in PPE, more focus, and higher leverage. We also find that riskier policy choices generally lead to compensation structures with higher vega and lower delta. Stock-return volatility has a positive effect on both vega and delta. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coles, J. L.; Daniel, N. D.; Naveen, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The new new financial thing: The origins of financial innovations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lerner, J.
The origins of financial innovations have attracted little empirical scrutiny. Using Wall Street Journal articles as an indicator, this paper examines which institutions were the key financial innovators between 1990 and 2002. The evidence suggests that smaller firms account for a disproportionate share of the innovations. Less profitable firms innovate more, though in the years subsequent to the introduction of the innovation, the profitability of the innovators increases significantly. Finally, older, less leveraged firms located in regions with more financial innovations innovate more. While several of the determinants of patenting are similar, small and unprofitable firms do not patent disproportionately. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lerner, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition among regulators and credit market integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dell'Ariccia, G.; Marquez, R.
We analyze the incentives for independent bank regulators with financially integrated jurisdictions to form a regulatory union. Externalities lead competing regulators to choose suboptimally low standards. Centralized regulation, however, entails a loss of flexibility if equal standards must be applied across jurisdictions. We find that, first, centralized regulation will more likely emerge among relatively homogeneous jurisdictions/countries. Second, centralized regulation will be unanimously preferred to independence only if it entails standards higher than those of the country with the highest individual standards. Third, financial integration among more than two jurisdictions may prevent partial unions, which, in turn, may prevent more comprehensive agreements. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dell'Ariccia, G.; Marquez, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A consumption-based-model of the term structure of interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wachter, J. A.
This paper proposes a consumption-based model that accounts for many features of the nominal term structure of interest rates. The driving force behind the model is a time-varying price of risk generated by external habit. Nominal bonds depend on past consumption growth through habit and on expected inflation. When calibrated to data on consumption, inflation, and the aggregate market, the model produces realistic means and volatilities of bond yields and accounts for the expectations puzzle. The model also captures the high equity premium and excess stock market volatility. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wachter, J. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who trades IPOs? A close look at the first days of trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, K.
I examine the enormous trading volume in the first two days of trading following an initial public offering (IPO) with a sample of Nasdaq IPOs. The composition of trading varies widely with the initial return and not all trading is investor-related. Cold IPOs have a high proportion of interdealer sell trades, whereas hot IPOs have balanced investor buying and selling. Market makers hold zero inventory throughout trading, offsetting any investor inventory imbalance with a trade with the lead underwriter. The paper also helps resolve the disconnect reported in the literature between high initial trading volume and low "flipping" activity. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ellis, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage and investment in diversified firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, S.; Denis, D. J.; Denis, D. K.
Within diversified firms, the negative impact of leverage on investment is significantly greater for high q than for low q segments and significantly greater for non-core than for core segments. This differs substantially from focused firms and is consistent with the view that diversified firms allocate a disproportionate share of their debt service burden to their higher q and non-core segments. We also find that, among low-growth firms, the positive relation between leverage and firm value is significantly weaker in diversified firms than in focused firms. We conclude that the disciplinary benefits of debt are partially offset by the additional managerial discretion in allocating debt service that is provided by the diversified organizational structure. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahn, S.; Denis, D. J.; Denis, D. K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The irrelevance of the MM dividend irrelevance theorem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, H.; DeAngelo, L.
Contrary to Miller and Modigliani [1961. Dividend policy, growth, and the valuation of shares. Journal of Business 34, 411-433], payout policy is not irrelevant and investment policy is not the sole determinant of value, even in frictionless markets. MM ask "Do companies with generous distribution policies consistently sell at a premium above those with niggardly payouts?" But MM's analysis does not address this question because the joint effect of their assumptions is to mandate 100% free cash flow payout in every period, thereby rendering "niggardly payouts" infeasible and forcing distributions to a global optimum. Irrelevance obtains. but in an economically vacuous sense because the firm's opportunity set is artificially constrained to payout policies that fully distribute free cash flow. When MM's assumptions are relaxed to allow retention, payout policy matters in exactly the same sense that investment policy does. Moreover (i) the standard Fisherian model is empirically refutable, predicting that firms will make large payouts in present value terms, (ii) only when payout policy is optimized will the present value of distributions equal the PV of project cash flows, (iii) the NPV rule for investments is not sufficient to ensure value maximization, rather an analogous rule for payout policy is also necessary, and (iv) Black's [1976. The dividend puzzle. Journal of Portfolio Management 2, 5-8] "dividend puzzle" is a non-puzzle because it is rooted in the mistaken idea that MM's irrelevance theorem applies to payout/retention decisions, which it does not. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeAngelo, H.; DeAngelo, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>R-2 around the world: New theory and new tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, L.; Myers, S. C.
Morck, Yeung and Yu show that R-2 is higher in countries with less developed financial systems and poorer corporate governance. We show how control rights and information affect the division of risk bearing between managers and investors. Lack of transparency increases R-2 by shifting firm-specific risk to managers. Opaque stocks with high R(2)s are also more likely to crash, that is, to deliver large negative returns. Using stock returns from 40 stock markets from 1990 to 2001, we find strong positive relations between R-2 and several measures of opaqueness. These measures also explain the frequency of crashes. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jin, L.; Myers, S. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity needs and vulnerability to financial underdevelopment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Raddatz, C.
This paper provides evidence that financial development has a large causal effect in the reduction of macroeconomic volatility resulting from the role of the financial system in liquidity provision. In particular, financial system development leads to a comparatively larger reduction in the volatility of output in sectors with high liquidity needs. Most of this decline results from the stabilization of the output of existing firms, although the volatility of the number of firms also drops significantly. Among different aspects of the financial system, the depth of financial intermediaries plays the main role in the reduction of volatility. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Raddatz, C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings and price momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, Tarun; Shivakumar, Lakshmanan
This paper examines whether earnings momentum and price momentum are related. Both in time-series as well as in cross-sectional asset pricing tests, we find that price momentum is captured by the systematic component of earnings momentum. The predictive power of past returns is subsumed by a zero-investment portfolio that is long on stocks with high earnings surprises and short on stocks with low earnings surprises. Further, returns to the earnings-based zero-investment portfolio are significantly related to future macroeconomic activities, including growth in GDP, industrial production, consumption, labor income, inflation, and T-bill returns. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chordia, Tarun; Shivakumar, Lakshmanan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who herds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernhardt, Dan; Campello, Murillo; Kutsoati, Edward
This paper develops a test for herding in forecasts by professional financial analysts that is robust to (a) correlated information amongst analysts; (b) common unforecasted industry-wide earnings shocks; (c) information arrival over the forecasting cycle; (d) the possibility that the earnings that analysts forecast differ from what the econometrician observes, and (e) systematic optimism or pessimism among analysts. We find that forecasts are biased, but that analysts do not herd. Instead, analysts "anti-herd": Analysts systematically issue biased contrarian forecasts that overshoot the publicly-available consensus forecast in the direction of their private information. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bernhardt, Dan; Campello, Murillo; Kutsoati, Edward</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An equilibrium model of incentive contracts in the presence of information manipulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldman, E.; Slezak, S. L.
This paper develops an agency model in which stock-based compensation is a double-edged sword, inducing managers to exert productive effort but also to divert valuable firm resources to misrepresent performance. We examine how the potential for manipulation affects the equilibrium level of pay-for-performance sensitivity and derive several new cross-sectional implications that are consistent with recent empirical studies. In addition, we analyze the impact of recent regulatory changes contained in the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 and show how policies intended to increase firm value by reducing misrepresentation can actually reduce firm value or increase the upward bias in manipulated disclosures. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goldman, E.; Slezak, S. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor attention, overconfidence and category learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peng, L.; Xiong, W.
Motivated by psychological evidence that attention is a scarce cognitive resource, we model investors' attention allocation in learning and study the effects of this on asset-price dynamics. We show that limited investor attention leads to category-learning behavior, i.e., investors tend to process more market and sector-wide information than firm-specific information. This endogenous structure of information, when combined with investor overconfidence, generates important features observed in return comovement that are otherwise difficult to explain with standard rational expectations models. Our model also demonstrates new cross-sectional implications for return predictability. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Peng, L.; Xiong, W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic liquidity in endowment economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, T. C.
This paper analyzes endogenous variations in aggregate liquidity that arise in standard representative-agent endowment economies. I introduce a natural definition of liquidity, essentially a shadow elasticity, that characterizes the price impact function or bid/ask spread that a small trader would experience. I compute this quantity for some tractable examples and uncover a rich variety of predictions that, in some cases, appear consistent with levels and covariations observed in the data. The results have important implications for the pricing and hedging of liquidity risk. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Johnson, T. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO incentives and earnings management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergstresser, D.; Philippon, T.
We provide evidence that the use of discretionary accruals to manipulate reported earnings is more pronounced at firms where the CEO's potential total compensation is more closely tied to the value of stock and option holdings. In addition, during years of high accruals, CEOs exercise unusually large numbers of options and CEOs and other insiders sell large quantities of shares. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bergstresser, D.; Philippon, T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of socialistic internal capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernardo, A. E.; Luo, J.; Wang, J. J. D.
We develop a model of a two-division firm in which the "strong" division has, on average, higher quality investment opportunities than the "weak" division. We show that, in the presence of agency and information problems, optimal effort incentives are less powerful and thus managerial effort is lower in the strong division. This leads the firm to bias its project selection policy against the strong division. The selection bias is more severe when there is a larger spread in the average quality of investment opportunities between the two divisions. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bernardo, A. E.; Luo, J.; Wang, J. J. D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic forecasting behavior by analysts: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, J.; Subramanian, A.
We develop a multi-period learning model to examine the relation between analysts' forecasting behavior and their performance. In a competitive market for banking services, the surplus and the analyst's payoff, which is determined through bargaining, are convex in her reputation. The convexity of her payoff structure and the presence of employment risk lead to a U-shaped relation between the analyst's forecast boldness and prior performance and a positive relation between forecast boldness and experience. We find support for these predictions in our empirical analysis. Significant underperformers (outperformers) face higher (lower) employment risk and are more likely to issue bolder forecasts. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Clarke, J.; Subramanian, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic alliances, equity stakes, and entry deterrence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mathews, R. D.
I study how strategic alliances and their impact on future competitive incentives can motivate interfirm equity sales. In the model, an alliance between an entrepreneurial firm and an established firm improves efficiency for both. However, the requisite knowledge transfer heightens the established firm's incentive to enter one of its partner's markets. I show that equity can eliminate the entry incentive, but accommodation is sometimes chosen to encourage entreprencurial effort on future growth options. I analyze stake sizes, block pricing, and welfare effects. The results have implications for equity alliances, corporate venture capital, and the organization of research activities. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mathews, R. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do alliances promote knowledge flows?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomes-Casseres, B.; Hagedoorn, J.; Jaffe, A. B.
We explore the role of interfirm alliances as a mechanism for sharing technological knowledge. We argue that knowledge flows between alliance partners will be greater than flows between pairs of nonallied firms, and less than flows between units within single firms. Using patent citations as a proxy for knowledge flows, we find results that are consistent with these expectations. We then explore how firm characteristics affect knowledge flows within alliances and find positive effects due to technological, geographic, and business similarities between partners. We use alliance data from MERIT, patent data from the USPTO, and firm data from Compustat. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gomes-Casseres, B.; Hagedoorn, J.; Jaffe, A. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>NBER Conference on corporate alliances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lerner, J.; Rajan, R.
nan</description><author>Lerner, J.; Rajan, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of regulation on market risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grout, P. A.; Zalewska, A.
While it is crucial to understand the impact of regulatory changes on market risk, the literature does not show how risk responds to expected regulatory changes that are specifically designed to change risk. Our paper fills this gap by providing a detailed study of one such case. Using both a sample of privatized U.K. companies, and U.K. and U.S. control portfolios, between 1993 and 2000, we show (both for the single-factor market model and the three-factor Fama-French model) that the observed changes in market risk are significant and consistent with theory. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grout, P. A.; Zalewska, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock price synchronicity and analyst coverage in emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, K.; Hameed, A.
This paper examines the relation between the stock price synchronicity and analyst activity in emerging markets. Contrary to the conventional wisdom that security analysts specialize in the production of firm-specific information, we find that securities which are covered by more analysts incorporate greater (lesser) market-wide (firm-specific) information. Using the R-2 statistics of the market model as a measure of synchronicity of stock price movement, we find that greater analyst coverage increases stock price synchronicity. Furthermore, after controlling for the influence of firm size on the lead-lag relation, we find that the returns of high analyst-following portfolio lead returns of low analyst-following portfolio more than vice versa. We also find that the aggregate change in the earnings forecasts in a high analyst-following portfolio affects the aggregate returns of the portfolio itself as well as those of the low analyst-following portfolio, whereas the aggregate change in the earnings forecasts of the low analyst-following portfolio have no predictive ability. Finally, when the forecast dispersion is high, the effect of analyst coverage on stock price synchronicity is reduced. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, K.; Hameed, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are European IPOs so rarely priced outside the indicative price range?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jenkinson, T.; Morrison, A. D.; Wilhelm, W. J.
Unlike in the U.S., the initial price range for European IPOs is seldom revised, although issues are often priced at the upper bound. We develop a model that explains this seemingly inefficient pricing behavior. As in Europe, but not in the U.S., underwriters in the model obtain information from investors before establishing the indicative price range. A commitment to stay within the range is necessary to extract private information from investors. ours is therefore the first treatment in which the bookbuilding range has a clear economic role. The model has important implications for empirical research based on European primary market data. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jenkinson, T.; Morrison, A. D.; Wilhelm, W. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flights of fancy: Corporate jets, CEO perquisites, and inferior shareholder returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yermack, D.
This paper studies perquisites of CEOs, focusing on personal use of company planes. For firms that have disclosed this managerial benefit, average shareholder returns underperform market benchmarks by more than 4% annually, a severe gap far exceeding the costs of resources consumed. Around the date of the initial disclosure, firms' stock prices drop by an average of 1.1%. Regression analysis finds no significant associations between CEOs' perquisites and their compensation or percentage ownership, but variables related to personal CEO characteristics, especially long-distance golf club memberships, have significant explanatory power for personal aircraft use. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yermack, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do accurate earnings forecasts facilitate superior investment recommendations?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loh, Roger K.; Mian, G. Mujtaba
We find that analysts who issue more accurate earnings forecasts also issue more profitable stock recommendations. The average factor-adjusted return associated with the recommendations of analysts in the highest accuracy quintile exceeds the corresponding return for analysts in the lowest accuracy quintile by 1.27% per month. Our findings provide indirect empirical support for valuation models in the accounting and finance literatures (e.g., Ohlson, 1995) that emphasize the role of future earnings in predicting stock price movements. Our results also suggest that imperfectly efficient markets reward information gatherers, such as security analysts, for their costly activities in generating superior earnings forecasts. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loh, Roger K.; Mian, G. Mujtaba</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The American keiretsu and universal banks: Investing, voting and sitting on nonfinancials' corporate boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santos, J. A. C.; Rumble, A. S.
This paper investigates the equity investments and voting rights that American banks control through their trust business. The paper also studies whether the voting rights American banks control through their trust business help explain their presence on firms' corporate boards. We find that on average the largest 100 American banks control 10% of the voting rights of S&amp;P 500 firms. We also find that there are several firms in the S&amp;P 500 index in which the top banks control more than 20% of their voting rights, and several firms in the country in which these banks control more than 60% of their voting rights. Our investigation into the presence of American bankers on corporate boards shows that bankers are more likely to join the boards of firms in which they control a large voting stake. We also find that banks' lending relationships help explain bankers' board memberships. Our results further show that bankers who have both a voting stake in a firm and a lending relationship with it have a higher likelihood of joining the firm's board of directors. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights. reserved.</description><author>Santos, J. A. C.; Rumble, A. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do family ownership, control and management affect firm value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Villalonga, B.; Amit, R.
Using proxy data on all Fortune-500 firms during 1994-2000, we find that family ownership creates value only when the founder serves as CEO of the family firm or as Chairman with a hired CEO. Dual share classes, pyramids, and voting agreements reduce the founder's premium. When descendants serve as CEOs, firm value is destroyed. Our findings suggest that the classic owner-manager conflict in nonfamily firms is more costly than the conflict between family and nonfamily shareholders in founder-CEO firms. However, the conflict between family and nonfamily shareholders in descendant-CEO firms is more costly than the owner-manager conflict in nonfamily firms. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Villalonga, B.; Amit, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The outsourcing of R&amp;D through acquisitions in the pharmaceutical industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Higgins, Matthew J.; Rodriguez, Daniel
We examine the performance of 160 pharmaceutical acquisitions from 1994 to 2001 and find evidence that on average acquirers realize significant positive returns. These returns are positively correlated with prior acquirer access to information about the research and development activities at target firms and a superior negotiating position. A unique Desperation Index is employed to determine the current status of a firm's internal productivity. We find that firms experiencing declines in internal productivity or which are more desperate are more likely to engage in an outsourcing-type acquisition in an effort to replenish their research pipelines. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Higgins, Matthew J.; Rodriguez, Daniel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum and post-earnings-announcement drift anomalies: The role of liquidity risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sadka, R.
This paper investigates the components of liquidity risk that are important for understanding asset-pricing anomalies. Firm-level liquidity is decomposed into variable and fixed price effects and estimated using intraday data for the period 1983-2001. Unexpected systematic (market-wide) variations of the variable component rather than the fixed component of liquidity are shown to be priced within the context of momentum and post-earnings-announcement drift (PEAD) portfolio returns. As the variable component is typically associated with private information [e.g... Kyle, 1985. Econometrica 53, 1315-1335], the results suggest that a Substantial part of momentum and PEAD returns can be viewed as compensation for the unexpected variations in the aggregate ratio of informed traders to noise traders. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sadka, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend changes and catering incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Wei; Lie, Erik
We extend Baker and Wurgler's [2004a. Journal of Finance 59 1125-1165] catering theory to include decreases and increases in existing dividends. Consistent with our extended model, we find that the decision to change the dividend and the magnitude of the change depend on the premium that the capital market places on dividends. We also find that the stock market reaction to dividend changes depends on the dividend premium. Thus, the capital market rewards managers for considering investor demand for dividends when making decisions about the level of dividends. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Li, Wei; Lie, Erik</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax management strategies with multiple risky assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallmeyer, Michael F.; Kaniel, Ron; Tompaidis, Stathis
We study the consumption-portfolio problem in a setting with capital gain taxes and multiple risky stocks to understand how short selling influences portfolio choice with a shorting-the-box restriction. Our analysis uncovers a novel trading flexibility strategy whereby, to minimize future tax-induced trading costs, the investor optimally shorts one of the stocks (or equivalently, buys put options) even when no stock has an embedded gain. Alternatively, an imperfect form of shorting the box can reduce aggregate equity exposure ex post. Given these two short selling strategies, it is common for an unconstrained investor to short some equity while a constrained investor holds a positive investment in all stocks. With no shorting, the benefit of trading separately in multiple stocks is not economically significant. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Gallmeyer, Michael F.; Kaniel, Ron; Tompaidis, Stathis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder wealth effects and bid negotiation in freeze-out deals: Are minority shareholders left out in the cold?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, Thomas W.; Lemmon, Michael L.; Linck, James S.
This paper examines the shareholder wealth effects of bids by controlling shareholders seeking to acquire the remaining minority equity stake in a firm, deals commonly referred to as minority freeze-outs. Minority claimants in freeze-out offers receive an allocation of deal surplus at the bid announcement that exceeds their pro rata claim on the firm. An analysis of bid outcomes and renegotiation indicates that minority claimants and their agents exercise significant bargaining power during freeze-out proposals. Overall, our results suggest that legal standards and economic incentives are sufficient to deter self-dealing by controllers during freeze-out bids. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bates, Thomas W.; Lemmon, Michael L.; Linck, James S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPOs, acquisitions, and the use of convertible securities in venture capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hellmann, Thomas
This paper provides a new explanation for the use of convertible securities in venture capital. A key property of convertible preferred equity is that it allocates different cash flow rights, depending on whether exit occurs by acquisition or IPO. The paper builds a model with double moral hazard, where both the entrepreneur and the venture capitalist provide value-adding effort. The optimal contract gives the venture capitalist more cash flow rights in acquisitions than IPOs. This explains the use of convertible preferred equity, including automatic conversion at IPO. Contingent control rights are also important for achieving efficient exit decisions. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hellmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market liberalization and operating performance at the firm level</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitton, Todd
I use firm-specific measures of openness to foreign investors to study the impact of stock market liberalization on firm-level operating performance. In a sample of over 1, 100 firms from 28 countries, firms with stocks that are open to foreign investors experience higher growth, greater investment, greater profitability, greater efficiency, and lower leverage. Strategies to address potential endogeneity suggest that the observed relation reflects, at least in part, a causal effect of openness on operating performance. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mitton, Todd</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Output and expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rangvid, Jesper
This paper shows for 1929-2003 U.S. data and also for international G-7 data that the ratio of share prices to GDP tracks a large fraction of the variation over time in expected returns on the aggregate stock market, capturing more of that variation than do price-earnings and price-dividend ratios and often also providing additional information about excess returns. The price output ratio tracks long-term U.S. cumulative stock returns almost as well as the cay-ratio of Lettau and Ludvigson [2001a. Journal of Finance 56, 815-849, 2005. Journal of Financial Economics 76, 583-626], although the cay-ratio tracks variation in U.S. excess returns better. The price-output ratio, however, involves no parameter estimation and is easily constructed for non-U.S. countries. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rangvid, Jesper</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax shelters and corporate debt policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, John R.; Tucker, Alan L.
We gather a unique sample of 44 tax shelter cases to investigate the magnitude of tax shelter activity and whether participating in a shelter is related to corporate debt policy. The average annual deduction produced by the shelters in our sample is very large, equaling approximately nine percent of asset value. These deductions are more than three times as large as interest deductions for comparable companies. The firms in our sample use less debt when they engage in tax sheltering. Compared to companies with similar pre-shelter debt ratios, the debt ratios of firms engaged in tax shelters fall by about 8%. The tax shelter firms in our sample appear underlevered. if shelters are ignored but do not appear underlevered once shelters are considered. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Graham, John R.; Tucker, Alan L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend policy, signaling, and discounts on closed-end funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Shane A.; Lin, Ji-Chai; Song, Kyojik Roy
We test the predictions of dividend signaling models using closed-end equity funds that adopt explicit policies committing them to pay minimum dividend yields. These policies represent deliberate attempts to reduce share price undervaluation relative to NAV. Funds that adopt minimum dividend policies experience reductions in their share price discounts, trade at smaller discounts than other funds, earn greater excess returns following policy adoption, and their managers survive longer than other managers do. The results are broadly consistent with the predictions of dividend signaling models, and suggest that high quality closed-end funds can reduce undervaluation via dividend policy. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Johnson, Shane A.; Lin, Ji-Chai; Song, Kyojik Roy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence on the effects of bank competition on firm borrowing and investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zarutskie, Rebecca
This paper presents evidence on the financial and real effects of bank competition using a large panel of privately held firms. I trace the firm-level impact of the Riegle-Neal Interstate Banking and Branching Efficiency Act of 1994, which increased the competitiveness of U.S. banking markets. Following the deregulation, newly formed firms used significantly less external debt, were smaller, and realized higher returns on assets, consistent with their investing less due to greater financial constraints. These effects diminish as firms age, ultimately reversing sign. The differential impact that banking market reforms may have on newer and more established firms is underscored. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zarutskie, Rebecca</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>External finance constraints and the intertemporal pattern of intermittent investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Whited, Toni M.
Do external finance constraints affect the timing of large investment projects? Simulations of a model with fixed capital-stock adjustment costs establish the hypothesis that external finance constraints lower a firm's investment hazard: the probability of undertaking a large project today as a function of the time since the last project. Hazard model estimation that controls for productivity and adjustment costs supports this hypothesis. Small firms that distribute cash to shareholders have higher hazards than small firms that do not; very small firms have lower hazards than small firms; small stand-alone firms have significantly lower hazards than small segments of conglomerates. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of collateral</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jimenez, Gabriel; Salas, Vicente; Saurina, Jesus
We estimate a comprehensive model of the determinants of collateral in loans extended to business firms. We use a panel data on a sample of bank loans to Spanish firms from 1984 to 2002. Consistent with theories that view collateral as a solution to adverse selection problems, our results provide direct evidence of a negative association between collateral and a borrower's risk. We also present evidence on previously unexplored determinants of collateral such as credit market competition, lender type, and the business cycle. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jimenez, Gabriel; Salas, Vicente; Saurina, Jesus</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging, speculation, and shareholder value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adam, Tim R.; Fernando, Chitru S.
We document that gold mining firms have consistently realized economically significant cash flow gains from their derivatives transactions. We conclude that these cash flows have increased shareholder value since there is no evidence of an offsetting adjustment in firms' systematic risk. This finding contradicts a central assumption in the risk management literature that derivatives transactions have zero net present value, and highlights an important motive for firms to use derivatives that the literature has hitherto ignored. Although we find considerable evidence of selective hedging in our sample, the cash flow gains from selective hedging appear to be small at best. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adam, Tim R.; Fernando, Chitru S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Feedback and the success of irrational investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Titman, Sheridan
We provide a model in which irrational investors trade based upon considerations that have no inherent connection to fundamentals. However, trading activity affects market prices, and because of feedback from security prices to cash flows, the irrational trades influence underlying cash flows. As a result, irrational investors can, in some situations, earn abnormal (i.e., risk-adjusted) profits that can exceed the abnormal profits of rational informed investors. Although the trading of irrational investors cause prices to deviate from fundamental values, stock prices follow a random walk. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing in mutual funds when returns are predictable</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Wermers, Russ
This paper forms investment strategies in US domestic equity mutual funds, incorporating predictability in (i) manager skills, (ii) fund risk loadings, and (iii) benchmark returns. We find predictability in manager skills to be the dominant source of investment profitability-long-only strategies that incorporate such predictability outperform their Fama-French and momentum benchmarks by 2 to 4%/year by timing industries over the business cycle, and by an additional 3 to 6%/year by choosing funds that outperform their industry benchmarks. Our findings indicate that active management adds significant value, and that industries are important in locating outperforming mutual funds. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Own company stock in defined contribution pension plans: A takeover defense?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rauh, Joshua D.
If managers induce employees to hold company stock in defined contribution pension plans as a form of takeover defense, then changes in state laws that enhance managerial protection should lead to a reduction in employer stock in 401(k) plans. Delaware's mid-1990s validation of the poison pill in conjunction with a staggered board was followed by a significant decline in employee ownership within defined contribution plans for firms incorporated in Delaware. Evidence using governance data suggests that this is due to responses of firms with staggered boards. Binary choice models confirm that employee ownership in defined contribution plans lowers takeover probabilities. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rauh, Joshua D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political relationships, global financing, and corporate transparency: Evidence from Indonesia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leuz, Christian; Oberholzer-Gee, Felix
This study examines the role of political connections in firms' financing strategies and their long-run performance. We view political connections as an example for domestic arrangements which can reduce the benefits of global financing. Using data from Indonesia, we find that firms with strong political connections are less likely to have publicly traded foreign securities. As a result, estimates of the performance consequences of foreign financing are severely biased if value-creating domestic arrangements such as political relationships are ignored. Connections not only alter firms' financing strategies.. they also influence long-run performance. Tracking returns across several regimes, we show that firms have difficulty re-establishing connections with a new government when their patron falls from power, leading closely connected firms to underperform under the new regime and subsequently to increase their foreign financing. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leuz, Christian; Oberholzer-Gee, Felix</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The strategy of professional forecasting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ottaviani, Marco; Sorensen, Peter Norman
We develop and compare two theories of professional forecasters' strategic behavior. The first theory, reputational cheap talk, posits that forecasters endeavor to convince the market that they are well informed. The market evaluates their forecasting talent on the basis of the forecasts and the realized state. If the market expects forecasters to report their posterior expectations honestly, then forecasts are shaded toward the prior mean. With correct market expectations, equilibrium forecasts are imprecise but not shaded. The second theory posits that forecasters compete in a forecasting contest with pre-specified rules. In a winner-take-all contest, equilibrium forecasts are excessively differentiated. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ottaviani, Marco; Sorensen, Peter Norman</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend policy and the earned/contributed capital mix: a test of the life-cycle theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, Harry; DeAngelo, Linda; Stulz, Rene M.
Consistent with a life-cycle theory of dividends, the fraction of publicly traded industrial firms that pay dividends is high when retained earnings are a large portion of total equity (and of total assets) and falls to near zero when most equity is contributed rather than earned. We observe a highly significant relation between the decision to pay dividends and the earned/contributed capital mix, controlling for profitability, growth, firm size, total equity, cash balances, and dividend history, a relation that also holds for dividend initiations and omissions. In our regressions, the mix of earned/contributed capital has a quantitatively greater impact than measures of profitability and growth opportunities. We document a massive increase in firms with negative retained earnings (from 11.8% of industrials in 1978 to 50.2% in 2002). Controlling for the earned/contributed capital mix, firms with negative retained earnings show virtually no change in their propensity to pay dividends from the mid-1970s to 2002, while those whose earned equity makes them reasonable candidates to pay dividends have a propensity reduction that is twice the overall reduction in Fama and French [2000, Journal of Financial Economics 76, 549-582]. Finally, our simulations show that, if well-established firms had not paid dividends, their cash balances would be enormous and their long-term debt trivial, thus granting extreme discretion to managers of these mature firms. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeAngelo, Harry; DeAngelo, Linda; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the role of arbitrageurs in rational markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, Suleyman; Croitoru, Benjamin
We investigate the role of "arbitrageurs," who exploit price discrepancies between redundant securities. Arbitrage opportunities arise endogenously in an economy populated by rational, heterogeneous investors facing investment restrictions. We show that an arbitrageur alleviates these restrictions and improves the transfer of risk amongst investors. When the arbitrageur behaves noncompetitively, taking into account the price impact of his trades, he optimally limits the size of his positions due to his decreasing marginal profits. When the arbitrageur is subject to margin requirements and is endowed with capital from outside investors, the size of his trades and capital are endogenously determined in equilibrium. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Basak, Suleyman; Croitoru, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economic consequences of increased disclosure: Evidence from international cross-listings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bailey, Warren; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Salva, Carolina
We examine market behavior around earnings announcements to understand the consequences of the increased disclosure that non-U.S. firms face when listing shares in the U.S. We find that absolute return and volume reactions to earnings announcements typically increase significantly once a company cross-lists in the U.S. Furthermore, these increases are greatest for firms from developed countries and for firms that pursue over-the-counter listings or private placements, which do not have stringent disclosure requirements. Additional tests support the hypothesis that it is changes in the individual firm's disclosure environment, rather than changes in its market liquidity, ownership, or trading venue, that explain our findings. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bailey, Warren; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Salva, Carolina</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of tax shields IS equal to the present value of tax shields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Ian A.; Nyborg, Kjell G.
Fernandez [2004b. The value of tax shields is not equal to the present value of tax shields. Journal of Financial Economics 73, 145-165] argues that the present value effect of the tax saving on debt cannot be calculated as simply the present value of the tax shields associated with interest. This contradicts standard results in the literature. It implies that, even though the capital market is complete, value-additivity is violated. As a consequence, adjusted present value formulae of a standard sort cannot be used. Also, Fernandez's argument implies that the value of the tax saving differs front conventional estimates by a considerable amount. We reconcile Fernandez's results with standard valuation formulae for the tax saving from debt. We show that, as one would expect, the value of the debt tax saving is the present value of the tax savings from interest. The apparent violation of value-additivity in the Fernandez paper comes from mixing the Miles and Ezzell and Miller and Modigliani leverage policies. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cooper, Ian A.; Nyborg, Kjell G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-sectional forecasts of the equity premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Polk, Christopher; Thompson, Samuel; Vuolteenaho, Tuomo
If investors are myopic mean-variance optimizers, a stock's expected return is linearly related to its beta in the cross-section. The slope of the relation is the cross-sectional price of risk, which should equal the expected equity premium. We use this simple observation to forecast the equity-premium time series with the cross-sectional price of risk. We also introduce novel statistical methods for testing stock-return predictability based on endogenous variables whose shocks are potentially correlated with return shocks. Our empirical tests show that the cross-sectional price of risk (1) is strongly correlated with the market's yield measures and (2) predicts equity-premium realizations, especially in the first half of our 1927-2002 sample. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Polk, Christopher; Thompson, Samuel; Vuolteenaho, Tuomo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Was there a Nasdaq bubble in the late 1990s?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, Lubos; Veronesi, Pietro
Not necessarily: a firm's fundamental value increases with uncertainty about average future profitability, and this uncertainty was unusually high in the late 1990s. After calibrating a stock valuation model that takes this uncertainty into account, we compute the level of uncertainty that is needed to match the observed Nasdaq valuations at their peak. The uncertainty we obtain seems plausible because it matches not only the high level but also the high volatility of Nasdaq stock prices. In general, we argue that the level and volatility of stock prices are positively linked through firm-specific uncertainty about average future profitability. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pastor, Lubos; Veronesi, Pietro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient tests of stock return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John Y.; Yogo, Motohiro
Conventional tests of the predictability of stock returns could be invalid, that is reject the null too frequently, when the predictor variable is persistent and its innovations are highly correlated with returns. We develop a pretest to determine whether the conventional t-test leads to invalid inference and an efficient test of predictability that corrects this problem. Although the conventional t-test is invalid for the dividend-price and smoothed earnings-price ratios, our test finds evidence for predictability. We also find evidence for predictability with the short rate and the long-short yield spread, for which the conventional t-test leads to valid inference. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campbell, John Y.; Yogo, Motohiro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do a firm's equity returns reflect the risk of its pension plan?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Li; Merton, Robert C.; Bodie, Zvi
This paper examines the empirical question of whether systematic equity risk of US firms as measured by beta from the capital asset pricing model reflects the risk of their pension plans. There are a number of reasons to suspect that it might not. Chief among them is the opaque set of accounting rules used to report pension assets, liabilities, and expenses. Pension plan assets and liabilities are off-balance sheet and are often viewed as segregated from the rest of the firm, with its own trustees. Pension accounting rules are complicated. Furthermore, the role of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation clouds the real relation between pension plan risk and firm equity risk. The empirical findings in this paper are consistent with the hypothesis that equity risk does reflect the risk of the firm's pension plan despite arcane accounting rules for pensions. This finding is consistent with informational efficiency of the capital markets. It also has implications for corporate finance practice in the determination of the cost of capital for capital budgeting. Standard procedure uses de-leveraged equity return betas to infer the cost of capital for operating assets. But the de-leveraged betas are not adjusted for the risk of the pension assets and liabilities. Failure to make this adjustment typically biases upward estimates of the discount rate for capital budgeting. The magnitude of the bias is shown here to be large for a number of well-known US companies. This bias can result in positive net present value projects being rejected. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jin, Li; Merton, Robert C.; Bodie, Zvi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimation of continuous-time models with an application to equity volatility dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Ju, Nengjiu; Ou-Yang, Hui
The treatment of this article renders closed-form density approximation feasible for univariate continuous-time models. Implementation methodology depends directly on the parametric-form of the drift and the diffusion of the primitive process and not on its transformation to a unit-variance process. Offering methodological convenience, the approximation method relies on numerically evaluating one-dimensional integrals and circumvents existing dependence on intractable multidimensional integrals. Density-based inferences can now be drawn for a broader set of models of equity volatility. Our empirical results provide insights on crucial outstanding issues related to the rank-ordering of continuous-time stochastic volatility models, the absence or presence of nonlinearities in the drift function, and the desirability of pursuing more flexible diffusion function specifications. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Ju, Nengjiu; Ou-Yang, Hui</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric benchmarking in compensation: Executives are rewarded for good luck but not penalized for bad</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garvey, Gerald T.; Milbourn, Todd T.
Principal-agent theory suggests that a manager should be paid relative to a benchmark that removes the effect of market or sector performance on the firm's own performance. Recently, it has been argued that such indexation is not observed in the data because executives can set pay in their own interests; that is, they can enjoy "pay for luck" as well as "pay for performance." We first show that this argument is incomplete. The positive expected return on stock markets reflects compensation for bearing systematic risk. If executives' pay is tied to market movements, they can only expect to receive the market-determined return for risk-bearing. This argument, however, assumes that executive pay is tied to bad luck as well as to good luck. If executives can truly influence the setting of their pay, they will seek to have their performance benchmarked only when it is in their interest, namely, when the benchmark has fallen. Using industry benchmarks, we find significantly less pay for luck when luck is down (in which case, pay for luck would reduce compensation) than when it is up. These empirical results are robust to a variety of alternative hypotheses and robustness checks, and they suggest that the average executive loses 25-45% less pay from bad luck than is gained from good luck. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garvey, Gerald T.; Milbourn, Todd T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does good corporate governance include employee representation? Evidence from German corporate boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fauver, Larry; Fuerst, Michael E.
Within the German corporate governance system, employee representation on the supervisory board is typically legally mandated. We propose that such representation of labor on corporate boards confers valuable first-hand operational knowledge to corporate board decision-making. Indeed, we find that labor representation provides a powerful means of monitoring and reduces agency costs within the firm. Moreover, we show that the greater the need for coordination within the firm, the greater the potential improvement there is in governance effectiveness through the judicious use of labor representation. These benefits do not appear to hold for union representatives. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fauver, Larry; Fuerst, Michael E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A liquidity-augmented capital asset pricing model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Weimin
Using a new measure of liquidity, this paper documents a significant liquidity premium robust to the CAPM and the Fama-French three-factor model and shows that liquidity is an important source of priced risk. A two-factor (market and liquidity) model well explains the cross-section of stock returns, describing the liquidity premium, subsuming documented anomalies associated with size, long-term contrarian investment, and fundamental (cashflow, earnings, and dividend) to price ratios. In particular, the two-factor model accounts for the book-to-market effect, which the Fama-French three-factor model fails to explain. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Weimin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entry regulation as a barrier to entrepreneurship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klapper, Leora; Laeven, Luc; Rajan, Raghuram
Using a comprehensive database of European firms, we study the effect of market entry regulations on the creation of new limited-liability firms, the average size of entrants, and the growth of incumbent firms. We find that costly regulations hamper the creation of new firms, especially in industries that should naturally have high entry. These regulations also force new entrants to be larger and cause incumbent firms in naturally high-entry industries to grow more slowly. Our results hold even when we correct for the availability of financing, the degree of protection of intellectual property, and labor regulations. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Klapper, Leora; Laeven, Luc; Rajan, Raghuram</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing decisions when managers are risk averse</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewellen, Katharina
Leverage raises stock volatility, driving a wedge between the cost of debt to shareholders and the cost to undiversified, risk-averse managers. I quantify these "volatility costs" of debt and examine their impact on financing decisions. I find that: (1) the volatility costs of debt can be large for executives exposed to firm-specific risk; (2) for a range of empirically relevant parameters, higher option ownership tends to increase, not decrease, the volatility costs of debt; and (3) for managers with stock options, a stock price increase typically raises volatility costs. For a large sample of US firms, I find evidence that volatility costs affect both the level of and short-term changes in debt, and that volatility costs help explain a firm's choice between debt and equity. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lewellen, Katharina</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure, credit risk, and macroeconomic conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hackbarth, Dirk; Miao, Jianjun; Morellec, Erwan
This paper develops a framework for analyzing the impact of macroeconomic conditions on credit risk and dynamic capital structure choice. We begin by observing that when cash flows depend on current economic conditions, there will be a benefit for firms to adapt their default and financing policies to the position of the economy in the business cycle phase. We then demonstrate that this simple observation has a wide range of empirical implications for corporations. Notably, we show that our model can replicate observed debt levels and the countercyclicality of leverage ratios. We also demonstrate that it can reproduce the observed term structure of credit spreads and generate strictly positive credit spreads for debt contracts with very short maturities. Finally, we characterize the impact of macroeconomic conditions on the pace and size of capital structure changes, and debt capacity. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hackbarth, Dirk; Miao, Jianjun; Morellec, Erwan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Profitability, investment and average returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
Valuation theory says that expected stock returns are related to three variables: the book-to-market equity ratio (B-t/M-t), expected profitability, and expected investment. Given B-t/M-t and expected profitability, higher expected rates of investment imply lower expected returns. But controlling for the other two variables, more profitable firms have higher expected returns, as do firms with higher B-t/M-t. These predictions are confirmed in our tests. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. William
nan</description><author>Schwert, G. William</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ripples through markets: Inter-market impacts generated by large trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellul, Andrew
This paper uses a sample of large trades executed on the London Stock Exchange's SEAQ-I market for European cross-traded firms to investigate their impact on home market prices when parallel markets suffer from information frictions. I find that (a) large London trades produce price impacts in home markets even though no timely information is published, (b) market makers appear to pre- and post-position their inventories by splitting orders across markets, and (c) the price discovery process across markets changes significantly around large trades with the foreign market making a significantly bigger contribution to price discovery at this time, even though information opaqueness exists. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ellul, Andrew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt financing: Does it boost or hurt firm performance in product markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo
Previous research seeks to establish whether debt boosts or hurts a firm's product market performance. This paper proposes that both of these outcomes can be observed: debt can boost and hurt performance. I first model a nonmonotonic relation between debt-like finance and competitive conduct. I then empirically examine the within-industry relation between leverage and sales performance using data from 115 industries over 30 years. My tests deal with the endogencity of debt in a novel fashion: I use creditors' valuation of assets in liquidation to identify financial leverage. I find that moderate debt taking is associated with relative-to-rival sales gains; high indebtedness, however, leads to product market underperformance. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campello, Murillo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock price reaction to public and private information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vega, Clara
I use Easley and O'Hara's [1992, Journal of Finance 47, 577-604] private information-based trading variable, PIN, together with a comprehensive public news database to empirically measure the effect of private and public information on the post-announcement drift. I show that stocks associated with high PIN, consensus public news surprises, and low media coverage experience low or insignificant drift. Thus not all information acquisition variables have the same effect on the market's efficiency. Whether information is public or private is irrelevant; what matters is whether information is associated with the arrival rate of informed or uninformed traders. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vega, Clara</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>World markets for raising new capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henderson, Brian J.; Jegadeesh, Narasinihan; Weisbach, Michael S.
We examine the extent to which firms from different countries rely on alternative sources of capital, the locations in which they raise capital, and the factors that affect these choices. During the 1990-2001 period, firms raised about $25.3 trillion of new capital, including $4.9 trillion from abroad. International debt issuances are substantially more common than equity issuances, with debt (equity) issues accounting for 87% (9%) of all securities issued internationally, and about 20% (12%) of all public debt issuances. Market timing considerations appear to be important in security issuance decisions in most countries. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Henderson, Brian J.; Jegadeesh, Narasinihan; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the marketing of IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cook, Douglas O.; Kieschnick, Robert; Van Ness, Robert A.
Derrien [2005. Journal of Finance 60, 487-521] and Ljungqvist et al. [2006. Journal of Business] build upon the work of Miller [1977. Journal of Finance 32, 1151-1168] and claim that issuers and the regular customers of investment bankers benefit from the presence of sentiment investors (noise traders) in the market for an initial public offering (IPO). Thus we argue that investment bankers have an incentive to promote an IPO to induce sentiment investors into the market for it. Consistent with this motivation and these models, we expect that the promotional efforts of investment bankers should influence the compensation of investment bankers, the valuation of an IPO, its initial returns and trading, the wealth gains of insider shareholders, and the likelihood that an issuer switches investment bankers for a subsequent seasoned equity offering. Examining data for a sample of IPOs from 1993 through 2000, we find evidence consistent with these predictions and so with the proposition that an investment banker's ability to market an IPO to sentiment investors is important. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cook, Douglas O.; Kieschnick, Robert; Van Ness, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strength of analyst coverage following IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>James, Christopher; Karceski, Jason
Firms with poor aftermarket performance are given higher target prices and are more likely to receive strong buy recommendations, especially by analysts affiliated with the lead underwriter. This favorable coverage is relatively short lived, typically lasting less than six months. Controlling for the quantity of coverage received, stock prices of newly public firms increase more when the target price ratio is high and recommendation is a strong buy. These results suggest that when a firm goes public, underwriter-affiliated analysts provide protection in the form of "booster shots" of stronger coverage if the firm experiences poor aftermarket stock performance. (c) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>James, Christopher; Karceski, Jason</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The conditional CAPM does not explain asset-pricing anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewellen, Jonathan; Nagel, Stefan
Recent studies suggest that the conditional CAPM holds, period by period, and that time-variation in risk and expected returns can explain why the unconditional CAPM fails. In contrast, we argue that variation in betas and the equity premium would have to be implausibly large to explain important asset-pricing anomalies like momentum and the value premium. We also provide a simple new test of the conditional CAPM using direct estimates of conditional alphas and betas from short-window regressions, avoiding the need to specify conditioning information. The tests show that the conditional CAPM performs nearly as poorly as the unconditional CAPM, consistent with our analytical results. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lewellen, Jonathan; Nagel, Stefan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market transparency, liquidity externalities, and institutional trading costs in corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Maxwell, William; Venkataraman, Kumar
We develop a simple model of the effect of public transaction reporting on trade execution costs and test it using a sample of institutional trades in corporate bonds, before and after initiation of the TRACE reporting system. Trade execution costs fell approximately 50% for bonds eligible for TRACE transaction reporting, and 20% for bonds not eligible for TRACE reporting, suggesting the presence of a "liquidity externality." The key results are robust to changes in variables, such as interest rate volatility and trading activity that might also affect execution costs. Market shares and the cost advantage to large dealers decreased post-TRACE. These results indicate that market design can have first-order effects, even for sophisticated institutional customers. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Maxwell, William; Venkataraman, Kumar</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The other January effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Michael J.; McConnell, John J.; Ovtchinnikov, Alexel V.
Strectlore since at least 1973 has touted the market return in January as a predictor of market returns for the remainder of the year. We systematically examine the predictive power of January returns over the period 1940-2003 and find that January returns have predictive power for market returns over the next I I months of the year. The effect persists after controlling for macroeconomic/ business cycle variables that have been shown to predict stock returns, the Presidential Cycle in returns, and investor sentiment, and it persists among both large and small capitalization stocks and among both value and growth stocks. In addition, we find that January has predictive power for two of the three premiums in the Fama-French [1993. Journal of Financial Economics 33, 3-50] three-factor model of asset pricing. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cooper, Michael J.; McConnell, John J.; Ovtchinnikov, Alexel V.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tunneling, propping, and expropriation: evidence from connected party transactions in Hong Kong</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheung, Yan-Leung; Rau, P. Raghavendra; Stouraitis, Aris
We examine a sample of connected transactions between Hong Kong listed companies and their controlling shareholders. We address three questions: What types of connected transactions lead to expropriation of minority shareholders? Which firms are more likely to expropriate? Does the market anticipate the expropriation by firms? On average, firms announcing connected transactions earn significant negative excess returns, significantly lower than firms announcing similar arm's length transactions. We find limited evidence that firms undertaking connected transactions trade at discounted valuations prior to the expropriation, suggesting that investors cannot predict expropriation and revalue firms only when expropriation does occur. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cheung, Yan-Leung; Rau, P. Raghavendra; Stouraitis, Aris</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun
This paper studies whether incorporating business cycle predictors benefits a real time optimizing investor who must allocate funds across 3,123 NYSE-AMEX stocks and cash. Realized returns are positive when adjusted by the Fama-French and momentum factors as well as by the size, book-to-market, and past return characteristics. The investor optimally holds small-cap, growth, and momentum stocks and loads less (more) heavily on momentum (small-cap) stocks during recessions. Returns on individual stocks are predictable out-of-sample due to alpha variation, whereas the equity premium predictability, the major focus of previous work, is questionable. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing with unforeseen contingencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kraus, Alan; Sagi, Jacob S.
We investigate an economy of heterogeneous agents that cannot specify all exogenous welfare-relevant events and consequently view the impact of unforeseen contingencies as utility shocks. In this setting we characterize an appropriate market equilibrium concept when securities can trade only on demand- and price-contingent events. We establish the existence of an equilibrium for a class of parametric models in which aggregating taste shocks across agents can lead to nonconsumption pricing factors. To fit the stylized facts, (i) non consumption factors must dominate the pricing kernel and contribute to the variation of the wealth-consumption ratio, (ii) markets must be incomplete and the set of claims that are traded endogenously determined, (iii) agents' preferences with respect to unforeseen contingencies must be non-expected utility, and, (iv) although non-consumption pricing factors can be conditionally uncorrelated with aggregate consumption shocks, they must be correlated with shocks to expected consumption growth. (c) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kraus, Alan; Sagi, Jacob S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and cooperation among exchanges: A theory of cross-listing and endogenous listing standards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Fulghieri, Paolo
We analyze firms' choice of exchange to list equity and exchanges' choice of listing standards when insiders have private information about firm value, but outsiders can produce (noisy) information at a cost. Exchanges are populated by two kinds of investors, whose numbers vary across exchanges: sophisticated (low information production cost) investors and ordinary (high-cost) investors. While firms are short-lived, exchanges are long-lived, value-maximizing agents whose listing and disclosure standards evolve over time. The listing standards chosen by exchanges affect their "reputation," since outsiders can partially infer the rigor of these standards from the post-listing performance of firms. We show that, while exchanges use their listing standards as a tool in competing for listings with other exchanges, this will not necessarily lead to a "race to the bottom" in listing standards. Further, a merger between two exchanges may result in a higher listing standard for the combined exchange relative to that of either of the merging exchanges. We develop several other implications for firms' listing choices and resulting valuation effects, the impact of competition and co-operation among exchanges on listing standards, and the optimal regulation of exchanges. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Fulghieri, Paolo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The costs of entrenched boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bebchuk, L. A.; Cohen, A.
This paper investigates empirically how the value of publicly traded firms is affected by arrangements that protect management from removal. Staggered boards, which a majority of U.S. public companies have, substantially insulate boards from removal in either a hostile takeover or it proxy contest. We find that staggered boards are associated with ail economically meaningfull reduction in firm value (as measured by Tobin's Q). We also provide suggestive evidence that staggered boards bring about, and not merely reflect, a reduced firm value. Finally, we show that the correlation With reduced firm value is stronger for staggered boards that are established in the corporate charter (which shareholders cannot amend) than for staggered boards established in the company's bylaws (which shareholders can amend). (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bebchuk, L. A.; Cohen, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the suboptimality of single-factor exercise strategies for Bermudan swaptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Svenstrup, M.
This paper resolves the disagreement between Longstaff et al. [2001. Journal of Finance Economics 62, 39-66] and Andersen and Andreasen [2001. Journal of Financial Economics 62, 3-37] over the effectiveness of the common business practice of using best-fit single-factor term structure models to deduce exercise strategies of Bermudan swaptions. I examine the cost of using recalibrated single-factor models to determine the exercise strategy for Bermudan swaptions in a multifactor world. I show that single-factor exercise strategies applied in a multifactor world only give rise to economically insignificant losses. Furthermore. I find that the conditional model risk as defined in Longstaff et al. [2001. Journal of Finance Economics 62, 39-66] is statistically insignificant given the number of observations. Additional tests using the Primal-Dual algorithm of Andersen and Broadie [2004. Management Science 50(9)] indicate that losses found in Longstaff et al. [2001. Journal of Finance Economics 62, 39-66] cannot, as claimed, be ascribed to the number of factors. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Svenstrup, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical examination of the costs and benefits of executive stock options: Evidence from Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kato, H. K.; Lemmon, M.; Luo, M.; Schallheim, J.
In May 1997, the Japanese Commercial Code was amended to allow firms to begin granting stock options as compensation to top management and employees. Nearly 350 firms adopted option-based compensation plans between 1997 and 2001. These options typically have five year lives and are out-of-the-money by about 5% at the grant date. Firms exhibit abnormal stock returns of about 2%, around the announcements of plan adoptions. We find improvements in operating performance and observe that dividend policy and volatility remain unchanged post-adoption. Our evidence suggests that well-designed incentive compensation plans are consistent with the creation of shareholder Value. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kato, H. K.; Lemmon, M.; Luo, M.; Schallheim, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>