<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFE8</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>The choice between rights offerings and private equity placements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cronqvist, H.; Nilsson, M.
We develop and test a nested logit model to examine how firms choose between a rights offering and a private equity placement. Family controlled firms avoid issue methods that dilute control benefits or subject them to more monitoring, especially when the family's control margin is small and the wedge between votes and capital is large. Control considerations also affect security design. Private placements reduce contracting and ex post holdup Costs ill new product market relationships. Finally, firms with higher asymmetric information about firm value tend to involve underwriter certification in a rights offering, and to choose I private placement when information asymmetries are extreme. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cronqvist, H.; Nilsson, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity: Urban versus rural firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loughran, T.; Schultz, P.
Our paper examines the impact of geographic location on liquidity for U.S. rural- and Urban-based companies. Even after adjusting for size and other Factors, rural firms trade much less, are covered by fewer analysts, and are owned by fewer institutions than urban firms. Trading costs are higher for rural Nasdaq firms, and volume that can be attributed to marketwide factors is lower for rural stocks. The findings add to our understanding of the way that access to information and familiarity affect liquidity. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loughran, T.; Schultz, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prospect theory, mental accounting, and momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, M.; Han, B.
The tendency of some investors to hold on to their losing stocks, driven by prospect theory and mental accounting, creates a spread between a stock's fundamental value and its equilibrium price, as well as price underreaction to information. Spread convergence, arising from the random evolution of fundamental Values and the updating of reference prices, generates predictable equilibrium prices interpretable as possessing momentum. Empirically, a variable proxying for aggregate unrealized capital gains appears to be the key variable that generates the profitability of a momentum strategy. Controlling for this variable, past returns have no predictability for the cross-section of returns. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grinblatt, M.; Han, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short sales, institutional investors and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagel, S.
Short-sale constraints are most likely to bind among stocks with low institutional ownership. Because of institutional constraints, most professional investors simply never sell short and hence cannot trade against overpricing of stocks they do not own. Furthermore, stock loan supply tends to be sparse and short selling more expensive when institutional ownership is low. Using institutional ownership as a proxy, I find that short-sale constraints help explain cross-sectional stock return anomalies. Specifically, holding size fixed, the under-performance of stocks with high market-to-book, analyst forecast dispersion, turnover, or volatility is most Pronounced among stocks with low institutional ownership. Ownership by passive investors with large stock lending programs partly mitigates this under-performance, indicating some impact of stock loan supply. Prices of stocks with low institutional ownership also underreact to bad cash-flow news and overreact to good cash-flow news, consistent with the idea that short-sale constraints hold negative opinions off the market for these stocks. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nagel, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short interest, institutional ownership, and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asquith, P.; Pathak, P. A.; Ritter, J. R.
Stocks are short-sale constrained when there is a strong demand to sell short and a limited Supply of shares to borrow. Using data on both short interest (a proxy for demand) and institutional ownership (a proxy for supply) we find that constrained stocks underperform during the period 1988 - 2002 by a significant 215 basis points per month on an equally weighted basis, although by only in insignificant 39 basis points per month on a value-weighted basis. For the overwhelming majority of stocks, short interest and institutional ownership levels make short selling constraints unlikely. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asquith, P.; Pathak, P. A.; Ritter, J. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What happened to liquidity when world war I shut the NYSE?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Silber, W. L.
This paper examines how financial markets responded to the longest circuit breaker in American financial history: the four-month suspension of trading on the New York Stock Exchange following the outbreak of World War I. The suspension that began on July 31, 1914 fostered a substitute trading forum called the New Street market. Trading on New Street began almost immediately and offered economically meaningful liquidity services despite its impaired price transparency. A simple cross-sectional model of bid-ask spreads on New Street demonstrates that New Street liquidity responded to economic incentives. New Street's success implies that, from a public policy perspective, expensive back-up trading facilities are not required to preserve liquidity during a trading suspension in established markets. Back-up records of share ownership and transfer facilities, however, are crucial to maintaining liquidity. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Silber, W. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global trends in IPO methods: Book building versus auctions with endogenous entry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sherman, A. E.
The U.S. book-building method has become increasingly popular for initial public offerings (IPOs) worldwide over the last decade, whereas sealed-bid IPO auctions have been abandoned in nearly all of the many countries in which they have been tried. I model book building, discriminatory auctions, and uniform price auctions in an environment in which the number of investors and the accuracy of investors' information are endogenous. Book building lets underwriters manage investor access to shares, allowing them to reduce risk for both issuers and investors and to control spending on information acquisition, thereby limiting either underpricing or aftermarket volatility. Because more control and less risk are beneficial to all issuers, the advantages of book building's allocational flexibility could explain why global patterns of issuer choice are surprisingly consistent. My models also predict that offerings with higher expected underpricing have lower expected aftermarket volatility; that an auction open to large numbers of potential bidders is vulnerable to inaccurate pricing and to fluctuations in the number of bidders; and that both book-built and auctioned IPOs will exhibit partial adjustment to both private and public information. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sherman, A. E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-varying market integration and expected returns in emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Jong, F.; de Roon, F. A.
In the last two decades, emerging stock markets have become less segmented from world stock markets. The average annual decrease in se.-mentation of 0.055, on a [0,. 1] scale, reduces the cost of capital (measured by dividend yields) by about I I basis points, and reduces stock returns by about 4.5%. The decline in expected returns is due to a decrease in two types of segmentation. A fall in local segmentation accounts for about 2/3 of the decline in expected returns. The remaining 1/3 is due to a fall in the level of segmentation of the region. These results, which we document for 30 emerging markets, are robust to the addition of control variables. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Jong, F.; de Roon, F. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dimensions of execution quality: Recent evidence for US equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, E.
I analyze market-order execution quality using order-based data reported in accordance with Securities and Exchange Commission Rule 11Acl-5. These data facilitate a comprehensive investigation of multiple dimensions of execution quality, including measures of costs and speed, for large samples of common stocks on Nasdaq and the NYSE. The evidence is consistent with competitive equity markets. Overall execution costs on Nasdaq exceed those on the NYSE, but orders execute faster. This relationship reverses for larger orders exceeding 1,999 shares. The apparent trade-off between costs and speed suggests that inferring execution quality from costs alone could be problematical. It also illustrates the need for models of trader behavior that can accommodate multiple dimensions of execution quality. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boehmer, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund performance with learning across funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, C. S.; Shanken, J.
The average level and cross-sectional variability of fund alphas are estimated from a large sample of mutual funds. This information is incorporated, along with the usual regression estimate of alpha, in a (roughly) precision-weighted average measure of individual fund performance. Substantial "learning across funds" is documented, with significant effects on investment decisions. In a Bayesian framework, this form of learning is inconsistent with the assumption, made in the past literature, of prior independence across funds. Independence can be viewed as an extreme scenario in which the true cross-sectional distribution of alphas is presumed to be known a priori. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jones, C. S.; Shanken, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Profitable predictability in the cross section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanna, I. D.; Ready, M. I.
Haugen and Baker (1996) report that a long-short stock selection strategy based on more than 50 measures of accounting information and past return behavior would have generated excess returns of approximately 3% per month. We find that the Haugen and Baker strategies do not provide attractive returns after transaction costs if an investor already has access to strategy portfolios based on book-to-market and momentum. We also provide an extensive analysis of transaction costs over a long sample and we report results of independent interest to researchers in market microstructure. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanna, I. D.; Ready, M. I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does it pay to be loyal? An empirical analysis of underwriting relationships and fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burch, T. R.; Nanda, V.; Warther, V.
We examine underwriting fees for repeat issuers of new securities to determine the relation between loyalty to an underwriting bank and the fees charged. For a sample of offers over the 1975-2001 period, we find that loyalty is associated with lower fees for common stock offers, consistent with valuable relationship capital being built through loyalty. For debt offers, however, we find the opposite pattern, consistent with relationship capital not being as valuable. For both offer types, firms that graduate to higher-quality banks face lower fees. Firms that are more likely to be switching banks to improve analyst coverage face higher fees for common stock offers, but not for debt offers. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Burch, T. R.; Nanda, V.; Warther, V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morellec, E.; Zhdanov, A.
This paper presents a dynamic model of takeovers based on the stock market valuations of merging firms. The model incorporates competition and imperfect information and determines the terms and timing of takeovers by solving option exercise games between bidding and target shareholders. The implications of the model for returns to stockholders are consistent with the available evidence. In addition, the model generates new predictions relating these returns to the drift, volatility and correlation coefficient of the bidder and the target stock returns and to the dispersion of beliefs regarding the benefits of the takeover. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morellec, E.; Zhdanov, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants and implications of arbitrage holdings in acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsieh, J.; Walkling, R. A.
We find evidence of passive and active roles for arbitrageurs in the acquisition process. Using a simultaneous-equation framework to recognize endogeneity, we analyze 608 acquisition bids over the 1992-1999 period. Our results indicate that the change in arbitrage holdings is greater in successful offers. However, changes in arbitrage holdings are also related to the probability of success, bid premia, and arbitrage returns. In addition, the change in arbitrage holdings is positively associated with both revision returns and the occurrence of subsequent bids. Overall, we find that merger arbitrageurs play an important role in the market for corporate control. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hsieh, J.; Walkling, R. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation waves and merger activity: The empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rhodes-Kropf, M.; Robinson, D. T.; Viswanathan, S.
To test recent theories suggesting that valuation errors affect merger activity, we develop a decomposition that breaks the market-to-book ratio (M/B) into three components: the firm-specific pricing deviation from short-run industry pricing; sector-wide, short-run deviations from firms' long-run pricing; and long-run pricing to book. We find strong support for recent theories by Rhodes-Kropf and Viswanathan [2004. Market valuation and merger waves. Journal of Finance, forthcoming] and Shleifer and Vishny [2003. Stock market driven acquisitions. Journal of Financial Economics 70, 295-311], which predict that misvaluation drives mergers. So much of the behavior of M/B is driven by firm-specific deviations from short-run industry pricing, that long-run components of M/B run counter to the conventional wisdom: Low long-run value to book firms buy high long-run value-to-book firms. Misvaluation affects who buys whom, as well as method of payment, and combines with neoclassical explanations to explain aggregate merger activity. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rhodes-Kropf, M.; Robinson, D. T.; Viswanathan, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives merger waves?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, J.
Aggregate merger waves could be due to market timing or to clustering of industry shocks for which mergers facilitate change to the new environment. This study finds that economic, regulatory and technological shocks drive industry merger waves. Whether the shock leads to a wave of mergers, however, depends on whether there is sufficient overall capital liquidity. This macro-level liquidity component causes industry merger waves to cluster in time even if industry shocks do not. Market-timing variables have little explanatory power relative to an economic model including this liquidity component. The contemporaneous peak in divisional acquisitions for cash also suggests an economic motivation for the merger activity. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harford, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payout policy in the 21st century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, A.; Graham, J. R.; Harvey, C. R.; Michaely, R.
We survey 384 financial executives and conduct in-depth interviews with an additional 23 to determine the factors that drive dividend and share repurchase decisions. Our findings indicate that maintaining the dividend level is on par with investment decisions, while repurchases are made out of the residual cash flow after investment spending. Perceived stability of future earnings still affects dividend policy as in Lintner (1956. American Economic Review 46, 97-113). However, 50 years later, we find that the link between dividends and earnings has weakened. Many managers now favor repurchases because they are viewed as being more flexible than dividends and can be used in an attempt to time the equity market or to increase earnings per share. Executives believe that institutions are indifferent between dividends and repurchases and that payout policies have little impact on their investor clientele. In general, management views provide little support for agency, signaling, and clientele hypotheses of payout policy. Tax considerations play a secondary role. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brav, A.; Graham, J. R.; Harvey, C. R.; Michaely, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic risk management: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fehle, F.; Tsyplakov, S.
We present and test an infinite-horizon, continuous-time model of a firm that can dynamically adjust the use of risk management instruments which seek to reduce product price uncertainty and thereby mitigate financial distress losses and reduce taxes. The dynamic setting relaxes several restrictive assumptions common to static models. In the model, the firm can adjust its use and the hedge ratio and maturity of risk management instruments over time, risk management instruments expire as time progresses, the available maturity of the risk management instruments is shorter than the lifetime of the firm, and transaction costs are associated with initiation and adjustment of risk management contracts. The model produces a number of new time-series and cross-sectional implications on how firms use short-term instruments to hedge long-term cash flow uncertainty. Numerical results describe the optimal timing, adjustment, and rollover of risk management instruments and the choice of contract maturity and hedge ratio in response to changes in the firm's product price. The results show that the structure of transaction costs can have an important effect oil the firm's risk management strategy. The model predicts that firms that are either far front financial distress or deep in financial distress neither initiate nor adjust their risk management instruments, while firms between the two extremes initiate and actively adjust their risk management instruments. Using quarterly panel data on gold mining firms between 1993 and 1999, we find evidence of a non-monotonic relation between measures of financial distress and risk management activity consistent with the model. We also provide evidence supportive of the model's predictions with respect to the maturity choice of risk management contracts. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fehle, F.; Tsyplakov, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock price clustering on option expiration dates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ni, S. X. Y.; Pearson, N. D.; Poteshman, A. M.
This paper presents striking evidence that option trading changes the prices of underlying stocks. In particular, we show that on expiration dates the closing prices of stocks with listed options cluster at option strike prices. On each expiration date, the returns of optionable stocks are altered by an average of at least 16.5 basis points, which translates into aggregate market capitalization shifts on the order of $9 billion. We provide evidence that hedge rebalancing by option market makers and stock price manipulation by firm proprietary traders contribute to the clustering. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ni, S. X. Y.; Pearson, N. D.; Poteshman, A. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unchecked intermediaries: Price manipulation in an emerging stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khwaja, A. I.; Mian, A.
How costly is the poor governance of market intermediaries? Using unique trade level data from the stock market in Pakistan, we find that when brokers trade on their own behalf, they earn annual rates of return that are 50-90 percentage points higher than those earned by outside investors. Neither market timing nor liquidity provision by brokers can explain this profitability differential. Instead we find compelling evidence for a specific trade-based "pump and dump" price manipulation scheme: When prices are low, colluding brokers trade amongst themselves to artificially raise prices and attract positive-feedback traders. Once prices have risen, the former exit leaving the latter to suffer the ensuing price fall. Conservative estimates suggest these manipulation rents can account for almost a half of total broker earnings. These large rents may explain why market reforms are hard to implement and emerging equity markets often remain marginal with few outsiders investing and little capital raised. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khwaja, A. I.; Mian, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is value riskier than growth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Petkova, R.; Zhang, L.
We study the relative risk of value and growth stocks. We find that time-varying risk goes in the right direction in explaining the value premium. Value betas tend to covary positively, and growth betas tend to covary negatively with the expected market risk premium. Our inference differs from that of previous studies because we sort betas on the expected market risk premium, instead of on the realized market excess return. However, we also find that this beta-premium covariance is too small to explain the observed magnitude of the value premium within the conditional capital asset pricing model. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Petkova, R.; Zhang, L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining the size of the mutual fund industry around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khorana, A.; Servaes, H.; Tufano, P.
This paper studies the mutual fund industry in 56 countries and examines where this financial innovation has flourished. The fund industry is larger in countries with stronger rules, laws, and regulations, and specifically where mutual fund investors' rights are better protected. The industry is also larger in countries with wealthier and more educated populations, where the industry is older, trading costs are lower and in which defined contribution pension plans are more prevalent. The industry is smaller in countries where barriers to entry are higher. These results indicate that laws and regulations, supply-side and demand-side factors simultaneously affect the size of the fund industry. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khorana, A.; Servaes, H.; Tufano, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crossborder dividend taxation and the preferences of taxable and nontaxable investors: Evidence from Canada</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, S. E. K.; Geczy, C. C.; Musto, D. K.; Reed, A. V.
We consider how fund managers respond to the conflicting preferences of their investors. We focus on the conflict between the taxable and retirement accounts of international funds, which face different tradeoffs between dividends and capital gains. In principle, managers could resolve this conflict through dividend arbitrage, but a proprietary database of dividend-arbitrage transactions shows that in practice they cannot. Thus, managers must resolve it through their investment policies. We find robust evidence that managers with more retirement money favor the preferences of retirement investors and further evidence for this view in the difference between U.S. and Canadian funds' portfolio weights. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christoffersen, S. E. K.; Geczy, C. C.; Musto, D. K.; Reed, A. V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>You can't always get what you want: Trade-size clustering and quantity choice in liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moulton, P. C.
This paper examines whether investors care more about trading their exact quantity demands at some times than at others. Using a new data set of foreign exchange transactions, I find that customers trade more precise quantities at quarter-end, as evidenced by less trade-size clustering. Customers trade more odd lots and fewer round lots, while the number of trades and total volume are not significantly changed. I also find that the price impact of order flow is greater when customers care more about trading precise quantities. This work sheds new light on trade-size clustering and offers a potential explanation for time-series and cross-sectional variation in common liquidity measures. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moulton, P. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment timing, agency, and information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grenadier, S. R.; Wang, N.
This paper provides a model of investment timing by managers in a decentralized firm in the presence of agency conflicts and information asymmetries. When investment decisions are delegated to managers, contracts must be designed to provide incentives for managers to both extend effort and truthfully reveal private information. Using a real options approach, we show that an underlying option to invest can be decomposed into two components: a manager's option and an owner's option. The implied investment behavior differs significantly from that of the first-best no-agency solution. In particular, greater inertia occurs in investment, as the model predicts that the manager will have a more valuable option to wait than the owner. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grenadier, S. R.; Wang, N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dealer behavior and trading systems in foreign exchange markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bjonnes, G. H.; Rime, D.
We study dealer behavior in the foreign exchange spot market using detailed observations on all the transactions of four interbank dealers. There is strong support for an information effect in incoming trades. The direction of trade is most important, but we also find that the information effect increases with trade size in direct bilateral trades. All four dealers control their inventory intensively. Inventory control is not, however, manifested through a dealer's own prices in contrast to findings by Lyons (J. Financial Econ. 39(1995) 321). Furthermore, we document differences in trading styles, especially how they actually control their inventories. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bjonnes, G. H.; Rime, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial intermediation as a beliefs-bridge between optimists and pessimists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coval, J. D.; Thakor, A. V.
This paper proposes a new framework for understanding financial intermediation. In contrast to previous research, we consider a setting in which intermediaries possess no inherent information processing or monitoring advantages. Instead, in an economy with overly optimistic entrepreneurs who require funding from pessimistic investors, we show that intermediaries can arise endogenously. In such a setting, only a rational intermediary will be sufficiently optimistic to find it worthwhile to invest in a technology for screening entrepreneurs' projects, and yet be pessimistic enough to use this technology. Our framework produces implications consistent with heretofore unexplained stylized facts, and conjectures which are thus far untested. (c) 2004 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Coval, J. D.; Thakor, A. V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short- and long-term demand curves for stocks: theory and evidence on the dynamics of arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, R.
I develop a framework to analyze demand curves for multiple risky securities at extended horizons in a setting with firnits-to-arbitrage. Following an unexpected change in uninformed investor demand for several assets, I predict returns of each security to be proportional to the contribution of that security's demand shock to the risk of a diversified arbitrage portfolio. I show that securities that are not affected by demand shocks but are correlated with securities undergoing changes in demand should experience returns related to their hedging role in arbitrageurs' portfolios. Finally, I predict a negative cross-sectional relation between post-event returns and the initial return associated with the change in demand. I confirm these predictions using data from a unique redefinition of the Nikkei 225 index in Japan, in which 255 stocks simultaneously undergo significant changes in index investor demand, causing more than Y2, 000 billion of trading in one week and large price changes followed by subsequent reversals for all of the reweighted stocks. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Greenwood, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock and bond market interaction: Does momentum spill over?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gebhardt, W. R.; Hvidkjaer, S.; Swaminathan, B.
This paper examines the interaction between momentum in the returns of equities and corporate bonds. We find that investment grade corporate bonds do not exhibit momentum at the three- to 12-month horizons. Instead, the evidence suggests that they exhibit reversals. However, significant evidence exists of a momentum spillover from equities to investment grade corporate bonds of the same firm. Firms earning high (low) equity returns over the previous year earn high (low) bond returns the following year. The spillover results are stronger among firms with lower-grade debt and higher equity trading volume, seem robust to various risk and liquidity controls, and hold even after controlling for past earnings surprises. In examining the source of the spillover, we find that the bond ratings of firms with positive (negative) equity momentum continue to improve (deteriorate) in the future, suggesting underreaction to the information in past equity prices about changing default risk is a likely source of the spillover effect. Overall, our results suggest that both equity and debt underreact to firm fundamentals, but past equity returns is a better proxy of firm fundamentals than past bond returns. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gebhardt, W. R.; Hvidkjaer, S.; Swaminathan, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News spillovers in the sovereign debt market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gande, A.; Parsley, D. C.
We study the effect of a sovereign credit rating change of one country on the sovereign credit spreads of other countries from 1991 to 2000. We find evidence of spillover effects; that is, a ratings change in one country has a significant effect on sovereign credit spreads of other countries. This effect is asymmetric: positive ratings events abroad have no discernable impact on sovereign spreads, whereas negative ratings events are associated with an increase in spreads. On average, a one-notch downgrade of a sovereign bond is associated with a 12 basis point increase in spreads of sovereign bonds of other countries. The magnitude of the spillover effect following a negative ratings change is amplified by recent ratings changes in other countries. We distinguish between common information and differential components of spillovers. While common information spillovers imply that sovereign spreads move in tandem, differential spillovers are expected to result in opposite effects of ratings events across countries. Despite the predominance of common information spillovers, we also find evidence of differential spillovers among countries with highly negatively correlated capital flows or trade flows vis-A-vis the United States. That is, spreads in these countries generally fall in response to a downgrade of a country with highly negatively correlated capital or trade flows. Variables proxying for cultural or institutional linkages (e.g., common language, formal trade blocs, common law legal systems), physical proximity, and rule of law traditions across countries do not seem to affect estimated spillover effects. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gande, A.; Parsley, D. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do tender offers create value? New methods and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhagat, S.; Dong, M.; Hirshleifer, D.; Noah, R.
Conventional techniques of estimating takeover value improvements measure only a fraction of the total gain and include revelation about bidder stand-alone value. To address these biases, we develop the probability scaling method, which rescales announcement date returns; and the intervention method, which uses returns at intervening events. Perceived value improvements are larger than traditional methods indicate. We cannot reject the hypothesis that bidders on average pay fair prices. Combined bidder-target stock returns are higher for hostile offers, lower for equity offers, and lower for diversifying offers. These effects reflect revelation about bidder stand-alone value, not differences in gains from combination. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhagat, S.; Dong, M.; Hirshleifer, D.; Noah, R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How much value can blockholders tunnel? Evidence from the Bulgarian mass privatization auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanasov, V.
This study examines the emergence of the Bulgarian stock market and the role of controlling blockholders. A new approach using mass privatization auction data measures the premium for control and demonstrates that, in the absence of legal constraints, majority owners extract more than 85% of firm value as private benefits of control. Institutional investors form portfolios of predominantly controlling positions or participate in majority coalitions. Ownership stakes cluster at 51%. After the privatized companies begin trading on the Bulgarian Stock Exchange, majority-owned firms trade at 40-60% discounts. Overall, the results support the Fama and Jensen (J. law Ecorg 26 (1983) 301) view that majority-owned firms cannot persist as publicly traded corporations if the expropriating activities of controlling blockholders are not legally restricted. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Atanasov, V.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Let's make a deal! How shareholder control impacts merger payoffs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moeller, T.
Mergers and acquisitions are Well-suited events for a detailed study of the valuation effects of corporate governance structures. Using a sample of 388 takeovers announced in the friendly environment of the 1990s, I empirically show that target shareholder control, proxied by low target chief executive officer share ownership, low fractions of inside directors, and the presence of large Outside blockholders, is positively correlated with takeover premiums. In contrast, studies of takeovers in the hostile environment of the 1980s have shown a negative relation between target shareholder control and takeover premiums. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moeller, T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder investment horizons and the market for corporate control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaspar, J. M.; Massa, M.; Matos, P.
This paper investigates how the investment horizon of a firm's institutional shareholders impacts the market for corporate control. We find that target firms with short-term shareholders are more likely to receive an acquisition bid but get lower premiums. This effect is robust and economically significant: Targets whose shareholders hold their stocks for less four months, one standard deviation away from the average holding period of 15 months, exhibit a lower premium by 3%. In addition, we find that bidder firm with short-term shareholders experience significantly worse abnormal returns around the merger announcement, as well as higher long-run under-performance. These findings Suggest that firms held by short-term investors have a weaker bargaining position in acquisitions. Weaker monitoring from short-term shareholders could allow managers to proceed with value-reducing acquisitions or to bargain for personal benefits (e.g., job security, empire building) at the expense of shareholder returns. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gaspar, J. M.; Massa, M.; Matos, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do some firms give stock options to all employees?: An empirical examination of alternative theories</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oyer, P.; Schaefer, S.
Many firms issue stock options to all employees. We consider three potential economic justifications for this practice: providing incentives to employees, inducing employees to sort, and employee retention. We gather data from three sources on firms' stock option grants to middle managers. First, we directly calibrate models of incentives, sorting and retention, and ask whether observed magnitudes of option grants are consistent with each potential explanation. We also conduct a cross-sectional regression analysis of firms' option-granting choices. We reject an incentives-based explanation for broad-based stock option plans, and conclude that sorting and retention explanations appear consistent with the data. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oyer, P.; Schaefer, S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry structure and horizontal takeovers: Analysis of wealth effects on rivals, suppliers, and corporate customers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shahrur, H.
We examine the wealth effects of horizontal takeovers on rivals of the merging firms, and on firms in the takeover industry's supplier and customer industries. Inconsistent with the collusion and buyer power motives, we find significant positive abnormal returns to rivals, suppliers, and corporate customers for the subsample of takeovers with positive combined wealth effect to target and bidder shareholders. Overall, our findings suggest that the average takeover in our sample is driven by efficiency considerations. However, we find evidence suggesting that horizontal takeovers increase the buyer power of the merging firms if suppliers are concentrated. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shahrur, H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integration, organizational processes, and allocation of resources</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozbas, O.
Does the level of integration of a firm affect the quality of information available to its top decision makers responsible for allocating resources? Motivated by the pervasiveness of specific knowledge in large multi-division firms, I develop a model of internal competition for corporate resources among specialist managers and show that: (i) managers of integrated firms exaggerate the payoffs of their projects to obtain resources despite potentially adverse career consequences, and (ii) the exaggeration problem worsens with increased integration and reduces the allocative efficiency of an integrated firm. Control rights based on asset ownership enable the firm to set "the rules of the game" and improve managerial behavior through organizational processes such as rigid capital budgets, job rotation, centralization and hierarchies. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ozbas, O.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The "make or take" decision in an electronic market: Evidence on the evolution of liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloomfield, R.; O'Hara, M.; Saar, G.
This paper uses experimental asset markets to investigate the evolution of liquidity in an electronic limit order market. Our market setting includes salient features of electronic limit order markets, as well as informed traders and liquidity traders. We focus on the strategies of the traders and how these are affected by trader type, characteristics of the market, and characteristics of the asset. We find that informed traders use more limit orders than do liquidity traders. Our main result is that liquidity provision shifts as trading progresses, with informed traders increasingly providing liquidity in markets. The change in the behavior of the informed traders seems to be in response to the dynamic adjustment of prices to information; they take (provide) liquidity when the value of their information is high (low). Thus, a market-making role emerges endogenously in our electronic markets and is ultimately adopted by the traders who are least subject to adverse selection when placing limit orders. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bloomfield, R.; O'Hara, M.; Saar, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of external finance on the equilibrium allocation of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, H.; Wolfenzon, D.
We develop an equilibrium model to understand how the efficiency of capital allocation depends on outside investor protection and the external financing needs of firms. We show that when capital allocation is constrained by poor investor protection, an increase in firms' external financing needs may improve allocative efficiency by fostering the reallocation of capital from low to high productivity projects. We also find novel empirical support for this prediction. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Almeida, H.; Wolfenzon, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The timing of initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benninga, S.; Helmantel, M.; Sarig, O.
We study the dynamics of IPOs by examining the tradeoff between an entrepreneur's private benefits, which are lost whenever the firm is publicly traded, and the gains from diversification. We characterize the timing dimension of the decision to go public and its impact on firm value and the evolution of firm risk over time. By endogenizing the timing of the decision to go public, we explain the clustering of IPOs and buyouts in time, the industry concentration of IPO waves, the high incidence of reprivatization of recent IPOs, and the long-run underperformance of recently issued stock relative to the shares of longer-listed companies. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benninga, S.; Helmantel, M.; Sarig, O.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross-section of expected corporate bond returns: Betas or characteristics?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gebhardt, W. R.; Hvidkjaer, S.; Swaminathan, B.
This paper finds that default betas are significantly related to the cross-section of average bond returns even after controlling for characteristics such as duration, ratings, and yield-to-maturity. Among characteristics, only yield-to-maturity is significantly related to average bond returns after controlling for default and term betas. The default and term factors are able to price the returns of beta-sorted portfolios better than they do the returns of yield-sorted portfolios. The magnitude of the ex ante Sharpe ratio generated by yield-sorted portfolios suggests non-risk-based explanations. Overall, given the elusive nature of systematic risk in empirical asset pricing, the central finding of our paper is that systematic risk matters for corporate bonds. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gebhardt, W. R.; Hvidkjaer, S.; Swaminathan, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accounting transparency and the term structure of credit spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, F.
Theory predicts that the quality of a firm's information disclosure can affect the term structure of its corporate bond yield spreads. Using cross-sectional regression and Nelson-Siegel yield curve estimation, I find that firms with higher Association for Investment Management and Research disclosure rankings tend to have lower credit spreads. Moreover, this transparency spread is especially large among short-term bonds. These findings are consistent with the theory of discretionary disclosure as well as the incomplete accounting information model of Duffie and Lando (Econometrica 69 (2001) 633). The presence of a sizable short-term transparency spread can attenuate some of the empirical problems associated with structural credit risk models. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yu, F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The risk and return of venture capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cochrane, J. H.
This paper measures the mean, standard deviation, alpha, and beta of venture capital investments, using a maximum likelihood estimate that corrects for selection bias. The bias-corrected estimation neatly accounts for log returns. It reduces the estimate of the mean log return from 108% to 15%, and of the log market model intercept from 92% to -7%. The selection bias correction also dramatically attenuates high arithmetic average returns: it reduces the mean arithmetic return from 698% to 59%, and it reduces the arithmetic alpha from 462% to 32%. I confirm the robustness of the estimates in a variety of ways. I also find that the smallest Nasdaq stocks have similar large means, volatilities, and arithmetic alphas in this time period, confirming that the remaining puzzles are not special to venture capital. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cochrane, J. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation risk premia and the expectations hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, A.; Jiltsov, A.
We study the properties of the nominal and real risk premia of the term structure of interest rates. We develop and solve the bond pricing implications of a structural monetary version of a real business cycle model, with taxes and endogenous monetary policy. We show the relation of this model with the class of essentially affine models that incorporate an endogenous state-dependent market price of risk. We characterize and estimate the inflation risk premium and find that over the last 40 years the ten-year inflation risk premium has been has averaged 70 basis points. It is time-varying, ranging from 20 to 140 basis points over the business cycle and its term structure is sharply upward sloping. The inflation risk premium explains 23% (42%) of the time variation in the five (ten)-year forward risk premium and it plays an important role in help explain deviations from the expectations hypothesis of interest rates. (C) 2004 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Buraschi, A.; Jiltsov, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing, exit, and location decisions of firms: Evidence on the role of debt and operating efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khanna, N.; Tice, S.
We compare pricing and exit decisions of discounters across the business cycle. Cities containing high debt and/or low efficiency firms display higher prices during non-recession years. During recessions, prices increase in cities with less efficient incumbents, but decrease in cities with a mix of high and low debt firms. High debt firms are more likely to exit cities with lower prices, and high debt exiting firms are more likely to be efficient. Apparently, low debt firms strategically lower prices during recessions to force exit of efficient, financially constrained rivals. Weaker competitors face another cost. New entrants locate closer. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khanna, N.; Tice, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The many facets of privately negotiated stock repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peyer, U. C.; Vermaelen, T.
We investigate the causes and consequences of 737 privately negotiated share repurchases in the years 1984 2001. In contrast to the negative announcement returns and positive repurchase premiums reported by past research, we find positive announcement returns and premiums that are not significantly different from zero. Only when we investigate the 60 greenmail events separately do we find results similar to past research. However, for this subsample, we find long-horizon excess returns that are comparable to the average 18% repurchase premium, challenging the widely accepted opinion that managers overpay in greenmail repurchases. Moreover, we find that our understanding of the event improves when we split the non-greenmail repurchases according to the price paid. Repurchases at a premium can be modeled as signals, while other repurchases are mere wealth transfers between the corporation and the selling stockholders, the extent of which is determined by the relative bargaining power of the seller and the repurchasing firm. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Peyer, U. C.; Vermaelen, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can foreign firms bond themselves effectively by renting US securities laws?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siegel, J.
The study tests the functional convergence hypothesis, which states that foreign firms can leapfrog their countries' weak legal institutions by listing equities in New York and agreeing to follow U.S. securities law. Evidence shows that the SEC and minority shareholders have not effectively enforced the law against cross-listed foreign firms. Detailed evidence from Mexico further shows that while some insiders exploited this weak legal enforcement with impunity, others that issued a cross-listing and passed through an economic downturn with a clean reputation went on to receive privileged long-term access to outside finance. As compared with legal bonding, reputational bonding better explains the success of cross-listings. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Siegel, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comovement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barberis, N.; Shleifer, A.; Wurgler, J.
Building on Vijh (Rev. Financial Stud. 7 (1994)), we use additions to the S&amp;P 500 to distinguish two views of return comovement: the traditional view, which attributes it to comovement in news about fundamental value, and an alternative view, in which frictions or sentiment delink it from fundamentals. After inclusion, a stock's beta with the S&amp;P goes up. In bivariate regressions which control for the return of non-S&amp;P stocks, the increase in S&amp;P beta is even larger. These results are generally stronger in more recent data. Our findings cannot easily be explained by the fundamentals-based view and provide new evidence in support of the alternative friction- or sentiment-based view. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barberis, N.; Shleifer, A.; Wurgler, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information content of equity analyst reports</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asquith, P.; Mikhail, M. B.; Au, A. S.
We catalog the complete contents of Institutional Investor All-American analyst reports and examine the market reaction to their release. Including the justifications supporting an analyst's opinion reduces, and in some models eliminates, the significance of earnings forecasts and recommendation revisions. Analysts both provide new information and interpret previously released information. The information in a report is most important for downgrades; target prices and the analyst's justifications are the only significant elements for reiterations. No correlation exists between valuation methodology and either analyst accuracy or the market's reaction to a report. Our adjusted R(2)s are much larger than those of studies using only summary measures. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asquith, P.; Mikhail, M. B.; Au, A. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do hedge funds have enough capital? A value-at-risk approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, A.; Liang, B.
We examine the risk characteristics and capital adequacy of hedge funds through the Value-at-Risk approach. Using extensive data on nearly 1,500 hedge funds, we find only 3.7% live and 10.9% dead funds are undercapitalized as of March 2003. Moreover, the undercapitalized funds are relatively small and constitute a tiny fraction of total fund assets in our sample. Cross-sectionally, the variability in fund capitalization is related to size, investment style, age, and management fee. Hedge fund risk and capitalization also display significant time variation. Traditional risk measures like standard deviation or leverage ratios fail to detect these trends. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gupta, A.; Liang, B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic trading behavior and price distortion in a manipulated market: anatomy of a squeeze</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Merrick, J. J.; Naik, N. Y.; Yadav, P. K.
This paper investigates an attempted delivery squeeze in a bond futures contract traded in London. Using cash and futures trades of dealers and customers, we analyze their strategic trading behavior, price distortion, and learning in a market manipulation setting. We argue that marked differences in settlement failure penalties in the cash and futures markets create conditions that favor squeezes. We recommend that regulators require special flagging of forward term repurchase agreements on the key deliverables that span futures contract maturity dates, and that exchanges mark-to-market their contract specifications more frequently, or consider a cash-settled contract on a basket of bonds. (c) 2004 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Merrick, J. J.; Naik, N. Y.; Yadav, P. K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market manipulation: A comprehensive study of stock pools</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, G. L.; Mahoney, P. G.; Mei, J. P.
Using a new hand collected data set, this paper examines in detail a classic account of stock market manipulation, the "stock pools" of the 1920s, which prompted the current antimanipulation rules in the United States. We examine abnormal turnover and returns and the relation between them, as well as the long-term performance of the selected stocks. We conclude that the evidence suggests informed trading rather than manipulation. Our findings have implications for regulatory policy as well as the investigation and prosecution of manipulation cases. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, G. L.; Mahoney, P. G.; Mei, J. P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutions, ownership, and finance: the determinants of profit reinvestment among Chinese firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cull, R.; Xu, L. C.
Johnson et al. (2002. American Economic Review 92 (5), 1335-1356) examine the relative importance of property rights and external finance in several Eastern European countries. They find property rights to be overwhelmingly important, while external finance explains little of firm reinvestment. McMillan and Woodruff (2002. Journal of Economic Perspectives 16 (3), 153-170) further conjecture that as transition moves along, market-supporting (financial) institutions should become more important. This paper reexamines those issues in the context of China in 2002, when the transition had moved far. We also find that secure property rights are a significant predictor of firm reinvestment. However, in line with McMillan and Woodruff, we find that access to external finance in the form of bank loans is also associated with more reinvestment. Following Acemoglu and Johnson (2003. Unbundling institutions. Unpublished working paper 9934, National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA), we separate our proxies for the security of property rights into two groups: those measuring the risk of expropriation by the government and those measuring the ease and reliability of contract enforcement. Whereas those authors' cross-country results suggest that risk of expropriation is the more severe impediment to economic development, ours indicate that both expropriation risk and contract enforcement play a role in Chinese firms' reinvestment decisions. We also find that another aspect of property rights, the extent of private ownership, is associated with greater reinvestment. At China's current stage of development, expropriation risk, contract enforcement, access to finance, and ownership structure all appear to matter for reinvestment decisions. Some evidence also exists that access to finance and government expropriation affect small firms more than large ones. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cull, R.; Xu, L. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Law, finance, and economic growth in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, F.; Qian, J.; Qian, M. J.
China is an important counterexample to the findings in the law, institutions, finance, and growth literature: Neither its legal nor financial system is well developed, yet it has one of the fastest growing economies. While the law-finance-growth nexus applies to the State Sector and the Listed Sector, with arguably poorer applicable legal and financial mechanisms, the Private Sector grows much faster than the others and provides most of the economy's growth. The imbalance among the three sectors suggests that alternative financing channels and governance mechanisms, such as those based on reputation and relationships, support the growth of the Private Sector. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allen, F.; Qian, J.; Qian, M. J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does financial liberalization spur growth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, G.; Harvey, C. R.; Lundblad, C.
We show that equity market liberalizations, on average, lead to a 1% increase in annual real economic growth. The effect is robust to alternative definitions of liberalization and does not reflect variation in the world business cycle. The effect also remains intact when an exogenous measure of growth opportunities is included in the regression. We find that capital account liberalization also plays a role in future economic growth, but, importantly, it does not subsume the contribution of equity market liberalizations. Other simultaneous reforms only partially account for the equity market liberalization effect. Finally, the largest growth response occurs in countries with high-quality institutions. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bekaert, G.; Harvey, C. R.; Lundblad, C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of international equity market expectations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brennan, M. J.; Cao, H. H.; Strong, N.; Xu, X. Z.
This paper develops a noisy rational expectations model of the way in which international investors adjust their expectations of asset payoffs in a given country in response not only to public information signals but also to private information signals whose precision differs across investors. The model predicts that the perceptions of investors in one country about the future market returns in another country are related differently to realized past returns depending on their informational disadvantage relative to other investors: the greater is that informational disadvantage, the greater is the change in perception associated with returns. The predictions are confirmed by monthly survey data of institutional money managers investing in developed markets from 1995 to 2000. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brennan, M. J.; Cao, H. H.; Strong, N.; Xu, X. Z.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings expectations, investor trade size, and anomalous returns around earnings announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battalio, R. H.; Mendenhall, R. R.
We provide evidence that identifiable subsets of investors use significantly different information sets. Investors initiating large trades respond to analysts' earnings forecast errors, while investors initiating small trades respond to a less-sophisticated signal that underestimates the implications of current earnings innovations for future earnings levels. This suggests small investors exhibit the behavior that Bernard and Thomas [Journal of Accounting and Economics 13, 305-340] theorize causes post-earnings announcement drift. We also use analysts' forecasts to significantly improve the predictability of returns around earnings announcements previously documented by Bernard and Thomas. Finally, results attempting to link return predictability to the prevalence of small-investor trading are mixed. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Battalio, R. H.; Mendenhall, R. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Politicians and banks: Political influences on government-owned banks in emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dinc, I. S.
Government ownership of banks is very common in countries other than the United States. This paper provides cross-country, bank-level empirical evidence about political influences on these banks. It shows that government-owned banks increase their lending in election years relative to private banks. This effect is robust to controlling for country-specific macroeconomic and institutional factors as well as bank-specific factors. The increase in lending is about 11% of a government-owned bank's total loan portfolio or about 0.5% of the median country's GDP per election per government-owned bank. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dinc, I. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity of emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lesmond, D. A.
Emerging markets are characterized by volatile, but substantial returns that can easily exceed 75% per annum. Balancing these lofty returns are liquidity costs that, using the bid-ask spread as a basis, range from 1% for the Taiwanese market to over 47% for the Russian market. However, the paucity of bid-ask spread information across countries and time requires the use of liquidity estimates in emerging markets even though little is known about the efficacy of these estimates in measuring bid-ask spread costs. Using firm-level quoted bid-ask spreads as a basis, I find that price-based liquidity measures of Lesmond et al. [Review of Financial Studies 12 (1999) 1113] and Roll [Journal of Finance 39 (1984) 1127] perform better at representing cross-country liquidity effects than do volume based liquidity measures. Within-country liquidity is best measured with the liquidity estimates of either Lesmond, Ogden, and Trzcinka or, to a lesser extent, Amihud (2002). Examining the impact of legal origin and political institutions on liquidity levels shows that countries with weak political and legal institutions have significantly higher liquidity costs than do countries with strong political and legal systems, even to the exclusion of legal origin or insider trading enforcement. Higher incremental political risk is associated with a 10 basis point increase in transaction costs, using the Lesmond, Ogden, and Trzcinka estimate, or a 1.9% increase in price impact costs, using the Amihud estimate. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lesmond, D. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing with liquidity risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, V. V.; Pedersen, L. H.
This paper solves explicitly a simple equilibrium model with liquidity risk. In our liquidity-adjusted capital asset pricing model, a security's required return depends on its expected liquidity as well as on the covariances of its own return and liquidity with the market return and liquidity. In addition, a persistent negative shock to a security's liquidity results in low contemporaneous returns and high predicted future returns. The model provides a unified framework for understanding the various channels through which liquidity risk may affect asset prices. Our empirical results shed light on the total and relative economic significance of these channels and provide evidence of flight to liquidity. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, V. V.; Pedersen, L. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Issuer surplus and the partial adjustment of IPO prices to public information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edelen, R. M.; Kadlec, G. B.
This study develops a model in which rational issuers maximize the expected surplus from going public by choosing an offer price that weighs the benefit of higher proceeds if the offer is completed against the cost of foregone surplus if the offer fails. Increases in the market valuation of comparable firms during the waiting period imply higher surplus associated with going public; issuers respond with a partial revision in the offer price to elevate the probability of completion. The model offers insights into many facts associated with initial public offering pricing, including partial adjustment to market returns, the inverse relation between withdrawal and market returns, the asymmetric price adjustment to up versus down market returns, hot-issue markets, and unconditional underpricing. (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Edelen, R. M.; Kadlec, G. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal toeholds in takeover contests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldman, E.; Qian, J.
We offer an explanation for why raiders do not acquire the maximum possible toehold prior to announcing a takeover bid. By endogenously modeling the target firm's value following an unsuccessful takeover we demonstrate that a raider may optimally acquire a small toehold even if the acquisition does not drive up the pre-tender target price. This occurs because although a larger toehold increases profits if the takeover Succeeds it also conveys a higher level of managerial entrenchment and hence a tower firm value if the takeover fails. We derive new predictions regarding the optimal toehold and target value following a failed takeover. We also examine the impact of a rival bidder and dilution. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goldman, E.; Qian, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Professional trader discipline and trade disposition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Locke, P. R.; Mann, S. C.
Recent evidence indicates irrational behavior among retail investors. They hold onto losses and sell winners in a manner consistent with the disposition effect. Market professionals often use the term "discipline" to indicate trading strategies that minimize potential behavioral influences. We investigate the nature of trading discipline and whether professional traders are able to avoid the costly irrational behaviors found in retail populations. The full-time traders in our sample hold onto losses significantly longer than gains, but we find no evidence of costs associated with this behavior. The successful floor futures traders in our sample exhibit trading behavior characterized as rational and disciplined. Moreover, measures of relative trading discipline have predictive power for subsequent trading success. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Locke, P. R.; Mann, S. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does function follow organizational form? Evidence from the lending practices of large and small banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, A. N.; Miller, N. H.; Petersen, M. A.; Rajan, R. G.; Stein, J. C.
Theories based on incomplete contracting suggest that small organizations have a comparative advantage in activities that make extensive use of "soft" information. We provide evidence consistent with small banks being better able to collect and act on soft information than large banks. In particular, large banks are less willing to lend to informationally "difficult" credits, such as firms with no financial records. Moreover, after controlling for the endogeneity of bank-firm matching, we find that large banks lend at a greater distance, interact more impersonally with their borrowers, have shorter and less exclusive relationships, and do not alleviate credit constraints as effectively. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, A. N.; Miller, N. H.; Petersen, M. A.; Rajan, R. G.; Stein, J. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence on the speed of convergence to market efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, T.; Roll, R.; Subrahmanyam, A.
Daily returns for stocks listed on the New York Exchange (NYSE) are not serially correlated while order imbalances on the same stocks are highly persistent. These empirical facts can be reconciled if sophisticated investors react to order imbalances within the trading day by undertaking enough countervailing trades to remove serial dependence over a daily horizon. How long does this actually take? The pattern of intra-day serial dependence reveals that it takes more than five minutes but less than sixty minutes. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chordia, T.; Roll, R.; Subrahmanyam, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vasicek, O. A.
The paper looks at the behavior of investors in an economy consisting of a production process controlled by a state variable representing the state of technology. The participants in the economy maximize their individual utilities of consumption. Each participant has a constant relative risk aversion. The degrees of risk aversion, as well as the time preference functions, differ across participants. The participants may lend and borrow among themselves, either at a floating short rate, or by issuing or buying term bonds. We derive conditions under which such an economy is in equilibrium, and obtain equations determining interest rates. &amp;COPY; 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vasicek, O. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informational effects of regulation FD: evidence from rating agencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jorion, P.; Liu, Z.; Shi, C.
Regulation Fair Disclosure, implemented on October 23, 2000, prohibits U.S. public companies from making selective, nonpublic disclosures to favored investment professionals. Regulation Fair Disclosure has a number of exclusions, however, including disclosure of nonpublic information to credit rating agencies. As a result, credit analysts at rating agencies have access to confidential information that is no longer made available to equity analysts, potentially increasing the information content of credit ratings. We examine the effect of credit rating changes on stock prices and find that the informational effect of downgrades and upgrades is much greater in the post-FD period. &amp;COPY; 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jorion, P.; Liu, Z.; Shi, C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Management quality, certification, and initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, T. J.; Paeglis, I.
We empirically examine the relationship between the quality and reputation of a firm's management and various aspects of its IPO and post-IPO performance, a relationship that has so far received little attention in the literature. We hypothesize that better and more reputable managers are able to convey the intrinsic value of their firm more credibly to outsiders, thereby reducing the information asymmetry facing their firm in the equity market. Therefore, IPOs of firms with higher management quality will be characterized by lower underpricing, greater institutional interest, more reputable underwriters, and smaller underwriting expenses. Further, if higher management quality is associated with lower heterogeneity in investor valuations, firms with better managers will have greater long-term stock returns. Finally, since better managers are likely to select better projects (having a larger NPV for any given scale) and implement them more ably, higher management quality will also be associated with larger IPO offer sizes and stronger post-IPO operating performance. We present evidence consistent with the above hypotheses. &amp;COPY; 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chemmanur, T. J.; Paeglis, I.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Postprivatization corporate governance: The role of ownership structure and investor protection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubakri, N.; Cosset, J. C.; Guedhami, O.
We investigate the role of ownership structure and investor protection in postprivatization corporate governance. Using a sample of 209 privatized firms from 39 countries over the period 1980 to 2001, we find that the government relinquishes control over time to the benefit of local institutions, individuals, and foreign investors, and that private ownership tends to concentrate over time. Firm size, growth, and industry affiliation, privatization method, as well as the level of institutional development and investor protection, explain the cross-firm differences in ownership concentration. The positive effect of ownership concentration on firm performance matters more in countries with weak investor protection. &amp;COPY; 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubakri, N.; Cosset, J. C.; Guedhami, O.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exercise behavior, valuation, and the incentive effects of employee stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bettis, J. C.; Bizjak, J. M.; Lemmon, M. L.
We use a large database on ESO exercises to document characteristics of exercise behavior and calibrate a utility-based model for measuring how differences in exercise behavior are manifested in option values and incentives. Option values and incentives computed from the model calibrations are compared to those computed from models used to value tradable options. Our analysis provides guidance to both academics and practitioners about how differences in exercise behavior and model choice affect measures of ESO values and incentives, and underscores the importance of gaining a thorough understanding of the underlying economic forces that affect the behavior of ESO holders. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bettis, J. C.; Bizjak, J. M.; Lemmon, M. L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflicts between principals and agents: evidence from residential brokerage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rutherford, R. C.; Springer, T. M.; Yavas, A.
When a homeowner uses an agent to sell his property, lie may have less information than his agent and be disadvantaged in price setting and negotiating. This study examines whether the percentage commission structure in real estate brokerage creates agency problems. We investigate whether agents are able to use their information advantage to either sell their own property faster or for a higher price than their clients' properties. The empirical results confirm our theoretical predictions of agency problems, as we find that agent-owned houses sell no faster than client-owned houses, but they do sell at a price premium of approximately 4.5%. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rutherford, R. C.; Springer, T. M.; Yavas, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interactions of corporate financing and investment decisions: The effects of agency conflicts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Childs, P. D.; Mauer, D. C.; Ott, S. H.
We examine interactions between flexible financing and investment decisions in a model with stockholder-bondholder conflicts over investment policy. We find that financial flexibility encourages the choice of short-term debt thereby dramatically reducing the agency costs of under- and overinvestment. However, the reduction in agency costs may not encourage the firm to increase leverage, since the firm's initial debt level choice depends on the type of growth options in its investment opportunity set. The model has a number of testable predictions for the joint choice of leverage and maturity, and how these choices interact with a firm's growth opportunities. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Childs, P. D.; Mauer, D. C.; Ott, S. H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected returns and expected dividend growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lettau, M.; Ludvigson, S. C.
We investigate a consumption-based present-value relation that is a function of future dividend growth and find that changing forecasts of dividend growth are an important feature of the post-war U.S. stock market, despite the failure of the dividend-price ratio to uncover such variation. In addition, dividend forecasts are found to covary with changing forecasts of excess stock returns over business cycle frequencies. This covariation is important because positively correlated fluctuations in expected dividend growth and expected returns have offsetting effects on the log dividend-price ratio. The market risk premium and expected dividend growth thus vary considerably more than is apparent using the log divided-price ratio alone as a predictive variable. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lettau, M.; Ludvigson, S. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing decisions: who issues stock?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.
Financing decisions seem to violate the central predictions of the pecking order model about how often and under what circumstances firms issue equity. Specifically, most firms issue or retire equity each year, and the issues are on average large and not typically done by firms tinder duress. We estimate that during 1973-2002, the year-by-year equity decisions of more than half of our sample firms violate the pecking order. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>There is a risk-return trade-off after all</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghysels, E.; Santa-Clara, P.; Valkanov, R.
This paper studies the intertemporal relation between the conditional mean and the conditional variance of the aggregate stock market return. We introduce a new estimator that forecasts monthly variance with past daily squared returns, the mixed data sampling (or MIDAS) approach. Using MIDAS, we find a significantly positive relation between risk and return in the stock market. This finding is robust in subsamples, to asymmetric specifications of the variance process and to controlling for variables associated with the business cycle. We compare the MIDAS results with tests of the intertemporal capital asset pricing model based on alternative conditional variance specifications and explain the conflicting results in the literature. Finally, we offer new insights about the dynamics of conditional variance. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ghysels, E.; Santa-Clara, P.; Valkanov, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why stocks may disappoint</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, A.; Bekaert, G.; Liu, J.
We provide a formal treatment of both static and dynamic portfolio choice using the Disappointment Aversion preferences of Gul (1991. Econometrica 59(3), 667-686), which imply asymmetric aversion to gains versus losses. Our dynamic formulation nests the standard CRRA asset allocation problem as a special case. Using realistic data generating processes, we find reasonable equity portfolio allocations for disappointment averse investors with utility functions exhibiting low curvature. Moderate variation in parameters can robustly generate substantial cross-sectional variation in portfolio holdings, including optimal non-participation in the stock market. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, A.; Bekaert, G.; Liu, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited arbitrage and short sales restrictions: evidence from the options markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ofek, E.; Richardson, M.; Whitelaw, R. F.
We investigate empirically the well-known put-call parity no-arbitrage relation in the presence of short sales restrictions. Violations of put-call parity are asymmetric in the direction of short sales constraints, and their magnitudes are strongly related to the cost and difficulty of short selling. These violations are also related to both the maturity of the option and the level of valuations in the stock market, consistent with a behavioral finance theory of over-optimistic stock investors and market segmentation. Moreover, both the size of put-call parity violations and the cost of short selling are significant predictors of future returns for individual stocks. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ofek, E.; Richardson, M.; Whitelaw, R. F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-country determinants of mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rossi, S.; Volpin, P. F.
We study the determinants of mergers and acquisitions around the world by focusing on differences in laws and regulation across countries. We find that the volume of M&amp;A activity is significantly larger in countries with better accounting standards and stronger shareholder protection. The probability of an all-cash bid decreases with the level of shareholder protection in the acquirer country. In cross-border deals, targets Lire typically from countries with poorer investor protection than their acquirers' countries, suggesting that cross-border transactions play a governance role by improving the degree of investor protection within target firms. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rossi, S.; Volpin, P. F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial succession and firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huson, M. R.; Malatesta, P. H.; Parrino, R.
We examine CEO turnover and firm financial performance. Accounting measures of performance relative to other firms deteriorate prior to CEO turnover and improve thereafter. The degree of improvement is positively related to the level of institutional shareholdings, the presence of an outsider-dominated board, and the appointment of an outsider (rather than an insider) CEO. Turnover announcements are associated with significantly positive average abnormal stock returns, which are in turn significantly positively related to subsequent changes in accounting measures of performance. This suggests that investors view turnover announcements as good news presaging performance improvements. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huson, M. R.; Malatesta, P. H.; Parrino, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting returns with financial ratios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewellen, J.
This article studies whether financial ratios like dividend yield can predict aggregate stock returns. Predictive regressions are subject to small-sample biases, but the correction used by prior studies can substantially understate forecasting power. I show that dividend yield predicts market returns during the period 1946-2000, as well as in various subsamples. Book-to-market and the earnings-price ratio predict returns during the shorter sample 1963-2000. The evidence remains strong despite the unusual price run-up in recent years. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lewellen, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Style effects in the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Teo, M.; Woo, S. J.
Using CRSP stock and mutual fund data, we find strong evidence for reversals at the style level (e.g., large value, small growth, etc.). There are significant excess and risk-adjusted returns for stocks in styles characterized by the worst past returns and net inflows. We also find evidence for momentum and positive feedback trading at the style level. These value and momentum effects are driven neither by fundamental risk nor by stock-level reversals and momentum. Taken together, the results are consistent with the style-level positive feedback trading model of Barberis and Shleifer (2003). (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Teo, M.; Woo, S. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional trading and the turn-of-the-year effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ng, L. L.; Wang, Q. H.
This study provides evidence that links institutional trading behavior directly to anomalous turn-of-the-year return patterns of small stocks. We find that turn-of-the-year trading patterns of institutions reflect strategies generally consistent with window-dressing and risk-shifting behaviors. Institutions sell more loser small stocks in the last quarter of the year, but buy more small stocks, winners and losers, in the first quarter. Institutional buying (selling) of loser stocks at year-end weakens (strengthens) the turn-of-the-year effect. Buying of winner stocks after year-end causes a statistically significant, though weaker, effect. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ng, L. L.; Wang, Q. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of tax shields is NOT equal to the present value of tax shields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandez, P.
The value of tax shields is the difference between the present values of two different cash flows, each with their own risk: the present value of taxes for the unlevered company and the present value of taxes for the levered company. For constant growth companies, the value of tax shields in a world with no leverage cost is the present value of the debt, times the tax rate, times the unlevered cost of equity, discounted at the unlevered cost of equity. This result arises as the difference of two present values and does not mean that the appropriate discount for tax shields is the unlevered cost of equity. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fernandez, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does an electronic stock exchange need an upstairs market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, H.; Venkataraman, K.
We examine the Paris Bourse, whose electronic limit order market closely resembles the downstairs markets envisioned by theorists, to test several theoretical predictions regarding upstairs trading. We present direct evidence in support of the Grossman (J. Business (1992) 509) prediction that upstairs brokers lower execution costs by tapping into unexpressed liquidity, as actual execution costs upstairs are on average only 20% (35%) as large as they would be if block trades were executed against displayed (displayed and hidden) liquidity in the downstairs limit order book. Consistent with prior analyses, the Paris data also support the Seppi (J. Finance (1990) 73) hypothesis that upstairs brokers certify trades as uninformed. We also find that participants in stocks with less restrictive crossing rules agree to outside-the-quote executions for more difficult trades and at times when downstairs liquidity is lacking. These likely represent trades that could not have been otherwise completed, suggesting that market quality can be enhanced by allowing participants more flexibility to execute blocks at prices outside the quotes. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bessembinder, H.; Venkataraman, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common market makers and commonality in liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coughenour, J. F.; Saad, M. M.
Each NYSE specialist firm provides liquidity for more than one common stock. As a result of shared capital and information among specialists within a firm, we argue that stock liquidity will co-move with the liquidity of other stocks handled by the same specialist firm, with magnitude increasing with the risk of providing liquidity. The evidence indicates that individual stock liquidity co-varies with specialist portfolio liquidity apart from information reflected by market liquidity variation. Further tests based on specialist firm size, specialist firm mergers, and market returns indicate that liquidity co-variation increases with the risk of providing liquidity. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coughenour, J. F.; Saad, M. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage decision and manager compensation with choice of effort and volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cadenillas, A.; Cvitanic, J.; Zapatero, F.
We study the incentive effects of granting levered or unlevered stock to a risk-averse manager. The stock is granted by risk-neutral shareholders who choose leverage and compensation level. The manager applies costly effort and selects the level of volatility, both of which affect expected return. The results are driven by the attempt of the risk-neutral shareholders to maximize the value of their claims net of the compensation package. We consider a dynamic setting and find that levered stock is optimal for high-type managers, firms with high momentum, large firms, and firms for which additional volatility only implies a modest increase in expected return. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cadenillas, A.; Cvitanic, J.; Zapatero, F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance fee contract change and mutual fund risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golec, J.; Starks, L.
We examine the effect that an exogenously, specifically governmentally required change in compensation contract had on a managerial decision. We find that a group of mutual funds changed their portfolio risk levels after they were forced to change their performance fee schedules. Their portfolio risk choices differed predictably from a randomly selected group of nonperformance fee funds and a group of performance fee funds that were not required to change their compensation contracts. In addition, the affected mutual funds lost both shareholders and assets around the time of the imposition of the restriction while the other funds exhibited little change or gained assets and shareholders. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Golec, J.; Starks, L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An econometric model of serial correlation and illiquidity in hedge fund returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Getmansky, M.; Lo, A. W.; Makarov, I.
The returns to hedge funds and other alternative investments are often highly serially correlated. In this paper, we explore several sources of such serial correlation and show that the most likely explanation is illiquidity exposure and smoothed returns. We propose an econometric model of return smoothing and develop estimators for the smoothing profile as well as a smoothing-adjusted Sharpe ratio. For a sample of 908 hedge funds drawn from the TASS database, we show that our estimated smoothing coefficients vary considerably across hedge-fund style categories and may be a useful proxy for quantifying illiquidity exposure. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Getmansky, M.; Lo, A. W.; Makarov, I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disentangling diffusion from jumps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ait-Sahalia, Y.
Realistic models for financial asset prices used in portfolio choice, option pricing or risk management include both a continuous Brownian and a jump components. This paper studies our ability to distinguish one from the other. I find that, surprisingly, it is possible to perfectly disentangle Brownian noise from jumps. This is true even if, unlike the usual Poisson jumps, the jump process exhibits an infinite number of small jumps in any finite time interval, which ought to be harder to distinguish from Brownian noise, itself made up of many small moves. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ait-Sahalia, Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring stock illiquidity: An investigation of the demand and supply schedules at the TASE</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalay, A.; Sade, O.; Wohl, A.
We show that estimating demand and supply elasticities at the opening stage of trading at the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange is highly sensitive to which of several reasonable measures is used. We find that the demand curve is more elastic than the supply curve and that both are much more elastic in their "executable" areas. The empirical evidence indicates that elasticity is increasing during the continuous stage of trading. We discuss methods of estimation of price impact and document that the actual measure of price impact in call auctions is larger and more permanent for buys than for sells. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kalay, A.; Sade, O.; Wohl, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sources of gains in horizontal mergers: evidence from customer, supplier, and rival firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fee, C. E.; Thomas, S.
We investigate the upstream and downstream product-market effects of a large sample of horizontal mergers and acquisitions from 1980 to 1997. We construct a data set that identifies the corporate customers, suppliers, and rivals of the firms initiating horizontal mergers and use this data set to examine announcement-related stock market revaluations and post-merger changes in operating performance. We find little evidence consistent with increased monopolistic collusion. However, we do find evidence consistent with improved productive efficiency and buying power as sources of gains to horizontal mergers. The nature of the buying power gains, i.e., rents from monopsonistic collusion or improved purchasing efficiency, is also investigated. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fee, C. E.; Thomas, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate earnings and the equity premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, F. A.; Piazzesi, M.
Corporate cash flows are highly volatile and strongly procyclical. We examine the asset-pricing implications of the sensitivity of corporate cash flows to economic shocks within a continuous-time model in which dividends are a stochastic fraction of aggregate consumption. We provide closed-form solutions for stock values and show that the equity premium can be represented as the sum of three components which we call the consumption-risk, event-risk, and corporate-risk premia. Calibrated to historical data, the model implies a total equity premium many times larger than in the standard model. The model also generates levels of equity volatility consistent with those experienced in the stock market. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Longstaff, F. A.; Piazzesi, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Grandstanding, certification and the underpricing of venture capital backed IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, P. M.; Wahal, S.
We examine the role of venture capital backing in the Underpricing of IPOs. Controlling for endogeneity in the receipt of venture funding, we find that venture capital backed IPOs experience larger first-day returns than comparable non-venture backed IPOs. Between 1980 and 2000, the average return difference ranges from 5.01 percentage points to 10.32 percentage points. This return difference is particularly pronounced in the "bubble" period of 1999-2000. Consistent with the grandstanding hypothesis proposed by Gompers (J. Financial Econ. 42 (1996) 133), we find that higher underpricing leads to larger future flows of capital into venture capital funds, particularly after 1996. Cross-sectionally, the effect of underpricing is attenuated for younger venture capital firms and those that have previously conducted fewer IPOs. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, P. M.; Wahal, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The costs of shared ownership: Evidence from international joint ventures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, M. A.; Foley, C. F.; Hines, J. R.
This paper analyzes the determinants of partial ownership of the foreign affiliates of U.S. multinational firms and, in particular, the marked decline in the use of joint ventures over the last 20 years. The evidence indicates that whole ownership is most common when firms coordinate integrated production activities across different locations, transfer technology, and benefit from worldwide tax planning. Because operations and ownership levels are jointly determined, it is helpful to use the liberalization of ownership restrictions by host countries and the imposition of joint venture tax penalties in the U.S. Tax Reform Act of 1986 as instruments for ownership levels to identify these effects. Firms responded to these regulatory and tax changes by using wholly owned affiliates instead of joint ventures and expanding intrafirm trade and technology transfer. The implied complementarity of whole ownership and intrafirm trade suggests that the reduced costs of engaging in integrated global operations contributed substantially to the sharply declining propensity of American firms to organize their foreign operations as joint ventures over the last two decades. Estimates imply that as much as one-fifth to three-fifths of the decline in the use of joint ventures by multinational firms is attributable to the increased importance of intrafirm transactions. The forces of globalization appear to have diminished, rather than accelerated, the use of shared ownership. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Desai, M. A.; Foley, C. F.; Hines, J. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why constrain your mutual fund manager?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almazan, A.; Brown, K. C.; Carlson, M.; Chapman, D. A.
We examine the form, adoption rates, and economic rationale for various mutual fund investment restrictions. A sample of U.S. domestic equity funds from 1994 to 2000 reveals systematic patterns in investment constraints, consistent with an optimal contracting equilibrium in the fund industry. Restrictions are more common when (i) boards contain a higher proportion of inside directors, (ii) the portfolio manager is more experienced, (iii) the fund is managed by a team rather than an individual, and (iv) the fund does not belong to a large organizational complex. Low- and high-constraint funds produce similar risk-adjusted returns, also consistent with an optimal contracting equilibrium. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Almazan, A.; Brown, K. C.; Carlson, M.; Chapman, D. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Appearing and disappearing dividends: The link to catering incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, M.; Wurgler, J.
We document a close link between fluctuations in the propensity to pay dividends and catering incentives. First, we use the methodology of Fama and French (J. Finan. Econ. (2001)) to identify a total of four distinct trends in the propensity to pay dividends between 1963 and 2000. Second, we show that each of these trends lines up with a corresponding fluctuation in catering incentives: The propensity to pay increases when a proxy for the stock market dividend premium is positive and decreases when it is negative. The lone disconnect is attributable to Nixon-era controls. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baker, M.; Wurgler, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New lists: Fundamentals and survival rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.
The class of firms that obtain public equity financing expands dramatically in the 1980s and 1990s. The number of new firms listed on major U.S. stock markets jumps from 156 per year for 1973-1979 to 549 per year for 1980-2001. The characteristics of new lists also change. The cross section of profitability becomes progressively more left skewed, and growth becomes more right skewed. The result is a sharp decline in survival rates. We suggest that the changes in the characteristics of new lists are due to a decline in the cost of equity that allows weaker firms and firms with more distant expected payoffs to issue public equity. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm size and the gains from acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moeller, S. B.; Schlingemann, F. P.; Stulz, R. M.
We examine a sample of 12,023 acquisitions by public firms from 1980 to 2001. The equally weighted abnormal announcement return is 1.1%, but acquiring-firm shareholders lose $25.2 million on average upon announcement. This disparity suggests the existence of a size effect in acquisition announcement returns. The announcement return for acquiring-firm shareholders is roughly two percentage points higher for small acquirers irrespective of the form of financing and whether the acquired firm is public or private. The size effect is robust to firm and deal characteristics, and it is not reversed over time. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moeller, S. B.; Schlingemann, F. P.; Stulz, R. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A revealed preference approach to understanding corporate governance problems: Evidence from Canada</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chirinko, R. S.; Schaller, H.
Governance problems have a direct and immediate impact on the effective discount rate guiding investment decisions. Information from a transformed net present value rule and variation in firm-level panel data "reveal" the effective discount rate influencing investment. For the firms most likely to be affected by Jensen agency problems, investment behavior appears to be guided by discount rates less than the market rate by 350-400 basis points. This wedge is reduced for firms with a concentrated ownership structure. Firms facing free cash flow problems have a stock of fixed capital approximately 7-22% higher than would prevail under value maximizing behavior. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chirinko, R. S.; Schaller, H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gains in bank mergers: Evidence from the bond markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Penas, M. F.; Unal, H.
We present evidence that the adjusted returns of merging banks' bonds are positive and significant across pre-merger and announcement months. The cross-sectional evidence indicates that the primary determinants of merger-related bondholder gains are diversification gains, gains associated with achieving too-big-to-fail status, and, to a lesser degree, synergy gains. We obtain the same finding when we examine the acquiring banks' credit spreads on new debt issues both before and after the merger. We also provide the first study that shows acquirers benefit by the lower cost of funds on post-merger debt issues. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Penas, M. F.; Unal, H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The choice of equity-selling mechanisms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Y. L.
This paper examines the impact of information asymmetry and monitoring of managers on the choice between public offerings and private placements. Three key findings emerge. First, private placement firms have higher information asymmetry than public offering firms. Second, private placement investors do not engage in more monitoring than public offering investors. Finally, discounts for private placements sold to managers are higher than discounts for private placements in which managers do not participate. The final two findings cast doubts on the widely held view that private placements are motivated by a demand for enhanced monitoring. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Y. L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do security analysts exhibit persistent differences in stock picking ability?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mikhail, M. B.; Walther, B. R.; Willis, R. H.
We investigate whether security analysts exhibit persistence in their stock picking ability. We find that analysts whose recommendation revisions earned the most (least) excess returns in the past continue to outperform (underperform) in the future. Further, the market recognizes these performance differences in the five-day period surrounding the recommendation revision. This market reaction, however, is incomplete. Excess returns in the one and three trading months following the revision are significant and positively associated with analysts' prior performance. However, a trading strategy taking long (short) positions in recommendation upgrades (downgrades) conditional on analysts' prior performance is unprofitable. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mikhail, M. B.; Walther, B. R.; Willis, R. H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional estimation of diffusion processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, M. Q.; Pearson, N. D.; Poteshman, A. M.
There are a number of circumstances in finance in which it is useful to estimate diffusion processes conditional on some event. In this paper, we develop the theoretical and numerical tools necessary to perform conditional estimation of diffusion processes within a generalized method of moments framework. We illustrate our method by estimating a univariate diffusion process for a standard time-series of interest rate data conditioned to remain between lower and upper boundaries. A test statistic fails to reject by a wide margin the linearity of the conditionally estimated drift coefficient. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, M. Q.; Pearson, N. D.; Poteshman, A. M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of capital structure when expected agency costs are extreme</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harvey, C. R.; Lins, K. V.; Roper, A. H.
This paper conducts powerful new tests of whether debt can mitigate the effects of agency and information problems. We focus on emerging market firms for which pyramid ownership structures create potentially extreme managerial agency costs. Our tests incorporate both traditional financial statement data and new data on global debt contracts. Our analysis is mindful of the potential endogeneity between debt, ownership structure, and value, and it takes into account differences in the debt capacity of a firm's assets in place and future growth opportunities. The results indicate that the incremental benefit of debt is concentrated in firms with high expected managerial agency costs that are also most likely to have overinvestment problems resulting from high levels of assets in place or limited future growth opportunities. Subsequent internationally syndicated term loans are particularly effective at creating value for these firms. Our results support the recontracting hypothesis that equity holders value compliance with monitored covenants, particularly when firms are likely to overinvest. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harvey, C. R.; Lins, K. V.; Roper, A. H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Universal option valuation using quadrature methods (vol 67, pg 447, 2003)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andricopoulos, A. D.; Widdicks, M.; Duck, P. W.; Newton, D. P.
nan</description><author>Andricopoulos, A. D.; Widdicks, M.; Duck, P. W.; Newton, D. P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking market structure and financial stability: Evidence from the Texas real estate crisis in the 1980s</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gan, J.
This paper examines the relationship between banking market structure and financial stability. Using data on thrifts, a type of banking institution specializing in residential mortgage lending, I test two related hypotheses. First, competition reduces franchise value. Second, reduced franchise Value induces risk taking. Testing the second hypothesis exploits predictions that when hit by an exogenous shock, the slope of risk with respect to franchise value becomes more negative because thrifts adopt "bang-bang" strategies and choose minimal or maximal risk. Using the Texas real estate collapse in the 1980s as a natural experiment, I find evidence supporting both hypotheses. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gan, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing market efficiency using statistical arbitrage with applications to momentum and value strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hogan, S.; Jarrow, R.; Teo, M.; Warachka, M.
This paper introduces the concept of statistical arbitrage, a long horizon trading opportunity that generates a riskless profit and is designed to exploit persistent anomalies. Statistical arbitrage circumvents the joint hypothesis dilemma of traditional market efficiency tests because its definition is independent of any equilibrium model and its existence is incompatible with market efficiency. We provide a methodology to test for statistical arbitrage and then empirically investigate whether momentum and value trading strategies constitute statistical arbitrage opportunities. Despite adjusting for transaction costs, the influence of small stocks, margin requirements, liquidity buffers for the marking-to-market of short-sales, and higher borrowing rates, we find evidence that these strategies generate statistical arbitrage. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hogan, S.; Jarrow, R.; Teo, M.; Warachka, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who is in whose pocket? Director compensation, board independence, and barriers to effective monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ryan, H. E.; Wiggins, R. A.
We use a bargaining framework to examine empirically the relations between director compensation and board-of-director independence. Our evidence suggests that independent directors have a bargaining advantage over the CEO that results in compensation more closely aligned with shareholders' objectives. Firms with more outsiders on their boards award directors more equity-based compensation. When the CEO's power over the board increases, compensation provides weaker incentives to monitor. Firms with more inside directors and with entrenched CEOs use less equity-based pay. Furthermore, firms with entrenched CEOs and CEOs who also chair the board are less likely to replace cash pay with equity. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V.. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ryan, H. E.; Wiggins, R. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the market risk premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mayfield, E. S.
This paper provides a method for estimating the market risk premium that accounts for shifts in investment opportunities by explicitly modeling the underlying process governing the level of market volatility. I find that approximately 50% of the measured risk premium is related to the risk of future changes in investment opportunities. Evidence of a structural shift in the underlying volatility process suggests that the simple historical average of excess market returns may substantially overstate the magnitude of the market risk premium for the period since the Great Depression. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mayfield, E. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The timing and value of forecast and recommendation revisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivkovic, Z.; Jegadeesh, N.
This paper evaluates the information content of analysts' one-quarter-ahead earnings forecast revisions and recommendation revisions at various points in event time relative to earnings announcement dates. Across three sets of tests, we find that the revisions are least informative in the week after earnings announcements and that the information content of revisions generally increases over event time. We find a sharp increase in the information content of upward forecast revisions and recommendation upgrades in the week before earnings announcements, but we do not find a similar increase for downward revisions or for recommendation downgrades. (C) 2004 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Ivkovic, Z.; Jegadeesh, N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset prices and real investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kogan, L.
Firm investment activity and firm characteristics, particularly the market-to-book ratio or q, are functions of the state of the economy and therefore contain information about the dynamic behavior of stock returns. This paper develops a model of a production economy in which real investment is irreversible and subject to convex adjustment costs. During low-q (high-q) periods when the irreversibility constraint (constraint on the rate of investment) is binding, conditional volatility and expected returns on one hand, and market-to-book ratios on the other, should be negatively (positively) related. Empirical tests based on industry portfolios support these predictions for conditional volatility but not for expected returns. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kogan, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO compensation and incentives: Evidence from M&amp;A bonuses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinstein, Y.; Hribar, P.
We investigate CEO compensation for completing M&amp;A deals. We find that CEOs who have more power to influence board decisions receive significantly larger bonuses. We also find a positive relation between bonus compensation and measures of effort, but not between bonus compensation and deal performance. CEOs with more power also tend to engage in larger deals relative to the size of their own firms, and the market responds more negatively to their acquisition announcements. Our evidence is consistent with the argument that managerial power is the primary driver of M&amp;A bonuses. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grinstein, Y.; Hribar, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management and the market performance of acquiring firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Louis, H.
I examine the market's efficiency in processing manipulated accounting reports and provide an explanation for the post-merger underperformance anomaly. I find strong evidence suggesting that acquiring firms overstate their earnings in the quarter preceding a stock swap announcement. I also find evidence of a reversal of the stock price effects of the earnings management in the days leading to the merger announcement. However, the pre-merger reversal is only partial. I find evidence of a post-merger reversal of the stock price effects of the pre-merger earnings management. The results suggest that the extant evidence of post-merger underperformance by acquiring firms is partly attributable to the reversal of the price effects of earnings management. The study also suggests that the post-merger reversal is not fully anticipated by financial analysts in the month immediately following the merger announcement. However, consistent with suggestions in the financial press that managers guide analysts' forecasts to "beatable" levels, the effect of the earnings management reversal seems to be reflected in the consensus analysts' forecasts by the time of the subsequent quarterly earnings releases. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Louis, H.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of dividend imputation tax credits in Australia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cannavan, D.; Finn, F.; Gray, S.
A dividend imputation tax system provides shareholders with a credit (for corporate tax paid) that can be used to offset personal tax on dividend income. This paper shows how to infer the value of imputation tax credits from the prices of derivative securities that are unique to Australian retail markets. We also test whether a tax law amendment that was designed to prevent the trading of imputation credits affected their economic value. Before the amendment, tax credits were worth up to 50% of face value in large, high-yielding companies, but Subsequently it is difficult to detect any value at all. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cannavan, D.; Finn, F.; Gray, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market evidence on the opaqueness of banking firms' assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flannery, M. J.; Kwan, S. H.; Nimalendran, M.
We assess the market microstructure properties of U.S. banking firms' equity, to determine whether they exhibit more or less evidence of asset opaqueness than similar-sized nonbanking firms. The evidence indicates that large bank holding companies (BHC), traded on the NYSE, have very similar trading properties to their matched nonfinancial firms. In contrast, smaller BHCs, traded on NASDAQ, trade much less frequently despite having very similar spreads. Analysis of HIES earnings forecasts indicates that banking assets are not unusually opaque; they are simply boring. The implications for regulatory policy and future market microstructure research are discussed. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Flannery, M. J.; Kwan, S. H.; Nimalendran, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of illegal insider trading in dealer and specialist markets: evidence from a natural experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fishe, R. P. H.; Robe, M. A.
We examine insider trading in specialist and dealer markets, using the trades of stock brokers who had advance copies of a stock analysis column in Business Week magazine. We find that increases in price and volume occur after informed trades. During informed trading, market makers decrease depth. Depth falls more on the NYSE and Amex than on the Nasdaq. Spreads increase on the NYSE and Amex, but not on the Nasdaq. We find none of these prerelease changes in a nontraded control sample of stocks mentioned in the column. Our results show that insider trading has a negative impact on market liquidity; depth is an important tool to manage asymmetric information risk; and specialist markets are better at detecting informed trades. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fishe, R. P. H.; Robe, M. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal capital markets and investment policy: evidence from corporate spinoffs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, S.; Denis, D. J.
We analyze changes in investment policy following 106 spinoffs between 1981 and 1996. Pre-spinoff, the sample firms are valued at a discount and invest less in their high q segments than do their single-segment peers. Post-spinoff, there is a significant increase in measures of investment efficiency and the diversification discount is eliminated. Furthermore, changes in excess value around the spinoff are positively related to changes in measures of investment efficiency. These findings support the view that (i) diversified firms allocate investment funds inefficiently, and (ii) by breaking up the conglomerate, spinoffs create value by improving investment efficiency. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahn, S.; Denis, D. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of target capital structure: The case of dual debt and equity issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hovakimian, A.; Hovakimian, G.; Tehranian, H.
We examine whether market and operating performance affect corporate financing behavior because they are related to target leverage. Our focus on firms that issue both debt and equity enhances our ability to draw inferences. Consistent with dynamic trade-off theories, dual issuers offset the deviation from the target resulting from accumulation of earnings and losses. Our results also imply that high market-to-book firms have low target debt ratios. On the other hand, consistent with market timing, high stock returns increase the probability of equity issuance but have no effect on target leverage. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hovakimian, A.; Hovakimian, G.; Tehranian, H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting stock price movements from past returns: the role of consistency and tax-loss selling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, M.; Moskowitz, T. J.
The consistency of positive past returns and tax-loss selling significantly affects the relation between past returns and the cross-section of expected returns. Analysis of these additional effects across stock characteristics, seasons, and tax regimes provides clues about the sources of temporal relations in stock returns, pointing to potential explanations for this relation. A parsimonious trading rule generates surprisingly large economic returns despite controls for confounding sources of return premia, microstructure effects, and data snooping biases. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grinblatt, M.; Moskowitz, T. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order preferencing and market quality on NASDAQ before and after decimalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, K. H.; Chuwonganant, C.; McCormick, D. T.
Despite the widely held belief that order preferencing affects market quality, no hard evidence exists on the extent and determinants of order preferencing and its impact on dealer competition and execution quality. This study shows that the bid-ask spread (dealer quote aggressiveness) is positively (negatively) related to the proportion of internalized volume during both the pre- and post-decimalization periods. Although decimal pricing led to lower order preferencing on NASDAQ, the extent of order preferencing after decimalization is higher than what prior studies had predicted. The price impact of preferenced trades is smaller than that of unpreferenced trades and preferenced trades receive greater (smaller) size (price) improvements than unpreferenced trades. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, K. H.; Chuwonganant, C.; McCormick, D. T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information and bank credit allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dell'Ariccia, G.; Marquez, R.
Private information obtained by lenders leads to borrower capture to the extent that such information cannot be communicated credibly to outsiders. We analyze how this capture affects the loan portfolio allocation of informed lenders. First, we show that banks charge higher interest rates and finance relatively less creditworthy borrowers in market segments with greater information asymmetries. Second, when faced with greater competition from outside lenders, banks reallocate credit toward more captured borrowers (flight to captivity). Third, if borrower quality and captivity are sufficiently correlated, an increase in the competitiveness of uninformed lenders can worsen the informed lender's overall loan portfolio. The model explains observed consequences of financial liberalizations. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dell'Ariccia, G.; Marquez, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the IPO pricing process efficient?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lowry, M.; Schwert, G. W.
This paper investigates underwriters' treatment of public information throughout the IPO pricing process. Two key findings emerge. First, public information is not fully incorporated into the initial price range. While the economic magnitude of the bias is small, it is puzzling because it is not clear who benefits from it. Further, it indicates that the filing range midpoint is not an unbiased predictor of the offer price, as prior literature has assumed. Second, while public information is similarly not fully incorporated into the final offer price, the small economic significance of this relation indicates that the IPO pricing process is almost efficient. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lowry, M.; Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management, stock issues, and shareholder lawsuits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DuCharme, L. L.; Malatesta, P. H.; Sefcik, S. E.
Abnormal accounting accruals are unusually high around stock offers, especially high for firms whose offers subsequently attract lawsuits. Accruals tend to reverse after stock offers and are negatively related to post-offer stock returns. Reversals are more pronounced and stock returns are lower for sued firms than for those that are not sued. The incidence of lawsuits involving stock offers and settlement amounts are significantly positively related to abnormal accruals around the offer and significantly negatively related to post-offer stock returns. Our results support the view that some firms opportunistically manipulate earnings upward before stock issues rendering themselves vulnerable to litigation. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DuCharme, L. L.; Malatesta, P. H.; Sefcik, S. E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax-loss trading and wash sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, M.; Keloharju, M.
Finnish investors realize losses more than gains toward the end of December. Moreover, they repurchase the same stocks recently sold. The repurchase rate depends on loss magnitude, firm size, and how late in the year the sale takes place. This trading pattern generates net tax-loss buying pressure that is negative prior to the turn of the year and positive afterward. Cross-sectional regressions indicate that stock returns around the turn of the year, particularly for small firms, are related to net tax-loss buying pressure but not to firm size per se. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grinblatt, M.; Keloharju, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The basis risk of catastrophic-loss index securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cummins, J. D.; Lalonde, D.; Phillips, R. D.
Using a windstorm simulation model developed by Applied Insurance Research, we analyze the effectiveness of catastrophic-loss index options in hedging hurricane losses for Florida insurers. The results suggest that insurers in the two largest size quartiles can hedge losses almost as effectively using contracts based on four intrastate indices as they can using contracts that settle on their own losses. Many insurers in the third largest size quartile also can hedge effectively using the intrastate indices, but most insurers in the smallest quartile would encounter significant basis risk. Hedging using a statewide loss index is effective only for the largest insurers. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cummins, J. D.; Lalonde, D.; Phillips, R. D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-changed Levy processes and option pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carr, P.; Wu, L. R.
The classic Black-Scholes option pricing model assumes that returns follow Brownian motion, but return processes differ from this benchmark in at least three important ways. First, asset prices jump, leading to non-normal return innovations. Second, return volatilities vary stochastically over time. Third, returns and their volatilities are correlated, often negatively for equities. Time-changed Levy, processes can simultaneously address these three issues. We show that our framework encompasses almost all of the models proposed in the option pricing literature, and it is straightforward to select and test a particular option pricing model through the use of characteristic function technology. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carr, P.; Wu, L. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of stock market information production on internal resource allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldman, E.
We analyze the resource allocation decision of a manager inside a multidivision firm whose compensation is based on the firm's stock price. We find that internal investments exhibit a positive correlation across the firms divisions. Namely, when two single-division firms merge the optimal investment level in one division becomes more positively related to the investment level in the other division. In addition, following a spinoff, divisional investments decline (increase) whenever the separated division has a project with a low (high) Sharpe ratio. Finally, multidivision firms trade at a discount which is larger the more diverse the investment sets of the divisions. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goldman, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selling company shares to reluctant employees: France Telecom's experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degeorge, F.; Jenter, D.; Moel, A.; Tufano, P.
In 1997, France Telecom went through a partial privatization. Using a database that tracks over 200,000 eligible participants, we analyze employees' decisions whether to participate; how much to invest; and what stock alternatives to select. The results are broadly consistent with a neoclassical model of investing behavior. We report four anomalous findings: (1) The firm specificity of human capital has a negligible effect on employees' investment decisions; (2) the amount invested seems driven by different forces than the decision to participate, and we attempt to measure an apparent "threshold effect"; (3) employees "left on the table" benefits worth one to two months' salary by failing to participate; and (4) most participants underweighted the most valuable asset. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Degeorge, F.; Jenter, D.; Moel, A.; Tufano, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are foreign firms listed in the US worth more?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doidge, C.; Karolyi, G. A.; Stulz, R. M.
At the end of 1997, foreign companies with shares cross-listed in the U.S. had Tobin's q ratios that were 16.5% higher than the q ratios of non-cross-listed firms from the same country. The valuation difference is statistically significant and reaches 37% for those companies that list on major U.S. exchanges, even after controlling for a number of firm and country characteristics. We suggest that a U.S. listing reduces the extent to which controlling shareholders can engage in expropriation and thereby increases the firm's ability to take advantage of growth opportunities. We show that growth opportunities are more highly valued for firms that choose to cross-list in the U.S., particularly those from countries with poorer investor rights. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doidge, C.; Karolyi, G. A.; Stulz, R. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investibility and return volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, K. H.; Chan, K.; Ng, A.
Unlike previous studies that examine how emerging market return volatility changes subsequent to stock market liberalization, this paper investigates the impact of investibility, or the degree to which a stock can be foreign-owned, on emerging market volatility. We find a positive relation between return volatility and the investibility of individual stocks, even after controlling for country, industry, firm size, and turnover. We also find that a highly investible emerging market portfolio is subject to larger world market exposure than a non-investible portfolio, suggesting that highly investible stocks are more integrated with the world and therefore more vulnerable to world market risk. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bae, K. H.; Chan, K.; Ng, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and firm value: evidence from the Korean financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baek, J. S.; Kang, J. K.; Park, K. S.
During the 1997 Korean financial crisis, firms with higher ownership concentration by unaffiliated foreign investors experienced a smaller reduction in their share value. Firms that had higher disclosure quality and alternative sources of external financing also suffered less. In contrast, chaebol firms with concentrated ownership by controlling family shareholders experienced a larger drop in the value of their equity. Firms in which the controlling shareholders' voting rights exceeded cash flow rights and those who borrowed more from the main banks also had lower returns. Our results suggest that change in firm value during a crisis is a function of firm-level differences in corporate governance measures. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baek, J. S.; Kang, J. K.; Park, K. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bailout and conglomeration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, S. J.
This paper develops a model of business groups in emerging markets where banks cannot accurately distinguish between good (high productivity) and bad (low productivity) borrower firms. For stand-alone firms, banks can infer the proportion of bad firms among those that default on contracted debt repayments, and might optimally choose to liquidate all defaulting firms in order to reduce the number of bad firms. Business groups, however, obscure the productivity of individual firms. The optimal policy might then be full bailout so as not to risk eliminating good firms. Given the bank's bailout policy, risk-averse firms might form a conglomerate to reduce the risk of liquidation. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, S. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The illusory nature of momentum profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lesmond, D. A.; Schill, M. J.; Zhou, C. S.
Our paper re-examines the profitability of relative strength or momentum trading strategies (buying past strong performers and selling past weak performers). We find that standard relative strength strategies require frequent trading in disproportionately high cost securities such that trading costs prevent profitable strategy execution. In the cross-section, we find that those stocks that generate large momentum returns are precisely those stocks with high trading costs. We conclude that the magnitude of the abnormal returns associated with these trading strategies creates an illusion of profit opportunity when, in fact, none exists. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lesmond, D. A.; Schill, M. J.; Zhou, C. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Death spiral convertibles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hillion, P.; Vermaelen, T.
Floating-priced convertibles, known as death spirals, are privately held convertible securities with a conversion price set at a discount from the average of past stock prices in a look-back period. The issuance of floating-priced convertibles is followed by significant negative abnormal returns. The results are consistent with the faulty contract hypothesis that argues that the contract design encourages short-selling by the convertible holders and other professional short sellers. However, the results are also consistent with the last-resort financing hypothesis that argues that the stock price declines because the stock is overvalued at the time of the issue. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hillion, P.; Vermaelen, T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling the term structure of interest rates: A new approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kimmel, R. L.
The term structure of interest rates is modeled as a random field with conditional volatility. Random field models allow consistency with the current shape of the term structure without the need for recalibration. However, most such models are Gaussian, with no conditional volatility. State-dependent volatility is introduced while a key property of Gaussian random field models is retained. Each forward rate is part of a low-dimensional diffusion process, simplifying estimation and derivatives pricing. The modeling approach also implies that, in general, the set of zero coupon bonds does not complete the market, and term structure derivatives cannot always be priced by arbitrage. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kimmel, R. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order imbalance and individual stock returns: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, T.; Subrahmanyam, A.
This paper studies the relation between order imbalances and daily returns of individual stocks. Our tests are motivated by a model which considers how market makers dynamically accommodate autocorrelated imbalances emanating from large traders who optimally choose to split their orders. Price pressures caused by autocorrelated imbalances cause a positive relation between lagged imbalances and returns, which reverses sign after controlling for the current imbalance. We find empirical evidence consistent with these implications. We also find that imbalance-based trading strategies yield statistically significant returns. Our results shed light on the role of inventory effects in daily stock price movements. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chordia, T.; Subrahmanyam, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are dividends disappearing? Dividend concentration and the consolidation of earnings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, H.; DeAngelo, L.; Skinner, D. J.
Aggregate real dividends paid by industrial firms increased over the past two decades even though, as Fama and French (J. Financial Econ. 60, 3) (2001 a) document, the number of dividend payers decreased by over 50%. The reason is that (i) the reduction in payers occurs almost entirely among firms that paid very small dividends, and (ii) increased real dividends from the top payers swamp the modest dividend reduction from the loss of many small payers. These trends reflect high and increasing concentration in the supply of dividends which, in turn, reflects high and increasing earnings concentration. For example, the 25 firms that paid the largest dividends in 2000 account for a majority of the aggregate dividends and earnings of industrial firms. Industrial firms exhibit a two-tier structure in which a small number of firms with very high earnings collectively generates the majority of earnings and dominates the dividend supply, while the vast majority of firms has at best a modest collective impact on aggregate earnings and dividends. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeAngelo, H.; DeAngelo, L.; Skinner, D. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio choice and health status</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosen, H. S.; Wu, S.
This paper analyzes the role health status plays in household portfolio decisions using data from the Health and Retirement Study. The results indicate that health is a significant predictor of both the probability of owning different types of financial assets and the share of financial wealth held in each asset category. Households in poor health are less likely to hold risky financial assets, other things (including the level of total wealth) being the same. Poor health is associated with a smaller share of financial wealth held in risky assets and a larger share in safe assets. We find no evidence that the relationship between health status and portfolio allocation is driven by "third variables" that simultaneously affect health and financial decisions. Further, the relationship between health status and portfolio choice does not appear to operate through the effect of poor health on individuals' attitudes toward risk, their planning horizons, or their health insurance status. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rosen, H. S.; Wu, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US cross-listings and the private benefits of control: evidence from dual-class firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doidge, C.
Non-U.S. firms that cross-list on U.S. exchanges have voting premiums that are 43% lower than non-U.S. firms that do not cross-list. The difference in voting premiums is statistically significant after controlling for firm and country characteristics and the difference is larger for firms from countries that provide poor protection to minority investors. When a U.S. listing is announced, both the high- and low-voting share classes benefit, although the low-voting class benefits relatively more. The evidence supports the bonding hypothesis: cross-listing in the U.S. improves the protection afforded to minority investors and decreases the private benefits of control. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doidge, C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of syndicate structure in bank underwriting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayanan, R. P.; Rangan, K. P.; Rangan, N. K.
The re-entry of banking organizations into securities underwriting raises concerns over the possibility of banks using their lending-generated private information to benefit themselves and the issuing firm at the expense of investors. This paper illustrates the use of syndicate structure by lending banks to credibly commit against such opportunistic behavior and to exploit their proprietary information to lower issuance cost for borrowing firm issuers. We show that lending banks predominantly comanage with a high reputation nonlending underwriter. We present evidence that, relative to investment banks, comanaging issues allows lending banks to lower issuance costs for borrowing firms. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Narayanan, R. P.; Rangan, K. P.; Rangan, N. K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Smart investments by smart money: Evidence from seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gibson, S.; Safieddine, A.; Sonti, R.
We document that seasoned equity issuers experiencing the greatest increase in institutional investment around the offer date outperformed their benchmark portfolios in the year following the issue by a statistically and economically significant margin relative to those experiencing the greatest decrease. No such relationship exists for a control sample of matched non-issuers. Issuers with the greatest institutional investment are also found to have the highest ratio of sell-side analyst upgrades less downgrades to total forecasts in the two quarters following the issue. Again, no such relationship is found for matched non-issuers. We interpret our results as evidence that institutions are able to identify above-average seasoned equity offering SEO firms at the time of equity issuance and increase their holdings in these potential outperformers. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gibson, S.; Safieddine, A.; Sonti, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tick size, NYSE rule 118, and ex-dividend day stock price behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jakob, K.; Ma, T. S.
Bali and Hite (1998) and Dubofsky (1992) propose models in which market microstructure effects play a role in the ex-dividend day price drop anomaly. Bali and Hite suggest that the anomaly is caused solely by price discreteness, while Dubofsky suggests that NYSE Rule 118 is also involved. We test these models by examining cum- to ex-day price drops during the one-eighth, one-sixteenth, and decimal tick size regimes. While the evidence is qualitatively consistent with Dubofsky's predictions, neither model is satisfactory in a quantitative sense. One of our main empirical findings is that no significant decline was evident in the magnitude of the ex-day anomaly after the tick size reduction. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jakob, K.; Ma, T. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling the bid/ask spread: measuring the inventory-holding premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, N. P. B.; Smith, T.; Whaley, R. E.
The need to understand and measure the determinants of market maker bid/ask spreads is crucial in evaluating the merits of competing market structures and the fairness of market maker rents. This study develops a simple, parsimonious model for the market maker's spread that accounts for the effects of price discreteness induced by minimum tick size, order-processing costs, inventory-holding costs, adverse selection, and competition. The inventory-holding and adverse selection cost components of spread are modeled as an option with a stochastic time to expiration. This inventory-holding premium embedded in the spread represents compensation for the price risk borne by the market maker while the security is held in inventory. The premium is partitioned in such a way that the inventory-holding and adverse selection cost components, as well as the probability of an informed trade, are identified. The model is tested empirically using Nasdaq stocks in three distinct minimum tick size regimes and is shown to perform well both in an absolute sense and relative to competing specifications. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bollen, N. P. B.; Smith, T.; Whaley, R. E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The illiquidity puzzle: theory and evidence from private equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lerner, J.; Schoar, A.
This paper presents the theory that managers can use the liquidity of securities as a choice variable to screen for deep-pocket investors, those that have a low likelihood of facing a liquidity shock. We assume an information asymmetry about the quality of the manager between the existing investors and the market. The manager then faces a lemons problem when he has to-raise funds for a subsequent fund from outside investors, because the outsiders cannot determine whether the manager is of poor quality or the existing investors were hit by a liquidity shock. Thus, liquid investors can reduce the manager's cost of capital in future fundraising. We test the assumptions and predictions of our model in the context of the private equity industry. Consistent with the theory, we find that transfer restrictions on investors are less common in later funds organized by the same private equity firm, where information problems are presumably less severe. Also, partnerships whose investment focus is in industries with longer investment cycles display more transfer constraints. Finally, we present evidence consistent with the assumptions of our model, including the high degree of continuity in the investors of successive funds and the ability of sophisticated investors to anticipate funds that will have poor subsequent performance. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lerner, J.; Schoar, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Management turnover in subsidiaries of conglomerates versus stand-alone firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McNeil, C.; Niehaus, G.; Powers, E.
We compare turnover of subsidiary managers inside conglomerate firms to turnover of CEO's of comparable stand-alone firms. We find that, compared to turnover of CEOs, subsidiary manager turnover is significantly more sensitive to changes in performance and significantly more likely following poor performance. For subsidiary managers, the relation between turnover and performance is significantly stronger when the subsidiary operates in an industry that is related to the parent's primary industry. Results suggest that boards of directors are relatively ineffective disciplinarians of CEOs and despite their other apparent failings, conglomerate firms have relatively strict disciplining mechanisms for subsidiary managers. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McNeil, C.; Niehaus, G.; Powers, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The timing and terms of mergers motivated by economies of scale</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, B. M.
This paper analyzes the timing of mergers motivated by economies of scale. We show that firms have an incentive to merge in periods of economic expansion. Relaxing the assumption that firms are price takers, we find that market power strengthens the firms' incentive to merge and speeds up merger activity. Finally, comparing mergers with hostile takeovers we show that the way merger synergies are divided not only influences the acquirer's and the acquiree's returns from merging, but also the timing of the restructuring. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lambrecht, B. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of capital market characteristics on the value of start-up firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, R.; Muller, H. M.
We develop an equilibrium model of contracting, bargaining, and search in which the relative scarcity of venture capital affects the bargaining power of entrepreneurs and venture capitalists. This in turn affects the pricing, contracting, and value creation in start-ups. The relative scarcity of venture capital is endogenous and depends on the profitability of venture capital investments, entry costs, and transparency of the venture capital market. Supply and demand conditions also affect the incentives of venture capitalists to screen projects ex ante. We characterize both the short- and long-run dynamics of the venture capital industry, which provides us with a stylized picture of the Internet boom and bust periods. Our model is consistent with existing evidence and provides a number of new empirical predictions. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Inderst, R.; Muller, H. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Data-generating process uncertainty: What difference does it make in portfolio decisions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tu, J.; Zhou, G. F.
As the usual normality assumption is firmly rejected by the data, investors encounter a data-generating process (DGP) uncertainty in making investment decisions. In this paper, we propose a novel way to incorporate uncertainty about the DGP into portfolio analysis. We find that accounting for fat tails leads to nontrivial changes in both parameter estimates and optimal portfolio weights, but the certainty-equivalent losses associated with ignoring fat tails are small. This Suggests that the normality assumption works well in evaluating portfolio performance for a mean-variance investor. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tu, J.; Zhou, G. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of government ownership on bank lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sapienza, P.
This paper uses information on individual loan contracts to Study the effects of government ownership on bank lending behavior. State-owned banks charge lower interest rates than do privately owned banks to similar or identical firms, even if firms are able to borrow more from privately owned banks. State-owned banks mostly favor large firms and firms located in depressed areas. The lending behavior of state-owned banks is affected by the electoral results of the party affiliated with the bank: the stronger the political party in the area where the firm is borrowing, the lower the interest rates charged. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sapienza, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The importance of the loss function in option valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, P.; Jacobs, K.
Which loss function should be used when estimating and evaluating option valuation models? Many different functions have been suggested, but no standard has emerged. We emphasize that consistency in the choice of loss functions is crucial. First, for any given model, the loss function used in parameter estimation and model evaluation should be the same, otherwise suboptimal parameter estimates may be obtained. Second, when comparing models, the estimation loss function should be identical across models, otherwise inappropriate comparisons will be made. We illustrate the importance of these issues in an application of the so-called Practitioner Black-Scholes model to S&amp;P 500 index options. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christoffersen, P.; Jacobs, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of corporate spin-offs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, T. J.; Yan, A.
We develop a new rationale for corporate spin-offs, and for the performance and value improvements following them, based on corporate control considerations. We consider a firm with multiple divisions, with incumbent management having different abilities for managing these divisions. If the incumbent loses control to a more able rival, it benefits all shareholders (including the incumbent) by increasing equity value, but involves the incumbent losing his private benefits of control. We show that a spin-off increases the incumbent's chance of losing control to such a rival. This, in turn, motivates the incumbent either to work harder at managing the firm (in order to avoid any loss of control), or to relinquish control of one of the firms resulting from the spin-off (either immediately following the spin-off, or subsequently in a control contest). We show that spin-offs will be associated with positive announcement effects and increases in long-term operating performance. Further, certain categories of spin-offs will exhibit long-term positive abnormal stock returns. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chemmanur, T. J.; Yan, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the relationship between the conditional mean and volatility of stock returns: A latent VAR approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandt, M. W.; Kang, Q.
We model the conditional mean and volatility of stock returns as a latent VAR process to study their contemporaneous and intertemporal relationships in a flexible statistical framework and without relying on exogenous predictors. We find a strong and robust negative correlation between the innovations to the conditional moments leading to pronounced countercyclical variation in the Sharpe ratio. We document significant lead-lag correlations between the moments that also appear related to business cycles. Finally, we show that although the conditional correlation between the mean and volatility is negative, the unconditional correlation is positive due to these lead-lag correlations. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brandt, M. W.; Kang, Q.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO reputation and stock-based compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milbourn, T. T.
I develop a theory of stock-based compensation contracts for the chief executive officers (CEOs) of firms and confront the theoretical predictions with recent CEO compensation data. The model characterizes the optimal contract for a CEO whose reputation evolves as signals of the executive's ability are observed by shareholders. Using various proxies for CEO reputation, I show a positive and economically meaningful relationship between stock-based pay-sensitivities and CEO reputation. The findings are robust to controls for CEO age, firm size, the dollar, variability of the stock returns, and industry effects. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Milbourn, T. T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Style investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barberis, N.; Shleifer, A.
We study asset prices in an economy where some investors categorize risky assets into different styles and move funds among these styles depending on their relative performance. In our economy, assets in the same style comove too much, assets in different styles comove too little, and reclassifying an asset into a new style raises its correlation with that style. We also predict that style returns exhibit a rich pattern of own- and cross-autocorrelations and that while asset-level momentum and value strategies are profitable, their style-level counterparts are even more so. We use the model to shed light on several style-related empirical anomalies. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barberis, N.; Shleifer, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-horizon regressions: theoretical results and applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Valkanov, R.
I use asymptotic arguments to show that the t-statistics in long-horizon regressions do not converge to well-defined distributions. In some cases, moreover, the ordinary least squares estimator is not consistent and the R 2 is an inadequate measure of the goodness of fit. These findings can partially explain the tendency, of long-horizon regressions to find "significant" results where previous short-term approaches find none. I propose a rescaled t-statistic, whose asymptotic distribution is easy to simulate, and revisit some of the long-horizon evidence on return predictability and of the Fisher effect. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Valkanov, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Founding family ownership and the agency cost of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, R. C.; Mansi, S. A.; Reeb, D. M.
We investigate the impact of founding family ownership structure on the agency cost of debt. We find that founding family ownership is common in large, publicly traded firms and is related, both statistically and economically, to a lower cost of debt financing. Our results are consistent with the idea that founding family firms have incentive structures that result in fewer agency conflicts between equity and. debt claimants. This suggests that bond holders view founding family ownership as an organizational structure that better protects their interests. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anderson, R. C.; Mansi, S. A.; Reeb, D. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A closing call's impact on market quality at Euronext Paris</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pagano, M. S.; Schwartz, R. A.
The Paris Bourse (currently Euronext Paris) refined its trading system to include electronic call auctions at market closings in 1996 for its less-liquid Continuous B stocks and in 1998 for its more actively traded Continuous A stocks. This paper analyzes the effects of the innovation on market quality. Our empirical analysis of price behavior for two samples of firms (50 B stocks and 50 A stocks) for two different calendar dates (1996 and 1998) indicates that introduction of the closing calls has lowered execution costs for individual participants and sharpened price discovery for the broad market. We further observe that market quality is improved at market openings, albeit to a lesser extent. We suggest that a positive spillover effect explains the closing call's more pervasive impact. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pagano, M. S.; Schwartz, R. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and firm profitability: evidence from Korea before the economic crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joh, S. W.
This study examines how ownership structure and conflicts of interest among shareholders under a poor corporate governance system affected firm performance before the crisis. Using 5,829 Korean firms subject to outside auditing during 1993-1997, the paper finds that firms with low ownership concentration show low firm profitability, controlling for firm and industry characteristics. Controlling shareholders expropriated firm resources even when their ownership concentration was small. Firms with a high disparity between control rights and ownership rights showed low profitability. When a business group transferred resources from a subsidiary to another, they were often wasted, suggesting that "tunneling" occurred. In addition, the negative effects of control- ownership disparity and internal capital market inefficiency were stronger in publicly traded firms than in privately held ones. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Joh, S. W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The marketing role of IPOs: evidence from internet stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demers, E.; Lewellen, K.
This paper explores the potential marketing benefits of going public and of IPO underpricing. We examine the impact of IPO underpricing on website traffic, which is a direct measure of product market performance for internet firms. If underpricing attracts media attention and creates valuable publicity, we expect an increase in web traffic following the IPO. We find that web traffic growth in the month after the IPO is positively and significantly associated with initial returns, and the effect is economically significant. We also investigate media reaction to initial returns for a broader sample of IPOs. The results suggest that the marketing benefits of underpricing extend beyond the internet sector and the "hot issues" market of the late 1990s. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Demers, E.; Lewellen, K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debtor-in-possession financing and bankruptcy resolution: Empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahiya, S.; John, K.; Puri, M.; Ramirez, G.
Debtor-in-possession (DIP) financing is unique secured financing available to firms filing for Chapter 11. Opponents of DIP financing argue that it leads to overinvestment. Alternatively, DIP financing can allow funding for positive net present value projects that increase the likelihood of reorganization and reduce time in bankruptcy. Using a large sample of bankruptcy filings, we find little evidence of systematic overinvestment. DIP financed firms are more likely to emerge from Chapter 11 than non-DIP financed firms. DIP financed firms have a shorter reorganization period; they are quicker to emerge and also quicker to liquidate. The reorganization period is even shorter when prior lenders provide the DIP financing. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dahiya, S.; John, K.; Puri, M.; Ramirez, G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Control benefits and CEO discipline in automatic bankruptcy auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckbo, B. E.; Thorburn, K. S.
Swedish bankruptcy filing automatically terminates the employment of the chief executive officer (CEO) and triggers an auction of the firm. Critics of this system warn of excessive shareholder risk-shifting incentives prior to filing. We argue that private benefits of control induce managerial conservatism that may override shareholder risk-shifting incentives. By investing conservatively, the CEO increases the joint probability that the auction results in a going-concern sale and that the CEO is rehired. This uniquely implies that the rehiring probability is increasing in private control benefits, which our empirical results support. We also find that buyers in the auction screen on CEO quality. Overall, labor market discipline is dramatic, as filing CEOs suffer large income losses relative to CEOs of matched, non-bankrupt firms, Finns emerging from auction bankruptcy appear healthy as they typically go on to perform at par with industry rivals. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eckbo, B. E.; Thorburn, K. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance, investment, and growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlin, W.; Mayer, C.
This paper examines the relation between the institutional structures of advanced OECD countries and the comparative growth and investment of 27 industries in those countries over the period 1970 to 1995. The paper reports a strong relation between the structure of countries' financial systems, the characteristics of industries, and the growth and investment of industries in different countries. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carlin, W.; Mayer, C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive stock option repricing, internal governance mechanisms, and management turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chidambaran, N. K.; Prabhala, N. R.
We examine firms that reprice their executive stock options and find little evidence that repricing reflects managerial entrenchment or ineffective governance. Repricing grants are economically significant, but there is little else unusual about compensation in repricing firms. Repricers tend to be smaller, younger, rapidly growing firms that experience a deep, sudden shock to growth and profitability. They are also more concentrated in the technology, trade, and service sectors and have smaller boards of directors. Repricers have abnormally high CEO turnover rates, which is inconsistent with the entrenchment hypothesis. Over 40% of repricers exclude the CEO's options when they reprice. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chidambaran, N. K.; Prabhala, N. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance and boards of directors in closed-end investment companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Del Guercio, D.; Dann, L. Y.; Partch, M. M.
We analyze whether board structure and director independence in closed-end investment companies are related to shareholder interests in ways that are consistent with boards being effective monitors. We report that funds with relatively low expense ratios, one measure of board effectiveness, have smaller boards, a higher proportion of board members who are legally considered independent, relatively low director compensation, and charter provisions that specify remedial action if discounts become large. Evidence from our analysis of major fund restructuring decisions, including share repurchases, open-ending proposals and right offerings, is largely consistent with the expense ratio analysis. Overall, board characteristics that we identify with effective board independence are associated with lower expense ratios and value-enhancing restructurings. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Del Guercio, D.; Dann, L. Y.; Partch, M. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Control as a motivation for underpricing: a comparison of dual and single-class IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smart, S. B.; Zutter, C. J.
We find that dual-class firms experience less underpricing than single-class firms and explore several hypotheses which explain this phenomenon. Compared to single-class firms, dual-class companies have slightly higher post-IPO institutional ownership and experience fewer control events. Although dual-class firms achieve a lower underpricing cost, they trade at lower prices relative to earnings and sales than single-class IPOs. This pricing differential, combined with evidence that dual-class managers earn higher compensation and that dual-class shares are common among media and entertainment industry IPOs, suggests that dual-class ownership structures protect private control benefits. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Smart, S. B.; Zutter, C. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Takeover bids and target directors' incentives: the impact of a bid on directors' wealth and board seats</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, J.
I investigate the nature of the incentives that lead outside directors to serve stockholders' interests. Specifically, I document the effect of a takeover bid on target directors, both in terms of its immediate financial impact and its effect on the number of future board seats held by those target directors. Directors are rarely retained following a completed offer. All target directors hold fewer directorships in the future than a control group, suggesting that the target board seat is difficult to replace. For outside directors, the direct financial impact of a completed merger is predominately negative. This documents a cost to outside directors should they fail as monitors, forcing the external control market to act for them. Future seats are related to pre-bid performance. Among outside directors of poorly performing firms, those who rebuff an offer face partial settling-up in the directorial labor market, while those who complete the merger do not. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harford, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The great reversals: the politics of financial development in the twentieth century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajan, R. G.; Zingales, L.
The state of development of the financial sector does not change monotonically over time. In particular, by most measures, countries were more financially developed in 1913 than in 1980 and only recently have they surpassed their 1913 levels. To explain these changes, we propose an interest group theory of financial development where incumbents oppose financial development because it breeds competition. The theory predicts that incumbents' opposition will be weaker when an economy allows both cross-border trade and capital flows. This theory can go some way in accounting for the cross-country differences in, and the time-series variation of, financial development. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rajan, R. G.; Zingales, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special issue - Tuck Symposium on Corporate Governance - Preface</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. W.; Eckbo, B. E.
nan</description><author>Schwert, G. W.; Eckbo, B. E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure and product markets interactions: evidence from business cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, M.
This paper provides firm- and industry-level evidence of the effects of capital structure on product market outcomes for a large cross-section of industries over a number of years. The analysis uses shocks to aggregate demand as surrogates for exogenous changes in the product market environment. I find that debt financing has a negative impact on firm (relative-to-industry) sales growth in industries in which rivals are relatively unlevered during recessions, but not during booms. In contrast, no such effects are observed for firms competing in high-debt industries. At the industry level, markups are more countercyclical when industry debt is high. The cyclical dynamics I find for firm sales growth and for industry markups are consistent with Chevalier and Scharfstein's (American Economic Review (1996)) prediction that firms which rely heavily on external financing are more likely to cut their investment in market share building in response to negative shocks to demand and that the competitive outcomes resulting from such actions depend on the financial structures of their industry rivals. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campello, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of corporate voting rights and control: A cross-country analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nenova, T.
This paper measures the value of corporate voting rights, specifically of the control block of votes, in a sample of 661 dual-class firms in 18 countries, in 1997. A consistent measure across countries is proposed. The measure is adjusted for takeover probability, block-holding costs, and dividend and liquidity differences between the share classes. The value of controlblock votes varies widely across countries. It is close to half of firm market value in South Korea, and close to zero in Finland. The value of control-block votes is interpreted as a lower bound for actual private benefits of the controlling shareholder. The legal environment, law enforcement, investor protection, takeover regulations, and power-concentrating corporate charter provisions explain 68% of the cross-country variation in the value of control-block votes. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nenova, T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cronyism and capital controls: evidence from Malaysia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, S.; Mitton, T.
The onset of the Asian financial crisis in Malaysia reduced the expected value of government subsidies to politically connected firms, accounting for roughly 9% of the estimated $60 billion loss in their market value from July 1997 to August 1998. Firing the Deputy Prime Minister and imposing capital controls in September 1998 primarily benefited firms with strong ties to Prime Minister Mahathir, accounting for roughly 32% of these firms' estimated $5 billion gain in market value during September 1998. The evidence suggests Malaysian capital controls provided a screen behind which favored firms could be supported. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Johnson, S.; Mitton, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do family strategies affect fund performance? When performance-maximization is not the only game in town</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, M.
This is a first attempt to study how the structure of the industry affects mutual fund behavior. I show that industry structure matters; the mutual fund families employ strategies that rely on the heterogeneity of the investors in terms of investment horizon by offering the possibility to switch across different funds belonging to the same family at no cost. I argue that this option acts as an externality for all the funds belonging to the same family, affecting the target level of performance the family wants to reach and the number of funds it wants to set up. By using the universe of the U.S. mutual fund industry, I empirically confirm this intuition. I find evidence of family driven heterogeneity among funds and show that families actively exploit it. I argue that the more families are able to differentiate themselves in terms of non-performance-related characteristics, the less they need to compete in terms of performance. Product differentiation-i.e., the dispersion in the "services" (fees, performance) that the competing funds offer-affects performance and fund proliferation. In particular, I show that the degree of product differentiation negatively affects performance and positively affects fund proliferation. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Massa, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing the pecking order theory of capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frank, M. Z.; Goyal, V. K.
We test the pecking order theory of corporate leverage on a broad cross-section of publicly traded American firms for 1971 to 1998. Contrary to the pecking order theory, net equity issues track the financing deficit more closely than do net debt issues. While large firms exhibit some aspects of pecking order behavior, the evidence is not robust to the inclusion of conventional leverage factors, nor to the analysis of evidence from the 1990s. Financing deficit is less important in explaining net debt issues over time for firms of all sizes. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frank, M. Z.; Goyal, V. K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The personal-tax advantages of equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, R. C.; Hollifield, B.
We value a firm that pays its cash flows to equity through share repurchases in a dynamic environment where personal taxes are paid on capital gains upon realization. The cost of capital is reduced by approximately 0.8% through the use of repurchases relative to dividends. We use the empirical distribution of pre-tax free cash flows in Fama and French (1999) to evaluate the tradeoffs between the costs of financial distress, the personal-tax advantages of equity, and the corporate-tax advantage to debt. The optimal capital structure is interior with a 3% bankruptcy cost. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Green, R. C.; Hollifield, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive rank, pay and project selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barron, J. M.; Waddell, G. R.
This paper extends the literature on executive compensation by developing and testing a principal-agent model in the context of project selection. The model's focus on executive project selection decisions highlights the multidimensional nature of executive choices that affect the value of the firm. An executive not only makes an effort choice that determines the quality of information on which to base a decision but also sets the decision criteria for selecting projects. A project selection framework is also shown to introduce endogenous uncertainty into compensation that can influence the executive's effort choice. Using an extensive data set, our empirical work supports the main hypotheses of the model, including the significance of executive rank in determining the extent of use of incentive pay in general and equity-based incentive pay in particular. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barron, J. M.; Waddell, G. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Concealing and confounding adverse signals: insider wealth-maximizing behavior in the IPO process</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, J. S.; Brau, J. C.
We study a known negative signal, the sale of insider shares in an IPO and find that insiders adopt two concealment strategies consistent with wealth-maximizing behavior. First, insiders underreport the number of personally owned shares in the prominent original prospectus and use an obscure amendment to communicate the true higher level of shares to be offered. Second, when insiders increase shares in a later amendment, they tend to either increase secondary shares disproportional to primary share increases, or to reduce primary shares to wholly or partly conceal the increase in secondary shares offered. Insiders confound the negative secondary share signal by simultaneously sending a positive lockup signal. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, J. S.; Brau, J. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation effects of bank financing in acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bharadwaj, A.; Shivdasani, A.
in a sample of 115 cash tender offers between 1990 and 1996, banks extend financing in 70% of the tender offers and finance the entire tender offer in half of these takeovers. Bank financing of tender offers is more likely when internal cash reserves are low. Acquisitions that are entirely financed by banks are associated with large and significantly positive acquirer announcement returns. Announcement returns are also positively related to the fraction of the acquisition value financed by bank debt. The benefits of bank financing are most important for both poorly performing acquirers and acquirers facing substantial informational asymmetries. Our results suggest that bank debt performs an important certification and monitoring role for acquirers in tender offers. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bharadwaj, A.; Shivdasani, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firms and their distressed banks: lessons from the Norwegian banking crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ongena, S.; Smith, D. C.; Michalsen, D.
We use the near-collapse of the Norwegian banking system during the period 1988-1991 to measure the impact of bank distress announcements on the stock prices of firms maintaining a relationship with a distressed bank. Although banks experienced large and permanent downward revisions in their equity value during the event period, firms maintaining relationships with these banks faced only small and temporary changes, on average, in stock price. Firms with access to unused liquid bank funds and firms that issued equity just prior to the crisis experience relatively high abnormal returns. Overall, the aggregate impact of bank distress appears small. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ongena, S.; Smith, D. C.; Michalsen, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A multivariate model of strategic asset allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, J. Y.; Chan, Y. L.; Viceira, L. M.
We develop an approximate solution method for the optimal consumption and portfolio choice problem of an infinitely long-lived investor with Epstein-Zin utility who faces a set of asset returns described by a vector autoregression in returns and state variables. Empirical estimates in long-run annual and post-war quarterly U.S. data suggest that the predictability of stock returns greatly increases the optimal demand for stocks. The role of nominal bonds in long-term portfolios depends on the importance of real interest rate risk relative to other sources of risk. Long-term intlation-indexed bonds greatly increase the utility of conservative investors. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campbell, J. Y.; Chan, Y. L.; Viceira, L. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why does IPO volume fluctuate so much?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lowry, M.
IPO volume fluctuates substantially over time. This paper compares the extent to which the aggregate capital demands of private firms, the adverse-selection costs of issuing equity, and the level of investor optimism can explain these fluctuations. Empirical tests include both aggregate and industry-level time-series regressions using proxies for the above factors and an analysis of the relation between post-IPO stock returns and IPO volume. Results indicate that firms' demands for capital and investor sentiment are important determinants of IPO volume, in both statistical and economic terms. Adverse-selection costs are also statistically significant, but their economic effect appears small. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Lowry, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Allocations, adverse selection, and cascades in IPOs: evidence from the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amihud, Y.; Hauser, S.; Kirsh, A.
We examine theories of IPO underpricing using unique data from Israel where the allocation to subscribers is by equal proration. This enables us to simulate the return earned by uninformed investors. Consistent with Rock's (1986) theory of adverse selection, allocations were negatively related to underpricing. But uninformed investors earned a negative allocalion-weighted initial return, although the average initial return was 12%. They could break even, however, by using publicly available information. The data also supports Welch's (1992) theory of information cascades: demand is either extremely high or there is undersubscription, with very few cases in between. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Amihud, Y.; Hauser, S.; Kirsh, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Allocation of initial public offerings and flipping activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, R.
There is a general perception that the large trading volume in initial public offerings is mostly due to "flippers" that are allocated shares in the offering and immediately resell them. On average, however, flipping accounts for only 19% of trading volume and 15% of shares offered during the first two days of trading. Institutions do more flipping than retail customers and hot IPOs are flipped much more than cold IPOs. Institutions do not quickly flip cold IPOs to take advantage of price support activities by the underwriter. Explicit penalty bids are rarely assessed against flippers. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure choice: macroeconomic conditions and financial constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korajczyk, R. A.; Levy, A.
This paper provides new evidence of how macroeconomic conditions affect capital structure choice. We model firms' target capital structures as a function of macroeconomic conditions and firm-specific variables. We split our sample based on a measure of financial constraints. Target leverage is counter-cyclical for the relatively unconstrained sample, but pro-cyclical for the relatively constrained sample. Macroeconomic conditions are significant for issue choice for unconstrained firms but less so for constrained firms. Our results support the hypothesis that unconstrained firms time their issue choice to coincide with periods of favorable macroeconomic conditions, while constrained firms do not. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Korajczyk, R. A.; Levy, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News related to future GDP growth as a risk factor in equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vassalou, M.
A model that includes a factor that captures news related to future Gross Domestic Product (GDP) growth along with the market factor can explain the cross-section of equity returns about as well as the Fama-French model can. Furthermore, the Fama-French factors HML and SMB appear to contain mainly news related to future GDP growth. When news related to future GDP growth is present in the asset-pricing model, HML and SMB lose much of their ability to explain the cross-section. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vassalou, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Voting with their feet: institutional ownership changes around forced CEO turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parrino, R.; Sias, R. W.; Starks, L. T.
We investigate whether institutional investors "vote with their feet" when dissatisfied with a firm's management by examining changes in equity ownership around forced CEO turnover. We find that aggregate institutional ownership and the number of institutional investors decline in the year prior to forced CEO turnover. However, selling by institutions is far from universal. Overall, there is an increase in shareholdings of individual investors and a decrease in holdings of institutional investors who are more concerned with holding prudent securities, are better informed, or are engaged in momentum trading. Measures of institutional ownership changes are negatively related to the likelihoods of forced CEO turnover and that an executive from outside the firm is appointed CEO. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Parrino, R.; Sias, R. W.; Starks, L. T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium and welfare in markets with financially constrained arbitrageurs (vol 66, pg 361, 2002)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gromb, D.; Vayanos, D.
nan</description><author>Gromb, D.; Vayanos, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A barrier option framework for corporate security valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, P.; Turtle, H. J.
This paper proposes a framework for corporate security valuation based on path-dependent, barrier option models instead of the commonly used path-independent approach. We argue that path dependency is an intrinsic and fundamental characteristic of corporate securities because equity can be knocked out whenever a legally binding barrier is breached. A direct implication of this framework is that equity will be priced as a down-and-out call option. We provide empirical validation of the barrier model by showing that implied barriers are statistically and economically significant for a large cross-section of industrial firms. Additional robustness tests confirm that barriers remain significant over a wide range of input variable estimates. And finally, we apply the barrier option framework to bankruptcy prediction and find that implied failure probabilities dominate Z-scores in most cases. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brockman, P.; Turtle, H. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economic value of volatility timing using "realized" volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleming, J.; Kirby, C.; Ostdiek, B.
Recent work suggests that intradaily returns can be used to construct estimates of daily return volatility that are more precise than those constructed using daily returns. We measure the economic value of this "realized" volatility approach in the context of investment decisions. Our results indicate that the value of switching from daily to intradaily returns to estimate the conditional covariance matrix can be substantial. We estimate that a risk-averse investor would be willing to pay 50 to 200 basis points per year to capture the observed gains in portfolio performance. Moreover, these gains are robust to transaction costs, estimation risk regarding expected returns, and the performance measurement horizon. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fleming, J.; Kirby, C.; Ostdiek, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Universal option valuation using quadrature methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andricopoulos, A. D.; Widdicks, M.; Duck, P. W.; Newton, D. P.
This paper proposes and develops a novel, simple, widely applicable numerical approach for option pricing based on quadrature methods. Though in some ways similar to lattice or finite-difference schemes, it possesses exceptional accuracy and speed. Discretely monitored options are valued with only one timestep between observations, and nodes can be perfectly placed in relation to discontinuities. Convergence is improved greatly; in the extrapolated scheme, a doubling of points can reduce error by a factor of 256. Complex problems (e.g., fixed-strike lookback discrete barrier options) can be evaluated accurately and orders of magnitude faster than by existing methods. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Andricopoulos, A. D.; Widdicks, M.; Duck, P. W.; Newton, D. P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do equity financing cycles matter? evidence from biotechnology alliances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lerner, J.; Shane, H.; Tsai, A.
In periods characterized by diminished public market financing, small biotechnology firms appear to be more likely to fund R&amp;D through alliances with major corporations rather than with internal funds (raised through the capital markets). We consider 200 alliance agreements entered into by biotechnology firms between 1980 and 1995. Agreements signed during periods of limited external equity financing are more likely to assign the bulk of the control to the larger corporate partner, and are significantly less successful than other alliances. These agreements are also disproportionately likely to be renegotiated if financial market conditions subsequently improve. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lerner, J.; Shane, H.; Tsai, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Paper millionaires: how valuable is stock to a stockholder who is restricted from selling it?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahl, M.; Liu, J.; Longstaff, F. A.
Many firms have stockholders who face severe restrictions on their ability to sell their shares and diversify the risk of their personal wealth. We study the costs of these liquidity restrictions on stockholders using a continuous-time portfolio choice framework. These restrictions have major effects on the optimal investment and consumption strategies because of the need to hedge the illiquid stock position and smooth consumption in anticipation of the eventual lapse of the restrictions. These results provide a number of important insights about the effects of illiquidity in financial markets. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kahl, M.; Liu, J.; Longstaff, F. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payment for order flow</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parlour, C. A.; Rajan, U.
We develop a dynamic model of price competition in broker and dealer markets. With no payment for order flow, a zero-profit equilibrium exists. With payment for order flow, spreads widen to more than compensate for this payment; hence, there is no equilibrium in which market makers earn zero profits. While brokerage commissions for market orders can fall, the total transactions cost to submitting a market order remains positive. Consumer and social welfare are both lower in any equilibrium with payment for order flow; payment for order flow redistributes payoffs from traders who demand liquidity to those who supply it. (C) 2003 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Parlour, C. A.; Rajan, U.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>China share issue privatization: the extent of its success</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Q.; Tong, W. H. S.
We evaluate the performance changes of 634 state-owned enterprises (SOEs) listed on China's two exchanges upon share issuing privatisation (SIP) in the period 1994-1998. We find that SIP is effective in improving SOEs' earnings ability, real sales, and workers' productivity but is not successful in improving profit returns and leverage after privatisation. We also find state ownership having negative impacts on firm performance and legal-person ownership having positive impacts on firm performance after SIP, which suggests that legal persons behave differently from the state government. Surprisingly, foreign ownership does not show uniformly strong, positive impacts on firm performance. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Q.; Tong, W. H. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic derivative strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, J.; Pan, J.
We study optimal investment strategies given investor access not only to bond and stock markets but also to the derivatives market. The problem is solved in closed form. Derivatives extend the risk and return tradeoffs associated with stochastic volatility and price jumps. As a means of exposure to volatility risk, derivatives enable non-myopic investors to exploit the time-varying opportunity set; and as a means of exposure to jump risk, they enable investors to disentangle the simultaneous exposure to diffusive and jump risks in the stock market. Calibrating to the S&amp;P 500 index and options markets, we find sizable portfolio improvement from derivatives investing. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, J.; Pan, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Termination fees in mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Officer, M. S.
The paper provides evidence on the effects of including a target termination fee in a merger contract. I test the implications of the hypothesis that termination fees are used by self-interested target managers to deter competing bids and protect "sweetheart" deals with white knight bidders, presumably resulting in lower premiums for target shareholders. An alternative hypothesis is that target managers use termination fees to encourage bidder participation by ensuring that the bidder is compensated for the revelation of valuable private information released during merger negotiations. My empirical evidence demonstrates that merger deals with target termination fees involve significantly higher premiums and success rates than deals without such clauses. Furthermore, only weak support is found for the contention that termination fees deter competing bids. Overall, the evidence suggests that termination fee use is at least not harmful, and is likely beneficial, to target shareholders. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Officer, M. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Breaking up is hard to do? An analysis of termination fee provisions and merger outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, T. W.; Lemmon, M. L.
We examine the provision of termination fee clauses in merger agreements between 1989 and 1998. Target-payable fees are observed more frequently when bidding is costly and the potential for information expropriation by third parties is significant. Fee provisions appear to benefit target shareholders through higher deal completion rates and greater negotiated takeover premiums. We conclude that target-payable fees serve as an efficient contracting device, rather than a means by which to deter competitive bidding. Bidder fee provisions appear to be used to secure target wealth gains in deals with higher costs associated with negotiation and bid failure. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bates, T. W.; Lemmon, M. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management and investor protection: an international comparison</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leuz, C.; Nanda, D.; Wysocki, P. D.
This paper examines systematic differences in earnings management across 31 countries. We propose an explanation for these differences based on the notion that insiders, in an attempt to protect their private control benefits, use earnings management to conceal firm performance from outsiders. Thus, earnings management is expected to decrease in investor protection because strong protection limits insiders' ability to acquire private control benefits, which reduces their incentives to mask firm performance. Our findings are consistent with this prediction and suggest an endogenous link between corporate governance and the quality of reported earnings. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leuz, C.; Nanda, D.; Wysocki, P. D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The choice among bank debt, non-bank private debt, and public debt: evidence from new corporate borrowings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, D. J.; Mihov, V. T.
Using a sample of 1,560 new debt financings, we examine the choice among bank debt, non-bank private debt, and public debt. The primary determinant of the debt source is the credit quality of the issuer. Firms with the highest credit quality borrow from public sources, firms with medium credit quality borrow from banks, and firms with the lowest credit quality borrow from non-bank private lenders. Non-bank private debt thus plays a unique role in accommodating the financing needs of firms with low credit quality. In addition, the choice of debt source is (weakly) influenced by managerial discretion. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Denis, D. J.; Mihov, V. T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The calendar structure of risk and expected returns on stocks and bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ogden, J. P.
This paper documents, for 1947-2000, seasonalities in economic activity, stock and bond returns, and relationships among them. Evidence is consistent with an annual cycle view of economic activity and risk conditions. The power of lagged stock returns to forecast economic activity is greater for quarters ending in December and March. Mean excess returns on NYSE stocks in October through March account for 78-107% of their annual means and reflect a seasonal asymmetric return reversal tendency, which in turn explains low long-horizon variance ratios. Both market losses in April through September and subsequent returns in October through March are related, but with opposing signs, to October through March economic activity. The forecasting power of five variables is greatest for October through March. Tests of an asset-pricing model indicate that expected returns vary both cross-sectionally and over time. Implications for the debate between efficient markets and behavioral finance are discussed. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ogden, J. P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Divisional diversity and the conglomerate discount: evidence from spinoffs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burch, T. R.; Nanda, V.
Existing literature argues that disparity in investment opportunities within diversified firms can erode firm value. We investigate the diversity cost hypothesis of spinoffs by using post-spinoff data to (1) reconstruct the diversified firm after the spinoff and assess the aggregate improvement in value and (2) relate any value improvements to changes in diversity. We find that improvements in aggregate value depend significantly on changes in both a direct measure of diversity and measures based on industry proxies. We conclude that diversification discounts at least partially reflect a value loss due to the diversified nature of the firm itself, rather than selection bias or measurement error. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Burch, T. R.; Nanda, V.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>