<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFE5</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Tests of ex ante versus ex post theories of collateral using private and public information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Frame, W. Scott; Ioannidou, Vasso
Collateral is a widely used, but not well understood, debt contracting feature. Two broad strands of theoretical literature explain collateral as arising from the existence of either ex ante private information or ex post incentive problems between borrowers and lenders. However, the extant empirical literature has been unable to isolate each of these effects. This paper attempts to do so using a credit registry that is unique in that it allows the researcher to have access to some private information about borrower risk that is unobserved by the lender. The data also include public information about borrower risk, loan contract terms, and ex post performance for both secured and unsecured loans. The results suggest that the ex post theories of collateral are empirically dominant, although the ex ante theories are also valid for customers with short borrower-lender relations that are relatively unknown to the lender. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Frame, W. Scott; Ioannidou, Vasso</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do convertible issuers simultaneously repurchase stock? An arbitrage-based explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Jong, Abe; Dutordoir, Marie; Verwijmeren, Patrick
Over recent years, a substantial fraction of US convertible bond issues have been combined with a stock repurchase. This paper explores the motivations for these combined transactions. We argue that convertible debt issuers repurchase their stock to facilitate arbitrage-related short selling. In line with this prediction, we show that convertibles combined with a stock repurchase are associated with lower offering discounts, lower stock price pressure, higher expected hedging demand, and lower issue-date short selling than uncombined issues. We also find that convertible arbitrage strategies explain both the size and the speed of execution of the stock repurchases. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Jong, Abe; Dutordoir, Marie; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Research for sale: Determinants and consequences of paid-for analyst research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kirk, Marcus
I examine the determinants and market impact of paid-for coverage using a hand-collected sample of paid-for reports over 1999-2006. More than five hundred publicly listed US companies paid for analyst coverage since 1999. Yet little is known about the informational consequences of this analyst research. Firms with greater uncertainty, weaker information environments, and low turnover are more likely to buy coverage as they have the most to gain from analyst coverage but are unlikely to attract sell-side analysts. Despite the inherent conflicts of interest, I find paid-for reports have information content for investors based on 2-day abnormal returns. After the initiation of coverage, companies experience an increase in institutional ownership, sell-side analyst following, and liquidity. In addition, the results are strongest for the fee-based research firm with ex ante policies that reduce potential conflicts of interest. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kirk, Marcus</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price impact and portfolio impact</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Malamud, Semyon
We study survival, price impact, and portfolio impact in heterogeneous economies. We show that, under the equilibrium risk-neutral measure, long-run price impact is in fact equivalent to survival, whereas long-run portfolio impact is equivalent to survival under an agent-specific, wealth-forward measure. These results allow us to show that price impact and portfolio impact are two independent concepts: a nonsurviving agent with no long-run price impact can have a significant long-run impact on other agents' optimal portfolios. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Malamud, Semyon</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate investment and financing under asymmetric information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morellec, Erwan; Schuerhoff, Norman
We develop a dynamic model of corporate investment and financing decisions in which corporate insiders have superior information about the firm's growth prospects. We show that firms with positive private information can credibly signal their type to outside investors using the timing of corporate actions and their debt-equity mix. Using this result, we show that asymmetric information induces firms with good prospects to speed up investment, leading to a significant erosion of the option value of waiting to invest. Additionally, we demonstrate that informational asymmetries may not translate into a financing hierarchy or pecking order over securities. Finally, we generate a rich set of testable implications relating firms' investment and financing strategies, abnormal announcement returns, and external financing costs to a number of managerial, firm, and industry characteristics. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morellec, Erwan; Schuerhoff, Norman</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vintage capital and creditor protection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benmelech, Efraim; Bergman, Nittai K.
We provide novel evidence linking the level of creditor protection provided by law to the degree of usage of technologically older, vintage capital in the airline industry. Using a panel of aircraft-level data around the world, we find that better creditor rights are associated with both aircraft of a younger vintage and newer technology, as well as firms with larger aircraft fleets. We propose that by mitigating financial shortfalls, enhanced legal protection of creditors facilitates the ability of firms to make large capital investments, adapt advanced technologies, and foster productivity. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benmelech, Efraim; Bergman, Nittai K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification disasters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibragimov, Rustam; Jaffee, Dwight; Walden, Johan
The recent financial crisis has revealed significant externalities and systemic risks that arise from the interconnectedness of financial intermediaries' risk portfolios. We develop a model in which the negative externality arises because intermediaries' actions to diversify that are optimal for individual intermediaries may prove to be suboptimal for society. We show that the externality depends critically on the distributional properties of the risks. The optimal social outcome involves less risk-sharing, but also a lower probability for massive collapses of intermediaries. We derive the exact conditions under which risk-sharing restrictions create a socially preferable outcome. Our analysis has implications for regulation of financial institutions and risk management. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ibragimov, Rustam; Jaffee, Dwight; Walden, Johan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of corporate financial decisions with liquidity and solvency concerns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gryglewicz, Sebastian
This paper studies the impact of both liquidity and solvency concerns on corporate finance. I present a tractable model of a firm that optimally chooses capital structure, cash holdings, dividends, and default while facing cash flows with long-term uncertainty and short-term liquidity shocks. The model explains how changes in solvency affect liquidity and also how liquidity concerns affect solvency via capital structure choice. These interactions result in a dynamic cash policy in which cash reserves increase in profitability and are positively correlated with cash flows. The optimal dividend distributions implied by the model are smoothed relative to cash flows. I also find that liquidity concerns lead to a decrease of dispersion of credit spreads. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gryglewicz, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>General equilibrium pricing of options with habit formation and event risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Du
This paper proposes a general equilibrium model that explains the pricing of the S&amp;P 500 index options. The central ingredients are a peso component in the consumption growth rate and the time-varying risk aversion induced by habit formation which amplifies consumption shocks. The amplifying effect generates the excess volatility and a large jump-risk premium which combine to produce a pronounced volatility smirk for index options. The time-varying volatility and jump-risk premiums explain the observed state-dependent smirk patterns. Besides volatility smirks, the model has a variety of other implications which are broadly consistent with the aggregate stock and option market data. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Du, Du</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do hedge funds trade on private information? Evidence from syndicated lending and short-selling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massoud, Nadia; Nandy, Debarshi; Saunders, Anthony; Song, Keke
This paper investigates an important contemporary issue relating to the involvement of hedge funds in the syndicated loan market. In particular, we investigate the potential conflicts of interest that arise when hedge funds make syndicated loans and take short positions in the equity of borrowing firms. We find evidence consistent with the short-selling of the equity of the hedge fund borrowers prior to public announcements of both loan originations and loan amendments. We also find that hedge funds are more likely to lend to highly leveraged, lower credit quality firms, where access to private information is potentially the most valuable and where trading on such information could lead to enhanced profits. Overall, our results have important implications for the current debate regarding regulating the hedge fund industry. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Massoud, Nadia; Nandy, Debarshi; Saunders, Anthony; Song, Keke</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional demand pressure and the cost of corporate loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivashina, Victoria; Sun, Zheng
Between 2001 and 2007, annual institutional funding in highly leveraged loans went up from $32 billion to $426 billion, accounting for nearly 70% of the jump in total syndicated loan issuance over the same period. Did the inflow of institutional funding in the syndicated loan market lead to mispricing of credit? To understand this relation, we look at the institutional demand pressure defined as the number of days a loan remains in syndication. Using market-level and cross-sectional variation in time-on-the-market, we find that a shorter syndication period is associated with a lower final interest rate. The relation is robust to the use of institutional fund flow as an instrument. Furthermore, we find significant price differences between institutional investors' tranches and banks' tranches of the same loans, even though they share the same underlying fundamentals. Increasing demand pressure causes the interest rate on institutional tranches to fall below the interest rate on bank tranches. Overall, a one-standard-deviation reduction in average time-on-the-market decreases the interest rate for institutional loans by over 30 basis points per annum. While this effect is significantly larger for loan tranches bought by collateralized debt obligations (CDOs), it is not fully explained by their role. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ivashina, Victoria; Sun, Zheng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board structure and price informativeness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Daniel; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Raposo, Clara C.
We develop and test the hypothesis that stock price informativeness affects the structure of corporate boards. We find a negative relation between price informativeness and board independence. This finding is robust to the inclusion of many firm-level controls, including firm fixed effects, and to the choice of the measure of price informativeness. Consistent with the hypothesis that price informativeness and board monitoring are substitutes, this relation is particularly strong for firms more exposed to both external and internal governance mechanisms and for firms in which firm-specific knowledge is relatively unimportant. Our results suggest that firms, with more informative stock prices have less demanding board structures. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferreira, Daniel; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Raposo, Clara C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-varying short-horizon predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henkel, Sam James; Martin, J. Spencer; Nardari, Federico
In the G7 countries, the short-horizon performance of aggregate return predictors such as the dividend yield and the short rate appears non-existent during business cycle expansions but sizable during contractions. This phenomenon appears related to countercyclical risk premiums as well as the time-variation in the dynamics of predictors. Our empirical model outperforms the historical average out-of-sample in the US, but the results throughout the G7 are mixed. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Henkel, Sam James; Martin, J. Spencer; Nardari, Federico</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Breaking down the barriers: Competition, syndicate structure, and underwriting incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shivdasani, Anil; Song, Wei-Ling
We argue that the entry of commercial banks into bond underwriting led to the evolution of co-led underwriting arrangements and lowered the screening incentives of underwriters. Lead underwriters in co-led syndicates faced weaker incentives to screen issuer quality. In boom markets, issues underwritten by co-led syndicates were more likely to be involved in financial misrepresentation events. Underwriter incentives in co-led syndicates were particularly weak in industries where commercial banks stole substantial market share. Similar patterns do not hold in bust markets where investors are likely to engage in their own information collection efforts. Our results suggest that competition may have an adverse effect on the incentives of financial intermediaries in market environments where their information production is more valuable to investors. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shivdasani, Anil; Song, Wei-Ling</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity risk and expected corporate bond returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Hai; Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi
This paper studies the pricing of liquidity risk in the cross section of corporate bonds for the period from January 1994 to March 2009. The average return on bonds with high sensitivities to aggregate liquidity exceeds that for bonds with low sensitivities by about 4% annually. The positive relation between expected corporate bond returns and liquidity beta is robust to the effects of default and term betas, liquidity level, and other bond characteristics, as well as to different model specifications, test methodologies, and a variety of liquidity measures. The results suggest that liquidity risk is an important determinant of expected corporate bond returns. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Hai; Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange trading rules and stock market liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, Douglas; Johan, Sofia; Li, Dan
We examine stock exchange trading rules for market manipulation, insider trading, and broker-agency conflict, across countries and over time, in 42 stock exchanges around the world. Some stock exchanges have extremely detailed rules that explicitly prohibit specific manipulative practices, but others use less precise and broadly framed rules. We create new indices for market manipulation, insider trading, and broker-agency conflict based on the specific provisions in the trading rules of each stock exchange. We show that differences in exchange trading rules, over time and across markets, significantly affect liquidity. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cumming, Douglas; Johan, Sofia; Li, Dan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Share issuance and cash savings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McLean, R. David
Firms increasingly issue shares for the purpose of cash savings. During the 1970s, $1.00 of issuance resulted in $0.23 of cash savings; over the most recent decade, $1.00 of issuance resulted in $0.60 of cash savings. This increase is caused by increasing precautionary motives. Proxies for precautionary motives increase over the sample period, and firm-level increases in these proxies are associated with firm-level increases in share issuance-cash savings. Share issuance-cash savings are inversely related to issuance costs, suggesting that firms issue and save when costs are low, so as to avoid issuing when costs are high. This framework can also help explain patterns and trends in share issuance activity over time. Market timing does not explain these effects, as share issuance-cash savings are not related to post-issuance stock returns. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McLean, R. David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why mutual funds "underperform"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glode, Vincent
I propose a parsimonious model that reproduces the negative risk-adjusted performance of actively managed equity mutual funds. In the model, a fund manager can generate state-dependent active returns at a disutility. Negative expected performance and mutual fund investing simultaneously arise in equilibrium because the active return the fund manager generates covaries positively with a component of the pricing kernel that the performance measure omits, consistent with recent empirical evidence. Using data on U.S. funds, I also document new empirical evidence consistent with the model's cross-sectional implications. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Glode, Vincent</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technological change and the growing inequality in managerial compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lustig, Hanno; Syverson, Chad; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn
Three of the most fundamental changes in US corporations since the early 1970s have been (1) the increased importance of organizational capital in production, (2) the increase in managerial income inequality and pay-performance sensitivity, and (3) the secular decrease in labor market reallocation. Our paper develops a simple explanation for these changes: a shift in the composition of productivity growth away from vintage-specific to general growth. This shift has stimulated the accumulation of organizational capital in existing firms and reduced the need for reallocating workers to new firms. We characterize the optimal managerial compensation contract when firms. accumulate organizational capital but risk-averse managers cannot commit to staying with the firm. A calibrated version of the model reproduces the increase in managerial compensation inequality and the increased sensitivity of pay to performance in the data over the last three decades. This increased sensitivity of compensation to performance provides large, successful firms with the glue to retain their managers and the organizational capital embedded in them. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lustig, Hanno; Syverson, Chad; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge funds, managerial skill, and macroeconomic variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Kosowski, Robert; Naik, Narayan Y.; Teo, Melvyn
This paper evaluates hedge fund performance through portfolio strategies that incorporate predictability based on macroeconomic variables. Incorporating predictability substantially improves out-of-sample performance for the entire universe of hedge funds as well as for various investment styles. While we also allow for predictability in fund risk loadings and benchmark returns, the major source of investment profitability is predictability in managerial skills. In particular, long-only strategies that incorporate predictability in managerial skills outperform their Fung and Hsieh (2004) benchmarks by over 17% per year. The economic value of predictability obtains for different rebalancing horizons and alternative benchmark models. It is also robust to adjustments for backfill bias, incubation bias, illiquidity, fund termination, and style composition. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Kosowski, Robert; Naik, Narayan Y.; Teo, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavioral biases of mutual fund investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bailey, Warren; Kumar, Alok; Ng, David
We examine the effect of behavioral biases on the mutual fund choices of a large sample of US discount brokerage investors using new measures of attention to news, tax awareness, and fund-level familiarity bias, in addition to behavioral and demographic characteristics of earlier studies. Behaviorally biased investors typically make poor decisions about fund style and expenses, trading frequency, and timing, resulting in poor performance. Furthermore, trend chasing appears related to behavioral biases, rather than to rationally inferring managerial skill from past performance. Factor analysis suggests that biased investors often conform to stereotypes that can be characterized as Gambler, Smart, Overconfident, Narrow Framer, and Mature. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bailey, Warren; Kumar, Alok; Ng, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-term termination without deterring long-term investment: A theory of debt and buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex
The option to terminate a manager early minimizes investor losses if he is unskilled. However, it also deters a skilled manager from undertaking efficient long-term projects that risk low short-term earnings. This paper demonstrates how risky debt can overcome this tension. Leverage concentrates equityholders' stakes, inducing them to learn the cause of low earnings. If they result from investment (poor management), the firm is continued (liquidated). Therefore, unskilled managers are terminated and skilled managers invest without fear of termination. Unlike models of managerial discipline based on total payout, dividends are not a substitute for debt-they allow for termination upon non-payment, but at the expense of investment since they do not concentrate ownership and induce monitoring. Debt is dynamically consistent as the manager benefits from monitoring. In traditional theories, monitoring constrains the manager; here, it frees him to invest. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Edmans, Alex</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural breaks, parameter uncertainty, and term structure puzzles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bulkley, George; Giordani, Paolo
We show that uncertainty about parameters of the short rate model can account for the rejections of the expectations hypothesis for the term structure of interest rates. We assume that agents employ Bayes rule to learn parameter values in the context of a model that is subject to stochastic structural breaks. We show that parameter uncertainty also implies that the verdict on the expectations hypothesis varies systematically with the term of the long bond and the particular test employed, in the same way that is found in empirical tests. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bulkley, George; Giordani, Paolo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tracking down distress risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kapadia, Nishad
This paper shows that exposure to aggregate distress risk is the underlying source of the premiums for the Fama-French size (SMB) and value (HML) factors. Using a unique data set of aggregate business failures of both private and public firms from 1926 to 1997, I build portfolios that track news about future firm failures. These tracking portfolios optimally hedge aggregate distress risk and earn a Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM) alpha of approximately -4% a year. Both HML and SMB predict changes in future failure rates. Small stocks have lower returns than large stocks and value stocks have lower returns than growth stocks when the market expects an increase in future failure rates. Finally, a two-factor model with the market and the tracking portfolio for aggregate distress as factors does as well as the Fama-French three-factor model in pricing the 25 size and book-to-market sorted portfolios. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kapadia, Nishad</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor rights and corporate risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Amihud, Yakov; Litov, Lubomir
We propose that stronger creditor rights in bankruptcy affect corporate investment choice by reducing corporate risk-taking. In cross-country analysis, we find that stronger creditor rights induce greater propensity of firms to engage in diversifying acquisitions that are value-reducing, to acquire targets whose assets have high recovery value in default, and to lower cash-flow risk. Also, corporate leverage declines when creditor rights are stronger. These relations are usually strongest in countries where management is dismissed in reorganization and are also observed over time following changes in creditor rights. Our results thus identify a potentially adverse consequence of strong creditor rights. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Amihud, Yakov; Litov, Lubomir</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limits-to-arbitrage, investment frictions, and the asset growth anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lam, F. Y. Eric C.; Wei, K. C. John
We empirically evaluate the predictions of the mispricing hypothesis with limits-to-arbitrage suggested by Shleifer and Vishny (1997) and the q-theory with investment frictions proposed by Li and Zhang (2010) on the negative relation between asset growth and average stock returns. We conduct cross-sectional regressions of returns on asset growth on subsamples split by a given measure of limits-to-arbitrage or investment frictions. We show that: (i) proxies for limits-to-arbitrage and proxies for investment frictions are often highly correlated; (ii) the evidence based on equal-weighted returns shows significant support for both hypotheses, while the evidence from value-weighted returns is weaker; and (iii) in direct comparisons, each hypothesis is supported by a fair and similar amount of evidence. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lam, F. Y. Eric C.; Wei, K. C. John</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge fund leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Gorovyy, Sergiy; van Inwegen, Gregory B.
We investigate the leverage of hedge funds in the time series and cross-section. Hedge fund leverage is counter-cyclical to the leverage of listed financial intermediaries and decreases prior to the start of the financial crisis in mid-2007. Hedge fund leverage is lowest in early 2009 when the market leverage of investment banks is highest. Changes in hedge fund leverage tend to be more predictable by economy-wide factors than by fund-specific characteristics. In particular, decreases in funding costs and increases in market values both forecast increases in hedge fund leverage. Decreases in fund return volatilities predict future increases in leverage. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Gorovyy, Sergiy; van Inwegen, Gregory B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional investors and the limits of arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewellen, Jonathan
The returns and stock holdings of institutional investors from 1980 to 2007 provide little evidence of stock-picking skill. Institutions as a whole closely mimic the market portfolio, with pre-cost returns that have nearly perfect correlation with the value-weighted index and an insignificant CAPM alpha of 0.08% quarterly. Institutions also show little tendency to bet on any of the main characteristics known to predict stock returns, such as book-to-market, momentum, or accruals. While particular groups of institutions have modest stock-picking skill relative to the CAPM, their performance is almost entirely explained by the book-to-market and momentum effects in returns. Further, no group holds a portfolio that deviates efficiently from the market portfolio. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lewellen, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-run risk in durable consumption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Wei
Durable consumption growth is persistent and predicted by the price-dividend ratio. This provides strong and direct evidence for the existence of a highly persistent expected component. Durable consumption growth is left-skewed and exhibits time-varying volatility. I model durable consumption growth as containing a persistent expected component and driven by counter-cyclical volatility, nondurable consumption as a random walk, and dividend growth as exposed to the expected component of durable consumption growth. Together with nonseparable Epstein-Zin preferences, the model demonstrates that long-run risk in durable consumption can explain major asset market phenomena. The model also generates an upward-sloping real term structure. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yang, Wei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payday lenders: Heroes or villains?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morse, Adair
Does access to high-interest credit (payday loans) exacerbate or mitigate individual financial distress. Using natural disasters as an exogenous shock, I apply a propensity score-matched, triple-difference specification to identify a causal relation between welfare and access to credit. California foreclosures increase by 4.5 units per 1,000 homes after a natural disaster. The existence of payday lenders mitigates 1.0-1.3 of them, with the caveat that not all payday loans are for emergency distress. Payday lenders also mitigate larcenies (but not burglaries or vehicle thefts). In a placebo test of disasters covered by homeowner insurance, payday lending has no mitigation effect. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morse, Adair</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The CEO pay slice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Peyer, Urs C.
We investigate the relation between the CEO Pay Slice (CPS) the fraction of the aggregate compensation of the top-five executive team captured by the Chief Executive Officer and the value, performance, and behavior of public firms. The CPS could reflect the relative importance of the CEO as well as the extent to which the CEO is able to extracts rents. We find that, controlling for all standard controls, CPS is negatively associated with firm value as measured by industry-adjusted Tobin's q. CPS also has a rich set of relations with firms' behavior and performance. In particular, CPS is correlated with lower (industry-adjusted) accounting profitability, lower stock returns accompanying acquisitions announced by the firm and higher likelihood of a negative stock return accompanying such announcements, higher odds of the CEO receiving a lucky option grant at the lowest price of the month, lower performance sensitivity of CEO turnover, and lower stock market returns accompanying the filing of proxy statements for periods when CPS increases. Taken together, our results are consistent with the hypothesis that higher CPS is associated with agency problems and indicate that CPS can provide a useful tool for studying the performance and behavior of firms. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Peyer, Urs C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate cash holdings and CEO compensation incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Yixin; Mauer, David C.
We examine the effect of chief executive officer (CEO) compensation incentives on corporate cash holdings and the value of cash to better understand how compensation incentives designed to enhance the alignment of manager and shareholder interests could influence stockholder-bondholder conflicts. We find a positive relation between CEO risk-taking (vega) incentives and cash holdings, and we find a negative relation between vega and the value of cash to shareholders. The negative effect of vega on the value of cash is robust after controlling for corporate governance, is stronger in firms with high leverage, is reversed for unlevered firms, and is not present in financially constrained firms. We also find that the likelihood of liquidity covenants in new bank loans is increasing in CEO vega incentives. Our evidence primarily supports the costly contracting hypothesis, which asserts that bondholders anticipate greater risk-taking in high vega firms and, therefore, require greater liquidity. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Yixin; Mauer, David C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining asset pricing puzzles associated with the 1987 market crash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benzoni, Luca; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.
The 1987 market crash was associated with a dramatic and permanent steepening of the implied volatility curve for equity index options, despite minimal changes in aggregate consumption. We explain these events within a general equilibrium framework in which expected endowment growth and economic uncertainty are subject to rare jumps. The arrival of a jump triggers the updating of agents' beliefs about the likelihood of future jumps, which produces a market crash and a permanent shift in option prices. Consumption and dividends remain smooth, and the model is consistent with salient features of individual stock options, equity returns, and interest rates. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benzoni, Luca; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial literacy and stock market participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Rooij, Maarten; Lusardi, Annamaria; Alessie, Rob
We have devised two special modules for De Nederlandsche Bank (DNB) Household Survey to measure financial literacy and study its relationship to stock market participation. We find that the majority of respondents display basic financial knowledge and have some grasp of concepts such as interest compounding, inflation, and the time value of money. However, very few go beyond these basic concepts; many respondents do not know the difference between bonds and stocks, the relationship between bond prices and interest rates, and the basics of risk diversification. Most importantly, we find that financial literacy affects financial decision-making: Those with low literacy are much less likely to invest in stocks. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>van Rooij, Maarten; Lusardi, Annamaria; Alessie, Rob</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO waves, product market competition, and the going public decision: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; He, Jie
We develop a new rationale for initial public offering (IPO) waves based on product market considerations. Two firms, with differing productivity levels, compete in an industry with a significant probability of a positive productivity shock. Going public, though costly, not only allows a firm to raise external capital cheaply, but also enables it to grab market share from its private competitors. We solve for the decision of each firm to go public versus remain private, and the optimal timing of going public. In equilibrium, even firms with sufficient internal capital to fund their new investment may go public, driven by the possibility of their product market competitors going public. IPO waves may arise in equilibrium even in industries which do not experience a productivity shock. Our model predicts that firms going public during an IPO wave will have lower productivity and post-IPO profitability but larger cash holdings than those going public off the wave; it makes similar predictions for firms going public later versus earlier in an IPO wave. We empirically test and find support for these predictions. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; He, Jie</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Friends or foes? Target selection decisions of sovereign wealth funds and their consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kotter, Jason; Lel, Ugur
This paper examines investment strategies of sovereign wealth funds (SWFs), their effect on target firm valuation, and how both of these are related to SWF transparency. We find that SWFs prefer large and poorly performing firms facing financial difficulties. Their investments have a positive effect on target firms' stock prices around the announcement date but no substantial effect on firm performance and governance in the long run. We also find that transparent SWFs are more likely to invest in financially constrained firms and have a greater impact on target firm value than opaque SWFs. Overall, SWFs are similar to passive institutional investors in their preference for target characteristics and in their effect on target performance, and SWF transparency influences SWFs' investment activities and their impact on target firm value. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kotter, Jason; Lel, Ugur</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity risk management and credit supply in the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornett, Marcia Millon; McNutt, Jamie John; Strahan, Philip E.; Tehranian, Hassan
Liquidity dried up during the financial crisis of 2007-2009. Banks that relied more heavily on core deposit and equity capital financing, which are stable sources of financing, continued to lend relative to other banks. Banks that held more illiquid assets on their balance sheets, in contrast, increased asset liquidity and reduced lending. Off-balance sheet liquidity risk materialized on the balance sheet and constrained new credit origination as increased takedown demand displaced lending capacity. We conclude that efforts to manage the liquidity crisis by banks led to a decline in credit supply. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cornett, Marcia Millon; McNutt, Jamie John; Strahan, Philip E.; Tehranian, Hassan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium prices in the presence of delegated portfolio management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cuoco, Domenico; Kaniel, Ron
This paper analyzes the asset pricing implications of commonly used portfolio management contracts linking the compensation of fund managers to the excess return of the managed portfolio over a benchmark portfolio. The contract parameters, the extent of delegation, and equilibrium prices are all determined endogenously within the model we consider. Symmetric (fulcrum) performance fees distort the allocation of managed portfolios in a way that induces a significant and unambiguous positive effect on the prices of the assets included in the benchmark and a negative effect on the Sharpe ratios. Asymmetric performance fees have more complex effects on equilibrium prices and Sharpe ratios, with the signs of these effects fluctuating stochastically over time in response to variations in the funds' excess performance. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cuoco, Domenico; Kaniel, Ron</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent trends in trading activity and market quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, Tarun; Roll, Richard; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
We explore the sharp uptrend in recent trading activity and accompanying changes in market efficiency. Higher turnover has been associated with more frequent smaller trades, which have progressively formed a larger fraction of trading volume over time. Evidence indicates that secular decreases in trading costs have influenced the turnover trend. Turnover has increased the most for stocks with the greatest level of institutional holdings, suggesting professional investing as a key contributor to the turnover trend. Variance ratio tests suggest that more institutional trading has increased information-based trading. Intraday volatility has decreased and prices conform more closely to random walk in recent years. The sensitivity of turnover to past returns has increased and cross-sectional predictability of returns has decreased significantly, revealing a more widespread use of quantitative trading strategies that allow for more efficient securities prices. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chordia, Tarun; Roll, Richard; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CFOs versus CEOs: Equity incentives and crashes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Jeong-Bon; Li, Yinghua; Zhang, Liandong
Using a large sample of U.S. firms for the period 1993-2009, we provide evidence that the sensitivity of a chief financial officer's (CFO) option portfolio value to stock price is significantly and positively related to the firm's future stock price crash risk. In contrast, we find only weak evidence of the positive impact of chief executive officer option sensitivity on crash risk. Finally, we find that the link between CFO option sensitivity and crash risk is more pronounced for firms in non-competitive industries and those with a high level of financial leverage. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Jeong-Bon; Li, Yinghua; Zhang, Liandong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO optimism and forced turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, T. Colin; Gallmeyer, Michael; Johnson, Shane A.; Rutherford, Jessica; Stanley, Brooke W.
We show theoretically that optimism can lead a risk-averse Chief Executive Officer (CEO) to choose the first-best investment level that maximizes shareholder value. Optimism below (above) the interior optimum leads the CEO to underinvest (over-invest). Hence, if boards of directors act in the interests of shareholders, CEOs with relatively low or high optimism face a higher probability of forced turnover than moderately optimistic CEOs face. Using a large sample of turnovers, we find strong empirical support for this prediction. The results are consistent with the view that there is an interior optimum level of managerial optimism that maximizes firm value. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campbell, T. Colin; Gallmeyer, Michael; Johnson, Shane A.; Rutherford, Jessica; Stanley, Brooke W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the stock market fully value intangibles? Employee satisfaction and equity prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex
This paper analyzes the relationship between employee satisfaction and long-run stock returns. A value-weighted portfolio of the "100 Best Companies to Work For in America" earned an annual four-factor alpha of 3.5% from 1984 to 2009, and 2.1% above industry benchmarks. The results are robust to controls for firm characteristics, different weighting methodologies, and the removal of outliers. The Best Companies also exhibited significantly more positive earnings surprises and announcement returns. These findings have three main implications. First, consistent with human capital-centered theories of the firm, employee satisfaction is positively correlated with shareholder returns and need not represent managerial slack. Second, the stock market does not fully value intangibles, even when independently verified by a highly public survey on large firms. Third, certain socially responsible investing (SRI) screens may improve investment returns. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Edmans, Alex</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry and self-selection bias in bank loan announcement studies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maskara, Pankaj K.; Mullineaux, Donald J.
Event-study driven research has produced a consensus that loans are unique relative to other financial contracts. But these studies assume that small samples of loan announcements adequately represent the loan population. We find that loan announcements are rare and driven by factors such as information asymmetry and perceived materiality. We show that the sample used by Billett, Flannery, and Garfinkel (1995) fails to represent the loan universe and that significant abnormal announcement returns are confined to their smallest firms. Our sample, which better represents the loan population, produces an abnormal return insignificantly different from zero. The findings suggest that self-selection bias affects extant loan announcement research and do not support the views that loans are a special form of finance or that private and public debt differ in significant ways. Were all loans to be announced, the average abnormal return would likely be insignificant. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maskara, Pankaj K.; Mullineaux, Donald J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do small shareholders count?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kandel, Eugene; Massa, Massimo; Simonov, Andrei
We hypothesize that age similarity among small shareholders acts as an implicit coordinating device for their actions and, thus, could represent an indirect source of corporate governance in firms with dispersed ownership. We test this hypothesis on a sample of Swedish firms during the 1995-2000 period. Consistent with our hypothesis, we find that compared with shareholders of differing ages, same-age noncontrolling shareholders sell more aggressively following negative firm news; firms with more age-similar small shareholders are more profitable and command higher valuation; and an increase (decline) in a firm's small shareholder age similarity brings a significantly large increase (decline) in its stock price. The last effects are more pronounced in the absence of a controlling shareholder. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kandel, Eugene; Massa, Massimo; Simonov, Andrei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory pressure and fire sales in the corporate bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellul, Andrew; Jotikasthira, Chotibhak; Lundblad, Christian T.
This paper investigates fire sales of downgraded corporate bonds induced by regulatory constraints imposed on insurance companies. As insurance companies hold over one-third of investment-grade corporate bonds, the collective need to divest downgraded issues may be limited by a scarcity of counterparties. Using insurance company transaction data, we find that insurance companies that are relatively more constrained by regulation are more likely to sell downgraded bonds. Bonds subject to a high probability of regulatory-induced selling exhibit price declines and subsequent reversals. These price effects appear larger during periods when the insurance industry is relatively distressed and other potential buyers' carpital is scarce. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ellul, Andrew; Jotikasthira, Chotibhak; Lundblad, Christian T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance maximization of actively managed funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guasoni, Paolo; Huberman, Gur; Wang, Zhenyu
A growing literature suggests that, even in the absence of any ability to predict returns, holding options on the benchmarks or trading frequently can generate positive alpha. The ratio of alpha to its tracking error appraises a fund's performance. This paper derives the performance-maximizing strategy, which turns out to be a variant of a buy-write strategy, and the least upper bound on such performance enhancement. If common equity indices are used as benchmarks, the potential alpha generated from trading frequently can be substantial in magnitude, but it carries considerable risk. The statistical significance in estimated alpha is low, and the probability of a negative alpha is high. The performance enhancement from holding options can be significant - both economically and statistically - if the options' implied volatilities are higher than the volatilities of the benchmark returns. The performance-maximizing strategy derived in this paper is different from the strategies that switch portfolio exposure to the benchmarks. The exposure-switching strategies are not promising unless the switching is based on superior information. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guasoni, Paolo; Huberman, Gur; Wang, Zhenyu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does geography matter? Firm location and corporate payout policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>John, Kose; Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana
We investigate the impact of geography on agency costs and firm dividend policies. We argue that remote firm location increases the cost of shareholder oversight of managerial investment decisions. We hypothesize that remotely located firms facing free cash flow problems precommit to higher dividends to mitigate agency conflicts. We find that remotely located firms pay higher dividends. As expected, the effect of geography on dividends is most pronounced for firms with severe free cash flow problems. Further, remotely located firms rely more on regular dividends instead of special dividends or share repurchases and decrease dividends less often. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>John, Kose; Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of risk management in mergers and merger waves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garfinkel, Jon A.; Hankins, Kristine Watson
We show that merger activity and particularly waves are significantly driven by risk management considerations. Increases in cash flow uncertainty encourage firms to vertically integrate and this contributes to the start of merger waves. These effects are incremental to previously identified causes of wave activity. Our risk management hypothesis is further supported by cross-sectional differences in the likelihood that a firm vertically integrates, and by the post-acquisition characteristics of vertically integrating firms. These results are consistent with the view (from the industrial organization literature) that vertical integration is an operational hedging mechanism that reduces the cost of increased uncertainty. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garfinkel, Jon A.; Hankins, Kristine Watson</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How did increased competition affect credit ratings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Bo; Milbourn, Todd
The credit rating industry has historically been dominated by just two agencies, Moody's and Standard &amp; Poor's, leading to long-standing legislative and regulatory calls for increased competition. The material entry of a third rating agency (Fitch) to the competitive landscape offers a unique experiment to empirically examine how increased competition affects the credit ratings market. What we find is relatively troubling. Specifically, we discover that increased competition from Fitch coincides with lower quality ratings from the incumbents: Rating levels went up, the correlation between ratings and market-implied yields fell, and the ability of ratings to predict default deteriorated. We offer several possible explanations for these findings that are linked to existing theories. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Becker, Bo; Milbourn, Todd</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Directors' and officers' liability insurance and acquisition outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chen; Officer, Micah S.; Zou, Hong
We examine the effect of directors' and officers' liability insurance (D&amp;O insurance) on the outcomes of merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) decisions. We find that acquirers whose executives have a higher level of D&amp;O insurance coverage experience significantly lower announcement-period abnormal stock returns. Further analyses suggest that acquirers with a higher level of D&amp;O insurance protection tend to pay higher acquisition premiums and their acquisitions appear to exhibit lower synergies. The evidence provides support for the notion that the provision of D&amp;O insurance can induce unintended moral hazard by shielding directors and officers from the discipline of shareholder litigation. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Chen; Officer, Micah S.; Zou, Hong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Religious beliefs, gambling attitudes, and financial market outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Alok; Page, Jeremy K.; Spalt, Oliver G.
This study investigates whether geographic variation in religion-induced gambling norms affects aggregate market outcomes. We conjecture that gambling propensity would be stronger in regions with higher concentrations of Catholics relative to Protestants. Consistent with our conjecture, we show that in regions with higher Catholic-Protestant ratios, investors exhibit a stronger propensity to hold lottery-type stocks, broad-based employee stock option plans are more popular, the initial day return following an initial public offering is higher, and the magnitude of the negative lottery-stock premium is larger. Collectively, these results indicate that religion-induced gambling attitudes impact investors' portfolio choices, corporate decisions, and stock returns. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kumar, Alok; Page, Jeremy K.; Spalt, Oliver G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Egalitarianism and international investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siegel, Jordan I.; Licht, Amir N.; Schwartz, Shalom H.
This study identifies how country differences on a key cultural dimension-egalitarianism-influence international investment flows. A society's cultural orientation toward egalitarianism is manifested by intolerance for abuses of market and political power and a desire for protecting less powerful actors. We show egalitarianism to be based on exogenous factors including social fractionalization, dominant religion circa 1900, and war experience from the 19th century. We find a robust influence of egalitarianism distance on cross-national flows of bond and equity issuances, syndicated loans, and mergers and acquisitions. An informal cultural institution largely determined a century or more ago, egalitarianism exercises its effect on international investment via an associated set of consistent contemporary policy choices. But even after controlling for these associated policy choices, egalitarianism continues to exercise a direct effect on cross-border investment flows, likely through its direct influence on managers' daily business conduct. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Siegel, Jordan I.; Licht, Amir N.; Schwartz, Shalom H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deviation from the target capital structure and acquisition choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uysal, Vahap B.
This study finds that managers take deviations from their target capital structures into account when planning and structuring acquisitions. Specifically, firms that are overleveraged relative to their target debt ratios are less likely to make acquisitions and are less likely to use cash in their offers. Furthermore, they acquire smaller targets and pay lower premiums. Managers of overleveraged firms also actively rebalance their capital structures when they anticipate a high likelihood of making an acquisition. Finally, they pursue the most value-enhancing acquisitions. Collectively, these findings improve understanding of how firms choose their capital structures and shed light on the interdependence of capital structure and investment decisions in the presence of financial frictions. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Uysal, Vahap B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local underwriter oligopolies and IPO underpricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Xiaoding; Ritter, Jay R.
We develop a theory of initial public offering (IPO) underpricing based on differentiated underwriting services and localized competition. Even though a large number of investment banks compete for IPOs, if issuers care about non-price dimensions of underwriting, then the industry structure is best characterized as a series of local oligopolies. We test our model implications on all-star analyst coverage, industry expertise, and other non-price dimensions. Furthermore, we posit that venture capitalists (VCs) are especially focused on all-star analyst coverage, and develop the analyst lust theory of the underpricing of VC-backed IPOs. Consistent with this theory, we find that VC-backed IPOs are much more underpriced when they have coverage from an all-star analyst. (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Liu, Xiaoding; Ritter, Jay R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo; Hackbarth, Dirk
We study the interplay between corporate liquidity and asset reallocation. Our model shows that financially distressed firms are acquired by liquid firms in their industries even in the absence of operational synergies. We call these transactions "liquidity mergers," since their purpose is to reallocate liquidity to firms that are otherwise inefficiently terminated. We show that liquidity mergers are more likely to occur when industry-level asset-specificity is high and firm-level asset-specificity is low. We analyze firms' liquidity policies as a function of real asset reallocation, examining the trade-offs between cash and credit lines. We verify the model's prediction that liquidity mergers are more likely to occur in industries in which assets are industry-specific, but transferable across firms. We also show that firms are more likely to use credit lines (relative to cash) in industries in which liquidity mergers are more frequent. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo; Hackbarth, Dirk</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The influence of governance on investment: Evidence from a hazard model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, Matthew T.; Garfinkel, Jon A.; Jiang, Yi
Does corporate governance affect the timing of large investment projects? Hazard model estimates suggest strong shareholder governance may deter managers from pursuing large investments. Controlling for investment opportunities, firms with good governance experience longer spells between large investments. However, in the presence of financial constraints or strong CEO incentives (high delta (a)), we find no such timing differences. Finally, these higher investment hazard firms exhibit significantly negative long-run operating and stock performance. Overall, our findings are consistent with the notion that poor governance associates with overinvestment. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Billett, Matthew T.; Garfinkel, Jon A.; Jiang, Yi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of securitization in mortgage renegotiation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Amromin, Gene; Ben-David, Itzhak; Chomsisengphet, Souphala; Evanoff, Douglas D.
We study the effects of securitization on renegotiation of distressed residential mortgages over the current financial crisis. Unlike prior studies, we employ unique data that directly observe lender renegotiation actions and cover more than 60% of the U.S. mortgage market. Exploiting within-servicer variation in these data, we find that bank-held loans are 26-36% more likely to be renegotiated than comparable securitized mortgages (4.2-5.7% in absolute terms). Also, modifications of bank-held loans are more efficient: conditional on a modification, bank-held loans have 9% lower post-modification default rates (3.5% in absolute terms). Our findings support the view that frictions introduced by securitization create a significant challenge to effective renegotiation of residential loans. We also provide evidence supporting the affordability focus of recent policy actions, such as the Home Affordability Modification Program. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Amromin, Gene; Ben-David, Itzhak; Chomsisengphet, Souphala; Evanoff, Douglas D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The fragile capital structure of hedge funds and the limits to arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Xuewen; Mello, Antonio S.
During a financial crisis, when investors are most in need of liquidity and accurate prices, hedge funds cut their arbitrage positions and hoard cash. The paper explains this phenomenon. We argue that the fragile nature of the capital structure of hedge funds, combined with low market liquidity, creates a risk of coordination in redemptions among hedge fund investors that severely limits hedge funds' arbitrage capabilities. We present a model of hedge funds' optimal asset allocation in the presence of coordination risk among investors. We show that hedge fund managers behave conservatively and even abstain from participating in the market once coordination risk is factored into their investment decisions. The model suggests a new source of limits to arbitrage. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Xuewen; Mello, Antonio S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock price fragility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Thesmar, David
We study the relation between the ownership structure of financial assets and non-fundamental risk. We define an asset to be fragile if it is susceptible to non-fundamental shifts in demand. An asset can be fragile because of concentrated ownership, or because its owners face correlated or volatile liquidity shocks, i.e., they must buy or sell at the same time. We formalize this idea and apply it to mutual fund ownership of US stocks. Consistent with our predictions, fragility strongly predicts price volatility. We then extend the logic of fragility to investigate two natural extensions: (1) the forecast of stock return comovement and (2) the potentially destabilizing impact of arbitrageurs on stock prices. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth LBOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boucly, Quentin; Sraer, David; Thesmar, David
Using a data set of 839 French deals, we look at the change in corporate behavior following a leveraged buyout (LBO) relative to an adequately chosen control group. In the 3 years following a leveraged buyout, targets become more profitable, grow much faster than their peer group, issue additional debt, and increase capital expenditures. We then provide evidence consistent with the idea that in our sample, private equity funds create value by relaxing credit constraints, allowing LBO targets to take advantage of hitherto unexploited growth opportunities. First, post-buyout growth is concentrated among private-to-private transactions, i.e., deals where the seller is an individual, as opposed to divisional buyouts or public-to-private LBOs where the seller is a private or a public firm. Second, the observed post-buyout growth in size and post-buyout increase in debt and capital expenditures are stronger when the targets operate in an industry that is relatively more dependent on external finance. These results contrast with existing evidence that LBO targets invest less or downsize. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boucly, Quentin; Sraer, David; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO ownership, external governance, and risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, E. Han; Lu, Yao
This paper shows the relation between CEO ownership and firm valuation hinges critically on the strength of external governance (EG). The relation is hump-shaped when EG is weak, but is insignificant when EG is strong. The results imply that CEO ownership and EG are substitutes for mitigating agency problems when ownership is low. However, very high levels of share ownership can reduce firm value by entrenching the CEO and discouraging him from taking risk, unless mitigated by strong EG. We identify channels through which CEO ownership affects firm value by examining R&amp;D, which is discretionary and risky. We find CEO ownership similarly exhibits a hump-shaped relation with R&amp;D when EG is weak, but no relation when EG is strong. Our results are robust to endogeneity issues concerning CEO ownership and EG. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, E. Han; Lu, Yao</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance when founders are directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Feng; Srinivasan, Suraj
We examine chief executive officer (CEO) compensation, CEO retention policies, and mergers and acquisition (M&amp;A) decisions in firms in which founders serve as a director with a nonfounder CEO (founder-director firms). We find that founder-director firms offer a different mix of incentives to their CEOs than other firms. Pay-for-performance sensitivity for nonfounder CEOs in founder-director firms is higher and the level of pay is lower than that of other CEOs. CEO turnover sensitivity to firm performance is also significantly higher in founder-director firms compared with nonfounder firms. Overall, the evidence suggests that boards with founder-directors provide more high-powered incentives in the form of pay and retention policies than the average US board. Stock returns around M&amp;A announcements and board attendance are also higher in founder-director firms compared with nonfounder firms. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Feng; Srinivasan, Suraj</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership structure and financial constraints: Evidence from a structural estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Xuan, Yuhai
This article examines the impact of the divergence between corporate insiders' control rights and cash-flow rights on firms' external finance constraints via generalized method of moments estimation of an investment Euler equation. Using a large sample of U.S. firms during the 1994-2002 period, we find that the shadow value of external funds is significantly higher for companies with a wider insider control-ownership divergence, suggesting that companies whose corporate insiders have larger excess control rights are more financially constrained. The effect of insider excess control rights on external finance constraints is more pronounced for firms with higher degrees of informational opacity and for firms with financial misreporting, and is moderated by institutional ownership. The results show that the agency problems associated with the control-ownership divergence can have a real impact on corporate financial and investment outcomes. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue; Xuan, Yuhai</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adding and subtracting Black-Scholes: A new approach to approximating derivative prices in continuous-time models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kristensen, Dennis; Mele, Antonio
We develop a new approach to approximating asset prices in the context of continuous-time models. For any pricing model that lacks a closed-form solution, we provide a closed-form approximate solution, which relies on the expansion of the intractable model around an "auxiliary" one. We derive an expression for the difference between the true (but unknown) price and the auxiliary one, which we approximate in closed-form, and use to create increasingly improved refinements to the initial mispricing induced by the auxiliary model. The approach is intuitive, simple to implement, and leads to fast and extremely accurate approximations. We illustrate this method in a variety of contexts including option pricing with stochastic volatility, computation of Greeks, and the term structure of interest rates. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kristensen, Dennis; Mele, Antonio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional risk and performance evaluation: Volatility timing, overconditioning, and new estimates of momentum alphas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boguth, Oliver; Carlson, Murray; Fisher, Adlai; Simutin, Mikhail
Unconditional alphas are biased when conditional beta covaries with the market risk premium (market timing) or volatility (volatility timing). We demonstrate an additional bias (overconditioning) that can occur any time an empiricist estimates risk using information, such as a realized beta, that is not available to investors ex ante. Calibrating to U.S. equity returns, volatility timing and overconditioning can plausibly impact alphas more than market timing, which has been the focus of prior literature. To correct market- and volatility-timing biases without overconditioning, we show that incorporating realized betas into instrumental variables estimators is effective. Empirically, instrumentation reduces momentum alphas by 20-40%. Overconditioned alphas overstate performance by up to 2.5 times. We explain the sources of both the volatility-timing and overconditioning biases in momentum portfolios. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boguth, Oliver; Carlson, Murray; Fisher, Adlai; Simutin, Mikhail</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of liquidity: The effects of market conditions and bank characteristics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fecht, Falko; Nyborg, Kjell G.; Rocholl, Joerg
We study the prices that individual banks pay for liquidity (captured by borrowing rates in repos with the central bank and benchmarked by the overnight index swap) as a function of market conditions and bank characteristics. These prices depend in particular on the distribution of liquidity across banks, which is calculated over time using individual bank-level data on reserve requirements and actual holdings. Banks pay more for liquidity when positions are more imbalanced across banks, consistent with the existence of short squeezing. We also show that small banks pay more for liquidity and are more vulnerable to squeezes. Healthier banks pay less but, contrary to what one might expect, banks in formal liquidity networks do not. State guarantees reduce the price of liquidity but do not protect against squeezes. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fecht, Falko; Nyborg, Kjell G.; Rocholl, Joerg</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Post-merger restructuring and the boundaries of the firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maksimovic, Vojislav; Phillips, Gordon; Prabhala, N. R.
We examine how firms redraw their boundaries after acquisitions using plant-level data. We find that there is extensive restructuring in a short period following mergers and full-firm acquisitions. Acquirers of full firms sell 27% and close 19% of the plants of target firms within three years of the acquisition. Acquirers with skill in running their peripheral divisions tend to retain more acquired plants. Retained plants increase in productivity whereas sold plants do not. These results suggest that acquirers restructure targets in ways that exploit their comparative advantage. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maksimovic, Vojislav; Phillips, Gordon; Prabhala, N. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What determines stock option contract design?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liljeblom, Eva; Pasternack, Daniel; Rosenberg, Matts
We analyze the factors that drive exercise price policy for executive option plans (ESOPs) and their scope in a country where firms are not subject to the tax and accounting considerations that seem to have led to the dominance of at-the-money options in the US Our "unbounded" data for Finland provide us with an excellent opportunity to investigate whether contract design is consistent with compensation theory. Our findings are largely consistent with predictions from the optimal contracting literature. The size of the plan is negatively related to Tobin's Q and firm size and positively related to proxies for monitoring costs, which also influence the probability of launching premium ESOPs. Our results also show that the premium (out-of-the-moneyness) is negatively related to prior stock returns and cash flow-to-assets, which may be an indication of high-water mark contracting, or alternatively, of managerial power. Finally, we also find some support for a positive relation between the premium and the length of the vesting period when maturity is fixed, which indicates an effort to keep the incentives for management from falling over time. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liljeblom, Eva; Pasternack, Daniel; Rosenberg, Matts</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity grants to target CEOs during deal negotiations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heitzman, Shane
I investigate the determinants and consequences of granting equity to the target's Chief Executive Officer (CEO) during deal negotiations. These negotiation grants likely reflect information about the acquisition, benefit from the deal premium, and provide more timely bargaining incentives. I find that CEOs are more likely to receive equity during negotiations when they negotiate for the target, particularly when the target has more bargaining power. This suggests that boards use equity to enhance bargaining incentives for CEOs with the most influence over deal price. I find limited evidence that negotiation grants are used as compensation and no evidence that they have a material adverse effect on shareholders. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heitzman, Shane</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate bond default risk: A 150-year perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giesecke, Kay; Longstaff, Francis A.; Schaefer, Stephen; Strebulaev, Ilya
We study corporate bond default rates using an extensive new data set spanning the 1866-2008 period. We find that the corporate bond market has repeatedly suffered clustered default events much worse than those experienced during the Great Depression. For example, during the railroad crisis of 1873-1875, total defaults amounted to 36% of the par value of the entire corporate bond market. Using a regime-switching model, we examine the extent to which default rates can be forecast by financial and macroeconomic variables. We find that stock returns, stock return volatility, and changes in GDP are strong predictors of default rates. Surprisingly, however, credit spreads are not. Over the long term, credit spreads are roughly twice as large as default losses, resulting in an average credit risk premium of about 80 basis points. We also find that credit spreads do not adjust in response to realized default rates. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giesecke, Kay; Longstaff, Francis A.; Schaefer, Stephen; Strebulaev, Ilya</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate financing decisions, managerial market timing, and real investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, Alexander W.; Cornaggia, Jess; Grullon, Gustavo; Weston, James P.
Both market timing and investment-based theories of corporate financing predict under-performance after firms raise capital, but only market timing predicts that the composition of financing (equity compared with debt) should also forecast returns. In cross-sectional tests, we find that the amount of net financing is more important than its composition in explaining future stock returns. In the time series, investment-based factor models explain abnormal stock performance following a variety of corporate financing events that previous studies link to market timing. At the aggregate level, the amount of new financing is also more important for future market returns than its composition. Overall, our joint tests reveal that measures of real investment are correlated with future returns and measures of managerial market timing are not. (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Butler, Alexander W.; Cornaggia, Jess; Grullon, Gustavo; Weston, James P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information aggregation around macroeconomic announcements: Revisions matter</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilbert, Thomas
I show that an empirical relation exists between stock returns on macroeconomic news announcement days and the future revisions of the released data but that this link differs across the business cycle. Using three major macroeconomic series that undergo significant revisions (nonfarm payroll, gross domestic product, and industrial production), I present evidence that daily returns on the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index and revisions are positively related in expansions and negatively related in recessions. The results suggest that revisions do matter, i.e., that investors care about the final revised value of a macroeconomic series, that they infer accurate information from the release of the preliminary inaccurate report, and that the more precise information is aggregated into prices on the day of the initial announcement. The results are consistent with the predictions of rational expectations trading models around public announcements combined with well-established empirical results on the asymmetric interpretation of information across the business cycle. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gilbert, Thomas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Missing the marks? Dispersion in corporate bond valuations across mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cici, Gjergji; Gibson, Scott; Merrick, John J.
We study the dispersion of month-end valuations placed on identical corporate bonds by different mutual funds. Such dispersion is related to bond-specific characteristics associated with liquidity and market volatility. The Trade Reporting and Compliance Engine (TRACE) could have contributed to the general decline in dispersion over our sample period, though other factors most likely played roles. Further tests reveal marking patterns to be consistent with returns smoothing behavior by managers. Funds with ambiguous marking policies and those holding "hard-to-mark" bonds appear more prone to smooth reported returns. From a regulatory perspective, we see little downside to requiring funds to explicitly state their marking standards. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cici, Gjergji; Gibson, Scott; Merrick, John J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real investment and risk dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Ilan; Priestley, Richard
We ask to what extent the negative relation between investment and average stock returns is driven by risk We show that: (i) the average return spread between low and high asset growth and investment portfolios is largely accounted for by their spread in systematic risk, as measured by the loadings on the Chen, Roll, and Ross (1986) factors; (ii) as predicted by q-theory and real options models, systematic risk falls during large investment periods; (iii) the returns of factors formed on the investment-to-assets, asset growth, and investment growth all forecast aggregate economic activities. Our evidence suggests that risk plays an important role in explaining the investment-return relation. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cooper, Ilan; Priestley, Richard</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structures of equity and interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lettau, Martin; Wachter, Jessica A.
This paper proposes a dynamic risk-based model capable of jointly explaining the term structure of interest rates, returns on the aggregate market, and the risk and return characteristics of value and growth stocks. Both the term structure of interest rates and returns on value and growth stocks convey information about how the representative investor values cash flows of different maturities. We model how the representative investor perceives risks of these cash flows by specifying a parsimonious stochastic discount factor for the economy. Shocks to dividend growth, the real interest rate, and expected inflation are priced, but shocks to the price of risk are not. Given reasonable assumptions for dividends and inflation, we show that the model can simultaneously account for the behavior of aggregate stock returns, an upward-sloping yield curve, the failure of the expectations hypothesis, and the poor performance of the capital asset pricing model. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lettau, Martin; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accelerated share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bargeron, Leonce; Kulchania, Manoj; Thomas, Shawn
Accelerated share repurchases (ASRs) are credible commitments by firms to repurchase shares immediately. Including an ASR in a repurchase program reduces the flexibility that firms have to alter an announced program in response to subsequent changes in the price and liquidity of its shares, unexpected shocks to cash flow and/or investment, etc. Thus, we investigate whether firms' decisions to include ASRs in their repurchase programs are associated with factors expected to influence the costs of lost flexibility and the benefits of enhanced credibility and immediacy. We find robust evidence consistent with the costs of lost flexibility and the benefits of credibility and immediacy being important determinants of ASR adoption. Additionally, we find that ASR announcements are associated with positive average abnormal stock returns. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bargeron, Leonce; Kulchania, Manoj; Thomas, Shawn</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of a flow-through entity in an integrated corporate tax system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edwards, Alexander; Shevlin, Terry
In an integrated corporate tax system, resident shareholders receive a tax credit for corporate tax paid that can be used to offset personal tax on dividend income. Nonresident and tax-exempt (pension plan) investors cannot use the tax credit on corporate dividends and thus prefer to invest in flow-through entities. We estimate the value of the flow-through entity to nonresident and pension plan investors by examining the price change around the date of an unexpected announcement of a change in tax law related to Canadian publicly traded income trusts units creating an entity-level tax that makes them no longer tax-favored to these investors. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Edwards, Alexander; Shevlin, Terry</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market reaction to corporate governance regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larcker, David F.; Ormazabal, Gaizka; Taylor, Daniel J.
This paper investigates the market reaction to recent legislative and regulatory actions pertaining to corporate governance. The managerial power view of governance suggests that executive pay, the existing process of proxy access, and various governance provisions [e.g., staggered boards and Chief Executive Officer (CEO)-chairman duality] are associated with managerial rent extraction. This perspective predicts that broad government actions that reduce executive pay, increase proxy access, and ban such governance provisions are value-enhancing. In contrast, another view of governance suggests that observed governance choices are the result of value-maximizing contracts between shareholders and management. This perspective predicts that broad government actions that regulate such governance choices are value destroying. Consistent with the latter view, we find that the abnormal returns to recent events relating to corporate governance regulations are, on average, decreasing in CEO pay, decreasing in the number of large blockholders, decreasing in the ease by which small institutional investors can access the proxy process, and decreasing in the presence of a staggered board. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Larcker, David F.; Ormazabal, Gaizka; Taylor, Daniel J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock option grants to target CEOs during private merger negotiations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fich, Eliezer M.; Cai, Jie; Tran, Anh L.
Unscheduled stock options to target chief executive officers (CEOs) are a nontrivial phenomenon during private merger negotiations. In 920 acquisition bids during 1999-2007. over 13% of targets grant them. These options substitute for golden parachutes and compensate target CEOs for the benefits they forfeit because of the merger. Targets granting unscheduled options are more likely to be acquired but they earn lower premiums. Consequently, deal value drops by $62 for every dollar target CEOs receive from unscheduled options. Conversely, acquirers of targets offering these awards experience higher returns. Therefore, deals involving unscheduled grants exhibit a transfer of wealth from target shareholders to bidder shareholders. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fich, Eliezer M.; Cai, Jie; Tran, Anh L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor income dynamics at business-cycle frequencies: Implications for portfolio choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lynch, Anthony W.; Tan, Sinan
Young agents with low wealth-income ratios counter factually hold more stock than young, rich agents and old agents using the standard portfolio choice model with i.i.d. stock returns and labor income. This paper matches the countercyclical volatility and procyclical mean of U.S. labor income and finds that, consistent with U.S. data, young, poor agents now hold less stock than both young, rich agents and old agents, and no stock a large fraction of the time. Our results suggest that the predictability of labor income growth at a business-cycle frequency, particularly the countercyclical variation in volatility, plays an important role in a young agent's decision making about her portfolio's stock holding. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lynch, Anthony W.; Tan, Sinan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-varying rare disaster risk and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, Henk; Jacobsen, Ben; Lee, John B.
This study provides empirical support for theoretical models that allow for time-varying rare disaster risk. Using a database of 447 international political crises during the period 1918-2006, we create a crisis index that shows substantial variation over time. Changes in this crisis index, our proxy for changes in perceived disaster probability, have a large impact on both the mean and volatility of world stock market returns. Crisis risk is positively correlated with the earnings-price ratio and the dividend yield. Cross-sectional tests also show that crisis risk is priced: Industries that are more crisis risk sensitive yield higher returns. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berkman, Henk; Jacobsen, Ben; Lee, John B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do hedge funds' exposures to risk factors predict their future returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Caglayan, Mustafa Onur
This paper investigates hedge funds' exposures to various financial and macroeconomic risk factors through alternative measures of factor betas and examines their performance in predicting the cross-sectional variation in hedge fund returns. Both parametric and non-parametric tests indicate a significantly positive (negative) link between default premium beta (inflation beta) and future hedge fund returns. The results are robust across different subsample periods and states of the economy, and after controlling for market, size, book-to-market, and momentum factors as well as the trend-following factors in stocks, short-term interest rates, currencies, bonds, and commodities. The paper also provides macro-level and micro-level explanations of our findings. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Caglayan, Mustafa Onur</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of regulation on optimal corporate pension risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Love, David A.; Smith, Paul A.; Wilcox, David W.
We study firms' pension prefunding and portfolio allocation choices in a model in which firms trade off the need to compensate workers for the financial risk in their pension benefit against the cost advantage that may be gained by exploiting underpriced pension insurance. In the absence of pension insurance, the firm minimizes costs by rendering promised benefits free of risk to workers, who are assumed to be unable to hedge firm-specific risk. Various forms of government intervention, such as benefit guarantees, can alter this outcome dramatically by providing the firm with an incentive to shift risk to other parties. In this case, we find that the firm's decisions depend on, among other influences, the degree of insurance mispricing, the amount of guaranteed benefits, the stringency of minimum funding requirements, and the costs of financial distress. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Love, David A.; Smith, Paul A.; Wilcox, David W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information spillovers and performance persistence for hedge funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glode, Vincent; Green, Richard C.
We present a simple model that rationalizes performance persistence in hedge fund limited partnerships. In contrast to the model for mutual funds of Berk and Green (2004), the learning in our model pertains to profitability associated with an innovative trading strategy or emerging sector, rather than ability specific to the fund manager. As a result of potential information spillovers, which would increase competition if informed investors were to partner with non-incumbent managers, incumbent managers will let informed investors benefit from increases in estimated profitability following high returns realized with the trading strategy or in the sector. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Glode, Vincent; Green, Richard C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International diversification with frontier markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Dave; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Yang, J. Jimmy
We provide an analysis of frontier market equities with respect to world market integration and diversification. Principal component results reveal that frontier markets exhibit low levels of integration. In contrast with developed and emerging markets, frontier markets offer no indication of increasing integration through time. Furthermore, individual frontier market countries do not exhibit consistent rates of changing integration. Structural break tests identify breakpoints in integration, as well as integration dynamics across countries. We show that frontier markets have low integration with the world market and thereby offer significant diversification benefits. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Dave; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Yang, J. Jimmy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The costs of intense board monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faleye, Olubunmi; Hoitash, Rani; Hoitash, Udi
We study the effects of the intensity of board monitoring on directors' effectiveness in performing their monitoring and advising duties. We find that monitoring quality improves when a majority of independent directors serve on at least two of the three principal monitoring committees. These firms exhibit greater sensitivity of CEO turnover to firm performance, lower excess executive compensation, and reduced earnings management. The improvement in monitoring quality comes at the significant cost of weaker strategic advising and greater managerial myopia. Firms with boards that monitor intensely exhibit worse acquisition performance and diminished corporate innovation. Firm value results suggest that the negative advising effects outweigh the benefits of improved monitoring, especially when acquisitions or corporate innovation are significant value drivers or the firm's operations are complex. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faleye, Olubunmi; Hoitash, Rani; Hoitash, Udi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The causes and consequences of venture capital stage financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Xuan
This paper examines the causes and consequences of venture capital (VC) stage financing. Using information about the physical location of an entrepreneurial firm and the geographic distance between the VC investor and the firm, I show that VC investors located farther away from an entrepreneurial firm tend to finance the firm using a larger number of financing rounds, shorter durations between successive rounds, and investing a smaller amount in each round. However, VC investors' propensity to stage is independent of whether the firm is located in a close-knit community. I also find that VC staging positively affects the entrepreneurial firm's propensity to go public, operating performance in the initial public offering (IPO) year, and post-IPO survival rate, but only if the firm is located far away from the VC investor. However, the effect of VC staging on entrepreneurial firm's performance is independent of whether it is located in a close-knit community. The findings are robust to a variety of alternative proximity measures, instrumental variables, and econometric approaches for dealing with endogeneity problems. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tian, Xuan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The disparity between long-term and short-term forecasted earnings growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Warachka, Mitch
We find the disparity between long-term and short-term analyst forecasted earnings growth is a robust predictor of future returns and long-term analyst forecast errors. After adjusting for industry characteristics, stocks whose long-term earnings growth forecasts are far above or far below their implied short-term forecasts for earnings growth have negative and positive subsequent risk-adjusted returns along with downward and upward revisions in long-term forecasted earnings growth, respectively. Additional results indicate that investor inattention toward firm-level changes in long-term earnings growth is responsible for these risk-adjusted returns. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Warachka, Mitch</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm life expectancy and the heterogeneity of the book-to-market effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Huafeng
I argue that the reason the book-to-market effect is stronger in small stocks is because smaller stocks generally have shorter life expectancy and therefore shorter equity duration. I build a model in which the book-to-market effect is stronger in stocks with shorter life expectancy. Empirically, I use delisting probability as my proxy for life expectancy. The data support my model's central prediction and its additional implications for stock return and variance. My results provide a rational explanation for the heterogeneity of the book-to-market effect, evidence previously taken as support for behavioral explanations. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Huafeng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A model of dynamic compensation and capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo
This paper studies the optimal compensation problem between shareholders and the agent in the Leland (1994) capital structure model, and finds that the debt-overhang effect on the endogenous managerial incentives lowers the optimal leverage. Consistent with data, our model delivers a negative relation between pay-performance sensitivity and firm size, and the interaction between debt-overhang and agency issue leads smaller firms to take less leverage relative to their larger peers. During financial distress, a firm's cash flow becomes more sensitive to underlying performance shocks due to debt-overhang. The implications on credit spreads and debt covenants are also considered. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>He, Zhiguo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Media ownership, concentration and corruption in bank lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Houston, Joel F.; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue
Building on the pioneering study by Beck, Demirguc-Kunt, and Levine (2006), this study examines the effects of media ownership and concentration on corruption in bank lending using a unique World Bank data set covering more than 5,000 firms across 59 countries. We find strong evidence that state ownership of media is associated with higher levels of bank corruption. We also find that media concentration increases corruption both directly and indirectly through its interaction with media state ownership. In addition, we find that media state ownership and media concentration both accentuate the positive link between official supervisory power and lending corruption and attenuate the negative link between the regulations that empower private monitoring and corruption in lending. Media state ownership or media concentration also accentuates the positive link between banking concentration and corruption in lending. Furthermore, the links between media structure and corruption are more pronounced when the borrowing firm is privately owned. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Houston, Joel F.; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric information, adverse selection, and the pricing of CMBS</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>An, Xudong; Deng, Yongheng; Gabriel, Stuart A.
We demonstrate that asymmetric information between sellers (loan originators) and purchasers (investors and securities issuers) of commercial mortgages gives rise to a standard lemons problem, whereby portfolio lenders use private information to liquidate lower quality loans in commercial mortgage-backed securities (CMBS) markets. Conduit lenders, who originate loans for direct sale into securitization markets, mitigate problems of asymmetric information and adverse selection in loan sales. Our theory provides an explanation for the pricing puzzle observed in CMBS markets, whereby conduit CMBS loans are priced higher than portfolio loans, despite widespread belief that conduit loans are originated at lower quality. Consistent with theoretical predictions of a lemons discount, our empirical analysis of 141 CMBS deals and 16,760 CMBS loans shows that, after controlling for observable determinants of loan pricing, conduit loans enjoyed a 34 basis points pricing advantage over portfolio loans in the CMBS market. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>An, Xudong; Deng, Yongheng; Gabriel, Stuart A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional stock trading on loan market information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivashina, Victoria; Sun, Zheng
One of the most important developments in the corporate loan market over the past decade has been the growing participation of institutional investors. As lenders, institutional investors routinely receive private information about borrowers. However, most of these investors also trade in public securities. This leads to a controversial question: Do institutional investors use private information acquired in the loan market to trade in public securities? This paper examines the stock trading of institutional investors whose portfolios also hold loans. Using the Securities and Exchange Commission filings of loan amendments, we identify institutional investors with access to private information disclosed during loan amendments. We then look at abnormal returns on subsequent stock trades. We find that institutional participants in loan renegotiations subsequently trade in the stock of the same company and outperform trades by other managers and trades in other stocks by approximately 5.4% in annualized terms. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ivashina, Victoria; Sun, Zheng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking system control, capital allocation, and economy performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morck, Randall; Yavuz, M. Deniz; Yeung, Bernard
We observe less efficient capital allocation in countries whose banking systems are more thoroughly controlled by tycoons or families. The magnitude of this effect is similar to that of state control over banking. Unlike state control, tycoon or family control also correlates with slower economic and productivity growth, greater financial instability, and worse income inequality. These findings are consistent with theories that elite-capture of a country's financial system can embed "crony capitalism." (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morck, Randall; Yavuz, M. Deniz; Yeung, Bernard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Higher risk, lower returns: What hedge fund investors really earn</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dichev, Ilia D.; Yu, Gwen
The returns of hedge fund investors depend not only on the returns of the funds they hold but also on the timing and magnitude of their capital flows in and out of these funds. We use dollar-weighted returns (a form of Internal Rate of Return (IRR)) to assess the properties of actual investor returns on hedge funds and compare them to buy-and-hold fund returns. Our main finding is that annualized dollar-weighted returns are on the magnitude of 3% to 7% lower than corresponding buy-and-hold fund returns. Using factor models of risk and the estimated dollar-weighted performance gap, we find that the real alpha of hedge fund investors is close to zero. In absolute terms, dollar-weighted returns are reliably lower than the return on the Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P) 500 index, and are only marginally higher than the risk-free rate as of the end of 2008. The combined impression from these results is that the return experience of hedge fund investors is much worse than previously thought. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dichev, Ilia D.; Yu, Gwen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Country-specific sentiment and security prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun
I study the effect of country-specific sentiment on security prices. I provide evidence that a country's popularity among Americans affects US investors' demand for securities from that country and causes security prices to deviate from their fundamental values. Moreover, I find that country popularity is positively associated with the intensity of US cross-border mergers and acquisitions activity, suggesting that country popularity also affects firms' investment decisions. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sentiment and the mean-variance relation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Jianfeng; Yuan, Yu
This study shows the influence of investor sentiment on the market's mean-variance tradeoff. We find that the stock market's expected excess return is positively related to the market's conditional variance in low-sentiment periods but unrelated to variance in high-sentiment periods. These findings are consistent with sentiment traders who, during the high-sentiment periods, undermine an otherwise positive mean-variance tradeoff. We also find that the negative correlation between returns and contemporaneous volatility innovations is much stronger in the low-sentiment periods. The latter result is consistent with the stronger positive ex ante relation during such periods. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yu, Jianfeng; Yuan, Yu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dark side of financial innovation: A case study of the pricing of a retail financial product</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henderson, Brian J.; Pearson, Neil D.
The offering prices of 64 issues of a popular retail structured equity product were, on average. almost 8% greater than estimates of the products' fair market values obtained using option pricing methods. Under reasonable assumptions about the underlying stocks' expected returns, the mean expected return estimate on the structured products is slightly below zero. The products do not provide tax, liquidity, or other benefits, and it is difficult to rationalize their purchase by informed rational investors. Our findings are, however, consistent with the recent hypothesis that issuing firms might shroud some aspects of innovative securities or introduce complexity to exploit uninformed investors. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Henderson, Brian J.; Pearson, Neil D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ex post: The investment performance of collectible stamps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimson, Elroy; Spaenjers, Christophe
This paper uses stamp catalogue prices to investigate the returns on British collectible postage stamps over the period 1900-2008. We find an annualized return on stamps of 7.0% in nominal terms, or 2.9% in real terms. These returns are higher than those on bonds but below those on equities. The volatility of stamp prices approaches that of equities. Stamp returns are impacted by movements in the equity market, but the systematic risk of stamps remains low. Stamps partially hedge against unanticipated inflation. Estimates of average after-cost returns for individual investors show that stamps may rival equities in terms of realized performance. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dimson, Elroy; Spaenjers, Christophe</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are all CEOs above average? An empirical analysis of compensation peer groups and pay design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bizjak, John; Lemmon, Michael; Nguyen, Thanh
Companies can potentially use compensation peer groups to inflate pay by choosing peers that are larger, choosing a high target pay percentile, or choosing peer firms with high pay. Although peers are largely selected based on characteristics that reflect the labor market for managerial talent, we find that peer groups are constructed in a manner that biases compensation upward, particularly in firms outside the Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P) 500. Pay increases close only about one-third of the gap between the pay of the Chief Executive Officer (CEO) and the peer group, however, suggesting that boards exercise discretion in adjusting compensation. Preliminary evidence suggests that increased disclosure has reduced the biases in peer group choice. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bizjak, John; Lemmon, Michael; Nguyen, Thanh</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spot and forward volatility in foreign exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Della Corte, Pasquale; Sarno, Lucio; Tsiakas, Ilias
This paper investigates the empirical relation between spot and forward implied volatility in foreign exchange. We formulate and test the forward volatility unbiasedness hypothesis, which may be viewed as the volatility analogue to the extensively researched hypothesis of unbiasedness in forward exchange rates. Using a new dataset of spot implied volatility quoted on over-the-counter currency options, we compute the forward implied volatility that corresponds to the delivery price of a forward contract on future spot implied volatility. This contract is known as a forward volatility agreement. We find strong evidence that forward implied volatility is a systematically biased predictor that overestimates movements in future spot implied volatility. This bias in forward volatility generates high economic value to an investor exploiting predictability in the returns to volatility speculation and indicates the presence of predictable volatility term premiums in foreign exchange. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Della Corte, Pasquale; Sarno, Lucio; Tsiakas, Ilias</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving the predictability of real economic activity and asset returns with forward variances inferred from option portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Panayotov, George; Skoulakis, Georgios
This paper presents an option positioning that allows us to infer forward variances from option portfolios. The forward variances we construct from equity index options help to predict (i) growth in measures of real economic activity, (ii) Treasury bill returns, (iii) stock market returns, and (iv) changes in variance swap rates. Our yardstick for measuring predictive ability is both individual and joint parameter statistical significance within a market, as well as across a set of markets. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Panayotov, George; Skoulakis, Georgios</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is market fragmentation harming market quality?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Hara, Maureen; Ye, Mao
We examine how fragmentation is affecting market quality in US equity markets. We use newly available trade reporting facilities (TRFs) data to measure fragmentation, and we use a variety of empirical approaches to compare execution quality and efficiency of stocks with more and less fragmented trading. We find that fragmentation affects all stocks; more fragmented stocks have lower transactions costs and faster execution speeds; and fragmentation is associated with higher short-term volatility but greater market efficiency, in that prices are closer to being a random walk. Our results that fragmentation does not appear to harm market quality are consistent with US markets being a single virtual market with multiple points of entry. (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>O'Hara, Maureen; Ye, Mao</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of securitization in bank liquidity and funding management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loutskina, Elena
This paper studies the role of securitization in bank management. I propose a new index of "bank loan portfolio liquidity" which can be thought of as a weighted average of the potential to securitize loans of a given type, where the weights reflect the composition of a bank loan portfolio. I use this new index to show that by allowing banks to convert illiquid loans into liquid funds, securitization reduces banks' holdings of liquid securities and increases their lending ability. Furthermore, securitization provides banks with an additional source of funding and makes bank lending less sensitive to cost of funds shocks. By extension, the securitization weakens the ability of the monetary authority to affect banks' lending activity but makes banks more susceptible to liquidity and funding crisis when the securitization market is shut down. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Loutskina, Elena</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate tax avoidance and stock price crash risk: Firm-level analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Jeong-Bon; Li, Yinghua; Zhang, Liandong
Using a large sample of U.S. firms for the period 1995-2008, we provide strong and robust evidence that corporate tax avoidance is positively associated with firm-specific stock price crash risk. This finding is consistent with the following view: Tax avoidance facilitates managerial rent extraction and bad news hoarding activities for extended periods by providing tools, masks, and justifications for these opportunistic behaviors. The hoarding and accumulation of bad news for extended periods lead to stock price crashes when the accumulated hidden bad news crosses a tipping point, and thus comes out all at once. Moreover, we show that the positive relation between tax avoidance and crash risk is attenuated when firms have strong external monitoring mechanisms such as high institutional ownership, high analyst coverage, and greater takeover threat from corporate control markets. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Jeong-Bon; Li, Yinghua; Zhang, Liandong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global retail lending in the aftermath of the US financial crisis: Distinguishing between supply and demand effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Puri, Manju; Rocholl, Joerg; Steffen, Sascha
This paper examines the broader effects of the US financial crisis on global lending to retail customers. In particular we examine retail bank lending in Germany using a unique data set of German savings banks during the period 2006 through 2008 for which we have the universe of loan applications and loans granted. Our experimental setting allows us to distinguish between savings banks affected by the US financial crisis through their holdings in Landesbanken with substantial subprime exposure and unaffected savings banks. The data enable us to distinguish between demand and supply side effects of bank lending and find that the US financial crisis induced a contraction in the supply of retail lending in Germany. While demand for loans goes down, it is not substantially different for the affected and nonaffected banks. More important, we find evidence of a significant supply side effect in that the affected banks reject substantially more loan applications than nonaffected banks. This result is particularly strong for smaller and more liquidity-constrained banks as well as for mortgage as compared with consumer loans. We also find that bank-depositor relationships help mitigate these supply side effects. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Puri, Manju; Rocholl, Joerg; Steffen, Sascha</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting stock market returns: The sum of the parts is more than the whole</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Santa-Clara, Pedro
We propose forecasting separately the three components of stock market returns the dividend-price ratio, earnings growth, and price-earnings ratio growth the sum-of-the-parts (SOP) method. Our method exploits the different time series persistence of the components and obtains out-of-sample R-squares (compared with the historical mean) of more than 1.3% with monthly data and 13.4% with yearly data. This compares with typically negative R-squares obtained in a similar experiment with predictive regressions. The performance of the SOP method comes mainly from the dividend-price ratio and earnings growth components, and the robustness of the method is due to its low estimation error. An investor who timed the market using our method would have had a Sharpe ratio gain of 0.3. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Santa-Clara, Pedro</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend distributions and closed-end fund discounts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Day, Theodore E.; Li, George Z.; Xu, Yexiao
Empirical support for the hypothesis that closed-end fund discounts are related to overhanging tax liabilities has been mixed. We introduce a new approach to testing this hypothesis by examining changes in discount levels following distributions of dividends and capital gains. Since distributions reduce future shareholder tax liabilities, the tax liability hypothesis implies that closed-end fund discounts should decline following distributions. Focusing on changes in discounts isolates this tax effect by eliminating the impact of other fund-specific factors on discount levels. Our results support the tax liability hypothesis, showing that short-run fluctuations in discounts are directly affected by taxable distributions. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Day, Theodore E.; Li, George Z.; Xu, Yexiao</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vertical divestitures through equity carve-outs and spin-offs: A product markets perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jain, Bharat A.; Kini, Omesh; Shenoy, Jaideep
Using a product markets perspective to investigate the decision to vertically disintegrate, we find that vertical divestitures are more likely in response to positive industry demand shocks, favorable industry financing conditions, and lower parent firm relative productivity and are less likely when the potential for contracting problems is high. Conditional on vertical divestitures, equity carve-outs are more likely in environments in which relationship-specific investments are more prevalent and when the need for external funds is high, while spin-offs are more likely in larger industries and in industries that experience positive demand shocks. Our examinations of announcement-period wealth effects and changes in operating performance indicate that vertical divestitures are motivated by efficiency considerations. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jain, Bharat A.; Kini, Omesh; Shenoy, Jaideep</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of equity carve-outs and negative stub values under heterogeneous beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bayar, Onur; Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Liu, Mark H.
We develop a theory of new-project financing and equity carve-outs under heterogeneous beliefs. In our model, an employee of a firm generates an idea for a new project that can be financed either by issuing equity against the cash flows of the entire firm ("integration"), or by undertaking an equity carve-out of the new project alone ("non-integration"). While the patent underlying the new project is owned by the firm, the employee generating the idea needs to be motivated to exert optimal effort for the project to be successful. The firm's choice between integration and non-integration is driven primarily by heterogeneity in beliefs among outside investors (each of whom has limited wealth to invest in the equity market) and between firm insiders and outsiders: if the marginal outsider financing the new project is more optimistic about the prospects of the project than firm insiders, and this incremental optimism of the marginal outsider over firm insiders is greater regarding new-project cash flows than that about assets-in-place cash flows, then the firm will implement the project under non-integration rather than integration. Two other ingredients driving the firm's financing choice are the cost of motivating the employee to exert optimal effort, and the potential synergies between the new project and assets in place. We derive a number of testable predictions regarding a firm's equilibrium choice between integration and non-integration. We also provide a rationale for the "negative stub values" documented in the equity carve-outs of certain firms (e.g., the carve-out of Palm from 3Com) and develop predictions for the magnitude of these stub values. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bayar, Onur; Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Liu, Mark H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal compensation contracts when managers can hedge</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Huasheng
This paper examines optimal compensation contracts when executives can hedge their personal portfolios. In a simple principal-agent framework, I predict that the Chief Executive Officer's (CEO's) pay-performance sensitivity decreases with the executive-hedging cost. Empirically, I find evidence supporting the model's prediction. Providing further support for the theory, I show that shareholders also impose a high sensitivity of CEO wealth to stock volatility and increase financial leverage to resolve the executive-hedging problem. Moreover, executives with lower hedging costs hold more exercisable in-the-money options, have weaker incentives to cut dividends, and pursue fewer corporate diversification initiatives. Overall, the manager's ability to hedge the firm's risk affects governance mechanisms and managerial actions. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gao, Huasheng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating asset pricing models using the second Hansen-Jagannathan distance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Haitao; Xu, Yuewu; Zhang, Xiaoyan
We develop a specification test and a sequence of model selection procedures for non-nested, overlapping, and nested models based on the second Hansen-Jagannathan distance, which requires a good asset pricing model to not only have small pricing errors but also be arbitrage free. Our methods have reasonably good finite sample performances and are more powerful than existing ones in detecting misspecified models with small pricing errors but are not arbitrage-free and in differentiating models that have similar pricing errors of a given set of test assets. Using the Fama and French size and book-to-market portfolios, we reach dramatically different conclusions on model performances based on our approach and existing methods. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Haitao; Xu, Yuewu; Zhang, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEOs versus CFOs: Incentives and corporate policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh
We undertake a broad-based study of the effect of managerial risk-taking incentives on corporate financial policies and show that the risk-taking incentives of chief executive officers (CEOs) and chief financial officers (CFOs) significantly influence their firms' financial policies. In particular, we find that CEOs' risk-decreasing (-increasing) incentives are associated with lower (higher) leverage and higher (lower) cash balances. CFOs' risk-decreasing (-increasing) incentives are associated with safer (riskier) debt-maturity choices and higher (lower) earnings-smoothing through accounting accruals. We exploit the stock option expensing regulation of 2004 to establish a causal link between managerial incentives and corporate policies. Our findings have important implications for optimal corporate compensation design. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The world price of home bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lau, Sie Ting; Ng, Lilian; Zhang, Bohui
Theoretical arguments suggest that as the degree of a country's home bias increases, the global risk sharing between domestic and foreign investors will reduce and thereby increase the country's cost of capital. Consistent with this prediction, we find international differences in the cost of capital to be strongly and positively related to varying degrees of home bias for 38 markets. This finding is robust to different cost of capital proxies, different control variables, alternative home-bias measures, international tradability of stocks, and alternative specifications. Therefore, the overall evidence implies that countries may enjoy a significantly lower cost of capital by reducing the extent of their home bias and hence, increasing global risk sharing. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lau, Sie Ting; Ng, Lilian; Zhang, Bohui</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payoff complementarities and financial fragility: Evidence from mutual fund outflows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Qi; Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei
The paper provides empirical evidence that strategic complementarities among investors generate fragility in financial markets. Analyzing mutual fund data, we find that, consistent with a theoretical model, funds with illiquid assets (where complementarities are stronger) exhibit stronger sensitivity of outflows to bad past performance than funds with liquid assets. We also find that this pattern disappears in funds where the shareholder base is composed mostly of large investors. We present further evidence that these results are not attributable to alternative explanations based on the informativeness of past performance or on clientele effects. We analyze the implications for funds' performance and policies. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Qi; Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Going public to acquire? The acquisition motive in IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Celikyurt, Ugur; Sevilir, Merih; Shivdasani, Anil
Newly public firms make acquisitions at a torrid pace. Their large acquisition appetites reflect the concentration of initial public offerings (IPOs) in mergers and acquisitions(M&amp;A-) intensive industries, but acquisitions by IPO firms also outpace those by mature firms in the same industry. IPO firms' acquisition activity is fueled by the initial capital infusion at the IPO and through the creation of an acquisition currency used to raise capital for both cash- and stock-financed acquisitions along with debt issuance subsequent to the IPO. IPO firms play a bigger role in the M&amp;A process by participating as acquirers than they do as takeover targets, and acquisitions are as important to their growth as research and development (R&amp;D) and capital expenditures (CAPEX). The pattern of acquisitions following an WO shapes the evolution of ownership structure of newly public firms. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Celikyurt, Ugur; Sevilir, Merih; Shivdasani, Anil</author><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Average correlation and stock market returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pollet, Joshua M.; Wilson, Mungo
If the Roll critique is important, changes in the variance of the stock market may be only weakly related to changes in aggregate risk and subsequent stock market excess returns. However, since individual stock returns share a common sensitivity to true market return shocks, higher aggregate risk can be revealed by higher correlation between stocks. In addition, a change in stock market variance that leaves aggregate risk unchanged can have a zero or even negative effect on the stock market risk premium. We show that the average correlation between daily stock returns predicts subsequent quarterly stock market excess returns. We also show that changes in stock market risk holding average correlation constant can be interpreted as changes in the average variance of individual stocks. Such changes have a negative relation with future stock market excess returns. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pollet, Joshua M.; Wilson, Mungo</author><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and CEO turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bushman, Robert; Dai, Zhonglan; Wang, Xue
This paper investigates how performance risk impacts a board's ability to learn about the unknown talent of a chief executive officer (CEO). We theorize that the information content of performance is increasing in idiosyncratic risk and decreasing in systematic risk. We provide robust empirical evidence that the likelihood of CEO turnover is increasing in idiosyncratic risk and decreasing in systematic risk and that turnover performance-sensitivity is also increasing in idiosyncratic risk and decreasing in systematic risk. We further investigate relations between the threat of termination and CEO compensation, showing that for retained CEOs, both subsequent pay-performance-sensitivity and pay levels decrease in the probability of turnover. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bushman, Robert; Dai, Zhonglan; Wang, Xue</author><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Profiting from government stakes in a command economy: Evidence from Chinese asset sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calomiris, Charles W.; Fisman, Raymond; Wang, Yongxiang
We examine the market response to an unexpected announcement of the sale of government-owned shares in China. In contrast to earlier work, we find a negative effect of government ownership on returns at the announcement date and a symmetric positive effect from the policy's cancellation. We suggest that this results from the absence of a Chinese political transition to accompany economic reforms, so that the benefits of political ties outweigh the efficiency costs of government shareholdings. Companies managed by former government officials have positive abnormal returns, suggesting that personal ties can substitute for government ownership as a source of connections. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calomiris, Charles W.; Fisman, Raymond; Wang, Yongxiang</author><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade credit, collateral liquidation, and borrowing constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fabbri, Daniela; Menichini, Anna Maria C.
Assuming that firms' suppliers are better able to extract value from the liquidation of assets in default and have an information advantage over other creditors, the paper derives six predictions on the use of trade credit. (1) Financially unconstrained firms (with unused bank credit lines) take trade credit to exploit the supplier's liquidation advantage. (2) If inputs purchased on account are sufficiently liquid, the reliance on trade credit does not depend on credit rationing. (3) Firms buying goods make more purchases on account than those buying services, while suppliers of services offer more trade credit than those of standardized goods. (4) Suppliers lend inputs to their customers but not cash. (5) Greater reliance on trade credit is associated with more intensive use of tangible inputs. (6) Better creditor protection decreases both the use of trade credit and input tangibility. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fabbri, Daniela; Menichini, Anna Maria C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic asset allocation with stochastic income and interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Munk, Claus; Sorensen, Carsten
We solve for optimal portfolios when interest rates and labor income are stochastic with the expected income growth being affine in the short-term interest rate in order to encompass business cycle variations in wages. Our calibration based on the Panel Study of Income Dynamics (HID) data supports this relation with substantial variation across individuals in the slope of this affine function. The slope is crucial for the valuation and riskiness of human capital and for the optimal stock/bond/cash allocation both in an unconstrained complete market and in an incomplete market with liquidity and short-sales constraints. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Munk, Claus; Sorensen, Carsten</author><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncertainty about average profitability and the diversification discount</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hund, John; Monk, Donald; Tice, Sheri
The diversification discount (multiple segment firm value below the value imputed using single segment firm multiples) is commonly thought to be generated by agency problems, a lack of transparency, or lackluster future prospects for diversified firms. If multiple segment firms have lower uncertainty about mean profitability than single segment firms, rational learning about mean profitability provides an alternative explanation for the diversification discount that does not rely on suboptimal managerial decisions or a poor firm outlook. Empirical tests which examine changes in firm value across the business cycle and idiosyncratic volatility are consistent with lower uncertainty about mean profitability for multiple segment firms. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hund, John; Monk, Donald; Tice, Sheri</author><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board interlocks and the propensity to be targeted in private equity transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stuart, Toby E.; Yim, Soojin
We examine how board networks affect change-of-control transactions by investigating whether directors' deal exposure acquired through board service at different companies affect their current firms' likelihood of being targeted in a private equity-backed, take-private transaction. In our sample of all US publicly traded firms in 2000-2007, we find that companies which have directors with private equity deal exposure gained from interlocking directorships are approximately 42% more likely to receive private equity offers. The magnitude of this effect varies with the influence of directors on their current boards and the quality of these directors' previous take-private experience, and it is robust to the most likely classes of alternative explanations endogenous matching between directors and firms and proactive stacking of board composition by management. The analysis shows that board members and their social networks influence which companies become targets in change-of-control transactions. (c) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stuart, Toby E.; Yim, Soojin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and valuation in an uncertain world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen
During the 2007-2009 financial crisis there was little or no trading in a variety of financial assets, even though bid and ask prices existed for many of these assets. We develop a model in which this illiquidity arises from uncertainty, and we argue that this new form of illiquidity makes bid and ask prices unsuitable as metrics for establishing "fair value" for these assets. We show how the extreme uncertainty that traders face can be characterized by incomplete preferences over portfolios, and we use Bewley's (2002) model of decision making under uncertainty to derive equilibrium quotes and the nonexistence of trading at these quotes. We then suggest alternatives for valuing assets in illiquid markets. (c) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms appoint CEOs as outside directors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Low, Angie; Stulz, Rene M.
Companies actively seek to appoint outside CEOs to their boards. Consistent with our matching theory of outside CEO board appointments, we show that such appointments have a certification benefit for the appointing firm. CEOs are more likely to join boards of large established firms that are geographically close, pursue similar financial and investment policies, and have comparable governance to their own firms. The first outside CEO director appointment has a higher stock-price reaction than the appointment of another outside director. Except for a decrease in operating performance following the appointment of an interlocked director, CEO directors do not affect the appointing firm's operating performance, decision-making, and CEO compensation. (c) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Low, Angie; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The marketing of seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Xiaohui; Ritter, Jay R.
In an accelerated seasoned equity offering (SEO), an issuer foregoes the investment bank's marketing efforts in return for a lower fee. To explain why many issuing firms choose a higher cost fully marketed offer, we posit that the marketing effort flattens the issuer's short-run demand curve. Alternatively stated, with a fully marketed offer, the issuer is paying investment bankers to create demand, making the elasticity of demand at the time of issuance an endogenous choice variable. Empirical analysis shows that both the pre-issue elasticity of the issuing firm's demand curve and the offer size are important determinants of the offer method choice. We find evidence of a large transitory increase in the elasticity of demand for issuers conducting fully marketed SEOs. (c) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gao, Xiaohui; Ritter, Jay R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multi-market trading and arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gagnon, Louis; Karolyi, G. Andrew
We measure arbitrage opportunities by comparing the intraday prices and quotes of American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) and other types of cross-listed shares in U.S. markets with synchronous prices of their home-market shares on a currency-adjusted basis for a sample of 506 U.S. cross-listed stocks from 35 different countries. Deviations from price parity average an economically small 4.9 basis points, but they are volatile and can reach large extremes. Price parity deviations and their daily changes are positively related to proxies for holding costs that can impede arbitrage, even after controlling for transactions costs and foreign investment restrictions. (c) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gagnon, Louis; Karolyi, G. Andrew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local institutional investors, information asymmetries, and equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baik, Bok; Kang, Jun-Koo; Kim, Jin-Mo
We examine the informational role of geographically proximate institutions in stock markets. We find that both the level of and change in local institutional ownership predict future stock returns, particularly for firms with high information asymmetry; in contrast, such predictive abilities are relatively weak for nonlocal institutional ownership. The local advantage is especially evident for local investment advisors, high local ownership institutions, and high local turnover institutions. We also find that the stocks that local institutional investors hold (trade) earn higher excess returns around future earnings announcements than those that nonlocal institutional investors hold (trade). (c) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baik, Bok; Kang, Jun-Koo; Kim, Jin-Mo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comovement, information production, and the business cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, Paul; Liebenberg, Ivonne; Schutte, Maria
Recent theoretical research suggests that information production is a positive externality of aggregate economic activity (Veldkamp, 2005). Both the quantity and quality of information increase during periods of economic expansion and decrease during periods of contraction. Based on this insight, we hypothesize and confirm that time-varying information production drives the comovement patterns observed in stock returns. We examine stock return comovement in 36 countries from 1980 to 2007 and show that, consistent with the theory, comovement patterns are countercyclical; that is, when information production is high (low), comovement is low (high). We also find that the relation between comovement and the business cycle is stronger in countries that experience large intertemporal swings in information production. Finally, we show that the relation between business cycle and comovement is stronger in poor countries, countries with less developed financial markets, and countries with weaker accounting and transparency standards. These results suggest that financial development and transparency are conducive to a steady flow of financial information over the business cycle. (c) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brockman, Paul; Liebenberg, Ivonne; Schutte, Maria</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns of claims on the upside and the viability of U-shaped pricing kernels</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Madan, Dilip; Panayotov, George
When the pricing kernel is U-shaped, then expected returns of claims with payout on the upside are negative for strikes beyond a threshold, determined by the slope of the U-shaped kernel in its increasing region, and have negative partial derivative with respect to strike in the increasing region of the kernel. Using returns of (i) S&amp;P 500 index calls, (ii) calls on major international equity indexes, (iii) digital calls, (iv) upside variance contracts, and (v) a theoretical construct that we denote as kernel call, we find broad support for the implications of U-shaped pricing kernels. A possible theoretical reconciliation of our empirical findings is explored through a model that accommodates heterogeneity in beliefs about return outcomes and short-selling. (c) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Madan, Dilip; Panayotov, George</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preferred risk habitat of individual investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dorn, Daniel; Huberman, Gur
The preferred risk habitat hypothesis, introduced here, is that individual investors select stocks whose volatilities are commensurate with their risk aversion. The data, 1995-2000 holdings of over 20,000 clients at a large German broker, are consistent with the predictions of the hypothesis: the returns of stocks within each portfolio have remarkably similar volatilities, when stocks are sold they are replaced by stocks of similar volatilities, and the more risk-averse customers indeed hold less volatile stocks. Greater volatility specialization is associated with lower Sharpe ratios, primarily because more specialized investors hold fewer stocks and thereby expose themselves to more unsystematic risk. (c) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dorn, Daniel; Huberman, Gur</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The 2007-8 financial crisis: Lessons from corporate finance Introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kashyap, Anil K.; Zingales, Luigi
nan</description><author>Kashyap, Anil K.; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unstable banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shleifer, Andrei; Vishny, Robert W.
We propose a theory of financial intermediaries operating in markets influenced by investor sentiment. In our model, banks make, securitize, distribute, and trade loans, or they hold cash. They also borrow money, using their security holdings as collateral. Banks maximize profits, and there are no conflicts of interest between bank shareholders and creditors. The theory predicts that bank credit and real investment will be volatile when market prices of loans are volatile, but it also points to the instability of banks, especially leveraged banks, participating in markets. Profit-maximizing behavior by banks creates systemic risk. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shleifer, Andrei; Vishny, Robert W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank lending during the financial crisis of 2008</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivashina, Victoria; Scharfstein, David
This paper shows that new loans to large borrowers fell by 47% during the peak period of the financial crisis (fourth quarter of 2008) relative to the prior quarter and by 79% relative to the peak of the credit boom (second quarter of 2007). New lending for real investment (such as working capital and capital expenditures) fell by only 14% in the last quarter of 2008, but contracted nearly as much as new lending for restructuring (LBO5, M&amp;As, share repurchases) relative to the peak of the credit boom. After the failure of Lehman Brothers in September 2008, there was a run by short-term bank creditors, making it difficult for banks to roll over their short term debt. We find that there was a simultaneous run by borrowers who drew down their credit lines, leading to a spike in commercial and industrial loans reported on bank balance sheets. We examine whether these two stresses on bank liquidity led them to cut lending. In particular, we show that banks cut their lending less if they had better access to deposit financing and thus, they were not as reliant on short-term debt. We also show that banks that were more vulnerable to credit-line drawdowns because they co-syndicated more of their credit lines with Lehman Brothers reduced their lending to a greater extent. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ivashina, Victoria; Scharfstein, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Paulson's gift</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Veronesi, Pietro; Zingales, Luigi
We calculate the costs and benefits of the largest ever US government intervention in the financial sector announced during the 2008 Columbus-day weekend. We estimate that this intervention increased the value of banks' financial claims by $130 billion (bn) at a taxpayers' cost of $21-$44 billion with a net benefit between $86 and $109 bn. By looking at the limited cross section, we infer that this net benefit arises from a reduction in the probability of bankruptcy, which we estimate would destroy 22% of the enterprise value. The big winners of the plan were the bondholders of the three former investment banks and Citigroup, while the losers were JP Morgan shareholders and the US taxpayers. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Veronesi, Pietro; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and distressed loan renegotiation: Evidence from the subprime mortgage crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piskorski, Tomasz; Seru, Amit; Vig, Vikrant
We examine whether securitization impacts renegotiation decisions of loan servicers, focusing on their decision to foreclose a delinquent loan. Conditional on a loan becoming seriously delinquent, we find a significantly lower foreclosure rate associated with bank-held loans when compared to similar securitized loans: across various specifications and origination vintages, the foreclosure rate of delinquent bank-held loans is 3% to 7% lower in absolute terms (13% to 32% in relative terms). There is a substantial heterogeneity in these effects with large effects among borrowers with better credit quality and small effects among lower quality borrowers. A quasi-experiment that exploits a plausibly exogenous variation in securitization status of a delinquent loan confirms these results. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Piskorski, Tomasz; Seru, Amit; Vig, Vikrant</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Will the US bank recapitalization succeed? Eight lessons from Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoshi, Takeo; Kashyap, Anil K.
During the financial crisis that started in 2007, the U.S. government has used a variety of tools to try to rehabilitate the U.S. banking industry. Many of those strategies were also used in Japan to combat its banking problems in the 1990s. There are also a surprising number of other similarities between the current U.S. crisis and the recent Japanese crisis. The Japanese policies were only partially successful in recapitalizing the banks until the economy finally started to recover in 2003. From these unsuccessful attempts, we derive eight lessons. In light of these eight lessons, we assess the policies the U.S. has pursued. The U.S. has ignored three of the lessons and it is too early to evaluate the U.S. policies with respect to four of the others. So far, the U.S. has avoided Japan's problem of having impaired banks prop up zombie firms. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hoshi, Takeo; Kashyap, Anil K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Costly external finance, corporate investment, and the subprime mortgage credit crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duchin, Ran; Ozbas, Oguzhan; Sensoy, Berk A.
We study the effect of the recent financial crisis on corporate investment. The crisis represents an unexplored negative shock to the supply of external finance for non-financial firms. Corporate investment declines significantly following the onset of the crisis, controlling for firm fixed effects and time-varying measures of investment opportunities. Consistent with a causal effect of a supply shock, the decline is greatest for firms that have low cash reserves or high net short-term debt, are financially constrained, or operate in industries dependent on external finance. To address endogeneity concerns, we measure firms' financial positions as much as four years prior to the crisis, and confirm that similar results do not follow placebo crises in the summers of 2003-2006. Nor do similar results follow the negative demand shock caused by September 11, 2001. The effects weaken considerably beginning in the third quarter of 2008, when the demand-side effects of the crisis became apparent. Additional analysis suggests an important precautionary savings motive for seemingly excess cash that is generally overlooked in the literature. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duchin, Ran; Ozbas, Oguzhan; Sensoy, Berk A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The subprime credit crisis and contagion in financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, Francis A.
I conduct an empirical investigation into the pricing of subprime asset-backed collateralized debt obligations (CDOs) and their contagion effects on other markets. Using data for the ABX subprime indexes, I find strong evidence of contagion in the financial markets. The results support the hypothesis that financial contagion was propagated primarily through liquidity and risk-premium channels, rather than through a correlated-information channel. Surprisingly, ABX index returns forecast stock returns and Treasury and corporate bond yield changes by as much as three weeks ahead during the subprime crisis. This challenges the popular view that the market prices of these "toxic assets" were unreliable; the results suggest that significant price discovery did in fact occur in the subprime market during the crisis. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Longstaff, Francis A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Auction failures and the market for auction rate securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McConnell, John J.; Saretto, Alessio
The market for auction rate securities (ARS) made headlines during the second week of February 2008 when auctions at which the bonds' interest rates reset experienced a wave of "failures." Contrary to headlines that attribute the failures to a "frozen" market or investors' "irrationality," we find that (1) even at their height, less than 50% of ARS experienced auction failures, (2) the likelihood of auction failure was directly related to the level of the bonds' "maximum auction rates," (3) the implied market clearing yields of bonds with failed auctions were significantly above their maximum auction rates, and (4) ARS yields were generally higher than yields of various cash equivalent investment alternatives. We infer that investors priced the possibility of auctions failures into ARS yields and rationally declined to bid for bonds for which required market yields exceeded their maximum auction rates. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McConnell, John J.; Saretto, Alessio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The real effects of financial constraints: Evidence from a financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Graham, John R.; Harvey, Campbell R.
We survey 1,050 Chief Financial Officers (CFOs) in the U.S., Europe, and Asia to directly assess whether their firms are credit constrained during the global financial crisis of 2008. We study whether corporate spending plans differ conditional on this survey-based measure of financial constraint. Our evidence indicates that constrained firms planned deeper cuts in tech spending, employment, and capital spending. Constrained firms also burned through more cash, drew more heavily on lines of credit for fear banks would restrict access in the future, and sold more assets to fund their operations. We also find that the inability to borrow externally caused many firms to bypass attractive investment opportunities, with 86% of constrained U.S. CFOs saying their investment in attractive projects was restricted during the credit crisis of 2008. More than half of the respondents said they canceled or postponed their planned investments. Our results also hold in Europe and Asia, and in many cases are stronger in those economies. Our analysis adds to the portfolio of approaches and knowledge about the impact of credit constraints on real firm behavior. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Graham, John R.; Harvey, Campbell R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CFOs and CEOs: Who have the most influence on earnings management?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, John; Petroni, Kathy R.; Wang, Isabel Yanyan
This study examines the association between chief financial officer (CFO) equity incentives and earnings management. Chief executive officer (CEO) equity incentives have been shown to be associated with accruals management and the likelihood of beating analyst forecasts (Bergstresser and Philippon, 2006; Cheng and Warfield, 2005). Because CFOs' primary responsibility is financial reporting. CFO equity incentives should play a stronger role than those of the CEO in earnings management. We find that the magnitude of accruals and the likelihood of beating analyst forecasts are more sensitive to CFO equity incentives than to those of the CEO. Our evidence supports the Securities and Exchange Commission's (SEC) new disclosure requirement on CFO compensation. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, John; Petroni, Kathy R.; Wang, Isabel Yanyan</author><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tunneling through intercorporate loans: The China experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Guohua; Lee, Charles M. C.; Yue, Heng
This study investigates a particularly brazen form of corporate abuse, in which controlling shareholders use intercorporate loans to siphon billions of RMB from hundreds of Chinese listed companies during the 1996-2006 period. We document the nature and extent of these transactions, evaluate their economic consequences, examine factors that affect their cross-sectional severity, and report on the mitigating roles of auditors, institutional investors, and regulators. Collectively, our findings shed light on the severity of the minority shareholder expropriation problem in China, as well as the relative efficacy of various legal and extra-legal governance mechanisms in that country. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Guohua; Lee, Charles M. C.; Yue, Heng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives corporate liquidity? An international survey of cash holdings and lines of credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lins, Karl V.; Servaes, Henri; Tufano, Peter
We survey chief financial officers from 29 countries to examine whether and why firms use lines of credit versus non-operational (excess) cash for their corporate liquidity. We find that these two liquidity sources are employed to hedge against different risks. Nonoperational cash guards against future cash flow shocks in bad times, while credit lines give firms the option to exploit future business opportunities available in good times. Lines of credit are the dominant source of liquidity for companies around the world, comprising about 15% of assets, while less than half of the cash held by companies is held for non-operational purposes, comprising about 2% of assets. Across countries, firms make greater use of lines of credit when external credit markets are poorly developed. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lins, Karl V.; Servaes, Henri; Tufano, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing American options under stochastic volatility and stochastic interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Medvedev, Alexey; Scaillet, Olivier
We introduce a new analytical approach to price American options. Using an explicit and intuitive proxy for the exercise rule, we derive tractable pricing formulas using a short-maturity asymptotic expansion. Depending on model parameters, this method can accurately price options with time-to-maturity up to several years. The main advantage of our approach over existing methods lies in its straightforward extension to models with stochastic volatility and stochastic interest rates. We exploit this advantage by providing an analysis of the impact of volatility mean-reversion, volatility of volatility, and correlations on the American put price. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Medvedev, Alexey; Scaillet, Olivier</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating affine multifactor term structure models using closed-form likelihood expansions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ait-Sahalia, Yacine; Kimmel, Robert L.
We develop and implement a technique for closed-form maximum likelihood estimation (MLE) of multifactor affine yield models. We derive closed-form approximations to likelihoods for nine Dai and Singleton (2000) affine models. Simulations show our technique very accurately approximates true (but infeasible) MLE. Using US Treasury data, we estimate nine affine yield models with different market price of risk specifications. MLE allows non-nested model comparison using likelihood ratio tests; the preferred model depends on the market price of risk. Estimation with simulated and real data suggests our technique is much closer to true MLE than Euler and quasi-maximum likelihood (QML) methods. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ait-Sahalia, Yacine; Kimmel, Robert L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneity and peer effects in mutual fund proxy voting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Matvos, Gregor; Ostrovsky, Michael
This paper studies voting in corporate director elections. We construct a comprehensive data set of 2,058,788 mutual fund votes over a two-year period. We find systematic heterogeneity in voting: some funds are consistently more management-friendly than others. We also establish the presence of peer effects: a fund is more likely to oppose management when other funds are more likely to oppose it, all else being equal. We estimate a voting model whose supermodular structure allows us to compute social multipliers due to peer effects. Heterogeneity and peer effects are as important in shaping voting outcomes as firm and director characteristics. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Matvos, Gregor; Ostrovsky, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring the timing ability and performance of bond mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yong; Person, Wayne; Peters, Helen
This paper evaluates the ability of bond funds to "market time" nine common factors related to bond markets. Timing ability generates nonlinearity in fund returns as a function of common factors, but there are several non-timing-related sources of nonlinearity. Controlling for the non-timing-related nonlinearity is important. Funds' returns are more concave than benchmark returns, and this would appear as poor timing ability in naive models. With controls, the timing coefficients appear neutral to weakly positive. Adjusting for nonlinearity, the performance of many bond funds is significantly negative on an after-cost basis, but significantly positive on a before-cost basis. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Yong; Person, Wayne; Peters, Helen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity risk and the cross-section of hedge-fund returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sadka, Ronnie
This paper demonstrates that liquidity risk as measured by the covariation of fund returns with unexpected changes in aggregate liquidity is an important determinant in the cross-section of hedge-fund returns. The results show that funds that significantly load on liquidity risk subsequently outperform low-loading funds by about 6% annually, on average, over the period 1994-2008, while negative performance is observed during liquidity crises. The returns are independent of the liquidity a fund provides to its investors as measured by lockup and redemption notice periods, and they are also robust to commonly used hedge-fund factors, none of which carries a significant premium during the sample period. These findings highlight the importance of understanding systematic liquidity variations in the evaluation of hedge-fund performance. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying the effects of a lender of last resort on financial markets: Lessons from the founding of the fed</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Asaf; Hughson, Eric; Weidenmier, Marc D.
We use the founding of the Federal Reserve to identify the effects of a lender of last resort. We examine stock return and interest rate volatility during September and October, when markets were vulnerable because of financial stringency from the harvest. Stock volatility fell by 40% and interest rate volatility by more than 70% following the monetary regime change. The drop is insignificant if major panic years are omitted from the analysis, however. Because business cycle downturns occurred in the same year as financial crises, our results suggest that the existence of the Federal Reserve reduced liquidity risk. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bernstein, Asaf; Hughson, Eric; Weidenmier, Marc D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short selling in initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edwards, Amy K.; Hanley, Kathleen Weiss
Short sale constraints in the aftermarket of initial public offerings (IPOs) are often used to explain short-term underpricing that is subsequently reversed. This paper shows that short selling is integral to aftermarket trading and is higher in IPOs with greater underpricing. Perceived restrictions on borrowing shares are not systematically circumvented by "naked" short selling. Short sellers, on average, do not appear to earn abnormal profits in the near term and our findings are not driven by market makers. Short selling in IPOs is not as constrained as suggested by the literature, implying that other factors may be responsible for underpricing. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Edwards, Amy K.; Hanley, Kathleen Weiss</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Auctioned IPOs: The US evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degeorge, Francois; Derrien, Francois; Womack, Kent L.
Between 1999 and 2007, WR Hambrecht completed 19 initial public offerings (IPOs) in the US using an auction mechanism. We analyze investor behavior and mechanism performance in these auctioned IPOs using detailed bidding data. The existence of some bids posted at high prices suggests that some investors (mostly retail) try to free-ride on the mechanism. But institutional demand in these auctions is very elastic, suggesting that institutional investors reveal information in the bidding process. Investor participation is largely predictable based on deal size, and demand is dominated by institutions. Flipping is at most as prevalent in auctions as in bookbuilt deals. But, unlike in bookbuilding, investors in auctions do not flip their shares more in "hot" deals. Finally, we find that institutional investors, who provide more information, are rewarded by obtaining a larger share of the deals that have higher 10-day underpricing. Our results therefore suggest that auctioned IPOs can be an effective alternative to traditional bookbuilding. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Degeorge, Francois; Derrien, Francois; Womack, Kent L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Have the tax benefits of debt been overestimated?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blouin, Jennifer; Core, John E.; Guay, Wayne
We re-examine the claim that many corporations are underleveraged in that they fail to take full advantage of debt tax shields. We show prior results suggesting underleverage stems from biased estimates of tax benefits from interest deductions. We develop improved estimates of marginal tax rates using a non-parametric procedure that produces more accurate estimates of the distribution of future taxable income. We show that additional debt would provide firms with much smaller tax benefits than previously thought, and when expected distress costs and difficult-to-measure non-debt tax shields are also considered, it appears plausible that most firms have tax-efficient capital structures. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blouin, Jennifer; Core, John E.; Guay, Wayne</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Club deals in leveraged buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Officer, Micah S.; Ozbas, Oguzhan; Sensoy, Berk A.
We analyze the pricing and characteristics of club deal leveraged buyouts (LBOs)-those in which two or more private equity partnerships jointly conduct an LBO. Using a comprehensive sample of completed LBOs of U.S. publicly traded targets conducted by prominent private equity firms, we find that target shareholders receive approximately 10% less of pre-bid firm equity value, or roughly 40% lower premiums, in club deals compared to sole-sponsored LBOs. This result is concentrated before 2006 and in target firms with low institutional ownership. These results are robust to controls for target and deal characteristics, including size, Q measures of risk, and time and industry fixed effects. We find little support for benign motivations for club deals based on capital constraints, diversification motives, or the ability of clubs to obtain favorable debt amounts or prices, but it is possible that the lower pricing of club deals is an inadvertent byproduct of an unobserved benign motivation for club formation. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Officer, Micah S.; Ozbas, Oguzhan; Sensoy, Berk A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Negotiations under the threat of an auction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Roll, Richard
Many takeovers occur after one-on-one negotiations, which suggests a troubling lack of competition. We seek to determine whether acquirers in such friendly deals are truly insulated from competitive pressures. We study two countervailing influences: (1) potential but unobserved latent competition, i.e., the likelihood that rival bidders could appear, and (2) anticipated auction costs when negotiations fail. Using various proxies, we find that latent competition increases the bid premium offered in negotiated deals and that auction costs reduce the premium. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Habit formation, the cross section of stock returns and the cash-flow risk puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santos, Tano; Veronesi, Pietro
Non-linear external habit persistence models, which feature prominently in the recent "equity premium" asset pricing and macroeconomics literature, generate counterfactual predictions in the cross-section of stock returns. In particular, we show that in the absence of cross-sectional heterogeneity in firms' cash-flow risk, these models produce a "growth premium," that is, stocks with high price-to-fundamental ratios command a higher premium than stocks with low price-to-fundamental ratios. This implication is at odds with the well-established empirical observation of a "value premium" in the cross-section of stock returns. Substantial heterogeneity in firms' cash-flow risk yields both a value premium as well as most of the stylized facts about the cross-section of stock returns, but it generates a "cash-flow risk puzzle": Quantitatively, value stocks have to have "too much" cash-flow risk compared to the data to generate empirically plausible value premiums. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Santos, Tano; Veronesi, Pietro</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of excess cash and corporate governance: Evidence from US cross-listings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fresard, Laurent; Salva, Carolina
We examine whether and how a US cross-listing mitigates the risk that insiders will turn their firm's cash holdings into private benefits. We find strong evidence that the value investors attach to excess cash reserves is substantially larger for foreign firms listed on US exchanges and over-the-counter than for their domestic peers. Further, we show that this excess-cash premium stems not only from the strength of US legal rules and disclosure requirements, but also from the greater informal monitoring pressure that accompanies a US listing. Overall, because investors' valuation of excess cash mirrors how they expect the cash to be used, our analysis shows that a US listing constrains insiders' inefficient allocation of corporate cash reserves significantly. (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Fresard, Laurent; Salva, Carolina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inter-temporal variation in the illiquidity premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jensen, Gerald R.; Moorman, Theodore
We find evidence of a systematic link between monetary conditions and inter-temporal variation in the price of liquidity. Specifically, following an expansive monetary policy shift, funding conditions improve and market-wide liquidity increases, which is especially beneficial for illiquid securities. The improved liquidity and funding conditions reduce the returns required for holding illiquid securities. Consequently, illiquid stocks experience relatively large price increases when monetary conditions become expansive, and thus, the measured return spread between illiquid and liquid stocks expands substantially. Overall, our evidence supports the claim that the price of asset liquidity is dependent on monetary conditions. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jensen, Gerald R.; Moorman, Theodore</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal exercise of executive stock options and implications for firm cost</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carpenter, Jennifer N.; Stanton, Richard; Wallace, Nancy
This paper conducts a comprehensive study of the optimal exercise policy for an executive stock option and its implications for option cost, average life, and alternative valuation concepts. The paper is the first to provide analytical results for an executive with general concave utility. Wealthier or less risk-averse executives exercise later and create greater option cost. However, option cost can decline with volatility. We show when there exists a single exercise boundary, yet demonstrate the possibility of a split continuation region. We also show that, for constant relative risk averse utility, the option value does not converge to the Black and Scholes value as the correlation between the stock and the market portfolio converges to one. We compare our model's option cost with the modified Black and Scholes approximation typically used in practice and show that the approximation error can be large or small, positive or negative, depending on firm characteristics. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carpenter, Jennifer N.; Stanton, Richard; Wallace, Nancy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does q-theory with investment frictions explain anomalies in the cross section of returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Dongmei; Zhang, Lu
Q-theory predicts that investment frictions steepen the relation between expected returns and firm investment. Using financing constraints to proxy for investment frictions, we show only weak evidence that the investment-to-assets and asset growth effects in the cross section of returns are stronger in financially more constrained firms than in financially less constrained firms. There is no evidence that q-theory with investment frictions explains the investment growth, net stock issues, abnormal corporate investment, or net operating assets anomalies. Limits-to-arbitrage proxies dominate q-theory with investment frictions in explaining the magnitude of the investment-to-assets and asset growth anomalies in direct comparisons. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Dongmei; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The equity premium implied by production</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jermann, Urban J.
This paper studies the determinants of the equity premium as implied by producers' first-order conditions. A simple closed form expression is presented for the Sharpe ratio as a function of investment volatility and technology parameters. Calibrated to the US postwar economy, the model can match the historical first and second moments of the market return and the risk-free interest rate. The model also generates a very volatile Sharpe ratio and market price of risk. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jermann, Urban J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm values and sovereign wealth fund investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dewenter, Kathryn L.; Han, Xi; Malatesta, Paul H.
We analyze the impact of sovereign wealth fund (SWF) investments on firm values and provide evidence consistent with the tradeoff between the monitoring and lobbying benefits versus tunneling and expropriation costs of SWFs as blockholders. The data show significant positive (negative) returns to announcements of SWF investments (divestments). The returns are non-monotonic, first rising (falling) and then falling (rising) with the share sought (sold) for investments (divestments). Moreover, we find that SWFs are often active investors. Slightly more than half of the target firms experience one or more events indicative of SWF monitoring activity or influence. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dewenter, Kathryn L.; Han, Xi; Malatesta, Paul H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differences in beliefs and currency risk premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beber, Alessandro; Breedon, Francis; Buraschi, Andrea
This paper studies the importance of heterogeneous beliefs for the dynamics of asset prices. We focus on currency markets, where the absence of short-selling constraints allows us to perform sharper tests of theoretical predictions. Using a unique data set with detailed information on foreign-exchange forecasts, we construct an empirical proxy for differences in beliefs. We show that this proxy has a strong effect on the implied volatility of currency options beyond the volatility of macroeconomic fundamentals. We document that differences in beliefs impact also on the shape of the implied volatility smile, on the volatility risk-premiums, and on future currency returns. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beber, Alessandro; Breedon, Francis; Buraschi, Andrea</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rating the ratings: How good are commercial governance ratings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daines, Robert M.; Gow, Ian D.; Larcker, David F.
Proxy advisory and corporate governance rating firms (such as RiskMetrics/Institutional Shareholder Services, GovernanceMetrics International, and The Corporate Library) play an increasingly important role in U.S. public markets. They rank the quality of firm corporate governance, advise shareholders how to vote, and sometimes press for governance changes. We examine whether commercially available corporate governance rankings provide useful information for shareholders. Our results suggest that they do not. Commercial ratings do not predict governance-related outcomes with the precision or strength necessary to support the bold claims made by most of these firms. Moreover, we find little or no relation between the governance ratings provided by RiskMetrics with either their voting recommendations or the actual votes by shareholders on proxy proposals. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Daines, Robert M.; Gow, Ian D.; Larcker, David F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do subjective expectations explain asset pricing puzzles?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Skoulakis, Georgios
The structural uncertainty model with Bayesian learning, advanced by Weitzman (AER 2007), provides a framework for gauging the effect of structural uncertainty on asset prices and risk premiums. This paper provides an operational version of this approach that incorporates realistic priors about consumption growth volatility, while guaranteeing finite asset pricing quantities. In contrast to the extant literature, the resulting asset pricing model with subjective expectations yields well-defined expected utility, finite moment generating function of the predictive distribution of consumption growth, and tractable expressions for equity premium and risk-free return. Our quantitative analysis reveals that explaining the historical equity premium and risk-free return, in the context of subjective expectations, requires implausible levels of structural uncertainty. Furthermore, these implausible prior beliefs result in consumption disaster probabilities that virtually coincide with those implied by more realistic priors. At the same time, the two sets of prior beliefs have diametrically opposite asset pricing implications. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Skoulakis, Georgios</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate venture capital and the returns to acquiring portfolio companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benson, David; Ziedonis, Rosemarie H.
A prominent motive for corporate venture capital (CVC) is the identification of entrepreneurial-firm acquisition opportunities. Consistent with this view, we find that one of every five startups purchased by 61 top corporate investors from 1987 through 2003 is a venture portfolio company of its acquirer. Surprisingly, our analysis reveals that takeovers of portfolio companies destroy significant value for shareholders of acquisitive CVC investors, even though these same investors are "good acquirers" of other entrepreneurial firms. We explore numerous explanations for these puzzling findings, which seem rooted in managerial overconfidence or agency problems at the program level. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benson, David; Ziedonis, Rosemarie H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>More insiders, more insider trading: Evidence from private-equity buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Johnson, Timothy C.
Prior theoretical research has found that, in the absence of regulation, a greater number of insiders leads to more insider trading. We show that optimal regulation features detection and punishment policies that become stricter as the number of insiders increases, reducing insider trading in equilibrium. We construct measures of the likelihood of insider activity prior to bid announcements of private-equity buyouts during the period 2000-2006 and relate these to the number of financing participants. Suspicious stock and options activity is associated with more equity participants, while suspicious bond and CDS activity is associated with more debt participants consistent with models of limited competition among insiders but inconsistent with our model of optimal regulation. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Johnson, Timothy C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mispricing of dual-class shares: Profit opportunities, arbitrage, and trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, Paul; Shive, Sophie
This is the first paper to examine the microstructure of how mispricing is created and resolved. We study dual-class shares with equal cash flow rights and show that a simple trading strategy exploiting gaps between their prices appears to create abnormal profits after transactions costs. Trade and quote data show that investors shift their trading patterns to take advantage of gaps. Contrary to common perception, long-short arbitrage plays a minor part in eliminating gaps, and one-sided trades correct most of them. We also show that the more liquid share class is usually responsible for the price discrepancies. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schultz, Paul; Shive, Sophie</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of independent directors: Evidence from sudden deaths</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, Bang Dang; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner
We investigate contributions of independent directors to shareholder value by examining stock price reactions to sudden deaths in the US from 1994 to 2007. We find, first, that following director death stock prices drop by 0.85% on average. Second, the degree of independence and board structure determine the marginal value of independent directors. Third, independence is more valuable in crucial board functions. Finally, controlling for director-invariant heterogeneity using a fixed effect approach, we identify the value of independence over and above the value of individual skills and competences. Overall, our results suggest that independent directors provide a valuable service to shareholders. (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Nguyen, Bang Dang; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market for certification by external parties: Evidence from underwriting and banking relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duarte-Silva, Tiago
This paper provides evidence that an underwriter is better able to certify an equity issue if it has a lending relationship with the firm. An announcement of being underwritten by the firm's lending-relationship bank reduces ex post information asymmetry, thereby improving the announcement return. Further, because this reduction in information asymmetry effectively disseminates what was previously the lending bank's private information, it decreases its affiliated market maker's information advantage, thus reducing its contribution to price discovery and liquidity. These results provide evidence on the value of information production and transmission by banks, and more generally on the role of external parties in reducing information asymmetry. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duarte-Silva, Tiago</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nature or nurture: What determines investor behavior?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barnea, Amir; Cronqvist, Henrik; Siegel, Stephan
Using data on identical and fraternal twins' complete financial portfolios, we decompose the cross-sectional variation in investor behavior. We find that a genetic factor explains about one-third of the variance in stock market participation and asset allocation. Family environment has an effect on the behavior of young individuals, but this effect is not long-lasting and disappears as an individual gains experience. Frequent contact among twins results in similar investment behavior beyond a genetic factor. Twins who grew up in different environments still display similar investment behavior. Our interpretation of a genetic component of the decision to invest in the stock market is that there are innate differences in factors affecting effective stock market participation costs. We attribute the genetic component of asset allocation the relative amount invested in equities and the portfolio volatility to genetic variation in risk preferences. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barnea, Amir; Cronqvist, Henrik; Siegel, Stephan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monotonicity in asset returns: New tests with applications to the term structure, the CAPM, and portfolio sorts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patton, Andrew J.; Timmermann, Allan
Many theories in finance imply monotonic patterns in expected returns and other financial variables. The liquidity preference hypothesis predicts higher expected returns for bonds with longer times to maturity; the Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM) implies higher expected returns for stocks with higher betas; and standard asset pricing models imply that the pricing kernel is declining in market returns. The full set of implications of monotonicity is generally not exploited in empirical work, however. This paper proposes new and simple ways to test for monotonicity in financial variables and compares the proposed tests with extant alternatives such as r-tests, Bonferroni bounds, and multivariate inequality tests through empirical applications and simulations. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Patton, Andrew J.; Timmermann, Allan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank activity and funding strategies: The impact on risk and returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Huizinga, Harry
This paper examines the implications of bank activity and short-term funding strategies for bank risk and return using an international sample of 1,334 banks in 101 countries leading up to the 2008 financial crisis. Expansion into noninterest income-generating activities such as trading increases the rate of return on assets, and it could offer some risk diversification benefits at very low levels. Nondeposit, wholesale funding in contrast lowers the rate of return on assets, while it can offer some risk reduction at commonly observed low levels of nondeposit funding. A sizable proportion of banks, however, attract most of their short-term funding in the form of nondeposits at a cost of enhanced bank fragility. Overall, banking strategies that rely prominently on generating noninterest income or attracting nondeposit funding are very risky, consistent with the demise of the US investment banking sector. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Huizinga, Harry</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor rights, information sharing, and bank risk taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Houston, Joel F.; Lin, Chen; Lin, Ping; Ma, Yue
Looking at a sample of nearly 2,400 banks in 69 countries, we find that stronger creditor rights tend to promote greater bank risk taking. Consistent with this finding, we also show that stronger creditor rights increase the likelihood of financial crisis. On the plus side, we find that stronger creditor rights are associated with higher growth. In contrast, we find that the benefits of information sharing among creditors appear to be universally positive. Greater information sharing leads to higher bank profitability, lower bank risk, a reduced likelihood of financial crisis, and higher economic growth. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Houston, Joel F.; Lin, Chen; Lin, Ping; Ma, Yue</author><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Escape from New York: The market impact of loosening disclosure requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandes, Nuno; Lel, Ugur; Miller, Darius P.
We examine the first significant deregulation of U.S. disclosure requirements since the passage of the 1933/1934 Exchange and Securities Acts: the 2007 Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) Rule 12h-6. Rule 12h-6 has made it easier for foreign firms to deregister with the SEC and thereby terminate their U.S. disclosure obligations. We show that the market reacted negatively to the announcement by the SEC that firms from countries with weak disclosure and governance regimes could more easily opt out of the stringent U.S. reporting and legal environment. We also find that since the rule's passage, an unprecedented number of firms have deregistered, and these firms often had been previous targets of U.S. class action securities lawsuits or SEC enforcement actions. Our findings suggest that shareholders of non-U.S firms place significant value on U.S. securities regulations, especially when the home country investor protections are weak. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fernandes, Nuno; Lel, Ugur; Miller, Darius P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sentiment and stock prices: The case of aviation disasters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplanski, Guy; Levy, Haim
Behavioral economic studies reveal that negative sentiment driven by bad mood and anxiety affects investment decisions and may hence affect asset pricing. In this study we examine the effect of aviation disasters on stock prices. We find evidence of a significant negative event effect with an average market loss of more than $60 billion per aviation disaster, whereas the estimated actual loss is no more than $1 billion. In two days a price reversal occurs. We find the effect to be greater in small and riskier stocks and in firms belonging to less stable industries. This event effect is also accompanied by an increase in the perceived risk: implied volatility increases after aviation disasters without an increase in actual volatility. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaplanski, Guy; Levy, Haim</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership concentration, foreign shareholding, audit quality, and stock price synchronicity: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gul, Ferdinand A.; Kim, Jeong-Bon; Qiu, Annie A.
This paper investigates the effects of largest-shareholder ownership concentration, foreign ownership, and audit quality on the amount of firm-specific information incorporated into share prices, as measured by stock price synchronicity, of Chinese-listed firms over the 1996-2003 period. We show that synchronicity is a concave function of ownership by the largest shareholder with its maximum at an approximate 50% level. Further, we find that synchronicity is higher when the largest shareholder is government related. We also find that foreign ownership and auditor quality are inversely associated with synchronicity. Finally, we show that the amount of earnings information reflected in stock returns is lower for firms with high synchronicity. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gul, Ferdinand A.; Kim, Jeong-Bon; Qiu, Annie A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When should firms share credit with employees? Evidence from anonymously managed mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Reuter, Jonathan; Zitzewitz, Eric
We study the choice between named and anonymous Mutual fund managers. We argue that fund families weigh the benefits of naming managers against the cost associated with their increased future bargaining power. Named managers receive more media mentions, have greater inflows, and suffer less return diversion due to within family cross-subsidization, but departures of named managers reduce net flows. Naming managers became less common between 1993 and 2004. This was especially true in the asset classes and cities most affected by the hedge fund boom, which increased outside opportunities for, and the cost of retaining, successful named managers. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Reuter, Jonathan; Zitzewitz, Eric</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Renegotiation of cash flow rights in the sale of VC-backed firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Broughman, Brian; Fried, Jesse
Incomplete contracting theory suggests that venture capitalist (VC) cash flow rights, including liquidation preferences, could be subject to renegotiation. Using a hand-collected data set of sales of Silicon Valley firms, we find common shareholders do sometimes receive payment before VCs' liquidation preferences are satisfied. However, such deviations from VCs' cash flow rights tend to be small. We also find that renegotiation is more likely when governance arrangements, including the firm's choice of corporate law, give common shareholders more power to impede the sale. Our study provides support for incomplete contracting theory, improves understanding of VC exits, and suggests that choice of corporate law matters in private firms. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Broughman, Brian; Fried, Jesse</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional monitoring through shareholder litigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, C. S. Agnes; Huang, Henry He; Li, Yinghua; Lobo, Gerald
This paper investigates the effectiveness Of using securities class action lawsuits in monitoring defendant firms by institutional lead plaintiffs from two aspects: (1) immediate litigation outcomes, including the probability of surviving the motion to dismiss and the settlement amount, and (2) subsequent governance improvement such as changes in board independence. Using a large sample of securities lawsuits from 1996 to 2005, we show that institutional investors are more likely to serve as the lead plaintiff for lawsuits with certain characteristics. After controlling for these determinants of having an institutional lead plaintiff, we show that securities class actions with institutional owners as lead plaintiffs are less likely to be dismissed and have larger monetary settlements than securities class actions with individual lead plaintiffs. This effect exists for various types of institutions including public pension funds. We also find that, after the lawsuit filings, defendant firms with institutional lead plaintiffs experience greater improvement in their board independence than defendant firms with individual lead plaintiffs. Our study suggests that securities litigation is an effective disciplining tool for institutional owners. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cheng, C. S. Agnes; Huang, Henry He; Li, Yinghua; Lobo, Gerald</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pecking order, debt capacity, and information asymmetry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leary, Mark T.; Roberts, Michael R.
We quantify the empirical relevance of the pecking order hypothesis using a novel empirical model and testing strategy that addresses statistical power concerns with previous tests. While the classificatory ability of the pecking order varies significantly depending on whether one interprets the hypothesis in a strict or liberal (e.g., "modified" pecking order) manner, the pecking order is never able to accurately classify more than half of the observed financing decisions. However, when we expand the model to incorporate factors typically attributed to alternative theories, the predictive accuracy of the model increases dramatically-accurately classifying over 80% of the observed debt and equity issuances. Finally, we show that what little pecking order behavior can be found in the data is driven more by incentive conflicts, as opposed to information asymmetry. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leary, Mark T.; Roberts, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does corporate governance matter in competitive industries?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giroud, Xavier; Mueller, Holger M.
By reducing the threat of a hostile takeover, business combination (BC) laws weaken corporate governance and increase the opportunity for managerial slack. Consistent with the notion that competition mitigates managerial slack, we find that while firms in non-competitive industries experience a significant drop in operating performance after the laws' passage, firms in competitive industries experience no significant effect. When we examine which agency problem competition mitigates, we find evidence in support of a "quiet-life" hypothesis. Input costs, wages, and overhead costs all increase after the laws' passage, and only so in non-competitive industries. Similarly, when we conduct event studies around the dates of the first newspaper reports about the BC laws, we find that while firms in non-competitive industries experience a significant stock price decline, firms in competitive industries experience a small and insignificant stock price impact. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giroud, Xavier; Mueller, Holger M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bailouts, the incentive to manage risk, and financial crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Panageas, Stavros
A firm's termination leads to bankruptcy costs. This may create an incentive for outside stakeholders or the firm's debtholders to bail out the firm as bankruptcy looms. Because of this implicit guarantee, firm shareholders have an incentive to increase volatility in order to exploit the implicit protection. However, if they increase volatility too much they may induce the guarantee-extending parties to "walk away." I derive the optimal risk management rule in such a framework and show that it allows high volatility choices, while net worth is high. However, risk limits tighten abruptly when the firm's net worth declines below an endogenously determined threshold. Hence, the model reproduces the qualitative features of existing risk management rules, and can account for phenomena such as "flight to quality." (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Panageas, Stavros</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seasoned equity offerings, market timing, and the corporate lifecycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, Harry; DeAngelo, Linda; Stulz, Rene M.
Both a firm's market-timing opportunities and its corporate lifecycle stage exert statistically and economically significant influences on the probability that it conducts a seasoned equity offering (SEO), with the lifecycle effect empirically stronger. Neither effect adequately explains SEO decisions because a near-majority of issuers are not growth firms and the vast majority of firms with high M/B ratios and high recent and poor future stock returns fail to issue stock. Since without the offer proceeds 62.6% of issuers would run out of cash (81.1% would have subnormal cash balances) the year after the SEO, a near-term cash need is the primary SEO motive, with market-timing opportunities and lifecycle stage exerting only ancillary influences. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeAngelo, Harry; DeAngelo, Linda; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resolving the exposure puzzle: The many facets of exchange rate exposure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Brown, Gregory W.; Minton, Bernadette A.
Theory predicts sizeable exchange rate (FX) exposure for many firms. However, empirical research has not documented such exposures, To examine this discrepancy, we extend prior theoretical results to model a global firm's FX exposure and show empirically that firms pass through part of currency changes to customers and utilize both operational and financial hedges. For a typical sample firm, pass-through and operational hedging each reduce exposure by 10-15%. Financial hedging with foreign debt, and to a lesser extent FX derivatives, decreases exposure by about 40%. The combination of these factors reduces FX exposures to observed levels. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Brown, Gregory W.; Minton, Bernadette A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political rights and the cost of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qi, Yaxuan; Roth, Lukas; Wald, John K.
We examine the impact of country-level political rights on the cost of debt for corporate bonds issued by firms incorporated in 39 countries. Similar to, but separate from, the relation for creditor rights, greater political rights are associated with lower yield spreads. A one standard deviation increase in political rights is associated with an 18.6% decline in bond spreads. We find evidence that political and legal institutions are substitutes; marginal improvements in political rights produce greater reductions in the cost of debt for firms from countries with weaker creditor rights. We examine potential factors through which political rights may affect the cost of debt and find that greater freedom of the press provides an important channel for reducing bond risks. Moreover, debt of firms with cross-listed equity trades at a premium in U.S. markets, but this relation appears to be more consistent with improved visibility than with bonding effects. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Qi, Yaxuan; Roth, Lukas; Wald, John K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market liquidity, asset prices, and welfare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Jennifer; Wang, Jiang
This paper represents an equilibrium model for the demand and supply of liquidity and its impact on asset prices and welfare. We show that, when constant market presence is costly, purely idiosyncratic shocks lead to endogenous demand of liquidity and large price deviations from fundamentals. Moreover, market forces fail to lead to efficient supply of liquidity, which calls for potential policy interventions. However, we demonstrate that different policy tools can yield different efficiency consequences. For example, lowering the cost of supplying liquidity on the spot (e.g., through direct injection of liquidity or relaxation of ex post margin constraints) can decrease welfare while forcing more liquidity supply (e.g., through coordination of market participants) can improve welfare. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Jennifer; Wang, Jiang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed trading before analyst downgrades: Evidence from short sellers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christophe, Stephen E.; Ferri, Michael G.; Hsieh, Jim
This paper studies short-selling prior to the release of analyst downgrades in a sample of 670 downgrades of Nasdaq stocks between 2000 and 2001. We find abnormal levels of short-selling in the three days before downgrades are publicly announced. Further, we show that this pre-announcement abnormal short-selling is significantly related to the subsequent share price reaction to the downgrade, and especially so for downgrades that prompt the most substantial price declines. Our findings are robust to various controls that might also affect short-selling such as pre-announcement momentum, three-day pre-announcement returns, and announcement-day share price. In addition, the results are independent of scheduled earnings announcements, analyst herding, and non-routine events near downgrades. Further evidence suggests that tipping is more consistent with the data than the prediction explanation which posits that short sellers successfully predict downgrades on the basis of public information about firms' financial health. Finally, we present evidence that downgraded stocks with high abnormal short-selling perform poorly over the subsequent six months by comparison with those with low abnormal short-selling. Overall, our results support the hypothesis that short sellers are informed traders and exploit profitable opportunities provided by downgrade announcements. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christophe, Stephen E.; Ferri, Michael G.; Hsieh, Jim</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset liquidity and financial contracts: Evidence from aircraft leases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gavazza, Alessandro
Financial contracting theories agree that more-liquid assets decrease the expected cost of external financing, thus making leasing more attractive and reducing lessors' equilibrium return. However, the literature has ambiguous predictions about the effect of liquidity on the maturity of leases. These predictions are further complicated by the existence of two types of lease contracts-operating and capital-that differ in whether asset ownership transfers to the lessee at the end of the contract. Using data from commercial aircraft, 1 find that more-liquid assets (1) make leasing, operating leasing in particular, more likely; (2) have shorter operating leases; (3) have longer capital leases; and (4) command lower markups of operating lease rates. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gavazza, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are family firms more tax aggressive than non-family firms?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Shuping; Chen, Xia; Cheng, Qiang; Shevlin, Terry
Taxes represent a significant cost to the firm and shareholders, and it is generally expected that shareholders prefer tax aggressiveness. However, this argument ignores potential non-tax costs that can accompany tax aggressiveness, especially those arising from agency problems. Firms owned/run by founding family members are characterized by a unique agency conflict between dominant and small shareholders. Using multiple measures to capture tax aggressiveness and founding family presence, we find that family firms are less tax aggressive than their non-family counterparts, ceteris paribus. This result suggests that family owners are willing to forgo tax benefits to avoid the non-tax cost of a potential price discount, which can arise from minority shareholders' concern with family rent-seeking masked by tax avoidance activities [Desai and Dharmapala, 2006. Corporate tax avoidance and high-powered incentives. Journal of Financial Economics 79, 145-179]. Our result is also consistent with family owners being more concerned with the potential penalty and reputation damage from an IRS audit than non-family firms. We obtain similar inferences when using a small sample of tax shelter cases. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Shuping; Chen, Xia; Cheng, Qiang; Shevlin, Terry</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Activist arbitrage: A study of open-ending attempts of closed-end funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, Michael; Brav, Alon; Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei
This paper documents frequent attempts by activist arbitrageurs to open-end discounted closed-end funds, particularly after the 1992 proxy reform which reduced the costs of communication among shareholders. Open-ending attempts have a substantial effect on discounts, reducing them, on average, to half of their original level. The size of the discount is a major determinant of whether a fund gets attacked. Other important factors include the costs of communication among shareholders and the governance structure of the targeted fund. Our study contributes to the understanding of the actions undertaken by arbitrageurs in financial markets beyond just pure trading. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bradley, Michael; Brav, Alon; Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>First-passage probability, jump models, and intra-horizon risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Panayotov, George
This paper proposes a risk measure, based on first-passage probability, which reflects intra-horizon risk in jump models with finite or infinite jump activity. Our empirical investigation shows, first, that the proposed risk measure consistently exceeds the benchmark value-at-risk (VaR). Second, jump risk tends to amplify intra-horizon risk. Third, we find large variation in our risk measure across jump models, indicative of model risk. Fourth, among the jump models we consider, the finite-moment log-stable model provides the most conservative risk estimates. Fifth, imposing more stringent VaR levels accentuates the impact of intra-horizon risk in jump models. Finally, using an alternative benchmark VaR does not dilute the role of intra-horizon risk. Overall, we contribute by showing that ignoring intra-horizon risk can lead to underestimation of risk exposures. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Panayotov, George</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reduced-form valuation of callable corporate bonds: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jarrow, Robert; Li, Haitao; Liu, Sheen; Wu, Chunchi
We develop a reduced-form approach for valuing callable corporate bonds by characterizing the call probability via an intensity process. Asymmetric information and market frictions justify the existence of a call-arrival intensity from the market's perspective. Our approach both extends the reduced-form model of Duffle and Singleton (1999) for defaultable bonds to callable bonds and captures some important differences between call and default decisions. A comprehensive empirical analysis of callable bonds using both our model and the more traditional American option approach for valuing callable bonds shows that the reduced-form model fits callable bond prices well and that it outperforms the traditional approach both in- and out-of-sample. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert; Li, Haitao; Liu, Sheen; Wu, Chunchi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure decisions: Evidence from deregulated industries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ovtchinnikov, Alexei V.
Deregulation significantly affects the firms' operating environment and leverage decisions. Firms experience a significant decline in profitability, asset tangibility and a significant increase in growth opportunities following deregulation. Firms respond by reducing leverage. Deregulation also significantly affects the cross-sectional relation between leverage and its determinants. Leverage is much less negatively correlated with profitability and market-to-book and much more positively (negatively) correlated with firm size (earnings volatility) following deregulation. These results are consistent with the dynamic tradeoff theory of capital structure. Also consistent with the dynamic tradeoff theory, those firms that are more likely to be above their target capital structure issue significantly more equity in the first few years following deregulation. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ovtchinnikov, Alexei V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of state antitakeover laws on the firm's bondholders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar; John, Kose; Waisman, Maya
We examine how state antitakeover laws affect bondholders and the cost of debt, and report four findings. First, bonds issued by firms incorporated in takeover-friendly states have significantly higher at-issue yield spreads than bonds issued by firms in states with restrictive antitakeover laws. Second, firms in takeover friendly states have significantly higher leverage than their counterparts in restrictive law states. Third, bond issues are associated with negative average stock price reactions among firms in takeover-friendly states, but positive stock price reactions among firms in restrictive law states. Fourth, existing bond values increase, on average, upon the introduction of Business Combination antitakeover law. These results indicate that state antitakeover laws tend to decrease bond yields and increase bond Values, which is the opposite of their effect on equity values. This, in turn, implies that state laws help mitigate the agency cost of debt by shielding bondholders from expropriation in takeovers. Overall, the empirical evidence suggests that the effect of antitakeover provisions on firm value must take into account the impacts of both bondholders and stockholders. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar; John, Kose; Waisman, Maya</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>O/S: The relative trading activity in options and stock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roll, Richard; Schwartz, Eduardo; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
Relatively little is known about the trading volume in derivatives relative to the volume in underlying stocks. We study the time-series properties and the determinants of the options/stock trading volume ratio (O/S) using a comprehensive cross-section and time-series of data on equities and their listed options. O/S is related to many intuitive determinants such as delta and trading costs, and it also varies with institutional holdings, analyst following, and analyst forecast dispersion. O/S is higher around earnings announcements, suggesting increased trading in the options market. Further, post-announcement absolute returns are positively related to pre-announcement O/S, which suggests that at least part of the pre-announcement options trading is informed. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roll, Richard; Schwartz, Eduardo; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance persistence in entrepreneurship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gompers, Paul; Kovner, Anna; Lerner, Josh; Scharfstein, David
This paper presents evidence of performance persistence in entrepreneurship. We show that entrepreneurs with a track record of success are much more likely to succeed than first-time entrepreneurs and those who have previously failed. In particular, they exhibit persistence in selecting the right industry and time to start new ventures. Entrepreneurs with demonstrated market timing skill are also more likely to outperform industry peers in their subsequent ventures. This is consistent with the view that if suppliers and customers perceive the entrepreneur to have market timing skill, and is therefore more likely to succeed, they will be more willing to commit resources to the firm. In this way, success breeds success and strengthens performance persistence. (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Gompers, Paul; Kovner, Anna; Lerner, Josh; Scharfstein, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantifying private benefits of control from a structural model of block trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Schroth, Enrique
We study the determinants of private benefits of control in negotiated block transactions. We estimate the block pricing model in Burkart, Gromb and Panunzi (2000) explicitly accounting for both block premiums and block discounts in the data. The evidence suggests that the occurrence of a block premium or discount depends on the controlling block holder's ability to fight a potential tender offer for the target's stock. We find evidence of large private benefits of control and of associated deadweight losses, but also of value creation by controlling shareholders. Finally, we provide evidence consistent with Jensen's free cash flow hypothesis. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Schroth, Enrique</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The good news in short interest</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Huszar, Zsuzsa R.; Jordan, Bradford D.
Stocks with relatively high short interest subsequently experience negative abnormal returns, but the effect can be transient and of debatable economic significance. In contrast, relatively heavily traded stocks with low short interest experience both statistically and economically significant positive abnormal returns. These positive returns are often larger (in absolute value) than the negative returns observed for heavily shorted stocks. Thus, the positive information associated with low short interest, which is publicly available, is only slowly incorporated into prices, which raises a broader market efficiency issue. Our results also cast doubt on existing theories of the impact of short sale constraints. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Huszar, Zsuzsa R.; Jordan, Bradford D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited participation and consumption-saving puzzles: A simple explanation and the role of insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gormley, Todd; Liu, Hong; Zhou, Guofu
In this paper, we show that the existence of a large, negative wealth shock and insufficient insurance against such a shock could explain both the limited stock market participation puzzle and the low-consumption-high-savings puzzle. We then conduct an empirical analysis on the relation between household portfolio choices and access to private insurance and various types of government safety nets. The empirical results demonstrate that a lack of insurance against large, negative wealth shocks is positively correlated with lower participation rates and higher saving rates. Overall, the evidence suggests an important role of insurance in household investment and savings decisions. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gormley, Todd; Liu, Hong; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>