<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFE0</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Regulating a model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leitner, Yaron; Yilmaz, Bilge
We study a situation in which a regulator relies on risk models that banks produce in order to regulate them. A bank can generate more than one model and choose which models to reveal to the regulator. The regulator can find out the other models by monitoring the bank, but in equilibrium, monitoring induces the bank to produce less information. We show that a high level of monitoring is desirable when the bank's private gain from producing more information is either sufficiently high or sufficiently low. When public models are more precise, banks produce more information, but the regulator may end up monitoring more. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leitner, Yaron; Yilmaz, Bilge</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The CAPM strikes back? An equilibrium model with disasters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Hang; Hou, Kewei; Kung, Howard; Li, Erica X. N.; Zhang, Lu
Embedding disasters into a general equilibrium model with heterogeneous firms induces strong nonlinearity in the pricing kernel, helping explain the empirical failure of the (consumption) CAPM. Our single-factor model reproduces the failure of the CAPM in explaining the value premium in finite samples without disasters and its relative success in samples with disasters. Due to beta measurement errors, the estimated beta-return relation is flat, consistent with the beta "anomaly,"even though the true beta-return relation is strongly positive. Finally, the consumption CAPM fails in simulations, even though a non-linear model with the true pricing kernel holds exactly by construction. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bai, Hang; Hou, Kewei; Kung, Howard; Li, Erica X. N.; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateralizing liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parlatore, Cecilia
I develop a dynamic model of optimal funding to understand why financial assets are used as collateral instead of being sold to raise funds. Firms need funds to invest in risky projects with nonobservable returns. Since holding these assets allows firms to raise these funds, investing firms value the asset more than noninvesting ones. When assets are less than perfectly liquid and investment opportunities are persistent, collateralized debt minimizes asset transfers from investing to noninvesting firms and thus is optimal. Frictions in asset markets lead to an illiquidity discount and a collateral premium, which increase with the asset's illiquidity. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Parlatore, Cecilia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inferring latent social networks from stock holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Xu, Jiangmin
We infer the latent social networks of investors using data on their stock holdings. We map linkages to portfolio weights using a portfolio-choice model. The precision of an investor's private signal about firm value is assumed to increase with his connections in the city where the firm is headquartered. Using money-manager data, we find that managerial linkages to a city are overly dispersed relative to the Erclos-Renyi model of i.i.d. connections. Managers at the tail of this distribution with non-i.i.d. linkages have more university alumni in that city. Their stock holdings there outperform their holdings in other cities. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Xu, Jiangmin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who benefits in a crisis? Evidence from hedge fund stock and option holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aragon, George O.; Martin, J. Spencer; Shi, Zhen
We use a unique data set of hedge fund long equity and equity option positions to investigate a significant lockup-related premium earned during the tech bubble (1999-2001) and financial crisis (2007-2009). Net fund flows are significantly greater among lockup funds during crisis and noncrisis periods. Managers of hedge funds with locked-up capital trade opportunistically against flow-motivated trades of non-lockup managers, consistent with a hypothesis of rent extraction in providing crisis era liquidity. The success of this opportunistic trading is concentrated during periods of high borrowing costs, in less liquid stock markets, and is enhanced by hedging in the equity option market. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aragon, George O.; Martin, J. Spencer; Shi, Zhen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The profitability and investment premium: Pre-1963 evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wahal, Sunil
I investigate the profitability and investment premium in stock returns using hand collected data from Moody's Manuals for 1940-1963. Controlling for value, the profitability premium emerges as important in this period. In contrast, there is no reliable relation between investment and returns, regardless of whether investment is measured using growth in total assets or book equity and even after extending the data back to 1926. In spanning regressions, factors constructed from profitability and book-to-market ratios (RMW and HML, respectively) improve the mean-variance efficient tangency portfolio but the investment factor (CMA) does not. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wahal, Sunil</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How effective are trading pauses?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hautsch, Nikolaus; Horvath, Akos
Exploiting Nasdaq order book data and difference-in-differences methodology, we identify the distinct effects of trading pause mechanisms introduced on US stock exchanges after May 2010. We show that the mere existence of such a regulation makes market participants behave differently in anticipation of a pause. Pauses enhance price discovery during the break but have adverse effects on price stability and liquidity after the pause. We find that pauses ultimately do not "cool off" markets but cause extra volatility. This implies a regulatory trade-off between the protective role of trading pauses and their adverse effects on market quality. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hautsch, Nikolaus; Horvath, Akos</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mark Twain's Cat: Investment experience, categorical thinking, and stock selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Xing
This paper examines the effect of prior investment experience in specific industries on subsequent investment decisions. Using households' trading records from a large discount broker between 1991 and 1996, I find that prior success in a given industry increases the likelihood of subsequent purchases in the same industry. The effect is stronger for more recent experiences and for less sophisticated or diversified investors, and it is not wealth enhancing. The results suggest investors categorize industries at a highly resolved level, finer than the Fama-French ten-industry classification. Similar effects are also apparent for size- and value-based categories but at smaller magnitudes. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Xing</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of jumps on carry trade returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Suzanne S.; Wang, Minho
This paper investigates how jump risks are priced in currency markets. We find that currencies whose changes are more sensitive to negative market jumps provide significantly higher expected returns. The positive risk premium constitutes compensation for the extreme losses during periods of market turmoil. Using the empirical findings, we propose a jump modified carry trade strategy, which has approximately two-percentage-point (per annum) higher returns than the regular carry trade strategy. These findings result from the fact that negative jump betas are significantly related to the riskiness of currencies and business conditions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Suzanne S.; Wang, Minho</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firms' innovation strategy under the shadow of analyst coverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Bing; Perez-Castrillo, David; Toldra-Simats, Anna
We study the effect of analyst coverage on firms' innovation strategy and outcome. Using data of US firms from 1990 to 2012, we find evidence that an increase in financial analysts leads firms to cut research and development expenses, acquire more innovative firms, and invest in corporate venture capital. We attribute the first result to the effect of analyst pressure and the others to the informational role of analysts. We also find that financial analysts encourage firms to make more efficient investments related to innovation, which increases their future patents and citations and influences the novelty of their innovations. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guo, Bing; Perez-Castrillo, David; Toldra-Simats, Anna</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade credit and supplier competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chod, Jiri; Lyandres, Evgeny; Yang, S. Alex
This paper examines how competition among suppliers affects their willingness to provide trade credit financing. Trade credit extended by a supplier to a cash constrained retailer allows the latter to increase cash purchases from its other suppliers, leading to a free rider problem. A supplier that represents a smaller share of the retailer's purchases internalizes a smaller part of the benefit from increased spending by the retailer and, as a result, extends less trade credit relative to its sales. In consequence, retailers with dispersed suppliers obtain less trade credit than those whose suppliers are more concentrated. The free rider problem is especially detrimental to a trade creditor when the free-riding suppliers are its product market competitors, leading to a negative relation between product substitutability among suppliers to a given retailer and trade credit that the former provide to the latter. We test the model using both simulated and real data. The estimated relations are consistent with the model's predictions and are statistically and economically significant. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chod, Jiri; Lyandres, Evgeny; Yang, S. Alex</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common risk factors in the cross-section of corporate bond returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Jennie; Bali, Turan G.; Wen, Quan
We investigate the cross-sectional determinants of corporate bond returns and find that downside risk is the strongest predictor of future bond returns. We also introduce common risk factors based on the prevalent risk characteristics of corporate bonds downside risk, credit risk, and liquidity risk and find that these novel bond factors have economically and statistically significant risk premiums that cannot be explained by long-established stock and bond market factors. We show that the newly proposed risk factors outperform all other models considered in the literature in explaining the returns of the industry- and size/maturity-sorted portfolios of corporate bonds. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bai, Jennie; Bali, Turan G.; Wen, Quan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do idiosyncratic jumps matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kapadia, Nishad; Zekhnini, Morad
We show that idiosyncratic jumps are a key determinant of mean stock returns from both an ex post and ex ante perspective. Ex post, the entire annual average return of a typical stock accrues on the four days on which its price jumps. Ex ante, idiosyncratic jump risk earns a premium: a value-weighted weekly long-short portfolio that buys (sells) stocks with high (low) predicted jump probabilities earns annualized mean returns of 9.4% and four-factor alphas of 81%. This strategy's returns are larger when there are greater limits to arbitrage. These results are consistent with investor aversion to idiosyncratic jump risk. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kapadia, Nishad; Zekhnini, Morad</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do institutional investors drive corporate social responsibility? International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dyck, Alexander; Lins, Karl V.; Roth, Lukas; Wagner, Hannes E.
This paper assesses whether shareholders drive the environmental and social (E&amp;S) performance of firms worldwide. Across 41 countries, institutional ownership is positively associated with E&amp;S performance with additional tests suggesting this relation is causal. Institutions are motivated by both financial and social returns. Investors increase firms' E&amp;S performance following shocks that reveal financial benefits to E&amp;S improvements. In cross section, investors increase firms' E&amp;S performance when they come from countries with a strong community belief in the importance of E&amp;S issues, but not otherwise. As such, these institutional investors transplant their social norms regarding E&amp;S issues around the world. (C) 2018 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Dyck, Alexander; Lins, Karl V.; Roth, Lukas; Wagner, Hannes E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A trade-off theory of ownership and capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nicodano, Giovanna; Regis, Luca
This paper determines the optimal ownership share held by a unit into a second unit when both face a tax-bankruptcy trade-off. Full ownership is optimal when the first unit has positive debt, because dividends help avoid its default. Positive debt is, in turn, optimal when its corporate tax rate exceeds a threshold, and/or thin capitalization rules place an upper limit on the debt level in the second unit, and/or the Volcker Rule bans bailout transfers to the second unit. Full ownership is no longer optimal only if there is a tax on intercorporate dividend. This theory rationalizes observations on multinationals, financial conglomerates, and family groups. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nicodano, Giovanna; Regis, Luca</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bear beta</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Zhongjin; Murray, Scott
We test whether bear market risk, time variation in the probability of future bear market states, is priced. We construct an Arrow-Debreu security that pays off in bear market states (AD Bear) from traded Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P) 500 index options and use its returns to measure bear market risk. We find that bear beta (exposure to bear market risk) has a strong relation with expected stock returns that is robust, persistent, and remains strong among liquid and large stocks. Historical bear beta also predicts future bear market risk exposure. We conclude that bear market risk is priced in the cross section of stock returns. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lu, Zhongjin; Murray, Scott</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private information in currency markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michaelides, Alexander; Milidonis, Andreas; Nishiotis, George P.
Using daily abnormal currency returns for the universe of countries with flexible exchange rates, we show local currency depreciations ahead of unscheduled, public sovereign debt downgrade announcements. Consistent with the private information hypothesis, the effect is stronger in lower institutional quality countries and holds after we control for concurrent public information and for publicly available rumors about the forthcoming downgrades. Our results persist when abnormal currency returns are adjusted for global carry and dollar risk factors, world equity and bond returns, as well as local stock market returns. Finally, the currency depreciations are permanent, providing evidence for a link between fundamentals and currency markets. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Michaelides, Alexander; Milidonis, Andreas; Nishiotis, George P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inferring volatility dynamics and risk premia from the S&amp;P 500 and VIX markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bardgett, Chris; Gourier, Elise; Leippold, Markus
We estimate a flexible affine model using an unbalanced panel containing S&amp;P 500 and VIX index returns and option prices and analyze the contribution of VIX options to the model's in- and out-of-sample performance. We find that they contain valuable information on the risk-neutral conditional distributions of volatility at different time horizons, which is not spanned by the S&amp;P 500 market. This information allows enhanced estimation of the variance risk premium. We gain new insights on the term structure of the variance risk premium, present a trading strategy exploiting these insights, and show how to improve S&amp;P 500 return forecasts. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bardgett, Chris; Gourier, Elise; Leippold, Markus</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are lemons sold first? Dynamic signaling in the mortgage market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelino, Manuel; Gerardi, Kristopher; Hartman-Glaser, Barney
A central result in the theory of adverse selection in asset markets is that informed sellers can signal quality and obtain higher prices by delaying trade. This paper provides some of the first evidence of a signaling mechanism through trade delays using the residential mortgage market as a laboratory. We find a strong relationship between mortgage performance and time to sale for privately securitized mortgages. Additionally, deals made up of more seasoned mortgages are sold at lower yields. These effects are strongest in the "Alt-A" segment of the market, where mortgages are often sold with incomplete hard information, and in cases where the originator and the issuer of mortgage-backed securities are not affiliated. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adelino, Manuel; Gerardi, Kristopher; Hartman-Glaser, Barney</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indexing and stock market serial dependence around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baltussen, Guido; van Bekkum, Sjoerd; Da, Zhi
We show a striking change in index return serial dependence across 20 major market indexes covering 15 countries in North America, Europe, and Asia. While many studies find serial dependence to be positive until the 1990s, it switches to negative since the 2000s. This change happens in most stock markets around the world and is both statistically significant and economically meaningful. Further tests reveal that the decline in serial dependence links to the increasing popularity of index products (e.g., futures, exchange traded funds, and index mutual funds). The link between serial dependence and indexing is not driven by a time trend, holds up in the cross section of stock indexes, is confirmed by tests exploiting Nikkei 225 index weights and Standard &amp; Poor's 500 membership, and in part reflects the arbitrage mechanism between index products and the underlying stocks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baltussen, Guido; van Bekkum, Sjoerd; Da, Zhi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry familiarity and trading: Evidence from the personal portfolios of industry insiders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-David, Itzhak; Birru, Justin; Rossi, Andrea
We study whether industry familiarity is an advantage in stock trading by exploring the trading patterns of industry insiders in their own personal portfolios. To do so, we identify accounts of industry insiders in a large data set provided by a retail discount broker. We find that insiders trade firms from their own industry more frequently. Furthermore, they earn abnormal returns exclusively when trading own-industry stocks, especially obscure stocks (small, low analyst coverage, high volatility). In a battery of tests, we find no evidence of the use of private information. The results are most consistent with the interpretation that industry familiarity is an advantage in stock trading. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ben-David, Itzhak; Birru, Justin; Rossi, Andrea</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic corporate liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nikolov, Boris; Schmid, Lukas; Steri, Roberto
In contrast to cash holdings, credit lines give firms financial flexibility by providing liquidity contingent on realized funding needs, but they are often limited by collateral and covenants. We embed this trade-off into an estimated dynamic model of financing and investment. Our model highlights the relevance of drawing down credit lines to fund investment options in an effective way and quantitatively matches well the levels and dynamics of cash, credit lines, and leverage. In the cross-section, modeling credit lines as contingent liquidity provides novel empirical predictions and rationalizes several stylized facts regarding credit line usage, covenant violations, and cash holdings. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nikolov, Boris; Schmid, Lukas; Steri, Roberto</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preference for dividends and return comovement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hameed, Allaudeen; Xie, Jing
Stocks that initiate dividends tend to comove more with other dividend-paying stocks and comove less with non-dividend payers. This is also true for: (a) dividend initiations that are motivated by the exogenous 2003 dividend tax cut; and (b) the cash dividend share class of Citizens Utilities (relative to its stock dividend class). We find that flows to dividend prone (averse) mutual funds increase the comovement among dividend-paying (non dividend paying) stocks. Overall, the evidence supports the proposition that the trading of pro-dividend (dividend-averse) clienteles induces an extra factor in dividend payers (non payers), beyond those associated with changes in common factors. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hameed, Allaudeen; Xie, Jing</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Manager sentiment and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Fuwei; Lee, Joshua; Martin, Xiumin; Zhou, Guofu
This paper constructs a manager sentiment index based on the aggregated textual tone of corporate financial disclosures. We find that manager sentiment is a strong negative predictor of future aggregate stock market returns, with monthly in-sample and out-of-sample Res of 9.75% and 8.38%, respectively, which is far greater than the predictive power of other previously studied macroeconomic variables. Its predictive power is economically comparable and is informationally complementary to existing measures of investor sentiment. Higher manager sentiment precedes lower aggregate earnings surprises and greater aggregate investment growth. Moreover, manager sentiment negatively predicts cross-sectional stock returns, particularly for firms that are difficult to value and costly to arbitrage. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Fuwei; Lee, Joshua; Martin, Xiumin; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variance risk in aggregate stock returns and time-varying return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pyun, Sungjune
This paper introduces a new out-of-sample forecasting methodology for monthly market returns using the variance risk premium (VRP) that is both statistically and economically significant. This methodology is motivated by the 'beta representation,' which implies that the market risk premium is related to the price of variance risk by the variance risk exposure. Hence, when the slope of the contemporaneous regression of market returns on variance innovation is larger, future returns are more sharply related to the current VRP. Also, predictions are more accurate when market returns are highly correlated to variance shocks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pyun, Sungjune</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Acquirer reference prices and acquisition performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ma, Qingzhong; Whidbee, David A.; Zhang, Wei
In a comprehensive sample of mergers and acquisitions, we find a reference price effect: acquirers earn higher (lower) announcement-period returns when their pre-announcement stock prices are well below (near) their 52-week highs. This reference price effect is stronger in acquisitions of private targets, deals involving greater uncertainty, and acquirers with greater individual investor ownership, and it is reversed in the subsequent year. Further, acquirer reference prices affect bid premia and target announcement-period returns in deals with greater uncertainty in acquirer valuation. The overall evidence is consistent with investors irrationally using 52-week high prices as a measure of acquirer valuation. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ma, Qingzhong; Whidbee, David A.; Zhang, Wei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What a difference a (birth) month makes: The relative age effect and fund manager performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, John; Ma, Linlin; Mullally, Kevin A.; Solomon, David H.
Many US states have a single cutoff date for school entry, meaning that some children are older than others when they begin kindergarten. We show that this variation in birth months is associated with differences in adult labor market outcomes in the mutual fund industry. Relatively older managers (i.e., those born just after the cutoff) make better stock selections, and their funds outperform their younger peers' funds by 0.48% per annum. This difference is linked to increased confidence. Survey respondents judge relatively older managers as appearing more confident in photographs, and these managers display more confident behavior: making larger bets, window dressing their holdings less, and securing more fund flows conditional on performance. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bai, John; Ma, Linlin; Mullally, Kevin A.; Solomon, David H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probability of price crashes, rational speculative bubbles, and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jang, Jeewon; Kang, Jangkoo
We estimate an ex ante probability of extreme negative returns (crashes) of individual stocks as a measure of potential overpricing and find that stocks with a high probability of crashes earn abnormally low returns. Stocks with high crash probability are overpriced regardless of the level of institutional ownership or variations in investor sentiment, and moreover, they exhibit increasing institutional demand until their prices reach the peak of overvaluation. We also find that institutional investors who overweight high crash probability stocks outperform the others, indicating that they have skill in timing bubbles and crashes of individual stocks. Our findings imply that sophisticated investors may not always trade against mispricing but time the correction of overpricing, and suggest that the crash effect we find could arise at least partially from rational speculative bubbles, not entirely from sentiment-driven overpricing. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jang, Jeewon; Kang, Jangkoo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The present value relation over six centuries: The case of the Bazacle company</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>le Bris, David; Goetzmann, William N.; Pouget, Sebastien
We study asset pricing over the longue duree using share prices and net dividends from the Bazacle company of Toulouse, the earliest documented shareholding corporation. The data extend from the firm's foundation in 1372 to its nationalization in 1946. We find an average dividend yield of 5% per annum and near-zero long-term, real capital appreciation. Stationary dividends and stock prices enable us to directly study how prices relate to expected cash flows, without relying on a rate of return transformation. A reduced-form asset pricing model with persistent dividends and a time-varying risk correction is not rejected by the data. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>le Bris, David; Goetzmann, William N.; Pouget, Sebastien</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitized markets, international capital flows, and global welfare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phelan, Gregory; Toda, Alexis Akira
We study the effect of collateralized lending and securitization on international capital flows and welfare in a two-country general equilibrium model with idiosyncratic investment risk. The low-margin country (Home) endogenously supplies more safe assets and enables more risk sharing. Upon financial integration, capital flows from Foreign (high margin country) to Home, leading to lower interest rates and a larger global supply of safe assets. Unlike in standard models with partial equity issuance, in our model, Home can lose from financial integration due to the endogenous reduction in risk sharing and aggregate shocks can generate large gross capital flows. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Phelan, Gregory; Toda, Alexis Akira</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should Long-Term Investors Time Volatility?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moreira, Alan; Muir, Tyler
A long-term investor who ignores variation in volatility gives up the equivalent of 2.4% of wealth per year. This result holds for a wide range of parameters that are consistent with US stock market data, and it is robust to estimation uncertainty. We propose and test a new channel, the volatility composition channel, for how investment horizon interacts with volatility timing. Investors respond substantially less to volatility variation if the amount of mean reversion in returns disproportionally increases with volatility and also if mean reversion happens quickly. We find that these conditions are unlikely to hold in the data. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moreira, Alan; Muir, Tyler</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minimum payments and debt paydown in consumer credit cards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keys, Benjamin J.; Wang, Jialan
Using a data set covering one quarter of the U.S. general-purpose credit card market, we document that 29% of accounts regularly make payments at or near the minimum payment. To explain the prevalence of low payment amounts, we exploit changes in issuers' minimum payment formulas to quantify the explanatory power of two potential theories: liquidity constraints and anchoring. At least 22% of near-minimum payers (and 9% of all accounts) respond to the formula changes in a manner consistent with anchoring as opposed to liquidity constraints alone. Our results show that anchoring to a salient contractual term has a significant impact on household repayment decisions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Keys, Benjamin J.; Wang, Jialan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend payments as a response to peer influence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grennan, Jillian
I show dividend policies have peer effects. My estimates indicate that firms speed up the time taken to make a dividend change by about 1.5 quarters and increase payments by 16% in response to peer changes. The peer effects matter in increases but not decreases. In contrast to dividends, repurchases show no peer effects. In addition, announcement returns indicate that investors partially anticipate the consequences of peer effects. Overall, peer interdependencies account for 12% of total dividend payments. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grennan, Jillian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional herding and its price impact: Evidence from the corporate bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Fang; Han, Song; Li, Dan; Li, Yi
We examine the extent to which institutional investors herd in the U.S. corporate bond market and the price impact of their herding behavior. We find that the level of institutional herding in corporate bonds is substantially higher than what is documented for equities, and that sell herding is much stronger and more persistent than buy herding. The price impact of herding is also highly asymmetric. While buy herding facilitates price discovery, sell herding causes transitory yet large price distortions. Such price destabilizing effect of sell herding is particularly pronounced for speculative-grade, small, and illiquid bonds, and during the financial crisis. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cai, Fang; Han, Song; Li, Dan; Li, Yi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The leverage effect and the basket-index put spread</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Jennie; Goldstein, Robert S.; Yang, Fan
Benchmark models that exogenously specify equity dynamics cannot explain the large spread in prices between put options written on individual banks and options written on the bank index during the financial crisis. However, theory requires that asset dynamics be specified exogenously and that endogenously determined equity dynamics exhibit a "leverage effect" that increases put prices by fattening the left tail of the distribution. The leverage effect is larger for puts on individual stocks than for puts on the index, thus increasing the basket-index spread. Time-series and cross-sectional variation in the leverage effect explains option prices well. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bai, Jennie; Goldstein, Robert S.; Yang, Fan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do insiders time management buyouts and freezeouts to buy undervalued targets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Stanfield, Jared; Zhang, Feng
We provide evidence that managers and controlling shareholders time management buyouts (MBOs) and freezeout transactions to take advantage of industry-wide undervaluation. Portfolios of industry peers of MBO and freezeout targets show significant alphas of around 1% per month over the 12-month period following the transaction. These returns are not explained by a battery of risk factors or empirical methodologies, but exhibit significant heterogeneity across deals. Additional tests show that, on average, abnormal returns to industry peers are a reliable proxy for those to the target firm. Further, MBOs and freezeouts are announced during troughs of industry profitability. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Stanfield, Jared; Zhang, Feng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of access to finance: Evidence from M&amp;As</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornaggia, Jess; Li, Jay Yin
We examine synergies in mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As) generated by firms' comparative advantages in access to bank finance. We find robust evidence that greater access to bank finance increases firms' attractiveness as acquisition targets. Targets' comparative advantage in bank finance improves bank credit supply and reduces financing costs for the merged firms. These effects are more pronounced for acquirers with greater frictions in accessing bank loans and acquirers with greater growth opportunities. Overall, this paper reveals that targets, not just acquirers, contribute to financial synergies in M&amp;As. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier By.</description><author>Cornaggia, Jess; Li, Jay Yin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The use of credit default swaps by bond mutual funds: Liquidity provision and counterparty risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aragon, George O.; Li, Lei; Qian, Jun QJ
Corporate bond mutual funds increased their selling of credit protection in the credit default swaps (CDS) market during the 2007-2008 financial crisis. This trading activity was primarily in multi-name CDS, greater among larger and established funds, and directed toward counterparty dealers in financial distress. Funds that sold credit protection during the crisis experienced greater credit market risk and superior post-crisis performance, consistent with higher expected returns from liquidity provision. Funds using Lehman Brothers as a counterparty experienced abnormal outflows and returns of -2% immediately following Lehman's bankruptcy, suggesting that funds' opportunistic trading in CDS exposed investors to counterparty risk. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aragon, George O.; Li, Lei; Qian, Jun QJ</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good disclosure, bad disclosure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, Ray; Yang, Liyan
We study real-efficiency implications of disclosing public information in a model with multiple dimensions of uncertainty where market prices convey information to a real decision maker. Paradoxically, when disclosure concerns a variable that the real decision maker cares to learn about, disclosure negatively affects price informativeness, and in markets that are effective in aggregating private information, this negative price-informativeness effect can dominate so that better disclosure negatively impacts real efficiency. When disclosure concerns a variable that the real decision maker already knows much about, disclosure always improves price informativeness and real efficiency. Our analysis has important empirical and policy implications for different contexts such as disclosure of stress test information and regulation of credit ratings. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goldstein, Ray; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do valuations impact outcomes of asset sales with heterogeneous bidders?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorbenko, Alexander S.
Differences among bidder type-specific outcomes of asset sales are theoretically related to differences in bidders' valuations and participation. The lead application to quantify these relations is takeover auctions: bidders are classified into strategic and financial, and bids are available. I structurally estimate valuations from all bids. The positive difference in premiums between strategic and financial acquirers is driven by the difference in dispersions of valuations (e.g., strategic bidders' synergies are more dispersed) and the set of auction participants. The difference in average valuations is relatively unimportant. My approach can help explain outcomes of asset sales, even in settings with limited bidder data. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Gorbenko, Alexander S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The rise in student loan defaults</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mueller, Holger M.; Yannelis, Constantine
We examine the rise in student loan defaults in the Great Recession by linking administrative student loan data at the individual borrower level to student loan borrowers' individual tax records. A Blinder-Oaxaca style decomposition shows that shifts in the composition of student loan borrowers and the massive collapse in home prices during the Great Recession can each account for approximately 30% of the rise in student loan defaults. Falling home prices affect student loan defaults by impairing individuals' labor earnings, especially for low income jobs. By contrast, when comparing the default sensitivities of homeowners and renters, we find no evidence that falling home prices affect student loan defaults through a home equity-based liquidity channel. The Income Based Repayment (IBR) program introduced by the federal government in the wake of the Great Recession reduced both student loan defaults and their sensitivity to home price fluctuations, thus providing student loan borrowers with valuable insurance against negative shocks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mueller, Holger M.; Yannelis, Constantine</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bubbles for Fama</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Shleifer, Andrei; You, Yang
We evaluate Eugene F. Fama's claim that stock prices do not exhibit price bubbles. Based on US industry returns (1926-2014) and international sector returns (1985-2014), we present four findings (1) Fama is correct in that a sharp price increase of an industry portfolio does not, on average, predict unusually low returns going forward; (2) such sharp price increases predict a substantially heightened probability of a crash but not of a further price boom; (3) attributes of the price run-up, including volatility, turnover, issuance, and the price path of the run-up, help forecast an eventual crash; and (4) these attributes also help forecast future returns. Results hold similarly in US and international samples. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Shleifer, Andrei; You, Yang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public hedge funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Lin; Teo, Melvyn
Hedge funds managed by listed firms significantly under-perform funds managed by unlisted firms. The under-performance is more severe for funds with low manager deltas, poor governance, and no manager co-investment, or those managed by firms whose prices are sensitive to earnings news. Notwithstanding the under-performance, listed asset management firms raise more capital, by growing existing funds and launching new funds post listing, and harvest greater fee revenues than do comparable unlisted firms. The results are consistent with the view that, for asset management firms, going public weakens the alignment between ownership, control, and investment capital, thereby engendering conflicts of interest. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Lin; Teo, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pay now or pay later? The economics within the private equity partnership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivashina, Victoria; Lerner, Josh
The economics of partnerships have been of enduring interest to economists, yet it is not clear what profit sharing within a private partnership should look like. We examine over 700 private equity partnerships and show that the allocation of fund economics to individual partners varies drastically, even among the most senior partners, and appears divorced from past success as an investor, being instead related to status as a founder. A smaller share of carried interest and ownership and inequality in fund economics more generally is associated with departures of senior partners which, in turn is negatively related to the funds' ability to raise additional capital. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ivashina, Victoria; Lerner, Josh</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>JFE special issue on labor and finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Whited, Toni M.
nan</description><author>Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial frictions and employment during the Great Depression</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benmelech, Efraim; Frydman, Carola; Papanikolaou, Dimitris
We provide new evidence that a disruption in credit supply played a quantitatively significant role in the unprecedented contraction of employment during the Great Depression using a novel, hand-collected dataset of large industrial firms. Our identification strategy exploits preexisting variation in the need to raise external funds at a time when public bond markets essentially froze. Local bank failures inhibited firms' ability to substitute public debt for private debt, which exacerbated financial constraints. We estimate a large and negative causal effect of financing frictions on firm employment. We find that the lack of access to credit likely accounted for a substantial fraction of the aggregate decline in employment of large firms between 1928 and 1933. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benmelech, Efraim; Frydman, Carola; Papanikolaou, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing intangible capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Qi; Xiaolan, Mindy Z.
Firms finance intangible investment through employee compensation contracts. In a dynamic model in which intangible capital is embodied in a firm's employees, we analyze the firm's optimal decisions on intangible capital investment, employee compensation contracts, and financial leverage. Employee financing is achieved by delaying wage payments in the form of future claims. We show that intangible capital investment is highly correlated with employee financing but not with debt issuance or regular equity refinancing. In our quantitative analysis, we show that this new channel of employee financing explains the cross-industry differences in leverage and financing patterns. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Sun, Qi; Xiaolan, Mindy Z.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firing the wrong workers: Financing constraints and labor misallocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caggese, Andrea; Cunat, Vicente; Metzger, Daniel
Firms consider wages, current and expected productivity, as well as firing and hiring costs when firing a worker. Financing constraints distort this intertemporal trade-off, leading firms to sub-optimally fire short-tenured workers with high future expected productivity. We provide empirical evidence of this distortion using matched employer-employee data from the Swedish population between 2000 and 2010. We propose a new empirical strategy that uses credit ratings to identify financing constraints and uses exchange rates and trade data to identify demand shocks. Our empirical results identify an important new misallocation effect of financial frictions that operates within firms across different types of workers. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caggese, Andrea; Cunat, Vicente; Metzger, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy spillovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Shai; Colonnelli, Emanuele; Giroud, Xavier; Iverson, Benjamin
How do different bankruptcy approaches affect the local economy? Using US Census microdata, we explore the spillover effects of reorganization and liquidation on geographically proximate firms. We exploit the random assignment of bankruptcy judges as a source of exogenous variation in the probability of liquidation. We find that employment declines substantially in the immediate neighborhood of the liquidated establishments, relative to reorganized establishments. The spillover effects are highly localized and concentrate in nontradable and service sectors, consistent with a reduction in local consumer traffic and a decline in knowledge spillovers between firms. The evidence highlights the externalities that bankruptcy design can impose on nonbankrupt firms. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bernstein, Shai; Colonnelli, Emanuele; Giroud, Xavier; Iverson, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private equity and human capital risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antoni, Manfred; Maug, Ernst; Obernberger, Stefan
We study the human capital effects of private equity buyouts in Germany. We conduct matched-sample difference-in-differences estimations at the establishment and at the individual employee level with more than 152 thousand buyout employees and a carefully matched control group. Buyouts are followed by a reduction in overall employment and an increase in employee turnover. Employees of buyout targets experience earnings declines equivalent to 2.8% of median earnings in the fifth year after the buyout. Managers and older employees fare far worse after buyouts compared with the average target employee, even though they are not more likely to lose their jobs at the target compared with other employees. We argue that the employees most negatively affected after buyouts are those who are less likely to find new employment, not those who are most likely to lose their jobs. Evidence exists of a reduction in administrative staff and more hiring for jobs that require IT skills. (C) 2019 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Antoni, Manfred; Maug, Ernst; Obernberger, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Drivers of effort: Evidence from employee absenteeism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennedsen, Morten; Tsoutsoura, Margarita; Wolfenzon, Daniel
We use detailed information on individual absent spells of all employees in 4140 firms in Denmark to show large differences in average absenteeism across firms. Using employees who switch firms, we decompose days absent into an individual component (e.g., motivation, work ethic) and a firm component (e.g., incentives, corporate culture). We find the firm component explains 50%-60% of the difference in absenteeism across firms, with the individual component explaining the rest. We present suggestive evidence of the mechanisms behind the firm effect with family firm status and concentrated ownership strongly correlated with decreases in absenteeism. We also analyze the firm characteristics that correlate with the individual effect and find that firms with stronger career incentives attract lower-absenteeism employees. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bennedsen, Morten; Tsoutsoura, Margarita; Wolfenzon, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate leverage and employees' rights in bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellul, Andrew; Pagano, Marco
Corporate leverage responds differently to employees' rights in bankruptcy depending on whether it is driven by strategic concerns in wage bargaining or by credit constraints. Using novel data on employees' rights in bankruptcy, we estimate their impact on leverage, exploiting time-series, cross-country, and firm-level variation in the data. For financially unconstrained firms, results accord with the strategic debt model: leverage increases more in response to rises in corporate property values or profitability if employees have strong seniority in liquidation and weak rights in restructuring. Instead, in financially constrained firms leverage responds less to these shocks if employees have stronger seniority. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ellul, Andrew; Pagano, Marco</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Patent trolls and startup employment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Appel, Ian; Farre-Mensa, Joan; Simintzi, Elena
We analyze how frivolous patent infringement claims made by nonpracticing entities (NPEs, or "patent trolls") affect startups' ability to grow and create jobs, innovate, and raise capital. Our identification strategy exploits the staggered adoption of anti-troll laws in 32 US states. The laws lead to a 4.4% increase in employment at high-tech startups-an increase driven by IT firms, a frequent target of NPEs. Increased access to financing, both venture capital and patent-backed lending, is a key channel driving our findings. Measures aimed at curbing the threat posed by NPEs can thus help reduce the real and financing frictions faced by startups. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Appel, Ian; Farre-Mensa, Joan; Simintzi, Elena</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do labor markets discipline? Evidence from RMBS bankers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Kruger, Samuel; Maturana, Gonzalo
This paper examines whether employees involved in residential mortgage-backed security (RMBS) securitization experienced internal and external labor market consequences relative to similar non-RMBS employees in the same banks and why. Senior RMBS bankers experienced similar levels of job retention, promotion, and external job opportunities. Even signers of RMBS deals with high loss and misreporting rates or deals implicated in lawsuits experienced no adverse internal or external labor market outcomes. These findings are likely not explained by targeted or delayed employee discipline, small legal fines, or protection due to pending litigation but are consistent with implicit upper-management approval of RMBS activities. (C) 2018 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Kruger, Samuel; Maturana, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selection versus talent effects on firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Briana; Hong, Harrison
Measuring the value of labor-market hires for stock prices, be it underwriters when firms go public (IPOs) or chief executive officers (CEOs), is difficult due to selection. Opaque firms with higher costs of capital benefit more from prestigious underwriters, while productive firms benefit more from talented CEOs. Using assignment models, we show that the importance of talent (or agent heterogeneity) relative to selection (or firm heterogeneity) is measured by wage increases across agents of different compensation ranks divided by changes in output across their firms. The median of this ratio is 0.5% for underwriters and 2% for CEOs. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Briana; Hong, Harrison</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why did the q theory of investment start working?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrei, Daniel; Mann, William; Moyen, Nathalie
We show that the relation between aggregate investment and Tobin's g has become remarkably tight in recent years, contrasting with earlier times. We connect this change with the growing empirical dispersion in Tobin's q, which we show both in the cross-section and the time series. To study the source of this dispersion, we augment a standard investment model with two distinct mechanisms related to firms' research activities: innovations and learning. Both innovation jumps in cash flows and the frequent updating of beliefs about future cash flows endogenously amplify volatility in the firm's value function. Perhaps counterintuitively, the investment-q regression works better for research-intensive industries, a growing segment of the economy, despite their greater stock of intangible assets. We confirm the model's predictions in the data, and we disentangle the results from measurement error in q. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andrei, Daniel; Mann, William; Moyen, Nathalie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical tests of asset pricing models with individual assets: Resolving the errors-in-variables bias in risk premium estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jegadeesh, Narasimhan; Noh, Joonki; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Roll, Richard; Wang, Junbo
To attenuate an inherent errors-in-variables bias, portfolios are widely employed to test asset pricing models; but portfolios might mask relevant risk- or return-related features of individual stocks. We propose an instrumental variables approach that allows the use of individual stocks as test assets, yet delivers consistent estimates of ex post risk premiums. This estimator also yields well-specified tests in small samples. The market risk premium under the capital asset pricing model (CAPM) and the liquidity-adjusted CAPM, premiums on risk factors under the Fama-French three- and five-factor models, and the Hou et al. (2015) four-factor model are all insignificant after controlling for asset characteristics. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jegadeesh, Narasimhan; Noh, Joonki; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Roll, Richard; Wang, Junbo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How news and its context drive risk and returns around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calomiris, Charles W.; Mamaysky, Harry
We develop a classification methodology for the context and content of news articles to predict risk and return in stock markets in 51 developed and emerging economies. A parsimonious summary of news, including topic-specific sentiment, frequency, and unusualness (entropy) of word flow, predicts future country-level returns, volatilities, and drawdowns. Economic and statistical significance are high and larger for year ahead than monthly predictions. The effect of news measures on market outcomes differs by country type and over time. News stories about emerging markets contain more incremental information. Out-of-sample testing confirms the economic value of our approach for forecasting country-level market outcomes. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calomiris, Charles W.; Mamaysky, Harry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government debt and corporate leverage: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demirci, Irem; Huang, Jennifer; Sialm, Clemens
We empirically investigate the impact of government debt on corporate financing decisions in an international setting. We show a negative relation between government debt and corporate leverage using data on 40 countries between 1990-2014. This negative relation is stronger for government debt that is financed domestically, for firms that are larger and more profitable, and in countries with more developed equity markets. To address potential endogeneity concerns, we use an instrumental variable approach based on military spending and a quasi-natural experiment based on the introduction of the Euro currency. Our findings suggest that government debt crowds out corporate debt. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Demirci, Irem; Huang, Jennifer; Sialm, Clemens</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A capital structure channel of monetary policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grosse-Rueschkamp, Benjamin; Steffen, Sascha; Streitz, Daniel
We study the transmission channels from central banks' quantitative easing programs via the banking sector when central banks start purchasing corporate bonds. We find evidence consistent with a "capital structure channel" of monetary policy. The announcement of central bank purchases reduces the bond yields of firms whose bonds are eligible for central bank purchases. These firms substitute bank term loans with bond debt, thereby relaxing banks' lending constraints: banks with low tier-1 ratios and high nonperforming loans increase lending to private (and profitable) firms, which experience a growth in investment. The credit reallocation increases banks' risk-taking in corporate credit. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grosse-Rueschkamp, Benjamin; Steffen, Sascha; Streitz, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of bank monitoring on public bond terms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ma, Zhiming; Stice, Derrald; Williams, Christopher
This study examines the effect of bank loan monitoring on public bond contract design. We find that bond yield spreads are lower and that bond issuance amounts are larger when a borrower has recently obtained a private loan, consistent with bond issuers benefiting from the screening and ongoing monitoring of banks. We find that these bonds include more covenants than bonds issued without the cross-monitoring of banks, consistent with bondholders wanting to protect themselves from private lenders. This effect is larger for firms with high information asymmetry and larger potential conflicts between different lender types. Our results are robust to a battery of sensitivity tests. Overall, our empirical results suggest that borrowers that precede their public bond issuances with private loan agreements receive more favorable bond terms. Meanwhile, these benefits are associated with the cost of increased monitoring by public bonds. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ma, Zhiming; Stice, Derrald; Williams, Christopher</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility and the cross-section of corporate bond returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Kee H.; Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi
This paper examines the pricing of volatility risk and idiosyncratic volatility in the cross-section of corporate bond returns for the period of 1994-2016. Results show that bonds with high volatility betas have low expected returns, and this negative relation appears in all segments of corporate bonds. Further, bonds with high idiosyncratic bond (stock) volatility have high (low) expected returns, and this relation strengthens as ratings decrease. Conventional risk factors and bond/issuer characteristics cannot account for these cross-sectional relations. There is evidence that the effect of idiosyncratic stock volatility on expected bond returns works through the channel of contemporaneous stock returns. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, Kee H.; Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do firms hedge with foreign currency derivatives for employees?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Pinghsun; Huang, Hsin-Yi; Zhang, Yan
Using a sample of 3004 US firm-years with foreign sales, we provide the first evidence that a firm's employee treatment score is an important determinant of its fraction of foreign sales hedged with currency-based derivatives. The positive relation between employee treatment rating and currency hedging activity is driven by firms operating in competitive industries, businesses with relatively unique products or assets, and companies adopting aggressive business strategies. These results suggest that firms with foreign sales tend to factor employee benefits in their currency hedging policies when their acquisition, development, and retention of human capital are especially costly or highly valued. (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Huang, Pinghsun; Huang, Hsin-Yi; Zhang, Yan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of executive cash bonuses in providing individual and team incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guay, Wayne R.; Kepler, John D.; Tsui, David
Given CEOs' substantial equity portfolios, much recent literature on CEO incentives regards cash-based bonus plans as largely irrelevant, begging the question of why nearly all CEO compensation plans include such bonuses. We develop a new measure of bonus plan incentives and show that performance sensitivities are much greater than prior estimates. We also test hypotheses regarding the role of bonuses in providing executives with individualized and team incentives. We find little evidence supporting the individualized incentives hypotheses but find consistent evidence that bonus plans appear to be used to encourage mutual monitoring and to facilitate coordination across the top management team as a whole. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guay, Wayne R.; Kepler, John D.; Tsui, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cash conversion cycle spread</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Baolian
The cash conversion cycle (CCC) refers to the time span between the outlay of cash for purchases to the receipt of cash from sales. It is a widely used metric to gauge the effectiveness of a firm's management and intrinsic need for external financing. This paper shows that a zero-investment portfolio that buys the lowest CCC decile stocks and shorts the highest CCC decile stocks earns 5%-7% alphas per year. The CCC effect is prevalent across industries, remains even for large capitalization stocks, distinct from the known return predictors, and cannot be explained by the financial intermediary leverage risk. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Baolian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does social capital mitigate agency problems? Evidence from Chief Executive Officer (CEO) compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoi, Chun Keung; Wu, Qiang; Zhang, Hao
We find that social capital, as captured by secular norms and social networks surrounding corporate headquarters, is negatively associated with levels of CEO compensation. This relation holds in a range of robustness tests including those that address omitted variable bias and reverse causality. Additionally, social capital reduces the likelihood that firms make opportunistic option grant awards that unduly favor CEOs, including lucky awards, backdated awards, and unscheduled awards. Social capital also lessens the accretive effect of CEO power on CEO compensation. These findings indicate that social capital mitigates agency problems by restraining managerial rent extraction in CEO compensation. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hoi, Chun Keung; Wu, Qiang; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interconnectedness in the interbank market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunetti, Celso; Harris, Jeffrey H.; Mankad, Shawn; Michailidis, George
We study the behavior of the interbank market around the 2008 financial crisis. Using network analysis, we study two network structures, correlation networks based on publicly traded bank returns and physical networks based on interbank lending transactions, among these public and also private banks. While the two networks behave similarly pre-crisis, during the crisis the correlation network shows an increase in interconnectedness, while the physical network highlights a marked decrease in interconnectedness. Moreover, these networks respond differently to monetary and macroeconomic shocks. Physical networks forecast liquidity problems, while correlation networks forecast financial crises. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Brunetti, Celso; Harris, Jeffrey H.; Mankad, Shawn; Michailidis, George</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option prices and costly short-selling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atmaz, Adem; Basak, Suleyman
Much empirical evidence shows that stock short-selling costs and bans have significant effects on option prices. We reconcile these findings by providing a dynamic analysis of option prices with costly short-selling and option market makers. We obtain simple, closed-form, unique option bid and ask prices that represent option market makers' expected hedging costs, and are weighted averages of well-known benchmark prices (Black-Scholes, Heston). Our analysis delivers rich implications that support the empirical evidence on the effects of short-selling costs and bans on option prices, as well as uncovering several novel predictions. We also apply our methodology to corporate bonds, which have option-like payoffs. (C) 2019 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Atmaz, Adem; Basak, Suleyman</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Average skewness matters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jondeau, Eric; Zhang, Qunzi; Zhu, Xiaoneng
Average skewness, which is the average of monthly skewness values across firms, performs well at predicting future market returns. This prediction still holds after controlling for the size or liquidity of the firms or for current business cycle conditions. Also, average skewness compares favorably with other economic and financial predictors of subsequent market returns. The asset allocation exercise based on predictive regressions also shows that average skewness generates superior performance. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jondeau, Eric; Zhang, Qunzi; Zhu, Xiaoneng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size and value in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Jianan; Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yuan, Yu
We construct size and value factors in China. The size factor excludes the smallest 30% of firms, which are companies valued significantly as potential shells in reverse mergers that circumvent tight IPO constraints. The value factor is based on the earnings-price ratio, which subsumes the book-to-market ratio in capturing all Chinese value effects. Our three-factor model strongly dominates a model formed by just replicating the Fama and French (1993) procedure in China. Unlike that model, which leaves a 17% annual alpha on the earnings-price factor, our model explains most reported Chinese anomalies, including profitability and volatility anomalies. (C) 2019 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Liu, Jianan; Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yuan, Yu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of collateral in trade finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Costello, Anna M.
Suppliers are subject to the credit risk of their customers when they sell products on credit. However, rights to the collateral value of the products they sell may mitigate some of this risk. This paper demonstrates the important role of laws that support suppliers' rights to reclaim and liquidate collateral. Using a change in the US bankruptcy code that altered the rights of a subset of suppliers, I use a difference-in-differences setting to show that an improvement in suppliers' rights to the liquidation value of collateral results in an increase in the amount and duration of trade credit offered. The increase in collateral protection also reduced suppliers' lending standards, resulting in more dispersed trade credit lending and riskier customer portfolios. Finally, I find that the increase in collateral rights decreased suppliers' incentives to monitor their customers, consistent with collateral and monitoring being substitutes. Overall, the paper shows that with strong legal protections in place, trade credit has an important collateral component. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Costello, Anna M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From mining to markets: The evolution of bitcoin transaction fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen; Basu, Soumya
We investigate the role that transaction fees play in the bitcoin blockchain's evolution from a mining-based structure to a market-based ecology. We develop a game-theoretic model to explain the factors leading to the emergence of transactions fees, as well as to explain the strategic behavior of miners and users. Our model highlights the role played by mining rewards, transaction fees, price, and waiting time, discusses welfare issues, and examines how microstructure features such as exogenous structural constraints influence the dynamics of user participation on the blockchain. We provide empirical evidence on the model's predictions and discuss implications for bitcoin's evolution. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen; Basu, Soumya</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A tale of two volatilities: Sectoral uncertainty, growth, and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Segal, Gill
What is the impact of higher technological volatility on asset prices and macroeconomic aggregates? I find the answer hinges on its sectoral origin. Volatility that originates from the consumption (investment) sector drops (raises) macroeconomic growth rates and stock prices. Moreover, consumption (investment) sector's technological volatility has a positive (negative) market price of risk. I show that a quantitative two-sector DSGE model that features monopolistic power for firms and sticky prices, as well as early resolution of uncertainty, can explain the differential impact of sectoral volatilities on real and financial variables. In all, the sectoral decomposition of volatility can overturn the typical negative relation between aggregate volatility and economic activity. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Segal, Gill</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inverted fee structures, tick size, and market quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Gregoire, Vincent; Zhong, Zhuo
Stock exchanges compete for order flow through their fee models. A traditional model pays rebates to liquidity suppliers, and an inverted model pays rebates to liquidity demanders. Using a regulatory intervention to examine the interaction between tick size, restrictions on dark trading, and exchange fees, we show that traders use inverted venues to adjust for suboptimal tick sizes. Increased inverted venue activity improves pricing efficiency and liquidity, especially when the tick size is binding. We show that the sub-tick price improvement offered by inverted venues enhances competition for liquidity provision and increases information impounded into prices through nonmarketable limit orders. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Gregoire, Vincent; Zhong, Zhuo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An asset pricing approach to testing general term structure models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christensen, Bent Jesper; van der Wel, Michel
We develop a new empirical approach to term structure analysis that allows testing for time-varying risk premiums and arbitrage opportunities in models with both unobservable factors and factors identified as the innovations to observed macroeconomic variables. Factors can play double roles as both covariance-generating common shocks driving yields and determinants of market prices of risk in cross-sectional pricing. The evidence favors time-varying risk prices significantly related to the second Stock-Watson principal component of macroeconomic variables and to changes in the industrial production index. Our preferred specification includes these two observable and two unobservable factors, with the no-arbitrage condition imposed. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christensen, Bent Jesper; van der Wel, Michel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A tug of war: Overnight versus intraday expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lou, Dong; Polk, Christopher; Skouras, Spyros
We link investor heterogeneity to the persistence of the overnight and intraday components of returns. We document strong overnight and intraday firm-level return continuation along with an offsetting cross-period reversal effect, all of which lasts for years. We look for a similar tug of war in the returns of 14 trading strategies, finding in all cases that profits are either earned entirely overnight (for reversal and a variety of momentum strategies) or entirely intraday, typically with profits of opposite signs across these components. We argue that this tug of war should reduce the effectiveness of clienteles pursuing the strategy. Indeed, the smoothed spread between the overnight and intraday return components of a strategy generally forecasts time variation in that strategy's close-to-close performance in a manner consistent with that interpretation. Finally, we link cross-sectional and time-series variation in the decomposition of momentum profits to a specific institutional tug of war. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lou, Dong; Polk, Christopher; Skouras, Spyros</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Property rights institutions, foreign investment, and the valuation of multinational firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Leming; Mihov, Atanas; Sanz, Leandro; Stoyanova, Detelina
We study the effect of property rights institutions in host countries, the institutions protecting investors from expropriation by host country agents, on the geographic structure and valuation of US multinational corporations (MNCs). We provide firm-level evidence that better property rights attract investment from MNCs. We disentangle the effects of the Stulz (2005) "twin agency problems" in the context of foreign direct investment and show that our results are not driven by legal institutions protecting investors from expropriation by corporate insiders. Further, we show that changes in the quality of property rights in locations where MNCs operate have material impact on MNCs' valuations. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Leming; Mihov, Atanas; Sanz, Leandro; Stoyanova, Detelina</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crowdsourced employer reviews and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, T. Clifton; Huang, Ruoyan; Wen, Quan; Zhou, Dexin
We find that firms experiencing improvements in crowdsourced employer ratings significantly outperform firms with declines. The return effect is concentrated among reviews from current employees, stronger among early firm reviews, and also stronger when the employee works in the headquarters state. Decomposing employer ratings, we find the return effect is related to changing employee assessments of Career Opportunities and views of senior management. It is unrelated to work-life balance. Employer rating changes are associated with growth in sales and profitability and help forecast one-quarter-ahead earnings announcement surprises. The evidence is consistent with employee reviews revealing fundamental information about the firm. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Green, T. Clifton; Huang, Ruoyan; Wen, Quan; Zhou, Dexin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity, innovation, and endogenous growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malamud, Semyon; Zucchi, Francesca
We build a model of endogenous, innovation-driven growth in which innovative firms have costly access to outside financing and hoard cash reserves to maintain financial flexibility. We show that financing frictions slow down Schumpeterian creative destruction by discouraging entry. As a result, financing frictions importantly affect the composition of growth, by reducing the contribution of entrants but spurring the contribution of incumbents. We investigate the net impact of these countervailing effects on the equilibrium growth rate and welfare. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malamud, Semyon; Zucchi, Francesca</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross-section of labor leverage and equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donangelo, Andres; Gourio, Francois; Kehrig, Matthias; Palacios, Miguel
The relative size and inflexibility of labor expenses lead to a form of operating leverage, which we call labor leverage. We derive a set of conditions for the existence of labor leverage even when labor markets are frictionless. Our model provides theoretical support for the use of firm-level labor share as a measure of labor leverage. Using Compustat/CRSP and confidential Census data, we provide evidence for the existence and for the economic significance of labor leverage: high labor share firms have operating profits that are more sensitive to economic shocks and have higher expected returns. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Donangelo, Andres; Gourio, Francois; Kehrig, Matthias; Palacios, Miguel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Too good to be true? Fallacies in evaluating risk factor models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gospodinov, Nikolay; Kan, Raymond; Robotti, Cesare
This paper is concerned with statistical inference and model evaluation in possibly misspecified and unidentified linear asset pricing models estimated by maximum likelihood. Strikingly, when spurious factors (that is, factors that are uncorrelated with the returns on the test assets) are present, the model exhibits perfect fit, as measured by the squared correlation between the model's fitted expected returns and the average realized returns. Furthermore, factors that are spurious are selected with high probability, and factors that are useful are driven out of the model. While ignoring potential misspecification and lack of identification can be very problematic for models with macroeconomic factors, empirical specifications with traded factors (e.g., Fama and French, 1993; Hou et al., 2015) do not suffer from the identification problems shown in this study. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gospodinov, Nikolay; Kan, Raymond; Robotti, Cesare</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mood, firm behavior, and aggregate economic outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chhaochharia, Vidhi; Kim, Dasol; Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok
This study examines whether mood affects the aggregate state-level macroeconomy through its impact on firm-level decisions. Using sky cloud cover as a proxy for mood, we show that mood affects the economic expectations of small business managers. After relatively sunnier periods, managers have more optimistic expectations, and the component of their expectations related to mood influences hiring and investment decisions. Consequently, mood affects state-level job creation and new business starts, especially during periods of greater economic uncertainty. These results suggest that mood-induced economic expectations influence firm-level managerial decisions and state-level macroeconomic fluctuations. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chhaochharia, Vidhi; Kim, Dasol; Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Municipal borrowing costs and state policies for distressed municipalities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Pengjie; Lee, Chang; Murphy, Dermot
Policies on financially distressed municipalities differ across US states, with some allowing unconditional access to Chapter 9 bankruptcy (Chapter 9 states) and others having proactive policies to assist distressed municipalities (Proactive states). These differences significantly affect borrowing costs. In Chapter 9 states, local municipal bond yields are higher, more cyclical, and more sensitive to default events than Proactive states. Default events have a contagion effect in Chapter 9 states, but not Proactive states. Lower local borrowing costs in Proactive states come at the expense of the state via higher intergovernmental revenue transfers in times of weak economic conditions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gao, Pengjie; Lee, Chang; Murphy, Dermot</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital flows and sovereign debt markets: Evidence from index rebalancings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pandolfi, Lorenzo; Williams, Tomas
We analyze how capital flows into the sovereign debt market affect government bond prices, liquidity, and exchange rates. To address endogeneity concerns, we construct a measure of informationless capital Flows Implied by (mechanical) Rebalancings (FIR) in the largest emerging markets local currency government debt index. FIR is associated with higher returns and greater depth in the sovereign debt market after the rebalancings. Also, larger inflows (outflows) are associated with greater currency appreciations (depreciations). Our results highlight the increasing importance of capital flows driven by demand shocks, due to the growing relevance of benchmark indexes as the preferred habitat for institutional investors. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pandolfi, Lorenzo; Williams, Tomas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Attention allocation and return co-movement: Evidence from repeated natural experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Shiyang; Huang, Yulin; Lin, Tse-Chun
We hypothesize that when investors pay less attention to financial markets, they rationally allocate relatively more attention to market-level information than to firm-specific information, leading to increases in stock return co-movements. Using large jackpot lotteries as exogenous shocks that attract investors' attention away from the stock market, we find supportive evidence that stock returns co-move more with the market on large jack-pot days. This effect is stronger for stocks preferred by retail investors and is not driven by gambling sentiment. We also find that stock returns are less sensitive to earnings surprises and co-move more with industries on large jackpot days. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Shiyang; Huang, Yulin; Lin, Tse-Chun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity standards and the value of an informed lender of last resort</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santos, Joao A. C.; Suarez, Javier
We consider a dynamic model in which receiving support from the lender of last resort (LLR) may help banks to weather investor runs. We show the need for regulatory liquidity standards when the underlying social trade-offs make the uninformed LLR inclined to support troubled banks during a run. Liquidity standards increase the time available before the LLR must decide on supporting the bank. This facilitates the arrival of information on the bank's financial condition and improves the efficiency of the decision taken by the LLR, a role that can be modified but not replaced with the use of capital regulation. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Santos, Joao A. C.; Suarez, Javier</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An anatomy of the market return</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schneider, Paul
This paper introduces a model free decomposition of S&amp;P 500 forward market index returns in terms of realized and implied dispersion, downside, and tail risk using option portfolios. The decomposition lends itself by construction to learn about the different sources of risk in the market return and subsequently to visual and formal diagnosing of asset pricing models. It utilizes a novel conditional frequency analysis on the basis of available options rather than the times series of the S&amp;P 500. Empirically, downside risk accounts for most of the forward market return, while symmetric tail risk is not prominently featured. The predictable, persistent part of the realized return is small. Nevertheless, signals revealed by this risk anatomy provide predictive out of sample power for realized returns, in particular for longer maturities. Furthermore, it indicates that models with identically and independently distributed state variables are generally misspecified in this market, and that care must be taken when calibrating disaster risk models. A formal test based on the risk anatomy rejects a model with time-varying disaster intensity. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schneider, Paul</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entry and competition in takeover auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gentry, Matthew; Stroup, Caleb
We estimate the degree of uncertainty faced by potential bidders in takeover auctions and quantify how it affects prices in auctions and negotiations. The high degree of uncertainty revealed by our structural estimation encourages entry in auctions but reduces a target's bargaining power in negotiations. In the aggregate, auctions and negotiations produce similar prices, even though auctions are preferred in takeover markets with high uncertainty, while the reverse is true for negotiations. Firm characteristics predict pre-entry uncertainty and thus are informative about the relative performance of auctions and negotiations for individual targets. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Gentry, Matthew; Stroup, Caleb</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do private equity funds manipulate reported returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Gregory W.; Gredil, Oleg R.; Kaplan, Steven N.
Private equity funds hold assets that are hard to value. Managers have incentives to distort reported valuations if these reports are used by investors to decide on commitments to subsequent funds. Using a large dataset of buyout and venture funds, we test for the presence of return manipulations. We find that some underperforming managers inflate reported returns during fundraising. However, those managers are less likely to raise a next fund, suggesting that investors can see through the manipulation. In contrast, top-performing funds appear to understate valuations. A simple theoretical framework rationalizes our empirical results as well as those of related papers. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Gregory W.; Gredil, Oleg R.; Kaplan, Steven N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government debt and the returns to innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Croce, M. M.; Nguyen, Thien T.; Raymon, S.; Schmid, L.
Elevated levels of government debt raise concerns about their effects on long-term growth prospects. Using the cross-section of US stock returns, we show that (i) high-R&amp;D firms are more exposed to government debt and pay higher expected returns than low-R&amp;D firms, and (ii) higher levels of the debt-to-GDP ratio predict higher risk premiums for high-R&amp;D firms. Furthermore, rises in the cost of capital for innovation-intensive firms predict declines in subsequent productivity and economic growth. We propose a production-based asset pricing model with endogenous innovation and fiscal policy shocks that can rationalize key aspects of the empirical evidence. Our study highlights a novel and distinct risk channel shaping the link between government debt and future growth. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Croce, M. M.; Nguyen, Thien T.; Raymon, S.; Schmid, L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should investors learn about the timing of equity risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasler, Michael; Khapko, Mariana; Marfe, Roberto
The term structure of equity risk has been shown to be downward sloping. We capture this feature using return dynamics driven by both a transitory and a permanent component. We study the asset allocation and portfolio performance when transitory and permanent components cannot be observed and therefore need to be estimated. Strategies that account for the observed timing of equity risk outperform those that do not, particularly so out of sample. Indeed, the mean (median) certainty equivalent return increases from about 13% (12%) to about 21% (15%) because properly modeling the timing of equity risk implies surges in portfolio returns. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasler, Michael; Khapko, Mariana; Marfe, Roberto</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The liquidity cost of private equity investments: Evidence from secondary market transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nadauld, Taylor D.; Sensoy, Berk A.; Vorkink, Keith; Weisbach, Michael S.
This paper uses proprietary data from a leading intermediary to explain the magnitude and determinants of transaction costs in the secondary market for private equity stakes. Most transactions occur at a discount to net asset value. Buyers average an annualized public market equivalent of 1.023 compared with 0.976 for sellers, implying that buyers outperform sellers by a market-adjusted 5 percentage points annually. Both the cross-sectional pattern of transaction costs and the identity of sellers and buyers suggest that the market is one in which relatively flexible buyers earn returns by supplying liquidity to investors wishing to exit. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nadauld, Taylor D.; Sensoy, Berk A.; Vorkink, Keith; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New goods and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scanlon, Paul
I extend the consumption capital asset pricing model to incorporate expanding product variety over time and states of nature. In the model, consumers have a love of variety, and consumption consists of different components: product groups and brands. By raising future marginal utility, growth in product groups increases the incentive to save and reduces the risk-free rate. By making marginal utility more volatile, variation in brand and quality growth magnifies consumption risk and raises the equity premium. Embedding new goods in a long-run risk setting has similar implications. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Scanlon, Paul</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy externalities and banking integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smolyansky, Michael
Can policies directed at the banking sector in one jurisdiction spill over and affect real economic activity elsewhere? To investigate this question, I exploit changes in tax rates on bank profits across US states. Banks respond by reallocating small business lending to otherwise unaffected states. Moreover, counties in non-tax-changing states that have more exposure to treated banks experience greater changes in lending, which in turn impacts local employment. The findings demonstrate that policies aimed at the banking sector in one jurisdiction can impose externalities on other regions. Critically, financial linkages between regions serve as the transmission channel for these policy externalities. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Smolyansky, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Once bitten, twice shy: The power of personal experiences in risk taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, Steffen; Hanspal, Tobin; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner
We study whether personal experiences are so powerful that they make individuals actively shy away from risk. Our research design relies on portfolio decisions relating to inheritances, which alter the active decision from one of choosing to take risk to one of choosing to reduce risk. Experience derives from investments in banks that defaulted following the 2007-2009 financial crisis. We classify experiences into first-hand experiences, resulting from personal losses; second-hand experiences, from losses of family members; and third-hand experiences, from locations where banks defaulted. Our results demonstrate that experiences gained personally, not common shocks, make individuals shy away from risk. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Andersen, Steffen; Hanspal, Tobin; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technological links and predictable returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Charles M. C.; Sun, Stephen Teng; Wang, Rongfei; Zhang, Ran
Employing a classic measure of technological closeness between firms, we show that the returns of technology-linked firms have strong predictive power for focal firm returns. A long-short strategy based on this effect yields monthly alpha of 117 basis points. This effect is distinct from industry momentum and is not easily attributable to risk-based explanations. It is more pronounced for focal firms that: (a) have a more intense and specific technology focus, (b) receive lower investor attention, and (c) are more difficult to arbitrage. Our results are broadly consistent with sluggish price adjustment to more nuanced technological news. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Lee, Charles M. C.; Sun, Stephen Teng; Wang, Rongfei; Zhang, Ran</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gold, platinum, and expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Darien; Kilic, Mete
The ratio of gold to platinum prices (GP) reveals persistent variation in risk and proxies for an important economic state variable. GP predicts future stock returns in the time series, explains stock return variation in the cross-section, and is significantly correlated with option-implied tail risk measures. Contrary to conventional wisdom, gold prices fall in recessions, albeit by less than platinum prices. A model featuring recursive preferences, time-varying tail risk, and preference shocks for gold and platinum can account for asset pricing dynamics of equity, gold, and platinum markets, rationalize the return predictability, and explain why gold prices fall in bad times. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Darien; Kilic, Mete</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information and trading targets in a dynamic market equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Jin Hyuk; Larsen, Kasper; Seppi, Duane J.
This paper describes equilibrium interactions between dynamic portfolio rebalancing given a private end-of-day trading target and dynamic trading on long-lived private information. Order-splitting for portfolio rebalancing injects multifaceted dynamics in the market. These include autocorrelated order flow, sunshine trading, endogenous learning, and short-term speculation. The model has testable implications for intraday patterns in volume, liquidity, price volatility, order-flow autocorrelation, differences between informed-investor and re-balancer trading strategies, and for how these patterns comove with trading-target volatility and other market conditions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choi, Jin Hyuk; Larsen, Kasper; Seppi, Duane J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should retail investors' leverage be limited?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heimer, Rawley; Simsek, Alp
Does the provision of leverage to retail traders improve market quality or facilitate socially inefficient speculation that enriches financial intermediaries? We evaluate the effects of 2010 regulations that cap leverage in the U.S. retail foreign exchange market. Using three unique data sets and a difference-in-differences approach, we document that the leverage-constraint reduces trading volume by 23%, alleviates high-leverage traders' losses by 40%, and reduces brokerages' operating capital by 25%. Yet, the policy does not affect the relative bid-ask prices charged by the brokerages. These results suggest the policy improves belief-neutral social welfare without reducing market liquidity. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heimer, Rawley; Simsek, Alp</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In search of preference shock risks: Evidence from longevity risks and momentum profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhanhui; Yang, Bowen
Time-preference shocks affect agents' preferences for assets with different durations. We consider longevity risk as a source of time-preference shocks and model it in the recursive preferences setting. This implies a consumption-based three-factor model, including longevity risk, consumption growth rate, and the market portfolio, where longevity has a negative price of risk. Empirically, this model explains many well-known cross-sectional portfolios. Notably, we find that longevity risk and the momentum factor share a common business cycle component, i.e., short-run consumption risks. Prior winners (losers) provide hedging against mortality (longevity) risk and thus have higher (lower) expected returns, because winners have higher dividend growth and shorter equity durations than losers. Time-varying longevity risk captures most momentum profits over time, including the large momentum crashes observed in the data. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Zhanhui; Yang, Bowen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal capital structure and bankruptcy choice: Dynamic bargaining versus liquidation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antill, Samuel; Grenadier, Steven R.
We model a firm's optimal capital structure decision in a framework in which it may later choose to enter either Chapter 11 reorganization or Chapter 7 liquidation. Creditors anticipate equityholders' ex-post reorganization incentives and price them into the ex-ante credit spreads. Using a realistic dynamic bargaining model of reorganization, we show that the off-equilibrium threat of costly renegotiation can lead to lower leverage, even with liquidation in equilibrium. If reorganization is less efficient than liquidation, the added option of reorganization can actually make equityholders worse off ex-ante, even when they liquidate on the equilibrium path. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Antill, Samuel; Grenadier, Steven R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional investor cliques and governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crane, Alan D.; Koch, Andrew; Michenaud, Sebastien
We examine the impact of investor coordination on governance. We identify coordinating groups of investors (cliques) as those connected through the network of institutional holdings. Clique members vote together on proxy items: a one standard deviation increase in clique ownership more than doubles votes against low quality management proposals. We use the 2003 mutual fund trading scandal to show that this effect is causal. These findings suggest coordination strengthens governance via voice. Coordination, however, also weakens governance via threat of exit. Clique owners exit positions more slowly, and firm value responds negatively to liquidity shocks when clique ownership is high. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Crane, Alan D.; Koch, Andrew; Michenaud, Sebastien</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalized recovery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jensen, Christian Skov; Lando, David; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
We characterize when physical probabilities, marginal utilities, and the discount rate can be recovered from observed state prices for several future time periods. We make no assumptions of the probability distribution, thus generalizing the time-homogeneous stationary model of Ross (2015). Recovery is feasible when the number of maturities with observable prices is higher than the number of states of the economy (or the number of parameters characterizing the pricing kernel). When recovery is feasible, our model allows a closed-form linearized solution. We implement our model empirically, testing the predictive power of the recovered expected return and other recovered statistics. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jensen, Christian Skov; Lando, David; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information sensitivity of debt in good and bad times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brancati, Emanuele; Macchiavelli, Marco
We empirically show the dynamics of information production and information sensitivity of bank debt around the Great Recession. As more precise information is produced at the onset of the crisis, bank debt becomes informationally sensitive, along two separate dimensions. First, precise information amplifies the effect of market expectations on default risk; second, for banks that are already expected to perform poorly, more precise information further increases default risk. Both effects are muted in good times. Overall, our findings are consistent with information-based models of financial crises. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brancati, Emanuele; Macchiavelli, Marco</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The power of shareholder votes: Evidence from uncontested director elections</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Reena; Dahiya, Sandeep; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand R.
This paper asks whether dissent votes in uncontested director elections have consequences for directors. We show that contrary to popular belief based on prior studies, shareholder votes have power and result in negative consequences for directors. Directors facing dissent are more likely to depart boards, especially if they are not lead directors or chairs of important committees. Directors facing dissent who do not leave are moved to less prominent positions on boards. Finally, we find evidence that directors facing dissent face reduced opportunities in the market for directors. We also find that the effects of dissent votes go beyond those of proxy advisor recommendations. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, Reena; Dahiya, Sandeep; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transparency and dealer networks: Evidence from the initiation of post-trade reporting in the mortgage backed security market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, Paul; Song, Zhaogang
We examine the introduction of mandatory post-trade reporting in the To-Be-Announced mortgage-backed securities market. With post-trade reporting, trading costs fell for institutional investors. Trading costs declined more for investors' trades with peripheral dealers than for their trades with core dealers. Peripheral dealers' market share dropped after the introduction of post-trade reporting, suggesting that opacity was protecting inefficient high-cost dealers. Interdealer trades and volume declined as transparency made it easier to find natural counterparties. Relationships between dealers became less important and, after controlling for the number of trades, dealers used more counterparties in interdealer trades. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schultz, Paul; Song, Zhaogang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How valuable are independent directors? Evidence from external distractions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masulis, Ronald W.; Zhang, Emma Jincheng
We provide new evidence on the value of independent directors by exploiting exogenous events that seriously distract independent directors. Approximately 20% of independent directors are significantly distracted in a typical year. They attend fewer meetings, trade less frequently in the firm's stock, and resign from the board more frequently, indicating declining firm-specific knowledge and a reduced board commitment. Firms with more preoccupied independent directors have declining firm valuation and operating performance and exhibit weaker merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) profitability and accounting quality. These effects are stronger when distracted independent directors play key board monitoring roles and when firms require greater director attention. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Masulis, Ronald W.; Zhang, Emma Jincheng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate control activism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corum, Adrian Aycan; Levit, Doron
This paper studies the role of activist investors in the market for corporate control. Our theory proposes that activist investors have an inherent advantage relative to bidders in pressuring entrenched incumbents to sell. As counterparties to the acquisition, bidders have a fundamental conflict of interests with target shareholders from which activist investors are immune. Therefore, unlike activists, the ability of bidders to win proxy fights is very limited. This result is consistent with the large number of activist campaigns that have resulted with the target's sale to a third party and the evidence that most proxy fights are launched by activists, not by bidders. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Corum, Adrian Aycan; Levit, Doron</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrusted loans: A close look at China's shadow banking system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Qian, Yiming; Tu, Guoqian; Yu, Frank
We perform transaction-level analyses of entrusted loans, one of the largest components of shadow banking in China. Entrusted loans involve firms with privileged access to cheap capital channeling funds to less privileged firms, and the increase when credit is tight. Nonaffiliated loans have much higher interest rates than both affiliated loans and official bank loans, and they largely flow into real estate. The pricing of entrusted loans, especially of nonaffiliated loans, incorporates fundamental and informational risks. Stock market reactions suggest that both affiliated and nonaffiliated loans are fairly compensated investments. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Qian, Yiming; Tu, Guoqian; Yu, Frank</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity windfalls: The consequences of repo rehypothecation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Infante, Sebastian
This paper presents a model of repo intermediation in which dealers intermediate secured financing between lenders and borrowers using the same collateral. Lenders are insulated from dealers through their repo's collateral, but borrowers are exposed to dealers through the loss of their collateral. This makes lenders' repo terms insensitive to dealers' default, while borrowers' repo terms are not. The model shows that when repos serve to intermediate collateral, haircuts are negative. This paper explains the difference in haircuts between the bilateral and tri-party repo market and the different run dynamics observed across these markets during the financial crisis. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Infante, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do firms issue more equity when markets become more liquid?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanselaar, Rogier M.; Stulz, Rene M.; van Dijk, Mathijs A.
Using quarterly data on initial public offerings (IPOs) and seasoned equity offerings (SEOs) for 37 countries from 1995 to 2014, we show that changes in equity issuance are positively related to lagged changes in aggregate local stock market liquidity. This relation is as economically significant as the well-known relation between equity issuance and lagged stock returns. It survives the inclusion of proxies for market timing, capital market conditions, growth prospects, asymmetric information, and investor sentiment. Changes in liquidity are less relevant for issuance by firms with greater financial pressures and by firms in less financially developed countries. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanselaar, Rogier M.; Stulz, Rene M.; van Dijk, Mathijs A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decision fatigue and heuristic analyst forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Levi, Yaron; Lourie, Ben; Teoh, Siew Hong
Psychological evidence indicates that decision quality declines after an extensive session of decision-making, a phenomenon known as decision fatigue. We study whether decision fatigue affects analysts' judgments. Analysts cover multiple firms and often issue several forecasts in a single day. We find that forecast accuracy declines over the course of a day as the number of forecasts the analyst has already issued increases. Also consistent with decision fatigue, we find that the more forecasts an analyst issues, the higher the likelihood the analyst resorts to more heuristic decisions by herding more closely with the consensus forecast, self-herding (i.e., reissuing their own previous outstanding forecasts), and issuing a rounded forecast. Finally, we find that the stock market understands these effects and discounts for analyst decision fatigue. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Levi, Yaron; Lourie, Ben; Teoh, Siew Hong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The buyers' perspective on security design: Hedge funds and convertible bond call provisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grundy, Bruce D.; Verwijmeren, Patrick
We provide evidence that security design reflects the interplay of capital supplier and security issuer preferences. While call provisions have historically been the default option in convertible security design, only a minority of post-2005 issues are callable. Because hedge funds dominate the market for new convertibles today and because convertible arbitrage is less risky without callability, the recent diminution in the frequency of call provisions in new convertible bond issues illustrates the importance of the preferences of the suppliers of capital in security design. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grundy, Bruce D.; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants and consequences of information processing delay: Evidence from the Thomson Reuters Institutional Brokers' Estimate System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akbas, Ferhat; Markov, Stanimir; Subasi, Musa; Weisbrod, Eric
We present new evidence that highlights the role of information intermediaries in the distribution and processing of earnings estimates in capital markets. We find that the time taken to activate an analyst's earnings forecast in the Thomson Reuters institutional Brokers' Estimate System is related to measures of investor demand for timely information processing, processing difficulty, and limited attention. Furthermore, we find that forecast announcement returns are muted and post-announcement drift is magnified for forecasts with longer unexpected activation delay and that market inefficiency is concentrated in neglected stocks and potentially exploitable. Finally, analyzing intraday returns, we find that activations facilitate price discovery. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akbas, Ferhat; Markov, Stanimir; Subasi, Musa; Weisbrod, Eric</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pay me now (and later): Pension benefit manipulation before plan freezes and executive retirement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stefanescu, Irina; Wang, Yupeng; Xie, Kangzhen; Yang, Jun
Large US firms modify top executives' compensation before pension-related events. Top executives receive one-time increases in pensionable earnings through higher annual bonuses one year before a plan freeze and one year before retirement. Firms also boost pension payouts by lowering plan discount rates when top executives are eligible to retire with lump-sum benefit distributions. Increases in executive pensions do not appear to be an attempt to improve managerial effort or retention and are more likely to occur at firms with poor corporate governance. These findings suggest that in some circumstances managers are able to extract rents through their pension plans. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stefanescu, Irina; Wang, Yupeng; Xie, Kangzhen; Yang, Jun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial market frictions and diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Matvos, Gregor; Seru, Amit; Silva, Rui C.
We find new facts that relate the evolution of firm scope to the changing frictions in external capital markets over the last three decades. We find that large, diversified publicly traded firms increase their scope during times of high external capital market frictions, such as in the recent Great Recession. Moreover, during these times firms diversify their investment needs and cash flow across industries. We also find similar phenomena outside diversified public firms. Examining the mergers and acquisitions activity of stand-alone and diversified private firms, we uncover similar patterns. In aggregate data, we find that the composition of mergers shifts from focused to diversifying and back with changes in external market conditions. Our evidence is broadly consistent with the notion that firms diversify their scope in response to tightening in external capital markets. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Matvos, Gregor; Seru, Amit; Silva, Rui C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The globalization of angel investments: Evidence across countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lerner, Josh; Schoar, Antoinette; Sokolinski, Stanislav; Wilson, Karen
This paper examines the role of investments by angel groups across a heterogeneous set of 21 countries with varying entrepreneurship ecosystems. Exploiting quasi-random assignment of deals around the groups' funding thresholds, we find a positive impact of funding on firm growth, performance, survival, and follow-on fundraising, which is independent of the level of venture activity and entrepreneur-friendliness in the country. However, the maturity of startups that apply for funding (and are ultimately funded) inversely correlates with the entrepreneurship-friendliness of the country. This may reflect self-censoring by early-stage firms that do not expect to receive funding in these environments. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lerner, Josh; Schoar, Antoinette; Sokolinski, Stanislav; Wilson, Karen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The real effects of credit default swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danis, Andras; Gamba, Andrea
We examine the effect of introducing credit default swaps (CDSs) on firm value. Our model allows for dynamic investment and financing, and bondholders can trade in the CDS market. The model incorporates both negative and positive effects of CDSs. CDS markets lead to more liquidations, but they also reduce the probability of costly debt renegotiation and reduce costly equity financing. After calibrating the model, we find that firm value increases by 2.9% on average with the introduction of a CDS market. Firms also invest more and increase leverage. The effect on firm value is strongest for small, financially constrained, and low productivity firms. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Danis, Andras; Gamba, Andrea</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-rating revenue and conflicts of interest</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baghai, Ramin P.; Becker, Bo
Rating agencies produce ratings used by investors, but obtain most of their revenue from issuers, leading to a conflict of interest. We employ a unique data set on the use of non-rating services, and the associated payments, in India, to test if this conflict affects ratings quality. Agencies rate issuers that pay them for non-rating services higher (than agencies not hired for such services). Such issuers also have higher default rates. Both effects are increasing in the amount paid. These results suggest that issuers which hire agencies for non-rating services receive higher ratings despite having higher default risk. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baghai, Ramin P.; Becker, Bo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital gains lock-in and governance choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimmock, Stephen G.; Gerken, William C.; Ivkovic, Zoran; Weisbenner, Scott J.
Differences in accrued gains and investors' tax-sensitivity induce variation in a capital gains lock-in effect across mutual funds even for the same stock at the same time. Exploiting this variation, we show this effect influences funds' governance decisions: higher capital gains decrease the likelihood a fund exits prior to contentious votes and increase the likelihood a fund votes against management. Consistent with tax motivation, these findings are concentrated among funds with tax-sensitive investors. Further, high aggregate capital gains across funds holding a stock predict a higher likelihood management loses a vote and a lower likelihood a contentious vote is proposed. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dimmock, Stephen G.; Gerken, William C.; Ivkovic, Zoran; Weisbenner, Scott J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The option to quit: The effect of employee stock options on turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aldatmaz, Serdar; Ouimet, Paige; Van Wesep, Edward D.
We show that in the years following a large broad-based employee stock option (BBSO) grant, employee turnover falls at the granting firm. We find evidence consistent with a causal relation by exploiting unexpected changes in the value of unvested options. A large fraction of the reduction in turnover appears to be temporary with turnover increasing in the third year following the year of the adoption of the BBSO plan. The increase three years post-grant is equal in magnitude to the cumulative decrease in turnover over the three prior years, suggesting that long-vesting BBSO plans delay, instead of prevent, turnover. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aldatmaz, Serdar; Ouimet, Paige; Van Wesep, Edward D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When arm's length is too far: Relationship banking over the credit cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Degryse, Hans; De Haas, Ralph; van Horen, Neeltje
We conduct face-to-face interviews with bank chief executive officers to classify 397 banks across 21 countries as relationship or transaction lenders. We then use the geographic coordinates of these banks' branches and of 14,100 businesses to analyze how the lending techniques of banks near firms are related to credit constraints at two contrasting points of the credit cycle. We find that while relationship lending is not associated with credit constraints during a credit boom, it alleviates such constraints during a downturn. This positive role of relationship lending is stronger for small and opaque firms and in regions with a more severe economic downturn. Moreover, relationship lending mitigates the impact of a downturn on firm growth and does not constitute evergreening of loans. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Degryse, Hans; De Haas, Ralph; van Horen, Neeltje</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage constraints and asset prices: Insights from mutual fund risk taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boguth, Oliver; Simutin, Mikhail
Prior theory suggests that time variation in the degree to which leverage constraints bind affects the pricing kernel. We propose a measure for this leverage constraint tightness by inverting the argument that constrained investors tilt their portfolios to riskier assets. We show that the average market beta of actively managed mutual funds intermediaries facing leverage restrictions captures their desire for leverage and thus the tightness of constraints. Consistent with theory, it strongly predicts returns of the betting-against-beta portfolio, and is a priced risk factor in the cross-section of mutual funds and stocks. Funds with low exposure to the factor outperform high-exposure funds by 5% annually, and for stocks this difference reaches 7%. Our results show that the tightness of leverage constraints has important implications for asset prices. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boguth, Oliver; Simutin, Mikhail</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Belief-free price formation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horner, Johannes; Lovo, Stefano; Tomala, Tristan
We analyze security price formation in a dynamic setting in which long-lived dealers repeatedly compete for the opportunity to trade with short-lived retail traders. We characterize equilibria in which dealers' pricing strategies are optimal irrespective of the private information that each dealer may possess. Thus, our model's predictions are robust to different specifications of the dealers' information structure. These equilibria reconcile, in a unified and parsimonious framework, price dynamics that are reminiscent of well-known stylized facts: excess price volatility, price to trading flow correlation, stochastic volatility and inventory-related trading. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Horner, Johannes; Lovo, Stefano; Tomala, Tristan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxation and executive compensation: Evidence from stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bird, Andrew
Understanding the effects of taxes on executive compensation provides insight into the process determining this compensation and is a key input to top income tax rate policy. A 2010 tax reform in Canada, which greatly increased the effective tax rate on stock option compensation for a subset of firms, provides a natural experiment with which to address this issue. Difference-in-differences estimates suggest that this tax increase resulted in an immediate reduction in both stock option grants and the fraction of total compensation made up of stock options with limited, if any, substitution towards other components of compensation. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bird, Andrew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity risk and maturity management over the credit cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mian, Atif; Santos, Joao A. C.
We show that firm demand-side factors are strong drivers of procyclical refinancing behavior over the credit cycle using novel data from the Shared National Credit program. Firms are more likely to refinance early when credit conditions are good to keep the effective maturity of their loans long and hedge against having to refinance in tight credit conditions. High credit quality firms are better able to hedge, making their refinancing propensity more sensitive to credit cycles than less creditworthy firms. There is a strong relationship between refinancing a loan, and subsequent growth in capital expenditure, especially when a loan is refinanced early. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mian, Atif; Santos, Joao A. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alpha or beta in the eye of the beholder: What drives hedge fund flows?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Green, T. Clifton; Ren, Honglin
Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM) alpha explains hedge fund flows better than alphas from more sophisticated models. This suggests that investors pool together sophisticated model alpha with returns from exposures to traditional (except for the market) and exotic risks. We decompose performance into traditional and exotic risk components and find that while investors chase both components, they place greater relative emphasis on returns associated with exotic risk exposures that can only be obtained through hedge funds. However, we find little evidence of persistence in performance from traditional or exotic risks, which cautions against investors' practice of seeking out risk exposures following periods of recent success. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Green, T. Clifton; Ren, Honglin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The (dis)advantages of clearinghouses before the Fed</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jaremski, Matthew
Operating in individual cities, US clearinghouses were the closest thing to a central bank before 1914, but they only assisted banks that chose to join the association. Using an annual bank-level database for seven states between 1880 and 1910, this paper shows that after the entry of a clearinghouse member banks were less likely and nonmember banks in the same city were more likely to close. The results are driven by the fact that the presence of clearinghouses led all banks to become more exposed to systemic liquidity risk, yet provided liquidity only to member banks during panics. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jaremski, Matthew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disagreement about inflation and the yield curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ehling, Paul; Gallmeyer, Michael; Heyerdahl-Larsen, Christian; Illeditsch, Philipp
We show that inflation disagreement, not just expected inflation, has an impact on nominal interest rates. In contrast to expected inflation, which mainly affects the wedge between real and nominal yields, inflation disagreement affects nominal yields predominantly through its impact on the real side of the economy. We show theoretically and empirically that inflation disagreement raises real and nominal yields and their volatilities. Inflation disagreement is positively related to consumers' cross-sectional consumption growth volatility and trading in fixed income securities. Calibrating our model to disagreement, inflation, and yields reproduces the economically significant impact of inflation disagreement on yield curves. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ehling, Paul; Gallmeyer, Michael; Heyerdahl-Larsen, Christian; Illeditsch, Philipp</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resaleable debt and systemic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donaldson, Jason Roderick; Micheler, Eva
Many debt claims, such as bonds, are resaleable; others, such as repos, are not. There was a fivefold increase in repo borrowing before the 2008-2009 financial crisis. Why? Did banks' dependence on non-resaleable debt precipitate the crisis? In this paper, we develop a model of bank lending with credit frictions. The key feature of the model is that debt claims are heterogenous in their resaleability. We find that decreasing credit market frictions leads to an increase in borrowing via non-resaleable debt. Such borrowing has a dark side: It causes credit chains to form, because, if a bank makes a loan via non resaleable debt and needs liquidity, it cannot sell the loan but must borrow via a new contract. These credit chains are a source of systemic risk, as one bank's default harms not only its creditors but also its creditors' creditors. Overall, our model suggests that reducing credit market frictions may have an adverse effect on the financial system and even lead to the failures of financial institutions. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Donaldson, Jason Roderick; Micheler, Eva</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization bubbles: Structured finance with disagreement about default risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Broer, Tobias
An additional reason for the structured finance boom of the 2000s may have been disagreement about default risk of collateral assets. When risk-neutral investors disagree about average default probabilities, structuring collateral cash flow raises prices by concentrating optimists' demand on risky tranches. With disagreement about default correlation, low-correlation investors believe in diversification and pay high prices for senior tranches they deem riskless. High-correlation investors value junior tranches they expect to pay whenever aggregate conditions are good. Risk aversion and short selling through credit default swaps reduce the prices of both pass-through and structured securitizations but may increase the return to tranching. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Broer, Tobias</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The structure of information release and the factor structure of returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilbert, Thomas; Hrdlicka, Christopher; Kamara, Avraham
We model how firms releasing information on different dates causes the CAPM to fail, requiring an additional factor based on the information structure to price assets. We exemplify this mechanism's empirical relevance using quarterly earnings announcements, which cluster across months along size and book-to-market. Seventy percent of the alpha reduction from including SMB and HML occurs in the four main earnings announcement months. The information structure factor accounts for all of SMB and HML's seasonal alpha reduction and one third of their overall alpha reduction. Controlling for size and book-to market, exposures to SMB and HML vary with firms' earnings announcement month. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gilbert, Thomas; Hrdlicka, Christopher; Kamara, Avraham</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Carry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Pedersen, Lasse Heje; Vrugt, Evert B.
We apply the concept of carry, which has been studied almost exclusively in currency markets, to any asset. A security's expected return is decomposed into its "carry," an ex-ante and model-free characteristic, and its expected price appreciation. Carry predicts returns cross-sectionally and in time series for a host of different asset classes, including global equities, global bonds, commodities, US Treasuries, credit, and options. Carry is not explained by known predictors of returns from these asset classes, and it captures many of these predictors, providing a unifying framework for return predictability. We reject a generalized version of Uncovered Interest Parity and the Expectations Hypothesis in favor of models with varying risk premia, in which carry strategies are commonly exposed to global recession, liquidity, and volatility risks, though none fully explains carry's premium. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Pedersen, Lasse Heje; Vrugt, Evert B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Threat of entry and debt maturity: Evidence from airlines</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parise, Gianpaolo
I explore the effect of the threat posed by low-cost competitors on debt structure in the airline industry. I use the route network expansion of low-cost airlines to identify routes where the probability of future entry increases dramatically. I find that when a large portion of their market is threatened, incumbents significantly increase debt maturity before entry occurs. Overall, the main findings suggest that airlines respond to entry threats trading off the benefits of short-term financing for lower rollover risk. The results are consistent with models in which firms set their optimal debt structure in the presence of costly rollover failure. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Parise, Gianpaolo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Four centuries of return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golez, Benjamin; Koudijs, Peter
We combine annual stock market data for the most important equity markets of the last four centuries: the Netherlands and UK (1629-1812), UK (1813-1870), and US (1871-2015). We show that dividend yields are stationary and consistently forecast returns. The documented predictability holds for annual and multi-annual horizons and works both in- and out-of-sample, providing strong evidence that expected returns in stock markets are time varying. In part, this variation is related to the business cycle, with expected returns increasing in recessions. We also find that, except for the period after 1945, dividend yields predict dividend growth rates. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Golez, Benjamin; Koudijs, Peter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee representation and financial leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chen; Schmid, Thomas; Xuan, Yuhai
We analyze how direct employee voice affects financial leverage. German law mandates that firms' supervisory boards consist of an equal number of employees' and owners' representatives. This requirement, however, applies only to firms with more than two thousand domestic employees. We exploit this discontinuity and the law's introduction in 1976 for identification and find that direct employee power increases financial leverage. This is explained by a supply side effect: as banks' interests are similar to those of employees, higher employee power reduces agency conflicts with debt providers, leading to better financing conditions. These findings reveal a novel mechanism of direct employee influence. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Chen; Schmid, Thomas; Xuan, Yuhai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The consequences of managerial indiscretions: Sex, lies, and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cline, Brandon N.; Walkling, Ralph A.; Yore, Adam S.
Personal managerial indiscretions are separate from a firm's business activities but provide information about the manager's integrity. Consequently, they could affect counter parties' trust in the firm and the firm's value and operations. We find that companies of accused executives experience significant wealth deterioration, reduced operating margins, and lost business partners. Indiscretions are also associated with an increased probability of unrelated shareholder-initiated lawsuits, Department of Justice and Securities and Exchange Commission investigations, and managed earnings. Further, chief executive officers and boards face labor market consequences, including forced turnover, pay cuts, and lower shareholder votes at re-election. Indiscretions occur more often at poorly governed firms where disciplinary turnover is less likely. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cline, Brandon N.; Walkling, Ralph A.; Yore, Adam S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Patent collateral, investor commitment, and the market for venture lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hochberg, Yael V.; Serrano, Carlos J.; Ziedonis, Rosemarie H.
We explore the market for lending to start-ups and two mechanisms that facilitate trade within it: (1) the salability of patent collateral and (2) the credible commitment of equity investors. Intensified trading in the secondary patent market is strongly related to lending, particularly for start-ups with more redeployable patent assets. Utilizing the crash of 2000 as a severe and unexpected capital supply shock for venture capitalists, we further show that lenders continue to finance start-ups with recently funded investors better able to credibly commit to refinance their portfolio companies while withdrawing from otherwise promising projects that could have needed their funds the most. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hochberg, Yael V.; Serrano, Carlos J.; Ziedonis, Rosemarie H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In search of ideas: Technological innovation and executive pay inequality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frydman, Carola; Papanikolaou, Dimitris
We develop a general equilibrium model that delivers realistic fluctuations in pay inequality as a result of changes in the technology frontier. In our model, executives add value to the firm not only by participating in production decisions, as do other workers in the economy, but also by identifying new investment opportunities. Improvements in technology that are specific to new vintages of capital raise the return to managers' skills for discovering new growth projects and, thus, increase the compensation of executives relative to workers and disparities in pay across executives. Our model implies that, controlling for firm size, compensation is higher in fast-growing firms and that pay inequality increases as investment opportunities in the economy improve. Both predictions are consistent with the data. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frydman, Carola; Papanikolaou, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor rights and innovation: Evidence from patent collateral</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mann, William
I show that patents are pledged as collateral to raise significant debt financing, and that the pledgeability of patents contributes to the financing of innovation. In 2013, 38% of US patenting firms had previously pledged patents as collateral, and these firms performed 20% of research and development expense and patenting in Compustat. Employing court decisions as a source of exogenous variation in creditor rights, I show that patenting companies raised more debt, and spent more on R&amp;D, when creditor rights to patents strengthened. Subsequently, these companies exhibited a gradual increase in patenting output and the use of patents as collateral. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mann, William</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flexible prices and leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Acunto, Francesco; Liu, Ryan; Pflueger, Carolin; Weber, Michael
The frequency with which firms adjust output prices helps explain persistent differences in capital structure across firms. Unconditionally, the most flexible-price firms have a 19% higher long-term leverage ratio than the most sticky-price firms, controlling for known determinants of capital structure. Sticky-price firms increased leverage more than flexible price firms following the staggered implementation of bank deregulation across states and over time, which we use in a difference-in-differences strategy. Firms' frequency of price adjustment did not change around the deregulation. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>D'Acunto, Francesco; Liu, Ryan; Pflueger, Carolin; Weber, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When saving is gambling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cookson, J. Anthony
Prize-linked savings (PLS) accounts, which allocate interest using lottery payments rather than fixed interest, encourage savings by appealing to households' gambling preferences. I introduce new data on casino cash withdrawals to measure gambling, and examine how individual gambling expenditures respond to the introduction of PLS in Nebraska using a difference-in-differences design. After PLS is introduced, individuals who live in counties that offer PLS reduce gambling by at least 3% more than unaffected individuals. The substitution effect is stronger in low-frills gambling environments, which most resemble PLS, indicating that these accounts fulfill the desire to gamble. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cookson, J. Anthony</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term structures of asset prices and returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Backus, David; Boyarchenko, Nina; Chernov, Mikhail
We explore the term structures of claims to a variety of cash flows, namely, US government bonds (claims to dollars), foreign government bonds (claims to foreign currency), inflation-adjusted bonds (claims to the price index), and equity (claims to future equity indexes or dividends). The average term structures reflect the dynamics of the dollar pricing kernel, cash flow growth, and the interaction between the two. We use an affine model to illustrate how these two components can deliver term structures with a wide range of levels and shapes. Finally, we calibrate a representative agent economy to show that the evidence is consistent with the equilibrium models. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Backus, David; Boyarchenko, Nina; Chernov, Mikhail</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does hedge fund activism reshape corporate innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, Alon; Jiang, Wei; Ma, Song; Tian, Xuan
This paper studies how hedge fund activism impacts corporate innovation. Firms targeted by activists improve their innovation efficiency over the five-year period following hedge fund intervention. Despite a tightening in research and development (R&amp;D) expenditures, target firms increase innovation output, as measured by both patent counts and citations, with stronger effects among firms with more diversified innovation portfolios. Reallocation of innovative resources, redeployment of human capital, and change to board-level expertise all contribute to improve target firms' innovation. Additional tests help isolate the effect of intervention from alternative explanations, including mean reversion, sample attrition, voluntary reforms, or activist stock-picking. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brav, Alon; Jiang, Wei; Ma, Song; Tian, Xuan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inefficiencies and externalities from opportunistic acquirers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Di; Taylor, Lucian A.; Wang, Wenyu
If opportunistic acquirers can buy targets using overvalued shares, then there is an inefficiency in the merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) market: the most overvalued rather than the highest-synergy bidder may buy the target. We quantify this inefficiency using a structural estimation approach. We find that the M&amp;A market allocates resources efficiently on average. Opportunistic bidders crowd out high-synergy bidders in only 7% of transactions, resulting in an average synergy loss equal to 9% of the target's value in these inefficient deals. The implied average loss across all deals is 0.63%. Although the inefficiency is small on average, it is large for certain deals, and it is larger when misvaluation is more likely. Even when opportunistic bidders lose the contest, they drive up prices, imposing a large negative externality on the winning synergistic bidders. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Di; Taylor, Lucian A.; Wang, Wenyu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does improved information improve incentives?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaigneau, Pierre; Edmans, Alex; Gottlieb, Daniel
This paper studies the value of more precise signals on agent performance in an optimal contracting model with endogenous effort. With limited liability, the agent's wage is increasing in output only if output exceeds a threshold, else it is zero regardless of output. If the threshold is sufficiently high, the agent only beats it, and is rewarded for increasing output through greater effort, if there is a high noise realization. Thus, a fall in output volatility reduces effort incentives information and effort are substitutes offsetting the standard effect that improved information lowers the cost of compensation. We derive conditions relating the incentive effect to the underlying parameters of the agency problem. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chaigneau, Pierre; Edmans, Alex; Gottlieb, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance of banks and financial stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anginer, Deniz; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Huizinga, Harry; Ma, Kebin
We find that shareholder-friendly corporate governance is associated with higher standalone and systemic risk in the banking sector. Specifically, shareholder-friendly corporate governance results in higher risk for larger banks and for banks that are located in countries with generous financial safety nets as banks try to shift risk toward taxpayers. We confirm our findings by comparing banks to nonfinancial firms and examining changes in bank risk around an exogenous regulatory change in governance. Our results underline the importance of the financial safety net and too-big-to-fail guarantees in thinking about corporate governance reforms at banks. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Anginer, Deniz; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Huizinga, Harry; Ma, Kebin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Data abundance and asset price informativeness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dugast, Jerome; Foucault, Thierry
Information processing filters out the noise in data but it takes time. Hence, low precision signals are available before high precision signals. We analyze how this feature affects asset price informativeness when investors can acquire signals of increasing precision over time about the payoff of an asset. As the cost of low precision signals declines, prices are more likely to reflect these signals before more precise signals become available. This effect can ultimately reduce price informativeness because it reduces the demand for more precise signals (e.g., fundamental analysis). We make additional predictions for trade and price patterns. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dugast, Jerome; Foucault, Thierry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are CEOs born leaders? Lessons from traits of a million individuals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Renee; Keloharju, Matti; Knupfer, Samuli
What makes a successful CEO? We combine a near-exhaustive sample of male CEOs from Swedish companies with data on their cognitive and noncognitive ability and height at age 18. CEOs differ from other high-skill professions most in noncognitive ability. The median large-company CEO belongs to the top 5% of the population in the combination of the three traits. The traits have a monotonic and close to linear relation with CEO pay, but their correlations with pay, firm size, and CEO fixed effects in firm policies are relatively low. Traits appear necessary but not sufficient for making it to the top. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, Renee; Keloharju, Matti; Knupfer, Samuli</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Director skill sets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Renee B.; Akyol, Ali C.; Verwijmeren, Patrick
Directors are not one-dimensional. We characterize their skill sets by exploiting Regulation S-K's 2009 requirement that U.S. firms must disclose the experience, qualifications, attributes, or skills that led the nominating committee to choose an individual as a director. We then examine how skills cluster on and across boards. Factor analysis indicates that the main dimension along which boards vary is in the diversity of skills of their directors. We find that firm performance increases when director skill sets exhibit more commonality. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, Renee B.; Akyol, Ali C.; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing investment spikes in the years surrounding World War I</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bargeron, Leonce; Denis, David; Lehn, Kenneth
In the period surrounding World War I, US firms sharply increased investment in fixed assets and working capital to accommodate large increases in demand associated with the war. Concurrently, the US adopted an excess profits tax, which created a tax bias in favor of equity financing. Despite this tax bias, firms in need of external funds largely issued debt, not equity, to finance investment spikes when the excess profits tax was in effect. Further, we find these firms systematically reduced debt after the war, whereas other firms did not. The results support models that link the dynamics of firms' financing decisions with the dynamics of their investment opportunities and are inconsistent with models that emphasize taxes as a primary determinant of financing decisions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bargeron, Leonce; Denis, David; Lehn, Kenneth</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The execution quality of corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O' Hara, Maureen; Wang, Yihui; Zhou, Xing
This paper investigates execution quality issues in corporate bond trading. Using an extensive sample of bond trades by insurance companies, we find that an insurance company entering a trade of similar size and on the same side for the same bond on the same day with the same dealer will receive a better price if the insurance company is a more active trader than if it is a less active trader. Trading with the dominant dealer or underwriter worsens these differentials, while greater transparency and smaller trading networks lessens these effects. Our results provide strong evidence that execution quality differences remain pervasive in corporate bond trading. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>O' Hara, Maureen; Wang, Yihui; Zhou, Xing</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulating dark trading: Order flow segmentation and market quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Malinova, Katya; Park, Andreas
We examine the impact of a rule in the Canadian equities market that requires dark orders to offer price improvement over displayed orders. We show that this rule eliminated intermediation of retail orders in the dark and shifted retail orders onto the lit market with the lowest trading fee. Intermediaries shifted liquidity supply to this market leading to increased displayed liquidity. We conclude that reducing retail order segmentation enhances lit liquidity. Despite the improvement in liquidity, retail traders receive less price improvement. Retail brokers pay higher trading fees to exchanges, and high-frequency traders earn higher revenues from trading fees. Crown Copyright (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Malinova, Katya; Park, Andreas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do elections delay regulatory action?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leverty, J. Tyler; Grace, Martin F.
This paper investigates whether elections delay regulatory action against failing financial institutions by exploiting the cross-sectional and time-series heterogeneity in the exogenous electoral cycles of US insurance regulators and governors. We find causal evidence that regulators delay interventions before elections. The extent of the delay is larger for elected regulators than regulators appointed by the governor. Interventions by appointed regulators are less likely before competitive gubernatorial elections. Regulatory governance mechanisms that constrain the discretion of regulators reduce the delays of appointed regulators but not elected. Finally, we find evidence that suggests electoral delays increase the ultimate costs of failure. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leverty, J. Tyler; Grace, Martin F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Company stock price reactions to the 2016 election shock: Trump, taxes, and trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wagner, Alexander F.; Zeckhauser, Richard J.; Ziegler, Alexandre
Donald Trump's surprise election shifted expectations: corporate taxes would be lower and trade policies more restrictive. Relative stock prices responded appropriately. High-tax firms and those with large deferred tax liabilities (DTLs) gained: those with significant deferred tax assets from net operating loss carryforwards (NOL DTAs) lost. Domestically focused companies fared better than internationally oriented firms. A price contribution analysis shows that easily assessed consequences (DTLs, NOL DTA5, tax rates) were priced faster than more complex issues (net DTLs, foreign exposure). In sum, the analysis demonstrates that expectations about tax rates greatly impact firm values. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wagner, Alexander F.; Zeckhauser, Richard J.; Ziegler, Alexandre</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downside risks and the cross-section of asset returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farago, Adam; Tedongap, Romeo
In an intertemporal equilibrium asset pricing model featuring disappointment aversion and changing macroeconomic uncertainty, we show that besides the market return and market volatility, three disappointment-related factors are also priced: a downstate factor, a market downside factor, and a volatility downside factor. We find that expected returns on various asset classes reflect premiums for bearing undesirable exposures to these factors. The signs of estimated risk premiums are consistent with the theoretical predictions. Our most general, five-factor model is very successful in jointly pricing stock, option, and currency portfolios, and provides considerable improvement over nested specifications previously discussed in the literature. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Farago, Adam; Tedongap, Romeo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of mortgage securitization on foreclosure and modification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kruger, Samuel
Did securitization exacerbate the foreclosure crisis by altering mortgage servicing practices? I exploit the unanticipated freeze of private mortgage securitization in 2007 to provide new evidence that securitization increases foreclosure probability and decreases modification probability. These effects are economically large and persist over time even after implementation of the Home Affordable Modification Program (HAMP) in 2009. Using hand-collected data on the contractual terms of servicing agreements, I show that servicers typically have broad discretion to modify loans but face significant incentives favoring foreclosure. The evidence implies that securitization significantly increased foreclosure rates during and after the crisis. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kruger, Samuel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private equity portfolio company fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phalippou, Ludovic; Rauch, Christian; Umber, Marc
In private equity, general partners (GPs) receive fee payments from companies whose boards they control. Fees amount to $20 billion evenly distributed over time, representing over 6% of equity invested by GPs. They do not vary with business cycles, company characteristics, or GP performance. Fees vary significantly across GPs and are persistent within GPs, even after accounting for fee rebates to limited partners (LPs). GPs charging the least raise more capital postfinancial crisis and are backed by more skilled LPs. GPs increase fees prior to going public. We discuss how these results could be explained by optimal contracting and tax arbitrage. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Phalippou, Ludovic; Rauch, Christian; Umber, Marc</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size matters, if you control your junk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asness, Clifford; Frazzini, Andrea; Israel, Ronen; Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Pedersen, Lasse H.
The size premium has been accused of having a weak historical record, being meager relative to other factors, varying significantly over time, weakening after its discovery, being concentrated among microcap stocks, residing predominantly in January, relying on price based measures, and being weak internationally. We find, however, that these challenges disappear when controlling for the quality, or its inverse, junk, of a firm. A significant size premium emerges, which is stable through time, robust to specification, not concentrated in microcaps, more consistent across seasons, and evident for non-price-based measures of size, and these results hold in 30 different industries and 24 international equity markets. The resurrected size effect is on par with anomalies such as value and momentum in terms of economic significance and gives rise to new tests of, and challenges for, existing asset pricing theories. (C) 2018 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Asness, Clifford; Frazzini, Andrea; Israel, Ronen; Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Pedersen, Lasse H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stocks with extreme past returns: Lotteries or insurance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barinov, Alexander
The paper shows that lottery-like stocks are hedges against unexpected increases in market volatility. The loading on the aggregate volatility risk factor explains the majority of low abnormal returns to stocks with high maximum returns in the past month (Bali et al., 2011) and high expected skewness (Boyer et al., 2010). Aggregate volatility risk also explains the new evidence that the maximum effect and the skewness effect are stronger for firms with high market to book or high expected probability of bankruptcy. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barinov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do stocks outperform Treasury bills?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, Hendrik
The majority of common stocks that have appeared in the Center for Research in Security Prices (CRSP) database since 1926 have lifetime buy-and-hold returns less than one-month Treasuries. When stated in terms of lifetime dollar wealth creation, the best-performing 4% of listed companies explain the net gain for the entire US stock market since 1926, as other stocks collectively matched Treasury bills. These results highlight the important role of positive skewness in the distribution of individual stock returns, attributable to skewness in monthly returns and to the effects of compounding. The results help to explain why poorly diversified active strategies most often underperform market averages. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bessembinder, Hendrik</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity issuances and agency costs: The telling story of shareholder approval around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holderness, Clifford G.
Mandatory shareholder approval of equity issuances varies across and within countries. When shareholders approve issuances, average announcement returns are positive. When managers issue stock without shareholder approval, returns are negative and 4% lower. The closer the vote is to the issuance or the greater is the required plurality, the higher are the returns for public offers, rights offers, and private placements. When shareholder approval is required, rights offers predominate. When managers may issue stock without shareholder approval, public offers predominate. These findings suggest that agency problems affect equity issuances and challenge existing adverse selection, market timing, and signaling explanations. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Holderness, Clifford G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Day of the week and the cross-section of returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Birru, Justin
Long-short anomaly returns are strongly related to the day of the week. Anomalies for which the speculative leg is the short (long) leg experience the highest (lowest) returns on Monday. The opposite pattern is observed on Friday. The effects are large. Monday (Friday) alone accounts for over 100% of returns for all anomalies examined for which the short (long) leg is the speculative leg. Consistent with a mispricing explanation, the pattern is driven by the speculative leg. The observed patterns are consistent with the abundance of evidence in the psychology literature that mood increases on Friday and decreases on Monday. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Birru, Justin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing stigma during a financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anbil, Sriya
How should regulators design effective emergency lending facilities to mitigate stigma during a financial crisis? I explore this question using data from an unexpected disclosure of partial lists of banks that secretly borrowed from the lender of last resort during the Great Depression. I find evidence of stigma in that depositors withdrew more deposits from banks included on the lists in comparison with banks left off the lists. Overall, the results suggest that an emergency lending facility that never reveals bank identities would mitigate stigma. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Anbil, Sriya</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do an insider's wealth and income matter in the decision to engage in insider trading?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kallunki, Jenni; Kallunki, Juha-Pekka; Nilsson, Henrik; Puhakka, Mikko
We explore why insiders engage in informed trading, given the surprisingly small average insider returns reported in the literature and the potential costs involved. We begin by proposing a model of an insider's decision to engage in insider trading. We then empirically test the model's predictions using archival data of corporate insiders in Sweden. Consistent with the model, we find that less wealthy insiders are more likely to time their insider selling, and to sell in greater magnitudes, prior to abnormal price declines than wealthy insiders. We also find that less wealthy insiders with lower risk aversion as measured by their criminal behavior are particularly prone to timing their selling to avoid price declines. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kallunki, Jenni; Kallunki, Juha-Pekka; Nilsson, Henrik; Puhakka, Mikko</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informative fund size, managerial skill, and investor rationality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Min
This paper considers the nature of returns to scale in active management following Pastor et al. (2015) who fail to establish diseconomies of scale at the fund level. Using an enhanced empirical strategy, we find a significant negative impact of fund size on performance. This empirical evidence indicates that fund alpha and fund size are not independent entities. Consequently, skill, rather than being measured by the fund alpha, should be measured by the value that a fund extracts from capital markets. We also show that there exist sophisticated investors who correctly exploit positive net present value investment opportunities. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhu, Min</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Volcker Rule and corporate bond market making in times of stress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bao, Jack; O'Hara, Maureen; Zhou, Xing
Focusing on downgrades as stress events that drive the selling of corporate bonds, we show that the illiquidity of stressed bonds has increased after the Volcker Rule. Dealers regulated by the rule have curtailed their market-making activities and non-Volcker-affected dealers have not offset the decreased activities of Volcker-affected dealers. Furthermore, even Volcker-affected dealers that are not constrained by Basel Ill and Comprehensive Capital Analysis and Review regulations change their behavior, inconsistent with the effects being driven by these other regulations. Because Volcker-affected dealers have been the main liquidity providers, bonds have become less liquid during times of stress due to the Volcker Rule. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bao, Jack; O'Hara, Maureen; Zhou, Xing</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Micro(structure) before macro? The predictive power of aggregate illiquidity for stock returns and economic activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yong; Eaton, Gregory W.; Paye, Bradley S.
This paper constructs and analyzes various measures of trading costs in US equity markets covering the period 1926-2015. These measures contain statistically and economically significant predictive signals for stock market returns and real economic activity. We decompose illiquidity proxies into a component capturing aggregate volatility and a residual. The predictive content of these components differs in important ways. Specifically, we find strong evidence that the component of illiquidity uncorrelated with volatility forecasts stock market returns. Both the volatility and residual components of illiquidity contain information regarding future economic activity. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Yong; Eaton, Gregory W.; Paye, Bradley S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does policy uncertainty affect mergers and acquisitions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonaime, Alice; Gulen, Huseyin; Ion, Mihai
Political and regulatory uncertainty is strongly negatively associated with merger and acquisition activity at the macro and firm levels. The strongest effects are for uncertainty regarding taxes, government spending, monetary and fiscal policies, and regulation. Consistent with a real options channel, the effect is exacerbated for less reversible deals and for firms whose product demand or stock returns exhibit greater sensitivity to policy uncertainty, but attenuated for deals that cannot be delayed due to competition and for deals that hedge firm-level risk. Contractual mechanisms (deal premiums, termination fees, MAC clauses) unanimously point to policy uncertainty increasing the target's negotiating power. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bonaime, Alice; Gulen, Huseyin; Ion, Mihai</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing as a supply chain: The capital structure of banks and borrowers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gornall, Will; Strebulaev, Ilya A.
We develop a model of the joint capital structure decisions of banks and their borrowers. Bank leverage of 85% or higher emerges because bank seniority both dramatically reduces bank asset volatility and incentivizes risk-taking by producing a skewed return distribution. Nonfinancial firms choose low leverage to protect their banks, presenting a partial resolution to the low-leverage puzzle. Our setup naturally extends to include government actions as we model bank assets using a modified Basel framework. Deposit insurance and bailout expectations lead banks and borrowers to take on more risk. Capital regulation lowers bank leverage but can increase bank risk due to a compensating increase in borrower leverage. Despite this, doubling current capital requirements reduces bank default risk by up to 90%, with only a small increase in loan interest rates. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gornall, Will; Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cyclical investment behavior across financial institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Timmer, Yannick
This paper contrasts the investment behavior of different financial institutions in debt securities as a response to past returns. For identification, I use unique security-level data from the German Microdatabase Securities Holdings Statistics. Banks and investment funds respond in a procyclical manner to past security-specific holding period returns. In contrast, insurance companies and pension funds act countercyclically; they buy when returns have been negative and sell after high returns. The heterogeneous responses can be explained by differences in their balance sheet structure. I exploit within-sector variation in the financial constraint to show that tighter constraints are associated with relatively more procyclical investment behavior. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Timmer, Yannick</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Warehouse banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donaldson, Jason Roderick; Piacentino, Giorgia; Thakor, Anjan
We develop a theory of banking that explains why banks started out as commodities warehouses. We show that warehouses become banks because their superior storage technology allows them to enforce the repayment of loans most effectively. Further, interbank markets emerge endogenously to support this enforcement mechanism. Even though warehouses store deposits of real goods, they make loans by writing new fake warehouse receipts, rather than by taking deposits out of storage. Our theory helps to explain how modern banks create funding liquidity and why they combine warehousing (custody and deposit-taking), lending, and private money creation within the same institutions. It also casts light on a number of contemporary regulatory policies. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Donaldson, Jason Roderick; Piacentino, Giorgia; Thakor, Anjan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spillovers from good-news and other bankruptcies: Real effects and price responses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baranchuk, Nina; Rebello, Michael J.
We model debt restructurings that could endogenously end in bankruptcy, and study spillovers to competitors' operating decisions, profits, restructuring outcomes and security prices. We show that while bankruptcy could cause the firm's share price to drop, bankruptcy always signals good news about the firm. We identify the conditions under which a bankruptcy also signals good news about competitors. We demonstrate that when a firm's bankruptcy costs are relatively small, bankruptcy raises its share price while lowering the prices of competitors' shares and debt as well as boosting the probability that they will enter bankruptcy. When there is little information asymmetry about the firm's prospects, or the information asymmetry is about industry prospects, bankruptcy raises competitors' share and debt prices and lowers their probability of bankruptcy. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baranchuk, Nina; Rebello, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extrapolation and bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barberis, Nicholas; Greenwood, Robin; Jin, Lawrence; Shleifer, Andrei
We present an extrapolative model of bubbles. In the model, many investors form their demand for a risky asset by weighing two signals-an average of the asset's past price changes and the asset's degree of overvaluation-and "waver" over time in the relative weight they put on them. The model predicts that good news about fundamentals can trigger large price bubbles, that bubbles will be accompanied by high trading volume, and that volume increases with past asset returns. We present empirical evidence that bears on some of the model's distinctive predictions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barberis, Nicholas; Greenwood, Robin; Jin, Lawrence; Shleifer, Andrei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial intermediation in private equity: How well do funds of funds perform?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, Robert S.; Jenkinson, Tim; Kaplan, Steven N.; Stucke, Ruediger
This paper focuses on funds of funds (FOFs) as a form of financial intermediation in private equity (both buyout and venture capital). After accounting for fees, FOFs provide returns equal to or above public market indices for both buyout and venture capital. While FOFs focusing on buyouts outperform public markets, they underperform direct fund investment strategies in buyout. In contrast, the average performance of FOFs in venture capital is on a par with results from direct venture fund investing. This suggests that FOFs in venture capital (but not in buyouts) are able to identify and access superior performing funds. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harris, Robert S.; Jenkinson, Tim; Kaplan, Steven N.; Stucke, Ruediger</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital gains taxation and the cost of capital: Evidence from unanticipated cross-border transfers of tax base</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huizinga, Harry; Voget, Johannes; Wagner, Wolf
In a cross-border takeover, the tax base associated with future capital gains is transferred from target shareholders to acquirer shareholders. Cross-country differences in capital gains tax rates enable us to estimate the discount in target valuation on account of future capital gains. We estimate that a 1 percentage point increase in the capital gains tax rate reduces the value of equity by around 0.3%, which suggests that the capital gains tax significantly raises firms' cost of capital. Furthermore, we find that the implied capital gains tax burden is higher at times of high economic growth and low stock market valuation. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huizinga, Harry; Voget, Johannes; Wagner, Wolf</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What makes the bonding stick? A natural experiment testing the legal bonding hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Licht, Amir N.; Poliquin, Christopher; Siegel, Jordan I.; Li, Xi
We use a US Supreme Court case, Morrison v. National Australia Bank (2010), as a natural experiment to test the legal bonding hypothesis. By decreasing the potential liability of US-listed foreign firms, particularly due to class action lawsuits, Morrison arguably eroded their legal bonding to compliance with disclosure duties. Nevertheless, we find evidence of an increase or insignificant change in share values. Tests of longer-run effects of the legal event indicate that foreign firms' disclosure quality and likelihood of facing enforcement actions remained stable, as did investors' revealed preferences for trading on US markets. These results go against the legal bonding hypothesis but are consistent with reputational bonding and with market-based accounts of US cross-listing. Our results may contribute to ongoing debate about civil enforcement of securities laws through class actions. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Licht, Amir N.; Poliquin, Christopher; Siegel, Jordan I.; Li, Xi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploring the sources of default clustering</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Azizpour, S.; Giesecke, K.; Schwenkler, G.
We study the sources of corporate default clustering in the United States. We reject the hypothesis that firms' default times are correlated only because their conditional default rates depend on observable and latent systematic factors. By contrast, we find strong evidence that contagion, through which the default by one firm has a direct impact on the health of other firms, is a significant clustering source. The amount of clustering that cannot be explained by contagion and firms' exposure to observable and latent systematic factors is insignificant. Our results have important implications for the pricing and management of correlated default risk. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Azizpour, S.; Giesecke, K.; Schwenkler, G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-myopic betas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malamud, Semyon; Vilkov, Grigory
An overlapping generations model with investors having heterogeneous investment horizons leads to a two-factor asset pricing model. The risk premiums are determined by the exposure to the market (myopic betas) and the future return on the efficient portfolio (non-myopic betas), which is identified nonparametrically from equilibrium. Non-myopic betas are priced in the cross-section of stocks, producing increasing and economically significant risk-return relation. In the model with funding constraints, low non-myopic beta stocks deliver higher risk-adjusted returns. Empirically, a betting against non-myopic beta portfolio generates superior performance relative to common factor models and is negatively correlated with the market betting against beta portfolio. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malamud, Semyon; Vilkov, Grigory</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does the stock market absorb shocks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frank, Murray Z.; Sanati, Ali
Using a comprehensive set of news stories, we find a stark difference in market responses to positive and negative price shocks accompanied by new information. When there is a news story about a firm, positive price shocks are followed by reversal, while negative ones result in drift. This is interpreted as the stock market overreaction to good news and underreaction to bad news. These seemingly contradictory results can be explained in a single framework, considering the interaction of retail investors with attention bias, and arbitrageurs with short-run capital constraints. Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that both patterns are stronger when the attention bias is stronger, and when the arbitrage capital is scarce. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Frank, Murray Z.; Sanati, Ali</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Human capital relatedness and mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Kyeong Hun; Mauer, David C.; Xu, Emma Qianying
We construct a measure of the pairwise relatedness of firms' human capital to examine whether human capital relatedness is a key factor in mergers and acquisitions. We find that mergers are more likely and merger returns and postmerger performance are higher when firms have related human capital. These relations are stronger or only present in acquisitions where the merging firms do not operate in the same industries or product markets. Reductions in employment and wages following mergers with high human capital relatedness suggest that the merged firm has greater ability to layoff low quality and/or duplicate employees and reduce labor costs. We further show in a falsification test that human capital relatedness has no effect on acquiring firm returns in asset sales when little or no labor is transferred, which helps validate our measure of human capital relatedness. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Kyeong Hun; Mauer, David C.; Xu, Emma Qianying</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market intraday momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Lei; Han, Yufeng; Li, Sophia Zhengzi; Zhou, Guofu
Based on high frequency S &amp; P 500 exchange-traded fund (ETF) data from 1993-2013, we show an intraday momentum pattern: the first half-hour return on the market as measured from the previous day's market close predicts the last half-hour return. This predictability, which is both statistically and economically significant, is stronger on more volatile days, on higher volume days, on recession days, and on major macroeconomic news release days. Intraday momentum also exists for ten other most actively traded domestic and international ETFs. Theoretically, the intraday momentum is consistent not only with Bogousslaysky's (2016) model of infrequent portfolio rebalancing but also with a model of late-informed trading near the market close. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gao, Lei; Han, Yufeng; Li, Sophia Zhengzi; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax distortions and bond issue pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Landoni, Mattia
Original issue premium (OIP) bonds are the norm in the US tax-exempt market but very rare in the taxable market. A tax subsidy helps explain this disparity. Unlike bonds issued at par or discount, the price of OIP bonds can fall and yet remain above par, providing secondary market buyers with more tax-exempt coupon and less taxable market discount gain. The subsidy for OIP bonds explains additional, previously undocumented empirical facts. In a calibration exercise, the subsidy's expected cost to the U.S. Treasury is estimated at $1.7 billion per year. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Landoni, Mattia</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The 52-week high, q-theory, and the cross section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>George, Thomas J.; Hwang, Chuan-Yang; Li, Yuan
The Hou et al. (2015) q-factor model outperforms other factor models in capturing the price-to-high (PTH, the ratio of current price to 52-week high price) anomaly; that is, high-PTH stocks earn high future returns. PTH's relations with future profitability and future investment growth are both significantly positive, and they mirror PTH's relation with future returns in the cross section and by time horizons. Incorporating the information about future investment growth contained in price level variables (e.g., PTH) helps the q factors to capture better those anomalies rooted in future investment growth. Together, these results suggest that the PTH anomaly is consistent with the investment capital asset pricing model. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>George, Thomas J.; Hwang, Chuan-Yang; Li, Yuan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can financial innovation succeed by catering to behavioral preferences? Evidence from a callable options market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xindan; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Yang, Xuewei
We examine the notion that financial products which cater to investors' behavioral biases can yield high trading activity and thus be profitable for issuers. Our setting considers options with a callback feature, namely, callable bull/bear contracts (CBBCs). Such contracts have high skewness when close to callback and thus appeal to cumulative prospect theory preferences. CBBCs with high skewness earn negative average returns, and issuers' gross profits vary positively with CBBC skewness. Over the 2009-2014 period, issuers earn gross profits of about $1.67 billion by trading CBBCs on the Hang Seng Index. These findings highlight the role of behavioral finance in financial innovation. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Xindan; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Yang, Xuewei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An intertemporal CAPM with stochastic volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John Y.; Giglio, Stefano; Polk, Christopher; Turley, Robert
This paper studies the pricing of volatility risk using the first-order conditions of a longterm equity investor who is content to hold the aggregate equity market instead of over weighting value stocks and other equity portfolios that are attractive to short-term investors. We show that a conservative long-term investor will avoid such overweights to hedge against two types of deterioration in investment opportunities: declining expected stock returns and increasing volatility. We present novel evidence that low-frequency movements in equity volatility, tied to the default spread, are priced in the cross section of stock returns. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campbell, John Y.; Giglio, Stefano; Polk, Christopher; Turley, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of q and cash flow on investment in the presence of measurement error</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abel, Andrew B.
I analyze investment, q, and cash flow in a tractable stochastic model in which marginal q and average q are identically equal. I introduce classical measurement error and derive closed -form expressions for the coefficients in regressions of investment on q and cash flow. The cash -flow coefficient is positive and larger for faster growing firms, yet there are no financial frictions in the model. I develop the concepts of bivariate attenuation and weight shifting to interpret the estimated coefficients on q and cash flow in the presence of measurement error. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abel, Andrew B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate volatility, the yield curve, and the macroeconomy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joslin, Scott; Konchitchki, Yaniv
This paper provides theory and evidence that a low-dimensional term structure model can simultaneously price bonds and related options. It shows that a component of volatility risk largely unrelated to the shape of the yield curve is a determinant of expected excess returns for holding long maturity bonds. It also finds evidence for this return relationship both in the model and directly in the data through regression analysis. The paper also identifies a link between corporate earnings performance and interest rate volatility, providing a channel driving interest rate volatility. The structure of risk in the model that gives rise to these features of volatility is distinct from that inherent in recent models with unspanned stochastic volatility. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Joslin, Scott; Konchitchki, Yaniv</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash windfalls and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Beschwitz, Bastian
This article studies the effect of cash windfalls on the acquisition policy of companies. As identification, I use a German tax reform that permitted firms to sell their equity stakes tax free. Companies that could realize a cash windfall by selling equity stakes see an increase in the probability of acquiring another company by 14%. I find that these additional acquisitions destroy firm value. Following the tax reform, affected firms experience a decrease of 1.2 percentage points in acquisition announcement returns. These effects are stronger for larger cash windfalls. My findings are consistent with the free cash flow theory. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>von Beschwitz, Bastian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Protection of trade secrets and capital structure decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klasa, Sandy; Ortiz-Molina, Hernan; Serfling, Matthew; Srinivasan, Shweta
Firms strategically choose more conservative capital structures when they face greater competitive threats stemming from the potential loss of their trade secrets to rivals. Following the recognition of the Inevitable Disclosure Doctrine by US state courts, which exogenously increases the protection of a firm's trade secrets by reducing the mobility of its workers who know its secrets to rivals, the firm increases its leverage relative to unaffected rivals. The effect is stronger for firms with a greater risk of losing key employees to rivals, for those facing financially stronger rivals, and for those in industries where competition is more intense. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Klasa, Sandy; Ortiz-Molina, Hernan; Serfling, Matthew; Srinivasan, Shweta</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High frequency trading and extreme price movements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brogaard, Jonathan; Carrion, Allen; Moyaert, Thibaut; Riordan, Ryan; Shkilko, Andriy; Sokolov, Konstantin
Are endogenous liquidity providers (ELPs) reliable in times of market stress? We examine the activity of a common ELP type high frequency traders (HFTs) around extreme price movements (EPMs). We find that on average HFTs provide liquidity during EPMs by absorbing imbalances created by non-high frequency traders (nHFTs). Yet HFT liquidity provision is limited to EPMs in single stocks. When several stocks experience simultaneous EPMs, HFT liquidity demand dominates their supply. There is little evidence of HFTs causing EPMs. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brogaard, Jonathan; Carrion, Allen; Moyaert, Thibaut; Riordan, Ryan; Shkilko, Andriy; Sokolov, Konstantin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choosing factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
Our goal is to develop insights about the maximum squared Sharpe ratio for model factors as a metric for ranking asset pricing models. We consider nested and non-nested models. The nested models are the capital asset pricing model, the three-factor model of Fama and French (1993), the five-factor extension in Fama and French (2015), and a six-factor model that adds a momentum factor. The non-nested models examine three issues about factor choice in the six-factor model: (1) cash profitability versus operating profitability as the variable used to construct profitability factors, (2) long-short spread factors versus excess return factors, and (3) factors that use small or big stocks versus factors that use both. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Playing favorites: Conflicts of interest in mutual fund management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Del Guercio, Diane; Genc, Egemen; Tran, Hai
We examine the performance of mutual funds whose managers simultaneously manage portfolios with performance-based incentive fees for three account types: mutual funds, hedge funds, and separate accounts. Importantly, our data set is free of selection bias because it is hand-collected from mandatory SEC filings. We find that only funds whose managers also manage hedge funds significantly underperform peer mutual funds. Moreover, underperformance begins only after fund managers begin to manage a hedge fund. We find that managerial incentives and opportunities for cross-subsidization explain variation in underperformance across funds, supporting the conflicts of interest hypothesis in the debate on "side-by-side management." (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Del Guercio, Diane; Genc, Egemen; Tran, Hai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial myopia and the mortgage meltdown</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolasinski, Adam C.; Yang, Nan
Prominent policy makers assert that managerial short-termism was at the root of the sub-prime crisis of 2007-2009. Prior scholarly research, however, largely rejects this assertion. Using a more comprehensive measure of Chief Executive Officer (CEO) incentives for short-termism, we uncover evidence that short-termism indeed played a role. Firms whose CEOs were contractually allowed to sell or exercise more of their stock and options holdings sooner had more subprime exposure, a higher probability of financial distress, and lower risk-adjusted stock returns during the crisis, as well as higher fines and settlements for subprime-related fraud. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kolasinski, Adam C.; Yang, Nan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are stock-financed takeovers opportunistic?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckbo, B. Espen; Makaew, Tanakorn; Thorburn, Karin S.
The more the target knows about the bidder, the more difficult is paying the target with overpriced bidder shares. Thus, when bidders are opportunistic, the fraction of stock in the deal payment will be lower for better informed targets. We test this intuitive prediction against the alternative that stock payments primarily reflect bidder concerns with target adverse selection, which implies a greater fraction of stock in the deal payment for better informed targets. Discriminating between these two mutually exclusive and nested predictions requires measures of target information about the bidder but not of market mispricing. We find that public bidders systematically use more stock in the payment when the target knows more about the bidder. Tests exploiting exogenous variation in bidder market-to-book ratios also fail to support bidder opportunism. Finally, greater potential competition from private bidders is associated with greater propensity for public bidders to pay in cash. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eckbo, B. Espen; Makaew, Tanakorn; Thorburn, Karin S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time varying risk aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guiso, Luigi; Sapienza, Paola; Zingales, Luigi
Exploiting portfolio data and repeated surveys of an Italian bank's clients, we test whether investors' risk aversion increases following the 2008 crisis. We find that, after the crisis, both qualitative and quantitative measures of risk aversion increase substantially and that affected individuals divest more stock. We investigate four explanations: changes in wealth, expected income, perceived probabilities, and emotion-based changes of the utility function. Our data are inconsistent with the first two channels, while they suggest that fear is a potential mechanism underlying financial decisions, whether by increasing the curvature of the utility function or the salience of negative outcomes. (C) 2018 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Guiso, Luigi; Sapienza, Paola; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bid anticipation, information revelation, and merger gains</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Wenyu
Because firms' takeover motives are unobservable to investors, mergers are only partially anticipated and often appear as mixed blessings for acquirers. I construct and estimate a model to study the causes and consequences of bid anticipation and information revelation in mergers. Controlling for the market's reassessment of the acquirer's stand-alone value, I estimate that acquirers gain 4% from a typical merger. The total value of an active merger market averages 13% for acquirers, part of which is capitalized in their pre-merger market values. My model also explains the correlation between announcement returns and firm characteristics, as well as the low predictability of mergers. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Wenyu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO attributes, compensation, and firm value: Evidence from a structural estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Page, T. Beau
I present and estimate a dynamic model of chief executive officer (CEO) compensation and effort provision. I find that variation in CEO attributes explains the majority of variation in compensation (equity and total) but little of the variation in firm value. The primary drivers of cross-sectional compensation are risk aversion and influence on the board. Additionally, I estimate the magnitude of CEO agency issues. Removing CEO influence increases shareholder value in the typical firm by 1.74%, making CEOs risk neutral increases shareholder value by 16.12%, and removing all agency frictions increases shareholder value by 28.99%. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Page, T. Beau</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Management sub-advising in the mutual fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moreno, David; Rodriguez, Rosa; Zambrana, Rafael
This is a study of how contractual mechanisms can mitigate agency conflicts in sub advised mutual funds. Sub-advising contracts allow fund families to expand their product offerings to include new investment styles and thereby gain market share. We show that costly contractual arrangements, such as co-branding, multi-advising, and performance based compensation, can mitigate agency conflicts in outsourcing and protect investors from potential underperformance. Fund families will find it cost-effective to implement such incentive mechanisms only when investors are sophisticated in assessing manager skill. The findings help to explain why a large percentage of fund families outsource their funds to advisory firms. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moreno, David; Rodriguez, Rosa; Zambrana, Rafael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are overconfident CEOs better leaders? Evidence from stakeholder commitments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phua, Kenny; Tham, T. Mandy; Wei, Chishen
We find evidence that the leadership of overconfident chief executive officers (CEOs) induces stakeholders to take actions that contribute to the leader's vision. By being intentionally overexposed to the idiosyncratic risk of their firms, overconfident CEOs exhibit a strong belief in their firms' prospects. This belief attracts suppliers beyond the firm's observable expansionary corporate activities. Overconfident CEOs induce more supplier commitments including greater relationship-specific investment and longer relationship duration. Overconfident CEOs also induce stronger labor commitments as employees exhibit lower turnover rates and greater ownership of company stock in benefit plans. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Phua, Kenny; Tham, T. Mandy; Wei, Chishen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>