<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFE9</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Institutional trading and alternative trading systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, J.; Johnson, K. M.; Wahal, S.
We analyze the use of alternative trading systems in a large sample of institutional orders and the trades that constitute these orders. Proprietary data allow us to distinguish between orders and trades filled by day and after-hours crossing systems, electronic communication networks (ECNs), and traditional brokers. Controlling for variation in order and security characteristics, as well as endogeneity in the choice of trading venue, we find that realized execution costs are generally lower on alternative trading systems. Order handling rules and tick size changes implemented in 1997 appear to have reduced the cost advantage of trading on ECNs. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Conrad, J.; Johnson, K. M.; Wahal, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discounting and underpricing in seasoned equity offers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altinkilic, O.; Hansen, R. S.
Expected discounting in seasoned equity offers is a cost of uncertainty about firm value, marketing new shares, and acquiring information that raises the offer price. Stockholders incorporate predictable discounting in stock prices when equity offers are first announced. The surprise component of discounting, reflecting the lead bank's final adjustment to the offer price, releases information that often causes economically large price swings on the offer day. Disparities between the issuer's closing price and the price suggested in the lead bank's final order book are a primary source of information. The discount surprise appears to be used by lead banks to update capital suppliers with that eleventh-hour information before they commit their funds. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Altinkilic, O.; Hansen, R. S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do dealer firms manage inventory on a stock-by-stock or a portfolio basis?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Naik, N. Y.; Yadav, P. K.
This paper investigates whether dealer firms' trading and pricing decisions are governed by their equivalent inventories, based on Ho and Stoll (1983) or Froot and Stein (1998), or by their ordinary inventories. It finds that ordinary inventories best explain dealer firms' quote placement strategy, which dealer firm executes trades, and the quality of execution offered to the trades. This finding is consistent with decentralized nature of market-making where individual dealers focus on the position risk of stocks managed by them and not the position risks of stocks managed by other dealers in the firm. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Naik, N. Y.; Yadav, P. K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage risk and the book-to-market anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ali, A.; Hwang, L. S.; Trombley, M. A.
This paper shows that the book-to-market (B/M) effect is greater for stocks with higher idiosyncratic return volatility, higher transaction costs, and lower investor sophistication, consistent with the market-mispricing explanation for the anomaly. The B/M effect for high volatility stocks exceeds that for the low volatility stocks in 20 of the 22 sample years. Also, volatility exhibits significant incremental power beyond transaction costs and investor sophistication measures in explaining cross-sectional variation in the B/M effect. These findings are consistent with the Shleifer and Vishny (1997) thesis that risk associated with the volatility of arbitrage returns deters arbitrage activity and is an important reason why the B/M effect exists. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ali, A.; Hwang, L. S.; Trombley, M. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An examination of own account trading by dual traders in futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakravarty, S.; Li, K.
Using proprietary audit trail transaction data compiled by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, we investigate at the individual trader level (1) the timing and (2) the determinants of dual traders' personal trades. Our analysis reveals an absence of any trade timing by dual traders in relation to the execution of their customers' orders. Further examination employing correlation statistics and time series regressions provides strong support for the proposition that dual traders supply liquidity and actively manage inventory. Even after simultaneously controlling for factors representing information, liquidity supply, and inventory control, within a multivariate regression framework, liquidity supply and inventory control remain as the determinants of dual traders' personal trades. Overall, the emergent profile of a dual trader is that of an uninformed trader performing complimentary tasks. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chakravarty, S.; Li, K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market driven acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shleifer, A.; Vishny, R. W.
We present a model of mergers and acquisitions based on stock market misvaluations of the combining firms. The key ingredients of the model are the relative valuations of the merging firms and the market's perception of the synergies from the combination. The model explains who acquires whom, the choice of the medium of payment, the valuation consequences of mergers, and merger waves. The model is consistent with available empirical findings about characteristics and returns of merging firms, and yields new predictions as well. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shleifer, A.; Vishny, R. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Culture, openness, and finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stulz, R. M.; Williamson, R.
Differences in culture, proxied by differences in religion and language, cannot be ignored when examining why investor protection differs across countries. We show that a country's principal religion predicts the cross-sectional variation in creditor rights better than a country's natural openness to international trade, its language, its income per capita, or the origin of its legal system. Catholic countries protect the rights of creditors less well than Protestant countries. A country's natural openness to international trade mitigates the influence of religion on creditor rights. Culture proxies are also helpful in understanding how investor rights are enforced across countries. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stulz, R. M.; Williamson, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Boundaries of the firm: evidence from the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brickley, J. A.; Linck, J. S.; Smith, C. W.
Agency theory implies that asset ownership and decision authority are complements. Using 1998 data from Texas commercial banks, we test whether the likelihood of local ownership of bank offices increases with the importance of granting local managers greater decision authority (for example, due to location or customer base). Our empirical evidence is consistent with this hypothesis. It suggests that complementarities between strategy and organizational structure can foster differentiation among firms in terms of location, customers, and products. It also supports the growing view that small locally-owned banks have a comparative advantage over large banks within specific environments. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brickley, J. A.; Linck, J. S.; Smith, C. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quote-based competition and trade execution costs in NYSE-listed stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, H.
This study examines quotations, order routing, and trade execution costs for seven markets that compete for orders in large-capitalization NYSE-listed stocks. The competitiveness of quote updates from each market varies with measures of the profitability of attracting additional order and with volatility and inventory measures. The probability of a trade executing on each market increases when the market posts competitive quotes. Execution costs for non-NYSE trades when the local market posts competitive (non-competitive) quotes are virtually the same (substantially exceed) costs for matched NYSE trades. Collectively, these results imply a significant degree of quote-based competition for order flow and are consistent with off-NYSE liquidity providers using competitive quotations to signal when they are prepared to give better-than-normal trade executions. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bessembinder, H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How much do firms hedge with derivatives?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guay, W.; Kothari, S. P.
For 234 large non-financial corporations using derivatives, we report the magnitude of their risk exposure hedged by financial derivatives. If interest rates, currency exchange rates, and commodity prices change simultaneously by three standard deviations, the median firm's derivatives portfolio, at most, generates $15 million in cash and $31 million in value. These amounts are modest relative to firm size, and operating and investing cash flows, and other benchmarks. Corporate derivatives use appears to be a small piece of non-financial firms' overall risk profile. This suggests a need to rethink past empirical research documenting the importance of firms' derivative use. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guay, W.; Kothari, S. P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Likelihood-based specification analysis of continuous-time models of the short-term interest rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durham, G. B.
An extensive collection of continuous-time models of the short-term interest rate is evaluated over data sets that have appeared previously in the literature. The analysis, which uses the simulated maximum likelihood procedure proposed by Durham and Gallant (2002), provides new insights regarding several previously unresolved questions. For single factor models, I find that the volatility, not the drift, is the critical component in model specification. Allowing for additional flexibility beyond a constant term in the drift provides negligible benefit. While constant drift would appear to imply that the short rate is nonstationary, in fact, stationarity is volatility-induced. The simple constant elasticity of volatility model fits weekly observations of the three-month Treasury bill rate remarkably well but is easily rejected when compared with more flexible volatility specifications over daily data. The methodology of Durham and Gallant can also be used to estimate stochastic volatility models. While adding the latent volatility component provides a large improvement in the likelihood for the physical process, it does little to improve bond-pricing performance. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Durham, G. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The maturity of debt issues and predictable variation in bond returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, M.; Greenwood, R.; Wurgler, J.
The maturity of new debt issues predicts excess bond returns. When the share of long-term debt issues in total debt issues is high, future excess bond returns are low. This predictive power comes in two parts. First, inflation, the real short-term rate, and the term spread predict excess bond returns. Second, these same variables explain the long-term share, and together account for much of its own ability to predict excess bond returns. The results are consistent with survey evidence that firms use debt market conditions in an effort to determine the lowest-cost maturity at which to borrow. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baker, M.; Greenwood, R.; Wurgler, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock price reaction to news and no-news: drift and reversal after headlines</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, W. S.
Using a comprehensive database of headlines about individual companies, I examine monthly returns following public news. I compare them to stocks with similar returns, but no identifiable public news. There is a difference between the two sets. I find strong drift after bad news. Investors seem to react slowly to this information. I also find reversal after extreme price movements unaccompanied by public news. The separate patterns appear even after adjustments for risk exposure and other effects. They are, however, mainly seen in smaller, more illiquid stocks. These findings support some integrated theories of investor over- and underreaction. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, W. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Law, endowments, and finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, T.; Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Levine, R.
Using a sample of 70 former colonies, this paper assesses two theories regarding the historical determinants of financial development. The law and finance theory holds that legal traditions, brought by colonizers, differ in terms of protecting the rights of private investors vis-A-vis the state, with important implications for financial markets. The endowment theory argues that the disease environment encountered by colonizers influences the formation of long-lasting institutions that shape financial development. The empirical results provide evidence for both theories. However, initial endowments explain more of the cross-country variation in financial intermediary and stock market development. (C) 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, T.; Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Levine, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Protection of minority shareholder interests, cross-listings in the United States, and subsequent equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reese, W. A.; Weisbach, M. S.
This paper examines the hypothesis that non-US firms cross-list in the United States to increase protection of their minority shareholders. Cross-listing on the NYSE or Nasdaq subjects a non-US firm to a number of provisions of US securities law, and requires the firm to conform to US GAAP. It therefore increases the expected cost to managers of extracting private benefits, and commits the firm to protect minority shareholders' interests. The expected relation between the quantity of cross-listings and shareholder protection in the home country is ambiguous, because managers will consider both expected private benefits and the public value of their shares. However, there are clear predictions about the relation between subsequent equity issues, shareholder protection, and cross-listings: (1) Equity issues increase following all cross-listings, regardless of shareholder protection. (2) The increase should be larger for cross-listings from countries with weak protection. (3) Equity issues following cross-listings in the US will tend to be in the US for firms from countries with strong protection and outside the US for firms from countries with weak protection. We find evidence consistent with each of these predictions. Overall, the desire to protect shareholder rights appears to be an important reason why some non-US firms cross-list in the United States. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Reese, W. A.; Weisbach, M. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection and equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shleifer, A.; Wolfenzon, D.
We present a simple model of an entrepreneur going public in an environment with poor legal protection of outside shareholders. The model incorporates elements of Becker's (J. Political Econ. 106 (1968) 172) "crime and punishment" framework into a corporate finance environment of Jensen and Meckling (J. Financial Econ. 3 (1976) 305). We examine the entrepreneur's decision and the market equilibrium. The model is consistent with a number of empirical regularities concerning the relation between investor protection and corporate finance. It also sheds light on the patterns of capital flows between rich and poor countries and on the politics of reform of investor protection. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shleifer, A.; Wolfenzon, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO compensation, diversification, and incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, L.
This paper examines the relation between chief executive officers' (CEOs') incentive levels and their firms' risk characteristics. I show theoretically that, when CEOs cannot trade the market portfolio, optimal incentive level decreases with firm's nonsystematic risk but is ambiguously affected by firm's systematic risk; when CEOs can trade the market portfolio, optimal incentive level decreases with nonsystematic risk but is unaffected by systematic risk. Empirically I find support for these predictions. Furthermore, I find that incentives for CEOs likely facing binding short-selling constraints decrease with systematic as well as nonsystematic risk, as predicted by theory. Thus, compensation practice is consistent with predictions of theory. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jin, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Breadth of ownership and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, J.; Hong, H.; Stein, J. C.
We develop a stock market model with differences of opinion and short-sales constraints. When breadth is low-i.e., when few investors have long positions-this signals that the short-sales constraint is binding tightly, and that prices are high relative to fundamentals. Thus reductions in breadth should forecast lower returns. Using data on mutual fund holdings, we find that stocks whose change in breadth in the prior quarter is in the lowest decile of the sample underperform those in the top decile by 6.38% in the twelve months after formation. Adjusting for size, book-to-market, and momentum, the figure is 4.95%. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, J.; Hong, H.; Stein, J. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-sale constraints and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, C. M.; Lamont, O. A.
Stocks can be overpriced when short-sale constraints bind. We study the costs of shortselling equities from 1926 to 1933, using the publicly observable market for borrowing stock. Some stocks are sometimes expensive to short, and it appears that stocks enter the borrowing market when shorting demand is high. We find that stocks that are expensive to short or which enter the borrowing market have high valuations and low subsequent returns, consistent with the overpricing hypothesis. Size-adjusted returns are 1-2% lower per month for new entrants, and despite high costs it is profitable to short them. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jones, C. M.; Lamont, O. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stocks are special too: an analysis of the equity lending market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geczy, C. C.; Musto, D. K.; Reed, A. V.
With a year of equity loans by a major lender, we measure the effect of actual short-selling costs and constraints on trading strategies that involve short-selling. We find the loans of initial public offering (IPOs), DotCom, large-cap, growth and low-momentum stocks to be cheap relative to the strategies' documented profits and that investors who can short only stocks that are cheap and easy to borrow can enjoy at least some of the profits of unconstrained investors. Most IPOs are loaned on their first settlement days and throughout their first months, and the underperformance around lockup expiration is significant even for the IPOs that are cheap and easy to borrow. The effect of short-selling frictions appears strongest in merger arbitrage. Acquirers' stock is expensive to borrow, especially when the acquirer is small, though the major influence on trading profits is not through expense but availability. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V.. All rights reserved.</description><author>Geczy, C. C.; Musto, D. K.; Reed, A. V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of specialist firm acquisitions on market quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hatch, B. C.; Johnson, S. A.
Acquisitions among New York Stock Exchange specialist firms can increase specialist firm size, capitalization, and market concentration, and thereby affect the market quality of the stocks they trade. We find that while traded stocks show significant improvement in several market quality measures following acquisitions, similar changes are evident in matched control stocks not involved in acquisitions. We conclude that specialist firm acquisitions either do not improve market quality, or improve market quality, but competitive and other pressures (resulting partly from the acquisitions themselves) force improvements in market quality for control stocks also. Either interpretation implies that specialist acquisitions have not had deleterious effects on market quality. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hatch, B. C.; Johnson, S. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The bond/old-bond spread</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnamurthy, A.
I document the profits on a trade that is long the old 30-year Treasury bond and short the new 30-year Treasury bond, and is rolled over every auction cycle from June 1995 to November 1999. Despite the systematic convergence of the spread over the auction cycle, the average profits are close to zero. The difference in repo-market financing rates between the two bonds is a significant cost of carry in this trade. I show that variation in the bond/old-bond spread is driven by the Treasury supply of 30-year bonds as well as aggregate factors affecting investors' preference for liquid assets. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Krishnamurthy, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who underreacts to cash-flow news? evidence from trading between individuals and institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, R. B.; Gompers, P. A.; Vuolteenaho, T.
A large body of literature suggests that firm-level stock prices "underreact" to news about future cash flows; i.e., shocks to a firm's expected cash flows are positively correlated with shocks to expected returns on its stock. We examine the joint behavior of returns, cash-flow news, and trading between individuals and institutions. Institutions buy shares from (sell shares to) individuals in response to positive (negative) cash-flow news, thus exploiting the underreaction phenomenon. Institutions are not simply following price momentum strategies: When price goes up (down) in the absence of any cash-flow news, institutions sell shares to (buy shares from) individuals. Although institutions are trading in the "right" direction, institutions as a group outperform individuals by only 1.44% per annum before transaction and other costs, because they are extremely conservative in deviating from the value-weighted market index. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cohen, R. B.; Gompers, P. A.; Vuolteenaho, T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium and welfare in markets with financially constrained arbitrageurs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gromb, D.; Vayanos, D.
We propose a multiperiod model in which competitive arbitrageurs exploit discrepancies between the prices of two identical risky assets traded in segmented markets. Arbitrageurs need to collateralize separately their positions in each asset, and this implies a financial constraint limiting positions as a function of wealth. In our model, arbitrage activity benefits all investors because arbitrageurs supply liquidity to the market. However, arbitrageurs might fail to take a socially optimal level of risk, in the sense that a change in their positions can make all investors better off. We characterize conditions under which arbitrageurs take too much or too little risk. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gromb, D.; Vayanos, D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Synchronization risk and delayed arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abreu, D.; Brunnermeier, M. K.
We argue that arbitrage is limited if rational traders face uncertainty about when their peers will exploit a common arbitrage opportunity. This synchronization risk-which is distinct from noise trader risk and fundamental risk-arises in our model because arbitrageurs become sequentially aware of mispricing and they incur holding costs. We show that rational arbitrageurs "time the market" rather than correct mispricing right away. This leads to delayed arbitrage. The analysis suggests that behavioral influences on prices are resistant to arbitrage in the short and intermediate run. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abreu, D.; Brunnermeier, M. K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securities lending, shorting, and pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffie, D.; Garleanu, N.; Pedersen, L. H.
We present a model of asset valuation in which short-selling requires searching for security lenders and bargaining over the lending fee. If lendable securities are difficult to locate, then the price of the security is initially elevated, and expected to decline. This price decline is to be anticipated, for example, after an initial public offering, and is increasing in the degree of heterogeneity of beliefs about the future value of the security. The prospect of lending fees may push the initial price of a security above even the most optimistic buyer's valuation of the security's future dividends. A higher price can thus be obtained with some shorting than if shorting is disallowed. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duffie, D.; Garleanu, N.; Pedersen, L. H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market for borrowing stock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Avolio, G.
To short a stock, an arbitrageur must first borrow it. This paper describes the market for borrowing and lending U.S. equities, emphasizing the conditions generating and sustaining short-sale constraints. A large institutional lending intermediary provided eighteen months (4/ 2000-9/2001) of data on loan supply ("shortability"), loan fees ("specialness"), and loan recalls. The data suggest that while loan market specials and recalls are rare on average, the incidence of these short-sale constraints is increasing in the divergence of opinion among investors. Beyond some threshold, investor optimism itself can limit arbitrage via the loan market mechanism. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>D'Avolio, G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic IPO underpricing, information momentum, and lockup expiration selling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, R. K.; Krigman, L.; Womack, K. L.
Managers usually do not sell any of their own shares in an initial public offering but instead wait until the end of the lockup period. We develop a model in which managers strategically underprice IPOs to maximize personal wealth from selling shares at lockup expiration. First-day underpricing generates information momentum by attracting attention to the stock and thereby shifting the demand curve for the stock outwards. This allows managers to sell shares at the lockup expiration at prices higher than they would otherwise obtain. We test the model on a sample of IPOs in the 1990s. We find that higher ownership by managers is positively correlated with first-day underpricing, underpricing is positively correlated with research coverage, and, research coverage is positively correlated with stock returns and insider selling at the lockup expiration. These results are consistent with the model. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, R. K.; Krigman, L.; Womack, K. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity risk and specialness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, A.; Menini, D.
Repo contracts, the most important form of collateralized lending, are widely used by financial institutions and hedge funds to create short-selling positions and manage their leverage profile. Moreover, they have become the primary tool of money management and monetary control of several central banks, including the Bundesbank and the newly born European Central Bank. This paper is an empirical study of this market. More specifically, we study the extent to which the current term structure of long term "special" repo spreads discount the future collateral value (specialness) of Treasuries. We ask whether repo spreads embed a liquidity risk premium and whether such a risk premium is time-varying. We quantify the size of the average liquidity risk premium and we provide empirical evidence of the extent of its time-variation. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buraschi, A.; Menini, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of strategic venture investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hellmann, T.
Some venture capital investors seek purely financial gains while others, such as corporations, also pursue strategic objectives. The paper examines a model where a strategic investor can achieve synergies, but can also face a conflict of interest with the entrepreneur. If the start-up is a complement to the strategic partner, it is optimal to obtain funding front the strategic investor. If the start-up is a mild substitute, the entrepreneur prefers an independent venture capitalist. With a strong substitute, syndication becomes optimal, such that the independent venture capitalist is the active lead investor and the strategic partner a passive co-investor. The expected returns for the entrepreneur are nonmonotonic, lowest for a mild substitute, and higher for a strong substitute as well as for a complement. The paper also explains why it strategic investor often pays a higher valuation than an independent venture capitalist. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hellmann, T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A cross-firm analysis of the impact of corporate governance on the East Asian financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitton, T.
In a sample of 398 firms from Indonesia, Korea, Malaysia, the Philippines, and Thailand, firm-level differences in variables related to corporate governance had a strong impact on firm performance during the East Asian financial crisis of 1997-1998. Significantly better stock price performance is associated with firms that had indicators of higher disclosure quality (ADRs and auditors from Big Six accounting firms), with firms that had higher outside ownership concentration, and with firms that were focused rather than diversified. The results suggest that individual firms have some power to preclude expropriation of minority shareholders if legal protection is inadequate. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mitton, T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of durable bank relationships: evidence from Korean banking shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, K. H.; Kang, J. K.; Lim, C. W.
Using a large sample of exogenous events that negatively affected Korean banks during the 1997-98 period, we examine the value of durable bank relationships in Korea. We show that adverse shocks to banks have a negative effect not only on the value of the banks themselves but also on the value of their client firms, and that this adverse effect on firm value is a decreasing function of the financial health of both the banks and their client firms. Our results are concentrated in the second half of the sample period when Korean banks experienced severe difficulties. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bae, K. H.; Kang, J. K.; Lim, C. W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry growth and capital allocation: does having a market- or bank-based system matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, T.; Levine, R.
Are market-based or bank-based financial systems better at financing the expansion of industries that depend heavily on external finance, facilitating the formation of new establishments, and improving the efficiency of capital allocation across industries? We find evidence for neither the market-based nor the bank-based hypothesis. While legal system efficiency and overall financial development boost industry growth, new establishment formation, and efficient capital allocation, having a bank-based or market-based system per se does not seem to matter much. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, T.; Levine, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. W.
nan</description><author>Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm diversification and asymmetric information: evidence from analysts' forecasts and earnings announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thomas, S.
Managers frequently cite the desire to mitigate asymmetric information as a motivation for increasing firm focus. The information benefits of focus appear relevant for the subset of firms that actually increase their focus; however, the relevance of focus-related information benefits for the population of diversified firms is an open question. This paper examines the relation between corporate diversification and asymmetric information proxies derived from analysts' forecasts and abnormal returns associated with earnings announcements. I find that greater diversification is not associated with increased asymmetric information. These results call into question the notion that corporate diversification strictly exacerbates information problems. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Thomas, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock return predictability and model uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, D.
We use Bayesian model averaging to analyze the sample evidence on return predictability in the presence of model uncertainty. The analysis reveals in-sample and out-of-sample predictability, and shows that the out-of-sample performance of the Bayesian approach is superior to that of model selection criteria. We find that term and market premia are robust predictor.;. Moreover, small-cap value stocks appear more predictable than large-cap growth stocks. We also investigate the implications of model uncertainty from investment management perspectives. Vie show that model uncertainty is more important than estimation risk, and investors who discard model uncertainty face large utility losses. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avramov, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Untitled</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, R.; O'Hara, M.; Schwert, G. W.
nan</description><author>Green, R.; O'Hara, M.; Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund performance and seemingly unrelated assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, L.; Stambaugh, R. F.
Estimates of standard performance measures can be improved by using returns on assets not used to define those measures. Alpha, the intercept in a regression of a fund's return on passive benchmark returns, can be estimated more precisely by using information in returns on nonbenchmark passive assets, whether or not one believes those assets are priced by the benchmarks. A fund's Sharpe ratio can be estimated more precisely by using returns on other assets as well as the fund. New estimates of these performance measures for a large universe of equity mutual funds exhibit substantial differences from the usual estimates. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pastor, L.; Stambaugh, R. F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing in equity mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, L.; Stambaugh, R. F.
We construct optimal portfolios of equity funds by combining historical returns on funds and passive indexes with prior views about asset pricing and skill, By including both benchmark and nonbenchmark indexes, we distinguish pricing-model inaccuracy from managerial skill. Modest confidence in a pricing model helps construct portfolios with high Sharpe ratios. Investing in active mutual funds can be optimal even for investors who believe managers cannot outperform passive indexes. Optimal portfolios exclude hot-hand funds even for investors who believe momentum is priced. Our large universe of funds offers no close substitutes for the Fama-French and momentum benchmarks. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pastor, L.; Stambaugh, R. F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do after-tax returns affect mutual fund inflows?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergstresser, D.; Poterba, J.
This paper explores the relationship between the after-tax returns that taxable investors earn on equity mutual funds and the subsequent cash inflows to these funds. Previous studies have documented that funds with high pretax returns attract greater inflows. This paper presents evidence, based on a large sample of retail equity mutual funds over the period 1993-1999, that after-tax returns have more explanatory power than pretax returns in explaining inflows. In addition, funds with large overhangs of unrealized capital gains experience smaller inflows, all else equal, than funds without such unrealized gains. A large capital gain overhang discourages both gross fund inflows and gross outflows, but the inflow effect dominates the outflow effect. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bergstresser, D.; Poterba, J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectation puzzles, time-varying risk premia, and affine models of the term structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Q.; Singleton, K. J.
Linear projections of returns on the slope of the yield curve have contradicted the implications of the traditional "'expectations theory". This paper shows that these findings are not puzzling relative to a large class of richer dynamic term structure models. Specifically, we match all the key empirical findings reported by Fama and Bliss ((1987) American Economic Review 77 (4), 680 692) and Campbell and Shiller ((1991) Review of Economic Studies 58, 495-514), among others, within large subclasses of affine and quadratic-Gaussian term structure models. Additionally, we show that certain "risk-premium adjusted" projections of changes in yields on the slope of the yield curve recover the coefficients of unity predicted by the models. Key to this matching are parameterizations of the market prices of risk that let the risk factors affect the market prices of risk directly, and not only through factor volatilities. The risk premiums have a simple form consistent with Fama's findings on the predictability of forward rates, and are also shown to be consistent with interest-rate feedback rules used by a monetary authority in setting monetary policy. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dai, Q.; Singleton, K. J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric correlations of equity portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, A.; Chen, J.
Correlations between U.S. stocks and the aggregate U.S. market are much greater for downside moves, especially for extreme downside moves, than for upside moves. We develop a new statistic for measuring, comparing, and testing asymmetries in conditional correlations. Conditional on the downside, correlations in the data differ from the conditional correlations implied by a normal distribution by 11.6%. We find that conditional asymmetric correlations are fundamentally different from other measures of asymmetries, such as skewness and co-skewness. We find that small stocks, value stocks, and past loser stocks have more asymmetric movements. Controlling for size, we find that stocks with lower betas exhibit greater correlation asymmetries, and we find no relationship between leverage and correlation asymmetries. Correlation asymmetries in the data reject the null hypothesis of multivariate normal distributions at daily, weekly, and monthly frequencies, However, several empirical models with greater flexibility, particularly regime-switching models, perform better tit (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, A.; Chen, J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset liquidity, debt covenants, and managerial discretion in financial distress: the collapse of LA Gear</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, H.; DeAngelo, L.; Wruck, K. H.
A hot growth stock in the 1980s, L.A. Gear's equity fell from $1 billion in market value in 1989 to zero in 1998. For over six years as revenues declined precipitously, management tried a series of radical strategy shifts while subsidizing the firm's large losses through working-capital liquidations. The L.A. Gear case illustrates that asset liquidity (broadly construed, not limited to excess cash) can give managers substantial operating discretion during financial distress. It also shows (1) that debt covenants can be stronger disciplinary mechanisms than requirements to meet cash interest payments, (2) why debt contracts typically constrain earnings instead of cash flow, (3) why cash balances are not equivalent to negative debt, and (4) why debt maturity matters. We find that many firms have highly liquid asset structures, thus their managers have the potential to subsidize losing operations should the need arise. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeAngelo, H.; DeAngelo, L.; Wruck, K. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth opportunities and corporate debt policy: the case of the US defense industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyal, V. K.; Lehn, K.; Racic, S.
The U.S. defense industry provides a natural experiment for examining how changes in growth opportunities affect the level and structure of corporate debt. The growth opportunities of defense firms, compared with other firms, increased substantially during the Reagan defense buildup of the early 1980s but then declined significantly with the end of the cold war and associated defense budget cuts in the late 1980s and early 1990s. We examine how the level and Structure of corporate debt changed for a sample of 61 defense firms and a benchmark sample of 61 manufacturing firms during 1980-95, a period spanning the changes in growth opportunities. The debt levels of weapons manufacturers, which were most affected by the changes in growth opportunities, increased significantly as their growth opportunities declined. In addition, these firms lengthened the maturity structure of their debt, decreased the ratio of private to public debt, and decreased the use of senior debt as their growth opportunities declined. The results complement other studies that have found cross-sectional relations between proxies for growth opportunities and leverage variables and validate the prominent role played by growth opportunities in the theory of corporate finance. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goyal, V. K.; Lehn, K.; Racic, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance with poor investor protection: evidence from top executive turnover in Italy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Volpin, P. F.
This paper studies the determinants of executive turnover and firm valuation as a function of ownership and control structure in Italy, a country that features low legal protection for investors, firms with controlling shareholders, and pyramidal groups. The results suggest that there is poor governance, as measured by a low sensitivity of turnover to performance and a low Q ratio, when (i) the controlling shareholders are also top executives, (ii) the control is fully in the hands of one shareholder and is not shared by a set of core shareholders, and (iii) the controlling shareholders own less than 50% of the firm's cash-flow rights. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Volpin, P. F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited arbitrage in mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, M.; Savasoglu, S.
A diversified portfolio of risk arbitrage positions produces an abnormal return of 0.6 0.9% per month over the period from 198 1 to 1996. We trace these profits to practical limits on risk arbitrage. In our model of risk arbitrage, arbitrageurs' risk-bearing capacity is constrained by deal completion risk and the size of the position they hold. Consistent with this model, we document that the returns to risk arbitrage increase in an ex ante measure of completion risk and target size. We also examine the influence of the general supply of arbitrage capital, measured by the total equity holdings of arbitrageurs, on arbitrage profits. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V, All rights reserved.</description><author>Baker, M.; Savasoglu, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Divestitures and the liquidity of the market for corporate assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schlingemann, F. P.; Stulz, R. M.; Walkling, R. A.
The liquidity of the market for corporate assets plays an important role in explaining whether a firm divests a business segment, which segment the firm divests, and whether it divests a core segment or an unrelated segment. Firms are more likely to divest segments from industries with a more liquid market for corporate assets, unrelated segments, poorly performing segments, and small segments. Strikingly, the segment with the least liquid market is less likely to be divested than the best-performing segment, while the worst-performing segment is less likely to be divested than the segment with the most liquid market. 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schlingemann, F. P.; Stulz, R. M.; Walkling, R. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does the Internet affect trading? Evidence from investor behavior in 401(k) plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, J. J.; Laibson, D.; Metrick, A.
We analyze the impact of a Web-based trading channel on trader behavior and performance in two large corporate 401(k) plans. After 18 months of Web access, trading frequency at sample firms doubles relative to a control group of firms without a Web channel. Web trades tend to be smaller than trades made through other channels and Web traders tend to have smaller portfolios than other traders, so the Web's impact on portfolio turnover is substantially smaller than its effect on trading frequency. There is no evidence than any of this new trading on the Web is successful. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choi, J. J.; Laibson, D.; Metrick, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical pricing kernels</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosenberg, J. V.; Engle, R. F.
This paper investigates the empirical characteristics of investor risk aversion over equity return states by estimating a time-varying pricing kernel, which we call the empirical pricing kernel (EPK). We estimate the EPK on a monthly basis from 1991 to 1995, using S&amp;P 500 index option data and a stochastic volatility model for the S&amp;P 500 return process. We find that the EPK exhibits counter cyclical risk aversion over S&amp;P 500 return states. We also find that hedging performance is significantly improved when we use hedge ratios based the EPK rather than a time-invariant pricing kernel. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rosenberg, J. V.; Engle, R. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO allocations: discriminatory or discretionary?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ljungqvist, A. P.; Wilhelm, W. J.
We estimate the structural links between IPO allocations, pre-market information production, and initial underpricing and find that (1) allocation policies favor institutional investors, both in the US and worldwide; (2) increasing institutional allocations results in offer prices that deviate more from the pre-marketing price range; (3) constraints on bankers' discretion reduce institutional allocations and result in smaller price revisions, indicating diminished information production; and (4) initial returns are directly related to information production and inversely related to institutional allocations. Our results indicate that discretionary allocations promote price discovery in the IPO market and reduce indirect issuance costs for IPO firms. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ljungqvist, A. P.; Wilhelm, W. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dating the integration of world equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, G.; Harvey, C. R.; Lumsdaine, R. L.
Regulatory changes that appear comprehensive will have little impact on the functioning of a developing market if they fail to lead to foreign portfolio inflows. We specify a reduced-form model for a number of financial time series and search for a common, endogenous break in the data generating process. We also estimate a confidence interval for the break. Our endogenous break dates are accurately estimated but do not always correspond closely to dates of official capital market reforms. Indeed, the endogenous dates are usually later than official dates, highlighting the important distinction between market liberalization and market integration. circle dot 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bekaert, G.; Harvey, C. R.; Lumsdaine, R. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional performance measurement using portfolio weights: evidence for pension funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, W.; Khang, K.
This paper combines the use of portfolio holdings data and conditioning information to create a new performance measure. Our conditional weight-based measure has several advantages. Using conditioning information avoids biases in weight-based measures as discussed by Grinblatt and Titman (J. Business 60 (1993)). When conditioning information is used, returns-based measures face a bias if managers can trade between observation dates. The new measures avoid this interim trading bias. We use the new measures to provide fresh insights about performance in a sample of U.S. equity pension fund managers. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferson, W.; Khang, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and capital allocation in catastrophe insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zanjani, G.
This paper studies multi-line pricing and capital allocation by insurance companies when solvency matters to consumers, capital is costly to hold, and the average loss is uncertain. In this environment, product quality concerns lead firms to diversify across markets and charge high prices for risk that threatens company solvency, even if the risk is unrelated to other asset risk. Price differences across markets are traced to differences in capital required at the margin to maintain solvency. Finally, the paper shows that capital costs have significant effects on catastrophe insurance markets because of high marginal capital requirements. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zanjani, G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance consequences of mandatory increases in executive stock ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Core, J. E.; Larcker, D. F.
We examine a sample of firms that adopt "target ownership plans", under which managers are required to own a minimum amount of stock. We find that prior to plan adoption, such firms exhibit low managerial equity ownership and low stock price performance. Managerial equity ownership increases significantly in the two years following plan adoption. We also observe that excess accounting returns and stock returns are higher after the plan is adopted. Thus, for our sample of firms, the required increases in the level of managerial equity ownership result in improvements in firm performance. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Core, J. E.; Larcker, D. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. W.
nan</description><author>Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Litigation risk and IPO underpricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lowry, M.; Shu, S.
We examine the relation between risk and IPO underpricing and test two aspects of the litigation-risk hypothesis: (1) firms with higher litigation risk underprice their IPOs by a greater amount as a form of insurance (insurance effect) and (2) higher underpricing lowers expected litigation costs (deterrence effect). To adjust for the endogeneity bias in previous studies, we use a simultaneous equation framework. Evidence provides support for both aspects of the litigation-risk hypothesis. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science Ltd. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lowry, M.; Shu, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Funding growth in bank-based and market-based financial systems: evidence from firm-level data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Maksimovic, V.
We investigate whether firms' access to external financing to fund growth differs in market-based and bank-based financial systems. Using firm-level data for 40 countries, we compute the proportion of firms in each country relying on external finance and examine how that proportion differs across financial systems. We find that the development of a country's legal system predicts access to external finance, and stock markets and the banking system affect access to external finance differently. However, we find no evidence that firms' access to external financing is predicted by several proxies for relative development of stock markets to the development of the banking system. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Maksimovic, V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The ultimate ownership of Western European corporations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faccio, M.; Lang, L. H. P.
We analyze the ultimate ownership and control of 5,232 corporations in 13 Western European countries. Typically firms are widely held (36.93%) or family controlled (44.29%). Widely held firms are more important in the UK and Ireland, family controlled firms in continental Europe. Financial and large firms are more likely widely held, while non-financial and small firms are more likely family controlled. State control is important for larger firms in certain countries. Dual class shares and pyramids enhance the control of the largest shareholders, but overall there are significant discrepancies between ownership and control in only a few countries. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faccio, M.; Lang, L. H. P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting the next step of a random walk: experimental evidence of regime-shifting beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloomfield, R.; Hales, J.
Barberis et al. (J. Financial Econ. 49 (1998) 307), construct a model in which investors use the prevalence of past trend reversals as an indicator of the likelihood of future reversals. While such "regime-shifting" beliefs are consistent with a variety of psychological theories, other contrary predictions are consistent with the same theories. We report two experiments with MBA-student participants that strongly support the existence of regime-shifting beliefs. We conclude that regime-shifting models can provide a useful framework for understanding market anomalies, including underreactions to earnings changes and overreactions to long-term earnings trends. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Bloomfield, R.; Hales, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market efficiency in real time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Busse, J. A.; Green, T. C.
The Morning Call and Midday Call segments on CNBC TV provide a unique opportunity to study the efficient market hypothesis. The segments report analysts' views about individual stocks and are broadcast when the market is open. We find that prices respond to reports within seconds of initial mention, with positive reports fully incorporated within one minute. Trading intensity doubles in the first minute, with a significant increase in buyer- (seller-) initiated trades after positive (negative) reports. Traders who execute within 15 seconds of the initial mention make small but significant profits by trading on positive reports during the Midday Call. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Busse, J. A.; Green, T. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Building the IPO order book: underpricing and participation limits with costly information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sherman, A. E.; Titman, S.
We examine the book-building method for marketing IPOs. In our model, the underwriter selects a group of investors along with a pricing and allocation mechanism to maximize (at minimum cost) the information generated during the process of going public. We also address the moral hazard problem faced by investors when evaluation is costly. When there is little need for accurate pricing, the expected gain from underpricing exactly offsets the investors' costs of acquiring information. When pricing accuracy is important, however, the number of investors participating in the offering is larger, underpricing is greater, and investors can earn economic rents. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sherman, A. E.; Titman, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Econometric models of limit-order executions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lo, A. W.; MacKinlay, A. C.; Zhang, J.
We develop and estimate an econometric model of limit-order execution times using survival analysis and actual limit-order data. We estimate versions for time-to-first-fill and time-to-completion for both buy and sell limit orders, and incorporate the effects of explanatory variables such as the limit price, limit size, bid/offer spread, and market volatility. Execution times are very sensitive to the limit price, but are not sensitive to limit size. Hypothetical limit-order executions, constructed either theoretically from first-passage times or empirically from transactions data, are very poor proxies for actual limit-order executions. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lo, A. W.; MacKinlay, A. C.; Zhang, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-term interest rate dynamics: a spatial approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bandi, F. M.
We use new fully functional methods to describe and study the dynamics of the short-term interest rate process in continuous-time. The suggested procedure exploits the spatial properties, embodied in the local time process, of the diffusion of interest, and is robust against deviations from stationarity. Our results indicate that the misspecification of a standard constant elasticity of variance model with linear mean-reverting drift cannot be attributed to the nonlinear behavior of the infinitesimal first moment of the short-term interest rate process at high rates. Rather, it should be attributed to the martingale nature of the process over most of its empirical range (i.e., between 3% and about 15%). (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bandi, F. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order imbalance, liquidity, and market returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, T.; Roll, R.; Subrahmanyam, A.
Traditionally, volume has provided the link between trading activity and returns. We focus on a hitherto unexplored but intuitive measure of trading activity: the aggregate daily order imbalance, buy orders less sell orders, on the New York Stock Exchange. Order imbalance increases following market declines and vice versa, which reveals that investors are contrarians on aggregate. Order imbalances in either direction, excess buy or sell orders, reduce liquidity. Market-wide returns are strongly affected by contemporaneous and lagged order imbalances. Market returns reverse themselves after high-negative-imbalance, large-negative-return days. Even after controlling for aggregate volume and liquidity, market returns are affected by order imbalance. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Chordia, T.; Roll, R.; Subrahmanyam, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dilution impact of daily fund flows on open-end mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greene, J. T.; Hodges, C. W.
We examine how mutual fund flows that are correlated with subsequent fund returns can have a dilution impact on the performance of open-end funds. Active trading of open-end funds has a meaningful economic impact on the returns of passive, nontrading shareholders, particularly in U.S.-based international funds. The overall sample of domestic equity funds shows no dilution impact, but we find an annualized negative impact of 0.48% in international funds (and nearly 1% for a subsample of funds whose daily flows are particularly large). The exchange and pricing policies of mutual funds can thus have important performance-related implications. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Greene, J. T.; Hodges, C. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance with poor investor protection: evidence from top executive turnover in Italy (vol 64, pg 61, 2002)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Volpin, P. F.
nan</description><author>Volpin, P. F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The jump-risk premia implicit in options: evidence from an integrated time-series study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, J.
This paper examines the joint time series of the S&amp;P 500 index and near-the-money short-dated option prices with an arbitrage-free model, capturing both stochastic volatility and jumps. Jump-risk premia Uncovered from the joint data respond quickly to market volatility, becoming more prominent during volatile markets. This form of jump-risk premia is important not only in reconciling the dynamics implied by the joint data, but also in explaining the volatility "smirks" of cross-sectional options data. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pan, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity provision and specialist trading in NYSE-listed non-US stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bacidore, J. M.; Sofianos, G.
We examine how the intrinsic differences between U.S. and non-U.S. stocks affect market participants and the market quality of non-U.S. stocks relative to U.S. stocks. Using proprietary data on NYSE specialist trading, we find that, all else equal, specialist closing inventory positions for non-U.S. stocks are closer to zero than U.S. stocks. The evidence on specialist participation and stabilization rates is mixed. Non-U.S. stocks from developed markets have higher specialist participation and stabilization rates than U.S, stocks, while emerging market stocks have lower participation and stabilization rates than U.S. stocks. With respect to market quality, we find that, all else equal, non-U.S. stocks have wider spreads. less depth, and greater transitory volatility than U.S. stocks. We investigate the reasons behind the difference in liquidity and find that the larger non-U.S. spreads are primarily due to higher information asymmetry and increased adverse selection risk. We conclude that liquidity providers demand greater compensation for trading non-U.S. stocks, but this additional compensation is necessary to offset the higher adverse selection risk. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bacidore, J. M.; Sofianos, G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agents watching agents?: evidence from pension fund ownership and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Woidtke, T.
This paper examines the valuation effects associated with the incentive structures of different types of institutional investors using the ownership levels of public and private pension funds in a firm. The results suggest that institutional monitoring is associated with valuation effects when both observable and unobservable aspects of the relationship between institutions and firms are taken into account, Moreover, the valuation effects vary according to the objective functions of institutions' administrators. Thus, other shareholders do not necessarily benefit from relationships between institutions and managers, and they could be hurt when the institutional agents watching firm agents have conflicts of interest with other shareholders. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Woidtke, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contracting in the investment management industry: evidence from mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deli, D. N.; Varma, R.
We investigate the option to invest in derivative securities using a large sample of mutual funds. We find that those funds with the greatest transaction-cost benefit tend to permit investment in derivatives, and that funds tend to permit investment only in those derivatives that offer transaction-cost benefits. Our results indicate that a fund's decision to permit investment in derivatives is driven by increased efficiency rather than advisor opportunism. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Deli, D. N.; Varma, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does diversification destroy value? Evidence from the industry shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lamont, O. A.; Polk, C.
Does corporate diversification reduce shareholder value? Since firms endogenously choose to diversify, exogenous variation in diversification is necessary to draw inferences about the causal effect. We examine changes in the within-firm dispersion of industry investment, or "diversity". We find that exogenous changes in diversity, due to changes in industry investment, are negatively related to firm value. Thus diversification destroys value, consistent with the inefficient internal capital markets hypothesis. Measurement error does not cause this finding, We also find that exogenous changes in industry cash flow diversity are negatively related to firm value. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science S.A, All rights reserved.</description><author>Lamont, O. A.; Polk, C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate leverage and currency crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bris, A.; Koskinen, Y.
Currency crises can arise because it is optimal to bail out financially distressed exporting firms through a currency depreciation. Exporting firms will not undertake profitable investments when high leverage causes debt overhang problems. A currency depreciation increases the profitability of new investments when revenues are foreign-currency denominated and domestic-currency costs are nominally rigid. Ex ante, currency depreciation leads to excessive investment in risky projects even if safer, more valuable projects are available. However, currency depreciation is optimal ex ante if the risky projects have higher expected returns and if firms must rely on debt financing because of underdeveloped equity markets. C.. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bris, A.; Koskinen, Y.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Depositor discipline and changing strategies for regulating thrift institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldberg, L. G.; Hudgins, S. C.
This paper examines the role of uninsured deposits as a source of thrift funding from 1984 to 1994, and tests whether uninsured depositors have adjusted their holdings at thrifts in response to market forces, such as indications or impending institutional failure. It also examines how the reactions have changed over time as new legislation has been implemented. The study finds that failed institutions exhibit declining proportions of uninsured deposits-to-total-deposits prior to failure and that failing institutions attract fewer deposits from uninsured depositors prior to failure than do solvent institutions. Though there are some differences between the periods, the empirical results indicate that uninsured deposits will be governed by market discipline and that reducing the insurance limits on deposits will increase market discipline on thrifts. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goldberg, L. G.; Hudgins, S. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When a buyback isn't a buyback: open market repurchases and employee options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahle, K. M.
This paper examines how stock options affect the decision to repurchase shares. Firms announce repurchases when executives have large numbers of options outstanding and when employees have large numbers of options currently exercisable. Once the decision to repurchase is made, the amount repurchased is positively related to total options exercisable by all employees but independent of managerial options. These results are consistent with managers repurchasing both to maximize their own wealth and to fund employee stock option exercises. The market appears to recognize this motive, however, and reacts less positively to repurchases announced by firms with high levels of nonmanagerial options. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kahle, K. M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simulated likelihood estimation of diffusions with an application to exchange rate dynamics in incomplete markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandt, M. W.; Santa-Clara, P.
We present an econometric method for estimating the parameters of a diffusion model from discretely sampled data. The estimator is transparent, adaptive, and inherits the asymptotic properties of the generally unattainable maximum likelihood estimator. We use this method to estimate a new continuous-time model of the joint dynamics of interest rates in two countries and the exchange rate between the two currencies. The model allows financial markets to be incomplete and specifies the degree of incompleteness as a stochastic process. Our empirical results offer several new insights into the dynamics of exchange rates. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brandt, M. W.; Santa-Clara, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. W.
nan</description><author>Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resources, real options, and corporate strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernardo, A. E.; Chowdhry, B.
The types of investments a firm undertakes will depend in part on what it expects the outcome of those investments to reveal about its skills, capabilities. and assets (i.e., its resources). We predict that a firm will specialize when young, then experiment in a new line of business for some time, and then either expand into a large, multisegment business or focus and scale up its specialized business. We derive several empirical implications for firm valuations and the reaction of stock prices to news about firm prospects. We also offer a novel explanation for the well-documented "diversification" discount. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Bernardo, A. E.; Chowdhry, B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The portfolio flows of international investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Froot, K. A.; O'Connell, P. G. J.; Seasholes, M. S.
This paper explores daily international portfolio flows into and out of 44 countries from 1994 through 1998. We find several facts concerning the behavior of flows and their relationship with equity returns. First, we detect regional flow factors that have increased in importance through time. Second, the flows appear to be stationary, but far more persistent than returns. Third, flows are strongly influenced by past returns, a finding consistent with positive feedback trading by international investors. Fourth, inflows have positive forecasting power for future equity returns, and this power is statistically significant in emerging markets. Fifth, the sensitivity of local stock prices to foreign inflows is positive and large. Sixth, prices seem consistent with flow persistence, in that transitory inflows impact future returns negatively. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G15; F21; G11.</description><author>Froot, K. A.; O'Connell, P. G. J.; Seasholes, M. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate price effects of institutional trading: a study of mutual fund flow and market returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edelen, R. M.; Warner, J. B.
We study the relation between market returns and aggregate flow into U.S. equity funds, using daily flow data. The concurrent daily relation is positive. Our tests show that this concurrent relation reflects Row and institutional trading affecting returns. This daily relation is similar in magnitude to the price impact reported for an individual institution's trades in a stock. Aggregate flow also follows market returns with a one-day lag. The lagged response of flow suggests either a common response of both returns and now to new information, or positive feedback trading. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G23; G14.</description><author>Edelen, R. M.; Warner, J. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stockholder gains from focusing versus diversifying bank mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeLong, G. L.
This paper shows bank mergers that enhance value upon announcement can be distinguished from those that do not create value. I classify mergers of banking firms according to activity and geographic similarity (focus) or dissimilarity (diversification), and examine the abnormal returns to each group as a result of the merger announcement. Mergers that focus both activity and geography enhance stockholder value by 3.0% while the other types do not create value. Analysis reveals that abnormal returns upon merger announcement increase in relative size of target to bidder, but decrease in the pre-merger performance of targets. (C). 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14; G21; G34; L89.</description><author>DeLong, G. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sixteenths: direct evidence on institutional execution costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, C. M.; Lipson, M. L.
In June 1997, the New York Stock Exchange lowered its minimum price increment on most stocks from eighths to sixteenths. We use a sample of institutional trades to directly measure the effect of this tick size reduction on execution costs. Though quoted and effective spreads decline, realized execution costs for these institutions increase after the change to sixteenths. Costs increase most for orders that aggressively demand liquidity, including large orders, orders placed by momentum traders, and orders not worked by the trading desk. These findings emphasize that spreads are not a sufficient statistic for market quality. Smaller tick sizes may actually reduce market liquidity. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14; G18; G24.</description><author>Jones, C. M.; Lipson, M. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading activity and expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, T.; Subrahmanyam, A.; Anshuman, V. R.
Given the evidence that the level of liquidity affects asset returns, a reasonable hypothesis is that the second moment of liquidity should be positively related to asset returns, provided agents care about the risk associated with fluctuations in liquidity. Motivated by this observation, we analyze the relation between expected equity returns and the level as well as the volatility of trading activity, a proxy for liquidity. We document a result contrary to our initial hypothesis, namely, a negative and surprisingly strong cross-sectional relationship between stock returns and the variability of dollar trading volume and share turnover, after controlling for size, book-to-market ratio, momentum, and the level of dollar volume or share turnover. This effect survives a number of robustness checks, and is statistically and economically significant. Our analysis demonstrates the importance of trading activity-related variables in the cross-section of expected stock returns. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G12; G14.</description><author>Chordia, T.; Subrahmanyam, A.; Anshuman, V. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The capital gain lock-in effect and long-horizon return reversal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klein, P.
This paper develops and tests an asset pricing model that allows for the presence of a capital gain lock-in effect. The principal empirical implication of this model is that stock returns exhibit reversal behavior over long horizons because of investors' accrued capital gains. Empirical tests on the cross-section of stock returns find that long-horizon return reversal is primarily attributable to the effect of investors' accrued capital gains and that the effect is nonlinear in the manner predicted by the model. These finds are robust to the addition of size and past total return to the empirical tests. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G12; H20.</description><author>Klein, P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing the strategic value of putable securities in liquidity crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>David, A.
Putable security holders have a de facto first claim on the firm's liquid assets and can threaten to force solvent issuers to bear financial distress costs. Their threatening power implies that the puts have a strategic value larger than their intrinsic value. Strategic value depends on the issuer's size, potential distress costs, and the distribution of put ownership relative to the firm's liquidity position. The analysis of Kmart's put-induced crisis in 1995, and a calibration to observed secondary market yield reductions on poison put bonds, shows that strategic value is an important determinant of payouts received by bondholders. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G13; G33.</description><author>David, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The structure of debt and active equity investors: The case of the buyout specialist</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cotter, J. F.; Peck, S. W.
This paper examines the role buyout specialists play in structuring the debt used to finance the LBO and in monitoring management in the post-LBO firm. We find that when buyout specialists control the majority of the post-LBO equity, the LBO transaction is likely to be financed with less short-term and/or senior debt and less likely to experience financial distress. We also find that buyout specialists have greater board representation on smaller boards, suggesting that they actively monitor managers, and that for these transactions, using debt with tighter terms does not significantly increase the firm's performance. In contrast, in all other transactions using such debt does significantly increase the firm's performance. These findings suggest that active monitoring by a buyout specialist substitutes for tighter debt terms in monitoring and motivating managers of LBOs. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G32; G33; G34.</description><author>Cotter, J. F.; Peck, S. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stealth-trading: Which traders' trades move stock prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakravarty, S.
Using audit trail data for a sample of NYSE firms wt show that medium-size trades an associated with a disproportionately large cumulative stock price change relative to their proportion of all trades and volume. This result is consistent with the predictions of Barclay and Warners (1993) stealth-trading hypothesis. We find that the source of this disproportionately large cumulative prier impact of medium-size trades is trades initiated by institutions. This result is robust to various sensitivity checks. Our findings appear to confirm street lore that institutions are informed traders. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chakravarty, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock option plans for non-executive employees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Core, J. E.; Guay, W. R.
We examine determinants of non-executive employee stock option holdings, grants, and exercises for 756 firms during 1994-1997. We find that firms use greater stock option compensation when facing capital requirements and financing constraints. Our results are also consistent with firms using options to attract and retain certain types of employees as well as to create incentives to increase firm value. After controlling for economic determinants and stuck returns, option exercises are greater (less) when the firm's stock price hits 52-week highs (lows). which confirms in a broad sample the psychological bias documented by Heath et al. (Quarterly Journal of Economics 114 (1999) 601-628). (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Core, J. E.; Guay, W. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discretionary reductions in warrant exercise prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Howe, J. S.; Su, T.
Managers can decide to reduce a warrant's exercise price. A reduction in exercise price can induce exercise (a conversion-forcing reduction) or not (a long-term reduction). Conversion-Forcing firms show an abnormal return of -1.53% on the announcement day but they perform well over the three: years following the announcement. This finding suggests that the funds raised from warrant exercise are invested in profitable projects, Long-term reductions show an abnormal return of -1.15% on the announcement day. These firms also perform well following the reduction. which suggests that the lower exercise price restores managerial incentives. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Howe, J. S.; Su, T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An examination of executive stock option repricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carter, M. E.; Lynch, L. J.
Comparing a sample of firms that reprice executive stock options in 1998 to a control sample of firms with out-of-the-money options in 1998 that do not reprice, we find that the likelihood of repricing increases for young, high technology firms and firms whose options are more out-of-the-money, Further, we find that firms reprice in response to poor firm-specific, not pool industry, performance. However, we find no evidence that repricing is related to agency problems. Our results an consistent with firms repricing options to restore incentive effects and to deter managers in competitive labor markets from going to work for other firms. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carter, M. E.; Lynch, L. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset liquidity, capital structure, and secured debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morellec, E.
This paper investigates the impact of asset liquidity on the valuation of corporate securities and the firm's financing decisions. I show that asset liquidity increases debt capacity only when bond covenants restrict the disposition of assets. By contrast, I demonstrate that, with unsecured debt, greater liquidity increases credit spreads on corporate debt and reduces optimal leverage. The model also determines the extent to which pledging assets increases firm value and relates the optimal size of the pledge to firm and industry characteristics. Finally, I show that asset liquidity and security provisions may help explain leverage ratios and credit spreads observed in practice. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morellec, E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The option to withdraw IPOs during the premarket: empirical analysis (vol 60, pg 73, 2001)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Busaba, W. Y.; Benveniste, L. M.; Guo, R. J.
nan</description><author>Busaba, W. Y.; Benveniste, L. M.; Guo, R. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The duration of bank relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ongena, S.; Smith, D. C.
We analyze the duration of bank relationships using a unique panel data set of listed firms and their banks from the bank-dominated Norwegian market. We find that firms are more likely to leave a bank as the relationship matures. Small, profitable, and highly leveraged firms maintain shorter bank relationships, as do firms with multiple bank relationships. These findings are robust to censoring, alternate specifications for the distribution of relationship duration, and other control variables relevant to the Norwegian market. Overall., our results cast doubt on theories suggesting that firms become locked into bank relationships. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Ongena, S.; Smith, D. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial timing and corporate liquidity: evidence from actual share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, P.; Chung, D. Y.
We investigate the timing of open market share repurchases and the resultant impact on firm liquidity. Using the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong's unique disclosure environment, we identify the exact implementation dates for more than five thousand equity buybacks. We find that managers exhibit substantial timing ability. Consistent with the information-asymmetry hypothesis, bid-ask spreads widen and depths narrow during repurchase periods. We decompose bid-ask spreads and show that adverse selection costs increase substantially as market participants respond to the presence of informed managerial trading. Our findings provide additional insight into how markets process information and have significant implications for corporate payout and disclosure policies. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brockman, P.; Chung, D. Y.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Following the leader: a study of individual analysts' earnings forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, R. A.; Day, T. E.; Lewis, C. M.
This paper develops and tests procedures for ranking the performance of security analysts based on the timeliness of their earnings forecasts, the abnormal trading volume associated with these forecasts, and forecast accuracy. Our framework provides an objective assessment of analyst quality that differs from the standard approach, which uses survey evidence to rate analysts. We find that lead analysts identified by our measure of forecast timeliness have a greater impact on stock prices than follower analysts. Further, we find that performance rankings based on forecast timeliness are more informative than rankings based on abnormal trading volume and forecast accuracy. We also present evidence that analyst's forecast revisions are correlated with recent stock price performance, suggesting that security analysts use publicly available information to revise their earnings forecasts. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cooper, R. A.; Day, T. E.; Lewis, C. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting crashes: trading volume, past returns, and conditional skewness in stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, J.; Hong, H.; Stein, J. C.
We develop a series of cross-sectional regression specifications to forecast skewness in the daily returns of individual stocks. Negative skewness is most pronounced in stocks that have experienced (1) an increase in trading volume relative to trend over the prior six months, consistent with the model of Hong and Stein (NBER Working Paper, 1999), and (2) positive returns over the prior 36 months, which fits with a number of theories, most notably Blanchard and Watson's (Crises in Economic and Financial Structure. Lexington Books, Lexington, MA, 1982, pp. 295-315) rendition of stock-price bubbles. Analogous results also obtain when we attempt to forecast the skewness of the aggregate stock market, though our statistical power in this case is limited. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, J.; Hong, H.; Stein, J. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital budgeting and compensation with asymmetric information and moral hazard</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernardo, A. E.; Cai, H. B.; Luo, J.
We consider optimal capital allocation and managerial compensation mechanisms for decentralized firms when division managers have an incentive to misrepresent project quality and to minimize privately costly but value-enhancing effort. We show that in the optimal mechanism firms always underinvest in capital relative to a naive application of the net present value (NPV) rule. We make a number of novel cross-sectional predictions about the severity of the underinvestment problem and the composition of managerial compensation contracts. We also find that firms will optimally give greater performance-based pay (at the expense of fixed wages) to managers of higher quality projects to mitigate the incentive for managers to overstate project quality. Managers may thus receive greater performance-based pay because they manage higher quality projects, not that greater performance-based pay causes firm value to increase. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bernardo, A. E.; Cai, H. B.; Luo, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. W.
nan</description><author>Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The optimal spread and offering price for underwritten securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yeoman, J. C.
The paper develops the net proceeds maximization theory explaining how the spread and offering price are determined in all underwritten offerings in the U.S. The theory yields solutions for the optimal spread and offering price for all underwritten securities and it yields comparative statics that explain the cross-sectional variation in actual spreads and initial returns across different types of underwritten securities. The theory also suggests two alternative explanations to the ones offered by Chen and Ritter (J. Finance 55 (2000) 1105) for the clustering of unseasoned equity offerings spreads at 7%. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Yeoman, J. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>HBS-JFE conference volume: complementary research methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tufano, P.
The purpose of the Harvard Business School-Journal of Financial Economics conference was to reexamine the role of clinical work in our profession. Clinical research-empirical work that examines a relatively small number of events intensively-accounts for a very small fraction of published work in the field. The pieces in this conference volume are case studies of different "clinical" research techniques that are used to develop, test, apply and communicate theory. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tufano, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The theory and practice of corporate finance: evidence from the field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, J. R.; Harvey, C. R.
We survey 392 CFOs about the cost of capital, capital budgeting, and capital structure. Large firms rely heavily on present value techniques and the capital asset pricing model, while small firms are relatively likely to use the payback criterion. A surprising number of firms use firm risk rather than project risk in evaluating new investments. Firms are concerned about financial flexibility and credit ratings when issuing debt, and earnings per share dilution and recent stock price appreciation when issuing equity. We find some support for the pecking-order and trade-off capital structure hypotheses but little evidence that executives are concerned about asset substitution, asymmetric information, transactions costs, free cash flows, or personal taxes. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Graham, J. R.; Harvey, C. R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms switch underwriters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krigman, L.; Shaw, W. H.; Womack, K. L.
In the mid-1990s, 30% of firms completing an SEO within three years of their IPO switched lead underwriter, This article provides evidence on why they switched. Contrary to predictions of prior research, there is little evidence that firms switch due to dissatisfaction with underwriter performance at the time of the IPO. A surprising result is that switchers' IPOs were significantly less underpriced than non-switchers' IPOs. However, switchers raised fewer proceeds than expected, compared to the mid-point of the filing range, while non-switchers raised significantly more proceeds. There are two main reasons for switching. Firms graduate to higher reputation underwriters, and they strategically buy additional and influential analyst coverage from the new lead underwriter. Survey results support these conclusions. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Krigman, L.; Shaw, W. H.; Womack, K. L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where do merger gains come from? Bank mergers from the perspective of insiders and outsiders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Houston, J. F.; James, C. M.; Ryngaert, M. D.
Traditional studies fail to find conclusive evidence that bank mergers create value. We analyze a sample of the largest bank mergers between 1985 and 1996. For a subset of this sample, we obtain management estimates of projected cost savings and revenue enhancements. We find that recent mergers appear to result in positive revaluations of the combined value of bidder and target stocks. Although not as large as the present value of management's estimates, with the bulk of the revaluation being attributable to estimated cost savings rather than projected revenue enhancements. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Houston, J. F.; James, C. M.; Ryngaert, M. D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market reaction to public information: The atypical case of the Boston Celtics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, G. W.; Hartzell, J. C.
The publicly traded Boston Celtics Limited Partnership shares provide a unique means of studying the impact of information on equity prices. The results of the Celtics' basketball games significantly affect partnership share returns, trading volume, and volatility. Controlling for the expected value of the signal using betting-market point spreads has little effect on these relations. Investors respond asymmetrically to wins and losses, and playoff games have a larger impact on returns than regular-season games. Opening prices do not fully reflect game results, consistent with previous findings that significant volatility is caused by traders acting on private information. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, G. W.; Hartzell, J. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of litigation participation securities: the case of CalFed Bancorp</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Esty, B. C.
CalFed Bancorp is one of 126 S&amp;Ls suing the U.S. government for breach of contract related to supervisory goodwill, a form of goodwill created by the acquisition of insolvent thrifts during the early 1980s. Before a determination of damages in its lawsuit, CalFed announced and issued a litigation participation security giving shareholders a proportional claim on recovered damages, if any. This announcement generated a positive excess return in part because it made CalFed a more likely acquisition target. Trading in the security also reveals important, yet previously unavailable, information about CalFed's lawsuit: its price reveals a market-based estimate of damages while its beta reveals information regarding expected returns and trial duration. In a broader context, this paper identifies acquisition facilitation as a benefit of issuing targeted stock and highlights a series of lawsuits that will set important precedents regarding the determination of liability and the estimation of damages in breach of contract cases. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Esty, B. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing foreign exchange risk with derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, G. W.
This study investigates the foreign exchange risk management program of HDG Inc. (pseudonym), a US-based manufacturer of durable equipment. Precise examination of factors affecting why and how the firm manages its foreign exchange exposure are explored through the use of internal firm documents, discussions with managers, and data on 3,110 foreign-exchange derivative transactions. Informational asymmetries, facilitation of internal contracting, and competitive pricing concerns appear to motivate why the firm hedges. How HDG hedges depends on accounting treatment, derivative market liquidity, exchange rate volatility, exposure volatility, and recent hedging outcomes. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, G. W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cephalon, Inc. Taking risk management theory seriously</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chacko, G.; Tufano, P.; Verter, G.
Cephalon Inc., a biotech firm, bought call options on its own stock to meet its conditional cash flow needs. We analyze this decision by using the cash flow hedging concepts of Froot et al., (1993. Journal of Finance 5, 1629-1658). We identify the managerial analyses necessary to apply this theory and discuss managerial considerations absent from the theory. We find that managers consider deadweight costs of risk management, which theory tends to ignore. Theory provides little guidance in how to measure these and other deadweight costs. Finally, uncertainty about the availability of external financing and accounting considerations are critical considerations by managers. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chacko, G.; Tufano, P.; Verter, G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit enhancement through financial engineering: Freeport McMoRan's gold-denominated depositary shares</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chidambaran, N. K.; Fernando, C. S.; Spindt, P. A.
In 1993 and 1994, Freeport McMoRan Copper and Gold issued two series of gold-denominated depositary shares to finance the expansion of its mining capacity in Indonesia. The pricing of these securities reflected their enhanced credit quality, which arose from the positive correlation between the value of the firm and the value of the securities. This feature of the securities effectively bundles a gold hedge with financing. A bundled hedge avoids wealth transfers to senior bondholders, since junior bondholders can effectively net their bond-related claims on the firm against their hedge-related liability to the firm. Such securities cannot be replicated by conventional hedging strategies, and they also mitigate the asset substitution problem. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chidambaran, N. K.; Fernando, C. S.; Spindt, P. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm performance and executive compensation in the savings and loan industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hermalin, B. E.; Wallace, N. E.
This paper offers a new way to estimate the relation between pay and performance. In particular, unlike previous analyses, we account for the heterogeneity that theory tells us should exist across the compensation packages of different firms. Accounting for heterogeneity allows for more efficient estimates of the pay-for-performance relation and provides a means of testing the secondary hypotheses of agency theory. Among our findings are strong evidence of inter-firm heterogeneity in compensation, even within the same industry, the existence of trade-offs in using different performance measures, and insights about the factors that influence compensation packages. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hermalin, B. E.; Wallace, N. E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO compensation and bank mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bliss, R. T.; Rosen, R. J.
Recent bank mergers generally did not improve relative operating performance or produce positive abnormal returns to acquiring bank shareholders. We examine the relationship between mergers and CEO compensation during 1986-1995, a period marked by overcapacity and frequent mergers. We find that mergers have a net positive effect on compensation, mainly via the effect of size on compensation. Compensation generally increases even if mergers cause the acquiring bank's stock price to decline, as is typical after a merger announcement. The form of compensation affects merger decisions, since CEOs with. more stock-based compensation were less likely to make an acquisition. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bliss, R. T.; Rosen, R. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-sellers, fundamental analysis, and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dechow, P. M.; Hutton, A. P.; Meulbroek, L.; Sloan, R. G.
Firms with low ratios of fundamentals (such as earning and book values) to market values are known to have systematically lower future stock returns. We document that short-sellers position themselves in the stock of such firms, and then cover their positions as the ratios mean-revert. We also show that short-sellers refine their trading strategies to minimize transactions costs and maximize their investment returns. Our evidence is consistent with short-sellers using information in these ratios to take positions in stocks with lower expected future returns. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dechow, P. M.; Hutton, A. P.; Meulbroek, L.; Sloan, R. G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The distribution of realized stock return volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, T. G.; Bollerslev, T.; Diebold, F. X.; Ebens, H.
We examine "realized" daily equity return volatilities and correlations obtained from high-frequency intraday transaction prices on individual stocks in the Dow Jones industrial Average. Pie find that the unconditional distributions of realized variances and covariances are highly right-skewed, while the realized logarithmic standard deviations and correlations are approximately Gaussian, as are the distributions of the returns scaled by realized standard deviations. Realized volatilities and correlations show strong temporal dependence and appear to be well described by long-memory processes. Finally, there is strong evidence that realized volatilities and correlations move together in a manner broadly consistent with latent factor structure. (C) 2001 EIsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andersen, T. G.; Bollerslev, T.; Diebold, F. X.; Ebens, H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information production, dilution costs, and optimal security design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fulghieri, P.; Lukin, D.
We investigate the problem of a firm wishing to finance a project by issuing securities under asymmetric information. We find that, when outside investors can produce (noisy) information on the firm's quality, the degree of information asymmetry resulting in equilibrium is endogenous and depends on the information sensitivity of the security issued. Thus, in contrast to the prediction of the pecking order theory (see, e.g. Myers and Majluf, J. Financial Econom. 13 (1984) 187-221) a security with low sensitivity to private information, such as debt, does not always dominate one with high information sensitivity, such as equity. A firm's preference for equity rather than debt depends on the costs of information production, the precision of the information-production technology, and the extent of the information asymmetry. We also study the optimal security design problem and find that, depending on the cost and precision of the information-production technology, risky debt or a composite security with a convex payoff emerges as optimal securities. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fulghieri, P.; Lukin, D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and hedging in incomplete markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carr, P.; Geman, H.; Madan, D. B.
We present a new approach for positioning, pricing, and hedging in incomplete markets that bridges standard arbitrage pricing and expected utility maximization. Our approach for determining whether an investor should undertake a particular position involves specifying a set of probability measures and associated floors which expected payoffs must exceed in order for the investor to consider the hedged and financed investment to be acceptable. By assuming that the liquid assets are priced so that each portfolio of assets has negative expected return under at least one measure, we derive a counterpart to the first fundamental theorem of asset pricing. We also derive a counterpart to the second fundamental theorem, which leads to unique derivative security pricing and hedging even though markets are incomplete. For products that are not spanned by the liquid assets of the economy, we show how our methodology provides more realistic bid-ask spreads. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Carr, P.; Geman, H.; Madan, D. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond calls, credible commitment, and equity dilution: a theoretical and clinical analysis of simultaneous tender and call (STAC) offers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dhillon, U. S.; Noe, T. H.; Ramirez, G. G.
This paper is an exploration of the ability of game theory to explain real-world corporate maneuvering. We explore this issue by investigating bond tender offers accompanied by a threat to call nontendered bonds, so called "Simultaneous Tender and Call" (STAC) offers. We argue that STACs engender a transparent game played by bondholders and shareholders. We model this game and use this model to predict the outcome of STACs. Finally, we investigate the issue of whether this theoretical model explains the outcomes of four actual STAC issues made by James River, May Department Stores, and Houston Lighting &amp; Power Company. Our clinical analysis provides support for the explanatory power of our model. Calibrating the predictions of the model with data from these STACs, we demonstrate a correspondence between theory and actual corporate behavior. As predicted by our model, subgame perfection, or threat credibility, and preplay coordination are central to explaining the outcomes of the STACs. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dhillon, U. S.; Noe, T. H.; Ramirez, G. G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disappearing dividends: changing firm characteristics or lower propensity to pay?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.
The proportion of fir ms paying cash dividends falls from 66.5% in 1978 to 20.8% in 1999, due in part to the changing characteristics of publicly traded firms. Fed by new listings, the population of publicly traded firms tilts increasingly toward small firms with low profitability and strong growth opportunities - characteristics typical of firms that have never paid dividends. More interesting, we also show that regardless of their characteristics, firms have become less likely to pay dividends. This lower propensity to pay is at least as important as changing characteristics in the declining incidence of dividend-paying firms. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate payout policy and managerial stock incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fenn, G. W.; Liang, N.
We examine how corporate payout policy is affected by managerial stock incentives using data on more than 1,100 nonfinancial firms during 1993-97. We find that management stock ownership is associated with higher payouts by firms with potentially the greatest agency problems - those with low management stock ownership and few investment opportunities or high free cash flow. We also find that management stock options are related to the composition of payouts. We find a strong negative relationship between dividends and management stock options, as predicted by Lambert ct al (1989), acid a positive relationship between repurchases and management stock options. Our results suggest that the growth in stock options may help to explain the rise in repurchases at the expense of dividends. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Fenn, G. W.; Liang, N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictable changes in yields and forward rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Backus, D.; Foresi, S.; Mozumdar, A.; Wu, L. R.
We make two contributions to the study of interest rates, The first is to characterize their dynamics in a new way. We estimate forecasting relations based on one-period changes in forward rates, which are more easily compared than earlier work on yields to the stationary theory of bond pricing, The second is to approximate these dynamics and other salient features of interest rates with an affine model. We show that models with 'negative" factors come closer to accounting for the properties of interest rates, including their dynamics, than multifactor Cox-Ingersoll-Ross models. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. E43, G12.</description><author>Backus, D.; Foresi, S.; Mozumdar, A.; Wu, L. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do investment banks compete in IPOs?: the advent of the "7% plus contract"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hansen, R. S.
The large number of initial public offerings (IPOs) with a 7% spread suggests either that investment bankers collude to profit From 7% IPOs or that the 7% contract is an efficient innovation that better suits the IPO. My tests do not support the collusion theory. Low concentration and ease of entry characterize the IPO market. Moreover, the 7% spread is not abnormally profitable, nor has its use been diminished by public awareness of collusion allegations. In support of the efficient contract theory, banks compete in pricing 7% IPOs on the basis of reputation, I pricing. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G32: G34.</description><author>Hansen, R. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do the individuals closest to internet firms believe they are overvalued?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, P.; Zaman, M.
Two explanations are commonly offered for the large number of recent IPOs by Internet firms. The first argues that Internet firms are trying to grab market share in an industry with large economies of scale. The second argues that Internet firms are rushing to go public when Internet stuck prices are irrationally high. In this paper we examine the actions of those closest to Internet firms - firm managers, underwriters, and venture capitalists - to determine their motives for going public. Numerous strategic alliances and mergers and acquisitions provide strong evidence of a rush to grab market share. Other factors provide only weak evidence that Internet IPOs are attempts to sell overpriced stock. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G13: G32.</description><author>Schultz, P.; Zaman, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common factors in prices, order flows, and liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasbrouck, J.; Seppi, D. J.
How important are cross-stock common factors in the price discovery/liquidity provision process in equity markets? We investigate two aspects of this question for the 30 Dow stocks. First. using principal components and canonical correlation analyses we find that both returns acid order Rows are characterized by common factors. Commonality in the order flows explains roughly two-thirds of the commonality in returns. Second, we examine variation and common covariation in various liquidity proxies and market depth (trade impact) coefficients. Liquidity proxies such as the bid-ask spread and bid-ask quote sizes help explain time variation in trade impacts. The common factors in these liquidity proxies are, however, relatively small. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14.</description><author>Hasbrouck, J.; Seppi, D. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Direct foreign ownership, institutional investors, and firm characteristics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahlquist, M.; Robertsson, G.
In this paper, we characterize foreign ownership using a dataset of ownership and attributes of Swedish firms. The analysis reveals that foreigners show a preference for large firms, firms paying low dividends, and firms with large cash positions on their balance sheets. When we further analyze the preference for large firms, we find that market liquidity and presence in international markets, measured through export sales or listings on other exchanges, seem to characterize foreign holdings better than firm size alone. Foreigners also tend to underweight firms with a dominant owner. Importantly, we demonstrate that most of the features associated with foreign ownership are driven by the fact that foreign investors typically are mutual funds or other institutional investors. Hence. we identify an institutional investor bias rather than a foreign investor bias. Finally, using ownership data on a country level, we conclude that the results are particularly strong among U.S. investors, who comprise the largest institutions among foreign investors. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G1; G15.</description><author>Dahlquist, M.; Robertsson, G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange rate exposure and competition: evidence from the automotive industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williamson, R.
This study examines the effect of real exchange rare changes on multinational firms and incorporates the effect of intra-industry competition on the relation between exchange rates and firm value. To test the relation more effectively, tests are conducted using a sample of automotive firms from the United States and Japan. Consistent with theoretical predictions, there is significant exposure to exchange rate shocks. Moreover, there is evidence of time-variation in exchange rate exposure, which is consistent with changes in the competitive environment within the industry. Finally, evidence is presented that is consistent with foreign sales being a major determinant of exposure and the effectiveness of operational hedging through foreign production. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. F31: G30: G39.</description><author>Williamson, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage and internal capital markets: evidence from leveraged recapitalizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peyer, U. C.; Shivdasani, A.
We study the internal allocation of resources for diversified firms that complete a leveraged recapitalization. Before the recapitalization, internal capital markets allocate investment to high q segments. After the recapitalization, segment investment becomes less sensitive to q and more sensitive to segment cash how. We show that firm value is positively related to investment's sensitivity to segment q and negatively related to investments sensitivity to segment cash fl;ow. Our analysis highlights an indirect cost of debt that has received little attention: pressure to meet interest obligations creates an incentive to emphasize investments that generate high levels of current cash flow. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G31; G32; G34.</description><author>Peyer, U. C.; Shivdasani, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The option to withdraw IPOs during the premarket: empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Busaba, W. Y.; Benveniste, L. M.; Guo, R. J.
American IPOs are priced after a process of bookbuilding, during which issuers can withdraw at any time. We hypothesize that the option to withdraw reduces underpricing by strengthening the issuers' bargaining power with respect to investors. Empirical analysis reveals that underpricing is lower when investor perception of an IPO's likelihood of withdrawal is higher. Withdrawing issuers are neither smaller nor less profitable than issuers completing their IPOs, and engage underwriters that are as reputable as those managing completed offerings. Withdrawal is correlated with leverage, intended use of proceeds, expected issue size, venture backing, revenues, NASDAQ returns, and IPO activity. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Busaba, W. Y.; Benveniste, L. M.; Guo, R. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Locking out rival bidders: The use of lockup options in corporate mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burch, T. R.
Conventional wisdom suggests that lockup options are granted by self-interested target managers to discourage competition and hand-select an acquirer, thus harming target shareholder wealth. Evidence from 2,067 deals announced during 1988-1995 suggests that lockup options inhibit competition, but on average, deals with lockup options have higher target announcement and overall returns and lower bidder announcement returns, even after controlling for shareholder anticipation and other factors. An examination of 100 merger proxies suggests lockup options are no more prevalent in privately negotiated, preemptive deals, and average target returns are higher when such deals include a lockup option. The overall evidence is more consistent with managers using lockup options to enhance bargaining power than with lockup options harming shareholder wealth. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Burch, T. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the choice and replacement of chief financial officers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mian, S.
This paper. provides empirical evidence regarding why firms replace their CFOs. Empirical tests are based on a sample of 2,227 CFO appointments over the 1984-1997 time period. Key findings reported in the paper are: (a) external CFO succession rate is markedly higher than the external CEO succession rate, (b) the incidence of retirement is less common for serving CFOs as compared to the top executive, (c) CFO turnover is preceded by negative excess returns, (d) CFO turnover is preceded by a decline in operating return on assets in the pre-period, (c) announcements of CFO turnover are associated with a significant negative stock price reaction when old CFO quits and firm replaces with an internal appointment, and (f) CFO turnover is preceded by abnormally high CEO turnover. Overall, evidence is consistent with the hypothesis that CFO turnovers ai e disciplinary. Evidence is also consistent with the hypothesis that rapid sales growth accompanied by weak operating performance leads firms to bring in outside talent, (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Mian, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio choice and equity characteristics: characterizing the hedging demands induced by return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lynch, A. W.
This paper examines portfolio allocation across equity portfolios formed on the basis of characteristics like size and book-to-market. In particular, the paper assesses the impact of return predictability on portfolio choice for a multi-period investor with a coefficient of relative risk aversion of 4. Compared to the investor's allocation in her last period, return predictability with dividend yield causes the investor early in life to tilt her risky-asset portfolio away from high book-to-market stocks and away from small stocks. These results are explained using Merton's (Econometrica 41 (1973) 867) characterization of portfolio allocation by a multi-period investor in a continuous time setting. Abnormal returns relative to the investor's optimal early life portfolio are also calculated. These abnormal returns are found to exhibit the same cross-sectional patterns as abnormal returns calculated relative to the market portfolio: higher for small rather than large firms, and higher for high rather than low book-to-market firms. Thus, hedging demand may be a partial explanation for the high expected returns documented for small firms and high book-to-market firms. However, even with this hedging demand, the investor wants to sell short the low book-to market portfolio to hold the high book-to-market portfolio. The utility costs of using a value-weighted equity index or of ignoring predictability are also calculated. An investor using a value-weighted equity index would give up a much larger fraction of her wealth to have access to book-to-market portfolio than size portfolios. Finally, an investor would give up a much larger fraction of her wealth to have access to dividend yield information than term spread information. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Lynch, A. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of professional market timers: daily evidence from executed strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chance, D. M.; Hemler, M. L.
We examine the performance of 30 professional market timers during 1986-1994. Prior studies have analyzed implicit recommendations from mutual fund returns or explicit recommendations from newsletters. We analyze explicit recommendations executed in customer accounts. Using four tests, three benchmark portfolios., and daily data, we find significant unconditional and conditional ability that is robust with respect to transaction costs and survivorship bias. Relative ability persists and varies with the frequency of recommendation changes. When recommendations of successful timers are observed monthly instead or daily, significant ability generally disappears. Hence, the frequency with which recommendations are observed can change inferences regarding ability. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chance, D. M.; Hemler, M. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating the specification errors of asset pricing models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hodrick, R. J.; Zhang, X. Y.
This paper evaluates the specification errors of several empirical asset pricing models that have been developed as potential improvements on the CAPM, We use the methodology of Hansen and Jagannathan (J. Finance 51 (1997) 3). and the test assets are the 25 Fama-French (J. Financial Econom. 52 (1997) 557) equity portfolios sorted on size and book-to-market ratio. and the Treasury bill. We allow the parameters of each model's pricing kernel to fluctuate with the business cycle. While we cannot reject correct pricing for Campbell's (J. Political Econom. 104 (1996) 298) model, stability tests indicate that the parameters may not be stable. A robustness test also indicates that none of the models correctly price returns that are scaled by the term premium. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hodrick, R. J.; Zhang, X. Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extracting factors from heteroskedastic asset returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, C. S.
This paper proposes an alternative to the asymptotic principal components procedure of Connor and Korajczyk (J. Financial Econom. 15 (1986) 373) that is robust to time series heteroskedasticity in the factor model residuals. The new method is simple to use and requires no assumptions stronger than those made by Connor and Korajczyk, It is demonstrated through simulations and analysis of actual stock market data that allowing heteroskedasticity sometimes improves the quality of the extracted factors quite dramatically. Over the period from 1989 to 1993, for example, a single factor extracted using the Connor and Korajczyk method explains only 8.2% of the variation of the CRSP value-weighted index, while the factor extracted allowing heteroskedasticity explains 57.3%. Accounting for heteroskedasticity is also important for tests of the APT, with p-values sometimes depending strongly on the factor extraction method used. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jones, C. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convergence trading with wealth effects: an amplification mechanism in financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xiong, W.
I study convergence traders with logarithmic utility in a continuous-time equilibrium model. In general, convergence traders reduce asset price volatility and provide liquidity by taking risky positions against noise trading. However, when an unfavorable shock causes them to suffer capital losses, thus eroding their risk-bearing capacity, they liquidate their positions. thereby amplifying the original shock. In extreme circumstances, this wealth effect Causes convergence traders to be destabilizing in that they trade in exactly the same direction as noise traders, This situation is consistent with the near-collapse of Long-Term Capital Management in 1998. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xiong, W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An equilibrium model of irreversible investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kogan, L.
This paper presents a general equilibrium model of a two-sector production economy with irreversible real investment. Irreversibility of investment is the most prominent feature of the productive sector. It restricts capital accumulation, affecting firms' investment decisions. which in turn determine properties of asset prices. Thus, this model provides a framework for connecting stock returns to firm characteristics that proxy for real economic activity. The primary focus of this paper is on the analysis of the equilibrium and the effects of irreversibility of investment. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kogan, L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. W.
nan</description><author>Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Throwing away a billion dollars: the cost of suboptimal exercise strategies in the swaptions market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, F. A.; Santa-Clara, P.; Schwartz, E. S.
This paper studies the costs of applying single-factor exercise strategies to American swap options when the term structure is actually driven by multiple factors. Using a multifactor string market model of the term structure, we find that even when single-factor models are recalibrated to match the market at every exercise date, the exercise strategies they imply can be suboptimal. Based on estimates of notional amounts outstanding, the total present value costs of following single-factor strategies could be several billion dollars. These results illustrate the importance of using well-specified term structure models. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Longstaff, F. A.; Santa-Clara, P.; Schwartz, E. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factor dependence of Bermudan swaptions: fact or fiction?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, L.; Andreasen, J.
This paper investigates the effect of interest rate correlation in pricing and exercise of Bermudan swaptions. Investigating both Gaussian Markov models and Libor market models, we find that Bermudan swaption prices change only moderately (and in fact typically decrease slightly) when the number of factors in the underlying interest rate model is increased from one to two. We explain the rationale behind these results, and also demonstrate that exercise information generated within a best-fit one-factor model only leads to insignificant losses when properly applied in a two-factor model. Our results provide support for the standard Wall Street practice of using continuously re-calibrated one-factor models to price Bermudan swaptions, as long as calibration procedures are sufficiently comprehensive. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andersen, L.; Andreasen, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. W.
nan</description><author>Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the determinants of managerial ownership and the link between ownership and performance: comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhou, X. M.
Himmelberg et al. (J. Financial Econom. 53 (1999) 353-384) argue that fixed effects estimators should be used in examination of the relationship between managerial ownership and firm performance. I show that managerial ownership, while substantially different across firms, typically changes slowly from year to year within a company. With rational managers maximising long-term utility, small, one-year changes in ownership are not likely to reflect notable changes in incentives that would lead to substantive within-year changes in performance. By relying on within variation, fixed effects estimators may not detect an effect of ownership on performance even if one exists. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Zhou, X. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Delaware law improve firm value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daines, R.
I present evidence consistent with the theory that Delaware corporate law improves firm value and facilitates the sale of public firms. Using Tobin's Q as an estimate of firm value, I find that Delaware firms are worth significantly more than similar firms incorporated elsewhere. The result is robust to controls for firm size, diversification, profitability, investment opportunity, industry, managerial ownership, and unobservable firm heterogeneity. Delaware firms are also significantly more likely to receive takeover bids and be acquired. Results are robust to controls for endogeneity. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Daines, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Linking pay to performance - compensation proposals in the S&amp;P 500</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morgan, A. G.; Poulsen, A. B.
We study the proposal of manager-sponsored compensation plans linking pay to performance by S&amp;P 500 firms in the 1990s. We examine the market perception of these proposals and the characteristics of the firms that propose them. Shareholders gain at the announcement of the plans, especially when the plans are directed toward the firm's top executives. Proposing firms are those that can most benefit from the plans, given their asset type and agency considerations. Firms with more potential agency costs have the highest vote-for percentages for the plans. However, shareholders are less approving of plans with negative features such as high dilution levels. Our work suggests that stock-based compensation plans are helpful in improving managerial efforts to increase shareholder wealth. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morgan, A. G.; Poulsen, A. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pay for performance? Government regulation and the structure of compensation contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perry, T.; Zenner, M.
In 1992-1993, the SEC required enhanced disclosure on executive compensation and Congress enacted tax legislation limiting the deductibility of non-performance related compensation over one million dollars, i.e. Internal Revenue Code Section 162(m). We examine the effects of these regulatory changes and report small and large by the regulations. We further document that bonus and total compensation payouts are increasingly sensitive to stock returns after 1993, especially for firms with million-dollar pay packages. We also document that, once we control for other factors affecting CEO incentives, the sensitivity of the CEO's wealth to changes in shareholder wealth has increased from 1993 to 1996 for firms with CEOs near or above the million dollar compensation level. Overall, our results suggest that some firms have reduced salaries in response to 162(m). More importantly, the pay for performance sensitivity, measured using total annual compensation and firm-related CEO wealth, has increased for firms likely to be affected by 162(m). (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Perry, T.; Zenner, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankers on boards: monitoring, conflicts of interest, and lender liability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kroszner, R. S.; Strahan, P. E.
We investigate the trade-off between the benefits from bank monitoring when a banker is represented on a firm's board and the costs from two sources: conflicts Of interests between lenders and shareholders, and U.S. legal doctrines that generate lender liability for bankers on boards of firms in financial distress. Consistent with high costs of active involvement, bankers are on boards of large, stable firms with high proportions of collateralizable assets and low reliance on short-term financing. While permitting banks to own equity could mitigate conflicts, the protection of shareholder versus creditor rights could continue to reduce the role of U.S. banks in corporate governance. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science S.A.</description><author>Kroszner, R. S.; Strahan, P. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market for catastrophe risk: a clinical examination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Froot, K. A.
This paper examines the market for catastrophe event risk - i.e., financial claims that are linked to losses associated with natural hazards, such as hurricanes and earthquakes. Risk management theory suggests protection by insurers and other corporations against the largest cat events is most valuable. However, most insurers purchase relatively little cat reinsurance against large events, and premiums are high relative to expected losses. To understand why the theory fails, we examine transactions that look to capital markets, rather than traditional reinsurance markets, for risk-bearing capacity. We develop eight theoretical explanations and find the most compelling to be supply restrictions associated with capital market imperfections and market power exerted by traditional reinsurers. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Froot, K. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparing asset pricing models: an investment perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, L.; Stambaugh, R. F.
We investigate the portfolio choices of mean-variance-optimizing investors who use sample evidence to update prior beliefs centered on either risk-based or characteristic-based pricing models. With dogmatic beliefs in such models and an unconstrained ratio of position size to capital, optimal portfolios can differ across models to economically significant degrees. The differences are substantially reduced by modest uncertainty about the models' pricing abilities. When the ratio of position size to capital is subject to realistic constraints,the differences in portfolios across models become even less important and are nonexistent in some cases. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pastor, L.; Stambaugh, R. F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making markets for structured mortgage derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oldfield, G. S.
This paper distinguishes between securitization, in which simple pass-through instruments are created, and structuring, in which mortgages derivative claims are created. The point is to explain how structuring a transaction brings value to a deal's underwriter. Briefly, an underwriter must defeat arbitrage between pass-throughs and derivatives. The potential for market segmentation and price discrimination by the underwriter is used to analyze the structuring process. In the course of the analysis, the legal rules for trusts, the algebraic rules for structuring, and the limits on permissible price discrimination are discussed. Results for an actual transaction illustrate the important features of the analysis. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G24; G14; G21.</description><author>Oldfield, G. S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity, investment ability, and mutual fund structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nanda, V.; Narayanan, M. P.; Warther, V. A.
We develop a model of the mutual fund industry in which the management fees and loads charged by actively managed open-end funds and average fund returns are determined endogenously in a competitive market setting. It is shown that heterogeneity in managerial skills at investing and minimizing costs, and the existence of investor clienteles with differing liquidity and marketing needs, gives rise to a variety of open-end fund structures that differ in the average return delivered to investors. Managers choose a fund's structure to maximize the rents they capture from their ability, taking into account the effect on investor flows. In equilibrium, funds that constrain liquidity withdrawals may have to charge lower fees and share some profits in the form of higher investor returns, when there is relative scarcity of investors with low liquidity needs. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: C23; L14; L22.</description><author>Nanda, V.; Narayanan, M. P.; Warther, V. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cash-flow permanence and information content of dividend increases versus repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guay, W.; Harford, J.
We hypothesize that firms choose dividend increases to distribute relatively permanent cash-flow shocks and repurchases to distribute more transient shocks. As predicted, we find that post-shock cash flows of dividend increasing firms exhibit less reversion to pre-shock levels compared with repurchasing firms. We also examine whether the stock market uses the announcement of the payout method to update its beliefs about the permanence of cash-flow shocks. Controlling for payout size and the market's expectation about the permanence of the cash-flow shock, the stock price reaction to dividend increases is more positive than the reaction to repurchases. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G35; G32.</description><author>Guay, W.; Harford, J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special dividends and the evolution of dividend signaling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, H.; DeAngelo, L.; Skinner, D. J.
This paper documents that (1) special dividends were once commonly paid by NYSE firms, but are now rarely paid; (2) firms typically paid specials almost as predictably as they paid regular dividends; (3) despite the dramatic overall decline in specials, the incidence of very large specials increased in recent years; and (4) special dividends were not displaced by stock repurchases. Most plausibly, small specials disappeared because their predictability made them close substitutes for regular dividend signals, while large specials survived because their sheer size automatically differentiates them from regulars. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G35; D82.</description><author>DeAngelo, H.; DeAngelo, L.; Skinner, D. J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial flexibility and the choice between dividends and stock repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, M.; Stephens, C. P.; Weisbach, M. S.
This paper measures the growth in open market stock repurchases and the manner in which stock repurchases and dividends are used by U.S. corporations. Stock repurchases and dividends are used at different times from one another, by different kinds of firms. Stock repurchases are very pro-cyclical, while dividends increase steadily over time. Dividends are paid by firms with higher "permanent" operating cash flows, while repurchases are used by firms with higher "temporary", non-operating cash hows. Repurchasing firms also have much more volatile cash flows and distributions. Finally, firms repurchase stock following poor stock market performance and increase dividends following good performance. These results are consistent with the view that the flexibility inherent in repurchase programs is one reason why they are sometimes used instead of dividends. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G32; G35.</description><author>Jagannathan, M.; Stephens, C. P.; Weisbach, M. S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value and incentive effects of nontraditional executive stock option plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, S. A.; Tian, Y. S.
We examine the value and incentive effects of six nontraditional executive stock options: premium options, performance-vested options, repriceable options, purchased options, reload options, and indexed options. With reasonable parameter values, four options have lower value than a traditional option when granted, and large differences in value are evident across the types. Holding option value constant, five options create stronger incentives than traditional options to increase stock price, five create stronger incentives to increase risk, and three create stronger incentives to reduce dividend yield. Changing various option-specific parameters can produce large changes in incentive strengths. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: J33; G13.</description><author>Johnson, S. A.; Tian, Y. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indexed executive stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, S. A.; Tian, Y. S.
We design and derive a pricing model for an executive stock option with a strike price indexed to a benchmark and investigate its valuation and incentive implications. In both up and down markets, the indexed option filters out common risks beyond the executive's control, thereby increasing the efficiency of incentive contracts, The indexed option has a different payoff structure and much lower initial value than a traditional option. Incentive effects of the indexed option also differ from those of traditional options. We design an optional penalty function to reduce the payoff if executives manipulate specified model parameters such as volatility. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: J33; G13.</description><author>Johnson, S. A.; Tian, Y. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the optimality of resetting executive stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, V. V.; John, K.; Sundaram, R. K.
The practice of resetting strike prices on underwater executive stock options has drawn criticism for weakening managerial incentives. Our model shows that although the anticipation of resetting can negatively affect initial incentives, resetting can still be an important, value-enhancing aspect of compensation contracts, even from an ex-ante standpoint. In fact, we find that some resetting is almost always optimal. The relative advantages of resetting diminish with greater ability of managers to influence the resetting process, greater relative importance of external factors on stock performance, and lower costs of replacing incumbent managers. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G32; J33; L14.</description><author>Acharya, V. V.; John, K.; Sundaram, R. K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Altering the terms of executive stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brenner, M.; Sundaram, R. K.; Yermack, D.
We examine the practice of resetting the terms of previously-issued executive stock options. We identify properties of reset options, develop a model for valuing resettable options, and characterize the firms that have reset options. We find the vast majority of options are reset at-the-money, resulting, on average, in the strike price dropping 40%, Our valuation model suggests that resetting has only a small impact on the ex-ante value of an option award, but the ex-post gain can be substantial. Finally, we find resetting has a strong negative relation with firm performance even after correcting for industry performance. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G12; G13; G32.</description><author>Brenner, M.; Sundaram, R. K.; Yermack, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The 'repricing' of executive stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chance, D. M.; Kumar, R.; Todd, R. B.
We examine a sample of firms that reset the exercise prices on their executive options. These repricings follow a period of about one year of poor firm-specific performance in which the average firm loses one-fourth of its value. No other offsetting changes to option terms or compensation are made, and many firms reprice more than once. Without repricing, a majority of the options would have been at-the-money within two years. We find that when faced with circumstances in which repricing might be chosen, firms with greater agency problems, smaller size, and insider- dominated boards are more likely to reprice. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G30; G32; J33.</description><author>Chance, D. M.; Kumar, R.; Todd, R. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alternative flotation methods, adverse selection, and ownership structure: evidence from seasoned equity issuance in the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Slovin, M. B.; Sushka, M. E.; Lai, K. W. L.
We examine valuation effects of announcements of seasoned equity issuance and assess the impact of the choice of flotation method in the U.K. Rights offerings are predominant, but in 1986, British firms gained the flexibility to conduct placings, which are comparable to U.S, firm commitment offerings. A placing is a fixed-price bought deal that increases ownership dispersion. Placings generate significantly positive share price effects, whereas rights offerings have large negative valuation effects that become more adverse after 1985. We conclude that the option to conduct placings enhances the ability of firms to signal their quality and to use a seasoned equity offering to reduce ownership concentration. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G24; G32; G15.</description><author>Slovin, M. B.; Sushka, M. E.; Lai, K. W. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate policies restricting trading by insiders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bettis, J. C.; Coles, J. L.; Lemmon, M. L.
This paper examines policies and procedures put in place by corporations to regulate trading in the stock by the firm's own insiders. Over 92% of our sample companies have their own policies restricting trading by insiders, and 78% have explicit blackout periods during which the company prohibits trading by its insiders. Our data indicate that blackout periods successfully suppress trading, both purchases and sales, by insiders, and that the blackout period is associated with a bid-ask spread that's narrower by about two basis points. Consistent with this effect on the spread, allowed insider trades are modestly more profitable than insider trades made during prohibited blackout periods. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14; G18; C38; K22; L22.</description><author>Bettis, J. C.; Coles, J. L.; Lemmon, M. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can book-to-market, size and momentum be risk factors that predict economic growth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liew, J.; Vassalou, M.
We test whether the profitability of HML, SMB, and WML can be linked to future Gross Domestic Product (GDP) growth. Using data from ten countries, we find that HML and SMB contain significant information about future GDP growth. This information is to a large degree independent of that in the market factor. Even in the presence of popular business cycle variables, HML and SMB retain their ability to predict future economic growth in some countries. Our results support a risk-based explanation for the performance of HML and SMB. Little evidence is found to support such an explanation in the case of WML. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G11; G12; G15.</description><author>Liew, J.; Vassalou, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade size, order imbalance, and the volatility-volume relation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, K.; Fong, W. M.
This paper examines the roles of the number of trades, size of trades, and order imbalance (buyer- versus seller-initiated trades) in explaining the volatility-volume relation for a sample of NYSE and Nasdaq stocks. Our results reconfirm the significance of the size of trades, beyond that of the number of trades, in the volatility-volume relation on both markets. After controlling for the return impact of order imbalance, the volatility-volume relation becomes much weaker. For NYSE stocks, the order imbalance in large trade size categories affects the return more than in smaller size categories. For Nasdaq stocks, the largest return impact comes from the order imbalance in maximum-sized Small Order Execution System (SOES) trades. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G10; G12; G13.</description><author>Chan, K.; Fong, W. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance proposals and shareholder activism: the role of institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gillan, S. L.; Starks, L. T.
We study shareholder proposals across a period of substantial activity and find systematic differences both across sponsor identity and across time. To measure the success of shareholder activism, we examine voting outcomes and short-term market reactions conditioned on proposal type and sponsor identity. The voting analysis documents that sponsor identity, issue type, prior performance and time period are important influences on the voting outcome. Proposals sponsored by institutions or coordinated groups appear to act as substitutes gaining substantially more support than proposals sponsored by individuals. The nature of the stock market reaction, while typically small, varies according to the issue and the sponsor identity. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G34.</description><author>Gillan, S. L.; Starks, L. T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy auctions: costs, debt recovery, and firm survival</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thorburn, K. S.
This paper provides some first, large-sample evidence on the Swedish auction bankruptcy system. Compared to U.S. Chapter 11 cases, the small-firm bankruptcy auctions examined here are substantially quicker, have lower costs, and avoid deviations from absolute priority. Three-quarters of the firms are auctioned as going concerns, which is similar to Chapter 11 survival rates. Moreover, based on market values, creditors in going-concern auctions recover a similar fraction of face value as creditors of much larger firms in Chapter 11 reorganizations. The evidence presented here suggests that the auction bankruptcy system is a surprisingly efficient restructuring mechanism for small firms. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G33; G34; K22.</description><author>Thorburn, K. S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Herding among security analysts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Welch, I.
The paper shows that the buy or sell recommendations of security analysts have a significant positive influence on the recommendations of the next two analysts. This influence can be traced to short-lived information in the most recent revisions. In contrast, the influence of the prevailing consensus is not stronger if the consensus accurately forecasts subsequent stock price movements. This indicates consensus herding consistent with models in which analysts herd based on little information. The consensus also has a stronger influence when market conditions are favorable. The resulting poorer information aggregation could cause bull markets to be intrinsically more "fragile" (e.g., Bikhchandani et al., J. Political Economy 100(5) (1992) 992-1026). (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G11; G14; G24.</description><author>Welch, I.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of very short-term rates: New evidence for the expectations hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, F. A.
Empirical researchers have frequently rejected the expectations hypothesis. The expectations hypothesis, however, has seldom, if ever, been tested at the extreme short end of the term structure where maturities are measured in days or weeks. Using overnight, weekly, and monthly ripe rates, I find that term rates are almost unbiased estimates of the average overnight rate. This evidence provides new support for the expectations hypothesis. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: E43.</description><author>Longstaff, F. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing static tradeoff against pecking order models of capital structure: a critical comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chirinko, R. S.; Singha, A. R.
In a recent paper? Shyam-Sunder and Myers (1999) introduce a new test of the Pecking Order Model. This comment shows that their elegantly simple test generates misleading inferences when evaluating plausible patterns of external financing. Our results, coupled with the power problem with the Static Tradeoff Model documented by Shyam-Sunder and Myers, indicate that their empirical evidence can evaluate neither the Pecking Order nor Static Tradeoff Models. Alternative tests are needed that can identify the determinants of capital structure and can discriminate among competing hypotheses. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G32.</description><author>Chirinko, R. S.; Singha, A. R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection and corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>La Porta, R.; Lopez-De-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A.; Vishny, R.
Recent research has documented large differences among countries in ownership concentration in publicly traded firms, in the breadth and depth of capital markets, in dividend policies, and in the access of firms to external finance. A common element to the explanations of these differences is how well investors, both shareholders and creditors, are protected by law from expropriation by the managers and controlling shareholders of firms. We describe the differences in laws and the effectiveness of their enforcement across countries, discuss the possible origins of these differences, summarize their consequences, and assess potential strategies of corporate governance reform. We argue that the legal approach is a more fruitful way to understand corporate governance and its reform than the conventional distinction between bank-centered and market-centered financial systems. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; G28; G32.</description><author>La Porta, R.; Lopez-De-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A.; Vishny, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special issue on international corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwert, G. W.
nan</description><author>Schwert, G. W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Universal banking and the performance of German firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, G.; Schmid, F. A.
We empirically investigate the influence of German universal banks on the performance of German firms. We take into account banks' control rights from equity ownership, banks' proxy-voting rights, and the concentration of control rights from equity ownership (which includes complex forms such as pyramids, cross-shareholdings, and stocks with multiple votes). We also account for voting restrictions and the German codetermination system (under which employees of large firms have control rights that are unrelated to equity ownership). We find that firm performance improves to the extent that equity control rights are concentrated. Moreover, bank control rights from equity ownership significantly improve firm performance beyond what nonbank blockholders can achieve. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gorton, G.; Schmid, F. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The separation of ownership and control in East Asian Corporations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claessens, S.; Djankov, S.; Lang, L. H. P.
We examine the separation of ownership and control for 2,980 corporations in nine East Asian countries. In all countries, voting rights frequently exceed cash-flow rights via pyramid structures and cross-holdings. The separation of ownership and control is most pronounced among family-controlled firms and small firms. More than two-thirds of firms are controlled by a single shareholder. Managers of closely held firms tend to be relatives of the controlling shareholder's family. Older firms are generally family-controlled, dispelling the notion that ownership becomes dispersed over time. Finally, significant corporate wealth in East Asia is concentrated among a few families. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G32; L22.</description><author>Claessens, S.; Djankov, S.; Lang, L. H. P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The balance of power in closely held corporations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennedsen, M.; Wolfenzon, D.
We analyze a closely held corporation characterized by the absence of a resale market for its shares. We show that the founder of the firm can optimally choose an ownership structure with several large shareholders to force them to form coalitions to obtain control. By grouping member cash flows, a coalition internalizes to a larger extent the consequences of its actions and hence takes more efficient actions than would any of its individual members. The model has implications for the optimal bundling of cash flow and voting rights, and for the optimal number and size of shareholders. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G32; G34.</description><author>Bennedsen, M.; Wolfenzon, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance in the Asian financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, S.; Boone, P.; Breach, A.; Friedman, E.
The "Asian Crisis" of 1997-98 affected all the "emerging markets" open to capital flows. Measures of corporate governance, particularly the effectiveness of protection for minority shareholders, explain the extent of exchange rate depreciation and stock market decline better than do standard macroeconomic measures. A possible explanation is that in countries with weak corporate governance, worse economic prospects result in more expropriation by managers and thus a larger fall in asset prices. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G18; G38; K22.</description><author>Johnson, S.; Boone, P.; Breach, A.; Friedman, E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial markets and the allocation of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wurgler, J.
Financial markets appear to improve the allocation of capital. Across 65 countries, those with developed financial sectors increase investment more in their growing industries, and decrease investment more in their declining industries, than those with undeveloped financial sectors. The efficiency of capital allocation is negatively correlated with the extent of state ownership in the economy, positively correlated with the amount of firm-specific information in domestic stock returns, and positively correlated with the legal protection of minority investors. In particular, strong minority investor rights appear to curb overinvestment in declining industries. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G15; G31; D92.</description><author>Wurgler, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of stock markets: why do emerging markets have synchronous stock price movements?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morck, R.; Yeung, B.; Yu, W.
Stock prices move together more in poor economies than in rich economies. This finding is not due to market size and is only partially explained by higher fundamentals correlation in low-income economies. However, measures of property rights do explain this difference. The systematic component of returns variation is large in emerging markets, and appears unrelated to fundamentals co-movement, consistent with noise trader risk. Among developed economy stock markets, higher firm-specific returns variation is associated with stronger public investor property rights. We propose that strong property rights promote informed arbitrage, which capitalizes detailed firm-specific information. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G12; G14: G15; G38; N20.</description><author>Morck, R.; Yeung, B.; Yu, W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and the sources of growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, T.; Levine, R.; Loayza, N.
This paper evaluates the empirical relation between the level of financial intermediary development and (i) economic growth, (ii) total Factor productivity growth, (iii) physical capital accumulation, and (iv) private savings rates. We use (a) a pure cross-country instrumental variable estimator to extract the exogenous component of financial intermediary development, and (b) a new panel technique that controls for biases associated with simultaneity and unobserved country-specific effects. After controlling for these potential biases, we End that(1) financial intermediaries exert a large, positive impact on total factor productivity growth, which feeds through to overall GDP growth and (2) the long-run links between financial intermediary development and both physical capital growth and private savings rates are tenuous. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; O16; O40.</description><author>Beck, T.; Levine, R.; Loayza, N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do stock market liberalizations cause investment booms?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henry, P. B.
Stock market liberalizations lead private investment booms. In a sample of Il developing countries that liberalized their stock markets, 9 experience growth rates of private investment above their non-liberalization median in the first year after liberalizing. In the second and third years after liberalization, this number is 10 of 11 and 8 of 11, respectively. The mean growth rate of private investment in the three years immediately following stock market liberalization exceeds the sample mean by 22 percentage points. The evidence stands in sharp contrast to recent work that suggests capital account liberalization has no effect on investment. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: F3; F4; G15.</description><author>Henry, P. B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>DOS Kapital: Has antitrust action against Microsoft created value in the computer industry?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bittlingmayer, G.; Hazlett, T. W.
Antitrust enforcement that efficiently constrains Microsoft's behavior benefits firms supplying complements to and/or substitutes for Microsoft's operating system and applications software. However, from 1991 through 1997, 29 reports of federal antitrust enforcement action against Microsoft were accompanied by declines in the value of an index of 159 computer industry firms (excluding Microsoft). The mean loss to those firms exceeded $1 billion per event, Eight retreats or setbacks in enforcement were associated with increased computer sector value. Thus, financial markets reveal compelling evidence against the joint hypothesis that (a) Microsoft conduct is anticompetitive and (b) antitrust policy enforcement produces net efficiency gains. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G1; K2; L1; L4; L5.</description><author>Bittlingmayer, G.; Hazlett, T. W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uniformly least powerful tests of market efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loughran, T.; Ritter, J. R.
Defenders of market efficiency argue that anomalies involving long-term abnormal returns are not robust to alternative methodologies. We argue that because various methodologies use different weighting schemes, the magnitude of abnormal returns should differ, and in a predictable manner. Three problems are identified that cause low power in value-weighted three-factor time series regressions when abnormal returns following managerial actions are being estimated. We illustrate the sensitivities in the context of the new issues puzzle as well as with simulations. More generally, multifactor models as currently used do not, and cannot, test market efficiency. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G12; G14.</description><author>Loughran, T.; Ritter, J. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial discipline and corporate restructuring following performance declines</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, D. J.; Kruse, T. A.
We examine the incidence of disciplinary events that reduce the control of current managers, and corporate restructuring among firms experiencing a large decline in operating performance during an active takeover period (1985-1988) and a less active period (1989-1992). We document a significant decline in the disciplinary events from the active to the less active period that is driven by a significant decline in disciplinary takeovers, those takeovers that result in a top executive change. Following the performance decline, however, there is a substantial amount of corporate restructuring, and a significant improvement in operating performance, during both the active and the less active takeover period. We conclude that, although some managerial disciplinary events are related to overall takeover activity, the decline in takeover activity does not result in fewer performance-enhancing restructurings following performance declines. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G32; G34.</description><author>Denis, D. J.; Kruse, T. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can transparent markets survive?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloomfield, R.; O'Hara, M.
This paper investigates whether transparent markets can survive when faced with direct competition from less transparent markets. We first construct a game-theoretic model in which in equilibrium the low-transparency dealers capture early order flow, and use the resulting informational advantage to quote narrower spreads and earn more profits than their more transparent competitors. We then conduct a laboratory experiment that tests and supports all of these predictions. A second experiment shows that most dealers choose to be of lower transparency when they are allowed to do so. However, the informational advantage of low-transparency decreases as there are more such dealers, while the high-transparency dealers gel increasing benefit from informed traders who attempt to broadcast deceptive trades. As a result, a small number of transparent dealers persist in our markets. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14; G12; D82.</description><author>Bloomfield, R.; O'Hara, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factors affecting investment bank initial public offering market share</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dunbar, C. G.
This paper examines the effect of several factors on the market share of investment banks that act as book managers in initial public offerings (IPOs) between 1984 and 1995. For established banks, IPO first-day returns, one-year abnormal performance, abnormal compensation, industry specialization, analyst reputation, and association with withdrawn offers have a significant impact on changes in market share. These factors have a more significant effect on market share changes in low-volume IPO markets. These factors have a less significant effect on market share, statistically and economically, for less established banks, consistent with the notion that less reputation is placed at risk. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G24; C21.</description><author>Dunbar, C. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The investment behavior and performance of various investor types: a study of Finland's unique data set</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, M.; Keloharju, M.
Using data from Finland, this study analyzes the extent to which past returns determine the propensity to buy and sell. It also analyzes whether these differences in past-return-based behavior and differences in investor sophistication drive the performance of various investor types. We find that foreign investors tend to be momentum investors, buying past winning stocks and selling past losers. Domestic investors, particularly households, tend to be contrarians. The distinctions in behavior are consistent across a variety of past-return intervals. The portfolios of foreign investors seem to outperform the portfolios of households, even after controlling for behavior differences. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G10.</description><author>Grinblatt, M.; Keloharju, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When an event is not an event: the curious case of an emerging market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, U.; Daouk, H.; Jorgenson, B.; Kehr, C. H.
Shares trading in the Bolsa Mexicana de Valores do not seem to react to company news. Using a sample of Mexican corporate news announcements from the period July 1994 through June 1997, this paper finds that there is nothing unusual about returns, volatility of returns, volume of trade or bid-ask spreads in the event window. We provide evidence that suggests that unrestricted insider trading causes prices to fully incorporate the information before its public release. The paper thus points toward a methodology for ranking emerging stock markets in terms of their market integrity, an approach that can be used with the limited data available in such markets. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14: G15.</description><author>Bhattacharya, U.; Daouk, H.; Jorgenson, B.; Kehr, C. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value creation and corporate diversification: the case of Sears, Roebuck &amp; Co.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gillan, S. L.; Kensinger, J. W.; Martin, J. D.
We provide clinical evidence of corporate restructuring at Sears, Roebuck &amp; Co., beginning with the firm's 1981 diversification into financial services by acquiring Cold dwell, Banker &amp; Co. and Dean Witter, Reynolds Inc. The initial purchases resulted in a wealth gain to shareholders of approximately $400 million. Anticipated synergies did not materialize, however, and Sears' retail performance deteriorated. Coincident with pressure from institutional investor activists in 1992, Sears announced the divestiture of financial services and a refocusing on retail operations. This led to a $1.113 billion gain for shareholders. Despite more than $1.5 billion in gains over the entire diversification/divestiture period, Sears' shareholders suffered a significant opportunity loss when compared with a portfolio of focused firms. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G32; G34.</description><author>Gillan, S. L.; Kensinger, J. W.; Martin, J. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Abnormal returns to rivals of acquisition targets: A test of the 'acquisition probability hypothesis'</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, M. H.; Walkling, R. A.
We develop and test the Acquisition Pvobability Hypothesis, which asserts that rivals of initial acquisition targets earn abnormal returns because of the increased probability that they will be targets themselves. On average, rival firms earn positive abnormal returns regardless of the form and outcome of acquisition. These returns increase significantly with the magnitude of surprise about the initial acquisition, Moreover, the cross-sectional variation of rival abnormal returns in the announcement period is systematically related to variables associated with the probability of acquisition. In addition, rivals that subsequently become targets earn significantly higher abnormal returns in the announcement period. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S,A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G34; G14; G38; K21: G32.</description><author>Song, M. H.; Walkling, R. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When is time continuous?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertsimas, D.; Kogan, L.; Lo, A. W.
Continuous-time stochastic processes are approximations to physically realizable phenomena. We quantify one aspect of the approximation errors by characterizing the asymptotic distribution of the replication errors that arise from delta-hedging derivative securities in discrete time, and introducing the notion of temporal granularity which measures the extent to which discrete-time implementations of continuous-time models can track the payoff of a derivative security. We show that granularity is a particular function of a derivative contract's terms and the parameters of the underlying stochastic process. Explicit expressions for the granularity of geometric Brownian motion and an Ornstein-Uhlenbeck process for call and put options are derived, and we perform Monte Carlo simulations to illustrate the empirical properties of granularity. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G13.</description><author>Bertsimas, D.; Kogan, L.; Lo, A. W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spanning and derivative-security valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, G.; Madan, D.
This article provides the economic foundations for valuing derivative securities. In particular, it establishes how the characteristic function (of the future uncertainty) is basis augmenting and spans the payoff universe of most, if not all, derivative assets. From the characteristic function of the state-price density, it is possible to analytically price options on any arbitrary transformation of the underlying uncertainty. By differentiating (or translating) the characteristic function, limitless pricing and/or spanning opportunities can be designed. The strength and versatility of the methodology is inherent when valuing (1) average-interest options, (2) correlation options, and (3) discretely monitored knock-out options. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A, All rights reserved. JEL classification: CIO; G12; G13.</description><author>Bakshi, G.; Madan, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical examination of the convexity bias in the pricing of interest rate swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, A.; Subrahmanyam, M. G.
This paper examines the convexity bias, caused by the non-linearity of payoffs, in the pricing of interest rate swaps off the Eurocurrency futures curve. The evidence from four major currencies - $, pound, DM and Yen - during 1987-1996 suggests that swaps were initially being priced off the futures curve (ignoring the convexity adjustment); subsequently, the market swap rates drifted below the rates implied by futures prices. After rejecting alternative explanations, we use alternative term structure models to show that the convexity bias is related to the empirically observed swap-futures differential. We interpret these results as evidence of mispricing of swap contracts during the early years, which was eliminated over time. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G13; G14.</description><author>Gupta, A.; Subrahmanyam, M. G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money chasing deals? The impact of fund inflows on private equity valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gompers, P.; Lerner, J.
We show that inflows of capital into venture funds increase the valuation of these funds' new investments. This effect is robust to (i) controlling for firm characteristics and public market valuations, (ii) examining first differences, and (iii) using inflows into leveraged buyout funds as an instrumental variable. Interaction terms suggest that the impact of venture capital inflows on prices is greatest in states with the most venture capital activity. Changes in valuations do not appear related to the ultimate success of these firms. The findings are consistent with competition for a limited number of attractive investments being responsible for rising prices. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A, All rights reserved, JEL classification. G24; G12.</description><author>Gompers, P.; Lerner, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speed of issuance and the adequacy of disclosure in the 144A high-yield debt market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fenn, G. W.
I document the shift of high-yield issuance from the public to the Rule 144A private placement market and exploit data on credit spreads to investigate whether investors regard disclosure in the two markets as comparable. The key implications of the inadequate-disclosure hypothesis are that investors require premiums on 144A securities and that such premiums are largest for first-time bond issuers and privately owned firms about whom less information is publicly available. I find that 144A premiums, though positive initially, have vanished over time, and I find no evidence of larger 144A premiums for first-time issuers or private firms. Investors do, however, require premiums of first-time issuers, and to a lesser extent of privately owned firms, regardless of whether securities are issued in the 144A or public market. These findings imply that sophisticated investors do not value the incremental information provided by securities registration, but do value ongoing disclosure. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fenn, G. W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why firms issue targeted stock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Souza, J.; Jacob, J.
We analyze market reaction to targeted stock issuances and investigate possible motives for their use. We find a statistically significant abnormal return of 3.61% within a three-day window around the announcement of proposed targeted stock issuances, possibly attributable to greater information on targeted stock segments as well as monitoring and motivational advantages. We find lower tax-loss carry forwards among firms that issue targeted stock compared to those that spin off segments, suggesting that tax reasons motivate targeted stock use, The return and cash flows of targeted stocks are affected more by their common corporate affiliation, although industry influences remain strong. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>D'Souza, J.; Jacob, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From cradle to grave: How to loot a 401(k) plan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stanton, R.
The regulations governing asset distributions from many retirement plans give participants the option to time retirement or rollovers from the plan strategically. They possess a long-lived put option, whose exercise price resets periodically to the current value of the assets in the plan. I derive a recursive closed-form valuation formula for the option and develop a numerical algorithm for implementing the result. I find that, for reasonable assumptions about volatility and life expectancy, the option's value may approach 40% of the value of the assets in the plan, financed entirely by those still contributing. This wealth transfer can, however, be easily avoided by making a simple change to the current regulations governing valuation and payout of these retirement plans. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stanton, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A study towards a unified approach to the joint estimation of objective and risk neutral measures for the purpose of options valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernov, M.; Ghysels, E.
The purpose of this paper is to bridge two strands of the literature, one pertaining to the objective or physical measure used to model an underlying asset and the other pertaining to the risk-neutral measure used to price derivatives. We propose a generic procedure using simultaneously the fundamental price, S-t, and a set of option contracts [(sigma(it)(I))(i=1,m)] where m greater than or equal to 1 and sigma(it)(I) is the Black-Scholes implied volatility. We use Heston's (1993. Review of Financial Studies 6, 327-343) model as an example, and appraise univariate and multivariate estimation of the model in terms of pricing and hedging performance. Our results, based on the S&amp;P 500 index contract, show dominance of univariate approach, which relies solely on options data. A by-product of this finding is that we uncover a remarkably simple volatility extraction filter based on a polynomial lag structure of implied volatilities. The bivariate approach, involving both the fundamental security and an option contract, appears useful when the information from the cash market reflected in the conditional kurtosis provides support to price long term. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chernov, M.; Ghysels, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commonality in liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, T.; Roll, R.; Subrahmanyam, A.
Traditionally and understandably, the microscope of market microstructure has focused on attributes of single assets. Little theoretical attention and virtually no empirical work has been devoted to common determinants of liquidity nor to their empirical manifestation, correlated movements in liquidity. But a wider-angle lens exposes an imposing image of commonality. Quoted spreads, quoted depth, and effective spreads co-move with market- and industry-wide liquidity. After controlling for well-known individual liquidity determinants, such as volatility, volume, and price, common influences remain significant and material. Recognizing the existence of commonality is a key to uncovering some suggestive evidence that inventory risks and asymmetric information both affect intertemporal changes in liquidity. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G23; D82.</description><author>Chordia, T.; Roll, R.; Subrahmanyam, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Just another day in the inter-bank foreign exchange market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakrabarti, R.
In this paper, I develop a theory of bid-ask quotes provided by foreign exchange dealers in the inter-bank market based on their beliefs and their inventory positions. I then build an agent-based model of the inter-dealer market where dealers learn in a Bayesian manner from quotes from other dealers. Using simulations, I find that the resulting intra-day spreads and between-quote returns largely conform to the empirically observed intra-day U-shaped pattern - a feature that has not been satisfactorily explained in the literature. I also study the factors that determine this U-shape. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: D83; F31.</description><author>Chakrabarti, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The costs and determinants of order aggressiveness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffiths, M. D.; Smith, B. F.; Turnbull, D. A. S.; White, R. W.
This paper examines the costs and determinants of order aggressiveness. Aggressive orders have larger price impacts but smaller opportunity costs than passive orders. Price impacts are amplified by large orders, small firms, and volatile stock prices. To minimize the implementation shortfall, the optimal strategy is to enter buy (sell) orders at the bid task). Aggressive buy (sell) orders tend to follow other aggressive buy (sell) orders and occur when bid-ask spreads are narrow and depth on the same (opposite) side of the limit book is large (small). Aggressive buys are more likely than sells to be motivated by information. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved, JEL classification: G15; G24.</description><author>Griffiths, M. D.; Smith, B. F.; Turnbull, D. A. S.; White, R. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relative pricing of US Treasury STRIPS: empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jordan, B. D.; Jorgensen, R. D.; Kuipers, D. R.
We investigate pricing relations and the potential for arbitrage in the U.S. Treasury STRIPS market, stressing the importance of reconciling quoted Treasury data with actual market pricing conventions. We document that stripping and reconstitution profits in the STRIPS market are fleeting and rarely economically significant; that matched-maturity principal and coupon STRIPS generally have different prices due, at least in part, to richness or cheapness in the underlying note or bond; and that apparent negative forward rates in the STRIPS market are concentrated in certain long-maturity STRIPS that do not actually exist at the time. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G12; G13.</description><author>Jordan, B. D.; Jorgensen, R. D.; Kuipers, D. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Eighths, sixteenths, and market depth: changes in tick size and liquidity provision on the NYSE</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, M. A.; Kavajecz, K. A.
Using limit order data provided by the NYSE, we investigate the impact of reducing the minimum tick size on the liquidity of the market. While both spreads and depths (quoted and on the limit order book) declined after the NYSE's change from eighths to sixteenths, depth declined throughout the entire limit order book as well. The combined effect of smaller spreads and reduced cumulative limit order book depth has made liquidity demanders trading small orders better off; however, traders who submitted larger orders in lower volume stocks did not benefit, especially if those stocks were low priced. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14.</description><author>Goldstein, M. A.; Kavajecz, K. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Controlling stockholders and the disciplinary role of corporate payout policy: a study of the Times Mirror Company</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, H.; DeAngelo, L.
The Times Mirror Company, a NYSE-listed Fortune 500 firm controlled for 100 years by the Chandler family, hired an industry outsider as CEO in 1995 following an extended period of poor operating and stock price performance under non-family management. This change was apparently an unintended consequence of actions taken by old management to fund its capital expansion plans while satisfying the family's desire for dividends. Specifically, in 1994 old management agreed to (1) sell TM's cable business and reinvest most of the $1.3 billion proceeds in new technology, and (2) maintain the Chandlers' dividends while radically cutting those to minority stockholders. While Wall Street reacted favorably to the cable sale, it punished TM's stock when it later learned about management's reinvestment plans. Shortly thereafter TM's board brought in a noted financial disciplinarian, who as CEO substantially increased stockholder value by terminating low return investments and distributing free cash flow. While pressure to pay dividends and monitoring by large block stockholders ultimately improved TM's performance, the path to this outcome was slow and circuitous, so that these disciplinary forces were weaker than theory typically implies. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G35; G32.</description><author>DeAngelo, H.; DeAngelo, L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the abnormal return following equity issuances anomalous?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, A.; Geczy, C.; Gompers, P. A.
We examine whether a distinct equity issuer underperformance anomaly exists. In a sample of initial public offering (IPO) and seasoned equity offering (SEO) firms from 1975 to 1992, we find that underperformance is concentrated primarily in small issuing firms with low book-to-market ratios. SEO firms, that underperform these standard benchmarks have time series returns that covary with factor returns constructed from nonissuing firms. We conclude that the stock returns following equity issues reflect a more pervasive return pattern in the broader set of publicly traded companies. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G1; G2.</description><author>Brav, A.; Geczy, C.; Gompers, P. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seasoned public offerings: resolution of the 'new issues puzzle'</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckbo, B. E.; Masulis, R. W.; Norli, O.
The 'new issues puzzle' is that stocks of common stock issuers subsequently underperform nonissuers matched on size and book-to-market ratio. With 7000 + seasoned equity and debt issues, we document that issuer underperformance reflects lower systematic risk exposure for issuing firms relative to the matches. A consistent explanation is that, as equity issuers lower leverage, their exposures to unexpected inflation and default risks decrease, thus decreasing their stocks' expected returns relative to matched firms. Equity issues also significantly increase stock liquidity (turnover), again lowering expected returns relative to nonissuers. We conclude that the 'new issue puzzle' is explained by a failure of the matched-firm technique to provide a proper control for risk. This conclusion is robust to issue characteristics and the choice of factor model framework. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A, All rights reserved. JEL classification: G12; G14; G32.</description><author>Eckbo, B. E.; Masulis, R. W.; Norli, O.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment bank market share, contingent fee payments, and the performance of acquiring firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rau, P. R.
This paper investigates the determinants of the market share of investment banks acting as advisors in mergers and tender offers. In both mergers and tender offers, bank market share is positively related to the contingent fee payments charged by the bank and to the percentage of deals completed in the past by the bank. It is unrelated to the performance of the acquirers advised by the bank in the past. In tender offers, the post-acquisition performance of the acquirer is negatively related to the contingent fee payments charged by the bank, suggesting that the contingent fee structure in tender offers ensures that investment banks focus on completing the deal. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G34.</description><author>Rau, P. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>'Time to build, option value and investment decisions': a comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milne, A.; Whalley, A. E.
We correct the analysis of the model of time to build in Majd and Pindyck (1987 Journal of Financial Economics 18, 7-27) for the omission of an essential optimality condition, Our analysis reveals an additional insight: long times to build reduce the effects of increased project value volatility (i,e., higher investment thresholds) in comparison to standard real option models of investment under uncertainty, where investment is instantaneous. Thus, a 'naive' NPV rule can sometimes be an appropriate initial guide to investment. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved. JEL classification: C63; D92.</description><author>Milne, A.; Whalley, A. E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>