<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFQA1</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Why Do Fund Managers Identify and Share Profitable Ideas?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crawford, Steven S.; Gray, Wesley H.; Kern, Andrew F.
We study data from an organization in which fund managers privately share and discuss detailed investment recommendations. Buy recommendations generate positive abnormal returns, and sell recommendations result in negative abnormal returns. In the context of these results, we explore an important economic question: Why do skilled investors share profitable ideas with others? Evidence suggests that the managers in our sample share to receive feedback on their ideas and to attract additional arbitrageur capital to the securities they recommend in order to correct mispricings.</description><author>Crawford, Steven S.; Gray, Wesley H.; Kern, Andrew F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks' Internal Capital Markets and Deposit Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-David, Itzhak; Palvia, Ajay; Spatt, Chester
It is commonly believed that deposit rates are determined primarily by supply: Depositors require higher deposit rates from risky banks, thereby creating market discipline. An alternative perspective is that market discipline is limited (e.g., due to deposit insurance and/or enhanced capital regulation) and that internal demand for funding by banks determines rates. Using branch-level deposit rate data, we find little evidence for market discipline as rates are similar across bank capitalization levels. In contrast, banks' loan growth has a causal effect on deposit rates; for example, branches' deposit rates are correlated with loan growth in other states in which their bank has some presence, suggesting internal capital markets help reallocate the bank's funding.</description><author>Ben-David, Itzhak; Palvia, Ajay; Spatt, Chester</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender and Board Activeness : The Role of a Critical Mass</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwartz-Ziv, Miriam
This study analyzes detailed minutes of board meetings of business companies in which the Israeli government holds a substantial equity interest. Boards with at least 3 directors of each gender are found to be at least 79% more active at board meetings than those without such representation. This phenomenon is driven by women directors in particular; they are more active when a critical mass of at least 3 women is in attendance. Gender-balanced boards are also more likely to replace underperforming chief executive officers (CEOs) and are particularly active during periods when CEOs are being replaced.</description><author>Schwartz-Ziv, Miriam</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Turnover-Performance Sensitivity in Private Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Huasheng; Harford, Jarrad; Li, Kai
We compare chief executive officer (CEO) turnover in public and large private firms. Public firms have higher turnover rates and exhibit greater turnover-performance sensitivity (TPS) than private firms. When we control for pre-turnover performance, performance improvements are greater for private firms than for public firms. We investigate whether these differences are due to differences in quality of accounting information, the CEO candidate pool, CEO power, board structure, ownership structure, investor horizon, or certain unobservable differences between public and private firms. One factor contributing to public firms' higher turnover rates and greater TPS appears to be investor myopia.</description><author>Gao, Huasheng; Harford, Jarrad; Li, Kai</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Screens and Systematic Investor Boycott Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luo, H. Arthur; Balvers, Ronald J.
We model the pricing implications of screens adopted by socially responsible investors. The model reproduces the empirically observed abnormal return to sin stock and implies a premium for systematic investor boycott risk that affects targeted as well as nontargeted firms. The investor boycott premium is not displaced by litigation risk, measures of neglect effect, illiquidity, industry momentum, or concentration. The investor boycott risk factor is useful in explaining mean returns across industries, and its premium varies with the relative wealth of socially responsible investors and the business cycle.</description><author>Luo, H. Arthur; Balvers, Ronald J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model Uncertainty and Exchange Rate Forecasting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kouwenberg, Roy; Markiewicz, Agnieszka; Verhoeks, Ralph; Zwinkels, Remco C. J.
Exchange rate models with uncertain and incomplete information predict that investors focus on a small set of fundamentals that changes frequently over time. We design a model selection rule that captures the current set of fundamentals that best predicts the exchange rate. Out-of-sample tests show that the forecasts made by this rule significantly beat a random walk for 5 out of 10 currencies. Furthermore, the currency forecasts generate meaningful investment profits. We demonstrate that the strong performance of the model selection rule is driven by time-varying weights attached to a small set of fundamentals, in line with theory.</description><author>Kouwenberg, Roy; Markiewicz, Agnieszka; Verhoeks, Ralph; Zwinkels, Remco C. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Delays and Clustering in Hedge Fund Reported Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aragon, George O.; Nanda, Vikram
We use a novel database to study the timeliness of hedge fund monthly performance disclosures. Managers engage in strategic timing: poor monthly returns are reported with delay, sometimes clustered with stronger subsequent performance, suggestive of "performance smoothing." We posit that propensity to delay could reveal operational risk and/or poor managerial quality. Consistent with this, a portfolio strategy that buys (sells) funds with historically timely (untimely) reporting delivers 3% annual-style-adjusted returns. Investor flows are lower following reporting delays, although there are potential benefits to managers from delaying reporting when performance is sufficiently poor. We conclude that timely disclosure is an important consideration for hedge fund managers and investors.</description><author>Aragon, George O.; Nanda, Vikram</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign Default Risk and the US Equity Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jeanneret, Alexandre
This paper develops a two-country asset pricing model with defaultable firms and governments. This model shows that higher sovereign credit risk in a country depresses equity prices internationally and increases their volatility. The effect is strongest during adverse economic conditions and when firms are close to financial distress. A structural estimation provides evidence that sovereign default risk in Europe affects European and U.S. stock markets through the threat of an economic slowdown.</description><author>Jeanneret, Alexandre</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Option Portfolio Strategies: Deepening the Puzzle of Index Option Mispricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faias, Jose Afonso; Santa-Clara, Pedro
Traditional methods of asset allocation (such as mean-variance optimization) are not adequate for option portfolios because the distribution of returns is non-normal and the short sample of option returns available makes it difficult to estimate their distribution. We propose a method to optimize a portfolio of European options, held to maturity, with a myopic objective function that overcomes these limitations. In an out-of-sample exercise incorporating realistic transaction costs, the portfolio strategy delivers a Sharpe ratio of 0.82 with positive skewness. This performance is mostly obtained by exploiting mispricing between options and not by loading on jump or volatility risk premia.</description><author>Faias, Jose Afonso; Santa-Clara, Pedro</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Drives the Commonality between Credit Default Swap Spread Changes?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Mike
This paper documents an increase in the comovement between credit default swap (CDS) spread changes during the 2007-2009 crisis and investigates the source of that increase. One possible explanation is that comovement increased because fundamental values became more correlated. However, I find that changes in fundamentals account for only 23% of the increase in covariance. The remaining increase is attributed to changes in liquidity and the market price of default risk. In contrast, counterparty risk played an insignificant role. Although both contributed, the increase in covariance was driven more by variation in exposures than factor variance-covariance.</description><author>Anderson, Mike</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Options, Idiosyncratic Skewness, and Diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Del Viva, Luca; Kasanen, Eero; Trigeorgis, Lenos
We show how firm-level real options lead to idiosyncratic skewness in stock returns. We then document empirically that growth option variables are positive and significant determinants of idiosyncratic skewness. The real option impact on skewness is more significant in firms with lottery-type features, small size, high volatility, distressed, low return on assets, and low book-to-market ratio. We also find that expectation on idiosyncratic skewness is associated with lower Sharpe ratios. This suggests investors are willing to sacrifice mean-variance portfolio efficiency for greater skewness deriving from real options. Furthermore, financial flexibility has a positive incremental effect, enhancing the beneficial role of asset flexibility on idiosyncratic skewness.</description><author>Del Viva, Luca; Kasanen, Eero; Trigeorgis, Lenos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Key Human Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Israelsen, Ryan D.; Yonker, Scott E.
Firms whose human capital is concentrated in a few irreplaceable employees lack diversification in their human capital stock, exposing them to key human capital risk. Using disclosures of "key man life insurance" to measure this risk, we show that exposed firms are riskier. These younger, smaller, growth firms have abnormally high volatility, and following announcement of key employee departures, the most exposed firms lose 8% of their value. Key employees tend to be highly educated. They are four times more likely to hold PhD degrees than top managers, and firms with key human capital are more innovative.</description><author>Israelsen, Ryan D.; Yonker, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Term Reversals: The Effects of Past Returns and Institutional Exits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Si; Hameed, Allaudeen; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Titman, Sheridan
Price declines over the previous quarter lead to stronger reversals across the subsequent 2 months. We explain this finding based on the dual notions that liquidity provision can influence reversals and that agents who act as de facto liquidity providers may be less active in past losers. Supporting these observations, we find that active institutions participate less in losing stocks and that the magnitude of monthly return reversals fluctuates with changes in the number of active institutional investors. Thus, we argue that fluctuations in liquidity provision with past return performance account for the link between return reversals and past returns.</description><author>Cheng, Si; Hameed, Allaudeen; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamics of Performance Volatility and Firm Valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chi, Jianxin Daniel; Su, Xunhua
We construct a model to illustrate the dynamics of cash- flow volatility (CFV) and firm valuation. As a firm progressively invests in its growth opportunities, its book value increases and catches up with its market value, reducing the valuation multiple (Q). CFV decreases because of the diversification effect of investing in more market segments. We document a positive CFV-Q association, which varies with firm size, investment opportunities, and the correlation across market segments. Empirical findings strongly support the model's predictions and are robust to alternative explanations offered by extant studies on firm growth, volatility, and valuation.</description><author>Chi, Jianxin Daniel; Su, Xunhua</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal Asset Allocation: Evidence from Mutual Fund Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamstra, Mark J.; Kramer, Lisa A.; Levi, Maurice D.; Wermers, Russ
We analyze the flow of money between mutual fund categories, finding strong evidence of seasonality in investor risk aversion. Aggregate investor flow data reveal an investor preference for safe mutual funds in autumn and risky funds in spring. During September alone, outflows from equity funds average $13 billion, controlling for previously documented flow determinants (e.g., capital-gains overhang). This movement of large amounts of money between fund categories is correlated with seasonality in investor risk aversion, consistent with investors preferring safer (riskier) investments in autumn (spring). We find consistent evidence in Canada and also in Australia, where seasons are offset by 6 months.</description><author>Kamstra, Mark J.; Kramer, Lisa A.; Levi, Maurice D.; Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industrial Electricity Usage and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Huang, Dayong; Yun, Hayong
The growth rate of industrial electricity usage predicts future stock returns up to 1 year with an R-2 of 9%. High industrial electricity usage today predicts low stock returns in the future, consistent with a countercyclical risk premium. Industrial electricity usage tracks the output of the most cyclical sectors. Our findings bridge a gap between the asset pricing literature and the business cycle literature, which uses industrial electricity usage to gauge production and output in real time. Industrial electricity growth compares favorably with traditional financial variables, and it outperforms Cooper and Priestley's output gap measure in real time.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Huang, Dayong; Yun, Hayong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Diminishing Benefits of US Cross-Listing: Economic Consequences of SEC Rule 12h-6</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghosh, Chinmoy; He, Fan
On Mar. 21, 2007, the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) passed Exchange Act Rule 12h-6 to make it easier for cross-listed firms to deregister from the U.S. market and escape its regulatory costs. Using difference-in-difference (DD) tests, we find that, on average, Rule 12h-6's passage induced an increase in voting premium, a decline in equity raising, and a decline in cross-listing premium. These effects are observed for exchange-listed firms and for firms from countries with weak investor protection. We conclude that although cross-listed firms are still valued at a significant premium over non-cross-listed firms, the rule decreased the value of commitment to the U.S. regulatory system.</description><author>Ghosh, Chinmoy; He, Fan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Evidence on Mutual Fund Performance: A Comparison of Alternative Bootstrap Methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blake, David; Caulfield, Tristan; Ioannidis, Christos; Tonks, Ian
We compare two bootstrap methods for assessing mutual fund performance. The first produces narrow confidence intervals due to pooling over time, whereas the second produces wider confidence intervals because it preserves the cross correlation of fund returns. We then show that the average U.K. equity mutual fund manager is unable to deliver outperformance net of fees under either bootstrap. Gross of fees, 95% of fund managers on the basis of the first bootstrap and all fund managers on the basis of the second bootstrap fail to outperform the luck distribution of gross returns.</description><author>Blake, David; Caulfield, Tristan; Ioannidis, Christos; Tonks, Ian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Portfolio Choice with Linear Rebalancing Rules</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moallemi, Ciamac C.; Saglam, Mehmet
We consider a broad class of dynamic portfolio optimization problems that allow for complex models of return predictability, transaction costs, trading constraints, and risk considerations. Determining an optimal policy in this general setting is almost always intractable. We propose a class of linear rebalancing rules and describe an efficient computational procedure to optimize with this class. We illustrate this method in the context of portfolio execution and show that it achieves near optimal performance. We consider another numerical example involving dynamic trading with mean-variance preferences and demonstrate that our method can result in economically large benefits.</description><author>Moallemi, Ciamac C.; Saglam, Mehmet</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Default Prediction: A Bayesian Model-Averaging Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Traczynski, Jeffrey
I develop a new predictive approach using Bayesian model averaging to account for incomplete knowledge of the true model behind corporate default and bankruptcy filing. I find that uncertainty over the correct model is empirically large, with far fewer variables being significant predictors of default compared with conventional approaches. Only the ratio of total liabilities to total assets and the volatility of market returns are robust default predictors in the overall sample and individual industry groups. Model-averaged forecasts that aggregate information across models or allow for industry-specific effects substantially outperform individual models.</description><author>Traczynski, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Term Interest Rates and Stock Market Anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maio, Paulo; Santa-Clara, Pedro
We present a simple 2-factor model that helps explain several capital asset pricing model (CAPM) anomalies (value premium, return reversal, equity duration, asset growth, and inventory growth). The model is consistent with Merton's intertemporal CAPM (ICAPM) framework, and the key risk factor is the innovation on a short-term interest rate, the federal funds rate, or the T-bill rate. This model explains a large fraction of the dispersion in the average returns of the joint market anomalies. Moreover, the model compares favorably with alternative multifactor models widely used in the literature. Hence, short-term interest rates seem to be relevant for explaining several dimensions of cross-sectional equity risk premia.</description><author>Maio, Paulo; Santa-Clara, Pedro</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Market Mean Reversion and Portfolio Choice over the Life Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michaelides, Alexander; Zhang, Yuxin
We solve for optimal consumption and portfolio choice in a life-cycle model with short-sales and borrowing constraints; undiversifiable labor income risk; and a predictable, time-varying, equity premium and show that the investor pursues aggressive market timing strategies. Importantly, in the presence of stock market predictability, the model suggests that the conventional financial advice of reducing stock market exposure as retirement approaches is correct on average, but ignoring changing market information can lead to substantial welfare losses. Therefore, enhanced target-date funds (ETDFs) that condition on expected equity premia increase welfare relative to target-date funds (TDFs). Out-of-sample analysis supports these conclusions.</description><author>Michaelides, Alexander; Zhang, Yuxin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment-Cash Flow Sensitivity: Fact or Fiction?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agca, Senay; Mozumdar, Abon
We examine whether internal funds matter for investment when the measurement error in q is addressed. By carefully employing methodologies that tackle the measurement error in q, we show that cash flow is a significant determinant of investment. We also find that an analyst-forecast-based q measure is not superior to a stock-market-based q measure. We further propose an approach that uses two alternative proxies of q as instruments for addressing measurement error. Our evidence indicates that instrumental-variables-type generalized method of moments estimators yield empirically well-specified models.</description><author>Agca, Senay; Mozumdar, Abon</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Funds: The Good, the Bad, and the Lucky</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yong; Cliff, Michael; Zhao, Haibei
We develop an estimation approach based on a modified expectation-maximization (EM) algorithm and a mixture of normal distributions associated with skill groups to assess performance in hedge funds. By allowing luck to affect both skilled and unskilled funds, we estimate the number of skill groups, the fraction of funds from each group, and the mean and variability of skill within each group. For each individual fund, we propose a performance measure combining the fund's estimated alpha with the cross-sectional distribution of fund skill. In out-of-sample tests, an investment strategy using our performance measure outperforms those using estimated alpha and t-statistic.</description><author>Chen, Yong; Cliff, Michael; Zhao, Haibei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When and Why Do Venture-Capital-Backed Companies Obtain Venture Lending?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tykvova, Tereza
I model the decision of an informed early-stage venture capital (VC) investor that considers involving an uninformed VC or venture lending (VL) investor to finance the late stage. Early-stage VC investors that own high-quality value companies tend to signal their quality and they frequently turn to VL investors. Early-stage VC investors prefer VC if the proportion of high-quality companies in the population is high, if their companies have a high upside potential, if they can benefit from the value that late-stage VC investors add, or if uncertainty is high. I find empirical evidence consistent with these predictions.</description><author>Tykvova, Tereza</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Capital and Debt Contracting: Evidence from Bank Loans and Public Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, Iftekhar; Hoi, Chun Keung; Wu, Qiang; Zhang, Hao
We find that firms headquartered in U.S. counties with higher levels of social capital incur lower bank loan spreads. This finding is robust to using organ donation as an alternative social capital measure and incremental to the effects of religiosity, corporate social responsibility, and tax avoidance. We identify the causal relation using companies with a social-capital-changing headquarters relocation. We also find that high-social-capital firms face loosened nonprice loan terms, incur lower at-issue bond spreads, and prefer public bonds over bank loans. We conclude that debt holders perceive social capital as providing environmental pressure that constrains opportunistic firm behaviors in debt contracting.</description><author>Hasan, Iftekhar; Hoi, Chun Keung; Wu, Qiang; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender Differences in Executives' Access to Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inci, A. Can; Narayanan, M. P.; Seyhun, H. Nejat
We provide novel evidence on gender differences in insider-trading behavior and the profitability of senior corporate executives. On average, both female and male executives make positive profits from insider trading. Males, however, earn significantly more than females in equivalent positions and also trade more than females. These gender differences disappear when we limit the sample to firms in which female trading is relatively high. Collectively, these results suggest that female executives have a disadvantage relative to males in access to inside information, even if they have equal formal status, and informal networks may play an important role in attenuating this disadvantage.</description><author>Inci, A. Can; Narayanan, M. P.; Seyhun, H. Nejat</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual Investors' Dividend Taxes and Corporate Payout Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Oliver Zhen; Liu, Hang; Ni, Chenkai; Ye, Kangtao
The 2012 Dividend Tax Reform in China ties individual investors' dividend tax rates to the length of their shareholding period. We find that firms facing a reduction (increase) in their individual investors' dividend tax rates are more (less) likely to increase dividend payout. Such an effect is concentrated in firms where incentives of controlling shareholders and minority shareholders are aligned. Furthermore, investors respond to this tax law change by reducing trading activities before the cum-dividend day and successfully lower their dividend tax penalty. Overall, our evidence enhances the notion that individual investors' tax profiles shape firms' payout policies.</description><author>Li, Oliver Zhen; Liu, Hang; Ni, Chenkai; Ye, Kangtao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fortune Favors the Bold</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Meneghetti, Costanza; Williams, Ryan
We investigate whether incentives to join the Fortune 500 affect corporate decisions. Firms closer to the cutoff appear to take actions to join the list by engaging in more mergers and acquisitions activity, bidding for larger targets, and paying higher takeover premia. Further, the relation is stronger for firms with more-entrenched chief executive officers, and the stock market reaction to bids is worse when bidders are close to the Fortune 500's cutoff. A 1994 methodological change by Fortune acts as an exogenous shock for identification. Our results suggest that firms try to increase revenues to join the Fortune 500 but that such actions adversely affect shareholders.</description><author>Meneghetti, Costanza; Williams, Ryan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Attrition and Fund Flows in Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Xu, Haoyu
We explore the properties of equity mutual funds that experience a loss of assets after poor performance. We document that both inflows and outflows are less sensitive to performance, because performance-sensitive investors leave or decide not to invest after bad performance. Consistent with the idea that attrition measures the sorting of performance-sensitive investors, we find that attrition has less of an impact on the fund's flow-performance sensitivity for institutional funds where there is less dispersion in investor performance sensitivity. Also, attrition has no effect on the flow-performance sensitivity when attrition arises after good performance or investors invest for non-performance reasons.</description><author>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Xu, Haoyu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bid Resistance by Takeover Targets: Managerial Bargaining or Bad Faith?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, Thomas W.; Becher, David A.
This paper examines management's motives for rejecting takeover bids and the associated shareholder wealth effects. We develop measures of initial bid quality and find a significant negative correlation between the quality of a bid and rejection. The likelihood of higher follow-on offers decreases with bid quality and is greater when targets have classified boards and chief executive officers (CEOs) with significant personal wealth tied to the transaction. Target CEOs who fail to close high-quality offers experience a significant rate of forced turnover. Overall, the results support a price improvement motive for contested bids.</description><author>Bates, Thomas W.; Becher, David A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy Uncertainty and Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, Nam H.; Phan, Hieu V.
This research examines the relationship between policy uncertainty and mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As). We find that policy uncertainty is negatively related to firm acquisitiveness and positively related to the time it takes to complete M&amp;A deals. In addition, policy uncertainty motivates acquirers to use stock for payment and to pay lower bid premiums. Acquirers, on average, create larger shareholder value from M&amp;A deals undertaken during periods of high policy uncertainty, which is attributable to their prudence as well as the wealth transfer from the financially constrained targets to acquirers.</description><author>Nguyen, Nam H.; Phan, Hieu V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Labor Unions on CEO Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Qianqian; Jiang, Feng; Lie, Erik; Que, Tingting
We find evidence that labor unions affect chief executive officer (CEO) compensation. First, we find that firms with strong unions pay their CEOs less. The negative effect is robust to various tests for endogeneity, including cross-sectional variations and a regression discontinuity design. Second, we find that CEO compensation is curbed before union contract negotiations, especially when the compensation is discretionary and the unions have a strong bargaining position. Third, we report that curbing CEO compensation mitigates the chance of a labor strike, thus providing a rationale for firms to pay CEOs less when facing strong unions. The United Auto Workers says it knows it needs to help Detroit's automakers cut labor costs to reduce the gap in production expenses with Asian rivals. But as talks continue on new contracts, the union also is questioning why top executives at the automakers are paid what they are. (USA Today, Oct. 10, 2007)</description><author>Huang, Qianqian; Jiang, Feng; Lie, Erik; Que, Tingting</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Tournaments: A Cross-Country Analysis of Causes, Cultural Influences, and Consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burns, Natasha; Minnick, Kristina; Starks, Laura
Using a cross-country sample, we examine the chief executive officer (CEO) tournament structure (measured alternatively as the ratio and the difference of pay between the CEO and other top executives within a firm). We find the tournament structure to vary systematically with firm and country cultural characteristics. In particular, firm size and the cultural values of power distance, fair income differences, and competition are significantly associated with variations in tournament structures. We also establish support for the primary implication of tournament theory in that tournament structure tends to be positively related to firm value, even after controlling for endogeneity.</description><author>Burns, Natasha; Minnick, Kristina; Starks, Laura</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Timing and Source of Long-Run Returns Following Repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bargeron, Leonce; Bonaime, Alice; Thomas, Shawn
This paper investigates the timing and source of anomalous positive long-run abnormal returns following repurchase authorizations. Returns between program authorization and completion announcements are indistinguishable from 0. Abnormal returns occur only after completion announcements. Long-run returns are largely attributable to announcement returns at subsequent authorizations and takeover attempts; that is, anomalous post-authorization returns are not persistent drifts but rather step functions. These findings have important implications for prior papers examining this most persistent and widespread anomaly. Further, our results serve to refocus the search for a rational explanation for the anomaly on subsequent repurchase announcements and takeover bids.</description><author>Bargeron, Leonce; Bonaime, Alice; Thomas, Shawn</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Investment Constraints and Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Jie; Han, Bing; Wang, Qinghai
We test the hypothesis that investment constraints in delegated portfolio management may distort demand for stocks, leading to price underreaction to news and stock return predictability. We find that institutions tend not to buy more of a stock with good news that they already overweight; they are reluctant to sell a stock with bad news that they already underweight. Stocks with good news overweighted by institutions subsequently significantly outperform stocks with bad news underweighted by institutions. The impact of institutional investment constraints sheds new light on asset pricing anomalies such as stock price momentum and post-earnings announcement drift.</description><author>Cao, Jie; Han, Bing; Wang, Qinghai</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Best Practice for Cost-of-Capital Estimates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levi, Yaron; Welch, Ivo
Cost-of-capital assessments with factor models require quantitative forward-looking estimates. We recommend estimating Vasicek-shrunk betas with 1-4 years of daily stock returns and then shrinking betas a second time (and more for smaller stocks and longer-term projects), because the underlying betas are themselves time-varying. Such estimators also work well in other developed countries and for small-minus-big (SMB) and high-minuslow (HML) exposures. If own historical stock returns are not available, peer betas based on market cap should be used. Historical industry averages have almost no predictive power and should never be used.</description><author>Levi, Yaron; Welch, Ivo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Upper Bounds on Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Dashan; Zhou, Guofu
Can the degree of predictability found in data be explained by existing asset pricing models? We provide two theoretical upper bounds on the R-2 of predictive regressions. Using data on the market portfolio and component portfolios, we find that the empirical R(2)s are significantly greater than the theoretical upper bounds. Our results suggest that the most promising direction for future research should aim to identify new state variables that are highly correlated with stock returns instead of seeking more elaborate stochastic discount factors.</description><author>Huang, Dashan; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Short Sellers Like Qualitative News?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Beschwitz, Bastian; Chuprinin, Oleg; Massa, Massimo
Short sellers trade more on days with qualitative news, that is, news containing fewer numbers. We show that this behavior is not informationally motivated but can be explained by short sellers exploiting higher liquidity on such days. We document that liquidity and noise trading increase in the presence of qualitative news, enabling short sellers to better disguise their informed trades. Natural experiments support our findings. Qualitative news has a bigger effect on short sellers' trading after a decrease in liquidity following the stock's deletion from the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index and a smaller effect when investor attention is distracted by the Olympic Games.</description><author>von Beschwitz, Bastian; Chuprinin, Oleg; Massa, Massimo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stapled Financing, Value Certification, and Lending Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aslan, Hadiye; Kumar, Praveen
We examine whether financing commitments from a target firm's financial advisor, in the form of stapled financing, provide certification of target value. Using a data set of leveraged buyouts spanning 2002-2011, and addressing endogeneity issues, we find that stapled financing has significant positive effects on sellers' shareholder wealth, especially for targets suffering from greater adverse selection. Stapled financing facilitates deal financing by allowing buyers to obtain lower-cost and longer-maturity debt, and it is positively associated with bidding intensity. Investment banks offering stapled financing appear to trade off higher expected advisory fees against loss of lending efficiency ex post.</description><author>Aslan, Hadiye; Kumar, Praveen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed Trading around Stock Split Announcements: Evidence from the Option Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gharghori, Philip; Maberly, Edwin D.; Nguyen, Annette
Prior research shows that splitting firms earn positive abnormal returns and that they experience an increase in stock return volatility. By examining option-implied volatility, we assess option traders' perceptions on return and volatility changes arising from stock splits. We find that they do expect higher volatility following splits. There is only weak evidence, though, of option traders anticipating an abnormal increase in stock prices. We also show that our option measures can predict both stock volatility levels and changes after the announcement. However, there is little evidence that they can predict the returns of splitting firms.</description><author>Gharghori, Philip; Maberly, Edwin D.; Nguyen, Annette</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should Indirect Brokerage Fees Be Capped? Lessons from Mutual Fund Marketing and Distribution Expense</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oh, Natalie Y.; Parwada, Jerry T.; Tan, Eric K. M.
Theory predicts that capping brokers' compensation exacerbates the exploitation of retail investors. We show that regulated caps on mutual fund 12b-1 fees, effectively sales commissions, are associated with negative equity fund performance, but only after a structural shift toward maximum permitted levels of the fees around 2000. Past this break point, flow-performance sensitivity shifts from the middle-to the highest-performing funds, suggesting that the fee cap increases performance-chasing behavior by constraining brokers' incentives to learn about lower-ranked funds. The policy implication is that regulators must reevaluate the efficacy of caps on brokerage fees.</description><author>Oh, Natalie Y.; Parwada, Jerry T.; Tan, Eric K. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Annual Report Readability, Tone Ambiguity, and the Cost of Borrowing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ertugrul, Mine; Lei, Jin; Qiu, Jiaping; Wan, Chi
This paper investigates the impact of a firm's annual report readability and ambiguous tone on its borrowing costs. We find that firms with larger 10-K file sizes and a higher proportion of uncertain and weak modal words in 10-Ks have stricter loan contract terms and greater future stock price crash risk. Our results suggest that the readability and tone ambiguity of a firm's financial disclosures are related to managerial information hoarding. Shareholders of firms with less readable and more ambiguous annual reports not only suffer from less transparent information disclosure but also bear the increased cost of external financing.</description><author>Ertugrul, Mine; Lei, Jin; Qiu, Jiaping; Wan, Chi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Characteristics and Errors in Expectations : Experimental Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antoniou, Constantinos; Harrison, Glenn W.; Lau, Morten I.; Read, Daniel
We design an experiment to test the hypothesis that, in violation of Bayes' rule, some people respond more forcefully to the strength of information than to its weight. We provide incentives to motivate effort, use naturally occurring information, and control for risk attitude. We find that the strength-weight bias affects expectations but that its magnitude is significantly lower than originally reported. Controls for nonlinear utility further reduce the bias. Our results suggest that incentive compatibility and controls for risk attitude considerably affect inferences on errors in expectations.</description><author>Antoniou, Constantinos; Harrison, Glenn W.; Lau, Morten I.; Read, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inside Debt and Bank Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Bekkum, Sjoerd
Inside debt compensation held by top officers of U.S. banks is negatively related to risk and risk taking. The evidence reveals a robust and strongly negative relation between end-of-2006 inside debt and 2007-2009 bank-specific risk exposures in terms of lost stock market value, volatility, tail risk, and the probability of financial distress. Banks with managers having large inside debt holdings are also characterized by better-quality assets, more conservative balance sheet management, and a stronger tendency toward traditional banking activities. The results suggest that debt-based compensation limits bank risk and risk taking by encouraging more conservative decision making.</description><author>van Bekkum, Sjoerd</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Market Efficiency and Arbitrage Efficacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akbas, Ferhat; Armstrong, Will J.; Sorescu, Sorin; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
Efficiency in the capitalmarkets requires that capital flows are sufficient to arbitrage anomalies away. We examine the relation between flows to a quantitative (quant) strategy that is based on capital market anomalies and the subsequent performance of this strategy. When these flows are high, quant funds are able to implement arbitrage strategies more effectively, which in turn leads to lower profitability of market anomalies in the future, and vice versa. Thus, the degree of cross-sectional equity market efficiency varies across time with the availability of arbitrage capital.</description><author>Akbas, Ferhat; Armstrong, Will J.; Sorescu, Sorin; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Moves Markets in a Sudden Marketwide Crisis? Evidence from 9/11</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burch, Timothy R.; Emery, Douglas R.; Fuerst, Michael E.
We compare reactions in the prices and trading patterns of common stocks and closed-end funds (CEFs), securities with substantially different investor clienteles, to the Sept. 11, 2001 terrorist attacks. When the market reopened 6 days later, retail investors sold and there were sharp price declines, even in assets with net institutional buying. In the subsequent 2 weeks, price reversals were substantially security specific and thus not simply due to improved systematic sentiment. Consistent with microstructure theory, comparisons between CEFs and common stocks show the speed of these reversals depended significantly on the relative quality and availability of information about fundamental values.</description><author>Burch, Timothy R.; Emery, Douglas R.; Fuerst, Michael E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Mutual Funds in Corporate Governance: Evidence from Mutual Funds' Proxy Voting and Trading Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duan, Ying; Jiao, Yawen
This paper examines mutual fund families' proxy voting records to analyze their choices between voting against management ("voice") and voting with their feet ("exit"). Even though proxy voting is particularly conducive to governance through voice rather than exit, we provide evidence that both exit and voice are important governance mechanisms when Institutional Shareholder Services recommends voting against management. Funds with smaller ownership blocks and shorter investment horizons are more likely to exit, and funds are more likely to exit small, liquid firms with greater insider ownership.</description><author>Duan, Ying; Jiao, Yawen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gambling Preferences, Options Markets, and Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blau, Benjamin M.; Bowles, T. Boone; Whitby, Ryan J.
This study examines whether the gambling behavior of investors affects volume and volatility in financial markets. Focusing on the options market, we find that the ratio of call option volume relative to total option volume is greatest for stocks with return distributions that resemble lotteries. Consistent with the theoretical predictions of Stein (1987), we demonstrate that gambling-motivated trading in the options market influences future spot price volatility. These results not only identify a link between lottery preferences in the stock market and the options market, but they also suggest that lottery preferences can lead to destabilized stock prices.</description><author>Blau, Benjamin M.; Bowles, T. Boone; Whitby, Ryan J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Economic Shocks and Sovereign Credit Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Augustin, Patrick; Tedongap, Romeo
We provide new empirical evidence that U.S. expected growth and consumption volatility are closely related to the strong comovement in sovereign spreads. We rationalize these findings in an equilibrium model with recursive utility for credit default swap (CDS) spreads. The framework links a reduced-form default process with country-specific sensitivity to expected growth and macroeconomic uncertainty. Exploiting the high-frequency information in the CDS term structure across 38 countries, we estimate the model and find parameters consistent with preference for early resolution of uncertainty. Our results confirm the existence of time-varying risk premia in sovereign spreads as compensation for exposure to common U.S. macroeconomic risk.</description><author>Augustin, Patrick; Tedongap, Romeo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Benchmarking and Currency Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Wang, Yanbo; Zhang, Hong
We show that the currency risk embedded in the benchmarks of international mutual funds negatively affects fund performance. More specifically, a high benchmark-implied currency risk induces funds to invest in markets with less volatile currencies, leading to a higher degree of currency concentration in portfolio holdings. This currency concentration, however, departs from the optimal equity allocation strategy across countries and reduces fund performance. We document that funds resorting to high currency concentrations underperform funds with low currency concentrations by as much as 1%-2% per year.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Wang, Yanbo; Zhang, Hong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-Varying Margin Requirements and Optimal Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rytchkov, Oleg
This paper studies the optimal consumption and portfolio problem of an investor with recursive preferences who is subject to time-varying margin requirements. The level of the requirements at each moment is determined by contemporaneous volatility of returns, which is stochastic and may have jumps. I show that the nonstandard hedging demand produced by margin requirements increases with their persistence and volatility. However, for realistic values of parameters, the hedging demand is small even in the presence of jumps, and contemporaneous jumps in prices have a much stronger effect on optimal portfolio than jumps in constraints.</description><author>Rytchkov, Oleg</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systematic Tail Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Oordt, Maarten R. C.; Zhou, Chen
We test for the presence of a systematic tail risk premium in the cross section of expected returns by applying a measure of the sensitivity of assets to extreme market downturns, the tail beta. Empirically, historical tail betas help predict the future performance of stocks in extreme market downturns. During a market crash, stocks with historically high tail betas suffer losses that are approximately 2 to 3 times larger than their low-tail-beta counterparts. However, we find no evidence of a premium associated with tail betas. The theoretically additive and empirically persistent tail betas can help assess portfolio tail risks.</description><author>van Oordt, Maarten R. C.; Zhou, Chen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making Waves: To Innovate or Be a Fast Second?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yung, Chris
Internal finance leads to a stalemate in innovation games; each firm wants to free-ride on the others' costly experimentation. When instead innovation is financed externally (e.g., with venture capital or initial public offerings), there is an endogenous cost to delay. Waiting to make risky irreversible investment conveys pessimistic information. I characterize the relative sizes of waves of leaders and followers in innovation cycles, and the endogenous, intertemporal distribution of quality as each wave builds and crashes. Finally, old waves leave an adverse selection "hangover," such that too much early innovation can cause the market for future innovation to break down.</description><author>Yung, Chris</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Information-Processing Cost Affect Firm-Specific Information Acquisition? Evidence from XBRL Adoption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dong, Yi; Li, Oliver Zhen; Lin, Yupeng; Ni, Chenkai
We examine how information-processing cost affects investors' acquisition of firm-specific information using a natural experiment resulting from a recent mandate requiring U.S. firms to adopt eXtensible Business Reporting Language (XBRL) when submitting filings to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). XBRL filings make financial data standardized, tagged, and machine readable. We find that XBRL adoption reduces firms' stock return synchronicity. The reduction in synchronicity mainly applies to filings under the mandatory program as opposed to the voluntary program. Furthermore, such an effect is more pronounced for opaque and complex firms. Finally, we find that XBRL adoption also reduces price delay.</description><author>Dong, Yi; Li, Oliver Zhen; Lin, Yupeng; Ni, Chenkai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst Coverage and Real Earnings Management: Quasi-Experimental Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Irani, Rustom M.; Oesch, David
We study how securities analysts influence managers' use of different types of earnings management. To isolate causality, we employ a quasi-experiment that exploits exogenous reductions in analyst following resulting from brokerage house mergers. We find that managers respond to the coverage loss by decreasing real earnings management while increasing accrual manipulation. These effects are significantly stronger among firms with less coverage and for firms close to the zero-earnings threshold. Our causal evidence suggests that managers use real earnings management to enhance short-term performance in response to analyst pressure, effects that are not uncovered when focusing solely on accrual-based methods.</description><author>Irani, Rustom M.; Oesch, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Skin in the Game and Loan Contract Design: Evidence from Covenant-Lite Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, Matthew T.; Elkamhi, Redouane; Popov, Latchezar; Pungaliya, Raunaq S.
In a model of dual-agency problems where borrower-lender and bank-nonbank incentives may conflict, we predict a hockey stick relation between bank skin in the game and covenant tightness. As bank participation declines, covenant tightness increases until reaching a low threshold, at which point the relation sharply reverses and covenant protection is removed with a commensurate increase in spread. We find support for the hockey stick relation with bank's stake in covenant-lite loans averaging 8% (0% median). We also find that covenant-lite loans are more likely when borrower moral hazard is less severe and when bank relationship rents are high.</description><author>Billett, Matthew T.; Elkamhi, Redouane; Popov, Latchezar; Pungaliya, Raunaq S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Evidence on the Forward Premium Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boudoukh, Jacob; Richardson, Matthew; Whitelaw, Robert F.
The forward premium anomaly (exchange rate changes are negatively related to interest rate differentials) is one of the most robust puzzles in financial economics. We recast the underlying parity relation in terms of lagged forward interest rate differentials, documenting a reversal of the anomalous sign on the coefficient in the traditional specification. We show that this novel evidence is consistent with recent empirical models of exchange rates that imply exchange rate changes depend on two key variables: the interest rate differential and the magnitude of the deviation of the current exchange rate from that implied by purchasing power parity.</description><author>Boudoukh, Jacob; Richardson, Matthew; Whitelaw, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Boards and SEOs: The Effect of Certification and Monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel; Laux, Paul
In a sample of underwritten seasoned equity offerings (SEOs), issuers with boards dominated by independent directors experience higher abnormal announcement returns than issuers with boards dominated by insiders. Firm size, transparency, and other governance characteristics do not explain the effect of board independence. The positive relation between board independence and SEO returns is more pronounced for firms with lower monitoring costs and more severe financial constraints. The evidence suggests that independent directors have a positive effect because of their role in controlling both shareholder-manager conflicts (monitoring the use of funds) and current-new shareholder conflicts (certification of the issue's value).</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel; Laux, Paul</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Is the Nature of Hedge Fund Manager Skills? Evidence from the Risk-Arbitrage Strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Charles; Goldie, Bradley A.; Liang, Bing; Petrasek, Lubomir
To understand the nature of hedge fund managers' skills, we study the implementation of risk arbitrage by hedge funds using their portfolio holdings and comparing them with those of other institutional arbitrageurs. We find that hedge funds significantly outperform a naive risk-arbitrage portfolio by 3.7% annually on a risk-adjusted basis, whereas non-hedge fund arbitrageurs fail to outperform the benchmark. Our analysis reveals that hedge funds' superior performance does not reflect fund managers' ability to predict or affect the outcome of merger and acquisition deals; rather, hedge fund managers' superior performance is attributed to their ability to manage downside risk.</description><author>Cao, Charles; Goldie, Bradley A.; Liang, Bing; Petrasek, Lubomir</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Diversification and International Corporate Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Edith X.
This article examines the benefits of corporate bond diversification for U.S. investors. Analysis of a newly compiled bond-level data set for 2000-2010 finds that diversification with corporate bonds can significantly reduce volatility and increase risk-adjusted returns for U.S. investors. Unlike diversification with equities, corporate bonds offer significant out-of-sample risk reduction, particularly during the recent financial crisis. Risk-reduction gains are large even when the benchmark includes international equities or when longer samples of equities and sovereign bonds are used to inform corporate bond returns. Finally, significant risk-reduction gains remain after accounting for bond characteristics, liquidity, and informational costs.</description><author>Liu, Edith X.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding Portfolio Efficiency with Conditioning Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Penaranda, Francisco
I develop two new types of portfolio efficiency when returns are predictable. The first type maximizes the unconditional Sharpe ratio of excess returns and differs from unconditional efficiency unless the safe asset return is constant over time. The second type maximizes conditional mean-variance preferences and differs from unconditional efficiency unless, additionally, the maximum conditional Sharpe ratio is constant. Using stock data, I quantify and test their performance differences with respect to unconditionally and fixed-weight efficient returns. I also show the relevance of the two new portfolio strategies to test conditional asset pricing models.</description><author>Penaranda, Francisco</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Valuation of Hedge Funds' Equity Positions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cici, Gjergji; Kempf, Alexander; Puetz, Alexander
We provide evidence on the valuation of equity positions by hedge funds. Reported valuations deviate from standard valuations based on closing prices from the Center for Research in Security Prices for roughly 7% of the positions. These equity valuation deviations are positively related to illiquidity and price volatility of the underlying stocks. They respond to past performance and intensify after an advisor starts reporting to a commercial database. Furthermore, advisors with more valuation deviations show a stronger discontinuity in their reported returns around 0, manage a higher fraction of potentially fraudulent funds, report smoother returns, and exhibit an upward spike in their December reported returns.</description><author>Cici, Gjergji; Kempf, Alexander; Puetz, Alexander</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Rent-Protection Explanation for SEO Flotation-Method Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Xueping; Wang, Zheng; Yao, Jun
We model how a rent-protection motive drives the choice of flotation method in new equity issuance between two polar cases: rights issues and cash offers. Unexpected new block-holders would emerge in control-diluting cash offers and share in jealously guarded control benefits. But rights issues help the incumbent controlling shareholders avoid control dilution and safeguard their private benefits. Under asymmetric information about private benefits, the choice of flotation method can convey information about hidden private benefits and hence firm value. Our model can explain even a negative announcement effect of rights issues, and it supports not just one but three important equilibriums.</description><author>Wu, Xueping; Wang, Zheng; Yao, Jun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Style-Based Feedback Trading of Mutual Fund Managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frijns, Bart; Gilbert, Aaron; Zwinkels, Remco C. J.
This paper examines the style-based feedback trading behavior of U.S. mutual fund managers. We provide an empirical version of Barberis and Shleifer's style-switching model. We find style-based feedback trading for 77% of the funds, half of which is positive (negative) feedback trading. There is evidence for "twin style" switching, where capital is channeled between value and growth, and between large-and small-cap. Growth (value) funds apply more positive (negative) feedback trading. Funds that switch more aggressively are younger and have higher expense ratios. Finally, we find that positive (negative) feedback trading yields positive (negative) alpha.</description><author>Frijns, Bart; Gilbert, Aaron; Zwinkels, Remco C. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Price of Street Friends: Social Networks, Informed Trading, and Shareholder Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Jie; Walkling, Ralph A.; Yang, Ke
Recent studies suggest the transfer of privileged information via social ties but do not explicitly examine the cost of these ties to shareholders. We document a significant positive relation between stock transaction costs and a company's social ties to the investment community. Social ties based on education and leisure activities, stronger ties, and ties to individuals responsible for trading have greater effects. Using investment connection deaths as natural experiments, we document that exogenous severance of ties reduces trading costs and trading activities by connected parties. Our evidence illustrates an important and previously undocumented consequence of social ties.</description><author>Cai, Jie; Walkling, Ralph A.; Yang, Ke</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Ex Ante CEO Severance Pay Contracts Consistent with Efficient Contracting?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cadman, Brian D.; Campbell, John L.; Klasa, Sandy
Efficient contracting predicts that ex ante severance pay contracts are offered to chief executive officers (CEOs) as protection against downside risk and to encourage investment in risky projects with a positive net present value (NPV). Consistent with this prediction, we find that ex ante contracted severance pay is positively associated with proxies for a CEO's risk of dismissal and costs the CEO would incur from dismissal. Additionally, we show that the contracted severance payment amount is positively associated with CEO risk taking and the extent to which a CEO invests in projects that have a positive NPV. Overall, our findings imply that ex ante severance pay contracts are consistent with efficient contracting.</description><author>Cadman, Brian D.; Campbell, John L.; Klasa, Sandy</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk, Uncertainty, and Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Zhou, Hao
A conditional asset pricing model with risk and uncertainty implies that the time-varying exposures of equity portfolios to the market and uncertainty factors carry positive risk premia. The empirical results from the size, book-to-market, momentum, and industry portfolios indicate that the conditional covariances of equity portfolios with market and uncertainty predict the time-series and cross-sectional variation in stock returns. We find that equity portfolios that are highly correlated with economic uncertainty proxied by the variance risk premium (VRP) carry a significant annualized 8% premium relative to portfolios that are minimally correlated with VRP.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Zhou, Hao</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Narcissism and the Takeover Process: From Private Initiation to Deal Completion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Bollaert, Helen; Roll, Richard
Chief executive officer (CEO) narcissism affects the takeover process. Acquirer shareholders react less favorably to a takeover announcement when the target CEO is more narcissistic. Narcissistic acquiring CEOs negotiate faster. They are also marginally more likely to initiate deals. Acquirer CEO narcissism and target CEO narcissism are associated with a lower probability of deal completion and reduce the likelihood that the target CEO will be employed by the merged firm. Our findings highlight the importance of both acquirer and target CEO psychological characteristics throughout the takeover process.</description><author>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Bollaert, Helen; Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Personal Risk-Taking and Corporate Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cain, Matthew D.; McKeon, Stephen B.
This study analyzes the relation between chief executive officer (CEO) personal risk-taking, corporate risk-taking, and total firm risk. We find evidence that CEOs who possess private pilot licenses (our proxy for personal risk-taking) are associated with riskier firms. Firms led by pilot CEOs have higher equity return volatility, beyond the amount explained by compensation components that financially reward risk-taking. We trace the source of the elevated firm risk to specific corporate policies, including leverage and acquisition activity. Our results suggest that nonpecuniary risk preferences revealed outside the scope of the firm have implications for project selection and various corporate policies.</description><author>Cain, Matthew D.; McKeon, Stephen B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Default, Debt Structure, and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Valta, Philip
This paper theoretically and empirically investigates how debt structure and strategic interaction among shareholders and debt holders in the event of default affect expected stock returns. The model predicts that expected stock returns are higher for firms that face high debt renegotiation difficulties and that have a large fraction of secured or convertible debt. Using a large sample of publicly traded U.S. firms for the period 1985-2012, the paper presents new evidence on the link between debt structure and stock returns that is supportive of the model's predictions.</description><author>Valta, Philip</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Weakness and Product Market Performance: Internal Capital Market Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Ryoonhee
Using a data set of Korean business groups in the period 1999-2006, just after the Asian Financial Crisis, this study shows how business groups' financial leverage can lead group-affiliated firms to lose market share to industry rivals. This analysis reveals that the negative effect of group leverage is greater when an affiliated firm is financially weak. Additionally, high group leverage is more detrimental to firms operating in fast-growing industries, discouraging affiliated firms from investing while encouraging their rivals. The results suggest that groups' financial positions encompass a substantial strategic dimension of group-affiliated firms.</description><author>Kim, Ryoonhee</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Equity Firms' Reputational Concerns and the Costs of Debt Financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Rongbing; Ritter, Jay R.; Zhang, Donghang
A popular view is that private equity (PE) firms tend to expropriate other stakeholders of their portfolio companies. Bonds offered during 1992-2011 by companies after their initial public offerings (IPOs) do not reflect this view. We find that yield spreads on bonds offered by PE-backed companies are, on average, 70 basis points lower, holding other things constant. We also find that PE-backed companies have more conservative investment and dividend policies after bond offerings compared with non-PE-backed companies. These results suggest that PE firms' reputational concerns dominate their wealth expropriation incentives and help their portfolio companies reduce the costs of debt.</description><author>Huang, Rongbing; Ritter, Jay R.; Zhang, Donghang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business Microloans for US Subprime Borrowers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fracassi, Cesare; Garmaise, Mark J.; Kogan, Shimon; Natividad, Gabriel
We show that business microloans to U.S. subprime borrowers have a very large impact on subsequent firm success. Using data on startup loan applicants from a lender that employed an automated algorithm in its application review, we implement a regression discontinuity design assessing the causal impact of receiving a loan on firms. Startups receiving funding are dramatically more likely to survive, enjoy higher revenues, and create more jobs. Loans are more consequential for survival among subprime business owners with more education and less managerial experience.</description><author>Fracassi, Cesare; Garmaise, Mark J.; Kogan, Shimon; Natividad, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Competition and Financial Stability: Evidence from the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akins, Brian; Li, Lynn; Ng, Jeffrey; Rusticus, Tjomme O.
We examine the link between bank competition and financial stability using the recent financial crisis as the setting. We utilize variation in banking competition at the state level and find that banks facing less competition are more likely to engage in risky activities, more likely to face regulatory intervention, and more likely to fail. Focusing on the real estate market, we find that states with less competition had higher rates of mortgage approval, experienced greater inflation in housing prices before the crisis, and experienced a steeper decline in housing prices during the crisis. Overall, our study is consistent with greater competition increasing financial stability.</description><author>Akins, Brian; Li, Lynn; Ng, Jeffrey; Rusticus, Tjomme O.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gambling and Comovement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Alok; Page, Jeremy K.; Spalt, Oliver G.
This study shows that correlated trading by gambling-motivated investors generates excess return comovement among stocks with lottery features. Lottery-like stocks comove strongly with one another, and this return comovement is strongest among lottery stocks located in regions where investors exhibit stronger gambling propensity. Looking directly at investor trades, we find that investors with a greater propensity to gamble trade lottery-like stocks more actively and that those trades are more strongly correlated. Finally, we demonstrate that time variation in general gambling enthusiasm and income shocks from fluctuating economic conditions induce a systematic component in investors' demand for lottery-like stocks.</description><author>Kumar, Alok; Page, Jeremy K.; Spalt, Oliver G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flashes of Trading Intent at NASDAQ</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Skjeltorp, Johannes A.; Sojli, Elvira; Tham, Wing Wah
We use the introduction and subsequent removal of the flash-order functionality from NASDAQ as a natural experiment to investigate the impact of voluntary disclosure of trading intent on market quality. We find that flash orders significantly improve liquidity in NASDAQ. Furthermore, overall market quality improves (deteriorates) when flash functionality is introduced (removed). This result can be attributed to increased competition among liquidity suppliers across competing trading venues. Alternatively, flash orders attract responses from reactive traders immediately after the announcement, attracting more "hidden liquidity" and lowering risk-bearing costs for the overall market.</description><author>Skjeltorp, Johannes A.; Sojli, Elvira; Tham, Wing Wah</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Fund Performance Evaluation under the Stochastic Discount Factor Framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Haitao; Xu, Yuewu; Zhang, Xiaoyan
We study hedge fund performance evaluation under the stochastic discount factor framework of Farnsworth, Ferson, Jackson, and Todd (FFJT). To accommodate dynamic trading strategies and derivatives used by hedge funds, we extend FFJT's approach by considering models with option and time-averaged risk factors and incorporating option returns in model estimation. A wide range of models yield similar conclusions on the performance of simulated long/short equity hedge funds. We apply these models to 2,315 actual long/short equity funds from the Lipper TASS database and find that a small portion of these funds can outperform the market.</description><author>Li, Haitao; Xu, Yuewu; Zhang, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-Listing Waves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkissian, Sergei; Schill, Michael J.
Using a 57-year global foreign listing sample, we identify cross-listing waves at the host market, home market, and industry levels. Waves in host markets are often due to cross-listing waves in proximate home markets. Consistent with gravity-model implications and economic-synergy arguments of cross-listing decisions, cross-listing waves in a given host country coincide with the outperformance of the host and proximate home countries' economies and financial markets. The valuation gains from listings associated with cross-listing waves are transitory, supporting the market-timing component in these decisions. Our results provide novel evidence of nonmonotonic market development across countries and over time.</description><author>Sarkissian, Sergei; Schill, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Politics of Related Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Halling, Michael; Pichler, Pegaret; Stomper, Alex
We analyze the profitability of government-owned banks' lending to their owners, using a unique data set of relatively homogeneous government-owned banks; the banks are all owned by similarly structured local governments in a single country. Making use of a natural experiment that altered the regulatory and competitive environment, we find evidence that such lending was used to transfer revenues from the banks to the governments. Some of the evidence is particularly pronounced in localities where the incumbent politicians face significant competition for reelection.</description><author>Halling, Michael; Pichler, Pegaret; Stomper, Alex</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buyers versus Sellers: Who Initiates Trades, and When?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, Tarun; Goyal, Amit; Jegadeesh, Narasimhan
Models that examine investors' motivations to trade often make opposite predictions about the relation between trading decisions and past returns. We find that, in the aggregate, both buyer-and seller-initiated trades increase with past returns. The difference between buyer-and seller-initiated trades is negatively related to short horizon returns but positively related to returns over longer horizons. Tax-loss-related seller-initiated trades in December and January are accompanied by increased buyer-initiated trades. Past returns significantly affect trading decisions, and these findings are consistent with a number of different models of trading behavior.</description><author>Chordia, Tarun; Goyal, Amit; Jegadeesh, Narasimhan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anchoring Credit Default Swap Spreads to Firm Fundamentals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Jennie; Wu, Liuren
In this article, we examine the extent to which firm fundamentals can explain the cross-sectional variation in credit default swap (CDS) spreads. We construct a fundamental CDS valuation by combining the Merton distance-to-default measure with a long list of firm fundamentals via a Bayesian shrinkage method. Regressing CDS quotes against the fundamental valuation cross-sectionally generates an average R-2 of 77%. The explanatory power is stable over time and robust in out-of-sample tests. Deviations between market quotes and the valuation predict future market movements. The results highlight the important role played by firm fundamentals in differentiating the credit spreads of different firms.</description><author>Bai, Jennie; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculators, Prices, and Market Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunetti, Celso; Buyuksahin, Bahattin; Harris, Jeffrey H.
We use data from 2005-2009 that uniquely identify categories of traders to test how speculators such as hedge funds and swap dealers relate to volatility and price changes. In examining various subperiods where price trends are strong, we find little evidence that speculators destabilize financial markets. To the contrary, hedge fund position changes are negatively related to volatility in corn, crude oil, and natural gas futures markets. Additionally, swap dealer activity is largely unrelated to contemporaneous volatility. Our evidence is consistent with the hypothesis that hedge funds provide valuable liquidity and largely serve to stabilize futures markets.</description><author>Brunetti, Celso; Buyuksahin, Bahattin; Harris, Jeffrey H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Banks Issue Equity When They Are Poorly Capitalized?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dinger, Valeriya; Vallascas, Francesco
Debt overhang and moral hazard predict that poorly capitalized banks have a lower likelihood to issue equity, while the presence of regulatory and market pressures posits an opposite theoretical prediction. By using an international sample of bank seasoned equity offerings (SEOs), we show that the likelihood of issuing SEOs is higher in poorly capitalized banks and that such banks prefer SEOs to alternative capitalization strategies. A series of tests exploring the variation of capital regulation and market discipline show that market mechanisms rather than capital regulation are the primary driver of the decision to issue by poorly capitalized banks.</description><author>Dinger, Valeriya; Vallascas, Francesco</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Strategic Behavior of Firms with Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reboul, Jerome; Toldra-Simats, Anna
We empirically study the strategic behavior of levered firms in competitive and noncompetitive environments. We find that regulation induces firms to increase leverage, and this reduces their ability to compete when deregulation occurs. Large and small levered firms adopt different strategies upon deregulation. Whereas more levered small firms charge higher prices to increase margins at the expense of market shares, highly levered large firms prey on their rivals by increasing output and reducing prices to increase their market shares. The difference in their behavior is due to differences in their probability of bankruptcy and their financing constraints.</description><author>Reboul, Jerome; Toldra-Simats, Anna</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>To Pay or Be Paid? The Impact of Taker Fees and Order Flow Inducements on Trading Costs in US Options Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battalio, Robert; Shkilko, Andriy; Van Ness, Robert
Consistent with prior literature, we find that average relative effective spreads are higher for venues that pay for order flow (PFOF) than for venues utilizing the maker-taker (MT) model. This relation becomes more nuanced when liquidity fees are incorporated into liquidity cost measures. For the majority of options, PFOF venues offer lower average liquidity costs net of taker fees. Net liquidity costs for the high-priced options, however, are lower for MT venues. Overall, our results suggest that the inclusion of fees and rebates can rationalize the routing of most, but not all, marketable orders to PFOF venues.</description><author>Battalio, Robert; Shkilko, Andriy; Van Ness, Robert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Initial Public Offering Allocations, Price Support, and Secondary Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fjesme, Sturla Lyngnes
Tying initial public offering (IPO) allocations to after-listing purchases of other IPO shares as a form of price support has generated much theoretical interest and media attention. Price support is price manipulation and can reduce secondary investor return. In the past, obtaining data to investigate price support has proven to be difficult. I document that price support is harming secondary investor return using new data from the Oslo Stock Exchange. I also show that investors who engage in price support are allocated more future oversubscribed allocations, whereas harmed secondary investors significantly reduce their future participation in the secondary market.</description><author>Fjesme, Sturla Lyngnes</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alliances and Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Jie; Chordia, Tarun; Lin, Chen
Building on the growing literature on interfirm links and limited attention, we find evidence of return predictability across alliance partners. A long-short portfolio sorted on lagged returns of strategic alliance partners provides a return of 89 basis points per month that is robust to a number of specifications. Investor inattention and limits to arbitrage may be the source of the underreaction of a firm's returns to that of its partners.</description><author>Cao, Jie; Chordia, Tarun; Lin, Chen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder Composition and Managerial Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shinozaki, Shinya; Moriyasu, Hiroshi; Uchida, Konari
Stock options are used only sparingly in Japan. Japanese firms are more likely to adopt new stock option plans when they are more (less) owned by arms-length investors (stable and controlling shareholders). Those firms have significantly more independent boards and pay higher dividends surrounding the adoption year than their industry peers. These results suggest that firms adopting stock options endeavor to meet demands for good governance practice from arms-length shareholders and to follow good governance practices in other dimensions. The coexistence of arms-length, stable, and controlling shareholders generates a situation in which stock options are not widely used in Japan.</description><author>Shinozaki, Shinya; Moriyasu, Hiroshi; Uchida, Konari</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creative Destruction and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grammig, Joachim; Jank, Stephan
We relate Schumpeter's notion of creative destruction to asset pricing, thereby offering a novel explanation of size and value premia. We argue that small-value firms must offer higher expected returns to compensate for the risk posed by serendipitous invention activity, whereas large-growth stocks provide protection against creative destruction and receive expected return discounts. A 2-factor model that accounts for creative-destruction risk effectively explains the cross-sectional return variation of size-and book-to-market-sorted portfolios. The estimated risk compensations associated with creative destruction are substantial and statistically significant, indicating their relevance for asset pricing.</description><author>Grammig, Joachim; Jank, Stephan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Horizon Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamara, Avraham; Korajczyk, Robert A.; Lou, Xiaoxia; Sadka, Ronnie
The literature documents heterogeneity in the delay of stock price reaction to systematic shocks, implying that asset risk depends on investment horizon. We study the pricing of risk factors across investment horizons. Value (liquidity) risk is priced over intermediate (short) horizons. Conditioning horizon-factor exposures on firm characteristics indicates that characteristics, with the exception of momentum, are not priced beyond their contribution to systematic risk. Long-horizon institutional investors overweight assets with high intermediate-horizon exposures to value risk and high short-horizon exposures to liquidity risk. The results highlight the importance of investment horizon in determining risk premia.</description><author>Kamara, Avraham; Korajczyk, Robert A.; Lou, Xiaoxia; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Risk and the Credit Crunch of 2007-2008: Evidence from Micro-Level Data on Mortgage Loan Applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antoniades, Adonis
Recent empirical studies have shown that during the financial crisis of 2007-2008, banks that were more heavily exposed to liquidity risk contracted their supply of credit more sharply. I contribute to the identification of this effect by relying on the use of micro-level data on U.S. mortgage loan applications, which allows me to identify liquidity risk as an important determinant of the contraction of credit in the mortgage market but as separate from the precipitous fall in credit demand, disruptions in the securitization and subprime markets, shifts in asset risk, and changing risk aversion among loan officers.</description><author>Antoniades, Adonis</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Frictions Affect Corporate Investment? A Structural Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bustamante, M. Cecilia
This paper provides a structural approach to testing investment equations based on the log-likelihood function of a nonlinear investment rule. The analysis integrates the predictions of the q-theory for the commonly studied active region of investment and provides new inferences on how real and financing frictions affect the probability that a firm invests. The empirical findings are consistent with the macro-finance literature suggesting that q-theory models with nonconvex investment frictions better explain the data. I also find that both real and financing costs of investment are related to the capital intensity of the industry in which firms operate.</description><author>Bustamante, M. Cecilia</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-Varying Liquidity and Momentum Profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Cheng, Si; Hameed, Allaudeen
A basic intuition is that arbitrage is easier when markets are most liquid. Surprisingly, we find that momentum profits are markedly larger in liquid market states. This finding is not explained by variation in liquidity risk, time-varying exposure to risk factors, or changes in macroeconomic condition, cross-sectional return dispersion, and investor sentiment. The predictive performance of aggregate market illiquidity for momentum profits uniformly exceeds that of market return and market volatility states. While momentum strategies have been unconditionally unprofitable in the United States, in Japan, and in the Eurozone countries in the last decade, they are substantial following liquid market states.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Cheng, Si; Hameed, Allaudeen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Urban Agglomeration and CEO Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar; John, Kose; Waisman, Maya
We examine the relation between the agglomeration of firms around big cities and chief executive officer (CEO) compensation. We find a positive relation among the metropolitan size of a firm's headquarters, the total and equity portion of its CEO's pay, and the quality of CEO educational attainment. We also find that CEOs gradually increase their human capital in major metropolitan areas and are rewarded for this upon relocation to smaller cities. Taken together, the results suggest that urban agglomeration reflects local network spillovers and faster learning of skilled individuals, for which firms are willing to pay a premium and which are therefore important factors in CEO compensation.</description><author>Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar; John, Kose; Waisman, Maya</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Holdings, Competition, and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lyandres, Evgeny; Palazzo, Berardino
We demonstrate theoretically and empirically that strategic considerations are important in shaping the cash policies of innovative firms. In our model, firms compete in product markets with uncertain structure using cash as a commitment device to invest in innovation. We show that firms' equilibrium cash holdings are related to the expected intensity of competition. The sign and magnitude of this relation depends on firms' financial constraints. Consistent with the strategic motive for hoarding cash, we show that firms' cash holdings are negatively affected by their rivals' cash-holding choices, even more so when competition is expected to be intense.</description><author>Lyandres, Evgeny; Palazzo, Berardino</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spreading the Misery? Sources of Bankruptcy Spillover in the Supply Chain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolay, Madhuparna; Lemmon, Michael; Tashjian, Elizabeth
We document that suppliers to purely financially distressed companies that are highly likely to reorganize in bankruptcy incur little or no spillover costs. In contrast, suppliers to economically distressed firms experience large losses in market value that are linked to proxies for the cost of replacing the bankrupt customers. Suppliers experience increased selling, general, and administrative (SG&amp;A) expenses and lower margins in the year following the bankruptcy of their trading partners, which we link to proxies for partner replacement costs. Suppliers continue to extend trade credit to firms that are healthier and in situations where the cost of replacing the partner is higher.</description><author>Kolay, Madhuparna; Lemmon, Michael; Tashjian, Elizabeth</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sentiment and the Effectiveness of Technical Analysis: Evidence from the Hedge Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smith, David M.; Wang, Na; Wang, Ying; Zychowicz, Edward J.
This article presents a unique test of the effectiveness of technical analysis in different sentiment environments by focusing on its usage by perhaps the most sophisticated and astute investors, namely, hedge fund managers. We document that during high-sentiment periods, hedge funds using technical analysis exhibit higher performance, lower risk, and superior market-timing ability than nonusers. The advantages of using technical analysis disappear or even reverse in low-sentiment periods. Our findings are consistent with the view that technical analysis is relatively more useful in high-sentiment periods with larger mispricing, which cannot be fully exploited by arbitrage activities because of short-sale impediments.</description><author>Smith, David M.; Wang, Na; Wang, Ying; Zychowicz, Edward J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Continuing Overreaction and Stock Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Byun, Suk Joon; Lim, Sonya S.; Yun, Sang Hyun
We study the return predictability of a measure of continuing overreaction based on the weighted average of signed volumes. We find that the strategies of buying stocks with upward continuing overreaction and selling stocks with downward continuing overreaction generate significant positive returns and that our measure of continuing overreaction is a better predictor of future returns than past returns. The results are stronger among stocks primarily held by investors more prone to biased self-attribution. Our results provide direct support for the model of return predictability based on overconfidence and biased self-attribution.</description><author>Byun, Suk Joon; Lim, Sonya S.; Yun, Sang Hyun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blockholder Heterogeneity, CEO Compensation, and Firm Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clifford, Christopher P.; Lindsey, Laura
This paper examines heterogeneity in blockholder monitoring across investor types. We document which blockholder types (e.g., mutual funds, hedge funds) are more likely to be associated with active monitoring and show that firms targeted by such blockholders are more likely to increase the equity portion of chief executive officer (CEO) pay. Further, using market-wide and exogenous shocks to liquidity to identify differences in efficacy across blockholder types, we observe greater operating-performance improvements in actively monitored firms when passive monitoring is less effective, suggesting causal impact. We propose differences in compensation arrangements across blockholder types as a mechanism underlying blockholders' heterogeneous role.</description><author>Clifford, Christopher P.; Lindsey, Laura</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric Information, Financial Reporting, and Open-Market Share Repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, Matthew T.; Yu, Miaomiao
We explore the link between open-market share repurchases (OMRs) and asymmetric information based on financial reporting quality and find that opaque firms experience positive abnormal returns of twice the magnitude of those of transparent firms. These significant differences remain after controlling for governance, earnings management, and firm characteristics. We document significantly positive long-run postannouncement returns for opaque firms, but not for transparent firms. We find that takeover activity and premiums rise with repurchase activity by opaque firms, which may explain some of the wealth effects. Our results suggest that asymmetric information plays an important role in the wealth effects around OMRs.</description><author>Billett, Matthew T.; Yu, Miaomiao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Competition Matter for Corporate Governance? The Role of Country Characteristics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cosset, Jean-Claude; Some, Hyacinthe Y.; Valery, Pascale
We investigate the role of country characteristics on the competition-governance relation. We find that competition is associated with higher ratings in corporate governance, but only in developing countries. Further, corporate governance is associated with greater firm value, but only in less competitive industries from developed countries. For developing countries, the evidence suggests that corporate governance is valuable mostly in competitive industries. Additional tests show that corporate governance increases labor productivity and cost efficiency, mostly in less competitive industries in both developed and developing countries. Furthermore, in developing countries, corporate governance increases investment in capital, but primarily in competitive industries.</description><author>Cosset, Jean-Claude; Some, Hyacinthe Y.; Valery, Pascale</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Determinants and Performance Impact of Outside Board Leadership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balsam, Steven; Puthenpurackal, John; Upadhyay, Arun
Outside board chairs are more likely in firms that are smaller, have greater stock volatility and research and development intensity, and have a lower proportion of inside directors and less institutional ownership; they are also more likely when chief executive officers have shorter tenure and lower ownership. We also find that the existence of an outside chair is associated with geographical and industry norms. An outside chair is positively associated with firm performance, a finding robust to various estimation methods, including event study and multivariate analyses incorporating controls for endogeneity, as well as market and accounting measures of performance. We note, however, that the relationship between outside chair and firm performance varies with firm characteristics.</description><author>Balsam, Steven; Puthenpurackal, John; Upadhyay, Arun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Human Capital, Management Quality, and the Exit Decisions of Entrepreneurial Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Shan; Li, C. Wei
We model the employee incentive problem jointly with a firm's exit decision. Our model predicts that firms in industries where human capital is important are more likely to go public and use high-powered, stock-based compensation. We also show that the higher the management quality, the more likely a firm is to go public than to be acquired. Regarding life cycle, a firm with high capital intensity and/or high management quality will choose to go public at a younger age.</description><author>He, Shan; Li, C. Wei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity Aversion and Underdiversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guidolin, Massimo; Liu, Hening
We examine asset allocation decisions under smooth ambiguity aversion when an investor has a prior degree of belief in the domestic capital asset pricing model (CAPM). Different from a Bayesian approach, the investor separately relies on the conditional distribution of returns and on the posterior over parameters to make decisions, rather than on the predictive distribution of returns that integrates priors and likelihood information. We find that in the perspective of U.S. investors, ambiguity aversion generates strong home bias in equity holdings, regardless of beliefs in the CAPM or risk aversion. Results become stronger under regime-switching investment opportunities.</description><author>Guidolin, Massimo; Liu, Hening</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Valuation with Macro-Finance Variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dorion, Christian
I propose a model in which the price of an option is partly determined by macro-finance variables. In an application using an index of current business conditions, the new model outperforms existing benchmarks in fitting underlying asset returns and in pricing options. The model performs particularly well when business conditions are deteriorating. Using the recent financial crisis as an out-of-sample experiment, the new model has option-pricing errors that are 18% below those of a nested 2-component volatility benchmark. Results are robust to using alternative business conditions proxies and comparing to different benchmark models.</description><author>Dorion, Christian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Government Interventions in the Financial Sector on Banking Competition and the Evolution of Zombie Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calderon, Cesar; Schaeck, Klaus
We investigate how government interventions such as blanket guarantees, liquidity support, recapitalizations, and nationalizations affect banking competition. These issues are critical for stability, access to finance, and economic growth. Exploiting cross-country and cross-time variation in the timing of interventions and accounting for their nonrandomness, we document that liquidity support, recapitalizations, and nationalizations trigger large increases in competition. We also find some more nuanced evidence that zombie banks' market shares in crisis countries evolve together with interventions. A higher frequency of interventions coincides with greater zombie bank presence, and increases in competition are larger when zombie banks occupy bigger market shares.</description><author>Calderon, Cesar; Schaeck, Klaus</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating Beta</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hollstein, Fabian; Prokopczuk, Marcel
We conduct a comprehensive comparison of market beta estimation techniques. We study the performance of several historical, time-series model, and option-implied estimators for estimating realized market beta. Thereby, we find the hybrid methodology of Buss and Vilkov to consistently outperform all other approaches. In addition, all other approaches, including fully implied and dynamic conditional beta, based on generalized autoregressive conditional heteroskedasticity (GARCH) models, are dominated by a simple beta estimate based on historical (co-)variances and an approach based on the Kalman filter. Our conclusions remain unchanged after performing several robustness checks.</description><author>Hollstein, Fabian; Prokopczuk, Marcel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment and Cash Flow: New Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewellen, Jonathan; Lewellen, Katharina
We study the investment-cash flow sensitivities of U.S. firms from 1971-2009. Our tests extend the literature in several key ways and provide strong evidence that cash flow explains investment beyond its correlation with q. A dollar of current-and prior-year cash flow is associated with $0.32 of additional investment for firms that are the least likely to be constrained and $0.63 of additional investment for firms that are the most likely to be constrained, even after correcting for measurement error in q. Our results suggest that financing constraints and free-cash-flow problems are important for investment decisions.</description><author>Lewellen, Jonathan; Lewellen, Katharina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Common Analyst Coverage Explain Excess Comovement?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Israelsen, Ryan D.
This article shows that correlated errors in news about fundamentals are an important, rational determinant of excess comovement. Individual analysts' forecast errors tend to be correlated across stocks. Using a proxy for correlated forecast errors based on analyst coverage, I find that stocks with similar sets of analysts exhibit more excess comovement, controlling for industry and other variables. Exogenous changes in commonality in analyst coverage around i) brokerage firm mergers and ii) additions to an index lead to changes in excess comovement. This information channel explains 10% to 25% of the increase in comovement around additions to the S&amp;P 500 index.</description><author>Israelsen, Ryan D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor Income, Relative Wealth Concerns, and the Cross Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomez, Juan-Pedro; Priestley, Richard; Zapatero, Fernando
The finance literature documents a relation between labor income and the cross section of stock returns. One possible explanation for this is the hedging decisions of investors with relative wealth concerns. This implies a negative risk premium associated with stock returns correlated with local undiversifiable wealth because investors are willing to pay more for stocks that help their hedging goals. We find evidence that is consistent with these regularities. In addition, we show that the effect varies across geographic areas depending on the size and variability of undiversifiable wealth, proxied by labor income.</description><author>Gomez, Juan-Pedro; Priestley, Richard; Zapatero, Fernando</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differential Access to Price Information in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen; Yang, Liyan
Recently, exchanges have been directly selling market data. We analyze how this practice affects price discovery, the cost of capital, return volatility, market liquidity, information production, and trader welfare. We show that selling price data increases the cost of capital and volatility, worsens market efficiency and liquidity, and discourages the production of fundamental information relative to a world in which all traders observe prices. Generally, allowing exchanges to sell price information benefits exchanges and harms liquidity traders. Overall, our results suggest that regulations on selling market data can play an important role in improving market quality and trader welfare.</description><author>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Investability on Asset Valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Errunza, Vihang; Ta, Hai
We develop an international asset pricing model to measure the impact of investability constraints on asset pricing. For a sample of 18 emerging markets, we use Standard &amp; Poor's investable weight factor (IWF) to show a 26.33% reduction in the cost of equity capital when non-investable firms become partially investable, with a further 12.51% reduction when partially investable firms become unrestricted. We demonstrate the generality and usefulness of the IWF by examining stocks with global/American depositary receipts and foreign institutional holdings as alternate investability proxies. Our results provide strong evidence of the economic benefits of market liberalization policies.</description><author>Errunza, Vihang; Ta, Hai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Capital Structure Adjustment and the Impact of Fractional Dependent Variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elsas, Ralf; Florysiak, David
Researchers in empirical corporate finance often use bounded ratios (e.g., debt ratios) as dependent variables in their regressions. Using the example of estimating the speed of adjustment toward target leverage, we show by Monte Carlo and resampling experiments that commonly applied estimators yield severely biased estimates, as they ignore that debt ratios are fractional (i.e., bounded between 0 and 1). We propose a new unbiased estimator for adjustment speed in the presence of fractional dependent variables that also controls for unobserved heterogeneity and unbalanced panel data. This new estimator is suitable for corporate finance applications beyond capital structure research.</description><author>Elsas, Ralf; Florysiak, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Entrenchment and Firm Value: A Dynamic Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Xin; Zhang, Hong Feng
We examine the impact of managerial entrenchment on firm value using a dynamic model with firm fixed effects. To estimate the model, we employ the long-difference technique, which is shown by our simulation to deliver the least biased estimates. Based on a large sample of U.S. companies, we document a significantly negative and causal effect of managerial entrenchment on firm value after taking into account omitted variables, reverse causality, and highly persistent endogenous variables. Additional analysis suggests that the causality running from managerial entrenchment to firm value is more pronounced than that for reverse causality.</description><author>Chang, Xin; Zhang, Hong Feng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informational Content of Options Trading on Acquirer Announcement Return</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Konan; Ge, Li; Lin, Tse-Chun
This study examines the informational content of options trading on acquirer announcement returns. We show that implied volatility spread predicts positively on the cumulative abnormal return (CAR), and implied volatility skew predicts negatively on the CAR. The predictability is much stronger around actual merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) announcement days, as compared with pseudo-event days. The prediction is weaker if pre-M&amp;A stock price has incorporated part of the information, but stronger if the acquirer's options trading is more liquid. Finally, we find that a higher relative trading volume of options to stock predicts higher absolute CARs. The relation also exists among the target firms.</description><author>Chan, Konan; Ge, Li; Lin, Tse-Chun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Business Cycles and Local Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernile, Gennaro; Korniotis, George; Kumar, Alok; Wang, Qin
This study examines whether state-level economic conditions affect the liquidity of local firms. We find that liquidity levels of local stocks are higher (lower) when the local economy has performed well (poorly). This relation is stronger when local financing constraints are more binding, the local information environment is more opaque, and local institutional ownership levels and trading intensity are higher. Overall the evidence supports the notion that the geographical segmentation of U.S. capital markets generates predictable patterns in local liquidity.</description><author>Bernile, Gennaro; Korniotis, George; Kumar, Alok; Wang, Qin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Increased Competition Affect Credit Ratings? A Reexamination of the Effect of Fitch's Market Share on Credit Ratings in the Corporate Bond Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, Kee-Hong; Kang, Jun-Koo; Wang, Jin
We examine two competing views regarding the impact of competition among credit rating agencies on rating quality: the view that rating agencies do not sacrifice their reputation by inflating firm ratings, and the view that competition among rating agencies arising from the conflict of interest inherent in an "issuer pay" model creates pressure to inflate ratings. Using Fitch's market share as a measure of competition among rating agencies and controlling for the endogeneity problem caused by unobservable industry effects, we find no relation between Fitch's market share and ratings, suggesting that competition does not lead to rating inflation.</description><author>Bae, Kee-Hong; Kang, Jun-Koo; Wang, Jin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamics of Sovereign Credit Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jeanneret, Alexandre
This article proposes a structural model for sovereign credit risk with endogenous sovereign debt and default policies. A maximum-likelihood estimation of the model with local stock market prices generates daily model-implied sovereign spreads. This approach explains two-thirds of the daily variation in observed sovereign spreads for emerging and European economies over the 2000-2011 period. Global factors help to further explain the time variation in sovereign credit risk. In particular, sovereign spreads in emerging markets vary with U.S. market uncertainty, whereas European spreads depend on Euro-zone bond factors.</description><author>Jeanneret, Alexandre</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving Mean Variance Optimization through Sparse Hedging Restrictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goto, Shingo; Xu, Yan
In portfolio risk minimization, the inverse covariance matrix prescribes the hedge trades in which a stock is hedged by all the other stocks in the portfolio. In practice with finite samples, however, multicollinearity makes the hedge trades too unstable and unreliable. By shrinking trade sizes and reducing the number of stocks in each hedge trade, we propose a "sparse" estimator of the inverse covariance matrix. Comparing favorably with other methods (equal weighting, shrunk covariance matrix, industry factor model, nonnegativity constraints), a portfolio formed on the proposed estimator achieves significant out-of-sample risk reduction and improves certainty equivalent returns after transaction costs.</description><author>Goto, Shingo; Xu, Yan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading Patterns and Market Integration in Overlapping Experimental Asset Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chelley-Steeley, Patricia; Kluger, Brian; Steeley, James; Adams, Paul
This paper examines trading patterns and market integration using laboratory asset markets. Our markets are designed to approximately correspond to the trading day for stocks cross-listed in markets in Europe and North America. Some of our markets feature timing restrictions so that participants cannot trade across markets except during a fully integrated overlap period. Comparison of markets with and without timing restrictions shows that restrictions reduce trading activity and shift transactions to the overlap period. When asset values are extreme, price discovery can be impeded when trading restrictions exist. The measurement of liquidity suggests that trading restrictions increase overall spreads.</description><author>Chelley-Steeley, Patricia; Kluger, Brian; Steeley, James; Adams, Paul</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Parameter Uncertainty in Multiperiod Portfolio Optimization with Transaction Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMiguel, Victor; Martin-Utrera, Alberto; Nogales, Francisco J.
We study the impact of parameter uncertainty on the expected utility of a multiperiod investor subject to quadratic transaction costs. We characterize the utility loss associated with ignoring parameter uncertainty, and show that it is equal to the product between the single-period utility loss and another term that captures the effects of the multiperiod mean-variance utility and transaction cost losses. To mitigate the impact of parameter uncertainty, we propose two multiperiod shrinkage portfolios and demonstrate with simulated and empirical data sets that they substantially outperform portfolios that ignore parameter uncertainty, transaction costs, or both.</description><author>DeMiguel, Victor; Martin-Utrera, Alberto; Nogales, Francisco J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflicts in Bankruptcy and the Sequence of Debt Issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ravid, S. Abraham; Sverdlove, Ronald; Bris, Arturo; Coiculescu, Gabriela
This paper investigates the optimal sequencing of debt issues. Our theoretical model suggests that once firms issue debt with one level of seniority, they may have an incentive to alternate seniorities, because of violations of the priced absolute priority rule (APR). When we introduce explicit costs of class conflict, the model yields cases of alternating seniorities and other cases in which firms issue only one class of debt. The implications of the model are consistent with the observed regularities in a large database of debt issues. We test several other implications of our model as well.</description><author>Ravid, S. Abraham; Sverdlove, Ronald; Bris, Arturo; Coiculescu, Gabriela</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Activist Hedge Funds in Financially Distressed Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Jongha
In this paper I investigate the role of activist hedge funds in the restructuring of a sample of 469 firms that attempted to resolve distress either out of court, in conventional Chapter 11, or via prepackaged restructuring. Activist hedge funds strategically gain a position of influence in the restructuring of economically viable firms with contracting problems that prevent efficient restructuring without outside intervention. I find that hedge fund involvement is associated with a higher probability of completing prepackaged restructurings, faster restructurings, and greater debt reduction. Overall, the evidence in this article suggests that activist hedge funds can create value by enabling more efficient contracting.</description><author>Lim, Jongha</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skin in the Game versus Skimming the Game: Governance, Share Restrictions, and Insider Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozik, Gideon; Sadka, Ronnie
This paper advances the proposition that share restrictions engender potential conflicts of interest between fund managers and investors. Fund flows predict future fund returns for share-restricted funds, especially among funds with low levels of governance and funds managing insiders' wealth, providing managers incentive to trade in advance of their clients. Some direct evidence for such managerial action is presented, using proprietary data on managerial investment in their own funds. The evidence suggests that private information about a fund, not necessarily its holdings, may constitute material information, with implications for proper fund governance and disclosure policy concerning managerial actions.</description><author>Ozik, Gideon; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Biases and the Pricing of Cross-Sectional Idiosyncratic Volatility around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Yufeng; Hu, Ting; Lesmond, David A.
This paper examines data from 45 world markets and shows that the previously documented relation between mean returns and idiosyncratic volatility arises because of biases in volatility estimates that we can attribute to the bid-ask bounce in trade prices. We show that no significant relation exists between mean returns and idiosyncratic volatility estimated from quote-midpoint returns. Further, there is no significant relation between mean returns and the portion of transaction-price-based idiosyncratic volatility that is orthogonal to bid-ask spreads. The pricing of idiosyncratic volatility is due to the negative pricing of the bid-ask spread.</description><author>Han, Yufeng; Hu, Ting; Lesmond, David A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Momentum an Echo?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyal, Amit; Wahal, Sunil
In the United States, momentum portfolios formed from 12 to 7 months prior to the current month deliver higher future returns than momentum portfolios formed from 6 to 2 months prior, suggesting an "echo" in returns. In 37 countries excluding the United States, there is no robust evidence of such an echo. In portfolios that combine securities in developed and emerging markets, or across three major geographic regions (Americas excluding United States, Asia, and Europe), there is also no evidence of an echo. Any echo in the United States appears to be driven largely by a carryover of short-term reversals from month -2.</description><author>Goyal, Amit; Wahal, Sunil</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did TARP Banks Get Competitive Advantages?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Roman, Raluca A.
We investigate whether the Troubled Assets Relief Program (TARP) gave recipients competitive advantages. Using a difference-in-difference (DID) approach, we find that: i) TARP recipients received competitive advantages and increased both their market shares and market power; ii) results may be driven primarily by the safety channel (TARP banks may be perceived as safer), which is partially offset by the cost-disadvantage channel (TARP funds may be relatively expensive); and iii) these competitive advantages are primarily or entirely due to TARP banks that repaid early. These results may help explain other findings in the literature, and yield important policy implications.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Roman, Raluca A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lending Relationships and the Effect of Bank Distress: Evidence from the 2007-2009 Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carvalho, Daniel; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro
We study the transmission of bank distress to nonfinancial firms from 34 countries during the 2007-2009 financial crisis using systemic and bank-specific shocks. We find that bank distress is associated with equity valuation losses and investment cuts to borrower firms with the strongest lending relationships with banks. The losses are not offset by borrowers' access to public debt markets and are concentrated in firms with the greatest information asymmetry problems and weakest financial positions. Our findings suggest that public debt markets do not mitigate the effects of relationship bank distress during financial crises.</description><author>Carvalho, Daniel; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneity in Beliefs and Volatility Tail Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Madan, Dilip; Panayotov, George
We propose a model of volatility tail behavior in which investors display aversion to both low-volatility and high-volatility states, and hence, the derived pricing kernel exhibits an increasing and decreasing region in the volatility dimension. The model features investors who have heterogeneity in beliefs about volatility outcomes and maximize their utility by choosing volatility-contingent cash flows. Our empirical examination suggests that the model is better suited to reproduce data features in the left tail of the volatility distribution, both qualitatively and quantitatively.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Madan, Dilip; Panayotov, George</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign Currency Returns and Systematic Risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanasov, Victoria; Nitschka, Thomas
We apply an empirical approximation of the intertemporal capital asset pricing model (ICAPM) to show that cross-sectional dispersion in currency returns can be rationalized by differences in currency excess returns' sensitivities to the market return's cash-flow news component. This finding echoes recent explanations of the value and growth stock market anomaly. The distinction between cash-flow news and discount-rate news is key to jointly explain average stock and currency returns. Our analysis reveals the presence of a common source of systematic risk in stock and foreign currency returns that is reflected in the market return's cash-flow news component.</description><author>Atanasov, Victoria; Nitschka, Thomas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Diminishing Liquidity Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Kadan, Ohad; Wohl, Avi
Stock liquidity has improved over the recent 4 decades. This improvement was accompanied by a dramatic increase in trading activity. The net effect on the liquidity premium is ambiguous. We show that the characteristic liquidity premium of U.S. stocks has significantly declined over the past 4 decades. In recent years, characteristic liquidity is significantly priced only for the smallest common stocks. This decline stems from an improvement in liquidity and from a lower sensitivity of expected returns to liquidity. By contrast, systematic liquidity has not been trending down and is still significantly priced primarily among NASDAQ stocks.</description><author>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Kadan, Ohad; Wohl, Avi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Religion and Stock Price Crash Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Callen, Jeffrey L.; Fang, Xiaohua
This study examines whether religiosity at the county level is associated with future stock price crash risk. We find robust evidence that firms headquartered in counties with higher levels of religiosity exhibit lower levels of future stock price crash risk. This finding is consistent with the view that religion, as a set of social norms, helps to curb bad-news-hoarding activities by managers. Our evidence further shows that the negative relation between religiosity and future crash risk is stronger for riskier firms and for firms with weaker governance mechanisms measured by shareholder takeover rights and dedicated institutional ownership.</description><author>Callen, Jeffrey L.; Fang, Xiaohua</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Once Burned, Twice Shy: Money Market Fund Responses to a Systemic Liquidity Shock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Strahan, Philip E.; Tanyeri, Basak
After Lehman's collapse in 2008, investors ran from risky money market funds. In 27 funds, outflows overwhelmed cash inflows, thus forcing asset sales. These funds sold their safest and most liquid holdings. Funds were thus left with riskier and longer maturity assets. Over the subsequent quarter, however, the hard-hit funds reduced risk more than other funds. In contrast, money funds hit by idiosyncratic liquidity shocks before Lehman did not alter portfolio risk. The result suggests that moral hazard concerns with the Treasury Guarantee of investor claims did not increase risk taking. Funds that benefited most from the government bailout reduced risk.</description><author>Strahan, Philip E.; Tanyeri, Basak</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industries and Stock Return Reversals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hameed, Allaudeen; Mian, G. Mujtaba
This paper documents pervasive evidence of intra-industry reversals in monthly returns. Unlike the conventional reversal strategy based on stock returns relative to the market portfolio, we document intra-industry return reversals that are larger in magnitude, consistently present over time, and prevalent across subgroups of stocks, including large and liquid stocks. These return reversals are driven by order imbalances and noninformational shocks. Consistent with reversals representing compensation for supplying liquidity, intra-industry reversals are stronger following aggregate market declines and volatile times, reflecting binding capital constraints and limited risk-bearing capacity of liquidity providers.</description><author>Hameed, Allaudeen; Mian, G. Mujtaba</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Mortality and Natal Financial Care</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Borisov, Alexander; Yu, Xiaoyun
We construct a mortality table for U.S. public companies during 1985-2006. We find that the age-specific mortality rates of firms initially increase, peaking at age three, and then decrease with age, implying that the first 3 years of public life are critical. Financial intermediaries involved around the "public birth" of a firm (e.g., venture capitalists (VCs) and high-quality underwriters) are associated with lower firm mortality rates, sometimes for up to 7 years after the initial public offering (IPO). VCs reduce mortality rates more through natal financial care than through selection, whereas high-quality underwriters affect firm mortality more through selection.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Borisov, Alexander; Yu, Xiaoyun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend Yields, Dividend Growth, and Return Predictability in the Cross Section of Stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maio, Paulo; Santa-Clara, Pedro
There is a generalized conviction that variation in dividend yields is exclusively related to expected returns and not to expected dividend growth, for example, Cochrane's (2011) presidential address. We show that this pattern, although valid for the aggregate stock market, is not true for portfolios of small and value stocks, where dividend yields are related mainly to future dividend changes. Thus, the variance decomposition associated with the aggregate dividend yield has important heterogeneity in the cross section of equities. Our results are robust to different forecasting horizons, econometric methodology (long-horizon regressions or first-order vector autoregression), and alternative decomposition based on excess returns.</description><author>Maio, Paulo; Santa-Clara, Pedro</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Acquirer Valuation and Acquisition Decisions: Identifying Mispricing Using Short Interest</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-David, Itzhak; Drake, Michael S.; Roulstone, Darren T.
We use short interest as an investor-based measure of over-or undervaluation that distinguishes between the misvaluation and Q-theories of mergers. Using this measure, we find that misvaluation is a strong determinant of merger decision-making. Firms in the top quintile of short interest are 54% more likely to engage in stock acquisitions and 22% less likely to engage in cash acquisitions. Stock (but not cash) acquirers have higher short interest than their targets. Overall, our results suggest that the previously documented underperformance of stock acquirers and the overperformance of cash acquirers can be explained by misvaluation, as captured by short interest.</description><author>Ben-David, Itzhak; Drake, Michael S.; Roulstone, Darren T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Credit Default Swaps a Sideshow? Evidence That Information Flows from Equity to CDS Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hilscher, Jens; Pollet, Joshua M.; Wilson, Mungo
This article provides evidence that equity returns lead credit protection returns at daily and weekly frequencies, whereas credit protection returns do not lead equity returns. Our results indicate that informed traders are primarily active in the equity market rather than the credit default swap (CDS) market. These findings are consistent with standard theories of market selection by informed traders in which market selection is determined partially by transaction costs. We also find that credit protection returns respond more quickly during salient news events (earnings announcements) compared to days with similar equity returns and turnover. This evidence provides support for explanations related to investor inattention.</description><author>Hilscher, Jens; Pollet, Joshua M.; Wilson, Mungo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust, Investment, and Business Contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, James S.; Cheng, Yingmei; Wu, Chaopeng
How does trust affect business contracting at the firm level? We analyze the case of foreign high-tech companies investing in China, where the risk of expropriation of their intellectual property is high. We find that firms mitigate this type of risk by taking local trustworthiness into account when making investment decisions. Firms prefer to invest in regions where local partners and employees are considered more trustworthy; they are also more likely to establish joint ventures and to make greater research and development investments. We employ instrumental variable regressions and dynamic panel generalized method of moments estimators to alleviate endogeneity concerns and control for time-invariant heterogeneity.</description><author>Ang, James S.; Cheng, Yingmei; Wu, Chaopeng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Securities Class Action Litigation on Corporate Liquidity and Investment Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arena, Matteo; Julio, Brandon
The risk of securities class action litigation alters corporate savings and investment policy. Firms with greater exposure to securities litigation hold significantly more cash in anticipation of future settlements and other related costs. The result is due to firms accumulating cash in anticipation of lawsuits and not a consequence of plaintiffs targeting firms with high cash levels. The market value of cash is lower for firms exposed to litigation risk. Corporate investment decisions are also affected by litigation risk, as firms reduce capital expenditures in response. Our results are robust to endogeneity concerns and possible spurious temporal effects.</description><author>Arena, Matteo; Julio, Brandon</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Happy People Make Optimistic Investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplanski, Guy; Levy, Haim; Veld, Chris; Veld-Merkoulova, Yulia
Do happy people predict future risk and return differently from unhappy people, or do individuals rely only on economic facts? We survey investors on their subjective sentiment-creating factors, return and risk expectations, and investment plans. We find that noneconomic factors systematically affect return and risk expectations, where the return effect is more profound. Investment plans are also affected by noneconomic factors. Sports results and general feelings significantly affect predictions. Sufferers from seasonal affective disorder have lower return expectations in the autumn than in other seasons, supporting the winter blues hypothesis.</description><author>Kaplanski, Guy; Levy, Haim; Veld, Chris; Veld-Merkoulova, Yulia</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticipating the 2007-2008 Financial Crisis: Who Knew What and When Did They Know It?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adebambo, Biljana; Brockman, Paul; Yan, Xuemin
We examine the ability of three groups of informed market participants to anticipate the 2007-2008 financial crisis. Institutional investors and financial analysts exhibit some awareness of the impending crisis in their preference for nonfinancial stocks over financial stocks. In contrast, corporate insiders of financial firms appear to be completely unaware of the timing and extent of the financial crisis. Net purchases by managers of financial firms exceed those by managers of nonfinancial firms over the entire 2006-2008 period. Our results add considerable weight to the argument that the financial crisis was more a case of flawed judgment than flawed incentives.</description><author>Adebambo, Biljana; Brockman, Paul; Yan, Xuemin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond the Carry Trade: Optimal Currency Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barroso, Pedro; Santa-Clara, Pedro
We test the relevance of technical and fundamental variables in forming currency portfolios. Carry, momentum, and value reversal all contribute to portfolio performance, whereas the real exchange rate and the current account do not. The resulting optimal portfolio produces out-of-sample returns that are not explained by risk and are valuable to diversified investors holding stocks and bonds. Exposure to currencies increases the Sharpe ratio of diversified portfolios by 0.5 on average, while reducing crash risk. We argue that besides risk, currency returns reflect the scarcity of speculative capital.</description><author>Barroso, Pedro; Santa-Clara, Pedro</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry Expertise of Independent Directors and Board Monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Cong; Xie, Fei; Zhu, Min
We examine whether the industry expertise of independent directors affects board monitoring effectiveness. We find that the presence of independent directors with industry experience on a firm's audit committee significantly curtails firms' earnings management. In addition, a greater representation of independent directors with industry expertise on a firm's compensation committee reduces chief executive officer (CEO) excess compensation, and a greater presence of such directors on the full board increases the CEO turnover-performance sensitivity and improves acquirer returns from diversifying acquisitions. Overall, the evidence is consistent with the hypothesis that having relevant industry expertise enhances independent directors' ability to perform their monitoring function.</description><author>Wang, Cong; Xie, Fei; Zhu, Min</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Director Histories and the Pattern of Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rousseau, Peter L.; Stroup, Caleb
We trace directors through time and across firms to study whether acquirers' access to nonpublic information about potential targets via their directors' past board service histories affects the market for corporate control. In a sample of publicly traded U.S. firms, we find acquirers about 4.5 times more likely to buy firms where their directors once served. Effects are stronger when the acquirer has better corporate governance, the interlocked director has a larger ownership stake at the acquirer, or the director played an important role during past service. The findings are robust to endogeneity of board composition and controls for contemporaneous interfirm interlocks.</description><author>Rousseau, Peter L.; Stroup, Caleb</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>You're Fired! New Evidence on Portfolio Manager Turnover and Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kostovetsky, Leonard; Warner, Jerold B.
We study managerial turnover for both internally managed mutual funds and those managed externally by subadvisors. We argue that turnover of subadvisors provides sharper tests and helps address several unresolved issues and puzzles from the previous literature. We find dramatically stronger inverse relations between subadvisor departures and lagged returns, and new evidence on how past flow predicts turnover. We find no evidence of improvements in return performance related to departures, but flow improvements are associated with departures of poor past performers. Our findings represent new evidence on how investors, sponsors, and boards learn about and evaluate mutual fund management performance.</description><author>Kostovetsky, Leonard; Warner, Jerold B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Giants at the Gate: Investment Returns and Diseconomies of Scale in Private Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lopez-de-Silanes, Florencio; Phalippou, Ludovic; Gottschalg, Oliver
We document the wide dispersion of private equity investment returns and examine performance determinants using a newly constructed database of 7,500 investments worldwide. One in 10 investments does not return any money, whereas 1 in 4 has an internal rate of return (IRR) above 50%. Quick flips are associated with the highest returns. Performance does not appear scalable: Investments held by private equity firms in periods with a high number of simultaneous investments underperform substantially. Results are consistent with the theoretical literature on organizational diseconomies linked to firm structure. Private equity firms' actions do not appear to be mechanical or easily scalable.</description><author>Lopez-de-Silanes, Florencio; Phalippou, Ludovic; Gottschalg, Oliver</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Suitability Checks and Household Investments in Structured Products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Eric C.; Tang, Dragon Yongjun; Ben Zhang, Miao
The suitability of complex financial products for household investors is an important issue in light of consumer financial protection. The U.S. Dodd-Frank Act, for instance, mandates that distributors check suitability when selling structured products to retail investors. However, little empirical evidence exists on such transactions. Using data from Hong Kong, we find that investors purchase 8% more structured products, on average, when the suitability is not checked. The effect of suitability checks is more pronounced for less financially literate investors. Moreover, investors tend to buy products with lower risk-adjusted returns when product suitability is not checked.</description><author>Chang, Eric C.; Tang, Dragon Yongjun; Ben Zhang, Miao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Related Securities and Equity Market Quality: The Case of CDS</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Chava, Sudheer; Tookes, Heather E.
We document that equity markets become less liquid and equity prices become less efficient when markets for single-name credit default swap (CDS) contracts emerge. This finding is robust across a variety of market quality measures. We analyze the potential mechanisms driving this result and find evidence consistent with negative trader-driven information spillovers that result from the introduction of CDS. These spillovers greatly outweigh the potentially positive effects associated with completing markets (e.g., CDS markets increase hedging opportunities) when firms and their equity markets are in "bad" states. In "good" states, we find some evidence that CDS markets can be beneficial.</description><author>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Chava, Sudheer; Tookes, Heather E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Post-Acquisition Returns of Stock Deals: Evidence of the Pervasiveness of the Asset Growth Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mortal, Sandra; Schill, Michael J.
A growing literature finds that firm asset growth rates are negatively correlated with subsequent stock returns. We show that the poor post-deal returns that have been documented for stock acquisitions are more precisely explained by the return effects associated with systematically larger asset growth rates for stock deals. We find a similar result for other cross-sectional and time-series acquisition effects, including poor returns for glamour deals, weakly monitored deals, and deals done during high-valuation periods. We suggest that the distinguishing characteristic associated with poor performing acquisitions is simply their tendency to grow assets.</description><author>Mortal, Sandra; Schill, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bonus-Driven Repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Yingmei; Harford, Jarrad; Zhang, Tianming
Using a large hand-collected database of chief executive officer (CEO) bonus structures, we find that when a CEO's bonus is directly tied to earnings per share (EPS), his company is more likely to conduct a buyback. This effect is especially pronounced when a company's EPS is right below the threshold for a bonus award. Share repurchasing increases the probability the CEO receives a bonus and the magnitude of that bonus, but only when bonus pay is EPS based. Bonus-driven repurchasing firms do not exhibit positive long-run abnormal returns.</description><author>Cheng, Yingmei; Harford, Jarrad; Zhang, Tianming</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Investors and the Information Production Theory of Stock Splits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Hu, Gang; Huang, Jiekun
We make use of a large sample of transaction-level institutional trading data to test an extended version of Brennan and Hughes' (1991) information production theory of stock splits. We compare brokerage commissions paid by institutional investors before and after a split, assess the private information held by them, and relate the informativeness of their trading to brokerage commissions paid. We show that institutions make abnormal profits net of brokerage commissions by trading in splitting stocks. We also show that the information asymmetry faced by firms goes down after stock splits. Overall, our empirical results support the information production theory.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Hu, Gang; Huang, Jiekun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changing the Nexus: The Evolution and Renegotiation of Venture Capital Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bengtsson, Ola; Sensoy, Berk A.
We study the evolution and renegotiation of the cash-flow rights that venture capitalists (VCs) obtain in their portfolio companies. When company performance between financing rounds is poor, subsequent contracts contain stronger VC cash-flow rights, and existing VCs tend to either give new VCs senior claims or forfeit their existing rights altogether. These results are consistent with the importance of financing problems between different VCs and with theory predicting that financing frictions worsen with poor performance. A consequence is that VC cash-flow rights are frequently significantly diluted before exit, implying that VC investments are riskier than previously estimated.</description><author>Bengtsson, Ola; Sensoy, Berk A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Government in the Labor-Creditor Relationship: Evidence from the Chrysler Bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blaylock, Bradley; Edwards, Alexander; Stanfield, Jared
We examine the role of government in the labor-creditor relationship using the case of the Chrysler bankruptcy. As a result of the government intervention, firms in more unionized industries experienced lower event-window abnormal bond returns, higher abnormal bond yields, and lower cumulative abnormal bond returns. The results are stronger for firms closer to distress. We also observe the effect in firms in which labor bargaining power is stronger and those with larger pension liabilities. Overall, the results underline the importance of government as a significant force in shaping the agency conflict between creditors and workers.</description><author>Blaylock, Bradley; Edwards, Alexander; Stanfield, Jared</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Structure Decisions around the World: Which Factors Are Reliably Important?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oeztekin, Oezde
This article examines the international determinants of capital structure using a large sample of firms from 37 countries. The reliable determinants for leverage are firm size, tangibility, industry leverage, profits, and inflation. The quality of the countries' institutions affects leverage and the adjustment speed toward target leverage in significant ways. High-quality institutions lead to faster leverage adjustments, whereas laws and traditions that safeguard debt holders relative to stockholders (e.g., more effective bankruptcy procedures and stronger creditor protection) lead to higher leverage.</description><author>Oeztekin, Oezde</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes and Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faccio, Mara; Xu, Jin
We use nearly 500 shifts in statutory corporate and personal income tax rates as natural experiments to assess the effect of corporate and personal taxes on capital structure. We find both corporate and personal income taxes to be significant determinants of capital structure. Based on ex post observed summary statistics, across Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Development (OECD) countries, taxes appear to be as important as other traditional variables in explaining capital structure choices. The results are stronger among corporate tax payers, dividend payers, and companies that are more likely to have an individual as the marginal investor.</description><author>Faccio, Mara; Xu, Jin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sophistication, Sentiment, and Misreaction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Chuang-Chang; Hsieh, Pei-Fang; Wang, Yaw-Huei
This study investigates whether the existence or strength of any misreaction in the options market is affected by investor sophistication and investor sentiment. Based on a unique data set of the complete history of all transactions in the Taiwan options market, we find that individual investors exhibit significant misreaction to information and that this misreaction becomes stronger during periods of high investor sentiment. In addition, more active or aggressive individual investors always exhibit misreaction and do not learn from their past mistakes. Our empirical results are robust to alternative measures of investor sentiment and definitions of long- and short-term horizons.</description><author>Chang, Chuang-Chang; Hsieh, Pei-Fang; Wang, Yaw-Huei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Future Lending Income and Security Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prado, Melissa Porras
I test the Duffie, Garleanu, and Pedersen hypothesis that security prices incorporate expected future securities lending income. To determine whether institutional investors anticipate gains from future lending of securities, I examine their trading behavior around loan-fee increases. The evidence suggests that institutions buy shares in response to an increase in lending fees, and that this could explain the premium associated with high-lending-fee stocks. Expected future lending income affects stock prices, although the effect seems to be attenuated by the negative information that arises from short selling.</description><author>Prado, Melissa Porras</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Keynes the Stock Market Investor: A Quantitative Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chambers, David; Dimson, Elroy; Foo, Justin
The consensus view of the influential economist John Maynard Keynes is that he was a stellar investor. We provide an extensive quantitative appraisal of his performance over a quarter century and present detailed analysis of his archived trading records. His top-down approach initially generated disappointing returns with no evidence of any market-timing ability. However, from the early 1930s his performance improved as he evolved into a bottom-up stock picker with substantial active risk and pronounced size and value tilts. Our reconstruction of Keynes's stock trading provides a unique record of realized performance and sheds light on how equity investing developed historically.</description><author>Chambers, David; Dimson, Elroy; Foo, Justin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Synthesis of Two Factor Estimation Methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Connor, Gregory; Korajczyk, Robert A.; Uhlaner, Robert T.
Two-pass cross-sectional regression (TPCSR) is frequently used in estimating factor risk premia. Recent papers argue that the common practice of grouping assets into portfolios to reduce the errors-in-variables (EIV) problem leads to loss of efficiency and masks potential deviations from asset pricing models. One solution that allows the use of individual assets while overcoming the EIV problem is iterated TPCSR (ITPCSR). ITPCSR converges to a fixed point regardless of the initial factors chosen. ITPCSR is intimately linked to the asymptotic principal components (APC) method of estimating factors since the ITPCSR estimates are the APC estimates, up to a rotation.</description><author>Connor, Gregory; Korajczyk, Robert A.; Uhlaner, Robert T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Important Is Financial Risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Brown, Gregory W.; Waller, William
We explore the determinants of equity price risk of nonfinancial corporations. Operating and asset characteristics are by far the most important determinants of risk. For the median firm, financial risk accounts for only 15% of observed stock price volatility. Furthermore, financial risk has declined over the last 3 decades, indicating that any upward trend in equity volatility was driven entirely by economic risk factors. This explains why financial distress (as opposed to economic distress) was surprisingly uncommon in the nonfinancial sector during the 2007-2009 crisis even as measures of equity volatility reached unprecedented highs.</description><author>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Brown, Gregory W.; Waller, William</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Enterprise Multiple Investment Strategy: International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Walkshaeusl, Christian; Lobe, Sebastian
The enterprise multiple (EM) predicts the cross section of international returns. The return predictability of EM is similarly pronounced in developed and emerging markets and likewise strong among small and large firms. An international portfolio of low-EM firms outperforms a portfolio of high-EM firms by about 1% per month. The EM value premium is individually significant for the majority of countries, remains largely unexplained by existing asset pricing models, is robust after controlling for comovement with the respective U.S. premium, and is highly persistent for up to 5 years after portfolio formation, making it a promising strategy for investors.</description><author>Walkshaeusl, Christian; Lobe, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Influence in the Housing Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Carrie H.; Pirinsky, Christo A.
We utilize the decennial U.S. Census to study social effects in housing consumption across 4 million households from 126 ethnic groups and 2,071 geographic locations in the United States. We find that the homeownership decisions within ethnic groups are locally correlated, after controlling for the homeownership rates within the group and the region. Social influence is stronger for younger, less educated, and lower-income individuals; immigrants; and Americans with ancestors from more unequal, uncertainty-avoiding, and collectivistic cultures. Our results suggest that both status and information considerations play an important role in the social comparison process in capital markets.</description><author>Pan, Carrie H.; Pirinsky, Christo A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Sentiment and Mutual Fund Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Yadav, Vijay
We show that mutual funds employ portfolio strategies based on market sentiment. We build a proxy for the degree of a fund's sentiment beta (or FSB). The low-FSB funds outperform high-FSB funds, even after controlling for standard risk factors and fund characteristics. This effect is sizable and delivers a net-of-risk performance of 3.8% per year. Funds with a lower FSB follow more idiosyncratic strategies, suggesting that FSB is a deliberate, active choice of the fund manager. A sentiment contrarian strategy leads to high flows due to its superior performance, whereas a sentiment catering strategy fails to attract significant investor flows.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Yadav, Vijay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using 10-K Text to Gauge Financial Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Loughran, Tim; McDonald, Bill
Measuring the extent to which a firm is financially constrained is critical in assessing capital structure. Extant measures of financial constraints focus on macro firm characteristics such as age and size, variables highly correlated with other firm attributes. We parse 10-K disclosures filed with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) using a unique lexicon based on constraining words. We find that the frequency of constraining words exhibits very low correlation with traditional measures of financial constraints and predicts subsequent liquidity events, such as dividend omissions or increases, equity recycling, and underfunded pensions, better than widely used financial constraint indexes.</description><author>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Loughran, Tim; McDonald, Bill</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spillover Effects among Financial Institutions: A State-Dependent Sensitivity Value-at-Risk Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Zeno; Fuess, Roland; Gropp, Reint
In this paper, we develop a state-dependent sensitivity value-at-risk (SDSVaR) approach that enables us to quantify the direction, size, and duration of risk spillovers among financial institutions as a function of the state of financial markets (tranquil, normal, and volatile). For four sets of major financial institutions (commercial banks, investment banks, hedge funds, and insurance companies), we show that while small during normal times, equivalent shocks lead to considerable spillover effects in volatile market periods. Commercial banks and, especially, hedge funds appear to play a major role in the transmission of shocks to other financial institutions.</description><author>Adams, Zeno; Fuess, Roland; Gropp, Reint</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Specificity, Industry-Driven Recovery Risk, and Loan Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>James, Christopher; Kizilaslan, Atay
This paper examines the relationship between a firm's exposure to industry downturns that we call industry risk and bank loan pricing. We measure industry risk based on the relationship between a firm's stock returns and industry returns conditional on an industry downturn. We find industry risk is significantly related to the recovery rates in bankruptcy and the likelihood of the firm experiencing financial distress when its peers are also in distress. More importantly, we find that the spreads on unsecured bank loans are positively related to industry risk measures. These relationships are stronger for firms with more industry-specific assets.</description><author>James, Christopher; Kizilaslan, Atay</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Value of Realized Volatility: Using High-Frequency Returns for Option Valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Feunou, Bruno; Jacobs, Kris; Meddahi, Nour
Many studies have documented that daily realized volatility estimates based on intraday returns provide volatility forecasts that are superior to forecasts constructed from daily returns only. We investigate whether these forecasting improvements translate into economic value added. To do so, we develop a new class of affine discrete-time option valuation models that use daily returns as well as realized volatility. We derive convenient closed-form option valuation formulas, and we assess the option valuation properties using Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P) 500 return and option data. We find that realized volatility reduces the pricing errors of the benchmark model significantly across moneyness, maturity, and volatility levels.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Feunou, Bruno; Jacobs, Kris; Meddahi, Nour</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Strategic Listing Decisions of Hedge Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jorion, Philippe; Schwarz, Christopher
The voluntary nature of hedge fund database reporting creates strategic listing opportunities for hedge funds. However, little is known about how managers list funds across multiple databases or whether investors are fooled by funds' listing decisions. In this paper, we find that hedge funds strategically list their small, best-performing funds in multiple outlets immediately while preserving the option to list their other funds in additional databases later. We generally find that investors react rationally to these fund listings based on the predictability of performance. Finally, our results lead to specific guidelines on handling backfilled returns to minimize biases.</description><author>Jorion, Philippe; Schwarz, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contingent Capital: The Case of COERCs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pennacchi, George; Vermaelen, Theo; Wolff, Christian C. P.
This paper introduces and analyzes a new form of contingent convertible: a call option enhanced reverse convertible (COERC). If an issuing bank's market value of capital breaches a trigger, COERCs convert to many new equity shares that would heavily dilute existing shareholders, except that shareholders have the option to purchase these shares at the bond's par value. COERCs have low risk: They are almost always fully repaid in cash. Yet, they reduce government bailouts by replenishing a bank's capital. COERCs' design also avoids problems with market-value triggers, such as manipulation or panic, while reducing moral hazard and debt overhang.</description><author>Pennacchi, George; Vermaelen, Theo; Wolff, Christian C. P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does the Market Value Toxic Assets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, Francis A.; Myers, Brett W.
How does the market value "toxic" structured-credit securities? We study the valuation of what is possibly the most toxic of all toxic assets: the equity tranche of a collateralized debt obligation (CDO). In theory, CDO equity should be similar in nature to bank stock since both represent residual claims on a portfolio of loans. We find CDO equity returns are much more related to stock returns than to fixed-income returns. CDO equity returns track the returns of financial stocks much more closely than any other industry. Nearly two-thirds of the variation in CDO returns can be explained by fundamentals.</description><author>Longstaff, Francis A.; Myers, Brett W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leaders, Followers, and Risk Dynamics in Industry Equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlson, Murray; Dockner, Engelbert J.; Fisher, Adlai; Giammarino, Ron
We study the distinct impacts of own and rival actions on risk and return when firms strategically compete in the product market. Contrary to simple intuition, a competitor's options to adjust capacity reduce own-firm risk. For example, if a rival possesses a growth option, an increase in industry demand directly enhances profits but also encourages value-reducing competitor expansion. The rival option thus acts as a natural hedge. Within the industry, we obtain endogenous differences in expected returns. In a leader-follower equilibrium, own-firm and competitor risks and required returns move together through contractions and oppositely during expansions, providing testable new predictions.</description><author>Carlson, Murray; Dockner, Engelbert J.; Fisher, Adlai; Giammarino, Ron</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Expertise of the Board, Risk Taking, and Performance: Evidence from Bank Holding Companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Minton, Bernadette A.; Taillard, Jerome P.; Williamson, Rohan
Financial expertise among independent directors of U.S. banks is positively associated with balance-sheet and market-based measures of risk in the run-up to the 2007-2008 financial crisis. While financial expertise is weakly associated with better performance before the crisis, it is strongly related to lower performance during the crisis. Overall, the results are consistent with independent directors with financial expertise supporting increased risk taking prior to the crisis. Despite being consistent with shareholder value maximization ex ante, these actions become detrimental during the crisis. These results are not driven by powerful chief executive officers who select independent financial experts to rubber stamp strategies that satisfy their risk appetite.</description><author>Minton, Bernadette A.; Taillard, Jerome P.; Williamson, Rohan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transparency and Financing Choices of Family Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Tai-Yuan; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Yu, Yangxin
While recent literature documents that U.S. family firms differ markedly from their nonfamily counterparts, there is a paucity of evidence on how these firms differ in terms of their cost of capital or financial structure. In this paper, we show that family and nonfamily firms differ in their debt maturity and leverage ratios in a manner consistent with the higher expropriation potential of family firms. Moreover, while more transparency causes both family and nonfamily firms to increase the maturity structure of their debt and reduce leverage ratios, the effects are stronger for family firms.</description><author>Chen, Tai-Yuan; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Yu, Yangxin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Solvency Constraint, Underdiversification, and Idiosyncratic Risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Hong
Contrary to the prediction of the standard portfolio diversification theory, many investors place a large fraction of their stock investment in a small number of stocks. I show that underdiversification may be caused by solvency requirements. My model predicts that for quite general preferences and return distributions: (1) underdiversification decreases in discretionary wealth; and (2) expected return and covariance determine which stocks to invest in, but variance, higher moments, and Sharpe ratio do not matter for this choice. In addition, a less-diversified stock portfolio has a higher expected return, a higher volatility, and a higher skewness, and idiosyncratic risks are priced.</description><author>Liu, Hong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual Investors and Broker Types</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fong, Kingsley Y. L.; Gallagher, David R.; Lee, Adrian D.
We study the informativeness of trades via discount and full-service retail brokers. We find that trades via full-service retail brokers are statistically and economically more informative than are trades via discount retail brokers. This finding holds in every year over the 12-year sample period and in various subsamples. We also find that past returns, volatility, and news announcements positively relate to the net volume of discount retail brokers, but these variables are unrelated to the net volume of full-service retail brokers. Our results suggest that broker type selection bias is an important consideration in studying individual investors' trades.</description><author>Fong, Kingsley Y. L.; Gallagher, David R.; Lee, Adrian D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Incentives, Risk Aversion, and Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milidonis, Andreas; Stathopoulos, Konstantinos
We investigate the risk choices of risk-averse CEOs. Following recent theoretical work, we expect CEO risk aversion to be more pronounced in firms with high leverage or high default probability. We find that the CEOs of these firms reduce firm risk, even in the presence of strong risk-taking incentives. Our results are robust to controls for the sensitivity of CEO wealth to stock price changes, firm risk determinants, the endogenous feedback effects of firm risk on CEO incentives, unobserved firm and market effects, and debt governance. The impact of CEO risk aversion is economically significant.</description><author>Milidonis, Andreas; Stathopoulos, Konstantinos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest Rate Risk and the Cross Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lioui, Abraham; Maio, Paulo
We derive a macroeconomic asset pricing model in which the key factor is the opportunity cost of money. The model explains well the cross section of stock returns in addition to the excess market return. The interest rate factor is priced and seems to drive most of the explanatory power of the model. In this model, both value stocks and past long-term losers enjoy higher average (excess) returns because they have higher interest rate risk than growth/past winner stocks. The model significantly outperforms the nested models ( capital asset pricing model (CAPM) and consumption CAPM (CCAPM)) and compares favorably with alternative macroeconomic models.</description><author>Lioui, Abraham; Maio, Paulo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Gains from Buying Bad Bidders?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Offenberg, David; Straska, Miroslava; Waller, H. Gregory
We study the value gains from takeovers of firms with poor acquisition histories. We document that the premium received by target shareholders is higher when the value loss from the targets' prior acquisitions is larger. However, the gains to target shareholders seem to be offset by losses to acquiring shareholders. The average announcement return to acquiring shareholders is negative and decreasing in the value loss from the targets' prior acquisitions. Additionally, the combined acquirer-target value created in these takeovers is insignificant. These results suggest that the value lost from targets' prior acquisitions is not recovered through changes in corporate control.</description><author>Offenberg, David; Straska, Miroslava; Waller, H. Gregory</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recovering Delisting Returns of Hedge Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hodder, James E.; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten; Kolokolova, Olga
Numerous hedge funds stop reporting each year to commercial databases, wreaking havoc with analyzing investment strategies that incur the unobserved delisting return. We use estimated portfolio holdings for funds-of-funds to back out estimated hedge-fund delisting returns. For all exiting funds, the estimated mean delisting return is insignificantly different from the average monthly return for live hedge funds. However, funds with poor prior performance and no clearly stated delisting reason had a significantly negative estimated mean delisting return of -5.97%, suggesting that a shock to their returns "tips them over the edge" and leads to delisting.</description><author>Hodder, James E.; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten; Kolokolova, Olga</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Growth Options in Explaining Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trigeorgis, Lenos; Lambertides, Neophytos
We extend the Fama-French (1992) model by considering growth option (as well as distress/leverage) variables in explaining the cross section of stock returns. We find that growth option variables, namely growth in capital investment and yet-unexercised growth options (GO), are significantly and negatively related to stock returns. Investors may be willing to accept lower average returns from growth stocks in exchange for a more favorable (positively skewed) risk-return profile. Book-to-market (BM) ratio seems to proxy for omitted distress/leverage variables. When these are explicitly accounted for, BM is not that significant. Our growth options variables have added explanatory power.</description><author>Trigeorgis, Lenos; Lambertides, Neophytos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate Earnings and Market Returns: International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Wen; Hu, Maggie
Kothari, Lewellen, and Warner (2006) document that aggregate earnings changes in the United States are negatively related to contemporaneous market returns. In this study we show that this negative aggregate earnings-returns relation is unique to the United States. In 28 non-U.S. markets, aggregate earnings changes are positively associated with contemporaneous market returns. Further evidence shows that the aggregate earnings-returns relation becomes less positive in countries with more transparent financial disclosure that helps investors forecast earnings more precisely. Our result supports Sadka and Sadka's (2009) argument that predictability of aggregate earnings leads to the negative relation between aggregate earnings and market returns in the United States.</description><author>He, Wen; Hu, Maggie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading in the Options Market around Financial Analysts' Consensus Revisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hayunga, Darren K.; Lung, Peter P.
This article investigates the options market around a revision in the financial analysts' consensus recommendation. The results demonstrate that options investors trade in the correct direction of the upcoming revision approximately 3 days prior to the announcement. We find this behavior in option-implied prices, implied volatilities, and options trading volume. Tests confirm that the options market leads the stock market before the financial analysts' revision. Moreover, using all firms with outstanding options, an out-of-sample analysis produces a profitable zero-cost trading strategy net of transaction costs based on the relative valuations between the synthetic and the underlying equity security.</description><author>Hayunga, Darren K.; Lung, Peter P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder Litigation, Reputational Loss, and Bank Loan Contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deng, Saiying; Willis, Richard H.; Xu, Li
We examine shareholder litigation and the price and nonprice terms of bank loan contracts. After filing a lawsuit, defendant firms pay higher loan spreads and up-front charges, experience more financial covenants, and are more likely to have a collateral requirement. These findings are consistent with reputational losses associated with shareholder litigation. The magnitude of a firm's lost market value when the lawsuit is filed is positively related to the increase in the firm's future borrowing costs. We investigate whether the lawsuit allegations and its merit affect future bank loan terms. Our results do not appear to be affected by self-selection.</description><author>Deng, Saiying; Willis, Richard H.; Xu, Li</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Return Predictability and Variance Risk Premia: Statistical Inference and International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollerslev, Tim; Marrone, James; Xu, Lai; Zhou, Hao
Recent empirical evidence suggests that the variance risk premium predicts aggregate stock market returns. We demonstrate that statistical finite sample biases cannot "explain" this apparent predictability. Further corroborating the existing evidence of the United States, we show that country-specific regressions for France, Germany, Japan, Switzerland, the Netherlands, Belgium, and the United Kingdom result in quite similar patterns. Defining a "global" variance risk premium, we uncover even stronger predictability and almost identical cross-country patterns through the use of panel regressions.</description><author>Bollerslev, Tim; Marrone, James; Xu, Lai; Zhou, Hao</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Stock-Bond Return Relation, the Term Structure's Slope, and Asset-Class Risk Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bansal, Naresh; Connolly, Robert A.; Stivers, Chris
We study whether asset-class risk dynamics can help explain the predominantly negative stock-bond return relation and movements in the term structure's slope over 1997-2011. Using option-derived implied volatilities to measure risk, we find i) the negative stock-bond return relation largely disappears when controlling for risk movements, at both monthly and weekly horizons; ii) the partial relation between equity-risk changes and 10-year T-bond excess returns (term-slope movements) is reliably positive (negative); and iii) a stronger link between equity risk and stock returns implies a more negative stock-bond return correlation. Our results suggest a flight-to-quality influence between equity-risk dynamics and longer-term Treasury pricing.</description><author>Bansal, Naresh; Connolly, Robert A.; Stivers, Chris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum Effect as Part of a Market Equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Seung Mo; Kim, Hwagyun
Does the momentum effect arise naturally from the determination of asset prices in market equilibrium? We calibrate a standard endowment model of multiple assets under recursive preferences. The momentum effect partly comes from investors' aversion to consumption risks. An unexpected dividend increase generates a positive return and increases the asset's proportion of consumption, raising the correlation between its future dividend growth and consumption growth. This is compensated by a higher expected return, generating the momentum effect. The cross-sectional difference in expected returns is also a key contributor. The quantified model produces sizable momentum profits, often close to the observed profits.</description><author>Choi, Seung Mo; Kim, Hwagyun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Location of Directors Matter? Information Acquisition and Board Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alam, Zinat S.; Chen, Mark A.; Ciccotello, Conrad S.; Ryan, Harley E.
Using data on over 4,000 individual residential addresses, we find that geographic distance between directors and corporate headquarters is related to information acquisition and board decisions. The fraction of a board's unaffiliated directors who live near headquarters is higher when information-gathering needs are greater. When the fraction of unaffiliated directors living near headquarters is lower, nonroutine chief executive officer (CEO) turnover is more sensitive to stock performance. Also, the level, intensity, and sensitivity of CEO equity-based pay increase with board distance. Overall, our results suggest that geographic location is an important dimension of board structure that influences directors' costs of gathering information.</description><author>Alam, Zinat S.; Chen, Mark A.; Ciccotello, Conrad S.; Ryan, Harley E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing in the "New Economy": Mutual Fund Performance and the Nature of the Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta-Mukherjee, Swasti
Although stock returns of intangibles-intensive firms tend to exceed physical assets-intensive firms, risk-adjusted returns of actively managed mutual funds significantly decrease (increase) with their portfolios' exposure to intangibles-intensive (physical assets-intensive) firms. Fund managers tend to exhibit skill when they focus on difficult-to-value (e. g., small) firms, except when the firms are intangibles-intensive. In sum, the worst-performing funds are in areas of the market that seem to offer ample opportunities for professional investors due to exacerbated mispricing. The negative impact of investments in intangibles-intensive firms on fund performance appears to be driven by extrapolation bias and decreases with learning from experience.</description><author>Gupta-Mukherjee, Swasti</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cross Section of Recovery Rates and Default Probabilities Implied by Credit Default Swap Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elkamhi, Redouane; Jacobs, Kris; Pan, Xuhui
Rather than assuming a fixed recovery rate in estimation, we estimate recovery rates from credit default swap spreads, using 3 years of daily data on 152 corporations. We use a quadratic pricing model, which ensures nonnegative default probabilities and recovery rates. The estimated cross section of recovery rates is plausible, with an average recovery rate of 54% and substantial cross-sectional variation. Estimated 5-year default probabilities are on average 67% higher than default probabilities obtained using the standard 40% recovery assumption. This finding critically impacts the valuation of structured credit products. Larger firms and firms with more tangible assets have higher recovery rates.</description><author>Elkamhi, Redouane; Jacobs, Kris; Pan, Xuhui</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hindsight Effects in Dollar-Weighted Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hayley, Simon
A growing number of studies use dollar-weighted (DW) returns as evidence that bad timing substantially reduces investor returns, and that consequently the equity risk premium must be considerably lower than previously thought. This paper demonstrates that this method is subject to a hindsight effect (as prior returns influence levels of new investment) and derives a technique that corrects it. The results show that for mainstream U. S. equities, DW returns are low because of this hindsight effect (bad investor timing had very little impact). Thus, low DW returns do not imply that the risk premium is correspondingly low.</description><author>Hayley, Simon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Relation between EGARCH Idiosyncratic Volatility and Expected Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Hui; Kassa, Haimanot; Ferguson, Michael F.
A spurious positive relation between exponential generalized autoregressive conditional heteroskedasticity (EGARCH) estimates of expected month t idiosyncratic volatility and month t stock returns arises when the month t return is included in estimation of model parameters. We illustrate via simulations that this look-ahead bias is problematic for empirically observed degrees of stock return skewness and typical monthly return time series lengths. Moreover, the empirical idiosyncratic risk-return relation becomes negligible when expected month t idiosyncratic volatility is estimated using returns only up to month t - 1.</description><author>Guo, Hui; Kassa, Haimanot; Ferguson, Michael F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Disposition Effect Matter in Corporate Takeovers? Evidence from Institutional Investors of Target Companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ye, Pengfei
This paper examines whether one of the most important participants in the takeover market, the institutional investors of target companies, suffers from the disposition effect and, if so, how this selling bias influences the takeover outcomes. I report robust evidence that target institutional investors are reluctant to realize losses. This bias further allows their sunk cost to affect both the takeover price and the deal success. My results are explained by neither the undervalued targets nor the 52-week-high price effect. They are most pronounced among targets whose investors have a strong propensity to hold on to loser stocks.</description><author>Ye, Pengfei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Gambling Preferences and Corporate Innovative Success</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yangyang; Podolski, Edward J.; Rhee, S. Ghon; Veeraraghavan, Madhu
This paper examines the role of local attitudes toward gambling on corporate innovative activity. Using a county's Catholics-to-Protestants ratio as a proxy for local gambling preferences, we find that firms located in gambling-prone areas tend to undertake riskier projects, spend more on innovation, and experience greater innovative output. We contrast the local gambling effect with chief executive officer (CEO) overconfidence, another behavioral effect reported to influence innovation. We find that local gambling preferences are a stronger determinant of innovative activity, with CEO overconfidence being more relevant to innovation in areas where gambling attitudes are strong.</description><author>Chen, Yangyang; Podolski, Edward J.; Rhee, S. Ghon; Veeraraghavan, Madhu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bribe Payments and Innovation in Developing Countries: Are Innovating Firms Disproportionately Affected?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayyagari, Meghana; Demirguec-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav
Innovating firms pay more bribes than noninnovators across 25,000 firms in 57 countries. The difference is larger in countries with more bureaucratic regulation and weaker governance. Innovators that pay bribes do not receive better services and do not have greater propensity to engage in other illegal activities such as tax evasion. Thus, innovators are more likely to be victims of corruption than perpetrators. Our findings point to the challenges facing entrepreneurs in developing countries and are consistent with the view that rent seeking by government officials unlike private criminal activity is more likely to target innovators.</description><author>Ayyagari, Meghana; Demirguec-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volume and Volatility in a Common-Factor Mixture of Distributions Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Xiaojun; Velu, Raja
This paper develops a multi-asset mixture distribution hypothesis model to investigate commonality in stock returns and trading volume. The model makes two main predictions: First, the factor structures of returns and trading volume are independent although they stem from the same valuation fundamentals and jointly depend on a latent information flow; second, cross-sectional positive volatility-volume relations arise solely from the dynamic features of the information flow. Empirical analyses at the market level support these predictions. Furthermore, the results indicate that removing the information flow significantly reduces the return volatility persistence and the extent of the reduction exhibits a size pattern.</description><author>He, Xiaojun; Velu, Raja</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Asset Illiquidity and the Cost of Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ortiz-Molina, Hernan; Phillips, Gordon M.
We show that firms with more illiquid real assets have a higher cost of capital. This effect is stronger when real illiquidity arises from lower within-industry acquisition activity. Real asset illiquidity increases the cost of capital more for firms that face more competition, have less access to external capital, or are closer to default, and for those facing negative demand shocks. The effect of real asset illiquidity is distinct from that of firms' stock illiquidity or systematic liquidity risk. These results suggest that real asset illiquidity reduces firms' operating flexibility and through this channel their cost of capital.</description><author>Ortiz-Molina, Hernan; Phillips, Gordon M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taking the Twists into Account: Predicting Firm Bankruptcy Risk with Splines of Financial Ratios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giordani, Paolo; Jacobson, Tor; von Schedvin, Erik; Villani, Mattias
We demonstrate improvements in predictive power when introducing spline functions to take account of highly nonlinear relationships between firm failure and leverage, earnings, and liquidity in a logistic bankruptcy model. Our results show that modeling excessive nonlinearities yields substantially improved bankruptcy predictions, on the order of 70%-90%, compared with a standard logistic model. The spline model provides several important and surprising insights into nonmonotonic bankruptcy relationships. We find that low-leveraged as well as highly profitable firms are riskier than those given by a standard model, possibly a manifestation of credit rationing and excess cash-flow volatility.</description><author>Giordani, Paolo; Jacobson, Tor; von Schedvin, Erik; Villani, Mattias</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Success in Global Venture Capital Investing: Do Institutional and Cultural Differences Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nahata, Rajarishi; Hazarika, Sonali; Tandon, Kishore
We analyze the impact of institutional and cultural differences on success in global venture capital (VC) investing. In both developed and emerging economies, superior legal rights (and enforcement) and better developed stock markets significantly enhance VC performance. Remarkably, cultural distance between countries of the portfolio company and its lead investor positively affects VC success. Further analysis reveals that cultural differences create incentives for rigorous ex ante screening, improving VC performance. Finally, local VC participation enhances success and mitigates foreign VCs' "liability of foreignness," albeit only in developed economies. Our findings follow from analyzing VC investments in nearly 10,000 companies across 30 countries.</description><author>Nahata, Rajarishi; Hazarika, Sonali; Tandon, Kishore</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>