<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFQA3</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Stock Returns and the Volatility of Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pereira, Joao Pedro; Zhang, Harold H.
This paper offers a rational explanation for the puzzling empirical fact that stock returns decrease with an increase in the volatility of liquidity. We model liquidity as a stochastic price impact process and define the liquidity premium as the additional return necessary to compensate a multiperiod investor for the adverse price impact of trading. The model demonstrates that a fully rational, utility maximizing, risk-averse investor can take advantage of time-varying liquidity by adapting his trades to the state of liquidity. We provide new empirical evidence supportive of the model.</description><author>Pereira, Joao Pedro; Zhang, Harold H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational Cross-Sectional Differences in Market Efficiency: Evidence from Mutual Fund Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, Paul
Markets should be inefficient enough to allow returns to security analysis to adequately compensate the marginal analyst for his efforts. Cross-sectional differences in the costs of analysis therefore imply cross-sectional differences in market efficiency and in before-cost returns to smart investors. Small growth stocks are difficult to analyze and costly to trade. I find that the abnormal returns of mutual fund investments in small growth stocks from 1980 to 2006 averaged 0.76% per month. Large value stocks are easier to analyze and cheaper to trade. Mutual funds earned average monthly abnormal returns of only 0.05% in large value stocks during the same period.</description><author>Schultz, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the Equity Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donaldson, R. Glen; Kamstra, Mark J.; Kramer, Lisa A.
Existing empirical research investigating the size of the equity premium has largely consisted of a series of innovations around a common theme: producing a better estimate of the equity premium by using better data or a better estimation technique. The equity premium estimate that emerges from most of this work matches one moment of the data alone: the mean difference between an estimate of the return to holding equity and a risk-free rate. We instead match multiple moments of U.S. market data, exploiting the joint distribution of the dividend yield, return volatility, and realized excess returns, and find that the equity premium lies within 50 basis points of 3.5%, a range much narrower than was achieved in previous studies. Additionally, statistical tests based on the joint distribution of these moments reveal that only those models of the conditional equity premium that embed time variation, breaks, and/or trends are supported by the data. In order to develop the joint distribution of the dividend yield, return volatility, and excess returns, we need a model of price and return fundamentals. We document that even recently developed analytically tractable models that permit autocorrelated dividend growth rates and discount rates impose restrictions that are rejected by the data. We therefore turn to a wider range of models, requiring numerical solution methods and parameter estimation by the simulated method of moments.</description><author>Donaldson, R. Glen; Kamstra, Mark J.; Kramer, Lisa A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Level-Dependent Annuities Defaults of Multiple Degrees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mjos, Aksel; Persson, Svein-Arne
Motivated by the effect on valuation of stopped or reduced debt coupon payments from a company in financial distress we value a level dependent annuity contract where the annuity rate depends on the value of an underlying asset process The range of possible values of this asset is divided Into a finite number of regions with constant annuity rates within each region We present closed-form formulas for the market value of level dependent annuities contracts when the market value of the underlying asset is assumed to follow a geometric Brownian motion Such annuities occur naturally in models of debt with credit risk in financial economics Our results are applied for valuing both corporate debt with suspended Interest payments under the U S Chapter 11 provisions and loans with contractual level-dependent interest rates</description><author>Mjos, Aksel; Persson, Svein-Arne</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Term Structure of Variance Swap Rates and Optimal Variance Swap Investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Egloff, Daniel; Leippold, Markus; Wu, Liuren
This paper performs specification analysis on the term structure of variance swap rates on the S&amp;P 500 index and studies the optimal investment decision on the variance swaps and the stock index The analysis identifies 2 stochastic variance risk factors which govern the short and long end of the variance swap term structure variation, respectively The highly negative estimate for the market price of variance risk makes it optimal for an investor to take short positions in a short term variance swap contract, long positions in a long-term variance swap contract and short positions in the stock index</description><author>Egloff, Daniel; Leippold, Markus; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Drove the Increase in Idiosyncratic Volatility during the Internet Boom?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fink, Jason; Fink, Kristin E.; Grullon, Gustavo; Weston, James P.
Aggregate idiosyncratic volatility spiked nearly fivefold during the Internet boom of the late 1990s dwarfing in magnitude a moderately increasing trend While some researchers argue that this rise in idiosyncratic risk was the result of changes in the characteristics of public firms others argue that it was driven by the changing sentiment of irrational traders We present evidence that the marketwide decline in maturity of the typical public firm can explain most of the increase in firm specific risk during the Internet boom Controlling for firm maturity we find no evidence that investor sentiment drives idiosyncratic risk throughout the Internet boom</description><author>Fink, Jason; Fink, Kristin E.; Grullon, Gustavo; Weston, James P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transparency, Price Informativeness, and Stock Return Synchronicity Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dasgupta, Sudipto; Gan, Jie; Gao, Ning
This paper argues that contrary to the conventional wisdom, stock return synchronicity (or R(2)) can Increase when transparency improves In a simple model, we show that in more transparent environments stock prices should be more informative about future events Consequently when the events actually happen in the future there should be less surprise" (i e less new information is impounded into the stock price) Thus a more informative stock price today means higher return synchronicity in the future We find empirical support for our theoretical predictions in 3 settings namely firm age seasoned equity offerings (SEOs), and listing of American Depositary Receipts (ADRs)</description><author>Dasgupta, Sudipto; Gan, Jie; Gao, Ning</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt Capacity and Tests of Capital Structure Theories</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lemmon, Michael L.; Zender, Jaime F.
We examine the Impact of explicitly Incorporating a measure of debt capacity in recent tests of competing theories of capital structure Our main results are that if external funds are required in the absence of debt capacity concerns debt appears to be preferred to equity Concerns over debt capacity largely explain the use of new external equity financing by publicly traded firms Finally, we present evidence that reconciles the frequent equity issues by small high-growth firms with the pecking order After accounting for debt capacity the pecking order theory appears to give a good description of financing behavior for a large sample of firms examined over an extended time period</description><author>Lemmon, Michael L.; Zender, Jaime F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Mutual Fund Managers Pick Stocks? Evidence from Their Trades Prior to Earnings Announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Malcolm; Litov, Lubomir; Wachter, Jessica A.; Wurgler, Jeffrey
Recent research finds that the stocks that mutual fund managers buy outperform the stocks that they sell (e g, Chen Jegadeesh and Wermers (2000)) We study the nature of this stock-picking ability We construct measures of trading skill based on how the stocks held and traded by fund managers perform at subsequent corporate earnings announcements This approach increases the power to detect skilled trading and sheds light on its source We find that the average fund s recent buys significantly outperform its recent sells around the next earnings announcement and that this accounts for a disproportionate fraction of the total abnormal returns to fund trades estimated in prior work We find that mutual fund trades also forecast earnings surprises We conclude that mutual fund managers are able to trade profitably in part because they are able to forecast earnings-related fundamentals</description><author>Baker, Malcolm; Litov, Lubomir; Wachter, Jessica A.; Wurgler, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Affine Models of the Joint Dynamics of Exchange Rates and Interest Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Bing; Hammond, Peter J.; Ramezani, Cyrus A.
This paper extends the affine class of term structure models to describe the Joint dynamics of exchange rates and interest rates In particular the issue of how to reconcile the low volatility of interest rates with the high volatility of exchange rates is addressed The in complete market approach of introducing exchange rate volatility that is orthogonal to both Interest rates and the pricing kernels is shown to be infeasible in the affine setting Models in which excess exchange rate volatility is orthogonal to Interest rates but not orthogonal to the pricing kernels are proposed and validated via Kalman filter estimation of maximal 5-factor models for 6 country pairs</description><author>Anderson, Bing; Hammond, Peter J.; Ramezani, Cyrus A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, Expected Utility, and Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Jun; Peleg, Ehud; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
We study the consumption-investment problem of an agent with a constant relative risk aversion preference function, who possesses noisy information about the future prospects of a stock We also solve for the value of information to the agent in closed form We find that information can significantly alter consumption and asset allocation decisions For reasonable parameter ranges, information increases consumption in the vicinity of 25% Information can shift the portfolio weight on a stock from 0% to around 70% Thus de pending on the stock beta the weight on the market portfolio can be considerably reduced with information causing the appearance of underdiversification The model indicates that stock holdings of informed agents are positively related to wealth unrelated to systematic risk and negatively related to idiosyncratic uncertainty We also show that the dollar value of information to the agent depends linearly on his wealth and decreases with both the propensity to intermediate consumption and risk aversion</description><author>Liu, Jun; Peleg, Ehud; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seasonality in the Cross Section of Stock Returns The International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heston, Steven L.; Sadka, Ronnie
This paper studies seasonal predictability in the cross section of international stock returns Stocks that outperform the domestic market in a particular month continue to outperform the domestic market in that same calendar month for up to 5 years The pattern appears in Canada, Japan, and 12 European countries Global trading strategies based on seasonal predictability outperform similar nonseasonal strategies by over 1% per month Abnormal seasonal returns remain after controlling for size beta and value using global or local risk factors In addition the strategies are not highly correlated across countries This suggests they do not reflect return premiums for systematic global risk</description><author>Heston, Steven L.; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Firms with Diversification Discounts Have Higher Expected Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitton, Todd; Vorkink, Keith
A diversified firm can trade at a discount to a matched portfolio of single-segment firms if the diversified firm has either lower expected cash flows or higher expected returns than the single-segment firms. We study whether firms with diversification discounts have higher expected returns in order to compensate investors for offering less upside potential (or skewness exposure) than focused firms. Our empirical tests support this hypothesis. First, we find that focused firms offer greater skewness exposure than diversified firms. Second, we find that diversified firms have significantly larger discounts when the diversified firm offers less skewness than matched single-segment firms. Finally, we find that up to 53% of the excess returns received on diversification-discount firms relative to diversification-premium firms can be explained by differences in exposure to skewness.</description><author>Mitton, Todd; Vorkink, Keith</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Quality and Stock Returns Revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brevik, Frode; d'Addona, Stefano
This paper investigates the relation between information on the state of the economy and equity risk premium. We use a setup where investors have Epstein-Zin preferences and the economy randomly switches between booms and recessions. We are able to establish 2 key results: First, investors with high elasticity of intertemporal substitution (EIS) will require lower excess returns for holding stocks if they are provided with better information on the state of the economy. Second, we find that this also holds for investors with moderate EIS if they are sufficiently risk averse.</description><author>Brevik, Frode; d'Addona, Stefano</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading Volume in Dealer Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malinova, Katya; Park, Andreas
We develop a financial market trading model in the tradition of Glosten and Milgrom (1985) that allows us to incorporate nontrivial volume. We observe that in this model price volatility is positively related to the trading volume and to the absolute value of the net order flow (i.e., the order imbalance). Moreover, higher volume leads to higher order imbalances. These findings are consistent with well-established empirical findings. Our model further predicts that higher trader participation and systematic improvements in the quality of traders' information lead to higher volume, larger order imbalances, lower market depth, shorter duration, and higher price volatility.</description><author>Malinova, Katya; Park, Andreas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneity and Volatility Puzzles in International Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Tao; Muzere, Mark L.
We develop an equilibrium model in a 2-country, 2-good, pure exchange economy in which investors with logarithmic utility functions have heterogeneous beliefs about exogenously given output or endowment processes. We obtain closed-form representations of real exchange rates and of stock prices. We show that heterogeneous beliefs together with heterogeneous preferences make the volatility of real exchange rates and of stocks exhibit some properties that have been well documented in the empirical literature. These properties include the high volatility of both real exchange rates and stocks compared with that of economic fundamentals, the high correlation of stocks during periods of volatile markets. The model can also generate the clustering of the volatility of foreign exchange rates and stocks if the differences of beliefs are clustering.</description><author>Li, Tao; Muzere, Mark L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Role of Jumps and Recovery Rates in the Market for Corporate Default Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schneider, Paul; Soegner, Leopold; Veza, Tanja
Using an extensive cross section of U.S. corporate credit default swaps (CDSs), this paper offers an economic understanding of implied loss given default (LGD) and jumps in default risk. We formulate and underpin empirical stylized facts about CDS spreads, which are then reproduced in our affine intensity-based jump-diffusion model. Implied LGD is well identified, with obligors possessing substantial tangible assets expected to recover more. Sudden increases in the default risk of investment-grade obligors are higher relative to speculative grade. The probability of structural migration to default is low for investment-grade and heavily regulated obligors because investors fear distress rather through rare but devastating events.</description><author>Schneider, Paul; Soegner, Leopold; Veza, Tanja</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Dynamics and Momentum Profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asem, Ebenezer; Tian, Gloria Y.
Recent evidence indicates that momentum profits are sensitive to market conditions. We find that the profits are higher when the markets continue in the same state than when they transition to a different state. These findings support Daniel, Hirshleifer, and Subrahmanyam (1998), who suggest that investor overconfidence is higher when the markets continue in the same state (UP or DOWN) than when they reverse, predicting higher momentum profits in the former. In contrast, our evidence following DOWN markets is not consistent with the other competing models for the market-state conditional momentum profits.</description><author>Asem, Ebenezer; Tian, Gloria Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Sensitivity of American Options to Suboptimal Exercise Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibanez, Alfredo; Paraskevopoulos, Ioannis
The value of American options depends on the exercise policy followed by option holders. Market frictions, risk aversion, or a misspecified model, for example, can result in suboptimal behavior. We study the sensitivity of American options to suboptimal exercise strategies. We show that this measure is given by the Gamma of the American option at the optimal exercise boundary. More precisely, "if B is the optimal exercise price, but exercise is either brought forward when or delayed until a price (B) over tilde has been reached, the cost of suboptimal exercise is given by 1/2 x Gamma(B) x (B - (B) over tilde)(2), where Gamma(B) denotes the American option Gamma." Therefore, the cost of suboptimal exercise is second-order in the bias of the exercise policy and depends on Gamma. This result provides new insights on American options.</description><author>Ibanez, Alfredo; Paraskevopoulos, Ioannis</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Connections and Minority-Shareholder Protection: Evidence from Securities-Market Regulation in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, Henk; Cole, Rebel A.; Fu, Lawrence J.
We examine the wealth effects of 3 regulatory changes designed to improve minority-shareholder protection in the Chinese stock markets. Using the value of a firm's related-party transactions as an inverse proxy for the quality of corporate governance, we find that firms with weaker governance experienced significantly larger abnormal returns around announcements of the new regulations than did firms with stronger governance. We also find that firms with strong ties to the government did not benefit from the regulations, suggesting that minority shareholders did not expect regulators to enforce the new rules on firms where blockholders have strong political connections.</description><author>Berkman, Henk; Cole, Rebel A.; Fu, Lawrence J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pharmaceutical R&amp;D Spending and Threats of Price Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golec, Joseph; Hegde, Shantaram; Vernon, John A.
Do threats of pharmaceutical price regulation affect subsequent research and development (R&amp;D) spending? This study uses the Clinton administration's Health Security Act (HSA) of 1993 as a natural experiment to study this issue. We link events surrounding the HSA to pharmaceutical stock price changes and then examine the cross-sectional relation between firms' stock price changes and their subsequent unexpected R&amp;D spending changes. Results show that the HSA had significant negative effects on stock Prices and firm-level R&amp;D spending. Conservatively, the HSA reduced R&amp;D spending by about $1 billion even though it never became law.</description><author>Golec, Joseph; Hegde, Shantaram; Vernon, John A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund Flow Volatility and Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rakowski, David
This paper provides a detailed analysis of the impact of daily mutual fund flow volatility on fund performance. I document a significant negative relationship between the volatility of daily fund flows and cross-sectional differences in risk-adjusted performance. This relationship is driven by domestic equity funds, as well as small funds, well-performing funds, and funds that experience inflows over the sample period. My results are consistent with performance differences arising from the transaction costs of nondiscretionary trading driven by daily fund flows, but not with performance differences arising from the suboptimal cash holdings that arise from fund flows.</description><author>Rakowski, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting Hedge Fund Failure: A Comparison of Risk Measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liang, Bing; Park, Hyuna
This paper compares downside risk measures that incorporate higher return moments with traditional risk measures such as standard deviation in predicting hedge fund failure. When controlling for investment strategies, performance, fund age, size, lockup, high-water mark, and leverage, we find that funds with larger downside risk have a higher hazard rate. However, standard deviation loses the explanatory power once the other explanatory variables are included in the hazard model. Further, we find that liquidation does not necessarily mean failure in the hedge fund industry. By reexamining the attrition rate, we show that the real failure rate of 3.1% is lower than the attrition rate of 8.7% on an annual basis during the period of 1995-2004.</description><author>Liang, Bing; Park, Hyuna</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Epidemic Model of Investor Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shive, Sophie
I test whether social influence affects individual investors' trading and stock returns. In each of the 20 most active stocks in Finland over 9 years, the number of owners in a municipality multiplied by the number of investors who do not own a stock, a measure of the rate of transmission of diseases and rumors through social contact, predicts individual investor trading. I control for known determinants of trade, including daily news, and show that competing explanations for the relation are unlikely. Socially motivated trades predict stock returns, and the effects are not reversed, suggesting that individuals share useful information. Individuals' susceptibility to social influence has declined during the period, but the opportunities for social influence have increased.</description><author>Shive, Sophie</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Protection, Equity Returns, and Financial Globalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Koskinen, Yrjoe
We study the effects of investor protection on stock returns and portfolio allocation decisions. In our theoretical model, if investor protection is weak, wealthy investors have an incentive to become controlling shareholders. In equilibrium, the stock price reflects the demand from both controlling shareholders and portfolio investors. Due to the high demand from controlling shareholders, the price of weak corporate governance stocks is not low enough to fully discount the extraction of private benefits. Thus, stocks have lower expected returns when investor protection is weak. This has implications for domestic and foreign investors' stockholdings. In particular, we show that portfolio investors' participation in the domestic stock market and home equity bias are positively related to investor protection and provide original evidence in their support.</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Koskinen, Yrjoe</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Liquidity Affect Government Bond Yields?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Favero, Carlo; Pagano, Marco; von Thadden, Ernst-Ludwig
The paper explores the determinants of yield differentials between sovereign bonds, using euro-area data. There is a common trend in yield differentials, which is correlated with a measure of aggregate risk. In contrast, liquidity differentials display sizeable heterogeneity and no common factor. We propose a simple model with endogenous liquidity demand, where a bond's liquidity premium depends both on its transaction cost and on investment opportunities. The model predicts that yield differentials should increase in both liquidity and risk, with an interaction term of the opposite sign. Testing these predictions on daily data, we find that the aggregate risk factor is consistently priced, liquidity differentials are priced for a subset of countries, and their interaction with the risk factor is in line with the model's prediction and crucial to detect their effect.</description><author>Favero, Carlo; Pagano, Marco; von Thadden, Ernst-Ludwig</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Signaling Hypothesis Revisited: Evidence from Foreign IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Lothian, James R.; Sun, Xian
While the signaling hypothesis has played a prominent role as the economic rationale associated with the initial public offering (IPO) underpricing puzzle (Welch (1989)), the empirical evidence on it has been mixed at best (Jegadeesh, Weinstein, and Welch (1993), Michaely and Shaw (1994)). This paper revisits the issue from the vantage point of close to two decades of additional experience by examining a sample of foreign IPOs-firms from both financially integrated and segmented markets-in U.S. markets. The evidence indicates that signaling does matter in determining IPO underpricing, especially for firms domiciled in countries with segmented markets, which as a result face higher information asymmetry and lack access to external capital markets. We find a significant positive and robust relationship between the degree of IPO underpricing and segmented-market firms' seasoned equity offering (SEO) activities. For firms from integrated markets, in contrast, the analyst-coverage purchase hypothesis appears to matter more in explaining IPO underpricing, and the aftermarket price appreciation explains these firms' SEO activities. The evidence, therefore, clearly supports the notion that some firms are willing to leave money on the table voluntarily to get a more favorable price at seasoned offerings when they are substantially wealth constrained, a prediction embedded in the signaling hypothesis.</description><author>Francis, Bill B.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Lothian, James R.; Sun, Xian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting Global Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hjalmarsson, Erik
I test for stock return predictability in the largest and most comprehensive data set analyzed so far, using four common forecasting variables: the dividend-price (DP) and earnings-price (EP) ratios, the short interest rate, and the term spread. The data contain over 20,000 monthly observations from 40 international markets, including 24 developed and 16 emerging economies. In addition, I develop new. methods for predictive regressions with panel data. Inference based on the standard fixed effects estimator is shown to suffer from severe size distortions in the typical stock return regression, and an alternative robust estimator is proposed. The empirical results indicate that the short interest rate and the term spread are fairly robust predictors of stock returns in developed markets. In contrast, no strong or consistent evidence of predictability is found when considering the EP and DP ratios as predictors.</description><author>Hjalmarsson, Erik</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Clientele Change, Liquidity Shock, and the Return on Financially Distressed Stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Gao, Pengjie
We show that the abnormal returns on high default risk stocks documented by Vassalou and Xing (2004) are driven by short-term return reversals rather than systematic default risk. These abnormal returns occur only during the month after portfolio formation and are concentrated in a small subset of stock's that had recently experienced large negative returns. Empirical evidence supports the view that the short-term return reversal arises from a liquidity shock triggered by a clientele change.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Gao, Pengjie</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is There Shareholder Expropriation in the United States? An Analysis of Publicly Traded Subsidiaries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanasov, Vladimir; Boone, Audra; Haushalter, David
This paper examines the relation between the performance and valuations of publicly traded subsidiaries in the United States and the ownership stake of their parent companies. Cross-sectional and time-series tests demonstrate that subsidiaries of parents that own a substantial minority stake exhibit negative peer-adjusted operating performance and are valued at a 23% median discount relative to peers. In contrast, majority-owned and fully divested subsidiaries show no abnormal performance or valuations. The results of our study indicate that the association between parent ownership and subsidiary performance is nonlinear and that some parents behave opportunistically toward their publicly traded subsidiaries.</description><author>Atanasov, Vladimir; Boone, Audra; Haushalter, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prospect Theory and the Disposition Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaustia, Markku
This paper shows that prospect theory is unlikely to explain the disposition effect. Prospect theory predicts that the propensity to sell a stock declines as its price moves away from the purchase price in either direction. Trading data, on the other hand, show that the propensity to sell jumps at zero return, but it is approximately constant over a wide range of losses and increasing or constant over a wide range of gains. Further, the pattern of realized returns does not seem to stem from optimal after-tax portfolio rebalancing, a belief in mean-reverting returns, or investors acting on target prices.</description><author>Kaustia, Markku</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Longer Look at the Asymmetric Dependence between Hedge Funds and the Equity Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Byoung Uk; In, Francis; Kim, Gunky; Kim, Tong Suk
This paper reexamines, at a range of investment horizons, the asymmetric dependence between hedge fund returns and market returns. Given the current availability of hedge fund data, the joint distribution of longer-horizon returns is extracted from the dynamics of monthly returns using the filtered historical simulation; we then apply the method based on copula theory to uncover the dependence structure therein. While the direction of asymmetry remains unchanged, the magnitude of asymmetry is attenuated considerably as the investment horizon increases. Similar horizon effects also occur on the tail dependence. Our findings suggest that nonlinearity in hedge fund exposure to market risk is more short term in nature, and that hedge funds provide higher benefits of diversification, the longer the horizon.</description><author>Kang, Byoung Uk; In, Francis; Kim, Gunky; Kim, Tong Suk</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Feedback and Equity Issuance: Evidence from Repeat Equity Issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hovakimian, Armen; Hutton, Irene
Higher first-year post-issue returns are associated with a significantly higher probability of follow-on equity issuance over the next 5 years. This result holds when we control for pre-issue returns and other factors known to affect the probability of equity issuance. The result is most consistent with the market feedback hypothesis that a high post-issue return encourages managers to increase the firm's investment because it implies that, in the market's view, the marginal return to the project is high.</description><author>Hovakimian, Armen; Hutton, Irene</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Factors and Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhongzhi; Huh, Sahn-Wook; Lee, Bong-Soo
This study develops an econometric model that incorporates features of price dynamics across assets as well as through time. With the dynamic factors extracted via the Kalman filter, we formulate an asset pricing model, termed the dynamic factor pricing model (DFPM). We then conduct asset pricing tests in the in-sample and out-of-sample contexts. Our analyses show that the ex ante factors are a key component in asset pricing and forecasting. By using the ex ante factors, the DFPM improves upon the explanatory and predictive power of other competing models, including unconditional and conditional versions of the Fama and French (1993) 3-factor model. In particular, the DFPM can explain and better forecast the momentum portfolio returns, which are mostly missed by alternative models.</description><author>He, Zhongzhi; Huh, Sahn-Wook; Lee, Bong-Soo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Friend or Foe? The Role of State and Mutual Fund Ownership in the Split Share Structure Reform in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Firth, Michael; Lin, Chen; Zou, Hong
The recent split share structure reform in China involves the nontradable shareholders proposing a compensation package to the tradable shareholders in exchange for the listing rights of their shares. We find that state ownership (the major owners of nontradable shares) has a positive effect on the final compensation ratio. In contrast, mutual fund ownership (the major institutional owner of tradable shares) has a negative effect on the compensation ratio and especially in state-owned firms. The evidence is consistent with our predictions that state shareholders have incentives to complete the reform quickly and exert political pressure on mutual funds to accept the terms without a fight.</description><author>Firth, Michael; Lin, Chen; Zou, Hong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Reexamination of the Causes of Time-Varying Stock Return Volatilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Chu
The decline of average stock return volatility in the 2001-2006 period provides an opportunity to test various theories on why the average return volatility increased in the pre-2000 period. This paper compares fundamentals-based theories with trading volume-based theories. While both fundamentals-based and trading volume-based theories explain the upward trend in the average volatility in U.S. stocks from 1976 to 2000 and international stocks from 1990 to 2000, only the fundamentals-based theories explain the volatility pattern for 2001-2006. Much of the variation in the stock return volatilities can be explained by the variation in the earnings volatilities and proxies for growth options, but not by trading-related variables. Evidence also shows that the explanatory power of the fundamentals variables is time varying.</description><author>Zhang, Chu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Does the Individual Option Volatility Smirk Tell Us About Future Equity Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xing, Yuhang; Zhang, Xiaoyan; Zhao, Rui
The shape of the volatility smirk has significant cross-sectional predictive power for future equity returns. Stocks exhibiting the steepest smirks in their traded options underperform stocks with the least pronounced volatility smirks in their options by 10.9% per year on a risk-adjusted basis. This predictability persists for at least 6 months, and firms with the steepest volatility smirks are those experiencing the worst earnings shocks in the following quarter. The results are consistent with the notion that informed traders with negative news prefer to trade out-of-the-money put options, and that the equity market is slow in incorporating the information embedded in volatility smirks.</description><author>Xing, Yuhang; Zhang, Xiaoyan; Zhao, Rui</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disagreement, Portfolio Optimization, and Excess Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duchin, Ran; Levy, Moshe
Disagreement, a key factor inducing trading, has been receiving ever increasing attention in recent years. Most research has focused on disagreement about the expected returns. Several authors have shown that if the average belief coincides with the true expected return, in the portfolio context prices are unaffected by disagreement. In this paper we study the pricing effects of disagreement about return variances. We show that i) disagreement about variances has systematic and significant pricing effects-more disagreement leads to higher prices, and ii) prices are very sensitive to the degree of disagreement: Even if the average belief about the variance is constant, tiny fluctuations in the disagreement about the variance lead to substantial price fluctuations. This second result may offer an explanation for the excess volatility puzzle: When small changes in the degree of disagreement occur, they induce relatively large price changes. Yet, the changes in disagreement may be hard to directly detect empirically, leading to apparent "excess volatility."</description><author>Duchin, Ran; Levy, Moshe</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Frictions and the Substitution between Internal and External Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo
Ample evidence points to a negative relation between internal funds (profitability) and the demand for external funds (debt issuance). This relation has been interpreted as evidence supporting the pecking order theory. We show, however, that the negative effect of internal funds on the demand for external financing is concentrated among firms that are least likely to face high external financing costs (firms that distribute large amounts of dividends, that are large, and whose debt is rated). For firms on the other end of the spectrum (low payout, small, and unrated), external financing is insensitive to internal funds. These cross-firm differences hold separately for debt and equity, and they are magnified in the aftermath of macroeconomic movements that tighten financing constraints. We argue that the greater complementarity between internal funds and external financing for constrained firms is a consequence of the interdependence of their financing and investment decisions.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Response of Corporate Financing and Investment to Changes in the Supply of Credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lemmon, Michael; Roberts, Michael R.
We examine how shocks to the supply of credit impact corporate financing and investment using the collapse of Drexel Burnham Lambert, Inc.; the passage of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989; and regulatory changes in the insurance industry as an exogenous contraction in the supply of below-investment-grade credit after 1989. A difference-in-differences empirical strategy reveals that substitution to bank debt and alternative sources of capital (e.g., equity, cash balances, and trade credit) was limited, leading to an almost one-for-one decline in net investment with the decline in net debt issuances. Despite this sharp change in behavior, corporate leverage ratios remained relatively stable, a result of the contemporaneous decline in debt issuances and investment. Overall, our findings highlight how even large firms with access to public credit markets are susceptible to fluctuations in the supply of capital.</description><author>Lemmon, Michael; Roberts, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic General Equilibrium and T-Period Fund Separation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gerber, Anke; Hens, Thorsten; Woehrmann, Peter
In a dynamic general equilibrium model, we derive conditions for a mutual fund separation property by which the savings decision is separated from the asset allocation decision. With logarithmic utility functions, this separation holds for any heterogeneity in discount factors, while the generalization to constant relative risk aversion holds only for homogeneous discount factors but allows for any heterogeneity in endowments. The logarithmic case provides a general equilibrium foundation for the growth-optimal portfolio literature. Both cases yield equilibrium asset pricing formulas that allow for investor heterogeneity, in which the return process is endogenous and asset prices are determined by expected discounted relative dividends. Our results have simple asset pricing implications for the time series as well as the cross section of relative asset prices. It is found that on data from the Dow Jones Industrial Average, a risk aversion smaller than in the logarithmic case fits best.</description><author>Gerber, Anke; Hens, Thorsten; Woehrmann, Peter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informational Efficiency and Liquidity Premium as the Determinants of Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Chun; Yu, Xiaoyun
This paper investigates how a firm's capital structure choice affects the informational efficiency of its security prices in the secondary markets. We identify two new determinants of a firm's capital structure policy: the liquidity (adverse selection) premium due to investors' anticipated losses to informed trading, and operating efficiency improvement due to information revelation from the firm's security prices. We show that the capital structure decision affects traders' incentives to acquire information and subsequently, the distribution of informed traders across debt and equity claims. When information is less imperative for improving its operating decisions, a firm issues zero or negative debt (i.e., holding excess cash reserves) in order to reduce socially wasteful information acquisition and the liquidity premium associated with it. When information is crucial for a firm's operating decisions, the optimal debt level is one that achieves maximum information revelation at the lowest possible liquidity cost. Our model can explain why many firms consistently hold no debt. It also provides new implications for financial system design and for the relationship among leverage, liquidity premium, profitability, and the cost of information acquisition.</description><author>Chang, Chun; Yu, Xiaoyun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Syndicate Short Sales Affect the Informational Efficiency of IPO Prices and Underpricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartling, Bjoern; Park, Andreas
When a company goes public, it is standard practice that the underwriting syndicate allocates more shares than are issued. The underwriter thus holds a short position that it commonly fills by aftermarket trading when market prices fall or, when prices rise, by executing the so-called overallotment option. This option is a standard feature of initial public offering (IPO) arrangements that allows the underwriter to purchase more shares from the issuer at the original offer price. We propose a theoretical model to study the implications of this combination of short position and overallotment option on the pricing of the IPO. Maximizing the sum of both the profits from their share of the offer revenue and the potential profits from aftermarket trading, we show that underwriters strategically distort the offer price. This results either in exacerbated underpricing when favorably informed underwriters lower prices to secure a signaling benefit, or in informationally inefficient offer prices when underwriters pool in offer prices irrespective of their information.</description><author>Bartling, Bjoern; Park, Andreas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of the Euro on Equity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cappiello, Lorenzo; Kadareja, Arjan; Manganelli, Simone
This paper investigates whether comovements between euro area equity returns at national and industry level changed after the introduction of the euro. By adopting a regression quantile-based methodology, we find that after 1999 the degree of comovements among euro area national equity markets was augmented. By explicitly controlling for the impact of global factors, we show that this result cannot be explained by recent worldwide trends. A more refined analysis based on an industry breakdown suggests that the increase in national index comovements is mainly driven by financial, industrial, and consumer services sectors.</description><author>Cappiello, Lorenzo; Kadareja, Arjan; Manganelli, Simone</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting Volatility Using Long Memory and Comovements: An Application to Option Valuation under SFAS 123R</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, George J.; Tian, Yisong S.
Horizon-matched historical volatility is commonly used to forecast future volatility for option valuation under the Statement of Financial Accounting Standards (SFAS) 123R. In this paper, we empirically investigate the performance of using historical volatility to forecast long-term stock return volatility in comparison with a number of alternative forecasting methods. In analyzing forecasting errors and their impact on reported income due to option expensing, we find that historical volatility is a poor forecast for long-term volatility and that shrinkage adjustment toward comparable-firm volatility only slightly improves its performance. Forecasting performance can be improved substantially by incorporating both long memory and comovements with common market factors. We also experiment with a simple mixed-horizon realized volatility model and find its long-term forecasting performance to be more accurate than historical forecasts but less accurate than long-memory forecasts.</description><author>Jiang, George J.; Tian, Yisong S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploitable Predictable Irrationality: The FIFA World Cup Effect on the</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplanski, Guy; Levy, Haim
In a recently published paper, Edmans, Garcia, and Norli (2007) reveal a strong association between results of soccer games and local stock returns. Inspired by their work, we propose a novel approach to exploit this effect on the aggregate international level with the following three unique features: i) The aggregate effect does not depend on the games' results; hence, the effect is an exploitable predictable effect. ii) The aggregate effect is based on many games; hence, it is very large and highly significant. We find that the average return on the U.S. market over the World Cup's effect period is -2.58%, compared to +1.21% for all-days average returns over the same period length. in) Exploiting the aggregate effect is involved with trading in a single index for a relatively long period.</description><author>Kaplanski, Guy; Levy, Haim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deviations from Put-Call Parity and Stock Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, Martijn; Weinbaum, David
Deviations from put-call parity contain information about future stock returns. Using the difference in implied volatility between pairs of call and put options to measure these deviations, we find that stocks with relatively expensive calls outperform stocks with relatively expensive puts by 50 basis points per week. We find both positive abnormal performance in stocks with relatively expensive calls and negative abnormal performance in stocks with relatively expensive puts, which cannot be explained by short sale constraints. Rebate rates from the stock lending market directly confirm that our findings are not driven by stocks that are hard to borrow. The degree of predictability is larger when option liquidity is high and stock liquidity low, while there is little predictability when the opposite is true. Controlling for size, option prices are more likely to deviate from strict put-call parity when underlying stocks face more information risk. The degree of predictability decreases over the sample period. Our results are consistent with mispricing during the earlier years of the study, with a gradual reduction of the mispricing over time.</description><author>Cremers, Martijn; Weinbaum, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Optimization with Mental Accounts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, Sanjiv; Markowitz, Harry; Scheid, Jonathan; Statman, Meir
We integrate appealing features of Markowitz's mean-variance portfolio theory (MVT) and Shefrin and Statman's behavioral portfolio theory (BPT) into a new mental accounting (MA) framework. Features of the MA framework include an MA structure of portfolios, a definition of risk as the probability of failing to reach the threshold level in each mental account, and attitudes toward risk that vary by account. We demonstrate a mathematical equivalence between MVT. MA, and risk management using value at risk (VaR). The aggregate allocation across MA subportfolios is mean-variance efficient with short selling. Short-selling constraints on mental accounts impose very minor reductions in certainty equivalents, only if binding for the aggregate portfolio, offsetting utility losses from errors in specifying risk-aversion coefficients in MVT applications. These generalizations of MVT and BPT via a unified MA framework result in a fruitful connection between investor consumption goals and portfolio production.</description><author>Das, Sanjiv; Markowitz, Harry; Scheid, Jonathan; Statman, Meir</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factoring Information into Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; Hvidkjaer, Soeren; O'Hara, Maureen
We examine the potential profits of trading on a measure of private information (PIN) in a stock. A zero-investment portfolio that is size-neutral but long in high PIN stocks and short in low PIN stocks earns a significant abnormal return. The Fama-French, momentum, and liquidity factors do not explain this return. However, significant covariation in returns exists among high PIN stocks and among low PIN stocks, suggesting that PIN might proxy for an underlying factor. We create a PIN factor as the monthly return on the zero-investment portfolio above and show that it is successful in explaining returns to independent PIN-size portfolios. We also show that it is robust to inclusion of the Pastor-Stambaugh liquidity factor and the Amihud illiquidity factor. We argue that information remains an important determinant of asset returns even in the presence of these additional factors.</description><author>Easley, David; Hvidkjaer, Soeren; O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance and Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Kee H.; Elder, John; Kim, Jang-Chul
We investigate the empirical relation between corporate governance and stock market liquidity. We find that firms with better corporate governance have narrower spreads, higher market quality index, smaller price impact of trades, and lower probability of information-based trading. In addition, we show that changes in our liquidity measures are significantly related to changes in the governance index over time. These results suggest that firms may alleviate information-based trading and improve stock market liquidity by adopting corporate governance standards that mitigate informational asymmetries. Our results are remarkably robust to alternative model specifications, across exchanges, and to different measures of liquidity.</description><author>Chung, Kee H.; Elder, John; Kim, Jang-Chul</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional versus Individual Investment in IPOs: The Importance of Firm Fundamentals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Field, Laura Casares; Lowry, Michelle
Consistent with institutions having an advantage over individuals, we find that newly public firms with the highest levels of institutional investment significantly outperform those with the lowest levels. While prior literature has attributed much of institutions higher returns around various corporate events to private information, we find that much of the difference simply reflects better interpretation of readily available public information. Individuals dis-proportionately invest in the types of firms that earn significantly lower abnormal returns over the long run. Individuals either disregard or misinterpret the relevance of readily available public information, and as a result, they bear the brunt of IPO underperformance.</description><author>Field, Laura Casares; Lowry, Michelle</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Joint Framework for Consistently Pricing Interest Rates and Interest Rate Derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heidari, Massoud; Wu, Liuren
Dynamic term structure models explain the yield curve variation well but perform poorly in pricing and hedging interest rate options. Most existing option pricing practices take the yield curve as given, thus having little to say about the fair valuation of the underlying interest rates. This paper proposes an m + n model structure that bridges the gap in the literature by successfully pricing both interest rates and interest rate options. The first m factors capture the yield curve variation, whereas the latter n factors capture the interest rate options movements that cannot be effectively identified from the yield curve. We propose a sequential estimation procedure that identifies the m yield curve factors from the LIBOR and swap rates in the first step and the n options factors from interest rate caps in the second step. The three yield curve factors explain over 99% of the variation in the yield curve but account for less than 50% of the implied volatility variation for the caps. Incorporating three additional options factors improves the explained variation in implied volatilities to over 99%.</description><author>Heidari, Massoud; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Market Imperfections and the Sensitivity of Investment to Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ovtchinnikov, Alexei V.; McConnell, John J.
Prior studies argue that investment by undervalued firms that require external equity is particularly sensitive to stock prices in irrational capital markets. We present I model in which investment can appear to be more sensitive to stock prices when capital markets are national, but subject to imperfections Such as debt overhang, information asymmetries, and financial distress costs. Our empirical tests support the rational (but imperfect) capital markets view. Specifically, investment-stock price sensitivity is related to firm leverage, financial slack, and probability of financial distress, but is not related to proxies for firm undervaluation. Because, in our model, stock prices reflect the net present values (NPVs) of investment opportunities, our results are consistent with rational capital markets improving the allocation of capital by channeling more funds to firms with positive NPV projects.</description><author>Ovtchinnikov, Alexei V.; McConnell, John J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managers' and Investors' Responses to Media Exposure of Board Ineffectiveness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joe, Jennifer R.; Louis, Henock; Robinson, Dahlia
We analyze the impact of the press on the behavior of various economic agents by examining how media exposure of board ineffectiveness affects corporate governance, investor trading behavior, and Security prices. Our focus oil board quality is motivated by the strong media criticism to which corporate boards and corporate America, in general, have been recently subjected. The results indicate that media releases of (noisy) information have significant economic consequences. In particular, media exposure of board ineffectiveness forces the targeted agents to take corrective actions and enhances shareholder wealth. Individual investors appear to react negatively to the media exposure, whereas investment firms act as if they anticipate the targeted firms' corrective actions.</description><author>Joe, Jennifer R.; Louis, Henock; Robinson, Dahlia</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Style Preferences of Individual Investors and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Alok
This study shows that individual investors systematically shift their preferences across extreme style portfolios (small vs. large, value vs. growth). These preference shifts are influenced by past style returns and earnings differentials. and advice from investment newsletters, but are unaffected by innovations in macroeconomic variables or shifts in expectations about future cash flows. Furthermore, investors' dynamic style preferences influence returns along multiple dimensions: i) the contemporaneous relation between style returns and style-level preference shifts is strong, ii) there is weak evidence of style return predictability, and iii) the correlations among stocks within a style increase when investors move into or Out of the style with greater intensity. Overall. the results indicate that stock categorization influences investors portfolio decisions and stock returns.</description><author>Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing the Elasticity of Corporate Yield Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacoby, Gady; Liao, Rose C.; Batten, Jonathan A.
What drives the compensation demanded by investors in risky bonds? Longstaff and Schwartz (1995) predict that one key factor is the time-varying negative correlation between interest rates and the yield spreads oil corporate bonds. However. the effects of callability and taxes also need to be considered in empirical analyses. Canadian bonds have no tax effects, yet. after controlling for callability. the correlation between risk less interest rates and corporate bond spreads remains negligible. Our results provide support for reduced-form models that explicitly define a default hazard process and Untie the relation between the firm's asset value and default probability.</description><author>Jacoby, Gady; Liao, Rose C.; Batten, Jonathan A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of the Media in the Internet IPO Bubble</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Galpin, Neal; Ray, Rina; Yu, Xiaoyun
We read all news items that came out between 1996 and 2000 on 458 Internet initial public offerings (IPOs) and a matching sample of 458 non-Internet IPOs (a total of 171,488 news items) and classify each news item as good news, neutral news, or bad news.We first document that the media were more positive for Internet IPOs in the period of the dramatic rise in share prices and more negative for Internet IPOs in the period of the dramatic fall in share prices. We then document that media hype is unable to explain the Internet bubble: A 1,646% difference exists in returns between Internet stocks and non-Internet stocks from January 1, 1997, through March 24, 2000 (the market peak), and the media can explain only 2.9% of that.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Galpin, Neal; Ray, Rina; Yu, Xiaoyun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sudden Deaths: Taking Stock of Geographic Ties</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faccio, Mara; Parsley, David C.
Analysis of a worldwide sample of sudden deaths of politicians reveals a market-adjusted 1.7% decline in the value of companies headquarted in the politician's hometown. The decline in value is followed by a drop in the rate of growth in sales and access to credit. Our results are particularly pronounced for family firms, with high growth prospects, firms in industries over which the politician has jurisdiction, and firms headquartered in highly corrupt countries.</description><author>Faccio, Mara; Parsley, David C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probability Judgment Error and Speculation in Laboratory Asset Market Bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ackert, Lucy F.; Charupat, Narat; Deaves, Richard; Kluger, Brian D.
In 12 sessions conducted in a typical bubble-generating experimental environment, we design a pair of assets that can detect both irrationality and speculative behavior. The specific form of irrationality we investigate is the probability judgement error associated with low-probability, high-payoff outcomes. Independently, we test for speculation by comparing prices off identically paying assets in multiperiod versus single-period markets. We establish that aggregate irrationality measured in one dimension (probability judgement error) is associated with aggregate irrationality measured in another (bubble formation).</description><author>Ackert, Lucy F.; Charupat, Narat; Deaves, Richard; Kluger, Brian D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Adaptive Markets Hypothesis: Evidence from the Foreign Exchange Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neely, Christopher J.; Weller, Paul A.; Ulrich, Joshua M.
We analyze the intertemporal stability of excess returns to technical trading rules in the foreign exchange market by conducting true, out-of-sample tests on previously studied rules. The excess returns of the 1970s and 1980s were genuine and not just the result of data mining. But these profit opportunities had disappeared by the early 1990s for filter and. moving average rules. Returns to less-studied rules also have declined but have probably not completely disappeared. High volatility prevents precise estimation of mean returns. These regularities are consistent with the Adaptive Markets Hypothesis (Lo (2004)), but not with the Efficient Markets Hypothesis.</description><author>Neely, Christopher J.; Weller, Paul A.; Ulrich, Joshua M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Founder-CEOs, Investment Decisions, and Stock Market Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger
Eleven percent of the largest public U.S. firms are headed by the CEO who founded the firm. Founder-CEO firms differ systematically from successor-CEO firms with respect to firm valuation, investment behavior, and stock market performance. Founder-CEO firms invest more in research and development, have higher capital expenditures, and make more focused mergers and acquisitions. An equal-weighted investment strategy that had invested in founder-CEO firms from 1993 to 2002 would have earned a bench mark-adjusted return of 8.3% annually. The excess return is robust; after controlling for a wide variety of firm characteristics, CEO characteristics, and industry affiliation, the abnormal return is still 4.4% annually. The implications of the investment behavior and stock market performance of founder-CEO firms are discussed.</description><author>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are the Wall Street Analyst Rankings Popularity Contests?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Emery, Douglas R.; Li, Xi
We investigate the (sell-side) analyst rankings of Institutional Investor (I/I) and The Wall Street Journal (WSJ), using data from 1993-2005. We find that factors with a primary component of recognition are the most important determinants of the rankings, although performance measures are statistically significant determinants in some cases. The single exception to this finding is with existing WSJ stars, where industry-adjusted investment-recommendation performance is the only significant determinant of repeating as a star. Further, in the year after becoming stars, the recommendations of WSJ stars are significantly worse than those of nonstars; and the recommendations and earnings forecasts of I/I stars, as well as the earnings forecasts of WSJ stars, are not significantly different from those of nonstars. We conclude that these rankings are largely "popularity contests."</description><author>Emery, Douglas R.; Li, Xi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Options and Total Payout</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cuny, Charles J.; Martin, Gerald S.; Puthenpurackal, John J.
In this paper, we examine how stock option usage affects total corporate payout. Using fixed-effects panel data estimators on various samples of ExecuComp firms from 1993 to 2005, we find the higher the executive stock options, the lower the total payout, ceteris paribus. We also find some evidence that firms increase payouts through repurchases in order to offset earnings per share dilution that occurs due to usage of executive and non-executive stock options. However, incentives from not having dividend protection for options appear to dominate those from antidilution, resulting in lower total payout for firms with higher options usage.</description><author>Cuny, Charles J.; Martin, Gerald S.; Puthenpurackal, John J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anchoring Bias in Consensus Forecasts and Its Effect on Market Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, Sean D.; Sharpe, Steven A.
Previous empirical studies on the "rationality" of economic. and financial forecasts generally test for generic properties such as bias or autocorrelated errors but provide only limited insight into the behavior behind inefficient forecasts. This paper tests for a specific form of forecast bias. In particular, we examine whether expert consensus forecasts of monthly economic releases are systematically biased toward the value of previous months' releases. Such a bias would be consistent with the anchoring and adjustment heuristic described by Tversky and Kahneman (1974) or could arise from professional forecasters' strategic incentives. We find broad-based and significant evidence for this form of bias, which in some cases results in sizable predictable forecast errors. To investigate whether market participants' expectations are influenced by this bias, we examine interest rate reactions to economic news. We find that bond yields react only to the residual, or unpredictable, component of the forecast error and not to the component induced by anchoring, suggesting that expectations of market participants anticipate this bias embedded in expert forecasts.</description><author>Campbell, Sean D.; Sharpe, Steven A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money and the C-CAPM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balvers, Ronald J.; Huang, Dayong
We consider asset pricing in a monetary economy where liquid assets are held to lower transaction costs. The ensuing model extends the capital asset pricing model (CAPM) and the consumption CAPM by deriving real money growth as an additional factor determining returns. Empirically, the two model versions compare favorably to other theoretical asset pricing models along several dimensions, supporting the traditional intertemporal asset pricing perspective. A value premium arises because value firms are sensitive to liquidity shocks but growth firms are not. Although no alternative factor drives out the money growth factor, the conditioning CAY factors of Lettau and Ludvigson (2001b) add explanatory power.</description><author>Balvers, Ronald J.; Huang, Dayong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing International Asset Pricing Models Using Implied Costs of Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Charles; Ng, David; Swaminathan, Bhaskaran
This paper tests international asset pricing models using firm-level expected returns estimated from an implied cost of capital approach. We show that the implied approach provides clear evidence of economic relations that would otherwise be obscured by the noise in realized returns. Among G-7 countries, expected returns based on implied costs of capital have less than one-tenth the volatility of those based on realized returns. Our tests show that firm-level expected returns increase with world market beta, idiosyncratic volatility, financial leverage, and book-to-market ratios, and decrease with currency beta and firm size.</description><author>Lee, Charles; Ng, David; Swaminathan, Bhaskaran</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Funds for Retail Investors? An Examination of Hedged Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Boyson, Nicole M.; Naik, Narayan Y.
Recently, there has been rapid growth in the assets managed by "hedged Mutual funds"-mutual funds mimicking hedge fund strategies. We examine the performance of these funds relative to hedge funds and traditional mutual funds. Despite using similar trading strategies, hedged mutual funds underperform hedge funds. We attribute this finding to hedge funds' lighter regulation and better incentives. Conversely, hedged mutual funds outperform traditional mutual funds. Notably, this Superior performance is driven by managers with experience implementing hedge fund strategies. Our findings have implications for investors seeking hedge-fund-like payoffs at a lower cost and within the comfort of a regulated environment.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Boyson, Nicole M.; Naik, Narayan Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing Theories of Capital Structure and Estimating the Speed of Adjustment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Rongbing; Ritter, Jay R.
This paper examines time-series patterns of external financing decisions and shows that publicly traded U.S. firms fund a much larger proportion of their financing deficit with external equity when the cost of equity capital is low. The historical values of the cost of equity capital have long-lasting effects on firms' capital structures through their influence on firms' historical financing decisions. We also introduce a new econometric technique to deal with biases in estimates of the speed of adjustment toward target leverage. We find that firms adjust toward target leverage at a moderate speed, with a half-life of 3.7 years for book leverage, even after controlling for the traditional determinants of capital structure and firm fixed effects.</description><author>Huang, Rongbing; Ritter, Jay R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Volatility and Comovement of US Financial Markets around Macroeconomic News Announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brenner, Menachem; Pasquariello, Paolo; Subrahmanyam, Marti
The objective of this paper is to provide a deeper insight into the links between financial markets and the real economy. To that end, we Study the short-term anticipation and response of U.S. stock, Treasury, and corporate bond markets to the first release Of Surprise U.S. macroeconomic information. Specifically, we focus on the impact of these announcements not only on the level, but also on the volatility and comovement of those assets' returns. We do so by estimating several extensions of the parsimonious multivariate GARCH-DCC model of Engle (2002) for the excess holding-period returns Oil seven portfolios of these asset classes. We find that both the process of price formation in each of those financial markets and their interaction appear to be driven by fundamentals. Yet Our analysis reveals a statistically and economically significant dichotomy between the reaction of the stock and bond markets to the arrival of unexpected fundamental information. We also show that the conditional mean, volatility, and comovement among stock. Treasury, and corporate bond returns react asymmetrically to the information content of these surprise announcements. Overall, the above results shed new light on the mechanisms by which new information is incorporated into prices within and across U.S. financial markets.</description><author>Brenner, Menachem; Pasquariello, Paolo; Subrahmanyam, Marti</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organization and Financing of Innovation, and the Choice between Corporate and Independent Venture Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fulghieri, Paolo; Sevilir, Merih
This paper examines the impact of competition on the optimal organization and financing structures in innovation-intensive industries. We show that as an optimal response to competition, firms may choose external organization structures established in collaboration with specialized start-ups where they provide start-tip financing from their own resources. As the intensity of the competition to innovate increases, firms move from internal to external organization of projects to increase the speed of product innovation and to obtain a competitive advantage with respect to rival firms in their industry. We also show that as the level of competition increases, firms provide a higher level of financing for externally organized projects in the form of corporate venture capital (CVC). Our results help explain the emergence of organization and financing arrangements such as CVC and strategic alliances, where large established firms organize their projects in collaboration with external specialized firms and provide financing for externally organized projects from their own internal resources.</description><author>Fulghieri, Paolo; Sevilir, Merih</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Firms Target Credit Ratings or Leverage Levels?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kisgen, Darren J.
Firms reduce leverage following credit rating downgrades. In the year following a downgrade, downgraded firms issue approximately 1.5%-2.0% less net debt relative to net equity as a percentage of assets compared to other firms. This relationship persists within an empirical model of target leverage behavior. The effect of a downgrade is larger at downgrades to it speculative grade rating and if commercial paper access is affected. In particular, firms downgraded to speculative are about twice as likely to reduce debt as other firms. Rating upgrades do not affect Subsequent capital structure activity, suggesting that firms target minimum rating levels.</description><author>Kisgen, Darren J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Skin in the Game Matter? Director Incentives and Governance in the Mutual Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, Martijn; Driessen, Joost; Maenhout, Pascal; Weinbaum, David
We use a unique database oil ownership stakes of equity mutual fund directors to analyze whether the directors' incentive structure is related to fund performance. Ownership of both independent and nonindependent directors plays an economically and statistically significant role. Funds in which directors have low ownership, or "skin in the game," significantly underperform. We posit two economic mechanisms to explain this relation. First, lack of ownership could indicate a director's lack of alignment with fund shareholder interests. Second, directors may have superior private information oil future performance. We find evidence in Support of the first and against the second mechanism.</description><author>Cremers, Martijn; Driessen, Joost; Maenhout, Pascal; Weinbaum, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Did Japanese Investments Influence International Art Prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hiraki, Takato; Ito, Akitoshi; Spieth, Darius A.; Takezawa, Naoya
We test the luxury Consumption hypothesis of Ait-Sahalia. Parker, and Yogo (2004), Using a unique international art price, import/export flow, and stock market data set. We find that the demand for art by Japanese collectors is positively correlated with art prices and Japanese stock prices. This correlation is magnified during the "bubble period" of the Japanese economy (the mid-1980s to the early 1990s) and gains even further strength for works of art typically favored by Japanese collectors. Our results suggest that Japanese investors (or Japanese asset markets) indeed affect international art prices-especially during the bubble period and its aftermath.</description><author>Hiraki, Takato; Ito, Akitoshi; Spieth, Darius A.; Takezawa, Naoya</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Option Repricing and Its Alternatives: An Empirical Examination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalpathy, Swaminathan
In this paper I examine the likelihood of CEO stock option repricing and its alternatives: namely, option grant, stock grant, and "do nothing." Multinomial logit results Suggest that firms reprice options to increase sensitivity of pay to stock price and to temper down sensitivity of pay to volatility. Moreover, repricing firms are Younger and more concentrated in industries where human capital is important. Finally, I find no evidence that internal governance or executive conflicts of interest are relevant in explaining repricing. My results indicate that repricing is motivated by incentive alignment and retention, and not by agency cost considerations.</description><author>Kalpathy, Swaminathan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Paying for Market Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anand, Amber; Tanggaard, Carsten; Weaver, Daniel G.
Many financial markets, including electronic limit order markets, assign designated liquidity providers (LPs). We study the experience of the Stockholm Stock Exchange, where listed firms contract directly with LPs. Our analysis offers insights regarding situations where designated liquidity provision may be beneficial. In addition, we consider the form of liquidity provision contracts, including affirmative obligations required of the LP and compensation for LP services. We find that low current trading activity, wide spreads, and higher information asymmetry increase the attractiveness of contracted liquidity provision. The evidence indicates that LPs trade against market movements and in times of wide spreads. On balance, firms contracting with LPs experience a decreased cost of capital and significant improvements in market quality and price discovery.</description><author>Anand, Amber; Tanggaard, Carsten; Weaver, Daniel G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Block Ownership, Trading Activity, and Market Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, Paul; Chung, Dennis Y.; Yan, Xuemin
We examine the impact of block ownership oil the firm's trading activity and secondary-market liquidity. Our empirical results show that block ownership takes potential trading activity off the table relative to a diffuse ownership structure and impairs the firm's market liquidity. These adverse liquidity effects disappear, however, once we control for trading activity. Our findings suggest that block ownership is detrimental to the firm's market liquidity because of its adverse impact on trading activity-a real friction effect. After controlling for this real friction effect, we find little evidence that block ownership has a negative impact on informational friction. Our results Suggest that the relative lack of trading, and not the threat of informed trading, explains the inverse relation between block ownership and market liquidity.</description><author>Brockman, Paul; Chung, Dennis Y.; Yan, Xuemin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hard-to-Value Stocks, Behavioral Biases, and Informed Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Alok
This paper uses investor-level data to provide direct evidence for an intuitive but surprisingly untested proposition that investors make larger investment mistakes when valuation uncertainty is higher and stocks are more difficult to value. Using multiple measures of valuation uncertainty and multiple behavioral bias proxies, I show that individual investors exhibit stronger behavioral biases when stocks are harder to value and when market-level uncertainty is higher. I also find that informed trading intensity is higher among stocks where individual investors exhibit stronger behavioral biases. Collectively, these results indicate that uncertainty at both stock and market levels amplifies individual investors' behavioral biases and that relatively better informed investors attempt to exploit those biases.</description><author>Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term Structure, Inflation, and Real Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berardi, Andrea
This paper estimates an internally consistent structural model that imposes cross-sectional restrictions on the dynamics of the term structure of interest rates, inflation, and output growth. Distinct from previous term structure settings, this model introduces both time-varying central tendencies and a stochastic conditional mean of output growth. The estimation of the model, which is based on U.S. data over a 1960 to 2005 sample period, provides reliable estimates for the implicit term structures of real interest rates, expected inflation rates, and inflation risk premia, as well as for expectations of macroeconomic variables. The model has better out-of-sample forecasting properties than a number of alternative models, and it contradicts the puzzling evidence that during the "Great Moderation" in inflation subsequent to the mid-1980s, the forecasting ability of structural models deteriorated with respect to atheoretic statistical models.</description><author>Berardi, Andrea</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, Trading Volume, and International Stock Return Comovements: Evidence from Cross-Listed Stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gagnon, Louis; Karolyi, G. Andrew
We investigate the joint dynamics of returns and trading volume of 556 foreign stocks cross-listed on U.S. markets. Heterogeneous-agent trading models rationalize how trading volume reflects the quality of traders' information signals and how it helps to disentangle whether returns are associated with portfolio-rebalancing trades or information-motivated trades. Based on these models, we hypothesize that returns in the home (U.S.) market on high-volume days are more likely to continue to spill over into the U.S. (home) market for those cross-listed stocks subject to the risk of greater informed trading. Our empirical evidence provides support for these predictions, which confirms the I ink between information, trading volume, and international stock return comovements that has eluded previous empirical investigations.</description><author>Gagnon, Louis; Karolyi, G. Andrew</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Substitution and Structured Financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vanden, Joel M.
This article shows how structured financing can be used to solve the asset substitution problem in a dynamic setting. Structuring induces the firm's owner to optimally choose the first best operating strategy even though the owner's value function might be locally convex (concave), which would ordinarily lead to overinvestment (underinvestment) in risky projects. This result is demonstrated in two different continuous time settings-one that is based on the risk-shifting framework of Leland (1998) and one that generalizes the scaled return model of Green (1984). It is shown that the contractual nature of the structuring is a key determinant of the issuing firm's dynamic asset volatility. Furthermore, unlike nonstructured financing, the default (conversion) probability of a structured debt security may be increasing (decreasing) in the firm's total assets. Structured securities are therefore hedge assets, which potentially explains the popularity of structured securities among investors and third-party issuers.</description><author>Vanden, Joel M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is There an Intertemporal Relation between Downside Risk and Expected Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Demirtas, K. Ozgur; Levy, Haim
This paper examines the intertemporal relation between downside risk and expected stock returns. Value at Risk (VaR), expected shortfall, and tail risk are used as measures of downside risk to determine the existence and significance of a risk-return tradeoff. We find a positive and significant relation between downside risk and the portfolio returns on NYSE/AMEX/Nasdaq stocks. VaR remains a superior measure of risk when compared with the traditional risk measures. These results are robust across different stock market indices, different measures of downside risk, loss probability levels, and after controlling for macroeconomic variables and volatility over different holding periods as originally proposed by Harrison and Zhang (1999).</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Demirtas, K. Ozgur; Levy, Haim</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commonality in Liquidity: A Global Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, Paul; Chung, Dennis Y.; Perignon, Christophe
We conduct a comprehensive study of commonality in liquidity using intraday spread and depth data from 47 stock exchanges. We find that firm-level changes in liquidity are significantly influenced by exchange-level changes across most of the world's stock exchanges. Emerging Asian exchanges have exceptionally strong commonality, while those of Latin America exhibit little if any commonality. After documenting the pervasive role of commonality within individual exchanges, we examine commonality across exchanges. We find evidence of a distinct, global component in bid-ask spreads and depths. Local (exchange-level) sources of commonality represent roughly 39% of the firm's total commonality in liquidity, while global sources contribute an additional 19%. We also investigate potential sources of exchange-level and global commonality. We show that commonality is driven by both domestic and U.S. macroeconomic announcements.</description><author>Brockman, Paul; Chung, Dennis Y.; Perignon, Christophe</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder-Initiated Class Action Lawsuits: Shareholder Wealth Effects and Industry Spillovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gande, Amar; Lewis, Craig M.
This paper documents significantly negative stock price reactions to shareholder-initiated class action lawsuits. We find that shareholders partially anticipate these lawsuits based on lawsuit filings against other firms in the same industry and capitalize part of these losses prior to a lawsuit filing date. We show that the more likely a firm is to be sued, the larger the partial anticipation effect (shareholder losses capitalized prior to a lawsuit filing date) and the smaller the filing date effect (shareholder losses measured on the lawsuit filing date). Our evidence suggests that previous research that typically focuses oil the filing date effect understates the magnitude of shareholder losses, and that such an understatement is greater for firms with a higher likelihood of being sued.</description><author>Gande, Amar; Lewis, Craig M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneous Beliefs and Momentum Profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Verardo, Michela
Recent theoretical models derive return continuation in a setting where investors have heterogeneous beliefs or receive heterogeneous information. This paper tests the link between heterogeneity of beliefs and return continuation in the cross-section of U.S. stock returns. Heterogeneity of beliefs about a firm's fundamentals is measured by the dispersion in analyst forecasts of earnings. The results show that momentum profits are significantly larger for portfolios characterized by higher heterogeneity of beliefs. Predictive cross-sectional regressions show that heterogeneity of beliefs has a positive effect on return continuation after controlling for a stock's visibility, the speed of information diffusion, uncertainty about fundamentals, information precision, and volatility. The results in this paper are robust to the potential presence of short-sale constraints and are not explained by arbitrage risk.</description><author>Verardo, Michela</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can the Cross-Sectional Variation in Expected Stock Returns Explain Momentum?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bulkley, George; Nawosah, Vivekanand
It has been hypothesized that momentum might be rationally explained as a consequence of the cross-sectional variation of unconditional expected returns. Stocks with relatively high unconditional expected returns will on average outperform in both the portfolio formation period and in the subsequent holding period. We evaluate this explanation by first removing unconditional expected returns for each stock from raw returns and then testing for momentum in the resulting series. We measure the unconditional expected return on each stock as its mean return in the whole sample period. We find momentum effects vanish in demeaned returns.</description><author>Bulkley, George; Nawosah, Vivekanand</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Prior Performance Affect a Mutual Fund's Choice of Risk? Theory and Further Empirical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hsiu-lang; Pennacchi, George G.
Recent empirical studies of mutual fund competition examine the relation between a fund's performance, the fund manager's compensation, and the fund manager's choice of portfolio risk. This paper models a manager's portfolio choice for compensation rules that can be either a concave, linear, or convex function of the fund's performance relative to that of a benchmark. For particular compensation Structures, a manager increases the fund's "tracking error" volatility as its relative performance declines. However, declining performance does not necessarily lead the manager to raise the volatility of the fund's return. The paper presents nonparametric and parametric tests of the relation between mutual fund performance and risk taking for more than 6,000 equity mutual funds over the 1962 to 2006 period. There is a tendency for mutual funds to increase the standard deviation of tracking errors, but not the standard deviation of returns, as their performance declines. This risk-shifting behavior appears more common for funds whose managers have longer tenures.</description><author>Chen, Hsiu-lang; Pennacchi, George G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing American Options under the Constant Elasticity of Variance Model and Subject to Bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vidal Nunes, Joao Pedro
This paper proposes an alternative characterization of the early exercise premium that is valid for any Markovian and diffusion underlying price process as well as for any parameterization of the exercise boundary. This new representation is shown to provide the best pricing alternative available in the literature for medium- and long-term American option contracts, under the constant elasticity of Variance model. Moreover, the proposed pricing methodology is also extended easily to the valuation of American options on defaultable equity and possesses appropriate asymptotic properties.</description><author>Vidal Nunes, Joao Pedro</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonparametric Estimation of the Short Rate Diffusion Process from a Panel of Yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sam, Abdoul G.; Jiang, George J.
In this paper, we propose a nonparametric estimator of the short rate diffusion process using observations of a panel of yields. The proposed estimator can greatly reduce the bias of the nonparametric estimator proposed in Stanton ( 1997) that uses a single time series of short rate observations. Simulations confirm that the new method significantly attenuates the Spurious nonlinearity of the drift function as documented in Chapman and Pearson (2000). We apply the method to estimate the U.S. short rate process using a panel of six Treasury yields. With 42 years' daily observations of the panel of yields, the proposed drift function estimator achieves the same efficiency as the Stanton ( 1997) estimator based oil 145 years of daily short rate observations. Finally, we show that the proposed estimator also has significant economic implications on the pricing of bonds and interest rate derivatives.</description><author>Sam, Abdoul G.; Jiang, George J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Liquidity and Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sibilkov, Valeriy
This paper tests alternative theories about the effect of asset liquidity on capital structure. Using data from a broad sample of U.S. public companies, I find that leverage is positively related to asset liquidity. Further analysis reveals that the relation between asset liquidity and secured debt is positive, whereas the relation between asset liquidity and unsecured debt is curvilinear. The results are consistent with the view that the costs of financial distress and inefficient liquidation are economically important and that they affect capital structure decisions. In addition, the results are consistent with the hypothesis that the costs of managerial discretion increase with asset liquidity.</description><author>Sibilkov, Valeriy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflicts of Interest in the Stock Recommendations of Investment Banks and Their Determinants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shen, Chung-Hua; Chih, Hsiang-Lin
This study explores the phenomena associated with conflicts of interest, particularly as they pertain to the brokerage and proprietary trading divisions of investment banks. This distinguishes it from past studies, which have researched conflicts of interest between underwriting and brokerage divisions. We examine whether or not an investment bank issues buy recommendations to the market and buys (sells) the same recommended stocks through its proprietary trading division before (after) recommendations, and if so, to what extent this goes on. We find that these conflicts of interest do exist and that these investment banks can profit from their recommendations in the short run.</description><author>Shen, Chung-Hua; Chih, Hsiang-Lin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Market Mispricing: Money Illusion or Resale Option?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Carl R.; Lung, Peter P.; Wang, F. Albert
We examine two hypotheses to explain stock mispricing: i) the money illusion hypothesis (Modigliani and Cohn (1979)) and ii) the resale option hypothesis (Scheinkman and Xiong (2003)). We find that the money illusion hypothesis may explain the level, but not the volatility, of mispricing in the U.S. market. In contrast, the stock resale option hypothesis, which stems from heterogeneous beliefs about future dividend growth rates and short-sale constraints, can explain both the level and the volatility of mispricing. The evidence suggests that while the two hypotheses complement each other in explaining the level of mispricing, the resale option hypothesis provides a more coherent explanation for asset price bubbles, in which extraordinarily high price levels are often accompanied by excessive volatility and frenzied trading.</description><author>Chen, Carl R.; Lung, Peter P.; Wang, F. Albert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Portfolio Optimality Test Based on the First-Order Stochastic Dominance Criterion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kopa, Milos; Post, Thierry
Existing approaches to testing for the efficiency of it given portfolio make strong parametric assumptions about investor preferences and return distributions. Stochastic dominance-based procedures promise a useful nonparametric alternative. However, these procedures have been limited to considering binary choices. In this paper we take a new approach that considers all diversified portfolios and thereby introduce a new concept of first-order Stochastic dominance (FSD) optimality of a given portfolio relative to all possible portfolios, Using Our new test, we show that the U.S. stock market portfolio is significantly FSD nonoptimal relative to benchmark portfolios formed on market capitalization and book-to-market equity ratios. Without appealing to parametric assumptions about the return distribution, we conclude that no nonsatiable investor would hold the market portfolio in the face of the attractive premia of small caps and value stocks.</description><author>Kopa, Milos; Post, Thierry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Relative Informational Efficiency of Stocks and Bonds: An Intraday Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Downing, Chris; Underwood, Shane; Xing, Yuhang
In light of recent improvements in the transparency of the corporate bond market, we examine the relation between high frequency returns on individual stocks and bonds. In contrast to the authors of previous literature, we employ comprehensive transactions data for both classes of securities. We find that hourly stock returns lead bond returns for non-convertible junk- and BBB-rated bonds, and that stock returns lead bond returns for convertible bonds in all rating classes. Most of the predictable nonconvertible bonds are issued by companies in financial distress, while the predictable convertible bonds are those with conversion options more deeply in-the-money. These results indicate that the corporate bond market is less informationally efficient than the stock market, notwithstanding the recent improvements in bond market transparency and associated reductions in corporate bond transaction costs.</description><author>Downing, Chris; Underwood, Shane; Xing, Yuhang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Management Quality, Financial and Investment Policies, and Asymmetric Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Paeglis, Imants; Simonyan, Karen
We develop measures of the management quality of firms and make use of a unique sample of hand-collected data to examine the relationship between the reputation and quality of,I firm's management and its financial and investment policies, a relationship that has so far received little attention in the literature. We hypothesize that better and more reputable managers are able to convey the intrinsic value of their firm more credibly to outsiders, thus reducing the information asymmetry facing their firm in the equity market. Given this, firms with better and more reputable managers will have more access to the equity market, so that we expect lower leverage ratios for these firms. In addition, they will have less need to signal using dividends, so that they will have lower dividend payout ratios. Further, since better managers are likely to select better projects (having a larger net present value (NPV) for any given scale) and to implement them more ably, higher management quality will also be associated with higher levels of investment. We present evidence consistent with the above hypotheses. Our direct tests of the relationship between management quality and asymmetric information also indicate that higher management quality leads to a reduction in the extent of information asymmetry facing I firm in the equity market.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Paeglis, Imants; Simonyan, Karen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Demand Curves for Stocks Slope Down?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Petajisto, Antti
Representative agent models are inconsistent with existing empirical evidence for steep demand curves for individual stocks. This paper resolves the puzzle by proposing that stock prices are instead set by two separate classes of investors. While the market portfolio is still priced by individual investors based on their collective risk aversion, those individual investors also delegate part of their wealth to active money managers, who use that capital to price stocks in the cross section. In equilibrium, the fee charged by active managers has to equal the before-fee alpha the), earn. This endogenously determines the amount of active capital and the slopes of demand curves. A calibration of the model reveals that demand curves can be steep enough to match the magnitude of many empirical findings, including the price effects for stocks entering or leaving the S&amp;P 500 index.</description><author>Petajisto, Antti</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Characteristics, Relative Efficiency, and Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, Giao X.; Swanson, Peggy E.
This Study uses a stochastic frontier approach to evaluate firm efficiency. The resulting efficiency score, based oil firm characteristics, is the input for performance evaluation. The portfolio composed of highly efficient firms significantly underperforms the portfolio composed of inefficient firms even after adjustment for firm characteristics and risk factors, suggesting a required premium for the inefficient firms. The difference in performance between the two portfolios remains for at least five years after the portfolio formation year. In addition, firm efficiency exhibits significant explanatory power for average equity returns in cross-sectional analysis.</description><author>Nguyen, Giao X.; Swanson, Peggy E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock and Bond Market Liquidity: A Long-Run Empirical Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyenko, Ruslan Y.; Ukhov, Andrey D.
This paper establishes liquidity linkage between stock and Treasury bond markets. There is a lead-lag relationship between illiquidity of the two markets and bidirectional Granger causality. The effect of stock illiquidity on bond illiquidity is consistent with flight-to-quality or flight-to-liquidity episodes. Monetary policy impacts illiquidity. The evidence indicates that bond illiquidity acts as a channel through which monetary policy shocks are transferred into the stock market. These effects are observed across illiquidity of bonds of different maturities and are especially pronounced for illiquidity of short-term maturities. The paper provides evidence of illiquidity integration between stock and bond markets.</description><author>Goyenko, Ruslan Y.; Ukhov, Andrey D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Investors, Past Performance, and Dynamic Loss Aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Connell, Paul G. J.; Teo, Melvyn
Using a proprietary database Of Currency trades, this paper explores the effects of trading gains and losses on risk-taking among large institutional investors. We find that institutional investors, unlike individuals, are not prone to the disposition effect. Instead, institutions aggressively reduce risk following losses and mildly increase risk following gains. This asymmetry is more pronounced later in the calendar year and among older and more experienced funds. We show that such performance dependence is consistent with dynamic loss aversion (Barberis, Huang, and Santos (2001)) and overconfidence. In addition, prior institutional gains and losses have palpable implications for future prices.</description><author>O'Connell, Paul G. J.; Teo, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the Value Premium a Proxy for Time-Varying Investment Opportunities: Some Time-Series Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Hui; Savickas, Robert; Wang, Zijun; Yang, Jian
We uncover a positive stock market risk-return tradeoff after controlling for the covariance of market returns with the value premium. Fama and French (1996) conjecture that the value premium proxies for investment opportunities; therefore, by ignoring it, early specifications suffer from an omitted variable problem that causes a downward bias in the risk-return tradeoff estimation. We also document a positive relation between the value premium and its conditional variance, and the estimated conditional value premium is strongly countercyclical. The latter evidence supports the view that value is riskier than growth in bad times, when the price of risk is high.</description><author>Guo, Hui; Savickas, Robert; Wang, Zijun; Yang, Jian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Determinants of Credit Default Swap Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ericsson, Jan; Jacobs, Kris; Oviedo, Rodolfo
Variables that in theory determine credit spreads have limited explanatory power in existing empirical work on corporate bond data. We investigate the linear relationship between theoretical determinants of default risk and default swap spreads. We find that estimated coefficients for a minimal set of theoretical determinants of default risk are consistent with theory and are significant statistically and economically. Volatility and leverage have substantial explanatory power in univariate and multivariate regressions. A principal component analysis of residuals and spreads indicates limited evidence for it residual common factor, confirming that the theoretical variables explain a significant amount of the variation in the data.</description><author>Ericsson, Jan; Jacobs, Kris; Oviedo, Rodolfo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Sentiment Drive the Retail Demand for IPos?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dorn, Daniel
Individual and institutional investors can trade German initial public equity offerings on an as-if/when-issued basis before the start of secondary trading. Using actual when-issued trades made by a sample of clients at I large German retail broker during 1999 and 2000, the paper documents that retail buyers consistently overpay for initial public offerings (IPOs) in the when-issued market relative to the immediate aftermarket. The observed willingness to overpay points to sentiment as a driver of retail trading decisions. Consistent with this interpretation and with sentiment affecting prices, IPOs that are aggressively bought by individuals in the when-issued market exhibit high first-day returns as well as poor aftermarket returns relative to benchmarks of similar stocks.</description><author>Dorn, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the Penalties Associated with Corporate Misconduct: An Empirical Examination of Earnings and Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murphy, Deborah L.; Shrieves, Ronald E.; Tibbs, Samuel L.
We examine the relationship between allegations of corporate misconduct and changes in profitability and risk of the alleged offender. Profitability is measured as reported earnings and analysts' earnings forecasts. Risk is measured as stock return volatility and concordance among analysts' forecasts. Decreases in earnings and increases in risk are found to accompany allegations of misconduct, and although the results are somewhat sensitive to the earnings and risk metrics used, the changes are found to be consistently greater for related-party offenses. The importance of reputational penalties is underscored by analysis of the association between allegation-related changes in firm value and changes in earnings and risk.</description><author>Murphy, Deborah L.; Shrieves, Ronald E.; Tibbs, Samuel L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting Liquidity Traders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalay, Avner; Wohl, Avi
We develop a measure (based oil the relative slopes of the demand and supply schedules) quantifying the asymmetric presence of liquidity traders in the market: a steeper slope of the demand (supply) schedule indicates a concentration of liquidity traders on the demand (supply) side. Using the opening session of the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange, we demonstrate the predictive power of our measure. Consistent with theory, we find that the concentration of liquidity traders on the demand (supply) side is negatively (positively) correlated with future returns. We find that liquidity traders are likely to arrive at the market together (commonality).</description><author>Kalay, Avner; Wohl, Avi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Information Content of Idiosyncratic Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, George J.; Xu, Danielle; Yao, Tong
Ang, Hodrick, Xing, and Zhang (2006a) show that stocks with high idiosyncratic return volatility tend to have low future returns. This paper further documents that idiosyncratic volatility is inversely related to future earning shocks, and more importantly, that the return-predictive power of idiosyncratic volatility is induced by its information content about future earnings. We examine various explanations of the triangular relation among idiosyncratic volatility, future earning shocks, and future stock returns. Our results show that the idiosyncratic volatility anomaly is not a simple manifestation of previously documented market anomalies related to excessive extrapolation oil firm growth, over-investment tendency, accounting accruals, or investor underreaction to earnings news. On the other hand, there is evidence that the idiosyncratic volatility anomaly is related to corporate selective disclosure, and the anomaly is stronger among stocks with a less sophisticated investor base.</description><author>Jiang, George J.; Xu, Danielle; Yao, Tong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio concentration and the performance of individual investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivkovic, Zoran; Sialm, Clemens; Weisbenner, Scott
This paper tests whether information advantages help explain why some individual investors concentrate their stock portfolios in a few stocks. Stock investments made by households that choose to concentrate their brokerage accounts in a few stocks outperform those made by households with more diversified accounts (especially among those with large portfolios). Excess returns of concentrated relative to diversified portfolios are stronger for stocks not included in the S&amp;P 500 index and local stocks, potentially reflecting concentrated investors' successful exploitation of information asymmetries. Controlling for households' average investment abilities, their trades and holdings perform better when their portfolios include fewer stocks.</description><author>Ivkovic, Zoran; Sialm, Clemens; Weisbenner, Scott</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pseudo market timing: A reappraisal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahlquist, Magnus; de Jong, Frank
The average firm going public or issuing new equity underperforms the market in the long run. This underperformance could be related to the endogeneity of the number of new issues if new issues cluster after periods of high abnormal returns oil new issues. In such a case, ex post measures of new issue abnormal returns may be negative on average, despite the absence of ex ante abnormal returns. We evaluate this endogeneity problem in event studies of long-run performance. We argue that it is unlikely that the endogeneity of the number of new issues explains the long-run underperformance of equity issues.</description><author>Dahlquist, Magnus; de Jong, Frank</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cost to firms of cooking the books</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Lee, D. Scott; Martin, Gerald S.
We examine the penalties imposed on the 585 firms targeted by SEC enforcement actions for financial misrepresentation from 1978-2002, which we track through November 15, 2005. The penalties imposed on firms through the legal system average only $23.5 million per firm. The penalties imposed by the market, in contrast, are huge. Our point estimate of the reputational penalty-which we define as the expected loss in the present value of future cash flows due to lower sales and higher contracting and financing costs-is over 7.5 times the sum of all penalties imposed through the legal and regulatory system. For each dollar that a firm misleadingly inflates its market value, on average, it loses this dollar when its misconduct is revealed, plus an additional $3.08. Of this additional loss, $0.36 is due to expected legal penalties and $2.71 is due to lost reputation. In firms that survive the enforcement process, lost reputation is even greater at $3.83. In the cross section, the reputation loss is positively related to measures of the firm's reliance on implicit contracts. This evidence belies a widespread belief that financial misrepresentation is disciplined lightly. To the contrary, reputation losses impose substantial penalties for cooking the books.</description><author>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Lee, D. Scott; Martin, Gerald S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate earnings, firm-level earnings, and expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Demirtas, K. Ozgur; Tehranian, Hassan
This paper provides an analysis of the predictability of stock returns using market-, industry-, and firm-level earnings. Contrary to Lamont (1998), we find that neither dividend payout ratio nor the level of aggregate earnings can forecast the excess market return. We show that these variables do not have robust predictive power across different stock portfolios and sample periods. In contrast to the aggregate-level findings, earnings yield has significant explanatory power for the time-series and cross-sectional variation in firm-level stock returns and the 48 industry portfolio returns. The mean reversion of stock prices as well as the earnings' correlation with expected stock returns are responsible for the forecasting power of earnings yield. These results are robust after controlling for book-to-market, size, price momentum, and post-earnings announcement drift. At the aggregate level, the information content of firm-level earnings about future cash flows is diversified away and higher aggregate earnings do not forecast higher returns.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Demirtas, K. Ozgur; Tehranian, Hassan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home-biased analysts in emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lai, Sandy; Teo, Melvyn
We find that local analyst recommendations are systematically more optimistic than foreign analyst recommendations in emerging markets. The effects of this novel "home bias" among local analysts overwhelm any information asymmetry between foreign and local analysts. Consequently, local analyst upgrades underperform foreign analyst upgrades, while local analyst downgrades outperform foreign analyst downgrades. Neither foreign investors, local institutions, nor retail investors appear to be fully cognizant of this bias. Trade reactions suggest that foreign investors overestimate the bias in foreign analyst recommendations while local institutions underestimate the bias in local analyst recommendations. These results are pervasive across Countries, time periods, and stock groupings, and can be traced to investment banking pressure.</description><author>Lai, Sandy; Teo, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New evidence of asymmetric dependence structures in international equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Okimoto, Tatsuyoshi
A number of recent studies finds two asymmetries in dependence structures in international equity markets; specifically, dependence tends to be high in both highly volatile markets and in bear markets. In this paper, a further investigation of asymmetric dependence structures in international equity markets is performed by using the Markov switching model and copula theory. Combining these two theories enables me to model dependence structures with sufficient flexibility. Using this flexible framework, I indeed find that there are two distinct regimes in the U.S.-U.K. market. I also show that for the U.S.-U.K. market the bear regime is better described by an asymmetric copula with lower tail dependence with clear rejection of the Markov switching multivariate normal model. In addition, I show that ignorance of this further asymmetry in bear markets is very costly for risk management. Lastly, I conduct a similar analysis for other G7 countries, where I find other cases in which the use of a Markov switching multivariate normal model would be inappropriate.</description><author>Okimoto, Tatsuyoshi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Irreversible investment, financing, and bankruptcy decisions in an oligopoly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jou, Jyh-Bang; Lee, Tan
This paper examines a firm's debt level, investment timing, and investment scale choices in a continuous-time model where the Output price of a good that the firm produces depends on a stochastic demand-shift variable and the total industry supply of the good. Using the simple symmetric Cournot-Nash equilibrium assumption that all firms are identical and therefore follow the same financing and investment strategies, we show that competition decreases the output price and hence encourages a firm to wait for a higher demand level before it is profitable to invest. We also demonstrate how uncertainty, bankruptcy costs, and corporate taxation affect the firm's financing and investment decisions.</description><author>Jou, Jyh-Bang; Lee, Tan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity, investment style, and the relation between fund size and fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yan, Xuemin
Using stock transactions data along with detailed stockholdings for a comprehensive sample of U.S. actively managed equity mutual funds from 1993 to 2002, this paper empirically examines the effect of liquidity and investment style on the relation between fund size and fund performance. Consistent with Chen, Hong, Huang, and Kubik (2004), 1 find a significant inverse relation between fund size and fund performance. Further, this inverse relation is stronger among funds that hold less liquid portfolios. The inverse relation between fund size and fund performance is also more pronounced among growth and high turnover funds that tend to have high demands for immediacy. Overall, this paper's findings suggest that liquidity is an important reason why fund size erodes performance.</description><author>Yan, Xuemin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The costs of owning employer stocks: Lessons from Taiwan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Yi-Tsung; Liu, Yu-Jane; Zhu, Ning
Using data on all employees at listed companies in Taiwan, we find that the bias toward employer stocks is generic to individual investor decision making, but not limited to retirement plans. Seventy-one percent of the sample employees invest in employer stocks, and employer stocks make up on average 47% of employee equity portfolios. The underdiversification resulting from the bias toward employer stocks is very costly. Holding current portfolio risk constant, employees forego 4.89% per annum in raw returns by investing in employer stocks, which represents 39.74% of their average 1998 salary income. Our findings have important implications for social security reform and retirement account management.</description><author>Lee, Yi-Tsung; Liu, Yu-Jane; Zhu, Ning</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Tests Based on Option Hedging Errors Correctly Identify Volatility Risk Premia?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branger, Nicole; Schlag, Christian
Tests for the existence and the sign of the volatility risk premium are often based on expected option hedging errors. When the hedge is performed under the ideal conditions of continuous trading and correct model specification, the sign of the premium is the same as the sign of the mean hedging error for a large class of models. We show that discrete trading and model misspecification may cause the standard test to yield unreliable results. In particular, ignoring jump risk premia can lead to incorrect conclusions. We also show that delta-gamma hedges do not increase the reliability of the test.</description><author>Branger, Nicole; Schlag, Christian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recovering Risk Neutral Densities from Option Prices: A New Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rompolis, Leonidas S.; Tzavalis, Elias
In this paper we present a new method of approximating the risk neutral density (RND) from option prices based on the C-type Gram-Charlier series expansion (GCSE) of a probability density function. The exponential form of this type of GCSE guarantees that it will always give positive values of the risk neutral probabilities, and it can allow for stronger deviations from normality, which are two drawbacks of the A-type GCSE used in practice. To evaluate the performance Of the suggested expansion of the RND, the paper presents simulation and empirical evidence.</description><author>Rompolis, Leonidas S.; Tzavalis, Elias</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using Innovative Securities under Asymmetric Information: Why Do Some Firms Pay with Contingent Value Rights?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chatterjee, Sris; Yan, An
This paper provides the first theoretical explanation and the first empirical analysis of contingent value rights (CVRs), which have been used as a means of payment in acquisitions, exchange offers, debt restructurings, Chapter 11 reorganizations, and lawsuit Settlements. A CVR is a put option committing to pay additional cash or securities to CVR holders. contingent on the issuer's share price falling below a prespecified reference level. In this paper. we develop a model to show that CVRs can help a higher-intrinsic-value firm to reveal its firm type when the firm faces an asymmetric information problem. Our model predicts that i) when CVRs are offered along with cash or stock, the announcement period abnormal stock return is greater than that in stock offers, ii) firms facing more severe asymmetric information problems are more likely to offer CVRs to signal their firm type, and iii) firms that are relatively more cash-constrained are more likely to offer CVRs rather than cash. We test all three predictions using a sample of mergers and acquisitions. Our empirical results are consistent with the predictions of the model.</description><author>Chatterjee, Sris; Yan, An</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Commercial Banks on Underwriting Spreads: Evidence from Three Decades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Dongcheol; Palia, Darius; Saunders, Anthony
This paper examines the effect of commercial bank en try on underwriting spreads for IPOs, SEOs. and debt issues using a long time series that spans 30 years, from 1975 to 2004. We find that, on average. commercial banks charge lower spreads of approximately 72 basis points for IPOs, 43 basis points for SEOs, and 14 basis points for debt over the entire sample period. The economic impact of commercial banks on lowering underwriting spreads is most significant when commercial banks were allowed to enter via Section 20 subsidiaries but persists beyond. Commercial bank entry into underwriting appears to have a procompetitive effect that lasts many years after their initial entry.</description><author>Kim, Dongcheol; Palia, Darius; Saunders, Anthony</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blockholder Scarcity, Takeovers, and Ownership Structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, Gary; Kahl, Matthias
Agency problems in firms are prevalent because of a scarcity of wealthy principals with corporate governance ability, whom we call "restructuring specialists." We investigate how this scarce resource, "agency cost-free capital," is allocated. We show that the restructuring specialists may acquire blocks only in those states of the world in which they can increase firm value the most, which corresponds to a takeover. Firms with dispersed ownership and firms with a financial intermediary as a blockholder can coexist, although they are otherwise identical. The model can explain differences in corporate ownership structures and restructuring mechanisms across economics.</description><author>Gorton, Gary; Kahl, Matthias</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Star Power: The Effect of Morningstar Ratings on Mutual Fund Flow</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Del Guercio, Diane; Tkac, Paula A.
We apply an event-study methodology on over 10,000 Morningstar star rating changes and find that Morningstar has Substantial independent influence on the investment allocation decisions of retail mututal fund investors. It is the discrete change in the star rating itself and not the change in the underlying performance measures that drives flow. We document economically and statistically significant positive abnormal flow following rating upgrades, and negative abnormal flow following rating downgrades. In contrast to the cross-sectional flow performance literature, we find evidence of investor punishment of performance declines, some of which is evident immediately in the month of the rating change.</description><author>Del Guercio, Diane; Tkac, Paula A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Style Investing and Institutional Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Froot, Kenneth; Teo, Melvyn
This paper explores the importance and price implications of style investing by institutional investors in the stock market. To analyze styles. we assign stocks to deciles or Segments across three style dimensions: size, value/growth, and sector. We find strong evidence that institutional investors reallocate across style groupings more intensively than across random stock groupings. In addition, we show that own segment style inflows and returns positively forecast future stock returns, while distant segment style inflows and returns forecast negatively. We argue that behavioral theories play a role in explaining these results.</description><author>Froot, Kenneth; Teo, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Traits and Capital Structure Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hackbarth, Dirk
This article incorporates well-documented managerial traits into it tradeoff model of capital structure to study their impact oil corporate financial policy and firm value. Optimistic and/or overconfident managers choose higher debt levels and issue new debt more often but need not follow a pecking order. The model also surprisingly uncovers that these managerial traits can play it positive role. Biased managers' higher debt levels restrain them from diverting funds, which increases firm value by reducing this manager-shareholder conflict. Although higher debt levels delay investment, mildly biased managers' investment decisions can increase firm value by reducing this bondholder-shareholder conflict.</description><author>Hackbarth, Dirk</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment Banking and Analyst Objectivity: Evidence from Analysts Affiliated with Mergers and Acquisitions Advisors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolasinski, Adam C.; Kothari, S. P.
We find evidence that conflicts of interest arising front mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;A) relations influence analysts' recommendations, corroborating regulators' and practitioners' suspicions in a setting, i.e., M&amp;A relations, not previously examined in research on analyst conflicts. In addition, the M&amp;A context allows us to disentangle the conflict of interest effect from selection bias. We find that analysts affiliated with acquirer advisors upgrade acquirer stocks around M&amp;A deals, even around all-cash deals, in which selection bias is unlikely. Also consistent with conflict of interest but not selection bias, target-affiliated analysts publish optimistic reports about acquirers after, but not before, the exchange ratio of an all-stock deal is</description><author>Kolasinski, Adam C.; Kothari, S. P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The genesis of home bias? The location and portfolio choices of investment company start-ups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parwada, Jerry T.
Fund managers' bias toward geographically proximate securities is a well-researched phenomenon, yet the origins of managers' location choices have received little empirical scrutiny. This paper traces the employment and geographic heritage of 358 entrepreneurial fund managers and analyzes the determinants of where they locate their firms and stock selections. The evidence suggests that start-ups tend to be based close to the origins of their founders and in regions with more investment management firms, banking establishments, and large institutional money managers. New money managers show a strong local bias in their equity holdings, three times the levels previously documented for mutual funds. The propensity to invest closer to home correlates strongly with the presence of sub-advisory opportunities from institutional investors in the vicinity. While home bias levels between managers who relocate with their start-ups and the rest of the entrepreneurs are similar, preferences for stocks that were formally local persist.</description><author>Parwada, Jerry T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insiders' tax preferences and firms' choices between dividends and share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsieh, Jim; Wang, Qinghai
This paper investigates whether corporate payout policy is associated with insiders' share holdings and their tax preferences. We find that insider ownership and the implied tax liabilities are positively related to a firm's propensity to employ share repurchases. Firms with higher levels of or greater increases in insider ownership prefer stock repurchases to cash dividends. This relation is more significant in years when dividends were more tax disadvantaged relative to capital gains. Our findings are robust to the endogeneity of insider ownership and the inclusion of various control variables such as firm size, permanence of cash flows, growth opportunities, institutional ownership, and executive stock options. Overall, our results suggest that personal tax considerations from insiders affect corporate payout decisions.</description><author>Hsieh, Jim; Wang, Qinghai</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market participation and the Internet</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bogan, Vicki
Theory indicates that frictions (e.g., information and transaction costs) could account for the lower than expected stock market participation rates. This paper examines the hypothesis that there has been a fundamental change in participation and links this change to the reduction of these frictions by the advent of the Internet. Using panel data on household participation rates over the past decade, the results show computer/Internet using households raised participation substantially more than non-computer using households. The increased probability of participation was equivalent to having over $27,000 in additional household income or over two more mean years of education.</description><author>Bogan, Vicki</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Control transfers, privatization, and corporate performance: Efficiency gains in China's listed companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Gongmeng; Firth, Michael; Xin, Yu; Xu, Liping
We investigate performance effects for China's listed firms when there is a change in the controlling shareholder. These changes include ownership transfers from one state entity to another state entity and from a state entity to a private entity. We find positive performance effects when control is passed to a private entity. In contrast, when the transfer is made to another branch of the state, there is little change in performance. The stock market responds positively to a change in control, with the largest effect observed for private transfers. Our results suggest the Chinese government should continue to sell down its share ownership in listed firms as the transfer of control to private owners enhances corporate profitability and efficiency. Moreover, to help ownership reform, China should encourage an active market for corporate control.</description><author>Chen, Gongmeng; Firth, Michael; Xin, Yu; Xu, Liping</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order consolidation, price efficiency, and extreme liquidity shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barclay, Michael J.; Hendershott, Terrence; Jones, Charles M.
We show that the consolidation of orders is important for producing efficient prices, especially during times of high liquidity demand. The NYSE's centralized opening call market performs better than Nasdaq's decentralized opening process on typical trading days. The NYSE is much better than Nasdaq on witching days when index arbitrage activity subjects S&amp;P 500 stocks to large, predictable, and mostly informationless order flow around quarterly futures contract expirations. Nasdaq opening price efficiency improves to NYSE levels once Nasdaq initiates a consolidated opening call in November 2004, but prices on the decentralized Nasdaq remain less efficient at other times of day.</description><author>Barclay, Michael J.; Hendershott, Terrence; Jones, Charles M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An explicit, multi-factor credit default swap pricing model with correlated factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Ren-Raw; Cheng, Xiaolin; Fabozzi, Frank J.; Liu, Bo
With the recent significant growth in the single-name credit default swap (CDS) market has come the need for accurate and computationally efficient models to value these instruments. While the model developed by Duffie, Pan, and Singleton (2000) can be used, the solution is numerical (solving a series of ordinary differential equations) rather than explicit. In this paper, we provide an explicit solution to the valuation of a credit default swap when the interest rate and the hazard rate are correlated by using the "change of measure" approach and solving a bivariate Riccati equation. CDS transaction data for the period 2/15/2000 through 4/8/2003 for 60 firms are used to test both the goodness of fit of the model and provide estimates of the influence of economic variables in the market for credit-risky bonds.</description><author>Chen, Ren-Raw; Cheng, Xiaolin; Fabozzi, Frank J.; Liu, Bo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of capital structure: Capital market-oriented versus bank-oriented institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antoniou, Antonios; Guney, Yilmaz; Paudyal, Krishna
The paper investigates how firms operating in capital market-oriented economies (the U.K. and the U.S.) and bank-oriented economies (France, Germany, and Japan) determine their capital structure. Using panel data and a two-step system-GMM procedure, the paper finds that the leverage ratio is positively affected by the tangibility of assets and the size of the firm, but declines with an increase in firm profitability, growth opportunities, and share price performance in both types of economies. The leverage ratio is also affected by the market conditions in which the firm operates. The degree and effectiveness of these determinants are dependent on the country's legal and financial traditions. The results also confirm that firms have target leverage ratios with French firms being the fastest in adjusting their capital structure toward their target level and Japanese firms the slowest. Overall, the capital structure of a firm is heavily influenced by the economic environment and its institutions, corporate governance practices, tax systems, the borrower-lender relation, exposure to capital markets, and the level of investor protection in the country in which the firm operates.</description><author>Antoniou, Antonios; Guney, Yilmaz; Paudyal, Krishna</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment and competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akdogu, Evrim; MacKay, Peter
This paper examines how industry structure affects corporate investment patterns. Real options theory shows that deferring irreversible investment in the face of uncertainty is valuable. Theory also shows that the value of waiting to invest falls if investment opportunities are contestable. Consistent with these theories, we find that firms in monopolistic industries exhibit lower investment-q sensitivity and are slower to invest than firms in competitive industries. However, we find that investment-q sensitivity and investment speed are highest in oligopolistic industries, suggesting that the value of investing strategically can outweigh the value of waiting. Indeed, oligopolistic industries experience less entry and more exit than other industries.</description><author>Akdogu, Evrim; MacKay, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic volatility and the cross section of expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret
This paper examines the cross-sectional relation between idiosyncratic volatility and expected stock returns. The results indicate that i) the data frequency used to estimate idiosyncratic volatility, ii) the weighting scheme used to compute average portfolio returns, iii) the breakpoints utilized to sort stocks into quintile portfolios, and iv) using a screen for size, price, and liquidity play critical roles in determining the existence and significance of a relation between idiosyncratic risk and the cross section of expected returns. Portfolio-level analyses based on two different measures of idiosyncratic volatility (estimated using daily and monthly data), three weighting schemes (value-weighted, equal-weighted, inverse volatility-weighted), three breakpoints (CRSP, NYSE, equal market share), and two different samples (NYSE/AMEX/NASDAQ and NYSE) indicate that no robustly significant relation exists between idiosyncratic volatility and expected returns.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional return smoothing in the hedge fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Pool, Veronika K.
We show that if true returns are independently distributed and a manager fully reports gains but delays reporting losses, then reported returns will feature conditional serial correlation. We use conditional serial correlation as a measure of conditional return smoothing. We estimate conditional serial correlation in a large sample of hedge funds. We find that the probability. of observing conditional serial correlation is related to the volatility and magnitude of investor cash flows, consistent with conditional return smoothing in response to the risk of capital flight. We also present evidence that conditional serial correlation is a leading indicator of fraud.</description><author>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Pool, Veronika K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing models with conditional betas and alphas: The effects of data snooping and spurious regression</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, Wayne E.; Sarkissian, Sergei; Simin, Timothy
This paper studies the estimation of asset pricing model regressions with conditional alphas and betas, focusing on the joint effects of data snooping and spurious regression. We find that the regressions are reasonably well specified for conditional betas, even in settings where simple predictive regressions are severely biased. However, there are biases in estimates of the conditional alphas. When time-varying alphas are suppressed and only time-varying betas are considered, the betas become biased. Previous studies overstate the significance of time-varying alphas.</description><author>Ferson, Wayne E.; Sarkissian, Sergei; Simin, Timothy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The poor predictive performance of asset pricing models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Simin, Timothy
This paper examines time-series forecast errors of expected returns from conditional and unconditional asset pricing models for portfolio and individual firm equity returns. A new result that increases predictive precision concerning model specification and forecasting is introduced. Conditional versions of the models generally produce higher mean squared errors than unconditional versions for step ahead prediction. This holds for individual firm data when the instruments are firm specific. Mean square forecast error decompositions indicate that the asset pricing models produce relatively unbiased predictions, but the variance is severe enough to ruin the step ahead predictive ability beyond that of a constant benchmark.</description><author>Simin, Timothy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Second-order stochastic dominance, reward-risk portfolio selection, and the CAPM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Giorgi, Enrico; Post, Thierry
Starting from the reward-risk model for portfolio selection introduced in De Giorgi (2005), we derive the reward-risk Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM) analogously to the classical mean-variance CAPM. In contrast to the mean-variance model, reward-risk portfolio selection arises from an axiomatic definition of reward and risk measures based on a few basic principles, including consistency with second-order stochastic dominance. With complete markets, we show that at any financial market equilibrium, reward-risk investors' optimal allocations are comonotonic and, therefore, our model reduces to a representative investor model. Moreover, the pricing kernel is an explicitly given, non-increasing function of the market portfolio return, reflecting the representative investor's risk attitude. Finally, an empirical application shows that the reward-risk CAPM captures the cross section of U.S. stock returns better than the mean-variance CAPM does.</description><author>De Giorgi, Enrico; Post, Thierry</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International diversification with large- and small-cap stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eun, Cheol S.; Huang, Wei; Lai, Sandy
To the extent that investors diversify internationally, large-cap stocks receive the dominant share of fund allocation. Increasingly, however, returns to large-cap stocks or stock market indices tend to comove, mitigating the benefits from international diversification. In contrast, stocks of locally oriented, small companies do not exhibit the same tendency. In this paper, we assess the potential of small-cap stocks as a vehicle for international portfolio diversification during the period 1980-1999. We show that the extra gains from the augmented diversification with small-cap funds are statistically significant for both in-sample and out-of-sample periods and remain robust to the consideration of market frictions.</description><author>Eun, Cheol S.; Huang, Wei; Lai, Sandy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic news, order flows, and exchange rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Love, Ryan; Payne, Richard
In textbook models of exchange rate determination, the news contained in public information announcements is directly impounded into prices with there being no role for trading in this process of information assimilation. This paper directly tests this theoretical result using transaction level exchange rate return and trading data and a sample of scheduled macroeconomic announcements. The main result of the paper is that even information that is publicly and simultaneously released to all market participants is partially impounded into prices via the key micro level price determinant-order flow. We quantify the role that order flow plays and find that approximately one third of price-relevant information is incorporated via the trading process.</description><author>Love, Ryan; Payne, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt capacity, cost of debt, and corporate insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zou, Hong; Adams, Mike B.
Using a unique insurance dataset for a sample of Chinese publicly listed companies for the period 1997 through 2003, this study tests the simultaneous linkages between debt capacity, cost of debt, and corporate property insurance. Our results suggest that, on the one hand, a higher cost of debt appears to motivate the use of more property insurance, but high leverage alone does not lead to the purchase of more property insurance. The latter finding might reflect the unique institutional setting of China, for example, where there is a low chance of legally enforced company liquidation. Also, there is evidence that leverage can interact with tangible assets intensity and exert a positive conjoint effect on the corporate purchase of property insurance. On the other hand, we find evidence that supports that property insurance helps expand insuring firms' debt capacity and helps lower their borrowing costs. However, the moderate evidence on the cost reduction effect suggests that lowering the borrowing cost is likely to be a concern secondary to facilitating corporate borrowing and thereby expanding debt capacity in corporate property insurance decisions in China. Overall, we conclude that debt capacity, cost of debt, and corporate insurance appear to be simultaneously related.</description><author>Zou, Hong; Adams, Mike B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are household portfolios efficient? An analysis conditonal on housing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pelizzon, Loriana; Weber, Guglielmo
Standard tests of portfolio efficiency neglect the existence of illiquid wealth. The most important illiquid asset in household portfolios is housing: if housing stock adjustments are infrequent, optimal portfolios in periods of no adjustment are affected by housing price risk through a hedge term and tests for portfolio efficiency of financial assets must be run conditionally upon housing wealth. We use Italian household portfolio data and time series on financial assets and housing stock returns to assess whether actual portfolios are efficient. We find that housing wealth plays a key role in determining whether portfolios chosen by homeowners are efficient.</description><author>Pelizzon, Loriana; Weber, Guglielmo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance, shareholder rights, and shareholder rights plans: Poison, placebo, or prescription?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caton, Gary L.; Goh, Jeremy
We examine the effect of poison pill adoptions on firm value, controlling for the adopting firm's preexisting corporate governance structure. We find that only companies with the most democratic governance structures, defined as those with the fewest preexisting protective governance provisions, experience significantly positive abnormal stock returns and significantly positive abnormal revisions in five-year earnings growth rate forecasts. Moreover, regression results indicate that abnormal returns and forecast revisions are significantly related to governance structure and not to board composition or subsequent merger activity.</description><author>Caton, Gary L.; Goh, Jeremy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information and the intermediary: Are market intermediaries informed traders in electronic markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anand, Amber; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
A significant but unresolved question in the current debate about the role of intermediaries in financial markets is whether intermediaries behave as passive traders or whether they actively seek and trade on information. We address this issue by explicitly comparing the informational advantages of intermediaries with those of other investors in the market. We find that intermediaries account for greater price discovery than other institutional and individual investors in spite of initiating fewer trades and volume. Furthermore, intermediary information does not arise from inappropriate handling of customer orders by intermediaries. We propose that our findings are consistent with noisy rational expectations models, where agents extract valuable information from past prices. Intermediaries bear little or no opportunity cost of monitoring market conditions, which gives them an advantage in making profitable price-contingent trades. Lower trading costs may also enable intermediaries to trade more effectively and frequently on their information.</description><author>Anand, Amber; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of mutual fund family membership on investor risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Green, T. Clifton
Many investors confine their mutual fund holdings to a single fund family either for simplicity or through restrictions placed by their retirement savings plan. We find evidence that mutual fund returns are more closely correlated within than between fund families. As a result, restricting investment to one fund family leads to a greater total portfolio risk than diversifying across fund families. We examine the sources of this increased correlation and find that it is due primarily to common stock holdings, but is also more generally related to families having similar exposures to economic sectors or industries. Fund families also show a propensity to focus on high or low risk strategies, which leads to a greater dispersion of risk across restricted investors. An investor considering adding an additional fund, either in the same family or outside the family, would need to believe the inside fund offered an extra 50 to 70 basis points to have the same Sharpe ratio.</description><author>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Green, T. Clifton</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of overnight periods on option pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boes, Mark-Jan; Drost, Feike C.; Werker, Bas J. M.
This paper investigates the effect of closed overnight exchanges on option prices. During the trading day, asset prices follow the literature's standard affine model that allows for stochastic volatility and random jumps. Independently, the overnight asset price process is modeled by a single jump. We find that the overnight component reduces the variation in the random jump process significantly. However, neither the random jumps nor the overnight jumps alone are able to empirically describe all features of option prices. We conclude that both random jumps during the day and overnight jumps are important in explaining option prices, where the latter account for about one quarter of total jump risk.</description><author>Boes, Mark-Jan; Drost, Feike C.; Werker, Bas J. M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multivariate tests for stochastic dominance efficiency of a given portfolio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Post, Thierry; Versijp, Philippe
We develop empirical tests for stochastic dominance efficiency of a given investment portfolio relative to all possible portfolios formed from a given set of assets. Our tests use multivariate statistics, which result in superior statistical power properties compared to existing stochastic dominance efficiency tests and increase the comparability with existing mean-variance efficiency tests. Using our tests, we demonstrate that the mean-variance inefficiency of the CRSP all-share index relative to beta-sorted portfolios can be explained by tail risk not captured by variance.</description><author>Post, Thierry; Versijp, Philippe</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Missed opportunities: Optimal investment timing when information is costly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guthrie, Graeme
Real option analysis typically assumes that projects are continuously evaluated and launched at precisely the time determined to be optimal, but real world projects cannot be managed in this way because of the costs of formally evaluating an investment opportunity. This paper shows that immediate investment is more attractive if evaluation costs are high or the amount of information to be revealed by an evaluation is large. The optimal delay until a reevaluation is long ifevaluation costs are high or the amount of information to be revealed by an evaluation is small. The reduction in the value of project rights is especially severe when the value of the completed project is strongly mean reverting because then precision in investment timing is particularly important.</description><author>Guthrie, Graeme</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underpricing in discriminatory and uniform-price treasury auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldreich, David
This paper compares the newer uniform-price U.S. Treasury auctions to the traditional discriminatory mechanism and examines the extent to which the auction mechanisms are responsible for underpricing. Empirically, I find that even for the newer uniform-price auctions, the average price received by the Treasury is less than the price of the same securities in the concurrent secondary market although this underpricing is reduced by half relative to the older mechanism. From the summary statistics released by the Treasury, I calibrate common value auction models for the two mechanisms and predict the level of underpricing in each auction. I find that the observed magnitude of underpricing in the auctions is consistent with the model's predictions.</description><author>Goldreich, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms go dark?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marosi, Andras; Massoud, Nadia
In recent years, a number of firms and banks have decided to "go dark," i.e., deregister with the Securities and Exchange Commission and delist from the major exchanges despite having a large number of outside shareholders. This paper seeks to answer two important questions: Why do firms choose to go dark? What are the consequences for shareholders? We find that firms with fewer valuable growth opportunities, greater insider ownership, lower institutional ownership, higher leverage, and lower market momentum are more likely to go dark. Furthermore, the cost of regulatory compliance is a driving force behind the going dark phenomenon.</description><author>Marosi, Andras; Massoud, Nadia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systematic share price fluctuations after bankruptcy filings and the investors who drive them</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dawkins, Mark C.; Bhattacharya, Nilabhra; Bamber, Linda Smith
Beginning in the 1990s, firms often continue to trade on the major national exchanges after Chapter 11 bankruptcy filings. For bankruptcies filed from 1993-2003, we find that the more negative the filing period price reaction, the more favorable the immediate post-filing returns, on average. This reversal is not attributable to bid-ask bounce, it holds after controlling for other factors associated with post-filing returns, and it appears more attributable to the activities of large traders than to small traders. Supplementary tests reveal that the pattern of post-filing returns differs significantly for bankruptcies filed in bull versus bear markets. Bankruptcies filed during the 1993 to 1999 bull market enjoy substantial but short-lived reversals averaging one-third of the filing period price plunge. These reversals are inconsistent with efficient assimilation of the bankruptcy information. In contrast, we find no evidence of post-filing reversals for bankruptcies filed from 2000 to 2003.</description><author>Dawkins, Mark C.; Bhattacharya, Nilabhra; Bamber, Linda Smith</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market liquidity and firm dividend policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Suman; Gatchev, Vladimir A.; Spindt, Paul A.
We provide evidence of a link between firm dividend policy and stock market liquidity. In the cross section, owners of less (more) liquid common stock are more (less) likely to receive cash dividends. Predictions of the proportion of dividend payers based on 19631977 cross-sectional estimates account for most of the declining propensity of firms to pay dividends as documented by Fama and French (2001). Furthermore, historic liquidity is an important determinant of dividend initiations and omissions. Finally, we show that sensitivity of firm value to aggregate liquidity declines after dividend initiations, suggesting that investors view stock market liquidity and dividends as substitutes.</description><author>Banerjee, Suman; Gatchev, Vladimir A.; Spindt, Paul A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do controlling families of public firms sell their remaining ownership stake?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klasa, Sandy
I investigate what leads controlling families of publicly traded firms to sell their remaining ownership stake. The sale of a controlling stake is best explained in the context of theories of the firm related to optimal risk bearing, the separation of ownership and management expertise, the CEO succession process, and the monitoring provided by outside blockholders. A timing explanation is only marginally supported. The sale of a controlling stake is not explained by insufficient financial resources to fully invest in growth opportunities. This study offers insights into the final stage of the process in which entrepreneurs sequentially sell their firm to outside parties and also identifies the nature of costs of concentrated ownership.</description><author>Klasa, Sandy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Initial public offerings of state-owned enterprises: An international study of policy risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lam, Swee-Sum; Tan, Ruth Seow-Kuan; Wee, Glenn Tsao-Min
Policy risk, rather than information asymmetry, explains the cross-sectional underpricing of privatized initial public offerings. The issuer governments of high policy risk issues tend to retain a large equity stake and underprice more with underpricing increasing in retained equity. While the issuer government's retained equity is an observable signal for policy risk, we find that the quality of a country's bureaucratic machinery is a more intuitive and practical measure of policy risk. Policy risk also explains the absence of a systematic relation between the initial returns on privatized and private initial public offerings.</description><author>Lam, Swee-Sum; Tan, Ruth Seow-Kuan; Wee, Glenn Tsao-Min</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A binomial lattice method for pricing corporate debt and modeling Chapter 11 proceedings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Broadie, Mark; Kaya, Oezguer
The pricing of corporate debt is still a challenging and active research area in corporate finance. Starting with Merton (1974), many authors proposed a structural approach in which the value of the assets of the firm is modeled by a stochastic process, and all other variables are derived from this basic process. These structural models have become more complex over time in order to capture more realistic aspects of bankruptcy proceedings. The literature in this area emphasizes closed-form solutions that are derived by either partial differential equation methods or analytical pricing techniques. However, it is not always possible to build a comprehensive model with realistic model features and achieve a closed-form solution at the same time. In this paper, we develop a binomial lattice method that can be used to handle complex structural models such as ones that include Chapter 11 proceedings of the U.S. bankruptcy code. Although lattice methods have been widely used in the option pricing literature, they are relatively new in corporate debt pricing. In particular, the limited liability requirement of the equity holders needs to be handled carefully in this context. Our method can be used to solve the Leland (1994) model and its extension to the finite maturity case, the more complex model of Broadie, Chernov, and Sundaresan (2007), and others.</description><author>Broadie, Mark; Kaya, Oezguer</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bayesian analysis of linear factor models with latent factors, Multivariate Stochastic volatility, and APT pricing restrictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nardari, Federico; Scruggs, John T.
We analyze a new class of linear factor models in which the factors are latent and the covariance matrix of excess returns follows a multivariate stochastic volatility process. We evaluate cross-sectional restrictions suggested by the arbitrage pricing theory (APT), compare competing stochastic volatility specifications for the covariance matrix, and test for the number of factors. We also examine whether return predictability can be attributed to time-varying factor risk premia. Analysis of these models is feasible due to recent advances in Bayesian Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods. We find that three latent factors with multivariate stochastic volatility best explain excess returns for a sample of 10 size decile portfolios. The data strongly favor models constrained by APT pricing restrictions over otherwise identical unconstrained models.</description><author>Nardari, Federico; Scruggs, John T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do market timing hedge funds time the market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yong; Liang, Bing
This paper examines whether self-described market timing hedge funds have the ability to time the U.S. equity market. We propose a new measure for timing return and volatility jointly that relates fund returns to the squared Sharpe ratio of the market portfolio. Using a sample of 221 market timing funds during 1994-2005, we find evidence of timing ability at both the aggregate and fund levels. Timing ability appears relatively strong in bear and volatile market conditions. Our findings are robust to other explanations, including public information-based strategies, options trading, and illiquid holdings. Bootstrap analysis shows that the evidence is unlikely to be attributed to luck.</description><author>Chen, Yong; Liang, Bing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentive contracts and hedge fund management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hodder, James E.; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten
We investigate incentive effects of a typical hedge fund contract for a manager with power utility. With a one-year horizon, the manager displays risk taking that varies dramatically with fund value. We extend the model to multiple yearly evaluation periods and find that the manager's risk taking is rapidly moderated if the fund performs reasonably well. The most realistic approach to modeling fund closure uses an endogenous shutdown barrier where the manager optimally chooses to shut down. The manager increases risk taking as fund value approaches that barrier, and this boundary behavior persists strongly with multiyear horizons.</description><author>Hodder, James E.; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysts' conflicts of interest and biases in earnings forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Louis K. C.; Karceski, Jason; Lakonishok, Josef
Analysts' earnings forecasts are influenced by their desire to win investment banking clients. We hypothesize that the equity bull market of the 1990s, along with the boom in investment banking business, exacerbated analysts' conflicts of interest and their incentives to strategically adjust forecasts to avoid earnings disappointments. We document shifts in the distribution of earnings surprises and related changes in the market's response to surprises and forecast revisions. The evidence for shifts is stronger for growth stocks, where conflicts of interest are more pronounced. However, shifts are less notable for analysts without ties to investment banking and in international markets.</description><author>Chan, Louis K. C.; Karceski, Jason; Lakonishok, Josef</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Characterizing world market integration through time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carrieri, Francesca; Errunza, Vihang; Hogan, Ked
International asset pricing models suggest that barriers to portfolio flows and availability of market substitutes affect the degree and time variation of world market integration. We use GARCH-in-mean methodology to assess the evolution in market integration for eight emerging markets over the period 1977-2000. Our results, suggest that while local risk is still a relevant factor in explaining time variation of emerging market returns, none of the countries appear to be completely segmented. We find that there are substantial cross-market differences in the degree of integration. The evolution toward more integrated financial markets is apparent although at times we do observe reversals. In addition, we provide clear evidence on the impropriety of directly using correlations of market-wide index returns as a measure of market integration. Finally, financial market development and financial liberalization policies play important roles in integrating emerging markets.</description><author>Carrieri, Francesca; Errunza, Vihang; Hogan, Ked</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of outside directors: Evidence from corporate governance reform in Korea</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Jongmoo Jay; Park, Sae Woon; Yoo, Sean Sehyun
This paper examines the valuation impacts of outside independent directors in Korea, where a regulation requiring outside directors was instituted after the Asian financial crisis. In contrast to studies of U.S. firms, the effects of independent directors on firm performance are strongly positive. Foreigners also have positive impacts. The effects of indigenous institutions such as chaebol or family control are insignificant or negative. This implies that the effect of outsiders depends on board composition as well as the nature of the market in which the firm operates.</description><author>Choi, Jongmoo Jay; Park, Sae Woon; Yoo, Sean Sehyun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting currency excess returns: Can the forward bias be exploited?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Villanueva, O. Miguel
The forward bias anomaly implies that currency excess returns are predictable by the forward premium. Yet, recent studies suggest that statistical inference problems may spuriously account for this predictability. This article demonstrates that while currency excess returns are not predictable out of sample using a standard mean square forecast error criterion, the forward premium nonetheless has directional predictability. This directional forecasting accuracy translates into statistically significant profits from trading on the forward bias anomaly.</description><author>Villanueva, O. Miguel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reassessing the impact of option introductions on market quality: A less restrictive test for event-date effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danielsen, Bartley R.; Van Ness, Bonnie F.; Warr, Richard S.
Prior research concludes that option introductions improve the average liquidity of the underlying stocks. We develop an improved, generalizable test to assess whether market quality changes occur on or near an event date. Applying this method to option listing events, we conclude that options do not systematically improve the market quality of the underlying security; rather, the market quality of the underlying security improves before the listing decision. Hazard model tests indicate that improving liquidity is a selection criterion in the option listing decision. Moreover, these tests suggest that the size of a stock's bid-ask spread is the single most important option listing determinant.</description><author>Danielsen, Bartley R.; Van Ness, Bonnie F.; Warr, Richard S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Basis convergence and long memory in volatility when dynamic hedging with futures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dark, Jonathan
When market returns follow a long memory volatility process, standard approaches to estimating dynamic minimum variance hedge ratios (MVHRs) are misspecified. Simulation results and an application to the S&amp;P 500 index document the magnitude of the misspecification that results from failure to account for basis convergence and long memory in volatility. These results have important implications for the estimation of MVHRs in the S&amp;P 500 example and other markets as well.</description><author>Dark, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of shareholder taxes on corporate payout choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moser, William J.
This study investigates whether the difference in individual shareholder tax rates between dividend income and capital gain (the dividend tax penalty) affects a firm's choice between distributing funds to shareholders through dividends or share repurchases. The results of this study suggest that, in periods in which the dividend tax penalty increases, firms are more likely to distribute funds to shareholders through share repurchases as opposed to dividends. The results also indicate that the relation between the dividend tax penalty and corporate payout choice is affected by the types of shareholders who own stock in the firm. As tax-disfavored institutional ownership increases and the dividend tax penalty increases, firms are more likely to repurchase shares as opposed to distributing dividends. In contrast, as tax-favored institutional ownership increases and the dividend tax penalty increases, firms are less likely to repurchase shares as opposed to distributing dividends. As senior managerial share ownership increases and the dividend tax penalty increases, firms are more likely to make distributions to shareholders in the form of share repurchases.</description><author>Moser, William J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information disclosure and market quality: The effect of SEC rule 605 on trading costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhao, Xin; Chung, Kee H.
The Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) adopted Rule 605 (formerly Rule 11Acl5) on November 15, 2000. The Rule requires market centers to make monthly public disclosure of execution quality. The Rule is intended to achieve a more competitive and efficient national market system by increasing the visibility of execution quality. The effective and quoted spreads for our study sample of NYSE, AMEX, and NASDAQ stocks declined significantly after implementation of the Rule. The decline cannot be attributed to a secular trend in spreads, concurrent changes in stock attributes, or the effect of decimal pricing. Although the quoted depth of NYSE stocks also declined, overall market quality is higher after implementation of the Rule. Based on these results, we conclude that the SEC's goal to improve execution quality through more transparent markets has been achieved.</description><author>Zhao, Xin; Chung, Kee H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of underwriter-investor relationships in the IPO process</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Binay, Murat M.; Gatchev, Vladimir A.; Pirinsky, Christo A.
We find that in allocating initial public offerings (IPOs), underwriters favor institutions they have previously worked with. Regular investors benefit more than casual investors in IPOs through greater participation in underpriced issues. Relationship participation is more important in the distribution of IPOs with stronger demand, TPOs of less liquid firms, and deals by less reputable underwriters. Overall, our results are consistent with book-building theories of IPOs. Interestingly, for 1999-2000 we find that regular investors receive even more underpriced IPOs relative to previous years while we do not find evidence that they provide additional services in IPOs.</description><author>Binay, Murat M.; Gatchev, Vladimir A.; Pirinsky, Christo A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board composition and corrective action: Evidence from corporate responses to bad acquisition bids</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paul, Donna L.
This study investigates the role of corporate boards following large declines in share value surrounding acquisition announcements. The results indicate that firms with independent boards are less likely to complete these value-decreasing bids, suggesting that boards influence corporate responses to information in stock prices. Board independence is also associated with unusually high frequencies of asset restructuring for bids that are completed, suggesting that independent boards promote restructuring in mergers the market believes are difficult to integrate. These results complement existing evidence on the board's exante role in averting bad outcomes by showing that independent boards intervene following value-decreasing events.</description><author>Paul, Donna L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of the designated market maker</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Venkataraman, Kumar; Waisburd, Andrew C.
The proliferation of electronic limit order books operating without dealers raises questions regarding the need for intermediaries with affirmative obligations to maintain markets. We develop a simple model of dealer participation and test it using a sample of less liquid firms that trade on the Paris Bourse. The results indicate that firms with designated dealers exhibit better market quality, and that younger firms, smaller firms, and less volatile firms choose a designated dealer. Around the announcement of dealer introduction, stocks experience an average cumulative abnormal return of nearly 5% that is positively correlated with improvements in liquidity. Overall, these findings emphasize the potential benefits of designing better market structures, even within electronic limit order books, and suggest that purely endogenous liquidity provision may not be optimal for all securities.</description><author>Venkataraman, Kumar; Waisburd, Andrew C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competitive equilibrium with debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhdanov, Alexei
This paper studies the interaction among financing, entry, and exit decisions of firms in a competitive industry subject to aggregate uncertainty. In contrast to Fries, Miller, and Perraudin (1997), 1 do not assume that a firm in default leaves the industry immediately. The implications on the optimal leverage ratios and equilibrium credit spreads are discussed. By incorporating the effect of competition, I show that the model results in significantly higher credit spreads than those predicted by traditional single firm models. Dynamic capital structure strategies in a competitive industry are also examined. The model renders a number of empirical predictions regarding leverage ratios and credit spreads of firms in a competitive industry.</description><author>Zhdanov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund attributes and investor Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.
I study the dynamics of investor cash flows in socially responsible mutual funds. Consistent with anecdotal evidence of loyalty, the monthly volatility of investor cash flows is lower in socially responsible funds than in conventional funds. I find strong evidence that cash flows into socially responsible funds are more sensitive to lagged positive returns than cash flows into conventional funds, and weaker evidence that cash outflows from socially responsible funds are less sensitive to lagged negative returns. These results indicate that investors derive utility from the socially responsible attribute, especially when returns are positive.</description><author>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal portfolio choice with parameter uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kan, Raymond; Zhou, Guofu
In this paper, we analytically derive the expected loss function associated with using sample means and the covariance matrix of returns to estimate the optimal portfolio. Our analytical results show that the standard plug-in approach that replaces the population parameters by their sample estimates can lead to very poor out-of-sample performance. We further show that with parameter uncertainty, holding the sample tangency portfolio and the riskless asset is never optimal. An investor can benefit by holding some other risky portfolios that help reduce the estimation risk. In particular, we show that a portfolio that optimally combines the riskless asset, the sample tangency portfolio, and the sample global minimum-variance portfolio dominates a portfolio with just the riskless asset and the sample tangency portfolio, suggesting that the presence of estimation risk completely alters the theoretical recommendation of a two-fund portfolio.</description><author>Kan, Raymond; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of credit spreads and ratings migrations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farnsworth, Heber; Li, Tao
There is a large and growing literature on how to model the dynamics of the default-free term structure to fit the observed historical data. Much less is known about how best to model the dynamics of defaultable yield curves. This paper develops a class of defaultable term structure models that is tractable enough to be empirically implemented and flexible enough to capture some important behaviors of the credit spreads in the data. We compare two non-nested models within this class using a Bayesian estimation technique, which helps to solve the problem of latent state variables. The Bayesian approach also enables us to test the two non-nested models on the basis of the Bayes factor. The results strongly suggest that models with constant transition probabilities will not be able to fit the observed dynamics of inter-rating spreads.</description><author>Farnsworth, Heber; Li, Tao</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is IPO underperformance a peso problem?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Gu, Li; Hochberg, Yael V.
Recent studies suggest that the underperformance of IPOs in the post-1970 sample may be a small sample effect or "Peso problem." That is, IPO underperformance may result from observing too few star performers ex post than were expected ex ante. We develop a model of IPO performance that captures this intuition by allowing returns to be drawn from mixtures of outstanding, benchmark, or poor performing states. We estimate the model under the null of no ex ante average IPO underperformance and construct small sample distributions of various statistics measuring IPO relative performance. We find that small sample biases are extremely unlikely to account for the magnitude of the post-1970 IPO underperformance observed in data.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Gu, Li; Hochberg, Yael V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board composition, corporate performance, and the cadbury committee recommendation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahya, Jay; McConnell, John J.
During the 1990s and beyond, countries around the world witnessed calls and/or mandates for more outside directors on publicly traded companies' boards even though extant studies find no significant correlation between outside directors and corporate performance. We examine the connection between changes in board composition and corporate performance in the U.K. over the interval 1989-1996, a period that surrounds publication of the Cadbury Report, which calls for at least three outside directors for publicly traded corporations. We find that companies that add directors to conform with this standard exhibit a significant improvement in operating performance both in absolute terms and relative to various peer group benchmarks. We also find a statistically significant increase in stock prices around announcements that outside directors were added in conformance with this recommendation. We do not endorse mandated board structures, but the evidence appears to be that such a mandate is associated with an improvement in performance in U.K. companies.</description><author>Dahya, Jay; McConnell, John J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bayesian learning in financial markets: Testing for the relevance of information precision in price discovery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hautsch, Nikolaus; Hess, Dieter
Bayesian learning claims that the strength of the price impact of unanticipated information depends on the relative precision of traders' prior and posterior beliefs. In this paper, we test for this implication of Bayesian models by analyzing intraday price responses of T-bond futures to U.S. employment announcements. By employing additional detailed information in addition to the widely used headline figures, we extract release-specific precision measures. We find that the price impact of more precise information is significantly stronger, even after controlling for an asymmetric price response to "good" and "bad" news. This result strengthens previous findings that differences in earnings response coefficients across companies are related to proxies for the credibility of the reported financial information.</description><author>Hautsch, Nikolaus; Hess, Dieter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The U-shaped investment curve: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cleary, Sean; Povel, Paul; Raith, Michael
We analyze how the availability of internal funds affects a firm's investment. We show that under fairly standard assumptions, the relation is U-shaped: investment increases monotonically with internal funds if they are large but decreases if they are very low. We discuss the tradeoff that generates the U-shape, and argue that models predicting an always increasing relation are based on restrictive assumptions. Using a large data set, we find strong empirical support for our predictions. Our results qualify conventional wisdom about the effects of financial constraints on investment behavior, and help to explain seemingly conflicting findings in the empirical literature.</description><author>Cleary, Sean; Povel, Paul; Raith, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An international examination of affine term structure models and the expectations hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tang, Huarong; Xia, Yihong
We examine the yield curve behavior and the relative performance of affine term structure models (ATSMs) using government bond yield data from Canada, Germany, Japan, the U.K., and the U.S. We find strong predictability of forward rates for excess bond returns and reject the expectations hypothesis in all five countries. A three-factor model is sufficient to capture movements in the yield curve of Canada, Japan, the U.K., and the U.S., but may not be enough for Germany. An exhaustive comparison among ATSMs with no more than three factors reveals that the three-factor essential affine model (A, (3)E), with only one factor affecting the volatility of the short rate but with all three factors affecting the price of risk, performs best in all five countries. Simulations provide inconclusive evidence on whether this best affine model can successfully generate the rich yield curve behavior observed in the data.</description><author>Tang, Huarong; Xia, Yihong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The empirical failure of the expectations hypothesis of the term structure of bond yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarno, Lucio; Thornton, Daniel L.; Valente, Giorgio
This paper tests the expectations hypothesis (EH) using U.S. monthly data for bond yields spanning the 1952-2003 sample period and ranging in maturity from one month to 10 years. We apply the Lagrange multiplier test developed by Bekaert and Hodrick (2001) and extend it to increase the test power by introducing economic variables as conditioning information and by using more than two bond yields in the model and testing the EH jointly on more than one pair of yields. While the conventional bivariate procedure provides mixed results, the more powerful testing procedures suggest rejection of the EH throughout the maturity spectrum examined.</description><author>Sarno, Lucio; Thornton, Daniel L.; Valente, Giorgio</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Chapter 11: Duration, outcome, and post-reorganization performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, Diane K.; Rodgers, Kimberly J.
We find that among firms that file Chapter 11 those that are smaller have better operating performance, and are in higher operating margin industries spend less time in Chapter 11. Firms are more likely to emerge as going concerns and to achieve positive post-reorganization profitability if they significantly reduce assets and liabilities while in Chapter 11. Higher pre-bankruptcy industry-adjusted operating margins and improvements in margin are associated with post-reorganization profitability but do not impact the decision to reorganize. These results reveal characteristics and actions associated with successful reorganizations and, furthermore, suggest that Chapter 11 allows promising firms to successfully reorganize.</description><author>Denis, Diane K.; Rodgers, Kimberly J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-series behavior of share repurchases and dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Bong-Soo; Rui, Oliver Meng
Given the growth in the importance and popularity of share repurchases, we use an alternative time-series approach to test two hypotheses on the motives for share repurchases and dividends: the flexibility hypothesis and the substitution hypothesis. By investigating both share repurchase and dividend payout policies in the context of a time-series vector autoregression, we account for the dynamic and multi-dimensional nature of the two payout policies. We find that share repurchases are associated with temporary components of earnings, whereas dividends are not, and that share repurchases and dividends are imperfect substitutes.</description><author>Lee, Bong-Soo; Rui, Oliver Meng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivative lawsuits as a corporate governance mechanism: Empirical evidence on board changes surrounding filings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferris, Stephen P.; Jandik, Tomas; Lawless, Robert M.; Makhija, Anil
Legal rights of investors are recognized as an essential component of corporate governance. We assess the efficacy of these rights by examining board changes surrounding the filings of shareholder derivative lawsuits. We find that the incidence of derivative lawsuits is higher for firms with a greater likelihood of agency conflicts. We also find that derivative lawsuits are associated with significant improvements in the boards of directors. In particular, the proportion of outside representation on the board of directors increases. There is also some evidence that other board characteristics change favorably. These findings suggest that shareholder derivative lawsuits are not frivolous as is often claimed, but rather that they can serve as an effective corporate governance mechanism.</description><author>Ferris, Stephen P.; Jandik, Tomas; Lawless, Robert M.; Makhija, Anil</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stealth trading in options markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anand, Amber; Chakravarty, Sugato
We investigate how price discovery occurs in the options markets through traders' trade size choice. By employing transactions data on all options traded on a sample of 100 firms, we show that informed traders fragment their orders into small (medium) trades for low (high) volume contracts. We also find that almost 60% of the price discovery occurs in the exchange with the largest market share for a given option, where informed traders favor medium size trades. Upon examining distinct option series for a given stock, we find that at-the-money calls display the highest information share.</description><author>Anand, Amber; Chakravarty, Sugato</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalized analytical upper bounds for American option prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, San-Lin; Chang, Hsieh-Chung
This paper generalizes and tightens Chen and Yeh's (2002) analytical upper bounds for American options under stochastic interest rates, stochastic volatility, and jumps, where American option prices are difficult to compute with accuracy. We first generalize Theorem I of Chen and Yeh (2002) and apply it to derive a tighter upper bound for American calls when the interest rate is greater than the dividend yield. Our upper bounds are not only tight, but also converge to accurate American call option prices when the dividend yield or strike price is small or when volatility is large. We then propose a general theorem that can be applied to derive upper bounds for American options whose payoffs depend on several risky assets. As a demonstration, we utilize our general theorem to derive upper bounds for American exchange options and American maximum options on two risky assets.</description><author>Chung, San-Lin; Chang, Hsieh-Chung</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>All events induce variance: Analyzing abnormal returns when effects vary across firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harrington, Scott E.; Shrider, David G.
We demonstrate analytically that cross-sectional variation in the effects of events, i.e., in true abnormal returns, necessarily produces event-induced variance increases, biasing popular tests for mean abnormal returns in short-horizon event studies. We show that unexplained cross-sectional variation in true abnormal returns plausibly produces non-proportional heteroskedasticity in cross-sectional regressions, biasing coefficient standard errors for both ordinary and weighted least squares. Simulations highlight the resulting biases, the necessity of using tests robust to cross-sectional variation, and the power of robust tests, including regression-based tests for nonzero mean abnormal returns, which may increase power by conditioning on relevant explanatory variables.</description><author>Harrington, Scott E.; Shrider, David G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>JFQA 2006 symposium on stock analysts: An introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, H.
nan</description><author>Bessembinder, H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross section of analyst recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sorescu, S.; Subrahmanyam, A.
We analyze the price reaction to analysts' revisions by testing the Griffin and Tversky (1992) hypothesis that agents place emphasis on the strength of the signal (the dramatic nature of the event) and may de-emphasize the weight (the ability of the analyst making the recommendation). Two attributes, namely, years of experience and the reputation of the analysts' brokerage houses form proxies for analyst ability (or weight) that we validate by documenting that revisions by high ability analysts outperform those by low ability ones. We find evidence of return persistence following small (low strength) revisions by high ability analysts and the opposite return pattern following large (high strength) revisions of low ability analysts, consistent with the arguments of Griffin and Tversky (1992). Our study provides an empirical link between evidence on individual decision making and stock market returns, and also helps promote an understanding of the analyst industry as well as its interaction with the investing population.</description><author>Sorescu, S.; Subrahmanyam, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What a difference a month makes: Stock analyst valuations following initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Houston, J.; James, C.; Karceski, J.
We examine how analysts establish target prices for IPO firms and whether comparable firms used to support target prices are helpful in explaining IPO offer prices. During the bubble period of 1999 to 2000, the average offer price was set at a discount relative to comparable firm valuations. In contrast, the average offer price was set at a small premium relative to comparables in the pre-bubble period. This shift appears to hold even after controlling for the differences in the types of firms going public during the bubble period. Moreover, target prices of IPO firms were set at a higher premium relative to comparables during the bubble period. While our results suggest that underwriters systematically discounted offer prices during the bubble period, an alternative explanation is that the shift arose because underwriters and analysts faced different incentives and legal exposures during the bubble period.</description><author>Houston, J.; James, C.; Karceski, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysts, industries, and price momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boni, L.; Womack, K. L.
This paper examines the value of analysts as industry specialists. We show analysts create value in their recommendations mainly through their ability to rank stocks within industries. An industry-based recommendation strategy substantially improves the return to risk ratio and reduces price momentum tilt relative to portfolios that ignore industry information. An examination of the links among analyst information, aggregated at the industry level, and industry returns and industry momentum shows that industry returns precede industry-aggregated analyst upgrades and downgrades, and the short-term industry price momentum phenomenon is partly explained by returns of firms with more analyst coverage leading those with less in that industry. Recommendation information is not valuable for predicting future relative industry returns, however.</description><author>Boni, L.; Womack, K. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buy-side analysts, sell-side analysts, and investment decisions of money managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Y. M.; Liu, M. H.; Qian, J.
We examine the role of financial analysts in forming institutional investors' investment decisions. In our model, a fund manager invests in a stock based on the optimal weighting of reports created by a biased sell-side analyst and an unbiased buy-side analyst. The manager puts a higher weight on the buy-side analyst's report when the quality of the buyside analyst's information relative to that of the sell-side analyst increases, or when the sell-side analyst's degree of bias or uncertainty about the bias increases. Utilizing a unique dataset of U.S. equity funds, we find evidence supporting our model predictions on how fund managers weigh buy-side research relative to sell-side and independent research.</description><author>Cheng, Y. M.; Liu, M. H.; Qian, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do analyst recommendations respond to major news?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, J.; Cornell, B.; Landsman, W. R.; Rountree, B. R.
We examine how analysts respond to public information when setting stock recommendations. We model the determinants of analysts' recommendation changes following large stock price movements. We find evidence of an asymmetry following large positive and negative returns. Following large stock price increases, analysts are equally likely to upgrade or downgrade. Following large stock price declines, analysts are more likely to downgrade. This asymmetry exists after accounting for investment banking relationships and herding behavior. This result suggests recommendation changes are "sticky" in one direction, with analysts reluctant to downgrade. Moreover, this result implies that analysts' optimistic bias may vary through time.</description><author>Conrad, J.; Cornell, B.; Landsman, W. R.; Rountree, B. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of client access to analyst recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, T. C.
Early access to stock recommendations provides brokerage firm clients with incremental investment value. After controlling for transaction costs, purchasing (selling) quickly following upgrades (downgrades) results in average two-day returns of 1.02% (1.50%). Short-term profit opportunities persist for two hours following the pre-market release of new recommendations. The results are robust within sub-periods and a calendar-based strategy produces positive abnormal daily returns of over 10 basis points, or roughly 30% annualized. Recommending firms' market makers shift their quotes accordingly, providing indirect evidence that clients make use of the informational advantage that arises from analysts' opinion changes.</description><author>Green, T. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns to acquirers of listed and unlisted targets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faccio, M.; McConnell, J. J.; Stolin, D.
We examine announcement period abnormal returns to acquirers of listed and unlisted targets in 17 Western European countries over the interval 1996-2001. Acquirers of listed targets earn an insignificant average abnormal return of -0.38%, while acquirers of unlisted targets earn a significant average abnormal return of 1.48%. This listing effect in acquirers' returns persists through time and across countries and remains after controlling for the method of payment for the target, the acquirer's size and Tobin's Q, pre-announcement leakage of information about the transaction, whether the acquisition created a blockholder in the acquirer's ownership structure, whether the acquisition was a cross-border deal, and other variables. The fundamental factors that give rise to this listing effect, which has also been documented in U.S. acquisitions, remain elusive.</description><author>Faccio, M.; McConnell, J. J.; Stolin, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are analyst recommendations biased? Evidence from corporate bankruptcies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, J.; Ferris, S. P.; Jayaraman, N.; Lee, J.
We test whether a bias exists in analyst recommendations for firms that file for bankruptcy during 1995-2001. We fail to find overoptimism in analyst recommendations, including those of affiliated analysts. Our multivariate analysis of the market reaction to changes in analyst recommendations indicates that prior affiliation exerts no impact on either returns or trading volume. We find that the market does not view recommendation upgrades by affiliated analysts as biased since there is no price reversal following these recommendation changes. Overall, our results suggest that recently passed legislation to reduce analysts' conflicts of interest might be an overreaction.</description><author>Clarke, J.; Ferris, S. P.; Jayaraman, N.; Lee, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are observed capital structures determined by equity market timing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hovakimian, A.
Contrary to Baker and Wurgler (2002), I find that the importance of historical average market-to-book ratios in leverage regressions is not due to past equity market timing. Although equity transactions may be timed to equity market conditions, they do not have significant long lasting effects on capital structure. Debt transactions exhibit timing patterns that are unlikely to induce a negative relation between market-to-book ratios and leverage. I also find that historical average market-to-book ratios have significant effects on current financing and investment decisions, implying that they contain information about growth opportunities not captured by current market-to-book ratios.</description><author>Hovakimian, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock returns, implied volatility innovations, and the asymmetric volatility phenomenon</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dennis, Patrick; Mayhew, Stewart; Stivers, Chris
We study the dynamic relation between daily stock returns and daily innovations in option-derived implied volatilities. By simultaneously analyzing innovations in index- and firm-level implied volatilities, we distinguish between innovations in systematic and idiosyncratic volatility in an effort to better understand the asymmetric volatility phenomenon. Our results indicate that the relation between stock returns and innovations in systematic volatility (idiosyncratic volatility) is substantially negative (near zero). These results suggest that asymmetric volatility is primarily attributed to systematic market-wide factors rather than aggregated firm-level effects. We also present evidence that supports our assumption that innovations in implied volatility are good proxies for innovations in expected stock volatility.</description><author>Dennis, Patrick; Mayhew, Stewart; Stivers, Chris</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-sale constraints, differences of opinion, and overvaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehme, Rodney D.; Danielsen, Bartley R.; Sorescu, Sorin M.
Miller (1977) hypothesizes that dispersion of investor opinion in the presence of short-sale constraints leads to stock price overvaluation. However, previous empirical tests of Miller's hypothesis examine the valuation effects of only one of these two necessary conditions. We examine the valuation effects of the interaction between differences of opinion and short-sale constraints. We find robust evidence of significant overvaluation for stocks that are subject to both conditions simultaneously. Stocks are not systematically overvalued when either one of these two conditions is not met.</description><author>Boehme, Rodney D.; Danielsen, Bartley R.; Sorescu, Sorin M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend smoothing and debt ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aivazian, V. A.; Booth, L.; Cleary, S.
We find that firms that regularly access public debt (bond) markets are more likely to pay a dividend and subsequently follow a dividend smoothing policy than firms that rely exclusively on private (bank) debt. In particular, firms with bond ratings follow a traditional Lintner (1956) style dividend smoothing policy, where the influence of the prior dividend payment is very strong and the current dividend is relatively insensitive to current earnings. In contrast, firms without bond ratings flow through more of their earnings as dividends and display very little dividend smoothing behavior. In effect, they seem to follow a residual dividend policy.</description><author>Aivazian, V. A.; Booth, L.; Cleary, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management and stock performance of reverse leveraged buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chou, D. W.; Gombola, M.; Liu, F. Y.
This study provides further evidence of earnings management around security offerings. We find positive and significant discretionary current accruals coincident with offerings of reverse LBOs. Issuers in the most aggressive quartile of earnings management have a one-year aftermarket return that is between 15% and 25% less than the most conservative quartile. We also find a negative and significant relation between abnormal accruals and post-issue abnormal returns within the first year after the offering. The relation remains after controlling for book-to-market ratio, firm size, offering size, and involvement of buy-out specialists or management. Although earnings management has been used to explain post-issue long-term underperformance of IPOs and SEOs, our study shows that earnings management can explain post-offering returns of reverse LBOs, even in the absence of post-offering underperformance.</description><author>Chou, D. W.; Gombola, M.; Liu, F. Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm growth and disclosure: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khurana, Inder K.; Pereira, Raynolde; Martin, Xiumin
Extant theoretical research posits that information asymmetry and agency issues affect the cost of external financing and hence impact the ability of firms to finance their growth opportunities. In contrast, the literature on disclosure policy posits that expanded and credible disclosure lowers the cost of external financing and improves a firm's ability to pursue potentially profitable projects. An empirical implication is that disclosure can help firms grow by relaxing external financing constraints, thereby allowing capital to flow to positive net present value projects. This paper empirically evaluates this prediction using firm-level data over an 11-year period. As anticipated by theory, we find a positive relation between firm disclosure policy and the externally financed growth rate, after controlling for other influences.</description><author>Khurana, Inder K.; Pereira, Raynolde; Martin, Xiumin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economic impact of corporate capital expenditures: Focused firms versus diversified firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, S. S.
This paper examines the role of focus versus diversification in explaining the economic impact of corporate capital investments. I find that the stock market's responses to announcements of capital investments are more favorable for focused firms than for diversified firms. I also show that focused firms exhibit significantly better post-investment operating performance than diversified firms. The overall findings in this study suggest that the investment opportunities hypothesis dominates the internal capital markets hypothesis in terms of the net economic impact of capital investments on the investing firms.</description><author>Chen, S. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Top management incentives and the pricing of corporate public debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ortiz-Molina, H.
This article examines managerial ownership structure and at-issue yield spreads on corporate bonds. There is a positive relation between managerial ownership and borrowing costs, and this relation is weaker at higher levels of ownership. In addition, managerial stock options have a larger effect on yield spreads than stock ownership. These effects exist after controlling for firm and bond characteristics, and are robust to endogeneity and sample selection concerns. The evidence suggests that rational bondholders price new debt issues using the information about a firm's future risk choices contained in managerial incentive structures, and that lenders anticipate higher risk-taking incentives from managerial stock options than from equity ownership.</description><author>Ortiz-Molina, H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The sources of debt matter too</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Y.
This paper examines the effects of different types of private debt on firm cash balances, equity risk, and investment. Firms with more bank loans have more cash and investment, but lower equity risk. Firms with more norbank private debt have more cash, lower equity risk, and less investment. Finns with more unused credit lines have less cash and lower equity risk, but greater investment. Results suggest that financial intermediaries' monitoring intensity increases with loan size. Depending on type, private debt mitigates information asymmetry or asset substitution, or both. Deposit relations associated with bank borrowing also contribute to banks' information advantage.</description><author>Liu, Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>