<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFQA5</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Blockholder ownership and market liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heflin, F.; Shaw, K. W.
This paper examines the association between block ownership and market liquidity. Blockholders are believed to have access to private, value-relevant information via their roles as monitors of firms' operations. Consistent with this, we find that firms with greater blockholder ownership, either by managers or external entities, have larger quoted spreads, effective spreads, adverse selection spread components, and smaller quoted depths.</description><author>Heflin, F.; Shaw, K. W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market segmentation and the cost of capital in international equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Errunza, V. R.; Miller, D. P.
While theoretical models predict a decrease in the cost of capital from depositary receipt offerings, the economic benefits of this liberalization have been difficult to quantify. Using a sample of 126 firms from 32 countries, we document a significant decline of 42% in the cost of capital. In addition, we show the decline is driven by the ability of U.S. investors to span the foreign security prior to cross-listing. Our findings support the hypothesis that financial market liberalizations have significant economic benefits.</description><author>Errunza, V. R.; Miller, D. P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The accuracy of trade classification rules: Evidence from Nasdaq</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, K.; Michaely, R.; O'Hara, M.
Researchers are increasingly using data from the Nasdaq market to examine pricing behavior, market design, and other microstructure phenomena. The validity of any study that classifies trades as buys or sells depends on the accuracy of the classification method. Using a Nasdaq proprietary data set that identifies trade direction, we examine the validity of several trade classification algorithms. We find that the quote rule, the tick rule, and the Lee and Ready (1991) rule correctly classify 76.4%, 77.66%, and 81.05% of the trades, respectively. However, all classification rules have only a very limited success in classifying trades executed inside the quotes, introducing a bias in the accuracy of classifying large trades, trades during high volume periods, and ECN trades. We also find that extant algorithms do a mediocre job when used for calculating effective spreads. For Nasdaq trades, we propose a new and simple classification algorithm that improves over extant algorithms.</description><author>Ellis, K.; Michaely, R.; O'Hara, M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The long-run performance of global equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foerster, S. R.; Karolyi, G. A.
We investigate the long-run return performance of non-U.S. firms that raise equity capital in U.S. markets. Overall, between 1982 and 1996, our sample of 333 global equity offerings with U.S. depositary receipt (ADR) tranches from 35 countries in Asia, Latin America, and Europe under-perform local market benchmarks of comparable firms by 8%-15% over the three years following issuance. We show that differences in long-run returns are related to the scope and magnitude of investment barriers that induce segmentation of capital markets around the world. While companies from markets with significant investment barriers for foreigners that issue equity on major U.S. exchanges outperform their benchmarks, those from segmented markets that issue equity in the U.S. by way of Rule 144A private placements significantly under-perform. We also show that inter-market competition for order flow in the post-issuance period affects long-run return performance. Post-issuance buy-and-hold abnormal returns are most significantly and positively related to the offering's ability to generate a larger share of U.S. trading volume.</description><author>Foerster, S. R.; Karolyi, G. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gains to bidder firms revisited: Domestic and foreign acquisitions in Canada</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckbo, B. E.; Thorburn, K. S.
We present large sample evidence on the performance of domestic and U.S. (foreign) bidder firms acquiring Canadian targets. Domestic bidders earn significantly positive average announcement period abnormal returns, while U.S. bidder returns are indistinguishable from zero. Measures of pre- and post-acquisition abnormal accounting performance are also consistent with a superior domestic bidder performance. Domestic bidder announcement returns are, on average, greatest for offers involving stock payment and for the bidders with the smallest equity size relative to the target. Neither direct foreign investment controls, horizontal product market relationships, nor acquisition propensities explain why domestic bidders outperform their U.S. competitors.</description><author>Eckbo, B. E.; Thorburn, K. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The rationality of asset allocation recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.
The popular finance literature describes the asset allocation decision as one of the most important factors in determining investment performance. This article reviews the implications of modern portfolio theory for the asset allocation decision and then examines the recommendations of some leading financial experts to see if they are consistent with theory.</description><author>Elton, E. J.; Gruber, M. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A two-factor hazard rate model for pricing risky debt and the term structure of credit spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madan, D.; Unal, H.
This paper proposes a two-factor hazard rate model, in closed form, to price risky debt. The likelihood of default is captured by the firm's non-interest sensitive assets and default-free interest rates. The distinguishing features of the model are threefold. First, the impact of capital structure changes on credit spreads can be analyzed. Second, the model allows stochastic interest rates to impact current asset values as well as their evolution. Finally, the proposed model is in closed form, enabling us to undertake comparative statics analysis, compute parameter deltas of the model, calibrate empirical credit spreads, and determine hedge positions. Credit spreads generated by our model are consistent with empirical observations.</description><author>Madan, D.; Unal, H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A reexamination of the motives and gains in joint ventures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, S. A.; Houston, M. B.
We distinguish between horizontal and vertical joint ventures, and find correspondingly different valuation effects. Horizontal joint ventures create synergistic gains that are shared by the partners. In contrast, vertical joint ventures generate gains only for suppliers. This is similar to the pattern we find for simple contracts, which suggests economic similarities between vertical joint ventures and contracts. Analyzing firms' choices between these contracting options, we find that firms choose vertical joint ventures over simple contracts when potential hold-up problems are severe and when suppliers face finance constraints. The results do not support a risk-sharing motive for joint ventures.</description><author>Johnson, S. A.; Houston, M. B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of contract terms in bank revolving credit agreements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dennis, S.; Nandy, D.; Sharpe, I. G.
The paper examines the determinants of contract terms on bank revolving credit agreements (revolvers) of medium/large publicly traded companies. We model the duration (maturity), secured status, and pricing decisions within a simultaneous decision framework, thereby overcoming the biased and inconsistent estimates in prior single equation studies of debt contract terms. We find strong interrelationships between contract terms with significant bi-directional relationships between duration and secured status and between the all-in-spread and commitment fees and a unidirectional relationship from both duration and secured status to all-in-spread. We also illustrate how several single equation studies of contract terms draw incorrect conclusions because of their (inappropriate) assumption that other contract terms and leverage were exogenous. Finally, our results support the hypothesis that the setting of contract terms plays an important role in alleviating contracting problems.</description><author>Dennis, S.; Nandy, D.; Sharpe, I. G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prices as aggregators of private information: Evidence from S&amp;P 500 futures data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cho, J. W.; Krishnan, M.
This paper assesses the importance of the role of prices as aggregators of private information in the S&amp;P 500 futures market. We estimate primitive parameters of the Hellwig (1980) noisy rational expectations model, when both prices and terminal values are observable. The variance-covariance parameters governing futures prices and terminal values can be inverted to obtain estimates of the primitive parameters, including the precision of private information and the variance of liquidity-motivated trades. We also estimate coefficients in the linear price conjecture, weights that agents place on different sources of information, and the informativeness of prices. We find that the variance of the error term in agents' private signals is several orders of magnitude larger than the variance of liquidity-motivated trades. But, in a large market, prices are still so informative that the market as a whole appears to weight them more than prior beliefs.</description><author>Cho, J. W.; Krishnan, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do the portfolios of small investors reflect positive feedback trading?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bange, M. M.
This study examines the stock market forecasts and portfolio allocation decisions of small individual investors, based on survey data for 1987-1994. When investors are bullish, they increase their equity holdings; when investors are bearish, they decrease equity holdings. The surveyed investors are unable ro time the stock market successfully. However, the shifts in their portfolios reflect past market movements and are consistent with positive feedback trading.</description><author>Bange, M. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of takeovers on shareholder wealth during the 1920s merger wave</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leeth, J. D.; Borg, J. R.
We examine the impact of merger announcements on portfolios of acquiring firm and target firm common stock from 1919 to 1930. Despite vast changes in the economic and regulatory environment, overall acquisition profitability has remained remarkably constant over the last 70 to 80 years. Target firm shareholders in the 1920s clearly gained from takeovers, averaging abnormal returns in excess of 15%, while acquiring firm shareholders essentially broke even. Synergistic or monopolistic gains from consolidation were minimal. Unlike the more recent experience, target firm and acquiring firm abnormal returns were largely unaffected by the mode of acquisition, the means of financing, or the degree of industrial relatedness.</description><author>Leeth, J. D.; Borg, J. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavioral portfolio theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shefrin, H.; Statman, M.
We develop a positive behavioral portfolio theory (BPT) and explore its implications for portfolio construction and security design. The optimal portfolios of BPT investors resemble combinations of bonds and lottery tickets, consistent with Friedman and Savage's (1948) observation. We compare the BPT efficient frontier with the mean-variance efficient frontier and show that, in general, the two frontiers do not coincide. Optimal BPT portfolios are also different from optimal CAPM portfolios. In particular, the CAPM two-fund separation does not hold in BPT. We present BPT in a single mental account version (BPT-SA) and a multiple mental account version (BPT-MA). BPT-SA investors integrate their portfolios into a single mental account, while BPT-MA investors segregate their portfolios into several mental accounts. BPT-MA portfolios resemble layered pyramids, where layers are associated with aspirations. We explore a two-layer portfolio where the low aspiration layer is designed to avoid poverty while the high aspiration layer is designed for a shot at riches.</description><author>Shefrin, H.; Statman, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Profitability of momentum strategies in the international equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, K.; Hameed, A.; Tong, W.
This paper examines the profitability of momentum strategies implemented on international stock market indices. Our results indicate statistically significant evidence of momentum profits. The momentum profits arise mainly from time-series predictability in stock market indices-very little profit comes from predictability in the currency markets. We also find higher profits for momentum portfolios implemented on markets with higher volume in the previous period, indicating that return continuation is stronger following an increase in trading volume. This result confirms the informational role of volume and its applicability in technical analysis.</description><author>Chan, K.; Hameed, A.; Tong, W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend behavior and dividend signaling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garrett, I.; Priestley, R.
We analyze the dividend behavior of the aggregate stock market. We propose a model that assumes managers minimize the costs of adjustment associated with being away from their target dividend payout. The target is expressed as a function of lagged stock prices and permanent earnings, generalizing previous models of dividend behavior. We present a new method for measuring unobserved permanent earnings based on the Kalman filter. Our specification of dividend behavior is strongly supported by the data relative to both alternative models and over time. We find significant evidence of dividend smoothing and dividends conveying information regarding unexpected positive changes in current permanent earnings. We also find that both the speed of adjustment of dividends to target dividends and tests of signaling are sensitive to the specification of the model.</description><author>Garrett, I.; Priestley, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing the empirical performance of stochastic volatility models of the short-term interest rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, T. G.
I introduce two-factor discrete time stochastic volatility models of the short-term interest rate to compare the relative performance of existing and alternative empirical specifications. I develop a nonlinear asymmetric framework that allows for comparisons of non-nested models featuring conditional heteroskedasticity and sensitivity of the volatility process to interest rate levels. A new class of stochastic volatility models with asymmetric drift and nonlinear asymmetric diffusion process is introduced in discrete time and tested against the popular continuous time and symmetric and asymmetric GARCH models. The existing models are rejected in favor of the newly proposed models because of the asymmetric drift of the short rate, and the presence of nonlinearity, asymmetry, GARCH, and level effects in its volatility. I test the predictive power of nested and non-nested models in capturing the stochastic behavior of the risk-free rate. Empirical evidence on three-, six-, and 12-month U.S. Treasury bills indicates that two-factor stochastic volatility models are better than diffusion and GARCH models in forecasting the future level and volatility of interest rate changes.</description><author>Bali, T. G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>