<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFQA2</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Deviations from Norms and Informed Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Alok; Page, Jeremy K.
Investment managers are subject to personal and institutional norms that can constrain their investment choices. We conjecture that norm-constrained investors deviate from such norms only when they have compelling information, and we predict that deviating investments earn relatively high abnormal returns ex post. Consistent with our conjecture, we find that institutions averse to holding lottery-like stocks or sin stocks earn relatively high abnormal returns when they choose to hold such stocks. We find similar but weaker results for deviations from broader style categories. Overall, our evidence indicates that deviations from established institutional or social norms signal informed investing.</description><author>Kumar, Alok; Page, Jeremy K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Communicating Private Information to the Equity Market Before a Dividend Cut: An Empirical Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Tian, Xuan
This paper presents the first empirical analysis of the choice of firms regarding whether to release private information ("prepare the market") in advance of a possible dividend cut and the consequences of such market preparation. We use a hand-collected data set of dividend cutting firms, which allows us to distinguish between prepared and nonprepared dividend cutters and to test the implications of two alternative theories: the "signaling through market preparation" theory and the "stock return volatility reduction" theory. We document several important differences between prepared and nonprepared dividend cutters. Overall, our empirical results are consistent with the signaling theory.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Tian, Xuan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance and Innovation: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sapra, Haresh; Subramanian, Ajay; Subramanian, Krishnamurthy V.
We develop a theory to show how external and internal corporate governance mechanisms affect innovation. We predict a U-shaped relation between innovation and external takeover pressure, which arises from the interaction between expected takeover premia and private benefits of control. Using ex ante and ex post innovation measures, we find strong empirical support for the predicted relation. We exploit the variation in takeover pressure created by the passage of antitakeover laws across different states. Innovation is fostered either by an unhindered market for corporate control or by antitakeover laws that are severe enough to effectively deter takeovers.</description><author>Sapra, Haresh; Subramanian, Ajay; Subramanian, Krishnamurthy V.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model-Free Measure of Aggregate Idiosyncratic Volatility and the Prediction of Market Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia, Rene; Mantilla-Garcia, Daniel; Martellini, Lionel
In this paper, we formally show that the cross-sectional variance of stock returns is a consistent and asymptotically efficient estimator for aggregate idiosyncratic volatility. This measure has two key advantages: It is model free and observable at any frequency. Previous approaches have used monthly model-based measures constructed from time series of daily returns. The newly proposed cross-sectional volatility measure is a strong predictor for future returns on the aggregate stock market at the daily frequency. Using the cross section of size and book-to-market portfolios, we show that the portfolios' exposures to the aggregate idiosyncratic volatility risk predict the cross section of expected returns.</description><author>Garcia, Rene; Mantilla-Garcia, Daniel; Martellini, Lionel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Better-Connected CEOs Innovate More?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faleye, Olubunmi; Kovacs, Tunde; Venkateswaran, Anand
We present evidence suggesting that chief executive officer (CEO) connections facilitate investments in corporate innovation. We find that firms with better-connected CEOs invest more in research and development and receive more and higher quality patents. Further tests suggest that this effect stems from two characteristics of personal networks that alleviate CEO risk aversion in investment decisions. First, personal connections increase the CEO's access to relevant network information, which encourages innovation by helping to identify, evaluate, and exploit innovative ideas. Second, personal connections provide the CEO with labor market insurance that facilitates investments in risky innovation by mitigating the career concerns inherent in such investments.</description><author>Faleye, Olubunmi; Kovacs, Tunde; Venkateswaran, Anand</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt Maturity Structure and Credit Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Song, Fenghua; Yerramilli, Vijay
We examine whether a firm's debt maturity structure affects its credit quality. Consistent with theory, we find that firms with greater exposure to rollover risk (measured by the amount of long-term debt payable within a year relative to assets) have lower credit quality; long-term bonds issued by those firms trade at higher yield spreads, indicating that bond market investors are cognizant of rollover risk arising from a firm's debt maturity structure. These effects are stronger among firms with a speculative-grade rating and declining profitability, and during recessions.</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Song, Fenghua; Yerramilli, Vijay</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Hedge Funds Reduce Idiosyncratic Risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Namho; Kondor, Peter; Sadka, Ronnie
This paper studies the effect of hedge-fund trading on idiosyncratic risk. We hypothesize that while hedge-fund activity would often reduce idiosyncratic risk, high initial levels of idiosyncratic risk might be further amplified due to fund loss limits. Panel-regression analyses provide supporting evidence for this hypothesis. The results are robust to sample selection and are further corroborated by a natural experiment using the Lehman bankruptcy as an exogenous adverse shock to hedge-fund trading. Hedge-fund capital also explains the increased idiosyncratic volatility of high-idiosyncratic-volatility stocks as well as the decreased idiosyncratic volatility of low-idiosyncratic-volatility stocks over the past few decades.</description><author>Kang, Namho; Kondor, Peter; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Concentration and Firm Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ekholm, Anders; Maury, Benjamin
This paper investigates the relation between shareholders' portfolio concentration and firm performance. Using data on more than 1.3 million unique shareholders, we create an index that measures how concentrated shareholder portfolios are in each firm. We posit that portfolio concentration will affect incentives when shareholders are resource constrained. We find that average shareholder portfolio concentration is positively related to future operational performance and valuation. We also find that portfolio concentration is positively correlated with abnormal stock returns. Our findings suggest that shareholders with concentrated portfolios are more informed and play a governance role through the stock market.</description><author>Ekholm, Anders; Maury, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Antitakeover Provisions and Shareholder Wealth: A Survey of the Literature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Straska, Miroslava; Waller, H. Gregory
We survey theoretical and empirical research on antitakeover provisions, focusing on the relation between antitakeover provisions and shareholder value. We divide the empirical studies based upon the evidence that they provide: short-term event studies, studies on performance and policy changes around adopting antitakeover provisions or passing state antitakeover laws, studies on the impact of antitakeover provisions on takeovers, studies on the relation between antitakeover provisions and firm characteristics, and long-term studies on the relation between antitakeover provisions and firm performance or policies. We also discuss the place of antitakeover provisions in the current debate about "good governance" practices.</description><author>Straska, Miroslava; Waller, H. Gregory</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Treasury Bond Illiquidity and Global Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyenko, Ruslan; Sarkissian, Sergei
In this study, using data from 46 markets and a 34-year time period, we examine the impact of the illiquidity of U.S. Treasuries on global asset valuation. We find that it predicts equity returns in both developed and emerging markets. This predictive relation remains intact after controlling for various world-and country-level variables. Asset pricing tests further reveal that bond illiquidity is a priced factor even in the presence of other conventional risks. Since the illiquidity of Treasuries is known to reflect monetary and macroeconomic shocks, our results suggest that it can be considered a proxy for aggregate worldwide risks.</description><author>Goyenko, Ruslan; Sarkissian, Sergei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managed Distribution Policies in Closed-End Funds and Shareholder Activism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cherkes, Martin; Sagi, Jacob S.; Wang, Z. Jay
In closed-end funds, a managed distribution policy (MDP) is a dividend commitment potentially requiring the liquidation of assets. We argue that MDPs lower managerial claims on fund assets and, when the fund is at a discount, increase shareholder value. This transfer of wealth can be rationalized by managers wishing to deter a challenge from activist shareholders through a costly proxy vote. We find strong empirical evidence that managers respond to the presence of activists using MDPs, that MDPs constitute an effective wealth transfer to shareholders, and that activists are less likely to challenge management when an MDP is in place.</description><author>Cherkes, Martin; Sagi, Jacob S.; Wang, Z. Jay</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting Regime Shifts in Credit Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chun, Olfa Maalaoui; Dionne, Georges; Francois, Pascal
Using an innovative random regime shift detection methodology, we identify and confirm two distinct regime types in the dynamics of credit spreads: a level regime and a volatility regime. The level regime is long lived and shown to be linked to Federal Reserve policy and credit market conditions, whereas the volatility regime is short lived and, apart from recessionary periods, detected during major financial crises. Our methodology provides an independent way of supporting structural equilibrium models and points toward monetary and credit supply effects to account for the persistence of credit spreads and their predictive power over the business cycle.</description><author>Chun, Olfa Maalaoui; Dionne, Georges; Francois, Pascal</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inside Debt and Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phan, Hieu V.
I empirically investigate the relation between chief executive officer (CEO) inside debt holdings and mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As), and find evidence consistent with the agency theory's prediction of a negative relation between CEO inside debt holdings and corporate risk taking. Further analysis shows that CEO inside debt holdings are positively correlated with M&amp;A announcement abnormal bond returns and long-term operating performance, but negatively correlated with M&amp;A announcement abnormal stock returns. Finally, I find evidence that acquirers restructure the postmerger composition of CEO compensation that mirrors their capital structure in order to alleviate incentives for wealth transfer from shareholders to bondholders or vice versa.</description><author>Phan, Hieu V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Bank Credit Risk: Systemic or Bank Specific? Evidence for the United States and United Kingdom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Junye; Zinna, Gabriele
We develop a multivariate credit risk model that accounts for joint defaults of banks and allows us to disentangle how much of banks' credit risk is systemic. We find that the United States and United Kingdom differ not only in the evolution of systemic risk but, in particular, in their banks' systemic exposures. In both countries, however, systemic credit risk varies substantially, represents about half of total bank credit risk on average, and induces high risk premia. The results suggest that sovereign and bank systemic risk are particularly interlinked in the United Kingdom.</description><author>Li, Junye; Zinna, Gabriele</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Policies of Republican Managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hutton, Irena; Jiang, Danling; Kumar, Alok
We demonstrate that personal political preferences of corporate managers influence corporate policies. Specifically, Republican managers who are likely to have conservative personal ideologies adopt and maintain more conservative corporate policies. Those firms have lower levels of corporate debt, lower capital and research and development (R&amp;D) expenditures, less risky investments, but higher profitability. Using the 9/11 terrorist attacks and Sept. 2008 Lehman Brothers bankruptcy as natural experiments, we demonstrate that investment policies of Republican managers became more conservative following these exogenous uncertainty-increasing events. Furthermore, around chief executive officer (CEO) turnovers, including CEO deaths, firm leverage policy becomes more conservative when managerial conservatism increases.</description><author>Hutton, Irena; Jiang, Danling; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend Predictability Around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rangvid, Jesper; Schmeling, Maik; Schrimpf, Andreas
We show that dividend-growth predictability by the dividend yield is the rule rather than the exception in global equity markets. Dividend predictability is weaker, however, in large and developed markets where dividends are smoothed more, the typical firm is large, and volatility is lower. Our findings suggest that the apparent lack of dividend predictability in the United States does not uniformly extend to other countries. Rather, cross-country patterns in dividend predictability are driven by differences in firm characteristics and the extent to which dividends are smoothed.</description><author>Rangvid, Jesper; Schmeling, Maik; Schrimpf, Andreas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where Have All the IPOs Gone?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Xiaohui; Ritter, Jay R.; Zhu, Zhongyan
During 1980-2000, an average of 310 companies per year went public in the United States. Since 2000, the average has been only 99 initial public offerings (IPOs) per year, with the drop especially precipitous among small firms. Many have blamed the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 and the 2003 Global Settlement's effects on analyst coverage for the decline in IPO activity. We find very little support for the conventional wisdom, and we offer an alternative explanation. Our economies of scope hypothesis posits that the advantages of selling out to a larger organization, which can speed a product to market and realize economies of scope, have increased relative to the benefits of operating as an independent firm.</description><author>Gao, Xiaohui; Ritter, Jay R.; Zhu, Zhongyan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Servant to Many Masters: Competing Shareholder Preferences and Limits to Catering</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manconi, Alberto; Massa, Massimo
We study what determines catering through the payout policy and how catering affects firm value. We create a catering index, measuring how the firm caters to its investors' payout preferences. The index is based on the revealed payout preferences of mutual funds holding the firm's stocks. Catering is constrained by market segmentation and dispersion in investor payout preferences. It is also associated with positive value effects: Firms increasing their catering index also experience an increase in value. Furthermore, greater catering ability is associated with a more positive market reaction to corporate announcements of equity issues and dividend payouts.</description><author>Manconi, Alberto; Massa, Massimo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance and Risk Taking in Pension Plans: Evidence from Defined Benefit Asset Allocations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phan, Hieu V.; Hegde, Shantaram P.
Based on theoretical advice and empirical evidence suggesting that risk taking in asset allocation enhances pension returns, we evaluate empirically whether good corporate governance leads to a larger allocation of pension assets to risky securities as compared to safe investments. Our findings suggest that firms with good external and internal corporate governance take more risk by investing heavily in equities and allocating a smaller share of the plan assets to cash, government debt, and insurance company accounts. The main underlying mechanisms appear to be higher investment returns and better pension funding status associated with higher equity and lower safe asset allocations.</description><author>Phan, Hieu V.; Hegde, Shantaram P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEOs Under Fire: The Effects of Competition from Inside Directors on Forced CEO Turnover and CEO Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mobbs, Shawn
This study examines board monitoring when a credible chief executive officer (CEO) replacement is on the board. Inside directors whose talents are in greater demand externally, as reflected by their holding outside directorships, are more likely to become CEOs, and their presence is associated with greater forced CEO turnover sensitivity to accounting performance and CEO compensation sensitivity to stock performance. These results reveal that certain insiders strengthen board monitoring by serving as a readily available CEO replacement and contradict the presumption that all insiders are under CEO control. Furthermore, the results persist when accounting for the endogenous firm selection of talented inside directors.</description><author>Mobbs, Shawn</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contracting with Nonfinancial Stakeholders and Corporate Capital Structure: The Case of Product Warranties</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kale, Jayant R.; Meneghetti, Costanza; Shahrur, Husayn
We investigate the relation between a firm's product warranty level and its leverage. We find that leverage relates negatively to the warranty level and that this relation is robust to controls for endogeneity and self-selection into offering warranties. The negative warranty-leverage relation obtains only in the subsample of firms in the manufacturing industries. We also show that firms with warranties have the lowest debt levels, firms without warranties but operating in industries where other firms offer warranties on average carry higher debt, and firms in industries where no firm offers a warranty have the highest debt levels.</description><author>Kale, Jayant R.; Meneghetti, Costanza; Shahrur, Husayn</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Shareholder Base and Payout Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Oestberg, Per
We examine the relation between the shareholder base and payout policy. Consistent with the idea that the shareholder base is related to the cost of external financing, we find that firms with small shareholder bases have lower payout levels and maintain higher cash holdings. We show that undertaking an open market repurchase results in a significant reduction in the size of the shareholder base. Consequently, we find that firms with small shareholder bases are less likely to undertake a repurchase (reduce the shareholder base even further) and are more likely to pay special dividends.</description><author>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Oestberg, Per</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A First Look at Mutual Funds That Use Short Sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Honghui; Desai, Hemang; Krishnamurthy, Srinivasan
We provide a first look at short selling by mutual funds, a phenomenon not examined by prior research. Mutual funds that short do so frequently and in significant amounts, averaging about 16% of fund assets. These funds outperform benchmarks by 1.5% per year. An analysis of portfolio holdings shows that these funds generate abnormal performance from their short (4.1% per year) and long (1.5% per year) positions. Managers of short-selling mutual funds also exhibit superior performance in other funds they manage that do not use short sales. These findings suggest that managers of short-selling mutual funds are skilled.</description><author>Chen, Honghui; Desai, Hemang; Krishnamurthy, Srinivasan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Material Adverse Change Clauses and Acquisition Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, David J.; Macias, Antonio J.
Material adverse change (MAC) clauses are a ubiquitous feature of acquisitions and exhibit substantial cross-sectional variation in the number and types of events that are excluded from being material adverse events (MAEs). MAEs are the underlying cause of 69% of acquisition terminations and 80% of renegotiations. These renegotiations lead to substantial changes in the price offered to target shareholders. Acquisitions with fewer MAE exclusions are characterized by wider arbitrage spreads during the acquisition period and are associated with higher offer premiums. We conclude that MAC clauses have an economically important impact on the dynamics of corporate acquisitions.</description><author>Denis, David J.; Macias, Antonio J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive Pay Disparity and the Cost of Equity Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhihong; Huang, Yuan; Wei, K. C. John
Executive pay disparity, as measured by chief executive officer (CEO) pay slice (CPS), is positively associated with the implied cost of equity, even after controlling for other determinants of the cost of equity. The difference in the cost of equity can explain 43% of the difference in the valuation effect attributable to CPS reported by Bebchuk, Cremers, and Peyer (2011). Further analysis shows that the positive association is stronger when agency problems of free cash flow are more severe and when CEO succession planning is more important. Our evidence suggests that a large CPS is associated with CEO entrenchment and high succession risk.</description><author>Chen, Zhihong; Huang, Yuan; Wei, K. C. John</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictable Dynamics in Higher-Order Risk-Neutral Moments: Evidence from the S&amp;P 500 Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neumann, Michael; Skiadopoulos, George
We investigate whether there are predictable patterns in the dynamics of higher-order risk-neutral moments (RNMs) extracted from the market prices of Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P) 500 index options. To this end, we conduct a horse race among alternative forecasting models within an out-of-sample context over various forecasting horizons. We consider both a statistical and an economic setting. We find that higher RNMs can be statistically forecasted. However, only the 1-day-ahead skewness forecasts can be economically exploited. This economic significance vanishes once we incorporate transaction costs. The results have implications for the dynamics of implied volatility surfaces.</description><author>Neumann, Michael; Skiadopoulos, George</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Stock Markets Catch the Flu?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McTier, Brian C.; Tse, Yiuman; Wald, John K.
We examine the impact of influenza on stock markets. For the United States, a higher incidence of flu is associated with decreased trading, decreased volatility, decreased returns, and higher bid-ask spreads. Consistent with the flu affecting institutional investors and market makers, the decrease in trading activity and volatility is primarily driven by the incidence of influenza in the greater New York City area. However, the effect of the flu on bid-ask spreads and returns is related to the incidence of flu nationally. International data confirm our findings of a decrease in trading activity and returns when flu incidence is high.</description><author>McTier, Brian C.; Tse, Yiuman; Wald, John K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt Maturity and Asymmetric Information: Evidence from Default Risk Changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyal, Vidhan K.; Wang, Wei
Asymmetric information models suggest that a borrower's choice of debt maturity depends on its private information about its default probabilities, that is, borrowers with favorable information prefer short-term debt while those with unfavorable information prefer long-term debt. We test this implication by tracing the evolution of debt issuers' default risk following debt issuances. We find that short-term debt issuance leads to a decline in borrowers' asset volatility and an increase in their distance to default. The opposite is true for long-term debt issues. The results suggest that borrowers' private information about their default risk is an important determinant of their debt maturity choices.</description><author>Goyal, Vidhan K.; Wang, Wei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Entrenchment and Corporate Hedging: Evidence from the Oil and Gas Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Praveen; Rabinovitch, Ramon
Using a unique data set with detailed information on the derivative positions of upstream oil and gas firms during 1996-2008, we find that hedging intensity is positively related to factors that amplify chief executive officer (CEO) entrenchment and free cash flow agency costs. There is also robust evidence that hedging is motivated by the reduction of financial distress and borrowing costs, and that it is influenced by both intrinsic cash flow risk and temporary spikes in commodity price volatility. We present a comprehensive perspective on the determinants of corporate hedging, and the results are consistent with the predictions of the risk management and agency costs literatures.</description><author>Kumar, Praveen; Rabinovitch, Ramon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Marriage to Family Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bunkanwanicha, Pramuan; Fan, Joseph P. H.; Wiwattanakantang, Yupana
This paper presents the first empirical evidence showing that the marriage of a member of the controlling family adds value to public corporations. The results, based on a uniquely comprehensive data set from Thailand, show that the family firm's stock price increases when the partner is from either a prominent business or a political family. Abnormal returns tend to be higher for firms whose operation depends on extensive networks. In contrast, marriages to ordinary citizens are not associated with any abnormal returns. These findings are generally supportive of the value of networks in general and marriage in particular.</description><author>Bunkanwanicha, Pramuan; Fan, Joseph P. H.; Wiwattanakantang, Yupana</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership Dynamics with Large Shareholders: An Empirical Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donelli, Marcelo; Larrain, Borja; Urzua, Francisco
We study the empirical determinants of corporate ownership dynamics using a unique, hand-collected 20-year data set on the ownership structure of Chilean companies. Controllers' blockholdings are on average high and stable over time. Controllers still make changes to their holdings through issuance and block trades. In a typical year controllers' blockholdings decrease (increase) by 5 percentage points or more in approximately 6% (7%) of firms. We find that the separation between controllers' voting and cash-flow rights reduces the likelihood of ownership dilution. Dilution is preceded by high stock returns and predicts low stock returns in the future when done through issuance.</description><author>Donelli, Marcelo; Larrain, Borja; Urzua, Francisco</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Zero-R-2 Hedge Funds and Market Neutrality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.
Factor models yield an R-2 insignificantly different from 0 for one-third of hedge funds in a broad sample. These funds illustrate the concept of market neutrality and feature lower volatilities, higher Sharpe ratios, and higher alphas than other funds, indicating that they provide a successful alternative investment. However, large portfolios of zero-R-2 funds contain fully half the volatility of portfolios of other funds, suggesting that they feature substantial systematic risk. Furthermore, these funds display an increased probability of failure even after controlling for idiosyncratic volatility. These results indicate the presence of an omitted factor that exposes investors to significant downside risk.</description><author>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volume Dynamics and Multimarket Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Halling, Michael; Moulton, Pamela C.; Panayides, Marios
The trading of shares of the same firm in multiple markets has become common over the last 30 years, but there is little empirical evidence on the extent to which investors actively exploit multimarket environments. We introduce a volume-based measure of multimarket trading to address this question. Analyzing a large set of cross-listed firms, we find higher multimarket trading among markets with similar designs and strong enforcement of insider trading laws and for firms with higher institutional ownership. These findings are important for firms evaluating the benefits of cross listing and for markets competing for order flow.</description><author>Halling, Michael; Moulton, Pamela C.; Panayides, Marios</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Telltale Tails: A New Approach to Estimating Unique Market Information Shares</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grammig, Joachim; Peter, Franziska J.
The trading of securities on multiple markets raises the question of each market's share in the discovery of the informationally efficient price. We exploit salient distributional features of multivariate financial price processes to uniquely determine these contributions, thereby resolving the main drawback of the widely used Hasbrouck (1995) methodology, which merely provides upper and lower bounds of a market's information share. We show how tail dependence of price changes, which may emerge as a result of differences in market design, can be exploited to estimate unique information shares. Two empirical applications illustrate the practical use of the new methodology.</description><author>Grammig, Joachim; Peter, Franziska J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance through Trading: Institutional Swing Trades and Subsequent Firm Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallagher, David R.; Gardner, Peter A.; Swan, Peter L.
Using unique daily fund-manager trade data, we examine the role of institutional trading in influencing firm performance. We show that short-horizon informed trading by multiple institutional investors effectively disciplines corporate management. Our focus is on short-term "swing" trades, sequences with three phases (e.g., buy-sell-buy). We find swing trades increase stock price informativeness, are profitable after costs, and improve market efficiency. This increase in stock price informativeness is associated with subsequent firm outperformance. Trades are most beneficial with optimal stock holdings that reflect the information acquisition incentives of investors as well as liquidity costs.</description><author>Gallagher, David R.; Gardner, Peter A.; Swan, Peter L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Closed-End Bond Funds Exist? An Additional Explanation for the Growth in Domestic Closed-End Bond Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Blake, Christopher R.; Shachar, Or
This paper provides a new explanation for why closed-end bond funds coexist along with otherwise identical open-end bond funds. Closed-end bond funds offer investors the opportunity to leverage their fixed income investment at very low borrowing rates and are attractive to investors for this reason. We find that differences in leverage are reflected in the discount on closed-end bond funds in a manner consistent with the advantage of leverage.</description><author>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Blake, Christopher R.; Shachar, Or</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculative Retail Trading and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Bing; Kumar, Alok
This paper examines the characteristics and pricing of stocks that are actively traded by speculative retail investors. We find that stocks with high retail trading proportion (RTP) have strong lottery features and they attract retail investors with strong gambling propensity. Furthermore, these stocks tend to be overpriced and earn significantly negative alpha. The average monthly return differential between the extreme RTP quintiles is -0.60%. This negative RTP premium is stronger among stocks that have lottery features or are located in regions where people exhibit stronger gambling propensity. Collectively, these results indicate that speculative retail trading affects stock prices.</description><author>Han, Bing; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State Antitakeover Laws and Voluntary Disclosure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhao, Yijiang; Allen, Arthur; Hasan, Iftekhar
We test the relationship between takeover protection and voluntary disclosure in a setting of antitakeover laws in a firm's state of incorporation. After correcting for the endogeneity of firms' incorporation choices, we find that firms incorporated in states with more antitakeover laws have higher levels of voluntary disclosure and stock market liquidity. Further tests do not support shareholder demands being the driving force for this association. Our findings are consistent with takeover protection and poor disclosure serving as substitute mechanisms for deterring takeovers. Therefore, as antitakeover statutes mitigate takeover threats, they enhance managers' incentives to disclose more in order to realize capital market benefits.</description><author>Zhao, Yijiang; Allen, Arthur; Hasan, Iftekhar</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Management with Leverage: Evidence from Project Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Byoun, Soku; Kim, Jaemin; Yoo, Sean Sehyun
We examine capital structures of 2,572 project-financed investments in 124 countries for the period 1997-2006. In contrast to the general prediction of the trade-off theory, we find that project companies use more leverage when project risk is high, but they use less leverage in the presence of risk-reducing features including offtake agreements. Project companies use less leverage and instead rely more on offtake agreements when the control benefits of cash flow from the project are high, suggesting that leverage and contract structures in the project company are important hedging mechanisms.</description><author>Byoun, Soku; Kim, Jaemin; Yoo, Sean Sehyun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Much Do Investors Care About Macroeconomic Risk? Evidence from Scheduled Economic Announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savor, Pavel; Wilson, Mungo
Stock market average returns and Sharpe ratios are significantly higher on days when important macroeconomic news about inflation, unemployment, or interest rates is scheduled for announcement. The average announcement-day excess return from 1958 to 2009 is 11.4 basis points (bp) versus 1.1 bp for all the other days, suggesting that over 60% of the cumulative annual equity risk premium is earned on announcement days. The Sharpe ratio is 10 times higher. In contrast, the risk-free rate is detectably lower on announcement days, consistent with a precautionary saving motive. Our results demonstrate a trade-off between macroeconomic risk and asset returns, and provide an estimate of the premium investors demand to bear this risk.</description><author>Savor, Pavel; Wilson, Mungo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cognitive Dissonance, Sentiment, and Momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antoniou, Constantinos; Doukas, John A.; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
We consider whether sentiment affects the profitability of momentum strategies. We hypothesize that news that contradicts investors' sentiment causes cognitive dissonance, slowing the diffusion of such news. Thus, losers (winners) become underpriced under optimism (pessimism). Short-selling constraints may impede arbitraging of losers and thus strengthen momentum during optimistic periods. Supporting this notion, we empirically show that momentum profits arise only under optimism. An analysis of net order flows from small and large trades indicates that small investors are slow to sell losers during optimistic periods. Momentum-based hedge portfolios formed during optimistic periods experience long-run reversals.</description><author>Antoniou, Constantinos; Doukas, John A.; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Overconfidence and International Merger and Acquisition Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferris, Stephen P.; Jayaraman, Narayanan; Sabherwal, Sanjiv
This study examines the role that chief executive officer (CEO) overconfidence plays in an explanation of international mergers and acquisitions during the period 2000-2006. Using a sample of CEOs of Fortune Global 500 firms over our sample period, we find that CEO overconfidence is related to a number of critical aspects of international merger activity. Overconfidence helps to explain the number of offers made by a CEO, the frequencies of nondiversifying and diversifying acquisitions, and the use of cash to finance a merger deal. Although overconfidence is an international phenomenon, it is most extensively observed in individuals heading firms headquartered in Christian countries that encourage individualism while de-emphasizing long-term orientation in their national cultures.</description><author>Ferris, Stephen P.; Jayaraman, Narayanan; Sabherwal, Sanjiv</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Director Ownership, Governance, and Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhagat, Sanjai; Bolton, Brian
We study the impact of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act on the relationship between corporate governance and company performance. We consider 5 measures of corporate governance during the period 1998-2007. We find a significant negative relationship between board independence and operating performance during the pre-2002 period, but a positive and significant relationship during the post-2002 period. Our most important contribution is a proposal of a governance measure, namely, dollar ownership of the board members, that is simple, intuitive, less prone to measurement error, and not subject to the problem of weighting a multitude of governance provisions in constructing a governance index.</description><author>Bhagat, Sanjai; Bolton, Brian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Portfolio Distortions Reflect Superior Information or Psychological Biases?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok
Using a demographics-based proxy for smartness, we show that the portfolio distortions of "smart" investors reflect an informational advantage, while the distortions of "dumb" investors reflect psychological biases. Specifically, smart investors outperform dumb investors by about 3% annually on a risk-adjusted basis. Furthermore, among investors with high portfolio distortions, smart investors outperform passive benchmarks by 2%, and the smart-dumb performance differential is 5%. At the stock level, a portfolio of stocks with smart investor clientele outperforms the dumb clientele portfolio by 3.50% annually. These findings suggest that behavioral and information-based explanations for portfolio distortions apply to distinct subsets of investors.</description><author>Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Solving the Return Deviation Conundrum of Leveraged Exchange-Traded Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tang, Hongfei; Xu, Xiaoqing Eleanor
The large deviation of the actual return of a leveraged exchange-traded fund (LETF) from the leveraged multiple of the underlying index return has drawn considerable attention from investors, regulators, and the financial media. Despite this attention, the sources and fundamental determinants of the LETF return deviation remain unidentified. This study constructs a clear, unified, objective, and executable framework that addresses the behaviors, sources, and determinants of the LETF compounding and noncompounding deviations. Our theoretical predictions and empirical results hold the promise of guiding investors, regulators, financial advisors, and portfolio managers toward a thorough understanding of the return behavior of LETFs.</description><author>Tang, Hongfei; Xu, Xiaoqing Eleanor</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using Samples of Unequal Length in Generalized Method of Moments Estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lynch, Anthony W.; Wachter, Jessica A.
This paper describes estimation methods, based on the generalized method of moments (GMM), applicable in settings where time series have different starting or ending dates. We introduce two estimators that are more efficient asymptotically than standard GMM. We apply these to estimating predictive regressions in international data and show that the use of the full sample affects inference for assets with data available over the full period as well as for assets with data available for a subset of the period. Monte Carlo experiments demonstrate that reductions hold for small-sample standard errors as well as asymptotic ones.</description><author>Lynch, Anthony W.; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Risk, Return Predictability, and Hedge Funds' Performance: An Empirical Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandon, Rajna Gibson; Wang, Songtao
This article analyzes the effect of liquidity risk on the performance of equity hedge fund portfolios. Similarly to Avramov, Kosowski, Naik, and Teo (2007), (2011), we observe that, before accounting for the effect of liquidity risk, hedge fund portfolios that incorporate predictability in managerial skills generate superior performance. This outperformance disappears or weakens substantially for most emerging markets, event-driven, and long/short hedge fund portfolios once we account for liquidity risk. Moreover, we show that the equity market-neutral and long/short hedge fund portfolios' "alphas" also entail rents for their service as liquidity providers. These results hold under various robustness tests.</description><author>Brandon, Rajna Gibson; Wang, Songtao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonmonetary Benefits, Quality of Life, and Executive Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deng, Xin; Gao, Huasheng
We examine the effects of nonmonetary benefits on overall executive compensation from the perspective of the living environment at the firm headquarters. Companies in polluted, high crime rate, or otherwise unpleasant locations pay higher compensation to their chief executive officers (CEOs) than companies located in more livable locations. This premium in pay for quality of life is stronger when firms face tougher competition in the managerial labor market, when the CEO is hired from outside, and when the CEO has short-term career concerns. Overall, the geographic desirability of the corporate headquarters is an effective substitute for CEO monetary pay.</description><author>Deng, Xin; Gao, Huasheng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive Compensation and Business Policy Choices at US Commercial Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeYoung, Robert; Peng, Emma Y.; Yan, Meng
We show that contractual risk-taking incentives for chief executive officers (CEOs) increased at large U. S. commercial banks around 2000, when industry deregulation expanded these banks' growth opportunities. Our econometric models indicate that CEOs responded positively to these incentives, especially at the larger banks best able to take advantage of these opportunities. Our results also suggest that bank boards responded to higher-than-average levels of risk by moderating CEO risk-taking incentives; however, this feedback effect is absent at the very largest banks with strong growth opportunities and a history of highly aggressive risk-taking incentives.</description><author>DeYoung, Robert; Peng, Emma Y.; Yan, Meng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Allocation by Public and Private Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mortal, Sandra; Reisel, Natalia
We compare investment policies across public and private firms in different institutional settings. Using a large cross-country data set, we find that public listed firms are better positioned to take advantage of growth opportunities than private firms. Specifically, public listed firms exhibit higher investment sensitivity to growth opportunities than private firms. This differential, however, only exists in countries with well-developed stock markets. Furthermore, the relative advantage public firms have at allocating capital depends on the degree of agency costs and reliance on external equity.</description><author>Mortal, Sandra; Reisel, Natalia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Anchoring Bias in the Equity Market: Evidence from Analysts' Earnings Forecasts and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cen, Ling; Hilary, Gilles; Wei, K. C. John
We test the implications of anchoring bias associated with forecast earnings per share (FEPS) for forecast errors, earnings surprises, stock returns, and stock splits. We find that analysts make optimistic (pessimistic) forecasts when a firm's FEPS is lower (higher) than the industry median. Further, firms with FEPS greater (lower) than the industry median experience abnormally high (low) future stock returns, particularly around subsequent earnings announcement dates. These firms are also more likely to engage in stock splits. Finally, split firms experience more positive forecast revisions, more negative forecast errors, and more negative earnings surprises after stock splits.</description><author>Cen, Ling; Hilary, Gilles; Wei, K. C. John</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Government Intervention in Banks on Corporate Borrowers' Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Norden, Lars; Roosenboom, Peter; Wang, Teng
We investigate whether and how government interventions in the U.S. banking sector influence the stock market performance of corporate borrowers during the financial crisis of 2007-2009. We measure firms' exposures to government interventions with an intervention score that is based on combined information on the firms' structure of bank relationships and their banks' participation in government capital support programs. We find that government capital infusions in banks have a significantly positive impact on borrowing firms' stock returns. The effect is more pronounced for riskier and bank-dependent firms and for those that borrow from banks that are less capitalized and smaller.</description><author>Norden, Lars; Roosenboom, Peter; Wang, Teng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>R&amp;D Spillover Effects and Firm Performance Following R&amp;D Increases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chen, Yan-Shing; Liang, Woan-lih; Wang, Yanzhi
We examine how research and development (R&amp;D) incoming spillovers affect long-run firm performance following firms' R&amp;D increases. We use a stochastic frontier production method to capture R&amp;D incoming spillover effects. Firms reaping more benefits from R&amp;D investment made by other firms experience more improvement in profitability and more favorable long-run stock performance in the post-R&amp;D-increase period. Firms with higher levels of R&amp;D incoming spillovers recruit more key employees from other firms, suggesting that obtaining know-how through hiring is an important source of incoming spillovers. The evidence also shows that firms experiencing more R&amp;D outgoing spillover effects tend to underinvest in R&amp;D.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chen, Yan-Shing; Liang, Woan-lih; Wang, Yanzhi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst Coverage, Information, and Bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrade, Sandro C.; Bian, Jiangze; Burch, Timothy R.
We examine the 2007 stock market bubble in China. Using multiple measures of bubble intensity for each stock, we find significantly smaller bubbles in stocks for which there is greater analyst coverage. We further show that the abating effect of analyst coverage on bubble intensity is weaker when there is greater disagreement among analysts. This suggests that, in line with resale option theories of bubbles, one channel through which analyst coverage may mitigate bubbles is by coordinating investors' beliefs and thus reducing its dispersion. Stock turnover provides further evidence consistent with this particular information mechanism.</description><author>Andrade, Sandro C.; Bian, Jiangze; Burch, Timothy R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification in Private Equity Funds: On Knowledge Sharing, Risk Aversion, and Limited Attention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Humphery-Jenner, Mark
This paper examines diversification as a source of value creation and destruction in private equity (PE) funds. Previous literature has focused on the "diversification discount" in corporations. However, in PE funds, diversification might increase returns by ameliorating managerial risk aversion and facilitating knowledge sharing. I examine a sample of 1,505 PE funds and show that industry and geographic diversification can increase PE fund returns. This is likely due to knowledge sharing and learning, not merely risk reduction. Diversification can reduce returns if it spreads staff too thinly across industries or is motivated by risk aversion rather than performance bonuses.</description><author>Humphery-Jenner, Mark</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Assets and Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Giambona, Erasmo
We characterize the relation between asset structure and capital structure by exploiting variation in the salability of corporate assets. To establish this link, we distinguish across different assets in firms' balance sheets (machinery, land, and buildings) and use an instrumental approach that incorporates market conditions for those assets. We also use a natural experiment driving differential increases in the supply of real estate assets across the United States: The Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990. Consistent with a supply-side view of capital structure, we find that asset redeployability is a main driver of leverage when credit frictions are high.</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Giambona, Erasmo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Joint Dynamics of Equity Market Factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Langlois, Hugues
The 4 equity market factors from Fama and French (1993) and Carhart (1997) are pervasive in academia and practice. However, not much is known about their joint distribution and dynamics. We find striking evidence of asymmetric tail dependence across the factors. While the linear factor correlations are small and even negative, the extreme correlations are large and positive, so that the linear correlations drastically overstate the benefits of diversification across the factors. We model the nonlinear factor dependence dynamics and explore their economic importance in a portfolio allocation experiment showing that significant economic value is earned when acknowledging nonlinear dependence.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Langlois, Hugues</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Development and the Asset Growth Effect: International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Titman, Sheridan; Wei, K. C. John; Xie, Feixue
A number of studies of U.S. stock returns document what is referred to as the investment or asset growth effect. Specifically, firms that increase investment or total assets subsequently earn lower risk-adjusted returns. This study finds substantial cross-country differences in the asset growth effect. In particular, the asset growth effect is stronger in countries with more developed financial markets, but it does not seem to be associated with corporate governance or the costs of trading. Overall, the evidence is consistent with a q-theory where financial market development captures either managers' willingness or ability to align investment expenditures to the cost of capital, but it is inconsistent with the hypothesis that the asset growth effect is due to bad governance and overinvestment.</description><author>Titman, Sheridan; Wei, K. C. John; Xie, Feixue</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A New Anomaly: The Cross-Sectional Profitability of Technical Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Yufeng; Yang, Ke; Zhou, Guofu
In this paper, we document that an application of a moving average timing strategy of technical analysis to portfolios sorted by volatility generates investment timing portfolios that substantially outperform the buy-and-hold strategy. For high-volatility portfolios, the abnormal returns, relative to the capital asset pricing model (CAPM) and the Fama-French 3-factor models, are of great economic significance, and are greater than those from the well-known momentum strategy. Moreover, they cannot be explained by market timing ability, investor sentiment, default, and liquidity risks. Similar results also hold if the portfolios are sorted based on other proxies of information uncertainty.</description><author>Han, Yufeng; Yang, Ke; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of (Stock) Liquidity in the M&amp;A Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Xu, Moqi
We study the value of stock liquidity in the market for corporate control and show that the target firm's liquidity has an impact on the transaction itself and on the resulting merged entity. We use a sample of U.S. merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) transactions (1987-2007) to show that acquiring a more liquid firm makes the stock of the acquirer more liquid. This has consequences for M&amp;A activity and pricing. Public acquirers are more likely than private acquirers to acquire more liquid targets. Liquidity also translates into a greater likelihood of completing the deal and higher compensation for the target.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Xu, Moqi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Hedge Funds Avoid Disclosure? Evidence from Confidential 13F Filings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aragon, George O.; Hertzel, Michael; Shi, Zhen
We study a sample of Form 13F filings where fund advisors seek confidential treatment for some or all of their 13(f)-reportable positions. Consistent with the hypothesis that managers seek confidentiality to protect proprietary information, we find that confidential positions earn positive and significant abnormal returns over the post-filing confidential period. We also find that managers are more likely to seek confidential treatment of illiquid positions that are more susceptible to front-running. Overall, our analysis highlights important benefits of reduced disclosure that are relevant to the current policy debate on hedge fund transparency.</description><author>Aragon, George O.; Hertzel, Michael; Shi, Zhen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Price Jumps and Cross-Sectional Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, George J.; Yao, Tong
We identify large discontinuous changes, known as jumps, in daily stock prices and explore the role of jumps in cross-sectional stock return predictability. Our results show that small and illiquid stocks have higher jump returns to the extent that cross-sectional differences in jumps fully account for the size and illiquidity effects. Based on value-weighted portfolios, jumps also account for the value premium. On the other hand, jumps are not the cause of momentum or net share issue effects. The findings of our study shed new light on stock return dynamics and present challenges to conventional explanations of stock return predictability.</description><author>Jiang, George J.; Yao, Tong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Importance of Golden Parachutes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fich, Eliezer M.; Tran, Anh L.; Walkling, Ralph A.
In acquisitions, target chief executive officers (CEOs) face a moral hazard: Any personal gain from the deal could be offset by the loss of the future compensation stream associated with their jobs. Larger, more important parachutes provide greater relief for these losses. To explicitly measure the moral hazard target CEOs face, we standardize the parachute payment by the expected value of their acquisition-induced lost compensation. We examine 851 acquisitions from 1999-2007, finding that more important parachutes benefit target shareholders through higher completion probabilities. Conversely, as parachute importance increases, target shareholders receive lower takeover premia, while acquirer shareholders capture additional rents from target shareholders.</description><author>Fich, Eliezer M.; Tran, Anh L.; Walkling, Ralph A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Horizons and Corporate Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Derrien, Francois; Kecskes, Ambrus; Thesmar, David
We study the effect of investor horizons on corporate behavior. We argue that longer investor horizons attenuate the effect of stock mispricing on corporate policies. Consistent with our argument, we find that when a firm is undervalued, greater long-term investor ownership is associated with more investment, more equity financing, and less payouts to shareholders. Our results do not appear to be explained by long-term investor self-selection, monitoring (corporate governance), or concentration (blockholdings). Our results are consistent with a version of market timing in which mispriced firms cater to the tastes of their short-term investors rather than their long-term investors.</description><author>Derrien, Francois; Kecskes, Ambrus; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creating Value by Changing the Old Guard: The Impact of Controlling Shareholder Heterogeneity on Firm Performance and Corporate Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deng, Hua; Moshirian, Fariborz; Pham, Peter Kien; Zein, Jason
Theory suggests that controlling shareholders can influence firm value through both shared benefits creation and private benefits consumption. Using negotiated control-block transfers from 31 countries, we look beyond ownership concentration and investigate how controlling shareholder heterogeneity influences the relative importance of these two effects. We document that a control transfer precipitates positive firm outcomes particularly when the vendor has maintained control over an extended period and the acquirer displays a strong incentive to engage in restructuring. In such cases, we observe a sustained positive price reaction, more focused corporate investments, lower leverage, higher operating efficiency, and superior long-term performance.</description><author>Deng, Hua; Moshirian, Fariborz; Pham, Peter Kien; Zein, Jason</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving Portfolio Selection Using Option-Implied Volatility and Skewness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMiguel, Victor; Plyakha, Yuliya; Uppal, Raman; Vilkov, Grigory
Our objective in this paper is to examine whether one can use option-implied information to improve the selection of mean-variance portfolios with a large number of stocks, and to document which aspects of option-implied information are most useful to improve their out-of-sample performance. Portfolio performance is measured in terms of volatility, Sharpe ratio, and turnover. Our empirical evidence shows that using option-implied volatility helps to reduce portfolio volatility. Using option-implied correlation does not improve any of the metrics. Using option-implied volatility, risk premium, and skewness to adjust expected returns leads to a substantial improvement in the Sharpe ratio, even after prohibiting short sales and accounting for transaction costs.</description><author>DeMiguel, Victor; Plyakha, Yuliya; Uppal, Raman; Vilkov, Grigory</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst Disagreement and Aggregate Volatility Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barinov, Alexander
The paper explains why firms with high dispersion of analyst forecasts earn low future returns. These firms beat the capital asset pricing model in periods of increasing aggregate volatility and thereby provide a hedge against aggregate volatility risk. The aggregate volatility risk factor can explain the abnormal return differential between high- and low-disagreement firms. This return differential is higher for firms with abundant real options, and this fact can be explained by aggregate volatility risk. Aggregate volatility risk can also explain why the link between analyst disagreement and future returns is stronger for firms with high short-sale constraints.</description><author>Barinov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Sarbanes-Oxley Act, Earnings Management, and Post-Buyback Performance of Open-Market Repurchasing Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Huang, Chia-Wei
We examine how the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) affects pre-repurchase earnings management and its association with post-repurchase firm performance. Unlike prior pre-SOX studies, our post-SOX results indicate that open-market repurchasers do not engage in pre-buyback downward accrual-based earnings management. Audit committee independence, reforms in corporate governance structures, and changes in executives' equity holdings prompted by SOX may explain the findings. Post-SOX, the significant negative association between pre-repurchase abnormal accruals and post-repurchase performance disappears, the market reaction to repurchase announcements becomes significantly less favorable, and there is no evidence of any shift away from accrual-based to real earnings management.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Huang, Chia-Wei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxation, Dividends, and Share Repurchases: Taking Evidence Global</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacob, Marcus; Jacob, Martin
We compile a comprehensive international dividend and capital gains tax data set to study tax-based explanations of corporate payout for a panel of 6,035 firms from 25 countries for the period 1990-2008. We find robust evidence that the tax penalty on dividends versus capital gains corresponds closely with firms' propensity to pay dividends and repurchase shares, and with the amount of dividends and shares repurchased. Our coefficient estimates suggest a smaller tax effect than is reported in recent single-country, single-event studies. Instead, our results correspond more closely with historic long-term estimates of the elasticity of dividends.</description><author>Jacob, Marcus; Jacob, Martin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Divisible Good Auctions with Asymmetric Information: An Experimental Examination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morales-Camargo, Emmanuel; Sade, Orly; Schnitzlein, Charles; Zender, Jaime F.
An experimental approach is used to compare bidding behavior and auction performance in uniform-price and discriminatory auctions when there is incomplete information concerning the common value of the auctioned good. In a symmetric information environment, the different auction formats provide the same average revenue. However, when information is asymmetric the discriminatory auction results in higher average revenue than the uniform-price auction. The volatility of revenue is higher in the uniform-price auctions in all treatments. The results, therefore, provide support for the use of the discriminatory format. Subject characteristics and measures of experience in recent auctions are found to be useful in explaining bidding behavior.</description><author>Morales-Camargo, Emmanuel; Sade, Orly; Schnitzlein, Charles; Zender, Jaime F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal versus External CEO Choice and the Structure of Compensation Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Palomino, Frederic; Peyrache, Eloic
Any firm choosing a chief executive officer (CEO) faces a double problem: candidate selection and choice of a compensation scheme. We derive sufficient conditions where the unique optimal compensation scheme is a capped-bonus contract in a pure moral-hazard environment, while equity is used when the firm also faces adverse selection. Then, we provide a rationale for the simultaneous increases in CEO pay, use of equity in compensation, and external hiring of CEOs. Our results are consistent with empirical evidence that shows externally hired CEOs earn more than those internally hired and that externally hired CEOs get a higher fraction of their compensation equity based.</description><author>Palomino, Frederic; Peyrache, Eloic</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Pension Plans as Takeover Deterrents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cocco, Joao F.; Volpin, Paolo F.
We use U.K. data to show that firms that sponsor a defined-benefit pension plan are less likely to be targeted in an acquisition and, conditional on an attempted takeover, they are less likely to be acquired. Our explanation is that the uncertainty in the value of pension liabilities is a source of risk for acquirers of the firm's shares, which works as a takeover deterrent. In support of this explanation we find that these same firms are more likely to use cash when acquiring other firms, and that the announcement of a cash acquisition is associated with positive announcement effects.</description><author>Cocco, Joao F.; Volpin, Paolo F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Algorithmic Trading and the Market for Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendershott, Terrence; Riordan, Ryan
We examine the role of algorithmic traders (ATs) in liquidity supply and demand in the 30 Deutscher Aktien Index stocks on the Deutsche Boerse in Jan. 2008. ATs represent 52% of market order volume and 64% of nonmarketable limit order volume. ATs more actively monitor market liquidity than human traders. ATs consume liquidity when it is cheap (i.e., when the bid-ask quotes are narrow) and supply liquidity when it is expensive. When spreads are narrow ATs are less likely to submit new orders, less likely to cancel their orders, and more likely to initiate trades. ATs react more quickly to events and even more so when spreads are wide.</description><author>Hendershott, Terrence; Riordan, Ryan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Strong Boards and Trading Their Own Firm's Stock Help CEOs Make Better Decisions? Evidence from Acquisitions by Overconfident CEOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolasinski, Adam C.; Li, Xu
Little evidence exists on whether boards help managers make better decisions. We provide evidence that strong and independent boards help overconfident chief executive officers (CEOs) avoid honest mistakes when they seek to acquire other companies. In addition, we find that once-overconfident CEOs make better acquisition decisions after they experience personal stock trading losses, providing evidence that a manager's recent personal experience, and not just educational and early career experience, influences firm investment policy. Finally, we develop and validate a new CEO overconfidence measure that is easily constructed from machine-readable insider trading data, unlike previously used measures.</description><author>Kolasinski, Adam C.; Li, Xu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Reaction to Corporate Press Releases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neuhierl, Andreas; Scherbina, Anna; Schlusche, Bernd
We classify a unique and comprehensive data set of corporate press releases into topics and study the market reaction to various types of news. While confirming prior findings regarding strong stock price responses to financial news, we also document significant reactions to news about corporate strategy, customers and partners, products and services, management changes, and legal developments. Consistent with regulators' expectations, the level of informational asymmetry in the market declines following most types of press releases. At the same time, return volatility frequently increases in the post-announcement period, which we show can be attributed to higher levels of valuation uncertainty.</description><author>Neuhierl, Andreas; Scherbina, Anna; Schlusche, Bernd</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Risk-Neutral Skewness Predict the Cross Section of Equity Option Portfolio Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Murray, Scott
We investigate the pricing of risk-neutral skewness in the stock options market by creating skewness assets comprised of two option positions (one long and one short) and a position in the underlying stock. The assets are created such that exposure to changes in the underlying stock price (delta) and exposure to changes in implied volatility (vega) are removed, isolating the effect of skewness. We find a strong negative relation between risk-neutral skewness and the skewness asset returns, consistent with a positive skewness preference. The returns are not explained by well-known market, size, book-to-market, momentum, short-term reversal, volatility, or option market factors.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Murray, Scott</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probability Weighting and Employee Stock Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spalt, Oliver G.
This paper documents that riskier firms with higher idiosyncratic volatility grant more stock options to nonexecutive employees. Standard models in the literature cannot easily explain this pattern; a model in which a risk-neutral firm and an employee with prospect theory preferences bargain over the employee's pay package can. The key feature that makes stock options attractive is probability weighting. The model fits the data on option grants well when calibrated using standard parameters from the experimental literature. The results are the first evidence that risky firms can profitably use stock options to cater to an employee demand for long-shot bets.</description><author>Spalt, Oliver G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Fund Return Predictability under the Magnifying Glass</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Barras, Laurent; Kosowski, Robert
This paper develops a unified approach to comprehensively analyze individual hedge fund return predictability, both in and out of sample. In sample, we find that variation in hedge fund performance across changing market conditions is widespread and economically significant. The predictability pattern is consistent with the economic rationale and largely reflects differences in key hedge fund characteristics, such as leverage or capacity constraints. Out of sample, we show that a simple strategy that combines the funds' return forecasts obtained from individual predictors delivers superior performance. We exploit this simplicity to highlight the drivers of this performance, and we find that in- and out-of-sample predictability are closely related.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Barras, Laurent; Kosowski, Robert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Overvaluation-Driven Stock Acquisitions Really Benefit Acquirer Shareholders?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akbulut, Mehmet E.
I study the effects of overvalued equity on acquisition activity and shareholder wealth, using managers' insider trades to measure overvaluation. I find that overvalued equity drives managers to make stock acquisitions, and such acquisitions destroy value for acquirer shareholders. Overvalued stock acquirers earn negative and lower returns in the short run and substantially underperform similarly overvalued nonacquirer firms in the long run. My results do not support the idea that managers can benefit shareholders by converting overvalued equity into real assets through stock acquisitions.</description><author>Akbulut, Mehmet E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stocks, Bonds, and Long-Run Consumption Risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasseltoft, Henrik
I evaluate whether the so-called long-run risk framework can jointly explain key features of both equity and bond markets as well as the interaction between asset prices and the macroeconomy. I find that shocks to expected consumption growth and time-varying macroeconomic volatility can account for the level of risk premia and its variation over time in both markets. The results suggest a common set of macroeconomic risk factors operating in equity and bond markets. I estimate the model using a simulation estimator that accounts for time aggregation of consumption growth and utilizes a rich set of moment conditions.</description><author>Hasseltoft, Henrik</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility Trading: What Is the Role of the Long-Run Volatility Component?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhou, Guofu; Zhu, Yingzi
We study an investor's asset allocation problem with a recursive utility and with tradable volatility that follows a 2-factor stochastic volatility model. Consistent with previous findings under the additive utility, we show that the investor can benefit substantially from volatility trading due to hedging demand. Unlike existing studies, we find that the impact of elasticity of intertemporal substitution (EIS) on investment decisions is of 1st-order importance. Moreover, the investor can incur significant economic losses due to model and/or parameter misspecifications where the EIS better captures the investor's attitude toward risk than the risk aversion parameter.</description><author>Zhou, Guofu; Zhu, Yingzi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dividend Initiation Decision of Newly Public Firms: Some Evidence on Signaling with Dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kale, Jayant R.; Kini, Omesh; Payne, Janet D.
We track the dividend initiation (DI) decisions from a sample of 6,588 firms that went public during the period 1979-2005 and find that 873 of them initiated dividends. Our primary objective is to determine whether information signaling can explain the DI decision. We find that variables suggested by the dividend-signaling models of John and Williams (1985) and Allen, Bernardo, and Welch (2000) are significant determinants of the DI decision and the associated announcement-period stock price effect. We also find support for the residual, agency, tax, clientele, transaction costs, catering, and life-cycle explanations of dividend policy.</description><author>Kale, Jayant R.; Kini, Omesh; Payne, Janet D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Connor, Matthew; Rafferty, Matthew
We use Tobin's q models of investments to estimate the relationship between corporate governance and the level of innovative activity. Simple ordinary least squares (OLS) models suggest that poor governance reduces innovative activity. However, OLS results are sensitive to controlling for serial correlation, unobserved effects, or using instrumental variables to control simultaneity. Controlling for these effects substantially reduces or eliminates the relationship between governance and innovative activity.</description><author>O'Connor, Matthew; Rafferty, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Clean Sweep: Informed Trading through Intermarket Sweep Orders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakravarty, Sugato; Jain, Pankaj; Upson, James; Wood, Robert
An intermarket sweep order (ISO) is a limit order that automatically executes in a designated market center even if another market center is publishing a better quotation. An investor submitting an ISO must satisfy order protection rules by concurrently submitting orders to the markets with better prices. We find that ISOs represent 46% of trades and 41% of volume in our sample. ISO trades have a significantly larger information share despite their small trade size relative to non-ISO trades. Post trade return analysis suggests that informed institutions are the main users of ISO trades.</description><author>Chakravarty, Sugato; Jain, Pankaj; Upson, James; Wood, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Repurchases, Reputation, and Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonaime, Alice Adams
This paper examines whether a firm's reputation is a determinant of repurchase completion rates (the ratio of actual to announced repurchases) and whether the stock market discounts announcements made by less reputable firms. Prior completion rates are positively correlated with current completion rates and announcement returns, suggesting consistency in repurchases and implying a reputational effect. Further, a nascent literature regarding accelerated share repurchases (ASRs) finds them to be more credible than open market repurchases. I show that the probability of announcing an ASR is greater for firms likely to be concerned about reputation because of low past completion rates.</description><author>Bonaime, Alice Adams</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It's All in the Timing: Simple Active Portfolio Strategies that Outperform Naive Diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kirby, Chris; Ostdiek, Barbara
De Miguel, Garlappi, and Uppal (2009) report that naive diversification dominates mean-variance optimization in out-of-sample asset allocation tests. Our analysis suggests that this is largely due to their research design, which focuses on portfolios that are subject to high estimation risk and extreme turnover. We find that mean-variance optimization often outperforms naive diversification, but turnover can erode its advantage in the presence of transaction costs. To address this issue, we develop 2 new methods of mean-variance portfolio selection (volatility timing and reward-to-risk timing) that deliver portfolios characterized by low turnover. These timing strategies outperform naive diversification even in the presence of high transaction costs.</description><author>Kirby, Chris; Ostdiek, Barbara</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Liquidity and Stock Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Kadan, Ohad; Pevzner, Mikhail
We study the relation between asset liquidity and stock liquidity. Our model shows that the relation may be either positive or negative depending on parameter values. Asset liquidity improves stock liquidity more for firms that are less likely to reinvest their liquid assets (i.e., firms with less growth opportunities and financially constrained firms). Empirically, we find a positive and economically large relation between asset liquidity and stock liquidity. Consistent with our model, the relation is more positive for firms that are less likely to reinvest their liquid assets. Our results also shed light on the value of holding liquid assets.</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Kadan, Ohad; Pevzner, Mikhail</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An International Comparison of Capital Structure and Debt Maturity Choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, Joseph P. H.; Titman, Sheridan; Twite, Garry
This study examines how the institutional environment influences capital structure and debt maturity choices of firms in 39 developed and developing countries. We find that a country's legal and tax system, corruption, and the preferences of capital suppliers explain a significant portion of the variation in leverage and debt maturity ratios. Specifically, firms in more corrupt countries and those with weaker laws tend to use more debt, especially short-term debt; explicit bankruptcy codes and deposit insurance are associated with higher leverage and more long-term debt. More debt is used in countries where there is a greater tax gain from leverage.</description><author>Fan, Joseph P. H.; Titman, Sheridan; Twite, Garry</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Strength and Product Market Competition: Evidence from Asbestos Litigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hadlock, Charles J.; Sonti, Ramana
We study the role of financial strength on product market competition by examining exogenous shocks to a firm's liability structure arising from asbestos litigation. We find that exogenous increases (decreases) in asbestos liabilities are interpreted by the market as negative (positive) news for a firm's close competitors. These reactions are magnified in events in which one asbestos-tainted firm goes bankrupt and other asbestos-tainted stocks fall on the news of the bankruptcy. For smaller competitors, market reactions are more pronounced in more concentrated industries. Our findings support the general hypothesis that increases in fixed liabilities lead to more aggressive product market interactions.</description><author>Hadlock, Charles J.; Sonti, Ramana</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-Return Tradeoff in US Stock Returns over the Business Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nyberg, Henri
In the empirical finance literature, findings on the risk-return tradeoff in excess stock market returns are ambiguous. In this study, I develop a new qualitative response (QR)-generalized autoregressive conditional heteroskedasticity-in-mean (GARCH-M) model combining a probit model for a binary business cycle indicator and a regime-switching GARCH-M model for excess stock market return with the business cycle indicator defining the regime. Estimation results show that there is statistically significant variation in the U.S. excess stock returns over the business cycle. However, consistent with the conditional intertemporal capital asset pricing model (ICAPM), there is a positive risk-return relationship between volatility and expected return independent of the state of the economy.</description><author>Nyberg, Henri</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inefficient Labor or Inefficient Capital? Corporate Diversification and Productivity around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitton, Todd
I study the relation between corporate diversification and labor productivity in a sample of over 500,000 firms from 46 countries. Across the entire sample, greater diversification is associated with significantly lower labor productivity. The negative relation between diversification and labor productivity is not stronger in countries with more burdensome employment regulation, but it is significantly stronger in countries with better financial development. In addition, the negative relation is stronger in industries with high capital/labor ratios. Overall, the results suggest that the lower productivity in diversified firms is due more to the misallocation of capital than to the inefficient use of labor.</description><author>Mitton, Todd</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sources of Gains in Corporate Mergers: Refined Tests from a Neglected Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becher, David A.; Mulherin, J. Harold; Walkling, Ralph A.
Our work provides refined tests of the source of merger gains in a neglected industry: utilities. Utilities offer fertile ground for analysis of traditional theories: synergy, collusion, hubris, and anticipation. Utility mergers create wealth for the combined firm, consistent with both the synergy and collusion hypotheses. To distinguish between these hypotheses, we study rival stock returns across dimensions related to collusion: deregulation, geography, and horizontal and withdrawn deals. We also find that the impact of mergers on consumer prices is consistent with synergy rather than collusion. Analysis of industry rivals that become targets also rejects collusion and is consistent with anticipation.</description><author>Becher, David A.; Mulherin, J. Harold; Walkling, Ralph A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Survival of Overconfidence in Currency Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oberlechner, Thomas; Osler, Carol
This paper tests the influential hypothesis that irrational traders will be driven out of financial markets by trading losses. The paper's main finding is that overconfident currency dealers are not driven out of the market. Dealers with extensive experience are neither more nor less overconfident than their junior colleagues. We set the stage for this investigation by providing evidence that currency dealers display two forms of overconfidence: They underestimate uncertainty, and they overestimate their professional success. This is notable because one might have expected the opposite: currency dealers face strong incentives for accuracy, they have access to comprehensive information, and they have extensive experience.</description><author>Oberlechner, Thomas; Osler, Carol</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cross Section of Expected Returns with MIDAS Betas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gonzalez, Mariano; Nave, Juan; Rubio, Gonzalo
This paper explores the cross-sectional variation of expected returns for a large cross section of industry and size/book-to-market portfolios. We employ mixed data sampling (MIDAS) to estimate a portfolio's conditional beta with the market and with alternative risk factors and innovations to well-known macroeconomic variables. The market risk premium is positive and significant, and the result is robust to alternative asset pricing specifications and model misspecification. However, the traditional 2-pass ordinary least squares (OLS) cross-sectional regressions produce an estimate of the market risk premium that is negative, and significantly different from 0. Using alternative procedures, we compare both beta estimators. We conclude that beta estimates under MIDAS present lower mean absolute forecasting errors and generate better out-of-sample performance of the optimized portfolios relative to OLS betas.</description><author>Gonzalez, Mariano; Nave, Juan; Rubio, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Performance of Corporate Bond Mutual Funds: Evidence Based on Security-Level Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cici, Gjergji; Gibson, Scott
This is the first study of corporate bond mutual fund performance that examines detailed security-level holdings and returns. The new database allows us to decompose the costs and benefits of active management. In contrast to prior research on equity funds that shows evidence of stock-selection ability, we do not find evidence consistent with bond fund managers, on average, being able to select corporate bonds that outperform other bonds with similar characteristics. We find neutral to weakly positive evidence of ability to time corporate bond characteristics. Overall results show that the costs of active management on average appear larger than the benefits.</description><author>Cici, Gjergji; Gibson, Scott</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rights Offerings, Subscription Period, Shareholder Takeup, and Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balachandran, Balasingham; Faff, Robert; Theobald, Michael; van Zijl, Tony
We examine the role of shareholder takeup in rights offerings on the subscription period price reaction and liquidity. Our results indicate that takeup information is reflected in price adjustments over the subscription period and that quality-related information disclosed on the rights announcement date further impacts prices in this period. Higher shareholder takeup improves liquidity. We do find some evidence of inefficiencies in the adjustment process over the subscription period that, in part, is consistent with a model where markets are characterized by overconfident investors and that also articulates with takeup information arriving in the market.</description><author>Balachandran, Balasingham; Faff, Robert; Theobald, Michael; van Zijl, Tony</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term Structure Estimation with Survey Data on Interest Rate Forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Don H.; Orphanides, Athanasios
The estimation of dynamic no-arbitrage term structure models with a flexible specification of the market price of risk is beset by severe small-sample problems arising from the highly persistent nature of interest rates. We propose using survey forecasts of a short-term interest rate as an additional input to the estimation to overcome the problem. To illustrate the methodology, we estimate the 3-factor affine-Gaussian model with U.S. Treasury yields data and demonstrate that incorporating information from survey forecasts mitigates the small-sample problem. The model thus estimated for the 1990-2003 sample generates a stable and sensible estimate of the expected path of the short rate, reproduces the well-known stylized patterns in the expectations hypothesis tests, and captures some of the short-run variations in the survey forecast of the changes in longer-term interest rates.</description><author>Kim, Don H.; Orphanides, Athanasios</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Preparing" the Equity Market for Adverse Corporate Events: A Theoretical Analysis of Firms Cutting Dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Tian, Xuan
This paper presents the first theoretical analysis of the choice of firms between "preparing" and not preparing the equity market in advance of a possible dividend cut. In our model, insiders have private information about their firm's intermediate cash flow as well as about the net present value of its growth opportunity. We show that, in equilibrium, firms in temporary financial difficulties but with good long-term growth prospects are more likely to prepare the market in advance of dividend cuts, while those with permanently declining earnings are less likely to prepare the market. Our model generates several new testable predictions.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Tian, Xuan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Optimal Use of Return Predictability: An Empirical Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abhyankar, Abhay; Basu, Devraj; Stremme, Alexander
In this paper we study the economic value and statistical significance of asset return predictability, based on a wide range of commonly used predictive variables. We assess the performance of dynamic, unconditionally efficient strategies, first studied by Hansen and Richard (1987) and Ferson and Siegel (2001), using a test that has both an intuitive economic interpretation and known statistical properties. We find that using the lagged term spread, credit spread, and inflation significantly improves the risk-return trade-off. Our strategies consistently outperform efficient buy-and-hold strategies, both in and out of sample, and they also incur lower transactions costs than traditional conditionally efficient strategies.</description><author>Abhyankar, Abhay; Basu, Devraj; Stremme, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend Growth, Cash Flow, and Discount Rate News</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garrett, Ian; Priestley, Richard
Using a new variable based on a model of dividend smoothing, we find that dividend growth is highly predictable and that cash flow news contributes importantly to return variability. Cash flow betas derived from this predictability are central to explaining the size effect in the cross section of returns. However, they do not explain the value effect; this is explained by noise betas. We also find that the relative importance of cash flow news in explaining recent stock price run-ups and subsequent declines increases when cash flow news is estimated directly.</description><author>Garrett, Ian; Priestley, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholders in the Boardroom: Wealth Effects of the SEC's Proposal to Facilitate Director Nominations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akyol, Ali C.; Lim, Wei Fen; Verwijmeren, Patrick
Current attempts to reform financial markets presume that shareholder empowerment benefits shareholders. We investigate the wealth effects associated with the Securities and Exchange Commission's rule to facilitate director nominations by shareholders. Our results are not in line with shareholder empowerment creating value: The average daily abnormal returns surrounding events that increase (decrease) the probability of the proposal's passage are significantly negative (positive). Furthermore, given an increase in the probability of the proposal's passage, firms whose shareholders are more likely to use the rule to nominate directors experience more negative abnormal returns.</description><author>Akyol, Ali C.; Lim, Wei Fen; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loss Allocation in Securitization Transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franke, Guenter; Herrmann, Markus; Weber, Thomas
This paper analyzes the loss allocation to first, second, and third loss positions in European collateralized debt obligation transactions. The quality of the underlying asset pool plays a predominant role for the loss allocation. A lower asset pool quality induces the originator to take a higher first loss position, but, in a synthetic transaction, a smaller third loss position. The share of expected default losses, borne by the first loss position, is largely independent of asset pool quality but lower in securitizations of corporate loans than in those of corporate bonds. Originators with a good rating and low Tobin's Q prefer synthetic transactions.</description><author>Franke, Guenter; Herrmann, Markus; Weber, Thomas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It Pays to Follow the Leader: Acquiring Targets Picked by Private Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, Amy; Li, Di; Nain, Amrita
This paper examines the impact of financial sponsor competition on corporate buyers. We find that corporate acquirers who purchase targets that financial buyers also bid on outperform corporate acquirers who buy targets bid on by corporate firms only. Deal characteristics, acquirer abilities, and observable target characteristics cannot explain this difference in returns. Corporate acquirers have higher returns when they follow a first bid by a financial buyer rather than a first bid by another corporate buyer. The results suggest that financial bidders identify targets with high potential for value improvement and winning corporate bidders are competent in exploiting this potential.</description><author>Dittmar, Amy; Li, Di; Nain, Amrita</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Credibility of Open Market Share Repurchase Signaling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Babenko, Ilona; Tserlukevich, Yuri; Vedrashko, Alexander
Open market share repurchase announcements are commonly associated with equity undervaluation, but their signal about firm value can often be misleading. We conjecture that executives who buy shares of their firm before an announcement add credibility to the undervaluation signal. Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that announcement returns are positively related to past insider purchases, especially for firms that are priced less efficiently. Firms whose insiders bought more shares are also more likely to complete their repurchase plans. Finally, we find that insider purchases predict post-announcement stock returns.</description><author>Babenko, Ilona; Tserlukevich, Yuri; Vedrashko, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Validation of Default Probabilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloechlinger, Andreas
Well-performing default predictions show good discrimination and calibration. Discrimination is the ability to separate defaulters from nondefaulters. Calibration is the ability to make unbiased forecasts. I derive novel discrimination and calibration statistics to verify forecasts expressed in terms of probability under dependent observations. The test statistics' asymptotic distributions can be derived in analytic form. Not accounting for cross correlation can result in the rejection of actually well-performing predictions, as shown in an empirical application. I demonstrate that forecasting errors must be serially uncorrelated. As a consequence, my multiperiod tests are statistically consistent.</description><author>Bloechlinger, Andreas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance, Finance, and the Real Sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fulghieri, Paolo; Suominen, Matti
We present a theory of the linkages between corporate governance, corporate finance, and the real sector of an economy. Using a structural model of industry equilibrium with endogenous entry, we show that poor corporate governance leads to low levels of competition, and to firms with high insider ownership and leverage. In contrast, good corporate governance promotes the adoption of more efficient technologies and development of sectors more exposed to moral hazard. We use our model to study equity market liberalization, and we show that liberalizations facilitate entry and adoption of more productive technologies, especially in countries with good corporate governance.</description><author>Fulghieri, Paolo; Suominen, Matti</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Flow and Discount Rate Risk in Up and Down Markets: What Is Actually Priced?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Botshekan, Mahmoud; Kraeussl, Roman; Lucas, Andre
We test whether asymmetric preferences for losses versus gains affect the prices of cash flow versus discount rate risk. We construct a return decomposition distinguishing cash flow and discount rate betas in up and down markets. Using U.S. data, we find that downside cash flow and discount rate betas carry the largest premia. Downside cash flow risk is priced consistently across different samples, periods, and return decomposition methods. It is the only component of beta with significant out-of-sample predictive ability. Downside cash flow premia mainly occur for small stocks, while large stocks are compensated for symmetric cash-flow-related risk.</description><author>Botshekan, Mahmoud; Kraeussl, Roman; Lucas, Andre</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate Idiosyncratic Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, Geert; Hodrick, Robert J.; Zhang, Xiaoyan
We examine aggregate idiosyncratic volatility in 23 developed equity markets, measured using various methodologies. We find no evidence of upward trends after extending the sample to 2008. Instead, idiosyncratic volatility is well described by a stationary autoregressive process that occasionally switches into a higher-variance regime that has relatively short duration. We also document that idiosyncratic volatility is highly correlated across countries. Most of the time variation in idiosyncratic volatility can be attributed to variation in a growth opportunity proxy, total (U.S.) market volatility, and in most specifications, the variance premium, a business cycle sensitive risk indicator.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Hodrick, Robert J.; Zhang, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Principal Principle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, Sanjiv R.
I analyze optimal loan modification schemes in a stochastic home price and stochastic interest-rate environment. Lenders maximize loan values by managing the borrower's option to default on the loan and prepayment option. Given negative equity, controlling for the borrower's ability to pay, rate reductions and maturity extensions result in a higher probability of redefault by homeowners even after modification of their loans. In contrast, loan write-downs (the Principal Principle), not a favored recipe, are value maximizing for the lender. A shared-appreciation mortgage enhances the ability to pay, mitigates adverse selection, and reduces the present value of expected deadweight foreclosure costs.</description><author>Das, Sanjiv R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of Bank Regulation and Lender Location on Loan Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hao, Li; Nandy, Debarshi K.; Roberts, Gordon S.
We investigate how differences in regulation regarding banking-commerce integration and banking sector concentration influence loan spreads across 29 countries. Theoretical research posits conflicting effects based on agency costs, information asymmetry costs, and market power. Increased integration is associated with lower loan spreads in countries with low concentration, but moving to high levels of integration increases spreads in countries with high concentration. Starting from lower levels, an increase in integration is associated with an increase in informational efficiency that disappears at higher levels of integration. We also show that market concentration affects loan spreads differently under high-, medium-, and low-integration regimes.</description><author>Hao, Li; Nandy, Debarshi K.; Roberts, Gordon S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Content of Earnings Announcements: Evidence from After-Hours Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Christine X.; Likitapiwat, Tanakorn; McInish, Thomas H.
We study after-hours trading (AHT), price contributions, and price discovery following quarterly earnings announcements released outside of the normal trading hours. For Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P) 500 index stocks from 2004-2008, AHT is heightened on announcement days. A significant portion of the price change and price discovery occurs immediately after the earnings releases. Prices in AHT show a large degree of informational efficiency, further demonstrating the importance of price discovery in AHT. We also provide evidence suggesting that firms prefer after-hours earnings announcements, as trades are mainly from informed traders, and those trades are relied upon to convey information to the general public.</description><author>Jiang, Christine X.; Likitapiwat, Tanakorn; McInish, Thomas H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling the Cross Section of Stock Returns: A Model Pooling Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Doherty, Michael; Savin, N. E.; Tiwari, Ashish
Model selection (i.e., the choice of an asset pricing model to the exclusion of competing models) is an inherently misguided strategy when the true model is unavailable to the researcher. This paper illustrates the advantages of a model pooling approach in characterizing the cross section of stock returns. The optimal pool combines models using the log predictive score criterion, a measure of the out-of-sample performance of each model, and consistently outperforms the best individual model. The benefits to model pooling are most pronounced during periods of economic stress, and it is a valuable tool for asset allocation decisions.</description><author>O'Doherty, Michael; Savin, N. E.; Tiwari, Ashish</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Futures Cross-Hedging with a Stationary Basis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ankirchner, Stefan; Dimitroff, Georgi; Heyne, Gregor; Pigorsch, Christian
When managing risk, frequently only imperfect hedging instruments are at hand. We show how to optimally cross-hedge risk when the spread between the hedging instrument and the risk is stationary. For linear risk positions we derive explicit formulas for the hedge error, and for nonlinear positions we show how to obtain numerically efficient estimates. Finally, we demonstrate that even in cases with no clear-cut decision concerning the stationarity of the spread, it is better to allow for mean reversion of the spread rather than to neglect it.</description><author>Ankirchner, Stefan; Dimitroff, Georgi; Heyne, Gregor; Pigorsch, Christian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Desire to Acquire and IPO Long-Run Underperformance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brau, James C.; Couch, Robert B.; Sutton, Ninon K.
We analyze 3,547 initial public offerings (IPOs) from 1985 through 2003 to determine the impact of acquisition activity on long-run stock performance. The results show that IPOs that acquire within a year of going public significantly underperform for 1-through 5-year holding periods following the 1st year, whereas nonacquiring IPOs do not significantly underperform over these time frames. For example, the mean 3-year style-adjusted abnormal return is 15.6% for acquirers and 5.9% for nonacquirers. Our cross-sectional and calendar-time results suggest that the acquisition activity of newly public firms plays an important and previously unrecognized role in the long-run underperformance of IPOs.</description><author>Brau, James C.; Couch, Robert B.; Sutton, Ninon K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A New Method to Estimate Risk and Return of Nontraded Assets from Cash Flows: The Case of Private Equity Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Driessen, Joost; Lin, Tse-Chun; Phalippou, Ludovic
We develop a new methodology to estimate abnormal performance and risk exposure of nontraded assets from cash flows. Our methodology extends the standard internal rate of return approach to a dynamic setting. The small-sample properties are validated using a simulation study. We apply the method to a sample of 958 private equity funds. For venture capital funds, we find a high market beta and underperformance before and after fees. For buyout funds, we find a relatively low market beta and no evidence for outperformance. We find that self-reported net asset values significantly overstate fund values for mature and inactive funds.</description><author>Driessen, Joost; Lin, Tse-Chun; Phalippou, Ludovic</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Performance of Investment Bank-Affiliated Mutual Funds: Conflicts of Interest or Informational Advantage?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hao; Yan, Xuemin
Using a comprehensive sample of U.S. mutual funds from 1992 to 2004, we find strong evidence that investment bank-affiliated funds underperform unaffiliated funds. Consistent with the conflict of interest hypothesis, we find that affiliated funds hold disproportionately large amounts of stocks of their initial public offering and seasoned equity offering clients. Moreover, worse-performing clients are more likely to be held by affiliated funds. Our results are robust to alternative risk adjustments, portfolio weighting schemes, and regression methodologies. Overall, our findings are consistent with the idea that investment banks use affiliated funds to support underwriting business at the expense of fund shareholders.</description><author>Hao; Yan, Xuemin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Pension-Related Business Ties Influence Mutual Fund Proxy Voting? Evidence from Shareholder Proposals on Executive Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ashraf, Rasha; Jayaraman, Narayanan; Ryan, Harley E.
We examine the relation between mutual fund votes on shareholder executive compensation proposals and pension-related business ties between fund families and the firms. In unconditional tests, we find that fund families support management when they have pension ties to the firm. We find no relation when we stratify by fund family in conditional tests, which suggests that fund families with pension ties vote with management at both client and nonclient firms. We confirm this result in an analysis of nonclient firms. Overall, our results suggest that pension-related business ties influence fund families to vote with management at all firms.</description><author>Ashraf, Rasha; Jayaraman, Narayanan; Ryan, Harley E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity Mispricing and Leverage Adjustment Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Warr, Richard S.; Elliott, William B.; Koeter-Kant, Johanna; Oeztekin, Oezde
We find that equity mispricing impacts the speed at which firms adjust to their target leverage (TL) and does so in predictable ways depending on whether the firm is over-or underlevered. For example, firms that are above their TL and should therefore issue equity (or retire debt) adjust more rapidly toward their target when their equity is overvalued. However, when a firm is undervalued but needs to reduce leverage, the speed of adjustment is much slower. Our findings support the role of equity mispricing as an important factor that alters the cost of making capital structure adjustments.</description><author>Warr, Richard S.; Elliott, William B.; Koeter-Kant, Johanna; Oeztekin, Oezde</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-Term Effects of a Financial Crisis: Evidence from Cash Holdings of East Asian Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, Kyojik; Lee, Youngjoo
We investigate the long-term effect of the Asian financial crisis on corporate cash holdings in 8 East Asian countries. The Asian firms build up cash holdings by decreasing investment activities after the crisis. We find that the increase in cash holdings is not explained by changes in firm characteristics but by changes in the firms' demand function for cash, which indicates that the crisis has systematically changed the firms' cash-holding policies. Specifically, the firms' increased sensitivity to cash flow volatility is one of the main factors explaining the higher level of their cash holdings in the postcrisis period.</description><author>Song, Kyojik; Lee, Youngjoo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Log-Linear Return Approximation, Bubbles, and Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engsted, Tom; Pedersen, Thomas Q.; Tanggaard, Carsten
We study in detail the log-linear return approximation introduced by Campbell and Shiller (1988a). First, we derive an upper bound for the mean approximation error, given stationarity of the log dividend-price ratio. Next, we simulate various rational bubbles that have explosive conditional expectation, and we investigate the magnitude of the approximation error in those cases. We find that, surprisingly, the Campbell-Shiller approximation is very accurate even in the presence of large explosive bubbles. Only in very large samples do we find evidence that bubbles generate large approximation errors. Finally, we show that a bubble model in which expected returns are constant can explain the predictability of stock returns from the dividend-price ratio that many previous studies have documented.</description><author>Engsted, Tom; Pedersen, Thomas Q.; Tanggaard, Carsten</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Active Investing: Can Active Institutional Investors Remove Excess Comovement of Stock Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ye, Pengfei
This study uses Cremers and Petajisto's (2009) method to separate active institutional investors from passive ones and shows that active investors can alleviate the anomalous comovement of stock returns. Focusing on 2 events linked to the excess comovement anomaly, Standard &amp; Poor's 500 Index additions and stock splits, I find that if an event stock has more active institutional investors trading in the post-event period, the anomalous comovement effect disappears. In contrast, if an event stock experiences a massive exit of active investors, this anomaly persists. The exit of active institutional investors also results in a strong price synchronicity effect.</description><author>Ye, Pengfei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sell-Side Information Production in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhaohui; Wilhelm, William J.
We study decisions to sell nonexcludable private information in the presence of a trading opportunity. Sell-side agents heighten competition among agents who buy their signals to combine with their own for proprietary trading purposes and thereby promote financial market efficiency. This result holds even When the sell-side production technology is not unique. But sell-side information is subject to underinvestment if producers do not internalize the benefits. The model suggests that fee-based compensation for corporate advisory services diminishes this problem and that market efficiency is undermined by forces steering investment-banking resources toward proprietary trading.</description><author>Chen, Zhaohui; Wilhelm, William J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage Expectations and Bond Credit Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flannery, Mark J.; Nikolova, Stanislava; Oeztekin, Oezde
In an efficient market, spreads will reflect both the issuer's current risk and investors' expectations about how that risk might change over time. Collin-Dufresne and Goldstein (2001) show analytically that a firm's expected future leverage importantly influences the spread on its bonds. We use capital structure theory to construct proxies for investors' expectations about future leverage changes and find that these significantly affect bond yields, above and beyond the effect of contemporaneous leverage. Expectations under the trade-off, pecking order, and credit-rating theories of capital structure all receive empirical support, suggesting that investors view them as complementary when pricing corporate bonds.</description><author>Flannery, Mark J.; Nikolova, Stanislava; Oeztekin, Oezde</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Paying Attention: Overnight Returns and the Hidden Cost of Buying at the Open</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, Henk; Koch, Paul D.; Tuttle, Laura; Zhang, Ying Jenny
We find a strong tendency for positive returns during the overnight period followed by reversals during the trading day. This behavior is driven by an opening price that is high relative to intraday prices. It is concentrated among stocks that have recently attracted the attention of retail investors, it is more pronounced for stocks that are difficult to value and costly to arbitrage, and it is greater during periods of high overall retail investor sentiment. The additional implicit transaction costs for retail traders who buy high-attention stocks near the open frequently exceed the effective half spread.</description><author>Berkman, Henk; Koch, Paul D.; Tuttle, Laura; Zhang, Ying Jenny</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are CFOs' Trades More Informative Than CEOs' Trades?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Weimin; Shin, Yong-Chul; Francis, Bill B.
We investigate whether trades made by chief financial officers (CFOs) reveal more information about future stock returns than those by chief executive officers (CEOs). We find that CFOs earn statistically and economically higher abnormal returns following their purchases of company shares than CEOs. During 1992-2002, CFOs earned an average 12-month excess return that'is 5% higher than that by CEOs. The superior performance by CFOs occurs notwithstanding controls for risk factors and persists even after their trades are publicly disclosed. Further analysis shows that CFO purchases are associated with more positive future earnings surprises than CEO purchases, suggesting that CFOs incorporate better information about future earnings.</description><author>Wang, Weimin; Shin, Yong-Chul; Francis, Bill B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Prevalence of the Disposition Effect in Mutual Funds' Trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cici, Gjergji
U.S. equity mutual funds, on average, prefer realization of capital losses to capital gains. Nevertheless, a substantial fraction exhibits the disposition effect of realizing gains more readily than losses. My analysis suggests that learning effects have reduced the manifestation of the disposition effect over time, implying that academic research has influenced industry practices. When funds experience outflows and are managed by teams of portfolio managers, they are more susceptible to selling disproportionately more winners than losers. Disposition-driven behavior affects investment style, causing lower market betas and characteristics of value-oriented and contrarian styles, but has no observable effect on fund performance.</description><author>Cici, Gjergji</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneous Beliefs and Risk-Neutral Skewness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friesen, Geoffrey C.; Zhang, Yi; Zorn, Thomas S.
This study tests whether belief differences affect the cross-sectional variation of riskneutral skewness using data on firm-level stock options traded on the Chicago Board Options Exchange from 2003 to 2006. We find that stocks with greater belief differences have more negative skews, even after controlling for systematic risk and other firm-level variables known to affect skewness. Factor analysis identifies latent variables linked to risk and belief differences. The belief factor explains more variation in the risk-neutral skewness than the risk-based factor. Our results suggest that belief differences may be one of the unexplained firm-specific components affecting skewness.</description><author>Friesen, Geoffrey C.; Zhang, Yi; Zorn, Thomas S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic Return Volatility and the Information Quality Underlying Managerial Discretion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Changling; Huang, Alan Guoming; Jha, Ranjini
Variation in idiosyncratic return volatility from 1978 to 2009 is attributable to discretionary accrual volatility and the correlation between premanaged earnings and discretionary accruals reflective of information quality across firms. These results are robust to controls for firm operating uncertainty, growth options, business-cycle variations, and firm age and industry effects, and they highlight the importance of managerial discretion in determining idiosyncratic volatility.</description><author>Chen, Changling; Huang, Alan Guoming; Jha, Ranjini</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Customer Order Flow, Intermediaries, and Discovery of the Equilibrium Risk-Free Rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkveld, Albert J.; Sarkar, Asani; van der Wel, Michel
Macro announcements change the equilibrium risk-free rate. We find that Treasury prices reflect part of the impact instantaneously, but intermediaries rely on their customer order flow after the announcement to discover the full impact. This customer flow informativeness is strongest when analyst macro forecasts are most dispersed. The result holds for 30-year Treasury futures trading in both electronic and open-outcry markets. We further show that intermediaries benefit from privately recognizing informed customer flow, as their own-account trading profitability correlates with customer order access.</description><author>Menkveld, Albert J.; Sarkar, Asani; van der Wel, Michel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing in Talents: Manager Characteristics and Hedge Fund Performances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Haitao; Zhang, Xiaoyan; Zhao, Rui
Using a large sample of hedge fund manager characteristics, we provide one of the first comprehensive studies on the impact of manager characteristics, such as education and career concern, on hedge fund performances. We document differential ability among hedge fund managers in either generating risk-adjusted returns or running hedge funds as a business. In particular, we find that managers from higher-SAT (Scholastic Aptitude Test) undergraduate institutions tend to have higher raw and risk-adjusted returns, more inflows, and take fewer risks. Unlike mutual funds, we find a rather symmetric relation between hedge fund flows and past performance, and that hedge fund flows do not have a significant negative impact on future performance.</description><author>Li, Haitao; Zhang, Xiaoyan; Zhao, Rui</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Term Structure of Bond Market Liquidity and Its Implications for Expected Bond Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyenko, Ruslan; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Ukhov, Andrey
Previous studies of Treasury market illiquidity span short time periods and focus on particular maturities. In contrast, we study the time series of illiquidity for different maturities over an extended period of time. We also compare time-series determinants of on-the-run and off-the-run illiquidity. Illiquidity increases and the difference between spreads of long- and short-term bonds significantly widens during recessions, suggesting a "flight to liquidity," wherein investors shift into the more liquid short-term bonds during economic contractions. Macroeconomic variables such as inflation and federal funds rates forecast off-the-run illiquidity significantly but have only modest forecasting ability for on-the-run illiquidity. Bond returns across maturities are forecastable by off-the-run but not on-the-run bond illiquidity. Thus, off-the-run illiquidity, by reflecting macro shocks first, is the primary source of the liquidity premium in the Treasury market.</description><author>Goyenko, Ruslan; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Ukhov, Andrey</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Patterns in the Timing of Corporate Event Waves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rau, P. Raghavendra; Stouraitis, Aris
Corporate events happen in waves. In this paper, we examine the timing patterns of 5 different types of corporate event waves (new stock and seasoned equity issues, stock- and cash-financed acquisitions, and stock repurchases) using a comprehensive data set of more than 151,000 corporate transactions over the 25-year period from 1980 to 2004. We document a distinctive pattern, previously not found in the literature, in the way stock-related waves form. Corporate waves seem to start with new issue waves (seasoned equity offering preceding initial public offering waves), followed by stock-financed merger waves, followed in turn by repurchase waves. Our results hold over separate decades and across industries. Our results seem consistent with both the neoclassical efficiency hypothesis and the misvaluation hypothesis, and there are distinct periods when one or the other appears dominant.</description><author>Rau, P. Raghavendra; Stouraitis, Aris</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance and Institutional Ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Kee H.; Zhang, Hao
In this study we examine the relation between corporate governance and institutional ownership. Our empirical results show that the fraction of a company's shares that are held by institutional investors increases with the quality of its governance structure. In a similar vein, we show that the proportion of institutions that hold a firm's shares increases with its governance quality. Our results are robust to different estimation methods and alternative model specifications. These results are consistent with the conjecture that institutional investors gravitate to stocks of companies with good governance structure to meet fiduciary responsibility as well as to minimize monitoring and exit costs.</description><author>Chung, Kee H.; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholders' Say on Pay: Does It Create Value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Jie; Walkling, Ralph A.
Congress and activists recently proposed giving shareholders a say (vote) on executive pay. We find that when the House passed the Say-on-Pay Bill, the market reaction was significantly positive for firms with high abnormal chief executive officer (CEO) compensation, with low pay-for-performance sensitivity, and responsive to shareholder pressure. However, activist-sponsored say-on-pay proposals target large firms, not those with excessive CEO pay, poor governance, or poor performance. The market reacts negatively to labor-sponsored proposal, announcements and positively when these proposals are defeated. Our findings suggest that say-on-pay creates value for companies with inefficient compensation but can destroy value for others.</description><author>Cai, Jie; Walkling, Ralph A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Are Derivative Warrants More Expensive Than Options? An Empirical Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Gang; Zhang, Chu
Derivative warrants typically have higher prices than do otherwise identical options. Using data from the Hong Kong market during 2002-2007, we show that the price difference reflects the liquidity premium of derivative warrants over options. Newly issued derivative warrants are much more liquid than options with similar terms. As a result, long-term derivative warrants are preferred by traders who trade frequently. In spite of their higher prices, short-term returns on long-term derivative warrants are, in fact, higher than the hypothetical short-term returns on options. The differences in price and liquidity measures decline as the contracts get closer to maturity.</description><author>Li, Gang; Zhang, Chu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency Costs of Free Cash Flow and the Effect of Shareholder Rights on the Implied Cost of Equity Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Kevin C. W.; Chen, Zhihong; Wei, K. C. John
In this paper, we examine the effect of shareholder rights on reducing the cost of equity and the impact of agency problems from free cash flow (FCF) on this effect. We find that firms with strong shareholder rights have a significantly lower implied cost of equity after controlling for risk factors, price momentum, analysts' forecast biases, and industry and year effects than do firms with weak shareholder rights. Further analysis shows that the effect of shareholder rights on reducing the cost of equity is significantly stronger for firms with more severe agency problems from FCFs.</description><author>Chen, Kevin C. W.; Chen, Zhihong; Wei, K. C. John</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Underwriters and the Marketing of Seasoned Equity Offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Rongbing; Zhang, Donghang
Using a sample of 2,281 seasoned equity offerings (SEOs) from 1995 to 2004, we show that the marketing of securities is important to issuers. The number of managing underwriters for an SEO is negatively related to the offer price discount, especially when the relative offer size is large and the stock return volatility is high. Larger investor networks of comanaging underwriters also lower offer price discounts. We argue that the evidence is supportive of the marketing hypothesis: The underwriters' marketing efforts can lower the offer price discount by shifting up and flattening the demand curve of an SEO.</description><author>Huang, Rongbing; Zhang, Donghang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Has the Propensity to Pay Out Declined?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grullon, Gustavo; Paye, Bradley; Underwood, Shane; Weston, James P.
Recent studies document both a significant decline in firms' propensity to pay dividends and a significant increase in firms' propensity to repurchase shares and issue equity over the past 30 years. In this paper we test whether firms' net cash disbursements to equity holders have declined in a pattern similar to firms' propensity to pay dividends. Contrary to the evidence using dividends, we find no evidence that the conditional propensity to distribute net cash to equity holders has declined over the past 3 decades. Surprisingly, we find that, conditional on firm characteristics, net payout yields have been increasing over time.</description><author>Grullon, Gustavo; Paye, Bradley; Underwood, Shane; Weston, James P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor Unions, Operating Flexibility, and the Cost of Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Huafeng Jason; Kacperczyk, Marcin; Ortiz-Molina, Hernan
We study whether the constraints on firms' operations imposed by labor unions affect firms' costs of equity. The cost of equity is significantly higher for firms in more unionized industries. This effect holds after controlling for several industry and firm characteristics, is robust to endogeneity concerns, and is not driven by omitted variables. Moreover, the unionization premium is stronger when unions face a more favorable bargaining environment and is highly countercyclical. Unionization is also positively related to various measures of operating leverage. Our findings suggest that labor unions increase firms' costs of equity by decreasing firms' operating flexibility.</description><author>Chen, Huafeng Jason; Kacperczyk, Marcin; Ortiz-Molina, Hernan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value-Maximizing Managers, Value-Increasing Mergers, and Overbidding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akdogu, Evrim
Some acquisitions can be viewed as the quickest means to obtain a scarce resource required for restructuring in response to an economic shock. Such acquisitions can give the acquirer a competitive edge and hurt its competitors. In this paper, I first show that if a firm will be adversely affected by a competitor's acquisition, then it can rationally "overpay" for the target to avoid this outcome within a value-maximizing framework due to industry equilibrium effects. Next, I show that depending on the level of anticipation by the market, the magnitude of the cost of losing, and the competition between bidders, an acquirer can earn negative payoffs at the announcement of such an acquisition. Even though the merger is the best decision given the circumstances, negative returns incorporate the understanding that the target is a necessary resource to survive in this changing environment, losing it to a rival is costly, and there is a positive probability that the bidder may not win or win by paying more than the synergy value of the target. Finally, I extend the model to include 2 targets that become available sequentially to multiple bidders and show that when there are alternatives available for the target's resources, overbidding subsides.</description><author>Akdogu, Evrim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Irrational Diversification: An Examination of Individual Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baltussen, Guido; Post, Gerrit T.
We study individual portfolio choice in a laboratory experiment and find strong evidence for heuristic behavior. The subjects tend to focus on the marginal distribution of an asset, while largely ignoring its diversification benefits. They follow a conditional 1/n diversification heuristic as they exclude the assets with an "unattractive" marginal distribution and divide the available funds equally between the remaining "attractive" assets. This strategy is applied even if it leads to allocations that are dominated in terms of first-order stochastic dominance and is clearly irrational. In line with these findings, we find that framing and problem presentation have substantial influence on portfolio decisions.</description><author>Baltussen, Guido; Post, Gerrit T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Time-Varying Systematic Risk of Carry Trade Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christiansen, Charlotte; Ranaldo, Angelo; Soederlind, Paul
We explain the currency carry trade (CT) performance using an asset pricing model in which factor loadings are regime dependent rather than constant. Empirical results show that a typical CT strategy has much higher exposure to the stock market and is mean reverting in regimes of high foreign exchange volatility. The findings are robust to various extensions. Our regime-dependent pricing model provides significantly smaller pricing errors than a traditional model. Thus, the CT performance is better explained by a time-varying systematic risk that increases in volatile markets, suggesting a partial resolution of the uncovered interest parity puzzle.</description><author>Christiansen, Charlotte; Ranaldo, Angelo; Soederlind, Paul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivatives Use and Risk Taking: Evidence from the Hedge Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yong
This paper examines the use of derivatives and its relation with risk taking in the hedge fund industry. In a large sample of hedge funds, 71% of the funds trade derivatives. After controlling for fund strategies and characteristics, derivatives users on average exhibit lower fund risks (e.g., market risk, downside risk, and event risk), such risk reduction is especially pronounced for directional-style funds. Further, derivatives users engage less in risk shifting and are less likely to liquidate in a poor market state. However, the flow-performance relation suggests that investors do not differentiate derivatives users when making investing decisions.</description><author>Chen, Yong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor-Focused Corporate Governance: Evidence from Mergers and Acquisitions in Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mehrotra, Vikas; van Schaik, Dimitri; Spronk, Jaap; Steenbeek, Onno
Mergers in Japan have the dubious distinction of not creating wealth for shareholders of target firms, in sharp contrast to what occurs in much of the rest of the world. Using a sample of 91 mergers from 1982 through 2003 we document several distinctive features of the merger market in Japan: Mergers tend to be countercyclical and appear to be driven chiefly by creditor concerns. In particular, where the merging firms share a common main bank, we find that merger gains are lower. Overall, our results point to a market that is distinctly less shareholder focused than that in the U.S., and a market where creditors play an important, perhaps dominant, role in corporate governance.</description><author>Mehrotra, Vikas; van Schaik, Dimitri; Spronk, Jaap; Steenbeek, Onno</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Traders Choose to Trade Anonymously?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Putnins, Talis J.; Tang, Kar Mei
This paper examines the use, determinants, and impact of anonymous orders in a market where disclosure of broker identity in the trading screen is voluntary. We find that most trading occurs nonanonymously, contrary to prior literature that suggests liquidity gravitates to anonymous markets. By strategically using anonymity when it is beneficial, traders reduce their execution costs. Traders select anonymity based on various factors including order source, order size and aggressiveness, time of day, liquidity, and expected execution costs. Finally, we report how anonymous orders affect market quality and discuss implications for market design.</description><author>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Putnins, Talis J.; Tang, Kar Mei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous Labor/Leisure/Investment Choice under Time Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, Dong-Hyun; Yoon, Sun-Joong
We posit the opportunity cost of time required to manage risky investments, including conducting research and performance monitoring, as a potential explanation for the equity premium puzzle. An economic agent, who should allocate a limited amount of time to labor, leisure, and risky investment, is subject to the opportunity time cost of investment activity, which is foregone labor or leisure. Our model envisages its impact on equity premium and volatility in the presence of such a time constraint, in particular; with closed-form solutions to the risky asset returns, volatility, and risk-free rate in a simple equilibrium framework wherein agents have log utility. The model is shown to yield excess return and volatility consistent with historical values observed in the U.S. stock market, even with a small amount of time cost. In addition, the model enables us to sort out the impact of endogenous labor/leisure choice on return dynamics by comparing it with the exogenous labor income case.</description><author>Ahn, Dong-Hyun; Yoon, Sun-Joong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large Foreign Ownership and Firm-Level Stock Return Volatility in Emerging Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Donghui; Nguyen, Quang N.; Pham, Peter K.; Wei, Steven X.
This study constructs a firm-level measure of large foreign ownership (LFO) and investigates its impact on stock return volatility in 31 emerging markets. We find a negative relationship between LFO and volatility, even after controlling for potential endogeneity and the impact of major domestic shareholders. This suggests a stabilizing role of LFO in emerging markets, which is consistent with previous suggestions in the literature on the strong commitments and potential monitoring role of large foreign shareholders. Overall, our study highlights the importance of recognizing the heterogeneity among foreign investors and the benefits of large foreign shareholders to emerging stock markets.</description><author>Li, Donghui; Nguyen, Quang N.; Pham, Peter K.; Wei, Steven X.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance Problems in Closely Held Corporations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagar, Venky; Petroni, Kathy; Wolfenzon, Daniel
A major governance problem in closely held corporations is the majority shareholders' expropriation of minority shareholders. As a solution, legal and finance research recommends that the main shareholder surrender some control to minority shareholders via ownership rights. We test this proposition on a large data set of closely held corporations. We find that shared-ownership firms report a substantially larger return on assets and lower expense-to-sales ratios. These findings are robust to institutionally motivated corrections for endogeneity of ownership structure. We provide evidence on the presence of governance problems and the effectiveness of shared ownership as a solution in settings characterized by illiquidity of ownership.</description><author>Nagar, Venky; Petroni, Kathy; Wolfenzon, Daniel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO Timing, Buyout Sponsors' Exit Strategies, and Firm Performance of RLBOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Jerry X.
This paper studies the impact of buyout sponsors' initial public offering (IPO) timing on the leveraged buyout (LBO) restructuring process and subsequent exit strategies. I find that LBO duration is negatively related to hot IPO market conditions. Further, following IPOs, reverse leveraged buyouts (RLBOs) with shorter LBO duration experience greater deterioration of performance and higher probability of bankruptcy. This suggests that sponsors' efforts to enhance operating efficiency succumb to market timing. IPO timing does not affect sponsors' exit strategies and monitoring post IPO. Sponsors keep an active long-run presence with more reputable sponsors who are more likely to exit by facilitating takeovers.</description><author>Cao, Jerry X.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Derivatives on Firm Risk and Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Brown, Gregory W.; Conrad, Jennifer
Using a large sample of nonfinancial firms from 47 countries, we examine the effect of derivative use on firm risk and value. We control for endogeneity by matching users and nonusers on the basis of their propensity to use derivatives. We also use a new technique to estimate the effect of omitted variable bias on our inferences. We find strong evidence that the use of financial derivatives reduces both total risk and systematic risk. The effect of derivative use on firm value is positive but more sensitive to endogeneity and omitted variable concerns. However, using derivatives is associated with significantly higher value, abnormal returns, and larger profits during the economic downturn in 2001-2002, suggesting that firms are hedging downside risk.</description><author>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Brown, Gregory W.; Conrad, Jennifer</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the Effects of Large Shareholders Using a Geographic Instrument</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Bo; Cronqvist, Henrik; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger
Large shareholders may play an important role for firm performance and policies, but identifying this empirically presents a challenge due to the endogeneity of ownership structures. We develop and test an empirical framework that allows us to separate selection from treatment effects of large shareholders. Individual blockholders tend to hold blocks in public firms located close to where they reside. Using this empirical observation, we develop an instrument (the density of wealthy individuals near a firm's headquarters) for the presence of large, nonmanagerial individual shareholders in firms. These shareholders have a large impact on firms, controlling for selection effects.</description><author>Becker, Bo; Cronqvist, Henrik; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Lobbying and Fraud Detection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Frank; Yu, Xiaoyun
This paper examines the relation between corporate lobbying and fraud detection. Using data on corporate lobbying expenses between 1998 and 2004, and a sample of large frauds detected during the same period, we find that firms' lobbying activities make a significant difference in fraud detection: Compared to nonlobbying firms, on average, firms that lobby have a significantly lower hazard rate of being detected for fraud, evade fraud detection 117 days longer, and are 38% less likely to be detected by regulators. In addition, fraudulent firms on average spend 77% more on lobbying than nonfraudulent firms, and they spend 29% more on lobbying during their fraudulent periods than during nonfraudulent periods. The delay in detection leads to a greater distortion in resource allocation during fraudulent periods. It also allows managers to sell more of their shares.</description><author>Yu, Frank; Yu, Xiaoyun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Investors See through Mistakes in Reported Earnings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bardos, Katsiaryna Salavei; Golec, Joseph; Harding, John P.
This study investigates whether investors see through materially misstated earnings, and whether they anticipate earnings restatements. For firms that restate at least one annual report, we find that investors are misled by mistakes in reported earnings at the time of initial earnings announcements. Investors react positively to the component of the favorable earnings surprise that will subsequently be restated, and they attach the same valuation to it as to the true earnings surprise. We also find that investors anticipate the subsequent downward restatements and start marking stock prices down several months before a restatement announcement, so that the full impact of a restatement is about three times as large as the restatement announcement effect. Indeed, we show that investors punish restating firms because the stock price gains that shareholders enjoy when firms initially announce overstated earnings are more than reversed by the time of the restatement announcement.</description><author>Bardos, Katsiaryna Salavei; Golec, Joseph; Harding, John P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Loans with Chinese Characteristics: Some Evidence on Inside Debt in a State-Controlled Banking System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bailey, Warren; Huang, Wei; Yang, Zhishu
We study a transitional economy where state-controlled banks make loan decisions based on noisy inside information on prospective borrowers, and may lend to avert unemployment and social instability. In China, poor financial performance and high managerial expenses increase the likelihood of obtaining a bank loan, and bank loan approval predicts poor subsequent borrower performance. Negative event study responses occur at bank loan announcements, particularly for borrowers measuring poorly on quality and creditworthiness, or for lenders or borrowers involved in litigation regarding loans. Our results highlight dilemmas in a state-led financial system and the local stock market's sophistication in interpreting news.</description><author>Bailey, Warren; Huang, Wei; Yang, Zhishu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Extended Macro-Finance Model with Financial Factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dewachter, Hans; Iania, Leonardo
This paper extends the benchmark macro-finance (MF) model by introducing, next to the standard macroeconomic factors, additional liquidity-related and return-forecasting factors. Liquidity factors are obtained from a decomposition of the money market spread, while the return-forecasting (risk premium) factor is extracted by imposing a single-factor structure on the 1-period expected excess holding return. The model is estimated on U.S. data using Markov chain Monte Carlo techniques. Two findings stand out. First, the model significantly outperforms most structural and nonstructural MF yield curve models in terms of the cross-sectional fit of the yield curve. Second, financial shocks have a statistically and economically significant impact on the yield curve.</description><author>Dewachter, Hans; Iania, Leonardo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutions and Corporate Investment: Evidence from Investment-Implied Return on Capital in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Qiao; Siu, Alan
We assess the impact of institutions on Chinese firms' corporate investment in an investment Euler equation framework. We allow the variables measuring institutions to affect the rate at which firm managers discount future investment payoffs. Applying generalized method of moments estimators to large samples of Chinese firms, we estimate the stochastic discount rates derived from actual investment and examine how they vary across institutional variables. We document robust evidence that ownership is the primary institutional factor affecting corporate investment in China. The derived discount rate for a nonstate firm is approximately 10 percentage points higher than that of an otherwise equal state firm. State firms tend to use higher discount rates to invest after they are partially privatized. We also find that firms with higher levels of corporate governance use higher discount rates to make investment.</description><author>Liu, Qiao; Siu, Alan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPOs versus Acquisitions and the Valuation Premium Puzzle: A Theory of Exit Choice by Entrepreneurs and Venture Capitalists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bayar, Onur; Chemmanur, Thomas J.
We analyze a private firm's choice of exit mechanism between initial public offerings (IPOs) and acquisitions, and we provide a resolution to the "IPO valuation premium puzzle." The private firm is run by an entrepreneur and a venture capitalist (VC) (insiders) who desire to exit partially from the firm. A crucial factor driving their exit choice is competition in the product market: While a stand-alone firm has to fend for itself after going public, an acquirer is able to provide considerable support to the firm in product market competition. A second factor is the difference in information asymmetry characterizing the two exit mechanisms. Finally, the private benefits of control accruing to the entrepreneur post-exit and the bargaining power of outside investors versus firm insiders are also different across the two mechanisms. We analyze two situations: the first, where the entrepreneur can make the exit choice alone (independent of the VC), and the second, where the entrepreneur can make the exit choice only with the concurrence of the VC. We derive a number of testable implications regarding insiders' exit choice between IPOs and acquisitions and about the IPO valuation premium puzzle.</description><author>Bayar, Onur; Chemmanur, Thomas J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Two Sides of Derivatives Usage: Hedging and Speculating with Interest Rate Swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernenko, Sergey; Faulkender, Michael
Existing cross-sectional findings on nonfinancial firms' use of derivatives that are usually interpreted as the result of hedging may alternatively be due to speculation. Panel data examinations can distinguish between derivatives practices that endure over time and are therefore more likely to result from hedging, and those that are more transient, thus more consistent with speculation. Our decomposition results indicate that hedging of interest rate risk is concentrated among high-investment firms, consistent with costly external finance. Simultaneously, firms appear to use interest rate swaps to manage earnings and to speculate when their executive compensation contracts are more performance sensitive.</description><author>Chernenko, Sergey; Faulkender, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Scope and Drivers of the Asset Growth Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lipson, Marc L.; Mortal, Sandra; Schill, Michael J.
Recent papers have debated whether the negative correlation between measures of firm asset growth and subsequent returns is of little importance since it applies only to small firms, is justified as compensation for risk, or is evidence of mispricing. We show that the asset growth effect is pervasive, and evidence to the contrary arises due to specification choices; that one measure of asset growth, the change in total assets, largely subsumes the explanatory power of other measures; that the ability of asset growth to explain either the cross section of returns or the time series of factor loadings is linked to firm idiosyncratic volatility (IVOL); that the return effect is concentrated around earnings announcements; and that analyst forecasts are systematically higher than realized earnings for faster growing firms. In general, there appears to be no asset growth effect in firms with low IVOL. Our findings are consistent with a mispricing-based explanation for the asset growth effect in which arbitrage costs allow the effect to persist.</description><author>Lipson, Marc L.; Mortal, Sandra; Schill, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Evidence on the Relation between the Enterprise Multiple and Average Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loughran, Tim; Wellman, Jay W.
Practitioners increasingly use the enterprise multiple (EM) as a valuation measure. EM is (equity value + debt + preferred stock cash) / (EBITDA). We document that EM is a strong determinant of stock returns. Following Fama and French (1993) and Chen. Novy-Marx, and Zhang (201 0), we create an EM factor that generates a return premium of 5.28% per year. We interpret EM as a proxy for the discount rate. Firms with low EM values appear to have higher discount rates and higher subsequent stock returns than firms with high EM values.</description><author>Loughran, Tim; Wellman, Jay W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Manager Characteristics and Capital Structure: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhagat, Sanjai; Bolton, Brian; Subramanian, Ajay
We investigate the effects of manager characteristics on capital structure in a structural model. We implement the manager's optimal contracts through financial securities that lead to a dynamic capital structure, which reflects the effects of taxes, bankruptcy costs, and manager-shareholder agency conflicts. Long-term debt declines with the manager's ability, inside equity stake, and the firm's long-term risk, but increases with its short-term risk. Short-term debt declines with the manager's ability, increases with her equity ownership, and declines with short-term risk. We show support for these implications in our empirical analysis.</description><author>Bhagat, Sanjai; Bolton, Brian; Subramanian, Ajay</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Determinants of Operational Risk in U.S. Financial Institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernobai, Anna; Jorion, Philippe; Yu, Fan
We examine the incidence of operational losses among U.S. financial institutions using publicly reported loss data from 1980 to 2005. We show that most operational losses can be traced to a breakdown of internal control, and that firms suffering from these losses tend to be younger and more complex, and have higher credit risk, more antitakeover provisions, and chief executive officers (CEOs) with higher stock option holdings and bonuses relative to salary. These findings highlight the correlation between operational risk and credit risk, as well as the role of corporate governance and proper managerial incentives in mitigating operational risk.</description><author>Chernobai, Anna; Jorion, Philippe; Yu, Fan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Innovation in Emerging Markets: The Role of Finance, Governance, and Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayyagari, Meghana; Demirguec-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav
We investigate the firm characteristics associated with innovation in over 19,000 firms across 47 developing economies. While existing finance literature on innovation is limited to large public firms in developed markets such as the United States, our database includes public and private firms, and small and medium-sized enterprises. We define innovation broadly to include introduction of new products and technologies, knowledge transfers, and new production processes. We find that access to external financing is associated with greater firm innovation. Further, having highly educated managers, ownership by families, individuals, or managers, and exposure to foreign competition is associated with greater firm innovation.</description><author>Ayyagari, Meghana; Demirguec-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture Capital Reputation, Post-IPO Performance, and Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnan, C. N. V.; Ivanov, Vladimir I.; Masulis, Ronald W.; Singh, Ajai K.
We examine the association of a venture capital (VC) firm's reputation with the post-initial public offering (IPO) long-run performance of its portfolio firms. We find that VC reputation measured by the past market share of VC-backed IPOs, has significant positive as-formance sociations with long-run firm performance measures. While more reputable VCs initially select better-quality firms, more reputable VCs continue to be associated with superior long-run performance, even after controlling for VC selectivity. We find that more rep- utable VCs exhibit more active post-involvement in the corporate governance of their portfolio firms, and this contined VC involvement positively influences post-IPO firm performance.</description><author>Krishnan, C. N. V.; Ivanov, Vladimir I.; Masulis, Ronald W.; Singh, Ajai K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where Did All the Dollars Go? The Effect of Cash Flows on Capital and Asset Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dasgupta, Sudipto; Noe, Thomas H.; Wang, Zhen
This paper documents the short- and long-term balance sheet effect of cash flows. We show that cash savings in the short run and debt reduction in both the short and the long run account for a substantial fraction of cash flow use. Although, in the long run, investment exhibits substantial sensitivity to cash flows, investment does not absorb the entire cash flow shock. In fact, the tighter the financial constraints, the smaller the fraction of cash flow absorbed by investment and the more by leverage reduction. Firms stage their response to increases in cash flow, delaying investment while building up cash stocks and reducing leverage. These results suggest that much of the short-run economic effect of cash flow shocks to the corporate sector may be channeled into the corporate debt market rather than the capital goods market, especially when financing constraints tighten.</description><author>Dasgupta, Sudipto; Noe, Thomas H.; Wang, Zhen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Margins and Hedge Fund Contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dudley, Evan; Nimalendran, Mahendrarajah
Funding risk measures the extent to which a fund can borrow money by posting collateral. Using a novel measure of funding risk based on futures margins, we are able to empirically identify the mechanism by which changes in funding risk affect the likelihood of contagion. An increase in margins of the order of magnitude observed during the subprime crisis increases the probability of contagion among certain types of funds by up to 34%. Our analysis shows that some types of hedge funds are more vulnerable to contagion than others. Our results also suggest that policies that limit the magnitude of changes in margins over short periods of time may reduce the likelihood of contagion among hedge funds.</description><author>Dudley, Evan; Nimalendran, Mahendrarajah</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Purchasing IPOs with Commissions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, Michael A.; Irvine, Paul; Puckett, Andy
We find direct evidence that institutions increase round-trip stock trades, increase average commissions per share, and pay unusually high commissions on some trades in order to send abnormally high commissions to the lead underwriters of profitable initial public offerings (IPOs). These excess commission payments are a particularly effective way for transient investors to receive lucrative WO allocations. Our results suggest that the underwriter's concern for their long-term client relationships limits the payment-for-IPO practice. We estimate that abnormal commission payments are large for the most profitable issues, and that an additional $1 excess commission payment to the lead underwriter results in $2.21 in investor profits from allocated shares.</description><author>Goldstein, Michael A.; Irvine, Paul; Puckett, Andy</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Firms Form New Banking Relationships?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Udell, Gregory F.; Yerramilli, Vijay
Using a large loan sample from 1990 to 2006, we examine why firms form new banking relationships. Small public firms that do not have existing relationships with large banks are more likely to form new banking relationships. On average, firms obtain higher loan amounts when they form new banking relationships, while small firms also experience an increase in sales growth, capital expenditure, leverage, analyst coverage, and public debt issuance subsequently. Our findings suggest that firms form new banking relationships to expand their access to credit and capital market services, and highlight an important cost of exclusive banking relationships.</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Udell, Gregory F.; Yerramilli, Vijay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Merger-Driven IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsieh, Jim; Lyandres, Evgeny; Zhdanov, Alexei
We propose a model that links a firm's decision to go public with its subsequent takeover strategy. A private bidder does not know a firm's true valuation, which affects its gain from a potential takeover. Consequently, a private bidder pursues a suboptimal restructuring policy. An alternative route is to complete an initial public offering (IPO) first. An IPO reduces valuation uncertainty, leading to a more efficient acquisition strategy, therefore enhancing firm value. We calibrate the model using data on IPOs and mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As). The resulting comparative statics generate several novel qualitative and quantitative predictions, which complement the predictions of other theories linking IPOs and M&amp;As. For example, the time it takes a newly public firm to attempt an acquisition of another firm is expected to increase in the degree of valuation uncertainty prior to the firm's IPO and in the cost of going public, and it is expected to decrease in the valuation surprise realized at the time of the IPO. We find strong empirical support for the model's predictions.</description><author>Hsieh, Jim; Lyandres, Evgeny; Zhdanov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor Coordination, Liquidation Timing, and Debt Valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruche, Max
This paper derives closed-form solutions for values of debt and equity in a continuous-time structural model in which the demands of creditors to be repaid cause a firm to be put into bankruptcy. This allows discussion of the effect of creditor coordination in recovering money on the values of debt, equity, and the firm, as well as on optimal capital structure. The effects of features of bankruptcy codes that prevent coordination failures between creditors, such as automatic stays and preference law, are also considered. The model suggests that such features, while preventing coordination failures, can decrease welfare.</description><author>Bruche, Max</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing Two Heterogeneous Trees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branger, Nicole; Schlag, Christian; Wu, Lue
We consider a Lucas-type exchange economy with two heterogeneous stocks (trees) and a representative investor with constant relative risk aversion. The dividend process for one stock follows a geometric Brownian motion with constant and known parameters. The expected dividend growth rate for the other tree is stochastic and in general unobservable, although there may be a signal from which the investor can learn about its current value. We find that the equilibrium quantities in our model significantly depend on the information structure and on the level of risk aversion. While an observable stochastic drift mainly makes the economy more risky, a latent expected growth rate process with learning significantly changes the equilibrium price-dividend ratios, price reactions to dividend and drift innovations, expected returns, volatilities, correlations, and differences between the stocks. These effects are the more pronounced the more risk averse the representative investor.</description><author>Branger, Nicole; Schlag, Christian; Wu, Lue</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend Increases and Initiations and Default Risk in Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charitou, Andreas; Lambertides, Neophytos; Theodoulou, Giorgos
This study extends the Grullon, Michaely, and Swaminathan (2002) analysis by incorporating default risk. Using data for firms that either increased or initiated cash dividend payments during the 23-year period 1986-2008, we find reduction in default risk. This reduction is shown to be a priced risk factor beyond the Fama and French (1993) risk measures, and it explains the dividend payment decision and the positive market reaction around dividend increases and initiations. Further analysis reveals that the reduction in default risk is a significant factor in explaining the 3-year excess returns following dividend increases and initiations.</description><author>Charitou, Andreas; Lambertides, Neophytos; Theodoulou, Giorgos</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demographic Trends, the Dividend-Price Ratio, and the Predictability of Long-Run Stock Market Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Favero, Carlo A.; Gozluklu, Arie E.; Tamoni, Andrea
This paper documents the existence of a slowly evolving trend in the log dividend-price ratio, DP(t), determined by a demographic variable, MY(t): the middle-aged to young ratio. Deviations of DP(t) from this long-run component explain transitory but persistent fluctuations in stock market returns. The relation between MY(t) and DP(t) is a prediction of an overlapping generation model. The joint significance of MY and DP(t) in long-horizon forecasting regressions for market returns explains the mixed evidence on the ability of DP(t) to predict stock returns and provide a model-based interpretation of statistical corrections for breaks in the mean of this financial ratio.</description><author>Favero, Carlo A.; Gozluklu, Arie E.; Tamoni, Andrea</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Commonality between CEO and Divisional Managers in Internal Capital Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaspar, Jose-Miguel; Massa, Massimo
We study the role played by the informal links, or "connections," between the chief executive officer (CEO) and the divisional managers of conglomerate organizations. Using data on a large sample of multisegment U.S. corporations from 1996 to 2004, we show that segments run by connected managers receive more investment and exhibit lower sensitivity to cash flow shortfalls (and exhibit higher sensitivity to other segments' cash flow). At the firm level, having more connected managers presiding over segments with high Tobin's Q improves resource allocation and increases firm value. These findings are consistent with the hypothesis that the mutual trust associated with connections reduces the need for wasteful reallocation of resources across divisions of conglomerate firms.</description><author>Gaspar, Jose-Miguel; Massa, Massimo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Methods for Inference in Long-Horizon Regressions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hjalmarsson, Erik
I develop new results for long-horizon predictive regressions with overlapping observations. 1 show that rather than using autocorrelation robust standard errors, the standard t-statistic can simply be divided by the square root of the forecasting horizon to correct for the effects of the overlap in the data. Further, when the regressors are persistent and endogenous, the long-run ordinary least squares (OLS) estimator suffers from the same problems as the short-run OLS estimator, and it is shown how similar corrections and test procedures as those proposed for the short-run case can also be implemented in the long run. An empirical application to stock return predictability shows that, contrary to many popular beliefs, evidence of predictability does not typically become stronger at longer forecasting horizons.</description><author>Hjalmarsson, Erik</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Renewing Assets with Uncertain Revenues and Operating Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adkins, Roger; Paxson, Dean
We study optimal replacement and abandonment decisions for real assets, when both revenues and costs are uncertain and deteriorate with age. We develop an implicit representation of the renewal boundary as the solution to a set of simultaneous equations. This quasi-analytical method has the merit of computational ease and transparency. We show that the correlation between revenues and operating costs has a significant influence on the renewal boundary, and that the increase in revenue immediately following a renewal has a greater relative influence on the boundary than either operating cost or renewal cost. The quasi-analytical method is sufficiently flexible to deal with other real option models involving 2 variables.</description><author>Adkins, Roger; Paxson, Dean</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysts' Incentives to Produce Industry-Level versus Firm-Specific Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Mark H.
Using stock returns around recommendation changes to measure the information produced by analysts, I find that analysts produce more firm-specific than industry-level information. Analysts produce more firm-specific information on stocks with higher idiosyncratic return volatilities. The amount of industry information produced by analysts increases with the absolute value of the stock's industry beta and decreases with the stock's idiosyncratic volatility. Other stocks in the industry also respond to the recommendation change, and the magnitude of the response increases with the absolute value of the industry beta of the recommended stock and that of other stocks in the industry. I also offer results on how investors may use analyst research more effectively and potentially improve their investment performance.</description><author>Liu, Mark H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Global Rise of the Value-Weighted Portfolio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Galpin, Neal
We first develop a theory-based metric to judge the popularity of value weighting in a stock market. We then use our metric to document that although value weighting is less popular in emerging markets than in developed markets, its popularity is increasing almost everywhere. Finally, as we have better data for the United States, we explore why value weighting is becoming more popular in the United States.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Galpin, Neal</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Dynamics and Cross-Autocorrelations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, Tarun; Sarkar, Asani; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
This paper examines the relation between information transmission and cross-autocorrelations. We present a simple Model, where informed trading is transmitted from large to small stocks with a lag. In equilibrium, large stock illiquidity induced by informed trading portends stronger cross-autocorrelations. Empirically, we find that the lead-lag relation increases with lagged large stock illiquidity. Further, the lead from large stock order flows to small stock returns is stronger when large stock spreads are higher. In addition, this lead-lag relation is stronger before macro announcements (when information-based trading is more likely) and weaker afterward (when information asymmetries are lower).</description><author>Chordia, Tarun; Sarkar, Asani; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings Management Surrounding Seasoned Bond Offerings: Do Managers Mislead Ratings Agencies and the Bond Market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caton, Gary L.; Chiyachantana, Chiraphol N.; Chua, Choong-Tze; Goh, Jeremy
We study earnings management (EM) efforts surrounding seasoned bond offerings using discretionary current accruals. We find that issuers tend to inflate earnings performance prior to an offering. In order for EM efforts to effectively mislead ratings agencies and the bond market, they must lead to inflated bond ratings and decreased offering yields. Regression results indicate the opposite; aggressive EM efforts are associated with lower initial ratings and higher offering yields. We also find a statistically lower proportion of subsequent downgrades for firms with the most aggressive EM efforts, which is inconsistent with these firms' inflated initial ratings. While some firms may attempt to mislead ratings agencies and market participants by window-dressing earnings, these efforts appear to be counterproductive.</description><author>Caton, Gary L.; Chiyachantana, Chiraphol N.; Chua, Choong-Tze; Goh, Jeremy</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Negative Hedging: Performance-Sensitive Debt and CEOs' Equity Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tchistyi, Alexei; Yermack, David; Yun, Hayong
We examine the relation between chief executive officers' equity incentives and their use of performance-sensitive debt contracts. These contracts require higher or lower interest payments when the borrower's performance deteriorates or improves, thereby increasing expected costs of financial distress while making a firm riskier to the benefit of option holders. We find that managers whose compensation is more sensitive to stock volatility choose steeper and more convex performance pricing schedules, while those with high delta incentives choose flatter, less convex pricing schedules. Performance pricing contracts therefore seem to provide a channel for managers to increase firms' financial risk to gain private benefits.</description><author>Tchistyi, Alexei; Yermack, David; Yun, Hayong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and Arbitrage in the Market for Credit Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nashikkar, Amrut; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Mahanti, Sriketan
The recent credit crisis has highlighted the importance of market liquidity and its interaction with the price of credit risk. We investigate this interaction by relating the liquidity of corporate bonds to the basis between the credit default swap (CDS) spread of the issuer and the par-equivalent bond yield spread. The liquidity of a bond is measured using a recently developed measure called latent liquidity, which is defined as the weighted average turnover of funds holding the bond, where the weights are their fractional holdings of the bond. We find that bonds with higher latent liquidity are more expensive relative to their CDS contracts after controlling for other realized measures of liquidity. Analysis of interaction effects shows that highly illiquid bonds of firms with a greater degree of uncertainty are also expensive, consistent with limits to arbitrage between CDS and bond markets, due to the higher costs of "shorting" illiquid bonds. Additionally, we document the positive effects of liquidity in the CDS market on the CDS-bond basis. We also find that several firm- and bond-level variables related to credit risk affect the basis, indicating that the CDS spread does not fully capture the credit risk of the bond.</description><author>Nashikkar, Amrut; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Mahanti, Sriketan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Price Pressure of Aggregate Mutual Fund Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Kandel, Shmuel; Wohl, Avi
Using a unique database of aggregate daily flows to equity mutual funds in Israel, we find strong support for the "temporary price pressure hypothesis" regarding mutual fund flows: Mutual fund flows create temporary price pressure that is subsequently corrected. We find that flows are positively autocorrelated, and are correlated with market returns (R(2) of 20%). Our main finding is that approximately one-half of the price change is reversed within 10 trading days. This support for the "temporary price pressure hypothesis" complements microstructure research concerning price impact and price noise in stocks by indicating price noise at the aggregate market level.</description><author>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Kandel, Shmuel; Wohl, Avi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Term Structure of Lease Rates with Endogenous Default Triggers and Tenant Capital Structure: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Ambrose, Brent W.; Huang, Hongming; Yildirim, Yildiray
This paper focuses on the defaultable lease rate term structure with endogenous default. We combine the competitive lease market argument proposed by Grenadier (1996) and the endogenous default structural model proposed by Leland and Toft (1996) to examine the interaction between the lessee's capital structure and the equilibrium lease rate. Under this framework, determining the lease rate is a simultaneous equation problem that captures the trade-off between debt and lease financing. Using data on 2,482 real estate lease transactions, we empirically confirm the predictions derived from the numerical analysis of the model.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Ambrose, Brent W.; Huang, Hongming; Yildirim, Yildiray</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Shocks, Liquidity Shocks, Jumps, and Price Discovery: Evidence from the US Treasury Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, George J.; Lo, Ingrid; Verdelhan, Adrien
In this paper, we identify jumps in U.S. Treasury-bond (T-bond) prices and investigate what causes such unexpected large price changes. In particular, we examine the relative importance of macroeconomic news announcements versus variation in market liquidity in explaining the observed jumps in the U.S. Treasury market. We show that while jumps occur mostly at prescheduled macroeconomic announcement times, announcement surprises have limited power in explaining bond price jumps. Our analysis further shows that pre-announcement liquidity shocks, such as changes in the bid-ask spread and market depth, have significant predictive power for jumps. The predictive power is significant even after controlling for information shocks. Finally, we present evidence that post-jump order flow is less informative relative to the case where there is no jump at announcement.</description><author>Jiang, George J.; Lo, Ingrid; Verdelhan, Adrien</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lemons or Cherries? Growth Opportunities and Market Temptations in Going Public and Private</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aslan, Hadiye; Kumar, Praveen
Is the decision to go public or private a stock-market-driven "sideshow" or does it have significant effects on investment and profitability? We address this issue using a comprehensive data set of private and public companies in the U.K. during 1996-2006. Firms with high investment-financing needs, lower information-production costs, and high industry market-to-book ratios are more likely to go public. In contrast to the literature, we find that capital investment and profitability increase substantially after the initial public offering (IPO). Consistent with the agency-cost-based theories of going private, firms decrease investment but increase profits after going private, especially firms bought out by private equity investors. Our analysis also highlights the effects of market conditions on the ownership structure decision.</description><author>Aslan, Hadiye; Kumar, Praveen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rare Event Risk and Heterogeneous Beliefs: The Case of Incomplete Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dieckmann, Stephan
This paper provides an equilibrium model subject to heterogeneous beliefs about the likelihood of rare events. I explore asset pricing implications in an incomplete capital market and the effects of market completion. Without explicit rare event insurance, investors insure themselves indirectly through the stock and money markets, the risk premium is countercyclical, and flight to quality effects arise. Upon market completion, the risk premium increases as investors increase their exposure to rare event risk. While market completion leads to a more efficient allocation based on investors' anticipatory utilities, its effect on ex post efficiency is ambiguous.</description><author>Dieckmann, Stephan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>VC Funds: Aging Brings Myopia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kandel, Eugene; Leshchinskii, Dima; Yuklea, Harry
We study the conflict of interests between the limited partners (LPs) and the general partner (GP) in a venture capital (VC) fund with a limited life span. LPs commit money, while the GP selects and monitors projects. Midway into the project, the GP privately observes the project's quality and the estimated time to exit. The fund's limited time horizon and the GP's informational advantage lead to inefficient decisions at this stage. First, the GP continues bad projects. Second, he may stop monitoring good, but delay-prone projects. We provide empirical predictions and illustrative evidence that the magnitude of the effect is significant.</description><author>Kandel, Eugene; Leshchinskii, Dima; Yuklea, Harry</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture Capital Conflicts of Interest: Evidence from Acquisitions of Venture-Backed Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masulis, Ronald W.; Nahata, Rajarishi
We analyze the effects of venture capital (VC) backing on profitability of private firm acquisitions. We find that VC backing leads to significantly higher acquirer announcement returns, averaging 3%, even after controlling for deal characteristics and endogeneity of venture funding. This leads us to investigate whether some VCs have interests that conflict with those of other investors. We show that such conflicts arise from VCs having financial relationships with both acquirers and targets, corporate VCs having a dominant strategic focus, and VC funds nearing maturity experiencing pressure to liquidate. Our conclusions follow from examinations of target takeover premia and acquirer announcement returns.</description><author>Masulis, Ronald W.; Nahata, Rajarishi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stale Prices and the Performance Evaluation of Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Meijun
Staleness in measured prices imparts a positive statistical bias and a negative dilution effect on mutual fund performance. First, evaluating performance with nonsynchronous data generates a spurious component of alpha. Second, stale prices create arbitrage opportunities for high-frequency traders whose trades dilute the portfolio returns and hence fund performance. This paper introduces a model that evaluates fund performance while controlling directly for these biases. Empirical tests of the model show that alpha net of these biases is on average positive although not significant and about 40 basis points higher than alpha measured without controlling for the impacts of stale pricing. The difference between the net alpha and the measured alpha consists of 3 components: a statistical bias, the dilution effect of long-term fund flows, and the dilution effect of arbitrage. flows. Whereas the former 2 components are small, the latter is large and widespread in the fund industry.</description><author>Qian, Meijun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Holdings Data, Security Returns, and the Selection of Superior Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Blake, Christopher A.
In this paper we show that selecting mutual funds using alpha computed from a fund's holdings and security betas produces better future alphas than selecting funds using alpha computed from a time-series regression on fund returns. This is true whether future alphas are computed using holding and security betas or a time-series regression on fund returns. Furthermore, we show that the more frequently the holdings data are available, the greater the benefit. This has major implications for the Securities and Exchange Commission's recent ruling on the frequency of holdings disclosure and the information plan sponsors should collect from portfolio managers. We also explore the effect of conditioning betas on macroeconomic variables as suggested by Ferson and Schadt (1996) to identify superior-performing mutual funds as well as the alternative way of employing holdings data proposed by Grinblatt and Titman (1993).</description><author>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Blake, Christopher A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO First-Day Return and Ex Ante Equity Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Hui
This paper proposes a measure of ex ante equity premium, IPOFDR, which is the average difference between the initial public offering (IPO) offer price and the 1st-trading-day close price. I test the idea in 3 ways. First, there is a positive relation between IPOFDR and future market returns. Second, changes in IPOFDR help explain the cross section of stock returns. Third, the predictive power of IPOFDR for stock returns reflects mainly its close relation with market variance and average idiosyncratic variance-arguably measures of systematic risk. These results cast doubt on the notion that the IPO 1st-day return is a measure of investor sentiment.</description><author>Guo, Hui</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Influence of Affect on Beliefs, Preferences, and Financial Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuhnen, Camelia M.; Knutson, Brian
Neuroeconomics research shows that brain areas that generate emotional states also process information about risk, rewards, and punishments, suggesting that emotions influence financial decisions in a predictable and parsimonious way. We find that positive emotional states such as excitement induce people to take risks and to be confident in their ability to evaluate investment options, while negative emotions such as anxiety have the opposite effects. Beliefs are updated so as to maintain a positive emotional state by ignoring information that contradicts individuals' prior choices. Marketplace features or outcomes of past choices may change emotions and thus influence future financial decisions.</description><author>Kuhnen, Camelia M.; Knutson, Brian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic Risk, Long-Term Reversal, and Momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McLean, R. David
This paper tests whether the persistence of the momentum and reversal effects is the result of idiosyncratic risk limiting arbitrage. Idiosyncratic risk deters arbitrage, regardless of the arbitrageur's diversification. Reversal is prevalent only in high idiosyncratic risk stocks, suggesting that idiosyncratic risk limits arbitrage in reversal mispricing. This finding is robust to controls for transaction costs, informed trading, and systematic relations between idiosyncratic risk and subsequent returns. Momentum is not related to idiosyncratic risk. Momentum generates a smaller aggregate return than reversal, so the findings along with those in related studies suggest that transaction costs are sufficient to prevent arbitrageurs from eliminating momentum mispricing.</description><author>McLean, R. David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage Risk and Stock Mispricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doukas, John A.; Kim, Chansog; Pantzalis, Christos
In this paper we examine the relation between equity mispricing and arbitrage risk and find that stocks with high arbitrage risk have higher estimated mispricing than stocks with low arbitrage risk. These results are not limited to high book-to-market or small capitalization stocks, and they are not sensitive to transaction and short-selling costs. In addition, they remain robust to alternative multifactor return generating specification models and mispricing measures. Overall, our empirical results are consistent with the conjecture that mispricing is a manifestation of the inability of arbitrageurs to hedge idiosyncratic risk, a major deterrent to arbitrage activity.</description><author>Doukas, John A.; Kim, Chansog; Pantzalis, Christos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavioral and Rational Explanations of Stock Price Performance around SEOs: Evidence from a Decomposition of Market-to-Book Ratios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hertzel, Michael G.; Li, Zhi
We examine the extent to which investment opportunities and/or mispricing motivate equity issuance and contribute to post-issue stock underperformance. We decompose market-to-book ratios into misvaluation and growth option components and find that issuing firms are both overvalued and have greater growth opportunities relative to nonissuers. Firms with greater growth opportunities invest more in capital expenditures and research and development (R&amp;D) after issuance but do not experience lower post-issue stock returns. In contrast, issuing firms with greater mispricing tend to decrease long-term debt and/or increase cash holdings and do earn lower returns. Our findings are consistent with behavioral explanations for post-issue stock price underperformance.</description><author>Hertzel, Michael G.; Li, Zhi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incorporating Economic Objectives into Bayesian Priors: Portfolio Choice under Parameter Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tu, Jun; Zhou, Guofu
This paper proposes a way to allow Bayesian priors to reflect the objectives of an economic problem. That is, we impose priors on the solution to the problem rather than on the primitive parameters whose implied priors can be backed out from the Euler equation. Using monthly returns on the Fama-French 25 size and book-to-market portfolios and their 3 factors from January 1965 to December 2004, we find that investment performances under the objective-based priors can be significantly different from those under alternative priors, with differences in terms of annual certainty-equivalent returns greater than 10% in many cases. In terms of an out-of-sample loss function measure, portfolio strategies based on the objective-based priors can substantially outperform both strategies under alternative priors and some of the best strategies developed in the classical framework.</description><author>Tu, Jun; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-Sectional Return Dispersion and Time Variation in Value and Momentum Premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stivers, Chris; Sun, Licheng
We find that the market's recent cross-sectional dispersion in stock returns is positively related to the subsequent value book-to-market premium and negatively related to the subsequent momentum premium. The partial relation between return dispersion (RD) and the subsequent value and momentum premiums remains strong when controlling for macroeconomic state variables suggested by the literature. Our findings are consistent with recent theoretical insights and empirical evidence that suggest that the market's RD may serve as a leading countercyclical state variable, that the value premium is countercyclical, and that the momentum premium is procyclical.</description><author>Stivers, Chris; Sun, Licheng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple Risky Assets, Transaction Costs, and Return Predictability: Allocation Rules and Implications for US Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lynch, Anthony W.; Tan, Sinan
This paper numerically solves the decision problem of a multiperiod constant relative risk aversion individual who faces transaction costs and has access to two risky assets, both with predictable returns. With proportional transaction costs and independent and identically distributed returns, we numerically find the rebalancing rule to be a no-trade region for the portfolio weights with rebalancing to the boundary. The shape of the no-trade region depends on the correlation between the two risky assets. With predictable returns, there is instead a no-trade region for each state. We also examine several important economic questions, including the utility cost of not being able to buy on margin or short stock.</description><author>Lynch, Anthony W.; Tan, Sinan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Longer-Term Time-Series Volatility Forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ederington, Louis H.; Guan, Wei
Option pricing models and longer-term value-at-risk (VaR) models generally require volatility forecasts over horizons considerably longer than the data frequency. The typical recursive procedure for generating longer-term forecasts keeps the relative weights of recent and older observations the same for all forecast horizons. In contrast, we find that older observations are relatively more important in forecasting at longer horizons. We find that the Ederington and Guan (2005) model and a modified EGARCH (exponential generalized autoregressive conditional heteroskedastic) model in which parameter values vary with the forecast horizon forecast better out-of-sample than the GARCH (generalized autoregressive conditional heteroskedastic), EGARCH, and Glosten, Jagannathan, and Runkle (GJR) models across a wide variety of markets and forecast horizons.</description><author>Ederington, Louis H.; Guan, Wei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>