<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JFQA0</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Union Concessions following Asset Sales and Takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lie, Erik; Que, Tingting
We document that the likelihood of asset sales increases with union presence and union wages. Furthermore, acquiring firms gain significant concessions from the incumbent union following asset sales. Finally, the anticipation of union concessions helps explain the excess stock returns around asset sale announcements. We find no comparable effects for takeovers. We conclude that asset sales, but not takeovers, are partially motivated by the potential to extract concessions from unions.</description><author>Lie, Erik; Que, Tingting</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tail Risk and the Cross-Section of Mutual Fund Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karagiannis, Nikolaos; Tolikas, Konstantinos
We test for the presence of a tail risk premium in the cross-section of mutual fund returns and find that the top tail risk quintile of funds outperforms the bottom by 4.4% per annum. This premium is not simply a reward for market risk, nor do commonly used risk factors offer an adequate explanation. Our findings hold across double-sorted portfolios formed on tail risk and a number of fund characteristics. We also find that funds susceptible to tail risk tend to be small, young, have high management fees, and have managers who do not risk their own capital.</description><author>Karagiannis, Nikolaos; Tolikas, Konstantinos</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Drift Before US Macroeconomic News: Private Information about Public Announcements?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kurov, Alexander; Sancetta, Alessio; Strasser, Georg; Wolfe, Marketa Halova
We examine stock index futures and Treasury futures around the release time of 30 U.S. macroeconomic announcements. Nine of the 20 announcements that move markets show evidence of substantial informed trading before the official release time. Prices begin to move in the "correct" direction approximately 30 minutes before the release time. The preannouncement price drift accounts on average for approximately 40% of the total price adjustment. This implies that some traders have private information about macroeconomic fundamentals. Preannouncement drift might originate from a combination of information leakage and superior forecasting that incorporates proprietary data.</description><author>Kurov, Alexander; Sancetta, Alessio; Strasser, Georg; Wolfe, Marketa Halova</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Operating Leverage, Profitability, and Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhiyao; Harford, Jarrad; Kamara, Avraham
Operating leverage increases profitability and reduces optimal financial leverage. Thus, operating leverage generates a negative relation between profitability and financial leverage that is thought to be inconsistent with the trade-off theory but is commonly observed in the data. We demonstrate the effect of operating leverage on firms' profitability and financial leverage, as well as on the empirical relation between profitability and financial leverage, by using China's entry into the World Trade Organization in 2001 and its effect on the capital-labor ratio of U.S. firms.</description><author>Chen, Zhiyao; Harford, Jarrad; Kamara, Avraham</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coskewness Risk Decomposition, Covariation Risk, and Intertemporal Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalev, Petko S.; Saxena, Konark; Zolotoy, Leon
We develop an intertemporal asset pricing model where cash-flow news, discount-rate news, and their second moments are priced by the market. This model generalizes the market-return decomposition framework, showing that intertemporal considerations imply a decomposition of squared market returns (coskewness risk). Our model accounts for 68% of the return variation across portfolios sorted by size, book-to-market ratio, momentum, investment, and profitability for a modern U.S. sample period. Further, our findings highlight the importance of covariation risk, that is, the risk of simultaneous unfavorable shocks to cash flows and discount rates, in understanding equity risk premia.</description><author>Kalev, Petko S.; Saxena, Konark; Zolotoy, Leon</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Outside Insiders: Does Access to Information Prior to an IPO Generate a Trading Advantage After the IPO?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozmel, Umit; Trombley, Timothy E.; Yavuz, M. Deniz
We investigate whether access to information prior to an initial public offering (IPO) generates a trading advantage after the IPO. We find that limited partners (LPs) of lead venture capital funds obtain high returns when they invest in newly listed stocks backed by their funds. These returns are not explained by LPs' differing stock-picking abilities, and they are higher when LPs' information advantage over the public is higher. LPs are more likely to invest if they have an information advantage, and access to information eliminates the familiarity bias that they display otherwise.</description><author>Ozmel, Umit; Trombley, Timothy E.; Yavuz, M. Deniz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-Country Evidence on the Relationship between Societal Trust and Risk-Taking by Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lobo, Gerald J.; Wang, Chong; Whalen, Dennis J.
We study the relationship between societal trust and risk-taking in the banking industry. Prior literature has found that societal trust is positively related to both financial reporting conservatism and financial reporting transparency, which reduce bank managers' ability to take excessive risk. Additionally, bank managers in high-trust countries are more likely to exhibit higher pro-social behavior and, therefore, less likely to take excessive risk for personal benefit. Consistent with these arguments, we document that banks in countries with higher societal trust exhibit lower risk-taking and that these banks also experienced less financial trouble and fewer failures during the 2007-2009 financial crisis.</description><author>Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lobo, Gerald J.; Wang, Chong; Whalen, Dennis J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Panel-Data Estimation in Finance: Testable Assumptions and Parameter (In)Consistency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grieser, William D.; Hadlock, Charles J.
We investigate the strict-exogeneity assumption, a necessary condition for estimator consistency in many finance panel-data applications. We outline tests for strict exogeneity in both traditional (non-instrumental variable (IV)) and IV settings. When we apply these tests in common traditional finance panel regressions, we find that the strict-exogeneity assumption is often strongly rejected, suggesting large inference errors. We test for strict exogeneity in specific finance panel-data IV settings and illustrate the potential for these tests to help confirm, or rule out, the validity of common panel-data IV estimators. We offer recommendations to address the strict-exogeneity issue in finance research.</description><author>Grieser, William D.; Hadlock, Charles J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric Information, Debt Capacity, and Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lemmon, Michael L.; Zender, Jaime F.
Capital structure choice based on costs associated with asymmetric information is examined in order to present a new perspective on the standard pecking order and trade-off theories. In the model, both the face value of debt and the restrictiveness of the associated debt covenants are chosen as part of the financial structure, allowing a more complete characterization of this decision. Debt structure choice balances ex ante adverse selection against ex post moral hazard, providing a natural integration of the pecking order and trade-off theories and the development of interesting empirical implications.</description><author>Lemmon, Michael L.; Zender, Jaime F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Protection and the Long-Run Performance of Activism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foroughi, Pouyan; Kang, Namho; Ozik, Gideon; Sadka, Ronnie
Using a parsimonious measure of investor protection constructed from fund organizational characteristics, this paper documents that companies targeted by activists with better investor protection structures outperform those targeted by those with poor investor protection structures by roughly 10% per year. The outperformance is observed only for active targets for which Schedule 13Ds are filed, not for passive Schedule 13G investments, indicating that the effect is not explained by a superior target-selection ability. The evidence suggests that funds with better investor protection achieve increased profitability and valuation ratio of their targets by reducing agency costs, improving corporate governance, and collaborating with other large institutional investors.</description><author>Foroughi, Pouyan; Kang, Namho; Ozik, Gideon; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Importance of Blockholder Heterogeneity: Security Market Effects and Follow-On Activities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsieh, Jim; King, Tao-Hsien Dolly
Recent research on blockholders focuses on activist hedge funds and documents positive stock but negative bond returns. This study investigates the role of blockholder heterogeneity on security market effects and target firm follow-on activities across three important dimensions: identity, motive, and purchasing method. We show that target firms' security returns and post-acquisition activities strongly correlate with blockholder heterogeneity. Further, bond returns are significantly positive for firms with blockholders' debt-assistance motive while both stock and bond returns are significantly negative in private placements. Overall, our findings highlight the importance of blockholder heterogeneity on the valuation and performance consequences in block acquisitions.</description><author>Hsieh, Jim; King, Tao-Hsien Dolly</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Lending and the European Sovereign Debt Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Marco, Filippo
I investigate whether bank exposures to sovereign debt during the European debt crisis affected the real economy. I show that a shock to the marked-to-market (MTM) value of bank exposures to sovereign debt led to credit tightening in 2010-2011 that had negative real effects on small and young firms. Because banks do not usually mark their holdings of sovereign bonds to market, I explore the transmission channels of the unrealized losses on credit supply. I show that a shock to MTM exposures reduced short-term bank funding from U.S. money market funds rather than affecting equity or working through alternative channels.</description><author>De Marco, Filippo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of CEO Turnover in Banks: Evidence Using Exogenous Turnovers in Indian Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkar, Arkodipta; Subramanian, Krishnamurthy; Tantri, Prasanna
We examine the effects of chief executive officer (CEO) turnover in banks. Incoming bank CEOs face problems of information asymmetry because banks' operations are opaque and bank risk can change dramatically in a short time. These CEOs may therefore change bank policies to manage their personal risks. Since CEO turnover is usually endogenous, we utilize a setting in which CEO turnover is based solely on retirement age and is thus exogenous to bank performance. Consistent with our thesis, incoming CEOs increase provisioning for future delinquencies and shrink lending. Bank stock prices decline following these changes. Politically motivated lending or ever-greening cannot explain our results.</description><author>Sarkar, Arkodipta; Subramanian, Krishnamurthy; Tantri, Prasanna</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneity of Beliefs and Trade in Experimental Asset Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carle, Tim A.; Lahav, Yaron; Neugebauer, Tibor; Noussair, Charles N.
We investigate the relationship between traders' expectations and market outcomes with experimental asset market data. The data show that those who have high price expectations buy more frequently and submit higher bids, and those who hold low price expectations sell more frequently and submit lower bids. Traders who have more accurate expectations achieve greater earnings. Simulations using only belief data reproduce the pricing patterns observed in the market well, indicating that the heterogeneity of expectations is a key to explaining market activity.</description><author>Carle, Tim A.; Lahav, Yaron; Neugebauer, Tibor; Noussair, Charles N.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Holdup by Junior Claimholders: Evidence from the Mortgage Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Amromin, Gene; Ben-David, Itzhak; Chomsisengphet, Souphala; Zhang, Yan
When borrowers are delinquent, senior debtholders prefer liquidation, whereas junior debtholders prefer to maintain their option value by delaying resolution or modifying the loan. In the mortgage market, a conflict of interest ("holdup") arises when servicers of securitized senior liens are also the owners of the junior liens on the same property. We show that holdup servicers are able to delay action on the first-lien mortgage. When they do act, servicers are more likely to choose resolutions that maintain their option value, favoring modification and soft foreclosures over outright foreclosures. Holdup behavior is more likely to result in borrower self-curing.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Amromin, Gene; Ben-David, Itzhak; Chomsisengphet, Souphala; Zhang, Yan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry Tournament Incentives and the Product-Market Benefits of Corporate Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Jian; Jain, Bharat A.; Kini, Omesh
We evaluate the link between chief executive officer (CEO) industry tournament incentives (ITIs) and the product-market benefits of corporate liquidity. We find that ITIs increase the level and marginal value of cash holdings. Furthermore, ITIs strengthen the relation between excess cash and market-share gains, especially for firms that face significant competitive threats. Additionally, for firms with excess cash, higher ITIs lead to increased research and development (R&amp;D) expenses, capital expenditures, and spending on focused acquisitions as well as reduced payouts. Overall, our findings suggest that ITIs increase the value of cash by incentivizing CEOs to deploy cash strategically to capture its product-market benefits.</description><author>Huang, Jian; Jain, Bharat A.; Kini, Omesh</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Shifting and Corporate Pension Plans: Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pedersen, David J.
Using a natural experiment to identify the causal effect of an increase in default risk on firm actions, I find little evidence managers shift risk to corporate pension plans following an exogenous shock to the firm's long-term liabilities. The finding is robust to focusing on firms where the incentive to engage in risk shifting is arguably the greatest, such as financially vulnerable firms and firms with fewer agency conflicts. This study casts doubt on the risk-shifting hypothesis and shows managers do not take risk-shifting actions that would increase shareholder value even when those actions pose little threat to managerial utility.</description><author>Pedersen, David J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business Loans and the Transmission of Monetary Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barraza, Santiago; Civelli, Andrea; Zaniboni, Nicola
We study the transmission mechanism of monetary policy through business loans and illustrate subtle aspects of its functioning that relate to the contractual characteristics and the borrower-lender types of loans. We show that the puzzling increase in business loans in response to monetary tightening, documented before the Great Recession, is largely driven by drawdowns from existing commitments at large banks. Spot loans also rise and take a considerable amount of time to adjust. Banks, nonetheless, do curtail credit supply by shortening maturities of new loans. Following the Great Recession, the mechanism has worked differently, with loan responses to monetary tightening displaying a significant downward shift.</description><author>Barraza, Santiago; Civelli, Andrea; Zaniboni, Nicola</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Attitudes Toward Noncompliance and the Demand for External Financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davidson, Robert H.; Pirinsky, Christo
We study the link between the individual propensity to violate moral principles and the demand for finance based on two data sets: the World Values Survey and a data set with the legal records of U.S. chief executive officers (CEOs). We find that individuals who are more tolerant of moral principle violations are more likely to borrow. Corporate executives with legal records are also associated with larger mortgages. Reverse causality and attitudes toward risk are unlikely explanations for our findings. We contend that noncompliance relaxes participation constraints in capital markets by lowering the psychological costs of entering and breaking a contract.</description><author>Davidson, Robert H.; Pirinsky, Christo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accounting Losses as a Heuristic for Managerial Failure: Evidence from CEO Turnovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghosh, Aloke; Wang, Jun
We study the effects of accounting losses on chief executive officer (CEO) turnover. If accounting losses provide incremental information about managerial ability, boards can utilize the information in losses to assess CEOs' stewardship of assets, which is why losses may serve as a heuristic for managerial failure. We find a positive relation between losses and subsequent CEO turnover after controlling for other accounting and stock-performance measures. We also find that losses are associated with an increase in board activity and that losses predict poor operating performance and future financial problems. Our results explain why CEOs manage earnings to avoid losses.</description><author>Ghosh, Aloke; Wang, Jun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Single-Factor Consumption-Based Asset Pricing Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delikouras, Stefanos; Kostakis, Alexandros
We propose a single-factor asset pricing model based on an indicator function of consumption growth being less than its endogenous certainty equivalent. This certainty equivalent is derived from generalized disappointment-aversion preferences, and it is located approximately 1 standard deviation below the conditional mean of consumption growth. Our single-factor model can explain the cross section of expected returns for size, value, reversal, profitability, and investment portfolios at least as well as the Fama-French multi-factor models. Our results show strong empirical support for asymmetric preferences and question the effectiveness of the smooth utility framework, which is traditionally used in consumption-based asset pricing.</description><author>Delikouras, Stefanos; Kostakis, Alexandros</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>SOX Section 404 and Corporate Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Huasheng; Zhang, Jin
This paper exploits a quasi-natural experiment to investigate the relation between the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002 and corporate innovation: firms with a public float under $75 million can delay compliance with Section 404 of the act. We find a significant decrease in the number of patents and patent citations for firms that are subject to Section 404 compliance relative to firms that are not. This relation is more pronounced when firms are financially constrained and when firms face high litigation risk. Overall, our evidence suggests that SOX imparts real costs to the economy by decreasing corporate innovativeness.</description><author>Gao, Huasheng; Zhang, Jin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Covenants, Creditors' Simultaneous Equity Holdings, and Firm Investment Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Wang, Rui; Zou, Hong
This article analyzes how creditors' simultaneous debt and equity holdings affect firm investment policies. We find that firms with dual ownership are less likely to have capital expenditure restrictions in loan contracts, and the relation varies in predicted ways with the monitoring needs of borrowers and the monitoring capacity of dual owners. A less frequent use of capital expenditure restrictions, however, does not result in borrowers' risk-shifting. Dual ownership firms are also more likely to be granted an unconditional waiver and do not significantly reduce debt issuance or investment expenditures after a financial covenant violation. Our results highlight how dual ownership can help mitigate shareholder-creditor conflicts.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Wang, Rui; Zou, Hong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and Bank Liquidity Creation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Liangliang; Levine, Ross; Lin, Chen
We use a new identification strategy to assess whether an intensification of competition among banks increases or decreases the provision of a key banking service: liquidity creation. Although theory offers conflicting predictions about the impact of competition on liquidity creation, we find that regulatory-induced competition reduces liquidity creation. Consistent with a subset of models emphasizing that banks pushed toward insolvency reduce risk-taking activities, we discover that regulatory-induced competition reduces liquidity creation more among banks with less risk-absorbing capacity (e.g., less profitable banks).</description><author>Jiang, Liangliang; Levine, Ross; Lin, Chen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Illiquidity Affect Delegated Portfolio Choice?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Min; Goncalves-Pinto, Luis; Xu, Jing
In response to how they are compensated, mutual fund managers who are underperforming by mid-year are likely to increase the risk of their portfolios toward the year-end. We argue that an increase in the liquidity of the stocks that managers use to shift risk can lead to an increase in the size of their risky bets. This in turn hurts fund investors by increasing the costs of misaligned incentives associated with delegated portfolio management. We provide both theoretical and empirical results that are consistent with this argument. We use decimalization as an exogenous shock to liquidity to identify causal effects.</description><author>Dai, Min; Goncalves-Pinto, Luis; Xu, Jing</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is It the Investment Bank or the Investment Banker? A Study of the Role of Investment Banker Human Capital in Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Ertugrul, Mine; Krishnan, Karthik
Using a novel data set that links individual investment bankers to the acquisition deals they advise on, we find that individual investment bankers with greater deal experience are associated with higher acquisition returns and post-acquisition operating performance, particularly for acquirers in complex and more opaque industries. The advisory fee on acquisitions is also positively associated with the investment banking team's experience. Finally, when more experienced investment bankers switch to a new bank, acquirers are more likely to move with them. Overall, our results suggest that the human capital of individual investment bankers is valuable to acquirers.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Ertugrul, Mine; Krishnan, Karthik</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Price Co-Movement and the Foundations of Pairs Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farago, Adam; Hjalmarsson, Erik
We study the theoretical implications of cointegrated stock prices on the profitability of pairs-trading strategies. If stock returns are fairly weakly correlated across time, cointegration implies very high Sharpe ratios. To the extent that the theoretical Sharpe ratios are "too large," our results suggest that either i) cointegration does not exist pairwise among stocks, and pairs-trading profits are a result of a weaker or less stable dependency structure among stock pairs, or ii) the serial correlation in stock returns stretches over considerably longer horizons than is usually assumed. Empirically, there is little evidence of cointegration, favoring the first explanation.</description><author>Farago, Adam; Hjalmarsson, Erik</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Capital and Lending: Evidence from Syndicated Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chu, Yongqiang; Zhang, Donghang; Zhao, Yijia
Using within-loan estimations to remove the impact of demand-side factors, we find that the capital levels of banks participating in the same syndicated loan are positively associated with the banks' contributions to the loan. Consistent with the argument that higher capital reduces the cost of uninsured debt, the positive effect of bank capital on lending is stronger among banks that rely more on wholesale funding. Furthermore, we find that banks increase their contributions to syndicated loans after receiving Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) funding. Taken together, we provide new evidence on the importance and causal effect of bank capital on lending.</description><author>Chu, Yongqiang; Zhang, Donghang; Zhao, Yijia</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good Volatility, Bad Volatility, and Option Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feunou, Bruno; Okou, Cedric
Advances in variance analysis permit the splitting of the total quadratic variation of a jump-diffusion process into upside and downside components. Recent studies establish that this decomposition enhances volatility predictions and highlight the upside/downside variance spread as a driver of the asymmetry in stock price distributions. To appraise the economic gain of this decomposition, we design a new and flexible option pricing model in which the underlying asset price exhibits distinct upside and downside semivariance dynamics driven by the model-free proxies of the variances. The new model outperforms common benchmarks, especially the alternative that splits the quadratic variation into diffusive and jump components.</description><author>Feunou, Bruno; Okou, Cedric</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticipatory Traders and Trading Speed</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fishe, Raymond P. H.; Haynes, Richard; Onur, Esen
We examine whether speed is an important characteristic of traders who anticipate local price trends. These anticipatory participants correctly trade prior to the overall market and systematically act before other participants. They use manual and algorithmic order entry methods, but most are not fast enough to be high frequency traders (HFTs). Those anticipating price trends have impacts as if they are informed traders, while the case for anticipatory participants affecting the volume of other traders is rejected. A follow-up sample shows significant attrition in accounts and difficulty maintaining the anticipatory strategies. To identify anticipatory traders, we devise novel methods to isolate local price trends using order book data from the West Texas Intermediate (WTI) crude oil futures market.</description><author>Fishe, Raymond P. H.; Haynes, Richard; Onur, Esen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Investment Constraints on Hedge Fund Investor Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joenvaara, Juha; Kosowski, Robert; Tolonen, Pekka
This paper examines the effect of real-world, investor-level investment constraints, including several that have not been studied before, on hedge fund performance and its persistence. Using a large consolidated database, we demonstrate that hedge fund performance persistence is significantly reduced when rebalancing rules reflect fund size restrictions and liquidity constraints but remains statistically significant at higher rebalancing frequencies. Hypothetical investor portfolios that incorporate additional minimum diversification constraints, minimum investment requirements, and focus on open funds suggest that the performance and its persistence documented in earlier studies of hedge funds is not easily exploitable, especially by large investors.</description><author>Joenvaara, Juha; Kosowski, Robert; Tolonen, Pekka</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-Frequency Trading Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brogaard, Jonathan; Garriott, Corey
Theory on high-frequency traders (HFTs) predicts that market liquidity for a security decreases in the number of HFTs trading the security. We test this prediction by studying a new Canadian stock exchange, Alpha, that experienced the entry of 11 HFTs over 4 years. We find that bid-ask spreads on Alpha converge to those at the Toronto Stock Exchange as more HFTs trade on Alpha. Effective and realized spreads for non-HFTs improve as HFTs enter the market. To explain the contrast with theory, which models the HFT as a price competitor, we provide evidence more consistent with HFTs fitting a quantity-competitor framework.</description><author>Brogaard, Jonathan; Garriott, Corey</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Information Content of Sudden Insider Silence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Claire Yurong; Li, Frank Weikai
We present evidence of investors underreacting to the absence of events in financial markets. Routine-based insiders strategically choose to be silent when they possess private information not yet reflected in stock prices. Consistent with our hypothesis, insider silence following a routine sell (buy) predicts positive (negative) future returns, as well as fundamentals. The return predictability of insider silence is stronger among firms with a poor information environment and facing higher arbitrage costs, and a large fraction of abnormal returns concentrates on future earnings announcements. A long-short strategy that exploits insiders' strategic silence behavior generates abnormal returns of 6% to 10% annually.</description><author>Hong, Claire Yurong; Li, Frank Weikai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Strong Corporate Governance Selectively Mitigate the Negative Influence of "Special Interest" Shareholder Activists? Evidence from the Labor Market for Directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Del Guercio, Diane; Woidtke, Tracie
Union and public pension funds, the most prolific institutional activists employing low-cost targeting methods, are often accused of pursuing private benefits. Extant literature finds that unions representing workers, as stakeholders, are not aligned with shareholders. Limiting shareholder power may mitigate "special interest" activism but can also exacerbate managerial agency problems. In two different settings, majority approved and withdrawn shareholder proposals, we examine and find supportive evidence that the director labor market as a corporate governance mechanism can selectively mitigate the negative influence that conflicted stakeholder-shareholder union funds have over firms without stifling all influence of low-cost activists.</description><author>Del Guercio, Diane; Woidtke, Tracie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dead Hand Proxy Puts and Hedge Fund Activism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffith, Sean J.; Reisel, Natalia
We investigate the Dead Hand Proxy Put, a contractual innovation in corporate debt agreements that may impact hedge fund activism. We find the provision principally in loans, not bonds, and provide evidence linking the adoption of the provision to hedge fund activism. Furthermore, controlling for endogeneity, we find that the provision significantly reduces the cost of loans. Bondholder wealth also increases. Moreover, cross-sectional analysis of share returns reveals that the provision is positively associated with repeat banking relationships and negatively associated with free cash flow problems, suggesting a cost-benefit tradeoff.</description><author>Griffith, Sean J.; Reisel, Natalia</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Consumption and Investment under Time-Varying Liquidity Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, Seryoong; Choi, Kyoung Jin; Lim, Byung Hwa
We study consumption and investment decisions given realistic time-varying constraints on borrowing. We first consider the case where borrowing is constrained by a maximum debt-to-income ratio. We then consider collateral borrowing with a maximum loan-to-value ratio. The resulting implications for optimal policies differ considerably from those obtained in the existing literature based on fixed borrowing limits but are consistent with those documented in the empirical literature.</description><author>Ahn, Seryoong; Choi, Kyoung Jin; Lim, Byung Hwa</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Mutual Funds Have Decreasing Returns to Scale? Evidence from Fund Mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McLemore, Ping
Using mergers as shocks to fund size, I analyze the return-to-scale property of mutual funds. I find that acquiring funds' performance deteriorates after experiencing a positive shock in size resulting from mergers, and liquidity plays an important role in the negative relationship between size and performance. I also find that the decline in performance is not due to higher performance prior to the merger, nor driven by higher integration costs after the event. These findings are consistent with mutual funds having decreasing returns to scale and thus provide empirical evidence that supports the theoretical model of Berk and Green (2004).</description><author>McLemore, Ping</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Best of the Best: A Comparison of Factor Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahmed, Shamim; Bu, Ziwen; Tsvetanov, Daniel
We compare major factor models and find that the Stambaugh and Yuan (2016) 4-factor model is the overall winner in the time-series domain. The Hou, Xue, and Zhang (2015) q-factor model takes second place and the Fama and French (2015) 5-factor model and the Barillas and Shanken (2018) 6-factor model jointly take third place. The pairwise cross-sectional R-2 and the multiple model comparison tests show that the Hou et al. (2015) q-factor model, the Fama and French (2015) 5-factor and 4-factor models, and the Barillas and Shanken (2018) 6-factor model take equal first place in the horse race.</description><author>Ahmed, Shamim; Bu, Ziwen; Tsvetanov, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing Intertemporal Risk When Investment Opportunities Are Unobservable</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cederburg, Scott
The intertemporal capital asset pricing model (ICAPM) predicts that an unobservable factor capturing changes in expected market returns should be priced in the cross section. My Bayesian framework accounts for uncertainty in the intertemporal risk factor and gauges the effects of prior information about investment opportunities on model inferences. Whereas an uninformative prior specification produces weak evidence that intertemporal risk is priced, incorporating prior information about market-return predictability generates a large space of ex ante reasonable priors in which the estimated intertemporal risk factor is positively priced. Overall, the cross-sectional tests reject the capital asset pricing model (CAPM) and indicate support for the ICAPM.</description><author>Cederburg, Scott</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Two Trees with Heterogeneous Beliefs: Spillover Effect of Disagreement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Bing; Lu, Lei; Zhou, Yi
In a model where investors disagree about the fundamentals of two stocks, the state-price density depends on investor disagreements for both stocks, especially the larger stock. This implies that disagreement among investors in a large firm has a spillover effect on the pricing of other stocks owned by these investors. The pricing effects of investor disagreements crucially depend on the average belief biases. Empirical findings support the novel model prediction of a disagreement spillover effect and help reconcile some mixed evidence in the literature.</description><author>Han, Bing; Lu, Lei; Zhou, Yi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pension Deficits and the Design of Private Debt Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balachandran, Balasingham; Duong, Huu Nhan; Vu, Van Hoang
We find a positive relation between the amount of pension deficits and the cost of bank loans. The effect of pension deficits on the cost of bank loans is driven by financial constraints, information-asymmetry problems, and higher pension-investment risk. Banks tighten lending terms for firms with larger pension deficits by requiring collateral, increasing the number of loan covenants, and shortening loan maturity. Borrowers with larger pension deficits are also more likely to violate covenants in the future. Collectively, these findings indicate that pension deficits represent an additional source of risk priced by banks.</description><author>Balachandran, Balasingham; Duong, Huu Nhan; Vu, Van Hoang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employment, Corporate Investment, and Cash-Flow Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alnahedh, Saad; Bhagat, Sanjai; Obreja, Iulian
We highlight the role of cash-flow uncertainty on corporate employment and investment. We find that a 1% increase in cash-flow uncertainty leads to a 0.62% decrease in tangible investment, a 1.39% decrease in intangible investment, and a 3.67% decrease in corporate employment growth. Our results are statistically and economically significant. We further find that these relationships are stronger during economic recessions. Our findings have significant policy implications. To wit, if policy makers would like corporations to increase their employment and investment, they should focus on policies that decrease corporate cash-flow uncertainty.</description><author>Alnahedh, Saad; Bhagat, Sanjai; Obreja, Iulian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Buybacks Good for Long-Term Shareholder Value? Evidence from Buybacks around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manconi, Alberto; Peyer, Urs; Vermaelen, Theo
Using a sample of over 9,000 buyback announcements from 31 non-U.S. countries, we find support for the results of studies based on U.S. data: On average, share repurchases are associated with significant positive short- and long-term excess returns. However, excess returns depend on the likelihood of undervaluation and the efficiency and liquidity of equity markets. In contrast to findings in U.S. markets, we do not find that these long-term excess returns are simply a compensation for takeover risk or have become less significant in recent years.</description><author>Manconi, Alberto; Peyer, Urs; Vermaelen, Theo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Unusual News Forecast Market Stress?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glasserman, Paul; Mamaysky, Harry
An increase in "unusual" news with negative sentiment predicts an increase in stock market volatility. Unusual positive news forecasts lower volatility. Our analysis is based on over 360,000 articles on 50 large financial companies, published during the period of 1996-2014. Unusualness interacted with sentiment forecasts company-specific and aggregate volatility several months ahead. Furthermore, unusual news is reflected more slowly in aggregate volatility than company-specific volatility. News measures from articles explicitly about the "market," which are more easily accessible to investors, do not forecast volatility. The observed responses of volatility to news may be explained by attention constraints on investors.</description><author>Glasserman, Paul; Mamaysky, Harry</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Evidence on Conditional Factor Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Ilan; Maio, Paulo
We estimate conditional multifactor models over a large cross section of stock returns matching 25 CAPM anomalies. Using conditioning information associated with different instruments improves the performance of the Hou, Xue, and Zhang (HXZ) (2015) and Fama and French (FF) (2015), (2016) models. The largest increase in performance holds for momentum, investment, and intangibles-based anomalies. Yet, there are significant differences in the performance of scaled models: HXZ clearly dominates FF in explaining momentum and profitability anomalies, while the converse holds for value-growth anomalies. Thus, the asset pricing implications of alternative investment and profitability factors (in a conditional setting) differ in a nontrivial way.</description><author>Cooper, Ilan; Maio, Paulo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hometown Biased Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Feng; Qian, Yiming; Yonker, Scott E.
We show that chief executive officers (CEOs) exhibit a hometown bias in acquisitions. Firms are over twice as likely to acquire targets located in the states of their CEOs' childhood homes than similar targets domiciled elsewhere. Small, private home-state deals underperform other small, private deals, and the bias is stronger when acquirer governance is lax, suggesting that CEOs acquire private home-state targets for their own benefits. In contrast, large, public home-state acquisitions are value enhancing. CEOs create value in public home-state acquisitions by avoiding extremely poor deals and through deals with higher synergies. Thus, both agency issues and hometown advantages drive home-state acquisitions.</description><author>Jiang, Feng; Qian, Yiming; Yonker, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimation of Multivariate Asset Models with Jumps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ballotta, Laura; Fusai, Gianluca; Loregian, Angela; Perez, M. Fabricio
We propose a consistent and computationally efficient 2-step methodology for the estimation of multidimensional non-Gaussian asset models built using Levy processes. The proposed framework allows for dependence between assets and different tail behaviors and jump structures for each asset. Our procedure can be applied to portfolios with a large number of assets because it is immune to estimation dimensionality problems. Simulations show good finite sample properties and significant efficiency gains. This method is especially relevant for risk management purposes such as, for example, the computation of portfolio Value at Risk and intra-horizon Value at Risk, as we show in detail in an empirical illustration.</description><author>Ballotta, Laura; Fusai, Gianluca; Loregian, Angela; Perez, M. Fabricio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Does the Family Govern the Family Firm?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bohren, Oyvind; Stacescu, Bogdan; Almli, Line F.; Sondergaard, Kathrine L.
We find that the controlling family holds both the chief executive officer and chair positions in 79% of Norwegian family firms. The family holds more governance positions when it owns large stakes in small, profitable, low-risk firms. This result suggests that the family trades off expected costs and benefits by conditioning participation intensity on observable firm characteristics. We find that the positive effect of performance on participation is twice as strong as the positive effect of participation on performance. The endogeneity of participation, therefore, should be carefully accounted for when analyzing the effect of family governance on the family firm's behavior.</description><author>Bohren, Oyvind; Stacescu, Bogdan; Almli, Line F.; Sondergaard, Kathrine L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Relation between Corporate and Government Debt Maturity in Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lugo, Stefano; Piccillo, Giulia
This article investigates the gap-filling explanation for corporate debt maturity choices in a multi-country setting. We argue that companies adjust their debt maturity in response to shocks in government debt maturity both at home and abroad; the difference between the two effects depends on the markets' relative size and level of integration. Focusing on the European case and treating the Economic and Monetary Union as a shock in market integration, we find strong empirical support for our predictions. Our results have relevant implications for the opportunity for individual governments to use their debt maturity structure as a policy tool.</description><author>Lugo, Stefano; Piccillo, Giulia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Political Uncertainty Increase External Financing Costs? Measuring the Electoral Premium in Syndicated Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Olivia S.
This article investigates the impact of political uncertainty on contractual lending terms using a large sample of syndicated loans and a within-firm estimation approach to achieve identification. Firms pay 7 basis points (bps) more on loans originated when their lenders are undergoing an election relative to when their lenders are not undergoing an election. Lenders from less financially developed countries are more likely to pass political uncertainty costs to borrowers. Consistent with electoral uncertainty driving this premium, the most contested elections have the largest impact (17 bps). Overall, political uncertainty leads to a tangible increase in firms' financing costs.</description><author>Kim, Olivia S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Interventions and Trade Credit: Evidence from Debt Covenant Violations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Zilong
This study examines the consequences of conflicts between creditors. Using the setting of debt covenant violations, I employ a regression discontinuity design to identify the effect of banks' interventions on their borrowers' trade credit. The results show that trade credit experiences a substantial decline when banks intervene in the borrowing firm following covenant violations. The decline is mitigated by the presence of dependent suppliers and exacerbated by banks' incentives to exercise control rights. Such externalities are reflected in the loan-contract design. Borrowing firms sign less restrictive loan contracts when they rely more on trade credit or trade creditors.</description><author>Zhang, Zilong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Aversion in a Dynamic Asset Allocation Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brocas, Isabelle; Carrillo, Juan D.; Giga, Aleksandar; Zapatero, Fernando
We conduct a controlled laboratory experiment in the spirit of Merton (1971), in which subjects dynamically choose their portfolio allocation between a risk-free and risky asset. Using the optimal allocation of an investor with hyperbolic absolute risk aversion (HARA) utility, we fit the experimental choices to characterize the risk profile of our participants. Despite substantial heterogeneity, decreasing absolute risk aversion and increasing relative risk aversion are the predominant types. We also find some evidence of increased risk taking after a gain. Finally, the session level risk attitudes show a different profile than the individual descriptions of risk attitudes.</description><author>Brocas, Isabelle; Carrillo, Juan D.; Giga, Aleksandar; Zapatero, Fernando</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency Regimes and the Carry Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Accominotti, Olivier; Cen, Jason; Chambers, David; Marsh, Ian W.
This study exploits a new long-run data set of daily bid and offered exchange rates in spot and forward markets from 1919 to the present to analyze carry returns in fixed and floating currency regimes. We first find that outsized carry returns occur exclusively in the floating regime, being zero in the fixed regime. Second, we show that fixed-to-floating regime shifts are associated with negative returns to a carry strategy implemented only on floating currencies, robust to the inclusion of volatility risks. These shifts are typically characterized by global flight-to-safety events that represent bad times for carry traders.</description><author>Accominotti, Olivier; Cen, Jason; Chambers, David; Marsh, Ian W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Shadow Rate or a Quadratic Policy Rule? The Best Way to Enforce the Zero Lower Bound in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andreasen, Martin M.; Meldrum, Andrew
We study whether it is better to enforce the zero lower bound (ZLB) in models of U.S. Treasury yields using a shadow rate model or a quadratic term structure model. We show that the models achieve a similar in-sample fit and perform comparably in matching conditional expectations of future yields. However, when the recent ZLB period is included in the sample, the models' ability to match conditional expectations away from the ZLB deteriorates because the time-series dynamics of the pricing factors change. In addition, neither model provides a reasonable description of conditional volatilities when yields are away from the ZLB.</description><author>Andreasen, Martin M.; Meldrum, Andrew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor Adjustment Costs and Risk Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qiu, Yue
This paper studies the effects of labor adjustment costs on corporate risk management. Labor adjustment costs attenuate the correlation between the internal funds of a firm and its investment opportunity, and create more incentives for the firm to smooth internal funds. Using a state border discontinuity approach, I find that state-level labor protection laws significantly impact a firm's use of foreign currency derivative contracts. I further find that a firm holds more cash when labor adjustment costs are larger, and such an effect concentrates on firms that do not engage in derivative hedging.</description><author>Qiu, Yue</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Boss Knows Best: Directors of Research and Subordinate Analysts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, Daniel; Gokkaya, Sinan; Liu, Xi
Research departments are managed by directors of research (DORs). Subordinate analysts working for higher-quality DORs provide superior earnings forecasts that elicit stronger market reactions, provide better investment recommendations, and have better career outcomes. For the broker, higher-quality DORs drive more trading commissions. Economically, analysts benefit the most from DOR-analyst industry alignment resulting from DORs' former analyst experience. We provide several tests to mitigate endogeneity concerns and explore various mechanisms to explain these results. Overall, our article identifies a unique channel whereby the industry-specific and general human capital of top management filters through to individual subordinates and consequently improves organizational performance.</description><author>Bradley, Daniel; Gokkaya, Sinan; Liu, Xi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Unlisted Targets Sell at Discounts?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jaffe, Jeffrey F.; Jindra, Jan; Pedersen, David J.; Voetmann, Torben
Academic literature, practitioners, courts, and regulators routinely assert that both private and subsidiary targets sell at discounts relative to public targets. However, the empirical evidence to support this conclusion is thin. Our work alters the methodology from prior research to avoid biases due to both one-sided sample truncation and Jensen's inequality. Following these changes, we find no evidence that unlisted targets sell at discounts. Our results hold under a number of different approaches and after controlling for known determinants of acquisition pricing.</description><author>Jaffe, Jeffrey F.; Jindra, Jan; Pedersen, David J.; Voetmann, Torben</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Inattention and Stock Prices: Evidence from Acquisitions with a Choice of Payment Type</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lie, Erik
I report evidence that shareholders holding a combined 15% of shares are inattentive or partially inattentive when confronted with the decision to receive cash or stock for their shares in acquisitions. The average cost of such inattention is 2%, and it increases to 6% for the tertile of transactions with the greatest difference between the cash and stock values. Most interestingly, I show that inattention affects stock prices because attentive shareholders bid up the stock price in anticipation of a wealth transfer from inattentive shareholders.</description><author>Lie, Erik</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State Ownership and Debt Choice: Evidence from Privatization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubakri, Narjess; Saffar, Walid
Using a large sample of privatized firms, we find that state ownership is significantly positively associated with the use of bank debt financing, suggesting that privatized firms benefit from the soft budget constraint associated with state ownership. We further find that the relation is more pronounced in countries with high government ownership of banks, high corruption in bank lending, a left-oriented government, and a collectivist national culture, which provides additional support for the soft-budget-constraint view. Finally, in external validity tests, we find that state ownership affects other aspects of debt structure, such as debt maturity and debt security.</description><author>Boubakri, Narjess; Saffar, Walid</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shelf versus Traditional Seasoned Equity Offerings: The Impact of Potential Short Selling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dutordoir, Marie; Strong, Norman; Sun, Ping
Traditional seasoned equity offerings (SEOs) elicit short selling from traders trying to increase offering discounts. Such short selling is more difficult for shelf offerings because the time between their announcement and issuance tends to be shorter. We predict and find that firms with higher short-selling potential (SSP) are more likely to choose shelf over traditional SEOs. This result is robust to alternative proxies for SSP and other sensitivity tests. Further analysis suggests that shelf issuers aim to mitigate the threat of manipulative short selling. Our findings add to a growing literature showing that short selling has a real impact on corporate finance decisions.</description><author>Dutordoir, Marie; Strong, Norman; Sun, Ping</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>At-the-Market Offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, Matthew T.; Floros, Ioannis; Garfinkel, Jon A.
We study at-the-market (ATM) equity offerings, which are direct share issuances sold in the secondary market that forgo underwriters and "dribble-out" shares over time rather than raising them all at once. Enabled in 2008, their use has increased dramatically, and in 2016, their incidence and total proceeds were, respectively, 63% and 26% of those for seasoned equity offerings (SEOs). Determinants of firms' choice between ATMs and SEOs are consistent with the costly certification hypothesis of Chemmanur and Fulghieri (1994). We also find that 65% of ATM proceeds are used to stockpile cash compared to 84% of SEO proceeds.</description><author>Billett, Matthew T.; Floros, Ioannis; Garfinkel, Jon A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relationship Bank Behavior during Borrower Distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Yan; Lu, Ruichang; Srinivasan, Anand
This article provides a comprehensive examination of the time-series behavior of relationship banks around and during borrower distress. Relationship and outside loans have similar interest rates during distress and even 2 years prior to distress. Relative to outside loans in distress, relationship loans in distress have lower maturity. The fraction of bank lending given by relationship banks reduces during borrower distress. Overall, borrowers in distress do not derive benefits from relationship banks. These findings are inconsistent with models that suggest banks have an implicit commitment to help their borrowers in distress due to reputation concerns.</description><author>Li, Yan; Lu, Ruichang; Srinivasan, Anand</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relationship-Based Resource Allocations: Evidence from the Use of "Guanxi" during SEOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, Paul; Firth, Michael; He, Xianjie; Mao, Xinyang; Rui, Oliver
We examine the role of relationship-based resource allocations during the approval process of seasoned equity offerings (SEOs) in the Chinese capital market. Our results show that guanxi-based relationships significantly increase the likelihood of SEO approvals, particularly for suspect SEO applicants with abnormal levels of earnings management (EM), related-party transactions (RPTs), and intercompany loans. More importantly, we find that guanxi-influenced SEO firms have significantly poorer performance in the post-SE degrees period, which indicates that it results in inefficient resource allocations. Overall, our evidence suggests that relationship-based resource allocations lead to negative spillover effects that impose social welfare losses.</description><author>Brockman, Paul; Firth, Michael; He, Xianjie; Mao, Xinyang; Rui, Oliver</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Getting Paid to Hedge: Why Don't Investors Pay a Premium to Hedge Downturns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kapadia, Nishad; Ostdiek, Barbara Bennett; Weston, James P.; Zekhnini, Morad
Stocks that hedge sustained market downturns should have low expected returns, but they do not. We use ex ante firm characteristics and covariances to construct a tradable safe minus risky (SMR) portfolio that hedges market downturns out of sample. Although down-turns (peaks to troughs in market index levels at the business-cycle frequency) predict significant declines in gross domestic product growth, SMR has significant positive average returns and 4-factor alphas (both around 0.8% per month). Risk-based models do not explain SMR's returns, but mispricing does. Risky stocks are overpriced when sentiment is high, resulting in subsequent returns of -0.9% per month.</description><author>Kapadia, Nishad; Ostdiek, Barbara Bennett; Weston, James P.; Zekhnini, Morad</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board Ancestral Diversity and Firm-Performance Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Zhao, Mengxin
We proxy for board members' opinions and values using directors' ancestral origins and show that diversity has costs and benefits, leading to high performance volatility. Consistent with the idea that diverse groups experiment more, firms with ancestrally diverse boards have more numerous and more cited patents. In addition, their strategies conform less to those of the industry peers. However, firms with greater ancestral diversity also have more board meetings and make less predictable decisions. These findings suggest that diversity may lead to inefficiencies in the decision-making process and conflicts in the boardroom.</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Zhao, Mengxin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factor Structure in Commodity Futures Return and Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Lunde, Asger; Olesen, Kasper
We uncover stylized facts of commodity futures' price and volatility dynamics in the post- financialization period and find a factor structure in daily commodity volatility that is much stronger than the factor structure in returns. The common factor in commodity volatility relates to stock market volatility as well as to the business cycle. Model-free realized commodity betas with the stock market were high during 2008-2010 but have since returned to the pre-crisis level, close to 0. While commodity markets appear segmented from the equity market when considering only returns, commodity volatility indicates a nontrivial degree of market integration.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Lunde, Asger; Olesen, Kasper</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regional Economic Activity and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smajlbegovic, Esad
This paper studies the diffusion of regional macroeconomic information into stock prices. I identify all U.S. states that are economically relevant for a company through textual analysis of annual reports and find that economic activity forecasts of company-relevant regions positively predict cross-sectional stock returns. Information arising from all relevant states is more important than that relating to the headquarter state alone. These forecasts also predict firms' performance and earnings surprises, suggesting that the return predictability stems from future cash flows that are gradually reflected in prices. Finally, regional information takes longer to be incorporated into prices among difficult-to-arbitrage stocks.</description><author>Smajlbegovic, Esad</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Economic Spillover Effects of Stock Market Listings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, Alexander W.; Fauver, Larry; Spyridopoulos, Ioannis
We show that initial public offerings (IPOs) have nontrivial positive spillover effects on local labor markets, business environments, consumer spending, real estate, and migration. We mitigate endogeneity concerns about unobserved heterogeneity with restrictive geographic fixed effects coupled with a matching procedure. We show that it is the listing decision, which encompasses both a wealth and liquidity shock, that induces economic spillovers. Conditional on an IPO occurring, we estimate that an additional $10 million in IPO proceeds is associated with an extra 41 jobs and 0.7 new establishments locally.</description><author>Butler, Alexander W.; Fauver, Larry; Spyridopoulos, Ioannis</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and Return in High-Frequency Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baron, Matthew; Brogaard, Jonathan; Hagstromer, Bjorn; Kirilenko, Andrei
We study performance and competition among firms engaging in high-frequency trading (HFT). We construct measures of latency and find that differences in relative latency account for large differences in HFT firms' trading performance. HFT firms that improve their latency rank due to colocation upgrades see improved trading performance. The stronger performance associated with speed comes through both the short-lived information channel and the risk management channel, and speed is useful for various strategies, including market making and cross-market arbitrage. We find empirical support for many predictions regarding relative latency competition.</description><author>Baron, Matthew; Brogaard, Jonathan; Hagstromer, Bjorn; Kirilenko, Andrei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securities Transaction Taxes and Market Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pomeranets, Anna; Weaver, Daniel G.
We study changes in market quality associated with 9 modifications to the New York State securities transaction tax (STT) between 1932 and 1981 and 3 changes to the federal STT between 1932 and 1966. We find that when there is an increase in the level of an STT, individual stock volatility increases, bid-ask spreads widen, price impacts are greater, and volume decreases. We examine the propensity of traders to switch trading locations to avoid the tax and find mixed evidence that they will change locations. Overall, our findings support the notion that the imposition of or increases in an STT harm market quality.</description><author>Pomeranets, Anna; Weaver, Daniel G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Premium Information from Treasury-Bill Yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Jaehoon
I find that short-maturity Treasury-bill yields have unique information about risk premiums that is not spanned by long-maturity Treasury-bond yields. I estimate 2 components of risk premiums: long term and short term. The long-term component steepens the slope of yield curves and has a forecastability horizon of longer than 1 year. In contrast, the short-term component affects Treasury-bill yields but is almost invisible from Treasury bonds, has a forecastability horizon of less than 1 quarter, and is related to bond liquidity premiums.</description><author>Lee, Jaehoon</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Innovation Strategy of Private Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Huasheng; Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Li, Kai
We compare innovation strategies of public and private firms based on a large sample over the period 1997-2008. We find that public firms' patents rely more on existing knowledge, are more exploitative, and are less likely in new technology classes, while private firms' patents are broader in scope and more exploratory. We investigate whether these strategies are due to differences in firm information environments, CEO risk preferences, firm life cycles, corporate acquisition policies, or investment horizons between these two groups of firms. Our evidence suggests that the shorter investment horizon associated with public equity markets is a key explanatory factor.</description><author>Gao, Huasheng; Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Li, Kai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Director Connectedness: Monitoring Efficacy and Career Prospects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Intintoli, Vincent J.; Kahle, Kathleen M.; Zhao, Wanli
We examine a specific channel through which director connectedness may improve monitoring: financial reporting quality. We find that the connectedness of independent, nonco-opted audit committee members has a positive effect on financial reporting quality and accounting conservatism. The effect is not significant for non-audit committee or co-opted audit committee members. Our results are robust to tests designed to mitigate self-selection. Consistent with connected directors being valuable, the market reacts more negatively to the deaths of highly connected directors than to the deaths of less connected directors. Better connected directors also have better career prospects, suggesting they have greater incentives to monitor.</description><author>Intintoli, Vincent J.; Kahle, Kathleen M.; Zhao, Wanli</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Financial Analysts Restrain Insiders' Informational Advantage?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellul, Andrew; Panayides, Marios
By collecting and disseminating price-sensitive information, financial analysts should reduce firm insiders' informational advantage with a consequent impact on trading dynamics and market quality. We empirically examine the impact of complete analysts' coverage termination on stocks' liquidity, price discovery, and insider trading profitability. Termination leads to deteriorating liquidity and price efficiency, more informed trading, and higher profitability of insider trades. The magnitude of these effects depends on the strength of insiders' ownership and on management's decision whether to improve the firm's information environment after coverage termination. Institutional investors alleviate, but do not eliminate, the negative effects of termination.</description><author>Ellul, Andrew; Panayides, Marios</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pitfalls in the Use of Systemic Risk Measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loeffler, Gunter; Raupach, Peter
We examine pitfalls in the use of return-based measures of systemic risk contributions (SRCs). For both linear and nonlinear return frameworks, assuming normal and heavy-tailed distributions, we identify nonexotic cases in which a change in a bank's systematic risk, idiosyncratic risk, size, or contagiousness increases the risk of the system but lowers the measured SRC of the bank. Assessments based on estimated SRCs could thus produce false interpretations and incentives. We also identify potentially adverse side effects: A change in a bank's risk structure can make the measured SRC of its competitors increase more strongly than its own.</description><author>Loeffler, Gunter; Raupach, Peter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Ratings the Worst Form of Credit Assessment Except for All the Others?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloechlinger, Andreas; Leippold, Markus
We present a prediction model to forecast corporate defaults. In a theoretical model, under incomplete information in a market with publicly traded equity, we show that our approach must outperform ratings, Altman's Z-score, and Merton's distance to default. We reconcile the statistical and structural approaches under a common framework; that is, our approach nests Altman's and Merton's approaches as special cases. Empirically, the combined approach is indeed the most powerful predictor, and the numbers of observed defaults align well with the estimated probabilities. With a new transformation method, we obtain cycle-adjusted forecasts that still outperform ratings.</description><author>Bloechlinger, Andreas; Leippold, Markus</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Ability and the Shareholder Tax Sensitivity of Dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guan, Jenny Xinjiao; Li, Oliver Zhen; Ma, Jiameng
We examine the impact of managerial ability on the shareholder tax sensitivity of dividends. We find that managerial ability increases the sensitivity of dividends to the dividend tax penalty. In addition, the positive association between managerial ability and the shareholder tax sensitivity of dividends decreases in institutional ownership. Further, managerial ability increases the shareholder tax sensitivity of the substitution of dividends with share repurchases. Finally, evidence from tax reforms reveals that high ability managers are more responsive to a reduction in dividend tax penalty than to an increase. We conclude that managerial ability influences the formation of tax-efficient dividend policies.</description><author>Guan, Jenny Xinjiao; Li, Oliver Zhen; Ma, Jiameng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Passive versus Active Fund Performance: Do Index Funds Have Skill?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crane, Alan D.; Crotty, Kevin
We apply methods designed to measure mutual fund skill to a cross section of funds that is unlikely to exhibit managerial portfolio selection skill: index funds. Surprisingly, these tests imply index fund skill exists, is persistent, and is in similar proportion as in active funds. We use the distribution of passive fund performance to gauge the incremental ability of active managers. Outperformance by top active funds is lower when benchmarked to the index fund distribution and disappears when we account for residual risk. Stochastic dominance tests suggest no risk-averse investor should choose a random active fund over a random index fund.</description><author>Crane, Alan D.; Crotty, Kevin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fiscal Policy, Consumption Risk, and Stock Returns: Evidence from US States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Warachka, Mitch; Yun, Hayong
We find that consumption risk is lower in states that implement countercyclical fiscal policies. Moreover, firms with an investor base that is concentrated in countercyclical states have lower stock returns, along with firms that relocate their headquarters to a countercyclical state. Therefore, countercyclical fiscal policies lower the consumption risk of investors and, consequently, their required equity return premium. This conclusion is confirmed by smaller declines in market participation during recessions in countercyclical states. Overall, the location of a firm's investor base enables state-level fiscal policy to influence stock returns.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Warachka, Mitch; Yun, Hayong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crash Risk in Currency Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernov, Mikhail; Graveline, Jeremy; Zviadadze, Irina
We develop an empirical model of bilateral exchange rates. It includes normal shocks with stochastic variance and jumps in an exchange rate and in its variance. The probability of a jump in an exchange rate corresponding to depreciation (appreciation) of the U.S. dollar is increasing in the domestic (foreign) interest rate. The probability of a jump in variance is increasing in the variance only. Jumps in exchange rates are associated with announcements; jumps in variance are not. On average, jumps account for 25% of currency risk. The dollar carry index retains these features. Options suggest that jump risk is priced.</description><author>Chernov, Mikhail; Graveline, Jeremy; Zviadadze, Irina</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flow-Induced Trading Pressure and Corporate Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lou, Xiaoxia; Wang, Albert Y.
The impact of liquidity-motivated institutional trading on firms' real decisions is not confined to periods of financial crisis. Firms subject to mutual fund flow-driven selling pressure reduce share issuance and investment, whereas firms experiencing buying pressure do not increase investment, although they issue more equity. Firms under extreme selling pressure cut quarterly investment by 0.075 percentage points of total assets, which is 4.3% of the average quarterly investment in our sample. We also find evidence that the effect is not attributed to managerial learning or catering incentives. Rather, flow-driven trading affects investment mainly through its impact on the financing cost.</description><author>Lou, Xiaoxia; Wang, Albert Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Liquidity Effects of Official Bond Market Intervention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Pooter, Michiel; Martin, Robert F.; Pruitt, Seth
To "ensure depth and liquidity," the European Central Bank intervened in sovereign debt markets through its Securities Markets Programme (SMP), providing a unique opportunity to estimate the effects of large-scale asset purchases on sovereign bond liquidity premia. From reduced-form estimates, we find robust, economically significant impact and lasting reductions in sovereign bonds' liquidity premia in response to official purchases. We develop a search-based asset-pricing model to understand our empirical results. The theory implies that bond liquidity premia fall in response to both official purchases and rising sovereign default probabilities, as seen in the data.</description><author>De Pooter, Michiel; Martin, Robert F.; Pruitt, Seth</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Commodities Add Economic Value inAsset Allocation? New Evidence from Time-Varying Moments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Xin; Nardari, Federico
We commodities in multiasset investment strategies that exploit the predictability of asset return moments. We find that predictability makes the inclusion of commodities profitable even when short selling and high leverage are not permitted. For instance, a mean-variance (non-mean-variance) investor with moderate risk aversion and leverage, rebalancing quarterly, would be willing to pay up to 108 (155) basis points per year after transaction cost for adding commodities to her stock, bond, and cash portfolio. Previous research had reached mixed or even opposite conclusions, especially in an out-of-sample context.</description><author>Gao, Xin; Nardari, Federico</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tips from TIPS: The Informational Content of Treasury Inflation-Protected Security Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Amico, Stefania; Kim, Don H.; Wei, Min
Treasury Inflation-Protected Securities (TIPS) are frequently thought of as risk-free real bonds. Using no-arbitrage term structure models, we show that TIPS yields exceeded risk-free real yields by as much as 100 basis points when TIPS were first issued and up to 300 basis points during the 2007-2008 financial crisis. This spread predominantly reflects the poorer liquidity of TIPS relative to nominal Treasury securities. Other factors, including the indexation lag and the embedded deflation protection in TIPS, play a much smaller role. Ignoring this spread also significantly distorts the informational content of TIPS break-even inflation, a widely used proxy for expected inflation.</description><author>D'Amico, Stefania; Kim, Don H.; Wei, Min</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Cultural Similarity on Mergers and Acquisitions: Evidence from Corporate Social Responsibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bereskin, Fred; Byun, Seong K.; Officer, Micah S.; Oh, Jong-Min
We study the effect of corporate cultural similarity on merger decisions and outcomes. Using the similarity in firms' corporate social responsibility characteristics to proxy for cultural similarity, we find that culturally similar firms are more likely to merge. Moreover, these mergers are associated with greater synergies, superior long-run operating performance, and fewer write-offs of goodwill. Our evidence is consistent with the notion that cultural similarity eases post-deal integration. Our results contribute to the literature on the determinants of merger success, provide new evidence on the impact of corporate culture, and offer a new approach to defining firms' cultural similarity.</description><author>Bereskin, Fred; Byun, Seong K.; Officer, Micah S.; Oh, Jong-Min</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Banks Grow Too Big for Their National Economies: Tail Risks, Risk Channels, and Government Guarantees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hagendorff, Jens; Keasey, Kevin; Vallascas, Francesco
Banks are growing ever larger compared to their national economies. We show that increases in relative bank size (measured as a bank's liabilities divided by national GDP) are linked to banks displaying higher tail risk. This effect is not entirely due to risk channels that disproportionately expose relatively large banks to systematic tail risks, sovereign risks, or banking crises. Instead, we detect a persistent component in the tail risk of relatively large banks that is bank-specific and connected to government guarantees. Furthermore, as banks grow in relative size, tail risks are shifted to debtholders without wealth gains for shareholders.</description><author>Hagendorff, Jens; Keasey, Kevin; Vallascas, Francesco</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Term Structure of Bond Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gehde-Trapp, Monika; Schuster, Philipp; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese
We analyze the impact of market frictions on the trading volume and liquidity premia of finite-maturity assets when investors differ in their trading needs. Our equilibrium model generates a clientele effect (frequently trading investors hold only short-term assets) and predicts i) a hump-shaped relation between trading volume and maturity, ii) lower trading volumes of older compared with younger assets, iii) an increasing liquidity term structure from ask prices, iv) a decreasing or U-shaped liquidity term structure from bid prices, and v) spillovers of liquidity from short-term to long-term maturities. Empirical tests for U.S. corporate bonds support our theoretical predictions.</description><author>Gehde-Trapp, Monika; Schuster, Philipp; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Compensation in Japan: Why So Different from the United States?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Luyao; Zhou, Xianming
In Mar. 2010, Japan's financial regulator implemented the country's first legislation concerning the disclosure of director compensation for named individuals. Using the first publicly available data for Japanese executives, we document direct evidence on the level, structure, and mechanisms of chief executive officer (CEO) compensation in Japan and perform a matched-sample comparison between Japan and the United States. In contrast to the findings of recent studies showing that international differentials in CEO pay have largely disappeared since the mid-2000s, our results show strikingly large differences between the Japanese and American systems that are difficult to explain by differences in conventional incentive contracts.</description><author>Pan, Luyao; Zhou, Xianming</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State Ownership and Corporate Cash Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Ruiyuan; El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Nash, Robert
Using a unique sample of newly privatized firms from 59 countries, this article provides new evidence about the agency costs of state ownership and new insight into the corporate governance role of country-level institutions. Consistent with agency theory, we find strong and robust evidence that state ownership is positively related to corporate cash holdings. Moreover, we find that the strength of country-level institutions affects the relation between state ownership and the value of cash holdings. In particular, as state ownership increases, markets discount the value of cash holdings more in countries with weaker institutions.</description><author>Chen, Ruiyuan; El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Nash, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Political Risk and Currency Momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Filippou, Ilias; Gozluklu, Arie E.; Taylor, Mark P.
Using a measure of political risk, relative to the United States, that captures unexpected political conditions, we show that political risk is priced in the cross section of currency momentum and contains information beyond other risk factors. Our results are robust after controlling for transaction costs, reversals, and alternative limits to arbitrage. The global political environment affects the profitability of the momentum strategy in the foreign exchange market; investors following such strategies are compensated for the exposure to the global political risk of those currencies they hold, that is, the past winners, and exploit the lower returns of loser portfolios. The risk compensation is mainly justified by the different exposures of foreign currencies in the momentum portfolio to U.S. political shocks, which is the main component of global political risk.</description><author>Filippou, Ilias; Gozluklu, Arie E.; Taylor, Mark P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Only Winners in Tough Times Repeat: Hedge Fund Performance Persistence over Different Market Conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Zheng; Wang, Ashley W.; Zheng, Lu
We provide novel evidence that hedge fund performance is persistent following weak hedge fund markets but is not persistent following strong markets. Specifically, we construct two performance measures, RET DOWN and RET UP, conditioned on the level of overall hedge fund sector returns. After adjusting for risks, funds in the highest RET DOWN quintile outperform funds in the lowest quintile by approximately 7% in the subsequent year, whereas funds with better RET UP do not outperform subsequently. The RET DOWN measure can predict future fund performance over a horizon as long as 3 years, for both winners and losers and for funds with few share restrictions.</description><author>Sun, Zheng; Wang, Ashley W.; Zheng, Lu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earthly Reward to the Religious: Religiosity and the Costs of Public and Private Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Feng; John, Kose; Li, C. Wei; Qian, Yiming
We document that a firm's culture, specifically, its religiosity, affects its cost of debt. Firms in higher-religiosity counties have higher credit ratings and lower debt costs. The impact of religiosity is stronger for firms with greater information asymmetry and during recessions. Further, religiosity has additional explanatory power for the cost of bank loans (but not the cost of public bonds) beyond its impact through ratings. This supports the argument that banks have superior abilities in pricing soft information, such as corporate culture. Finally, the impact of religiosity is stronger when the lender is a small bank.</description><author>Jiang, Feng; John, Kose; Li, C. Wei; Qian, Yiming</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Scarcity Value of Treasury Collateral: Repo-Market Effects of Security-Specific Supply and Demand Factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Amico, Stefania; Fan, Roger; Kitsul, Yuriy
We quantify the scarcity value of Treasury collateral by estimating the impact of security-specific demand and supply factors on the specific collateral repurchase agreement (repo) rates of all outstanding U.S. Treasury securities. We find a positive and significant scarcity premium for on-and off-the-run Treasuries that persists for approximately 3 months and is larger in magnitude for shorter-term securities. This scarcity effect seems to pass through to Treasury cash market prices, providing additional evidence for the scarcity channel of quantitative easing (QE). On the contrary, the Federal Reserve's reverse repo operations could help reduce the scarcity premium by alleviating potential shortages of high-quality collateral.</description><author>D'Amico, Stefania; Fan, Roger; Kitsul, Yuriy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Fund Boards and the Market for Independent Directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clifford, Christopher P.; Ellis, Jesse A.; Gerken, William C.
We provide the first examination of hedge fund boards and their directors. The majority of directorships are held by extremely busy independent directors. These directors are sought by funds because they have more reputational capital at stake, making them independent and credible monitors whose presence can certify fund quality to investors. Busy independent directors are more likely to be hired by high-quality funds, and their departure from the board is associated with investor withdrawals. Moreover, funds with busy independent directors are less likely to commit fraud, abuse discretionary liquidity restrictions, or engage in performance-based risk shifting.</description><author>Clifford, Christopher P.; Ellis, Jesse A.; Gerken, William C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Life-Cycle Asset Allocation with Ambiguity Aversion and Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peijnenburg, Kim
Ambiguity and learning about the equity premium can simultaneously explain the low fraction of financial wealth allocated to stocks over the life cycle and the stock market participation puzzle. Individuals are ambiguous about the size of the equity premium and are averse to this ambiguity, resulting in lower stock allocations over the life cycle, consistent with the data. As agents get older, they learn about the equity premium and increase their allocation to stocks. Furthermore, I find that ambiguity leads to underdiversification, home bias, lower Sharpe ratios, and higher savings. Similar results cannot be obtained by assuming higher risk aversion.</description><author>Peijnenburg, Kim</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Know Thy Neighbor: Industry Clusters, Information Spillovers, and Market Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engelberg, Joseph; Ozoguz, Arzu; Wang, Sean
Firms in industry clusters have market prices that are more efficient than firms outside clusters. To establish causality, we analyze exogenous firm relocations and find that firms that relocate into industry clusters have higher levels of industry information in their prices. We argue that geographical proximity allows for information spillovers, reducing marginal cost to information producers. Our evidence supports this view: Analysts are more likely to cover stocks inside industry clusters, and when institutional investors have a large position in one stock in the industry cluster, they are more likely to hold other stocks in the same industry cluster.</description><author>Engelberg, Joseph; Ozoguz, Arzu; Wang, Sean</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choosing the Precision of Performance Metrics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crane, Alan D.; Koch, Andrew; Wei, Chishen
There is a standard trade-off in compensation contracts between the provision of incentives and insurance. We hypothesize that this trade-off influences the precision with which firm performance is measured. We find that firm outcomes are measured less precisely when chance plays a large role in these outcomes. Further, this precision is determined through the choice of shares outstanding. This has several novel implications. Nominal stock prices can remain constant over time, and firms with unpredictable cash flows should have more shares and lower stock price levels, all else equal. We find evidence consistent with these implications.</description><author>Crane, Alan D.; Koch, Andrew; Wei, Chishen</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of State Solvency on Bank Values and Credit Supply: Evidence from State Pension Cut Legislation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lee Jeremy; Cornett, Marcia Millon; Mehran, Hamid; Tehranian, Hassan
We find the financial condition of states impacts bank credit supply through their municipal bond holdings. In particular, we treat sudden political and statutory actions during the 2011 union bargaining rights debates in Wisconsin and Ohio as exogenous shocks to state solvency. We show bank valuations and municipal bond spreads adjust to the announcements, and, over longer horizons, a new lending channel linked to state solvency emerges, whereby banks supply credit as municipal bond appreciations free up capital.</description><author>Cohen, Lee Jeremy; Cornett, Marcia Millon; Mehran, Hamid; Tehranian, Hassan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Data Providers as Information Intermediaries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schaub, Nic
This study investigates whether financial data providers serve as information intermediaries in capital markets. To this end, I examine whether the timeliness of earnings information disseminated by First Call (Thomson Reuters) affects the market's reaction to earnings announcements. I document that the immediate price and volume response is weaker and the post-earnings-announcement drift stronger for earnings news disseminated with a delay by First Call. To mitigate endogeneity concerns, I study the market reaction on the day of the delayed dissemination and show that a significant part of the stronger drift is clustered around this day.</description><author>Schaub, Nic</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Banks Price Independent Directors' Attention?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Henry He; Lobo, Gerald J.; Wang, Chong; Zhou, Jian
Masulis and Mobbs (2014), (2015) find that independent directors with multiple directorships allocate their monitoring efforts unequally based on a directorship's relative prestige. We investigate whether bank loan contract terms reflect such unequal allocation of directors' monitoring effort. We find that bank loans of firms with a greater proportion of independent directors for whom the board is among their most prestigious have lower spreads, longer maturities, fewer covenants, lower syndicate concentration, lower likelihood of collateral requirement, lower annual loan fees, and higher bond ratings. Our evidence indicates that independent directors' attention is associated with lower cost of borrowing.</description><author>Huang, Henry He; Lobo, Gerald J.; Wang, Chong; Zhou, Jian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, Investment Adjustment, and the Cost of Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Lixin; Kang, Qiang
Private information imposes a severe trading disadvantage on uninformed traders while at the same time providing firms with valuable signals for investment adjustment. The two forces have opposite impacts on the cost of capital, and the net effect depends on which force dominates. We show that stocks of firms with low flexibility in investment adjustment ("value firms") command an information premium, whereas stocks of firms with high flexibility in investment adjustment ("growth firms") deliver an information discount. These results are consistent with the findings that growth firms exhibit stronger investment sensitivity to information in stock prices than value firms.</description><author>Huang, Lixin; Kang, Qiang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium Price Dynamics of Emission Permits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hitzemann, Steffen; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese
This article presents a stochastic equilibrium model for environmental markets that allows us to study the characteristic properties of emission permit prices induced by the design of today's cap-and-trade systems. We characterize emission permits as highly nonlinear contingent claims on economy-wide emissions and reveal their hybrid nature between investment and consumption assets. Our model makes predictions about the dynamics and volatility structure of emission permit prices, the forward price curve, and the implications for option pricing in this market. Empirical evidence from existing emissions markets shows that the model explains the stylized facts of emission permit prices and related derivatives.</description><author>Hitzemann, Steffen; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technological Specialization and the Decline of Diversified Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anjos, Fernando; Fracassi, Cesare
We document a strong decline in corporate-diversification activity since the late 1970s, and we develop a dynamic model that explains this pattern, both qualitatively and quantitatively. The key feature of the model is that synergies endogenously decline with technological specialization, leading to fewer diversified firms in equilibrium. The model further predicts that segments inside a conglomerate should become more related over time, which is consistent with the data. Finally, the calibrated model also matches other empirical magnitudes well: output growth rate, market-to-book ratios, diversification discount, frequency and returns of diversifying mergers, and frequency of refocusing activity.</description><author>Anjos, Fernando; Fracassi, Cesare</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading in the Presence of Short-Lived Private Information: Evidence from Analyst Recommendation Changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kadan, Ohad; Michaely, Roni; Moulton, Pamela C.
We use a proprietary data set to test the implications of several asymmetric information models on how short-lived private information affects trading strategies and liquidity provision. Our identification rests on information acquisition before analyst recommendations are publicly announced. We provide the first empirical evidence supporting theoretical predictions that early-informed traders "sell the news" after "buying the rumor." Further, we find distinct profit-taking patterns across different classes of institutions. Uninformed institutions, but not individuals, emerge as de facto liquidity providers to better-informed institutions. Placebo tests confirm that these trading patterns are unique to situations in which some investors have a short-lived informational advantage.</description><author>Kadan, Ohad; Michaely, Roni; Moulton, Pamela C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Resilience to Banking Crises: The Roles of Trust and Trade Credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levine, Ross; Lin, Chen; Xie, Wensi
Are firms more resilient ot systemic banking crises in economies with higher levels of social trust? Using firm-level data in 34 countries from 1990 through 2011, we find that liquidity-dependent firms in high-trust countries obtain more trade credit and suffer smaller drops in profits and employment during banking crises than similar firms in low-trust economics. The results are consistent with the view that when banking crises block the normal bank-lending channel, greater social trust facilitates access to informal finance, cushioning the effects of these crises on corporate profits and employment.</description><author>Levine, Ross; Lin, Chen; Xie, Wensi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organization Capital and Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Kai; Qiu, Buhui; Shen, Rui
Using a sample of completed U.S. acquisition deals over the period 1984-2014, we find that acquirer organization capital as measured by capitalized selling, general, and administrative (SG&amp;A) expenses is associated with superior deal performance. We show that high organization-capital acquirers achieve significantly higher abnormal announcement period returns, and better post-merger operating and stock performance, than low organization-capital acquirers. Additional tests suggest a causal relation between acquirer organization capital and deal performance. We further show that post-merger, high organization-capital acquirers cut more on the cost of goods sold, invest more in SG&amp;A expenses, and achieve greater asset turnover and innovative efficiency.</description><author>Li, Kai; Qiu, Buhui; Shen, Rui</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Political Uncertainty, Family Control, and Investment Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amore, Mario Daniele; Minichilli, Alessandro
Estimating difference-in-differences models on a comprehensive data set of Italian companies, we provide novel insights into the literature on political uncertainty and firm investment. We first establish that local political uncertainty leads to declining investment. Next, we show that family control neutralizes this effect: Family firms are more likely than other firms to invest during politically uncertain times, especially when operating in industries dependent on public spending and/or managed by family members. Finally, we document that this investment resilience of family firms under political uncertainty translates into significantly greater profitability and growth.</description><author>Amore, Mario Daniele; Minichilli, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Playing Favorites? Industry Expert Directors in Diversified Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, Jesse A.; Fee, C. Edward; Thomas, Shawn
We examine the influence of outside directors' industry experience on segment investment, segment operating performance, and firm valuation for conglomerates. Given board composition is endogenous, we instrument for the presence of industry expert directors using the supply of experienced executives near conglomerate firms' headquarters. We find that industry expert representation on the board causes increased segment investment. Consistent with experienced directors playing favorites rather than acting as dispassionate advisors, segment profitability (firm value) is lower for segments (firms) with industry expert outside directors. We do not find analogous negative profitability or valuation effects of director experience for single-segment firms.</description><author>Ellis, Jesse A.; Fee, C. Edward; Thomas, Shawn</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unknown Unknowns: Uncertainty About Risk and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baltussen, Guido; van Bekkum, Sjoerd; van der Grient, Bart
Stocks with high uncertainty about risk, as measured by the volatility of expected volatility (vol-of-vol), robustly underperform stocks with low uncertainty about risk by 8% per year. This vol-of-vol effect is distinct from (combinations of) at least 20 previously documented return predictors, survives many robustness checks, and holds in the United States and across European stock markets. We empirically explore the pricing mechanism behind the vol-of-vol effect. The evidence points toward preference-based explanations and away from alternative explanations. Collectively, our results show that uncertainty about risk is highly relevant for stock prices.</description><author>Baltussen, Guido; van Bekkum, Sjoerd; van der Grient, Bart</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Evidence of Overbidding in M&amp;A Contests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Bodt, Eric; Cousin, Jean-Gabriel; Roll, Richard
Surprisingly few papers have attempted to develop a direct empirical test for overbidding in merger and acquisition contests. We develop such a test grounded on a necessary condition for profit-maximizing bidding behavior. The test is not subject to endogeneity concerns. Our results strongly support the existence of overbidding. We provide evidence that overbidding is related to conflicts of interest, but also some indirect evidence that it arises from failing to fully account for the winner's curse.</description><author>de Bodt, Eric; Cousin, Jean-Gabriel; Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetry in Stock Comovements: An Entropy Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Lei; Wu, Ke; Zhou, Guofu
We provide an entropy approach for measuring the asymmetric comovement between the return on a single asset and the market return. This approach yields a model-free test for stock return asymmetry, generalizing the correlation-based test proposed by Hong, Tu, and Zhou (2007). Based on this test, we find that asymmetry is much more pervasive than previously thought. Moreover, our approach also provides an entropy-based measure of downside asymmetric comovement. In the cross section of stock returns, we find an asymmetry premium: Higher downside asymmetric comovement with the market indicates higher expected returns.</description><author>Jiang, Lei; Wu, Ke; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Ability and the Shareholder Tax Sensitivity of Dividends (vol 53, pg 335, 2018)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guan, Jenny Xinjiao; Li, Oliver Zhen; Ma, Jiameng
nan</description><author>Guan, Jenny Xinjiao; Li, Oliver Zhen; Ma, Jiameng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Reaction to Bank Liquidity Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruno, Brunella; Onali, Enrico; Schaeck, Klaus
We measure market reactions to announcements concerning liquidity regulation, a key innovation in the Basel framework. Our initial results show that liquidity regulation attracts negative abnormal returns. However, the price responses are less pronounced when coinciding announcements concerning capital regulation are backed out, suggesting that markets do not consider liquidity regulation to be binding. Bank- and country-specific characteristics also matter. Liquid balance sheets and high charter values increase abnormal returns whereas smaller long-term funding mismatches reduce abnormal returns. Banks located in countries with large government debt and tight interbank conditions or with prior domestic liquidity regulation display lower abnormal returns.</description><author>Bruno, Brunella; Onali, Enrico; Schaeck, Klaus</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Risk-Taking Incentive and Firm Innovation: Evidence from FAS 123R</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mao, Connie X.; Zhang, Chi
We investigate how chief executive officers' (CEOs) risk incentive (VEGA) affects firm innovation. To establish causality, we exploit compensation changes instigated by the FAS 123R accounting regulation in 2005 that mandated stock option expensing at fair values. Our identification tests indicate a positive and causal effect of CEOs' VEGA on innovation activities. Furthermore, dampened managerial risk-taking incentive after the implementation of FAS 123R leads to a significant reduction in innovation related to firms' core business and explorative inventions. It implies that managers diversify their innovation portfolios and decrease explorative inventions to curtail business risk when their risk-taking incentive is reduced.</description><author>Mao, Connie X.; Zhang, Chi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Risk-Taking Incentives and Merger Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chen; Officer, Micah S.; Shen, Beibei
We provide evidence concerning the effect of managerial risk-taking incentives on merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) decisions and outcomes for different types of mergers: vertical, horizontal, and diversifying. Using chief executive officer (CEO) relative inside leverage to proxy for the incentives of risk-averse managers, we find that CEOs with higher inside leverage are more likely to engage in vertical mergers, and those mergers generate lower announcement returns for shareholders. This effect of CEO relative inside leverage on returns for shareholders in vertical acquisitions is more pronounced when the acquirer has a higher degree of informational opacity, weak governance, and excess cash.</description><author>Lin, Chen; Officer, Micah S.; Shen, Beibei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beta Matrix and Common Factors in Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, Seung C.; Horenstein, Alex R.; Wang, Na
We consider the estimation methods for the rank of a beta matrix corresponding to a multifactor model and study which method would be appropriate for data with a large number of assets. Our simulation results indicate that a restricted version of Cragg and Donald's (1997) Bayesian Information Criterion estimator is quite reliable for such data. We use this estimator to analyze some selected asset pricing models with U.S. stock returns. Our results indicate that the beta matrix from many models fails to have full column rank, suggesting that risk premiums in these models are underidentified.</description><author>Ahn, Seung C.; Horenstein, Alex R.; Wang, Na</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do IPOs Affect Market Price? Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shi, Song; Sun, Qian; Zhang, Xin
We examine whether sizable initial public offerings (IPOs) affect the whole market. Using a Chinese IPO sample, we find robust evidence that sizable IPOs depress the market price on not only the listing day but also the offering (subscription) day. The impact on the market is negatively correlated with IPO size on the listing day. However, this impact is largely transitory. The China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC) often places a moratorium on IPOs to support the market, which seems ineffective as the negative 1130 effect is transitory and moratoriums are not perceived as good news.</description><author>Shi, Song; Sun, Qian; Zhang, Xin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Interconnectedness between Financial Institutions with Bayesian Time-Varying Vector Autoregressions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geraci, Marco Valerio; Gnabo, Jean-Yves
We propose a market-based framework that exploits time-varying parameter vector autoregressions to estimate the dynamic network of financial spillover effects. We apply it to financials in the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index and estimate interconnectedness at the sectoral and institutional levels. At the sectoral level, we uncover two main events in terms of interconnectedness: the Long-Term Capital Management crisis and the 2008 financial crisis. After these crisis events, we find a gradual decrease in interconnectedness, not observable using the classical rolling-window approach. At the institutional level, our framework delivers more stable interconnectedness rankings than other comparable market-based measures.</description><author>Geraci, Marco Valerio; Gnabo, Jean-Yves</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Knowledge Protection Benefit Shareholders? Evidence from Stock Market Reaction and Firm Investment in Knowledge Assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qiu, Buhui; Wang, Teng
This article studies whether knowledge protection affects shareholder value and firms' investment in knowledge assets using the staggered adoptions and rejections of the inevitable disclosure doctrine (IDD) by U.S. state courts as exogenous changes in the level of knowledge protection. We find positive (negative) abnormal stock returns around the IDD adoption (rejection) day for firms headquartered in the state, and we uncover a positive IDD treatment effect on firms' investment in knowledge assets. Moreover, the effects on stock returns and knowledge assets investment are stronger in more knowledge-oriented industries and firms. Finally, enhancing knowledge protection does not discourage local entrepreneurial activity.</description><author>Qiu, Buhui; Wang, Teng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Default Swaps and Firm Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayanan, Rajesh; Uzmanoglu, Cihan
This article provides evidence that firm value declines when credit default swaps (CDSs) are initiated and that the effect is greater when CDS trading activity is higher. This decline, which arises from an increase in the cost of capital as opposed to a decrease in free cash flows, traces to a deterioration in the firm's credit quality and stock liquidity. Firm value declines less when CDS trading is likely to produce incremental information, suggesting that CDS trading has informational benefits for firm value. However, the evidence does not indicate that firm value increases because CDS availability facilitates investments.</description><author>Narayanan, Rajesh; Uzmanoglu, Cihan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Credit Competition on Banks' Loan-Loss Provisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dou, Yiwei; Ryan, Stephen G.; Zou, Youli
Exploiting differential interstate-branching deregulation across contiguous counties of adjacent states, we investigate the effect of entry threat on incumbent banks' loan-loss provisions. Incumbents exposed to entry threat have offsetting incentives; lower provisions make their loan-underwriting quality appear better, deterring entry, but make local economic conditions appear better, encouraging entry. We find that the incentive to increase apparent loan-underwriting quality dominates on average. We further find that this incentive is stronger in counties with a higher proportion of heterogeneous loans, while the other incentive dominates in counties with both low heterogeneous loans and highly volatile economic conditions.</description><author>Dou, Yiwei; Ryan, Stephen G.; Zou, Youli</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Pressure and Overnight Seasoned Equity Offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gustafson, Matthew T.
Between 2009 and 2014, 75% of seasoned equity offerings (SEOs) were announced and issued overnight, compared to 27% between 2000 and 2008. Overnight issuers obtain a higher SEO offer price because they experience more favorable pre-offer returns. Consistent with these favorable returns being due to the avoidance of pre-issue selling pressure, non-overnight issuers experience a 2.5% pre-issue stock-price decline that reverses within 7 days. This post-issue reversal is increasing in SEO offer size and bigger following large pre-issue price declines. In contrast, returns following overnight offerings are less positive and unrelated to SEO offer size or pre-issue returns.</description><author>Gustafson, Matthew T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Staying on Top of the Curve: A Cascade Model of Term Structure Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calvet, Laurent E.; Fisher, Adlai J.; Wu, Liuren
This paper specifies term structure dynamics by a recursive cascade of heterogeneously persistent factors. The cascade naturally orders economic shocks by their adjustment speeds, and generates smooth interest-rate curves in closed form. For a class of specifications, the number of parameters is invariant to the size of the state space, and the term structure converges to a stochastic limit as the state dimension goes to infinity. High-dimensional specifications fit observed term structure almost perfectly, match the observed low correlation between movements in different maturities, and produce stable interest-rate forecasts that outperform lower-dimensional specifications.</description><author>Calvet, Laurent E.; Fisher, Adlai J.; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Term Debt and Bank Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>du, Brian; Palia, Darius
The extant literature suggests that one of the main causes of the recent financial crisis was the excessive use of short-term debt by banks. Using a large sample of banks, we find that increases in repurchase agreements (repos) were recognized by external capital markets to increase bank risk in the pre-crisis period. In the crisis, we find a negative relationship between repos and risk. We attribute this result to evidence suggesting that "good" banks were able to continue funding their repos, whereas "bad" banks had to significantly decrease their repo funding.</description><author>du, Brian; Palia, Darius</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizational Form and Corporate Payout Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jordan, Bradford D.; Liu, Mark H.; Wu, Qun
We examine how organizational form affects corporate payouts. Conglomerates pay out more than pure plays in both cash dividends and total payouts (cash dividends plus share repurchases). Furthermore, their payouts are more sensitive to cash flows compared to pure-play firms. The sensitivity of payouts to cash flow increases as the cross-segment correlation in a conglomerate decreases. Corporate payouts increase after mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As), especially among M&amp;As in which acquirers and targets are less correlated. These results suggest that the coinsurance among different divisions of a conglomerate allows them to pay out more cash flow to their shareholders than pure-play firms.</description><author>Jordan, Bradford D.; Liu, Mark H.; Wu, Qun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Has the Value of Cash Increased Over Time?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, Thomas W.; Chang, Ching-Hung; Chi, Jianxin Daniel
The value of corporate cash holdings has increased significantly in recent decades. On average, $1 of cash is valued at $0.61 in the 1980s, $1.04 in the 1990s, and $1.12 in the 2000s. This increase is predominantly driven by the investment opportunity set and cash-flow volatility, as well as secular trends in product market competition, credit market risk, and within-firm diversification. We document a secular decrease in the speed of adjustment (SOA) in cash holdings, particularly for financially constrained firms with cash deficits, suggesting that capital market frictions can account for the trend in the value of cash holdings.</description><author>Bates, Thomas W.; Chang, Ching-Hung; Chi, Jianxin Daniel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short Covering Trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Duong, Truong X.; Huszar, Zsuzsa R.
Short sellers are known to have private information about security prices. Empirical evidence of short selling, however, is based on only half of short sellers' trading activity; specifically, the opening of the position. Using disclosed large-short-position data from the Japanese stock market, we provide the first detailed evidence of covering trades and find a positive reaction to short covering that only partially reverses. Although these results are consistent with substantial transaction costs for closing large short positions, they also reveal that some short sellers are privately informed about positive future events and have timing ability in covering positions.</description><author>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Duong, Truong X.; Huszar, Zsuzsa R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Characteristics and the Choice between IPOs and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; He, Jie; He, Shan; Nandy, Debarshi
Using unique U.S. Census data sets, we analyze how entrepreneurial firms' product market characteristics affect their choice between going public, being acquired, or remaining private. Size, total factor productivity (TFP), sales growth, capital expenditure, market share, access to private funding, and human capital intensiveness significantly increase a private firm's likelihood of an initial public offering (IPO) relative to an acquisition. Firms in industries with less information asymmetry and higher stock liquidity are more likely to choose an IPO over an acquisition. While TFP peaks around either form of exit, the rate of increase in TFP prior to acquisitions and the subsequent decrease is smaller than that around IPOs.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; He, Jie; He, Shan; Nandy, Debarshi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-Frequency Quoting: Short-Term Volatility in Bids and Offers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasbrouck, Joel
At subsecond horizons, bids and offers in U.S. equity markets are more volatile than what would be implied by long-term fundamentals. To assess costs and consequences, this paper suggests that traders' random delays (latencies) interact with quote volatility to generate execution price risk and relative latency costs. Analysis of the behavior of quote setters suggests that this volatility is more likely to arise from recurrent cycles of undercutting similar to the Edgeworth cycles found in product markets rather than mixed strategies of limit-order placement.</description><author>Hasbrouck, Joel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quiet Life No More? Corporate Bankruptcy and Bank Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gormley, Todd; Gupta, Nandini; Jha, Anand
Pursuing delinquent borrowers requires considerable effort, and creditors may lack the incentive to exert this costly effort in uncompetitive banking sectors. To examine this, we use a uniquely large data set of public and private corporate bankruptcy filings spanning a banking-sector reform that deregulated bank entry across different regions of India. We find that increased banking competition is associated with more firms seeking a stay on assets, a decline in bankruptcy duration, and a shift toward workouts rather than liquidations. The results are consistent with creditors exerting greater effort to pursue delinquent firms and resolve bankruptcies more quickly when competition increases.</description><author>Gormley, Todd; Gupta, Nandini; Jha, Anand</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Anatomy of a Credit Supply Shock: Evidence from an Internal Credit Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liberti, Jose Maria; Sturgess, Jason
We investigate how financial contracting interacts with lending-channel effects by tracing the anatomy of a credit supply shock using micro-level data from a multinational bank. Borrowers with stronger lending relationships, higher nonlending revenues, and those that pledge collateral, especially outside assets and real estate, experience less credit rationing. Consistent with a tightening of financing constraints post shock, borrower composition shifts toward larger and less risky firms, and loans exhibit higher collateralization rates. Our analysis highlights the value of relationships and suggests that relationship banking is a channel through which borrowers can mitigate lending-channel effects.</description><author>Liberti, Jose Maria; Sturgess, Jason</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A New Partial-Segmentation Approach to Modeling International Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karolyi, G. Andrew; Wu, Ying
We propose a new multi-factor model for international stock returns that includes size, value, and momentum factor portfolios and that builds them in a partial-segmentation capital market framework. Accounting for externalities driven by the incomplete accessibility to stocks and stock markets, our model not only captures strong common variation in international stock returns but also achieves low pricing errors and rejection rates relative to pure segmentation and pure integration models. This partial-segmentation approach is evaluated using monthly returns for over 37,000 stocks from 46 developed and emerging market countries over 2 decades and for a wide variety of test assets.</description><author>Karolyi, G. Andrew; Wu, Ying</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overnight Returns and Firm-Specific Investor Sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aboody, David; Even-Tov, Omri; Lehavy, Reuven; Trueman, Brett
We examine the suitability of using overnight returns to measure firm-specific investor sentiment by analyzing whether they possess characteristics expected of a sentiment measure. We document short-term overnight-return persistence, consistent with existing evidence of short-term persistence in the share demand of sentiment-influenced investors. We find that short-term persistence is stronger for harder-to-value firms, consistent with existing evidence that sentiment plays a larger role for such firms. We show that stocks with high (low) overnight returns underperform (outperform) over the longer term, consistent with prior evidence of temporary sentiment-driven mispricing. Overall, our evidence supports using overnight returns to measure firm-specific sentiment.</description><author>Aboody, David; Even-Tov, Omri; Lehavy, Reuven; Trueman, Brett</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Political Power of Nonfinancial Stakeholders Affect Firm Values? Evidence from Labor Unions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stanfield, Jared; Tumarkin, Robert
Whereas corporate political connections are known to enhance equity values, we demonstrate that union political activity can have the opposite effect. We examine the consequences of a recent Australian state law that restricts union political activity but does not change collective bargaining rights. In the wake of this law, the equity values of affected unionized firms significantly increase, and consistent with this market reaction, these firms are able to bargain for more favorable labor contracts than their unionized peers in other states. The evidence strongly suggests that unions use political activism to extract rents from shareholders and benefit their members.</description><author>Stanfield, Jared; Tumarkin, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crash Sensitivity and the Cross Section of Expected Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni; Ruenzi, Stefan; Weigert, Florian
This article examines whether investors receive compensation for holding crash-sensitive stocks. We capture the crash sensitivity of stocks by their lower-tail dependence (LTD) with the market based on copulas. We find that stocks with strong LTD have higher average future returns than stocks with weak LTD. This effect cannot be explained by traditional risk factors and is different from the impact of beta, downside beta, coskewness, cokurtosis, and Kelly and Jiang's (2014) tail risk beta. Hence, our findings are consistent with the notion that investors are crash-averse.</description><author>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni; Ruenzi, Stefan; Weigert, Florian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Short Sellers Trade on Private Information or False Information?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Purnanandam, Amiyatosh; Seyhun, H. Nejat
We investigate whether short sellers contribute toward the informational efficiency of market prices by trading on their private information or destabilize market prices by trading on rumors and false information. We find that short-selling activities are considerably informative about future stock returns when there is a higher likelihood of private information in stocks, as measured by insider-trading activities. Short sellers also bring considerable additional information to the market that is not fully captured by contemporaneous insider trading. Overall, these results suggest that on average, short sellers bring informational efficiency to market prices rather than destabilize them.</description><author>Purnanandam, Amiyatosh; Seyhun, H. Nejat</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes, Capital Structure Choices, and Equity Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faccio, Mara; Xu, Jin
We use a multitude of tax reforms across the Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Development (OECD) countries as natural experiments to estimate the market value of the tax benefits of debt financing. We report time-series evidence that tax reforms are followed by large changes in the value of corporate equity. However, the impact of tax reforms is greatly mitigated by the presence of leverage. The value of debt tax savings is greater among top taxpayers, among highly profitable firms, and in countries where tax laws are more strongly enforced. Importantly, the value of debt tax savings is in line with the benchmark implied by a traditional approach.</description><author>Faccio, Mara; Xu, Jin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Factors Do Not Span Their Basis Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, Mark; Saxena, Konark
To price assets with a parsimonious set of factor-mimicking portfolios, one typically identifies and weights well-diversified basis portfolios. Traditional weightings lead to factor-mimicking portfolios that are unlikely to price even the basis portfolios from which they are formed. We offer a method to combine basis portfolios into a single factor-mimicking portfolio that is closely linked to the optimal portfolio. In practice, this method improves the pricing accuracy of parsimonious factor models, even for anomaly portfolios formed from characteristics that are distinct from those underlying the basis portfolios.</description><author>Grinblatt, Mark; Saxena, Konark</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Text-Based Industry Momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoberg, Gerard; Phillips, Gordon M.
We test the hypothesis that low-visibility shocks to text-based network industry peers can explain industry momentum. We consider industry peer firms identified through 10-K product text and focus on economic peer links that do not share common Standard Industrial Classification (SIC) codes. Shocks to less visible peers generate economically large momentum profits and are stronger than own-firm momentum variables. More visible traditional SIC-based peers generate only small, short-lived momentum profits. Our findings are consistent with momentum profits arising partially from inattention to economic links of less visible industry peers.</description><author>Hoberg, Gerard; Phillips, Gordon M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deal Initiation in Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masulis, Ronald W.; Simsir, Serif Aziz
We investigate the effects of target initiation in M&amp;As. We find target-initiated deals are common and that important motives for these deals are target economic weakness, financial constraints, and negative economy-wide shocks. We determine that average takeover premia, target abnormal returns around merger announcements, and deal value to EBITDA multiples are significantly lower in target-initiated deals. This gap is not explained by weak target financial conditions. Adjusting for self-selection, we conclude that target managers' private information is a major driver of lower premia in target-initiated deals. This gap widens as information asymmetry between merger partners rises.</description><author>Masulis, Ronald W.; Simsir, Serif Aziz</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time Will Tell: Information in the Timing of Scheduled Earnings News</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Travis L.; So, Eric C.
Using novel earnings calendar data, we show that firms' advanced scheduling of earnings announcement dates foreshadows their earnings news. Firms that schedule later-than-expected announcement dates subsequently announce worse news than those scheduling earlier-than-expected announcement dates. Despite scheduling disclosures being observable weeks ahead of earnings announcements, we show that equity markets fail to reflect the information in these disclosures until the announcement itself. By also showing that option markets respond efficiently to volatility-timing information embedded in the same scheduling disclosures, we provide novel evidence that markets fail to react to information about future earnings despite investors immediately trading on the underlying signal.</description><author>Johnson, Travis L.; So, Eric C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Myopia and the Momentum Premium across International Equity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Docherty, Paul; Hurst, Gareth
Myopic investors focus on short-run price changes rather than long-term fundamental value, resulting in an overweighting of public information and a slow diffusion of fundamental news. Such processing of information can produce price drifts similar to those seen in behavioral models of momentum. We explore the impact of myopia over an international sample, finding that momentum is stronger in more myopic countries, and this relationship is magnified where the proportion of funds under delegated management is high. We therefore argue that investor myopia, which arises due to agency issues in delegated funds management, is an important determinant of momentum.</description><author>Docherty, Paul; Hurst, Gareth</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive Overconfidence and Securities Class Actions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Suman; Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Nanda, Vikram; Tham, Mandy
Overconfident CEOs/senior executives tend to have excessively positive views of their own skills and their company's future performance. We hypothesize that overconfident managers are more likely to engage in reckless or intentional actions/disclosures that give rise to securities class actions (SCAs). Empirical evidence is supportive: Overconfident CEOs/senior executives increase SCA likelihood, though litigation risk is ameliorated through improved governance, such as following the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002. Post-SCA, companies are less likely to hire an overconfident CEO. Following an SCA, overconfident CEOs appear to moderate behavior and to reduce their litigation risk.</description><author>Banerjee, Suman; Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Nanda, Vikram; Tham, Mandy</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Event-Related Exchange-Rate Forecasts Combining Information from Betting Quotes and Option Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanke, Michael; Poulsen, Rolf; Weissensteiner, Alex
Betting quotes provide valuable information on market-implied probabilities for outcomes of events such as elections or referendums, which may have an impact on exchange rates. We generate exchange-rate forecasts around such events based on a model that combines risk-neutral event probabilities implied from betting quotes with risk-neutral exchange-rate densities extracted from currency option prices. Its application to predict exchange rates around the Brexit referendum and the U.S. presidential elections shows that these forecasts, conditional on the respective outcomes, were accurate, and markets were able to separate their views on the likelihood and the impact of these events.</description><author>Hanke, Michael; Poulsen, Rolf; Weissensteiner, Alex</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Term Structure of Expected Recovery Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doshi, Hitesh; Elkamhi, Redouane; Ornthanalai, Chayawat
There is widespread agreement that corporate debts' recovery rates are time varying, but empirical work in this area is limited. We show that the joint information from the term structure of senior and subordinate credit default swaps can identify the level and the dynamics of recovery rates. We estimate a reduced-form no-arbitrage model on 46 firms across different industries. We find that the term structure of expected recovery rates is, on average, downward sloping. However, an inversion occurs during the 2008 crisis, suggesting the market expects higher recoveries conditional on short-term survival. The inversion is more pronounced for firms in distressed industries.</description><author>Doshi, Hitesh; Elkamhi, Redouane; Ornthanalai, Chayawat</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticipating Uncertainty: Straddles around Earnings Announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Chao; Xing, Yuhang; Zhang, Xiaoyan
Straddles on individual stocks generally earn negative and significant returns. However, average at-the-money straddles from 3 days before an earnings announcement to the announcement date yield a highly significant 3.34% return. The positive returns on straddles indicate that investors underestimate the magnitude of uncertainty around earnings announcements. We find that positive straddle returns are more pronounced for smaller firms and firms with higher volatility, higher kurtosis, more volatile past earnings surprises, and less trading volume/higher transaction costs. This suggests that when firm signals are noisy, and/or when it is costlier to trade, investors underestimate the uncertainty associated with earnings announcements.</description><author>Gao, Chao; Xing, Yuhang; Zhang, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary-Policy Rule as a Bridge: Predicting Inflation without Predictive Regressions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hua, Jian; Wu, Liuren
A major issue with predicting inflation rates using predictive regressions is that estimation errors can overwhelm the information content. This article proposes a new approach that uses a monetary-policy rule as a bridge between inflation rates and short-term interest rates and relies on the forward-interest-rate curve to predict future interest-rate movements. The 2-step procedure estimates the predictive relation not through a predictive regression but far more accurately through the contemporaneous monetary-policy linkage Historical analysis shows that the approach outperforms random walk out of sample by 30%-50% over horizons from 1 to 5 years.</description><author>Hua, Jian; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beta Active Hedge Fund Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duanmu, Jun; Malakhov, Alexey; McCumber, William R.
We reconsider whether hedge funds' time-varying risk factor exposures are predictive of superior performance. We construct an overall measure (BA) of fund managers and present evidence that top beta active managers deliver superior long-term out-of-sample performance compared to top alpha active managers. BA captures the time-varying nature of beta exposures and can be interpreted as a common factor of both systematic risk (SR) and (1 - R-2) measures. BA also compares favorably to extant measures of market timing, capturing the explanatory power of such measures of hedge fund performance.</description><author>Duanmu, Jun; Malakhov, Alexey; McCumber, William R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is It Who You Know or What You Know? Evidence from IPO Allocations and Mutual Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Chuan-Yang; Titman, Sheridan; Wang, Yuxi
Mutual fund managers with degrees from elite universities tend to outperform their counterparts from less elite universities. We show that the better performance of elite graduates is generated from their better connections with underwriters that facilitate allocations to underpriced initial public offerings (IPOs). Indeed, we find that the funds outperform only in months when they are connected to underwriters issuing IPOs. A strategy of buying mutual funds in months when they are connected to underwriters scheduled to issue IPOs generates significant abnormal returns, as high as 4.08% per annum in hot markets.</description><author>Hwang, Chuan-Yang; Titman, Sheridan; Wang, Yuxi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Monitoring on CEO Compensation in a Matching Equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaigneau, Pierre; Sahuguet, Nicolas
We consider a model of chief executive officer (CEO) selection, dismissal, and retention. Firms with larger blockholder ownership monitor more; they get more information about CEO ability, which facilitates the dismissal of low-ability CEOs. These firms are matched with CEOs whose ability is more uncertain. For retention purposes, the compensation of these CEOs is more sensitive to firm value and relatively less sensitive to business conditions. Moreover, these CEOs receive lower salaries when CEO skills are sufficiently transferable. A diffusion of best monitoring practices increases competition for CEOs and raises CEO pay in all firms, including those with unchanged monitoring ability.</description><author>Chaigneau, Pierre; Sahuguet, Nicolas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Right on Schedule: CEO Option Grants and Opportunism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daines, Robert M.; McQueen, Grant R.; Schonlau, Robert J.
After the public outcry over backdating, many firms began scheduling option grants. This eliminates backdating but creates other agency problems: Chief executive officers (CEOs) aware of upcoming option grants have an incentive to temporarily depress stock prices to obtain lower strike prices. We show that some CEOs have manipulated stock prices to increase option compensation, documenting negative abnormal returns before scheduled option grants and positive abnormal returns afterward. These returns are explained by measures of CEOs' incentives and ability to influence stock prices. We document several mechanisms used to lower stock price, including changing the substance and timing of disclosures.</description><author>Daines, Robert M.; McQueen, Grant R.; Schonlau, Robert J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Sentiment and Innovation Activities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dang, Tri Vi; Xu, Zhaoxia
We investigate potential mechanisms through which market-wide sentiment affects firms' innovation activities. We provide evidence for the financing channel by showing that financially constrained firms are more likely to issue equity and invest more in research and development (R&amp;D) than financially unconstrained firms at high market sentiment. Using time-varying manager sentiment measures, we find suggestive evidence for a sentiment spillover channel whereby market sentiment affects R&amp;D investments through influencing manager sentiment. Furthermore, better patent portfolios are produced from R&amp;D investments stimulated by high market sentiment. Market sentiment has a stronger impact on R&amp;D than the capital expenditures of financially constrained firms.</description><author>Dang, Tri Vi; Xu, Zhaoxia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Antitakeover Provisions Spur Corporate Innovation? A Regression Discontinuity Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Tian, Xuan
We study the effect of antitakeover provisions (ATPs) on innovation. To establish causality, we use a regression discontinuity approach that relies on locally exogenous variation generated by shareholder proposal votes. We find a positive, causal effect of ATPs on innovation. This positive effect is more pronounced in firms that are subject to a larger degree of information asymmetry and operate in more competitive product markets. The evidence suggests that ATPs help nurture innovation by insulating managers from short-term pressures arising from equity markets. Finally, the number of ATPs contributes positively to firm value for firms involved in intensive innovation activities.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Tian, Xuan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recruiting the CEO from the Board: Determinants and Consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoitash, Udi; Mkrtchyan, Anahit
We investigate an increasingly prevalent CEO succession strategy: recruiting CEOs from the board of directors (director-CEOs). Director-CEOs might be hired in a planned succession because they combine outsiders' new perspectives with insiders' firm-specific knowledge. Alternatively, directors may be recruited when the board is unprepared for a leadership change. We find that unplanned successions, in which director-CEOs are appointed as a "quick-fix" solution, result in a negative market reaction, deterioration in performance, and ill-fitting candidates with shorter tenures. Conversely, firms recruiting director-CEOs in planned successions perform similarly to other firms. We find no evidence that poor firm quality drives these results.</description><author>Hoitash, Udi; Mkrtchyan, Anahit</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage Effect, Volatility Feedback, and Self-Exciting Market Disruptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren
Equity index volatility variation and its interaction with the index return can come from three distinct channels. First, index volatility increases with the market's aggregate financial leverage. Second, positive shocks to systematic risk increase the cost of capital and reduce the valuation of future cash flows, generating a negative correlation between the index return and its volatility, regardless of financial leverage. Finally, large negative market disruptions show self-exciting behaviors. This article proposes a model that incorporates all three channels and examines their relative contribution to index option pricing and stock option pricing for different types of companies.</description><author>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Environmental Policy and Shareholder Value: Following the Smart Money</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernando, Chitru S.; Sharfrnan, Mark P.; Uysal, Vanap B.
We examine the value consequences of corporate social responsibility through the lens of institutional shareholders. We find a sharp asymmetry between corporate policies that mitigate the firm's exposure to environmental risk and those that enhance its perceived environmental friendliness ("greenness"). Institutional investors shun stocks with high environmental risk exposure, which we show have lower valuations, as predicted by risk management theory. These findings suggest that corporate environmental policies that mitigate environmental risk exposure create shareholder value. In contrast, firms that increase greenness do not create shareholder value and are also shunned by institutional investors.</description><author>Fernando, Chitru S.; Sharfrnan, Mark P.; Uysal, Vanap B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Reserves as a Hedge against Supply-Chain Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kulchania, Manoj; Thomas, Shawn
Deregulation of the trucking industry and significantly lowered transportation costs led to large, widespread, and plausibly exogenous reductions in inventory for U.S. firms, with consequent increased supply-chain disruption (SCD) costs. We find evidence that increased SCD costs help explain the puzzling long-term trend of increasing average U.S. firm cash holdings. We also find that firms facing higher expected costs of disruptions generally save more cash from capital freed up via supply-chain management innovations. Finally, we document significant postdisruption declines in cash holdings consistent with cash as a primary source of financing during disruptions.</description><author>Kulchania, Manoj; Thomas, Shawn</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Affects Innovation More: Policy or Policy Uncertainty?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Tian, Xuan; Xu, Yan
Motivated by a theoretical model, we examine for 43 countries whether it is policy or policy uncertainty that affects technological innovation more. Innovation activities, measured by patent-based proxies, are not, on average, affected by which policy is in place. Innovation activities, however, drop significantly during times of policy uncertainty measured by national elections. The drop is greater for more influential innovations (citations in the right tail, exploratory rather than exploitative innovations) and for innovation-intensive industries. We use close presidential elections and ethnic fractionalization to address endo-geneity concerns. We uncover the mechanism underlying the main result by showing that the number of patenting inventors decreases with policy uncertainty. Political compromise, we conclude, encourages innovation.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Tian, Xuan; Xu, Yan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Liquidity and Stock Price Crash Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Xin; Chen, Yangyang; Zolotoy, Leon
We find that stock liquidity increases stock price crash risk. To identify the causal effect, we use the decimalization of stock trading as an exogenous shock to liquidity. This effect is increasing in a firm's ownership by transient investors and nonblockholders. Liquid firms have a higher likelihood of future bad earnings news releases, which are accompanied by greater selling by transient investors, but not blockholders. Our results suggest that liquidity induces managers to withhold bad news, fearing that its disclosure will lead to selling by transient investors. Eventually, accumulated bad news is released all at once, causing a crash.</description><author>Chang, Xin; Chen, Yangyang; Zolotoy, Leon</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Foreign Institutional Investors Enhance Firm Innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luong, Hoang; Moshirian, Fariborz; Nguyen, Lily; Tian, Xuan; Zhang, Bohui
We examine the effect of foreign institutional investors on firm innovation. Using firm-level data across 26 non-U.S. economies between 2000 and 2010, we show that foreign institutional ownership has a positive, causal effect on firm innovation. We further explore three possible underlying mechanisms through which foreign institutions affect firm innovation: Foreign institutions act as active monitors, provide insurance for firm managers against innovation failures, and promote knowledge spillovers from high-innovation economies. Our article sheds new light on the real effects of foreign institutions on firm innovation.</description><author>Luong, Hoang; Moshirian, Fariborz; Nguyen, Lily; Tian, Xuan; Zhang, Bohui</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>DRIPs and the Dividend Pay Date Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, Henk; Koch, Paul D.
On the day that dividends are paid, we find a significant positive mean abnormal return that is completely reversed over the following days. This dividend pay date effect has strengthened since the 1970s and is consistent with the temporary price pressure hypothesis. The pay dale effect is concentrated among stocks with dividend reinvestment plans (DRIPs) and is larger for stocks with a higher dividend yield, greater DRIP participation, and greater limits to arbitrage. Over time, profits from a trading strategy that exploits this behavior are positively related to the dividend yield and spread and negatively associated with aggregate liquidity.</description><author>Berkman, Henk; Koch, Paul D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common Macro Factors and Currency Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Filippou, Ilias; Taylor, Mark P.
We study the role of domestic and global factors in the payoffs of portfolios mimicking carry, dollar-carry, and momentum strategies. Using factors summarizing large data sets of macroeconomic and financial variables, we find that global equity-market factors are predictive for carry-trade returns, whereas U.S. inflation and consumption variables drive dollar-carry-trade payoffs, momentum returns are predominantly driven by U.S. inflation factors, and global factors capture the countercyclical nature of currency premia. We also find predictability in the exchange-rate component of each strategy and demonstrate strong economic value for risk-averse investors with mean-variance preferences, regardless of base currency.</description><author>Filippou, Ilias; Taylor, Mark P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Constraints and Credit Card Delinquency: Evidence from Raising Minimum Payments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>d'Astous, Philippe; Shore, Stephen H.
We use credit card data to estimate the impact of increasing minimum payments on delinquency, payments, spending, and write-offs. Our identification strategy exploits an unusual institutional feature: Borrowers can use their account to make purchases with both revolving loans (on which minimum payments increased) and term loans (on which there was no change). Payment increases by delinquent borrowers are insufficient to match increasing minimums, resulting in lower cure rates and an increase in write-offs. Affected borrowers migrate away from these accounts by decreasing charges and increasing payments, consequently lowering the interest earned by the bank.</description><author>d'Astous, Philippe; Shore, Stephen H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected Business Conditions and Bond Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eriksen, Jonas N.
In this article, I study the predictability of bond risk premia by means of expectations to future business conditions using survey forecasts from the Survey of Professional Forecasters. I show that expected business conditions consistently affect excess bond returns and that the inclusion of expected business conditions in standard predictive regressions improve forecast performance relative to models using information derived from the current term structure or macroeconomic variables. The results are confirmed in a real-time out-of-sample exercise, where the predictive accuracy of the models is evaluated both statistically and from the perspective of a mean-variance investor that trades in the bond market.</description><author>Eriksen, Jonas N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payout Yields and Stock Return Predictability: How Important Is the Measure of Cash Flow?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eaton, Gregory W.; Paye, Bradley S.
We compare the stock return forecasting performance of alternative payout yields. The net payout yield produces more accurate forecasts relative to alternatives, including the traditional dividend yield. This remains true even after excluding several years during the Great Depression when issuance was unusually high. The measure of cash flow used to form the yield matters economically. Long-term investors' hedging demand for stock is considerably reduced when net payout, rather than dividends, serves as the cash-flow measure. An agent relying on an incorrect payout measure is willing to pay an economically significant "management fee" to switch to the optimal policy.</description><author>Eaton, Gregory W.; Paye, Bradley S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund Performance Evaluation and Best Clienteles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chretien, Stephane; Kammoun, Manel
This paper investigates investor disagreement and clientele effects in performance evaluation by developing a measure that considers the best potential clienteles of mutual funds. In an incomplete market under law-of-one-price (LOP) and no-good-deal conditions, we obtain an upper bound on admissible performance measures that identifies the most favorable alpha. Empirically, we find that a reasonable investor disagreement leads to generally positive performance for the best clienteles. Performance disagreement by investors can be significant enough to change the average evaluation of mutual funds from negative to positive, depending on the clienteles.</description><author>Chretien, Stephane; Kammoun, Manel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-Varying Beta and the Value Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Quo, Hui; Wu, Chaojiang; Yu, Yan
We model conditional market beta and alpha as flexible functions of state variables identified via a formal variable-selection procedure. In the post-1963 sample, the beta of the value premium comoves strongly with unemployment, inflation, and the price-earnings ratio in a countercyclical manner. We also uncover a novel nonlinear dependence of alpha on business conditions: It falls sharply and even becomes negative during severe economic downturns but is positive and flat otherwise. The conditional capital asset pricing model (CAPM) performs better than the unconditional CAPM, but this does not fully explain the value premium. Our findings are consistent with a conditional CAPM with rare disasters.</description><author>Quo, Hui; Wu, Chaojiang; Yu, Yan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tournament-Based Incentives, Corporate Cash Holdings ,and the Value of Cash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phan, Hieu V.; Simpson, Thuy; Nguyen, Hang T.
This research examines the relations between tournament-based incentives and corporate cash holdings and the value of cash. We find robust evidence that tournament-based incentives are positively related to cash holdings and the value of cash. Moreover, the effect of tournament-based incentives on the value of cash is stronger for financially constrained firms. Our evidence indicates that as tournament-based incentives motivate riskier corporate policy choices that lead to not only larger expected shareholder value but also greater cash-flow uncertainty, firms increase cash holdings to cushion potential liquidity shortfalls that may cause underinvestment.</description><author>Phan, Hieu V.; Simpson, Thuy; Nguyen, Hang T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Interpretation of Unanticipated News Arrivaland Analysts' Skill</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rubin, Amir; Segal, Benjamin; Segal, Dan
Analysts' functions are divided into discovery and interpretation roles, but distinguishing between the two is nontrivial. We conjecture that analysts' interpretation skill can be gauged by their forecast revisions following material unanticipated news, in particular, following nonearnings 8-K reports, which arrive at the market unexpectedly. We establish that unanticipated 8-Ks are informative for analysts and find that analysts who are more likely to revise their forecasts following unanticipated 8-Ks provide more timely and accurate forecasts. We document a positive association between analysts' tendency to react to unanticipated 8-Ks and market reaction to their recommendation changes, suggesting investors prefer these analysts' opinions.</description><author>Rubin, Amir; Segal, Benjamin; Segal, Dan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory Sanctions and Reputational Damage in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armour, John; Mayer, Colin; Polo, Andrea
We study the impact of the enforcement of financial regulation by the United Kingdom's regulatory authorities on the market price of penalized firms. Existing studies rely on analyses of multiple events that may distort the measurement of reputational losses. In the United Kingdom, the entire enforcement process involves only one public announcement and is accompanied by complete information on legal penalties. We find that reputational losses are nearly nine times the size of fines and are associated with misconduct harming customers or investors but not third parties.</description><author>Armour, John; Mayer, Colin; Polo, Andrea</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Performance of Short-Term Institutional Trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakrabarty, Bidisha; Moulton, Pamela C.; Trzcinka, Charles
Using a database of daily institutional trades, we document that a majority of short-term institutional trades lose money. In aggregate, over 23% of round-trip trades are held for less than 3 months, and the returns on these trades average 3.91% (nonannualized). These losses are pervasive across all types of stocks, with the lowest returns occurring in small stocks, value stocks, and low-momentum stocks. Short-term trades lose more in more volatile markets. Across funds, the worst short-term returns accrue to funds that do the most trading, and there is no evidence of persistent skill or disposition effect in short-term institutional trades.</description><author>Chakrabarty, Bidisha; Moulton, Pamela C.; Trzcinka, Charles</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interactions among High-Frequency Traders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benos, Evangelos; Brugler, James; Hjalmarsson, Erik; Zikes, Filip
Using unique transactions data for individual high-frequency trading (HFT) firms in the U.K. equity market, we examine the extent to which the trading activity of individual HFT firms is correlated with each other and the impact on price efficiency. We find that HFT order flow, net positions, and total volume exhibit significantly higher commonality than those of a comparison group of investment banks. However, intraday HFT order flow commonality is associated with a permanent price impact, suggesting that commonality in HFT activity is information based and so does not generally contribute to undue price pressure and price dislocations.</description><author>Benos, Evangelos; Brugler, James; Hjalmarsson, Erik; Zikes, Filip</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuations in Corporate Takeovers and Financial Constraintson Private Targets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greene, Daniel
I examine acquisitions of private firms by public acquirers to better understand the effects of financial constraints on the division of economic gains in takeovers. Empirical tests exploit interstate bank branching deregulation, which relaxes financial constraints on private firms and can strengthen their bargaining position in an acquisition. Using a proxy for the degree to which targets depend on acquirers for financing, I find that private targets depend less on acquirers as a result of interstate bank branching deregulation. Relaxing financial constraints on private targets leads to an increase in target valuation multiples and a decrease in acquirer wealth gains.</description><author>Greene, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Capital Market Anomalies Common to Equity and Corporate Bond Markets? An Empirical Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, Tarun; Goyal, Amit; Nozawa, Yoshio; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Tong, Qing
Corporate bond returns exhibit predictability in a manner consistent with efficient pricing. Many equity characteristics, such as accruals, standardized unexpected earnings, and idiosyncratic volatility, do not impact bond returns. Profitability and asset growth are negatively related to corporate bond returns. Because firms that are profitable or have high asset growth (and hence more collateral) should be less risky, with lower required returns, the evidence accords with the risk-reward paradigm. Past equity returns are positively related to bond returns, indicating that equities lead bonds. Cross-sectional bond return predictors generally do not provide materially high Sharpe ratios after accounting for trading costs.</description><author>Chordia, Tarun; Goyal, Amit; Nozawa, Yoshio; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Tong, Qing</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment Efficiency and Product Market Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoughton, Neal M.; Wong, Kit Pong; Yi, Long
Does more competition lead to more information production and greater investment efficiency? This question is largely unexplored in the finance literature. This article provides both a model and a series of extensive empirical tests. The model features a 2-stage Bayesian game in differentiated products market competition. We find that competition causes firms to acquire less information and investments to become more inefficient relative to a first-best case with the same market structure. Empirically, the panel regression analysis provides strong support for the theory and shows that investment is more efficient in concentrated industries.</description><author>Stoughton, Neal M.; Wong, Kit Pong; Yi, Long</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Uncertainty and IPO Activity: Evidence from US Gubernatorial Elections</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colak, Gonul; Durnev, Art; Qian, Yiming
We analyze initial public offering (IPO) activity under political uncertainty surrounding gubernatorial elections in the United States. There are fewer IPOs originating from a state when it is scheduled to have an election. To establish identification, we develop a neighboring-states method that uses bordering states without elections as a control group. The dampening effect of elections on IPO activity is stronger for firms with more concentrated businesses in their home states, firms that are more dependent on government contracts (particularly state contracts), and harder-to-value firms. This dampening effect is related to lower IPO offer prices (hence, higher costs of capital) during election years.</description><author>Colak, Gonul; Durnev, Art; Qian, Yiming</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Lottery-Demand-Based Explanation of the Beta Anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Murray, Scott; Tang, Yi
The low (high) abnormal returns of stocks with high (low) beta, which we refer to as the beta anomaly, is one of the most persistent anomalies in empirical asset pricing research. This article demonstrates that investors' demand for lottery-like stocks is an important driver of the beta anomaly. The beta anomaly is no longer detected when beta-sorted portfolios are neutralized to lottery demand, regression specifications control for lottery demand, or factor models include a lottery demand factor. The beta anomaly is concentrated in stocks with low levels of institutional ownership and it exists only when the price impact of lottery demand is concentrated in high-beta stocks.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Murray, Scott; Tang, Yi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Unintended Consequences of the Launch of the Single Supervisory Mechanism in Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fiordelisi, Franco; Ricci, Ornello; Lopes, Francesco Saverio Stentella
The launch of the Single Supervisory Mechanism (SSM) was an historic event. Beginning in Nov. 2014, the most significant banks came under the direct supervision of the European Central Bank (ECB), while national supervisory authorities (NSAs) maintained direct supervision of the remaining banks. Thus, supervision is conducted on two levels, which could cause inconsistency problems. Did the behavior of the significant banks differ from that of the less significant banks during the SSM launch? We find that the significant banks reduced their lending activity more than the less significant banks did in order to shrink their balance sheets and increase their capitalization.</description><author>Fiordelisi, Franco; Ricci, Ornello; Lopes, Francesco Saverio Stentella</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Horses for Courses: Fund Managers and Organizational Structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Yufeng; Noe, Tom; Rebello, Michael
We model and test the relations between the team management of mutual funds, managers' ability, performance, and holdings. Our model predicts that team-managed funds perform better and behave more conservatively than single-manager funds. However, the effect of team management is masked in equilibrium because high-ability managers rationally self-select into single-manager funds. Consistent with the model's prediction, we find that team-managed funds perform better and deviate less from their benchmark allocations than single-manager funds with the same characteristics. These differences are marked after we control for the endogenous self-selection of managers.</description><author>Han, Yufeng; Noe, Tom; Rebello, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Investor Expectations, Manager Performance, and Fund Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Howard; Martinez, Jose Vicente
Using survey data, we analyze institutional investors' expectations about the future performance of fund managers and the impact of those expectations on asset allocation decisions. We find that institutional investors allocate funds mainly on the basis of fund managers' past performance and of investment consultants' recommendations, but not because they extrapolate their expectations from these. This suggests that institutional investors base their investment decisions on the most defensible variables at their disposal and supports the existence of agency considerations in their decision making.</description><author>Jones, Howard; Martinez, Jose Vicente</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity Volatility Term Structures and the Cross Section of Option Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vasquez, Aurelio
The slope of the implied volatility term structure is positively related to future option returns. I rank firms based on the slope of the volatility term structure and analyze the returns for straddle portfolios. Straddle portfolios with high slopes of the volatility term structure outperform straddle portfolios with low slopes by an economically and statistically significant amount. The results are robust to different empirical setups and are not explained by traditional factors, higher-order option factors, or jump risk.</description><author>Vasquez, Aurelio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cultural Proximity and the Processing of Financial Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Qianqian; Yu, Frank; Yu, Xiaoyun
This paper examines how culture affects information asymmetry in financial markets. We extract firms traded in the United States but headquartered in regions sharing Chinese culture ("Chinese firms"), and we manually identify a group of U.S. analysts of Chinese ethnic origin ("Chinese analysts"). We find that Chinese analysts issue more accurate forecasts on Chinese firms than non-Chinese analysts. The effect is stronger among firms with less transparent information environments. Further evidence suggests that cultural proximity can go beyond language commonality and analysts' pre-existing channels for information. Market reaction is stronger when Chinese analysts issue favorable forecast revisions or upgrades about Chinese firms.</description><author>Du, Qianqian; Yu, Frank; Yu, Xiaoyun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Explains the Difference in Leverage between Banks and Nonbanks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berg, Tobias; Gider, Jasmin
Banks have much more leverage than nonbanks. In this article, we use a joint sample of banks and nonbanks between 1965 and 2013 to analyze the determinants of this leverage difference. We find that a single factor, asset risk, is able to explain up to 90% of this difference. Banks' assets consist of a diversified portfolio of nonbank debt. Therefore, banks have much lower asset risk than do nonbanks. Because asset risk is a major determinant of capital structure choice, this factor is able to explain a large fraction of the difference between bank and nonbank leverage.</description><author>Berg, Tobias; Gider, Jasmin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Turnovers and Disruptions in Customer-Supplier Relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Intintoli, Vincent J.; Serfling, Matthew; Shaikh, Sarah
Events that disrupt customer-supplier relationships pose a source of risk for suppliers that depend on a customer for a large portion of their revenues. We identify the replacement of a customer's chief executive officer (CEO) as a disruptive event that results in suppliers losing substantial sales. These losses are greater when an incumbent customer CEO is more likely to be entrenched and stem largely from the successor divesting assets. Finally, we document that losses in sales following a customer CEO turnover lead to declines in a supplier's financial performance and that suppliers experience negative abnormal stock returns to announcements of customer CEO departures.</description><author>Intintoli, Vincent J.; Serfling, Matthew; Shaikh, Sarah</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deleveraging Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Richardson, Scott; Saffi, Pedro A. C.; Sigurdsson, Kari
Deleveraging risk is the risk attributable to investing in a security held by levered investors. When there is an aggregate negative shock to the availability of funding capital, securities with a greater presence of levered investors experience extreme return realizations as these investors unwind their positions. Using data on equity loans as a proxy for the degree of levered positions in a given stock, we find robust evidence of deleveraging risk. Stocks with a high degree of short selling experience large positive returns and a decrease in short selling around periods of funding capital scarcity.</description><author>Richardson, Scott; Saffi, Pedro A. C.; Sigurdsson, Kari</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Premia and the VIX Term Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Travis L.
The shape of the Chicago Board Options Exchange Volatility Index (VIX) term structure conveys information about the price of variance risk rather than expected changes in the VIX, a rejection of the expectations hypothesis. The second principal component, SLOPE, summarizes nearly all this information, predicting the excess returns of synthetic Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P) 500 variance swaps, VIX futures, and S&amp;P 500 straddles for all maturities and to the exclusion of the rest of the term structure. SLOPE's predictability is incremental to other proxies for the conditional variance risk premia, economically significant, and inconsistent with standard asset pricing models.</description><author>Johnson, Travis L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Davids, Goliaths, and Business Cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duarte, Jefferson; Kapadia, Nishad
We show that a simple, intuitive variable, Goliath versus David (GVD), reflects time variation in discount rates related to changes in aggregate business conditions. GVD is the annual change in the weight of the largest 250 firms in the aggregate stock market and is motivated by research that shows that small firms are more severely impacted than large firms by economic shocks due to differences in access to external finance. We find that GVD is the best single predictor of out-of-sample market returns among traditional predictors, predicting quarterly market returns with an out-of-sample R-2 of 6.3% in the 1976-2011 evaluation period.</description><author>Duarte, Jefferson; Kapadia, Nishad</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Analysis of Market Segmentation on US Equity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hatheway, Frank; Kwan, Amy; Zheng, Hui
We examine the impact of trading on markets partially exempt from National Market System requirements ("dark venues") on equity-market quality. We find evidence consistent with the notion that dark venues rely on their special features to segregate order flow based on asymmetric information risk, which results in their transactions being less informed and contributing less to price discovery on the consolidated market. Except for the execution of large transactions and trading in small stocks, the effects of dark-venue order segmentation are damaging to overall market quality. Our results have important implications for the regulation of international equity markets.</description><author>Hatheway, Frank; Kwan, Amy; Zheng, Hui</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Risk Culture</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Yihui; Siegel, Stephan; Wang, Tracy Yue
We examine the formation and evolution of corporate risk culture, that is, the preferences toward risk and uncertainty shared by a firm's leaders, as well as its effect on corporate policies. We document persistent commonality in risk attitudes inside firms, which arises through the selection of leaders with similar preferences and is rooted in the founders' risk attitudes. Changes in corporate risk culture over time affect corporate investment policies, whereas cross-sectional differences in founders' risk attitudes, that is, firms' initial risk culture, contribute to differences across firms in persistent firm policies, such as research and development intensity.</description><author>Pan, Yihui; Siegel, Stephan; Wang, Tracy Yue</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did Saving Wall Street Really Save Main Street? The Real Effects of TARP on Local Economic Conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Roman, Raluca A.
We investigate whether saving Wall Street through TARP really saved Main Street during the recent financial crisis. Our difference-in-difference analysis suggests that TARP statistically and economically significantly increased net job creation and net hiring establishments and decreased business and personal bankruptcies. The results are robust, including accounting for endogeneity. The main mechanisms driving the results appear to be increases in commercial real estate lending and off-balance-sheet real estate guarantees. These results suggest that saving Wall Street via TARP may have helped save Main Street, complementing the TARP literature and contributing to the cost-benefit debate.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Roman, Raluca A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-Disaggregated Dividend-Price Ratio and Dividend Growth Predictability in Large Equity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asimakopoulos, Panagiotis; Asimakopoulos, Stylianos; Kourogenis, Nikolaos; Tsiritakis, Emmanuel
We consistently show that in large equity markets, the dividend-price ratio is significantly related to the growth of future dividends. To uncover this relation, we use monthly dividends and a mixed data sampling technique, which allows us to address within-year seasonality. Our approach avoids the use of overlapping observations and at the same time reduces the impact of price volatility on the dividend-price ratio. An empirical analysis using market-level data from the United States, United Kingdom, Canada, and Japan strongly supports the dividend growth predictability hypothesis, suggesting that time aggregation of dividends eliminates significant information.</description><author>Asimakopoulos, Panagiotis; Asimakopoulos, Stylianos; Kourogenis, Nikolaos; Tsiritakis, Emmanuel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-Term versus Short-Term contingencies in Asset Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Botshekan, Mahmoud; Lucas, Andre
We investigate whether long-term and short-term components of typical conditioning variables in asset pricing studies, such as the dividend yield or yield spread, have different implications for optimal asset allocation. We argue that short-term components relate mostly to momentum, and long-term components relate mostly to mean-reversion effects, respectively. Therefore, they may have a different information content for investors with different horizons. We obtain improvements in terms of out-of-sample Sharpe ratios and expected utilities for decomposed state variables that directly reflect information related to the stock market, such as the dividend yield and stock market trend.</description><author>Botshekan, Mahmoud; Lucas, Andre</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Multivariate Model of Strategic Asset Allocation with Longevity Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bisetti, Emilio; Favero, Carlo A.; Nocera, Giacomo; Tebaldi, Claudio
Population-wide increase in life expectancy is a source of aggregate risk. Longevity-linked securities are a natural instrument to reallocate that risk. This paper extends the standard Campbell-Viceira (2005) strategic asset allocation model by including a longevity-linked investment possibility. Model estimation, based on prices for standardized annuities publicly offered by U.S. insurance companies, shows that aggregate shocks to survival probabilities are predictors for long-term returns of the longevity-linked securities, and reveals an unexpected predictability pattern. Valuation of longevity risk premium confirms that longevity-linked securities offer inexpensive funding opportunities to asset managers.</description><author>Bisetti, Emilio; Favero, Carlo A.; Nocera, Giacomo; Tebaldi, Claudio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial Litigation and Venture Capital Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, Douglas; Haslem, Bruce; Knill, April
This article empirically examines the interaction between entrepreneurial plaintiff firm litigation and venture capital (VC). The data indicate that, relative to nonplaintiffs, firms that litigate prior to (after) obtaining VC i) receive financing from less (more) reputable venture capitalists (VCs), ii) are subject to greater (similar) oversight by VCs, iii) receive less (more) VC funding, iv) are more likely to exit through an initial public offering than through an acquisition, and v) are less likely to be liquidated when litigation occurs after VC financing. The results are robust to different specifications, methodologies, and endogeneity checks.</description><author>Cumming, Douglas; Haslem, Bruce; Knill, April</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Co Margin</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lopez, Jorge A. Cruz; Harris, Jeffrey H.; Hurlin, Christophe; Perignon, Christophe
We present CoMargin, a new methodology to estimate collateral requirements in derivatives central counterparties (CCPs). CoMargin depends on both the tail risk of a given market participant and its interdependence with other participants. Our approach internalizes trading externalities and enhances the stability of CCPs, thus reducing systemic risk concerns. We assess our methodology using proprietary data from the Canadian Derivatives Clearing Corporation that include daily observations of the actual trading positions of all of its members from 2003 to 2011. We show that CoMargin outperforms existing margining systems by stabilizing the probability and minimizing the shortfall of simultaneous margin-exceeding losses.</description><author>Lopez, Jorge A. Cruz; Harris, Jeffrey H.; Hurlin, Christophe; Perignon, Christophe</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Fund Return Dependence: Model Misspecification or Liquidity Spirals?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sias, Richard; Turtle, Harry J.; Zykaj, Blerina
We test whether model misspecification or liquidity spirals primarily explain the observed excess dependence in filtered (for economic fundamentals) hedge fund index returns and the links between volatility, liquidity shocks, and hedge fund return clustering. Evidence supports the model misspecification hypothesis: i) hedge fund filtered return clustering is symmetric, ii) filtered Short Bias fund returns exhibit negative dependence with filtered returns for other hedge fund types, iii) negative liquidity shocks are associated with clustering in both tails and market volatility subsumes the role of negative liquidity shocks, and iv) these same patterns appear in size-sorted equity portfolios.</description><author>Sias, Richard; Turtle, Harry J.; Zykaj, Blerina</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium-Informed Trading with Relative Performance Measurement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qiu, Zhigang
This article analyzes the informative trading of professional money managers within a rational-expectations equilibrium model in which managers care about their performance relative to their peer group. I find that the existence of uninformed managers causes informed managers with relative performance concerns to trade less informatively, engendering less informative prices. When managers are differentially informed, they need to forecast the average performance based on private signals, and each manager may place more weight on the private signal if the signal provides good information about the average performance. The price aggregates those signals and thus becomes more informative.</description><author>Qiu, Zhigang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Information Asymmetry Affect Corporate Tax Aggressiveness?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Tao; Lin, Chen
We investigate the effect of information asymmetry on corporate tax avoidance. Using a difference-in-differences matching estimator to assess the effects of changes in analyst coverage caused by broker closures and mergers, we find that firms avoid tax more aggressively after a reduction in analyst coverage. We further find that this effect is mainly driven by firms with higher existing tax-planning capacity (e.g., tax-haven presence), smaller initial analyst coverage, and a smaller number of peer firms. Moreover, the effect is more pronounced in industries where reputation matters more and in firms subject to less monitoring from tax authorities.</description><author>Chen, Tao; Lin, Chen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>To Group or Not to Group? Evidence from Mutual Fund Databases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patel, Saurin; Sarkissian, Sergei
Despite the overwhelming trend in mutual funds toward team management, empirical studies find no performance benefits for this phenomenon. We show it is caused by large discrepancies in reported managerial structures in Center for Research in Security Prices and Morningstar Principia data sets versus U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission records, resulting in up to 50-basis-points underestimation of the team impact on fund returns. Using more accurate Morningstar Direct data, we find that team-managed funds outperform single-managed funds across various performance metrics. The relation between team size and fund performance is nonlinear. Also, team-managed funds take on no more risk than single-managed funds. Overall, team management benefits fund industry performance.</description><author>Patel, Saurin; Sarkissian, Sergei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Risk Premia in the Fixed-Income Markets: The Intraday Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balduzzi, Pierluigi; Moneta, Fabio
We use high-frequency data to precisely estimate bond price reactions to macroeconomic announcements and the associated compensation for macro risks. We find evidence of a single factor summarizing the reaction of bond prices to different announcements. Before the financial crisis, the factor risk premium is substantial, significant, and mainly earned before announcement releases. After the crisis, the stock-bond covariance becomes negative and the preannouncement factor risk premium becomes insignificant. Our empirical results are consistent with information leakages that take place ahead of announcement releases and with the implications of a long-run risks model of bond risk premia.</description><author>Balduzzi, Pierluigi; Moneta, Fabio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>