<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Finance3</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Financial Distress and the Cross-section of Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Yan, Hong
We explicitly consider financial leverage in a simple equity valuation model and study the cross-sectional implications of potential shareholder recovery upon resolution of financial distress. Our model is capable of simultaneously explaining lower returns for financially distressed stocks, stronger book-to-market effects for firms with high default likelihood, and the concentration of momentum profits among low credit quality firms. The model further predicts (i) a hump-shaped relationship between value premium and default probability, and (ii) stronger momentum profits for nearly distressed firms with significant prospects for shareholder recovery. Our empirical analysis strongly confirms these novel predictions.</description><author>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Yan, Hong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Internal Governance of Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Myers, Stewart C.; Rajan, Raghuram G.
We develop a model of internal governance where the self-serving actions of top management are limited by the potential reaction of subordinates. Internal governance can mitigate agency problems and ensure that firms have substantial value, even with little or no external governance by investors. External governance, even if crude and uninformed, can complement internal governance and improve efficiency. This leads to a theory of investment and dividend policy, in which dividends are paid by self-interested CEOs to maintain a balance between internal and external control.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Myers, Stewart C.; Rajan, Raghuram G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Buyouts (Still) Create Value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Shourun; Hotchkiss, Edith S.; Song, Weihong
We examine how leveraged buyouts from the most recent wave of public to private transactions created value. Buyouts completed between 1990 and 2006 are more conservatively priced and less levered than their predecessors from the 1980s. For deals with post-buyout data available, median market- and risk-adjusted returns to pre- (post-) buyout capital invested are 72.5% (40.9%). In contrast, gains in operating performance are either comparable to or slightly exceed those observed for benchmark firms. Increases in industry valuation multiples and realized tax benefits from increasing leverage, while private, are each economically as important as operating gains in explaining realized returns.</description><author>Guo, Shourun; Hotchkiss, Edith S.; Song, Weihong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy and the Collateral Channel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benmelech, Efraim; Bergman, Nittai K.
Do bankrupt firms impose negative externalities on their nonbankrupt competitors? We propose and analyze a collateral channel in which a firm's bankruptcy reduces the collateral value of other industry participants, thereby increasing their cost of debt financing. We identify the collateral channel using novel data of secured debt tranches issued by U.S. airlines that include detailed descriptions of the underlying collateral pools. Our estimates suggest that industry bankruptcies have a sizeable impact on the cost of debt financing of other industry participants. We discuss how the collateral channel may lead to contagion effects that amplify the business cycle during industry downturns.</description><author>Benmelech, Efraim; Bergman, Nittai K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intermediated Investment Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoughton, Neal M.; Wu, Youchang; Zechner, Josef
Intermediaries such as financial advisers serve as an interface between portfolio managers and investors. A large fraction of their compensation is often provided through kickbacks from the portfolio manager. We provide an explanation for the widespread use of intermediaries and kickbacks. Depending on the degree of investor sophistication, kickbacks are used either for price discrimination or aggressive marketing. We explore the effects of these arrangements on fund size, flows, performance, and investor welfare. Kickbacks allow higher management fees to be charged, thereby lowering net returns. Competition among active portfolio managers reduces kickbacks and increases the independence of advisory services.</description><author>Stoughton, Neal M.; Wu, Youchang; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Illiquidity of Corporate Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bao, Jack; Pan, Jun; Wang, Jiang
This paper examines the illiquidity of corporate bonds and its asset-pricing implications. Using transactions data from 2003 to 2009, we show that the illiquidity in corporate bonds is substantial, significantly greater than what can be explained by bid-ask spreads. We establish a strong link between bond illiquidity and bond prices. In aggregate, changes in market-level illiquidity explain a substantial part of the time variation in yield spreads of high-rated (AAA through A) bonds, overshadowing the credit risk component. In the cross-section, the bond-level illiquidity measure explains individual bond yield spreads with large economic significance.</description><author>Bao, Jack; Pan, Jun; Wang, Jiang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are All Inside Directors the Same? Evidence from the External Directorship Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masulis, Ronald W.; Mobbs, Shawn
Agency theory and optimal contracting theory posit opposing roles and shareholder wealth effects for corporate inside directors. We evaluate these theories using the market for outside directorships to differentiate among inside directors. Firms with inside directors holding outside directorships have better operating performance and market-to-book ratios, especially when monitoring is more difficult. These firms make better acquisition decisions, have greater cash holdings, and overstate earnings less often. Announcements of outside board appointments improve shareholder wealth, while departure announcements reduce it, consistent with these inside directors improving board performance and outside directorships being an important source of inside director incentives.</description><author>Masulis, Ronald W.; Mobbs, Shawn</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Watch What I Do, Not What I Say: The Unintended Consequences of the Homeland Investment Act</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dharmapala, Dhammika; Foley, C. Fritz; Forbes, Kristin J.
The Homeland Investment Act provided a tax holiday for the repatriation of foreign earnings. Advocates argued the Act would alleviate financial constraints by reducing the cost to U.S. multinationals of accessing internal capital. This paper shows that repatriations did not increase domestic investment, employment, or R&amp;D-even for firms that appeared to be financially constrained or lobbied for the holiday. Instead, a $1 increase in repatriations was associated with a $0.60 to $0.92 increase in shareholder payouts. Regulations intended to restrict such payouts were undermined by the fungibility of money. Results indicate that U.S. multinationals were not financially constrained and were well-governed.</description><author>Dharmapala, Dhammika; Foley, C. Fritz; Forbes, Kristin J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Municipal Debt and Marginal Tax Rates: Is There a Tax Premium in Asset Prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, Francis A.
We study the marginal tax rate incorporated into short-term municipal rates using municipal swap market data. Using an affine model, we identify the marginal tax rate and the credit/liquidity spread in 1-week tax-exempt rates, as well as their associated risk premia. The marginal tax rate averages 38.0% and is related to stock, bond, and commodity returns. The tax risk premium is negative, consistent with the strong countercyclical nature of after-tax fixed-income cash flows. These results demonstrate that tax risk is a systematic asset pricing factor and help resolve the muni-bond puzzle.</description><author>Longstaff, Francis A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Security Issue Timing: What Do Managers Know, and When Do They Know It?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jenter, Dirk; Lewellen, Katharina; Warner, Jerold B.
We study put option sales on company stock by large firms. An often-cited motivation for these transactions is market timing, and managers' decision to issue puts should be sensitive to whether the stock is undervalued. We provide new evidence that large firms successfully time security sales. In the 100 days following put option issues, there is roughly a 5% abnormal stock return, with much of the abnormal return following the first earnings release date after the sale. Direct evidence on put option exercises reinforces these findings: exercise frequencies and payoffs to put holders are abnormally low.</description><author>Jenter, Dirk; Lewellen, Katharina; Warner, Jerold B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Joy of Giving or Assisted Living? Using Strategic Surveys to Separate Public Care Aversion from Bequest Motives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ameriks, John; Caplin, Andrew; Laufer, Steven; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn
The "annuity puzzle," conveying the apparently low interest of retirees in longevity insurance, is central to household finance. Two possible explanations are "public care aversion" (PCA), retiree aversion to simultaneously running out of wealth and being in need of long-term care, and an intentional bequest motive. To disentangle the relative importance of PCA and bequest motive, we estimate a structural model of the retirement phase using a novel survey instrument that includes hypothetical questions. We identify PCA as very significant and find bequest motives that spread deep into the middle class. Our results highlight potential interest in annuities that make allowance for long-term care expenses.</description><author>Ameriks, John; Caplin, Andrew; Laufer, Steven; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public Information and Coordination: Evidence from a Credit Registry Expansion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hertzberg, Andrew; Liberti, Jose Maria; Paravisini, Daniel
This paper provides evidence that lenders to a firm close to distress have incentives to coordinate: lower financing by one lender reduces firm creditworthiness and causes other lenders to reduce financing. To isolate the coordination channel from lenders' joint reaction to new information, we exploit a natural experiment that forced lenders to share negative private assessments about their borrowers. We show that lenders, while learning nothing new about the firm, reduce credit in anticipation of other lenders' reaction to the negative news about the firm. The results show that public information exacerbates lender coordination and increases the incidence of firm financial distress.</description><author>Hertzberg, Andrew; Liberti, Jose Maria; Paravisini, Daniel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalized Disappointment Aversion and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Routledge, Bryan R.; Zin, Stanley E.
We characterize generalized disappointment aversion (GDA) risk preferences that can overweight lower-tail outcomes relative to expected utility. We show in an endowment economy that recursive utility with GDA risk preferences generates effective risk aversion that is countercyclical. This feature comes from endogenous variation in the probability of disappointment in the representative agent's intertemporal consumption-saving problem that underlies the asset pricing model. The variation in effective risk aversion produces a large equity premium and a risk-free rate that is procyclical and has low volatility in an economy with a simple autoregressive endowment-growth process.</description><author>Routledge, Bryan R.; Zin, Stanley E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Quality and Long-Run Risk: Asset Pricing Implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ai, Hengjie
I study the asset pricing implications of the quality of public information about persistent productivity shocks in a general equilibrium model with Kreps-Porteus preferences. Low information quality is associated with a high equity premium, a low volatility of consumption growth, and a low volatility of the risk-free interest rate. The relationship between information quality and the equity premium differs from that in endowment economies. My calibration improves substantially upon the Bansal-Yaron model in terms of the moments of the wealth-consumption ratio and the return on aggregate wealth.</description><author>Ai, Hengjie</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday Patterns in the Cross-section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heston, Steven L.; Korajczyk, Robert A.; Sadka, Ronnie
Motivated by the literature on investment flows and optimal trading, we examine intraday predictability in the cross-section of stock returns. We find a striking pattern of return continuation at half-hour intervals that are exact multiples of a trading day, and this effect lasts for at least 40 trading days. Volume, order imbalance, volatility, and bid-ask spreads exhibit similar patterns, but do not explain the return patterns. We also show that short-term return reversal is driven by temporary liquidity imbalances lasting less than an hour and bid-ask bounce. Timing trades can reduce execution costs by the equivalent of the effective spread.</description><author>Heston, Steven L.; Korajczyk, Robert A.; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sell-Side School Ties</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren; Frazzini, Andrea; Malloy, Christopher
We study the impact of social networks on agents' ability to gather superior information about firms. Exploiting novel data on the educational background of sell-side analysts and senior corporate officers, we find that analysts outperform by up to 6.60% per year on their stock recommendations when they have an educational link to the company. Pre-Reg FD, this school-tie return premium is 9.36% per year, while post-Reg FD it is nearly zero. In contrast, in an environment that did not change selective disclosure regulation (the U.K.), the school-tie premium is large and significant over the entire sample period.</description><author>Cohen, Lauren; Frazzini, Andrea; Malloy, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictive Regressions: A Present-Value Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Koijen, Ralph S. J.
We propose a latent variables approach within a present-value model to estimate the expected returns and expected dividend growth rates of the aggregate stock market. This approach aggregates information contained in the history of price-dividend ratios and dividend growth rates to predict future returns and dividend growth rates. We find that returns and dividend growth rates are predictable with R-2 values ranging from 8.2% to 8.9% for returns and 13.9% to 31.6% for dividend growth rates. Both expected returns and expected dividend growth rates have a persistent component, but expected returns are more persistent than expected dividend growth rates.</description><author>van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Koijen, Ralph S. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Limit Orders Alter Inferences about Investor Performance and Behavior?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linnainmaa, Juhani T.
Individual investors lose money around earnings announcements, experience poor posttrade returns, exhibit the disposition effect, and make contrarian trades. Using simulations and trading records of all individual investors in Finland, I find that these trading patterns can be explained in large part by investors' use of limit orders. These patterns arise mechanically because limit orders are price-contingent and suffer from adverse selection. Reverse causality from behavioral biases to order choices does not appear to explain my findings. I propose a simple method for measuring a data set's susceptibility to this limit order effect.</description><author>Linnainmaa, Juhani T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Foreign Firms Leave US Equity Markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Stulz, Rene M.
Foreign firms terminate their Securities and Exchange Commission registration in the aftermath of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) because they no longer require outside funds to finance growth opportunities. Deregistering firms' insiders benefit from greater discretion to consume private benefits without having to raise higher cost funds. Foreign firms with more agency problems have worse stock-price reactions to the adoption of Rule 12h-6 in 2007, which made deregistration easier, than those firms more adversely affected by the compliance costs of SOX. Stock-price reactions to deregistration announcements are negative, but less so under Rule 12h-6, and more so for firms that raise fewer funds externally.</description><author>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Segmentation and Cross-predictability of Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menzly, Lior; Ozbas, Oguzhan
We present evidence supporting the hypothesis that due to investor specialization and market segmentation, value-relevant information diffuses gradually in financial markets. Using the stock market as our setting, we find that (i) stocks that are in economically related supplier and customer industries cross-predict each other's returns, (ii) the magnitude of return cross-predictability declines with the number of informed investors in the market as proxied by the level of analyst coverage and institutional ownership, and (iii) changes in the stock holdings of institutional investors mirror the model trading behavior of informed investors.</description><author>Menzly, Lior; Ozbas, Oguzhan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund Incubation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evans, Richard B.
Incubation is a strategy for initiating new funds, where multiple funds are started privately, and, at the end of an evaluation period, some are opened to the public. Consistent with incubation being used by fund families to increase performance and attract flows, funds in incubation outperform nonincubated funds by 3.5% risk-adjusted, and when they are opened to the public they attract higher flows. Postincubation, however, this outperformance disappears. This performance reversal imparts an upward bias to returns that is not removed by a fund size filter. Fund age and ticker creation date filters, however, eliminate the bias.</description><author>Evans, Richard B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential Address: Asset Price Dynamics with Slow-Moving Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffie, Darrell
I describe asset price dynamics caused by the slow movement of investment capital to trading opportunities. The pattern of price responses to supply or demand shocks typically involves a sharp reaction to the shock and a subsequent and more extended reversal. The amplitude of the immediate price impact and the pattern of the subsequent recovery can reflect institutional impediments to immediate trade, such as search costs for trading counterparties or time to raise capital by intermediaries. I discuss special impediments to capital formation during the recent financial crisis that caused asset price distortions, which subsided afterward. After presenting examples of price reactions to supply shocks in normal market settings, I offer a simple illustrative model of price dynamics associated with slow-moving capital due to the presence of inattentive investors.</description><author>Duffie, Darrell</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disagreement and Learning: Dynamic Patterns of Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Snehal; Kremer, Ilan
The empirical evidence on investor disagreement and trading volume is difficult to reconcile in standard rational expectations models. We develop a dynamic model in which investors disagree about the interpretation of public information. We obtain a closed-form linear equilibrium that allows us to study which restrictions on the disagreement process yield empirically observed volume and return dynamics. We show that when investors have infrequent but major disagreements, there is positive autocorrelation in volume and positive correlation between volume and volatility. We also derive novel empirical predictions that relate the degree and frequency of disagreement to volume and volatility dynamics.</description><author>Banerjee, Snehal; Kremer, Ilan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Genetic Variation in Financial Decision-Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cesarini, David; Johannesson, Magnus; Lichtenstein, Paul; Sandewall, Oerjan; Wallace, Bjorn
Individuals differ in how they construct their investment portfolios, yet empirical models of portfolio risk typically account only for a small portion of the cross-sectional variance. This paper asks whether genetic variation can explain some of these individual differences. Following a major pension reform Swedish adults had to form a portfolio from a large menu of funds. We match data on these investment decisions with the Swedish Twin Registry and find that approximately 25% of individual variation in portfolio risk is due to genetic variation. We also find that these results extend to several other aspects of financial decision-making.</description><author>Cesarini, David; Johannesson, Magnus; Lichtenstein, Paul; Sandewall, Oerjan; Wallace, Bjorn</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploring the Nature of "Trader Intuition"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruguier, Antoine J.; Quartz, Steven R.; Bossaerts, Peter
Experimental evidence has consistently confirmed the ability of uninformed traders, even novices, to infer information from the trading process. After contrasting brain activation in subjects watching markets with and without insiders, we hypothesize that Theory of Mind (ToM) helps explain this pattern, where ToM refers to the human capacity to discern malicious or benevolent intent. We find that skill in predicting price changes in markets with insiders correlates with scores on two ToM tests. We document GARCH-like persistence in transaction price changes that may help investors read markets when there are insiders.</description><author>Bruguier, Antoine J.; Quartz, Steven R.; Bossaerts, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Discovery in Illiquid Markets: Do Financial Asset Prices Rise Faster Than They Fall?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, Richard C.; Li, Dan; Schuerhoff, Norman
We study price discovery in municipal bonds, an important OTC market. As in markets for consumer goods, prices "rise faster than they fall." Round-trip profits to dealers on retail trades increase in rising markets but do not decrease in falling markets. Further, effective half-spreads increase or decrease more when movements in fundamentals favor dealers. Yield spreads relative to Treasuries also adjust with asymmetric speed in rising and falling markets. Finally, intraday price dispersion is asymmetric in rising and falling markets, as consumer search theory would predict.</description><author>Green, Richard C.; Li, Dan; Schuerhoff, Norman</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Big Bad Banks? The Winners and Losers from Bank Deregulation in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Levine, Ross; Levkov, Alexey
We assess the impact of bank deregulation on the distribution of income in the United States. From the 1970s through the 1990s, most states removed restrictions on intrastate branching, which intensified bank competition and improved bank performance. Exploiting the cross-state, cross-time variation in the timing of branch deregulation, we find that deregulation materially tightened the distribution of income by boosting incomes in the lower part of the income distribution while having little impact on incomes above the median. Bank deregulation tightened the distribution of income by increasing the relative wage rates and working hours of unskilled workers.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Levine, Ross; Levkov, Alexey</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Fund Contagion and Liquidity Shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyson, Nicole M.; Stahel, Christof W.; Stulz, Rene M.
Defining contagion as correlation over and above that expected from economic fundamentals, we find strong evidence of worst return contagion across hedge fund styles for 1990 to 2008. Large adverse shocks to asset and hedge fund liquidity strongly increase the probability of contagion. Specifically, large adverse shocks to credit spreads, the TED spread, prime broker and bank stock prices, stock market liquidity, and hedge fund flows are associated with a significant increase in the probability of hedge fund contagion. While shocks to liquidity are important determinants of performance, these shocks are not captured by commonly used models of hedge fund returns.</description><author>Boyson, Nicole M.; Stahel, Christof W.; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification and Its Discontents: Idiosyncratic and Entrepreneurial Risk in the Quest for Social Status</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roussanov, Nikolai
Social status concerns influence investors' decisions by driving a wedge in attitudes toward aggregate and idiosyncratic risks. I model such concerns by emphasizing the desire to "get ahead of the Joneses," which implies that aversion to idiosyncratic risk is lower than aversion to aggregate risk. The model predicts that investors hold concentrated portfolios in equilibrium, which helps rationalize the small premium for undiversified entrepreneurial risk. In the model, status concerns are more important for wealthier households. Consequently, these households own a disproportionate share of risky assets, particularly private equity, and experience greater volatility of consumption, consistent with empirical evidence.</description><author>Roussanov, Nikolai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Microstructure and Ambiguity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen
A goal for stock exchanges is to increase participation by firms and investors. We show how specific features of the microstructure can reduce perceived ambiguity, and induce participation by both investors and issuers. We develop a model with sophisticated traders, who we view as expected utility maximizers with rational expectations, and unsophisticated traders, who we view as rational traders facing ambiguity about the payoffs to participating in the market. We show how designing markets to reduce ambiguity can benefit investors through greater liquidity, exchanges through greater volume, and issuing firms through a lower cost of capital.</description><author>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Time for a Change": Loan Conditions and Bank Behavior when Firms Switch Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ioannidou, Vasso; Ongena, Steven
This paper studies loan conditions when firms switch banks. Recent theoretical work on bank-firm relationships motivates our matching models. The dynamic cycle of the loan rate that we uncover is as follows: a loan granted by a new (outside) bank carries a loan rate that is significantly lower than the rates on comparable new loans from the firm's current (inside) banks. The new bank initially decreases the loan rate further but eventually ratchets it up sharply. Other loan conditions follow a similar economically relevant pattern. This bank strategy is consistent with the existence of hold-up costs in bank-firm relationships.</description><author>Ioannidou, Vasso; Ongena, Steven</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual Investors and Local Bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seasholes, Mark S.; Zhu, Ning
The paper tests whether individuals have value-relevant information about local stocks (where "local" is defined as being headquartered near where an investor lives). Our methodology uses two types of calendar-time portfolios-one based on holdings and one based on transactions. Portfolios of local holdings do not generate abnormal performance (alphas are zero). When studying transactions, purchases of local stocks significantly underperform sales of local stocks. The underperformance remains when focusing on stocks with potentially high levels of information asymmetries. We conclude that individuals do not help incorporate information into stock prices. Our conclusions directly contradict existing studies.</description><author>Seasholes, Mark S.; Zhu, Ning</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Bayesian Approach to Real Options: The Case of Distinguishing between Temporary and Permanent Shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grenadier, Steven R.; Malenko, Andrey
Traditional real options models demonstrate the importance of the "option to wait" due to uncertainty over future shocks to project cash flows. However, there is often another important source of uncertainty: uncertainty over the permanence of past shocks. Adding Bayesian uncertainty over the permanence of past shocks augments the traditional option to wait with an additional "option to learn." The implied investment behavior differs significantly from that in standard models. For example, investment may occur at a time of stable or decreasing cash flows, respond sluggishly to cash flow shocks, and depend on the timing of project cash flows.</description><author>Grenadier, Steven R.; Malenko, Andrey</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Luck versus Skill in the Cross-Section of Mutual Fund Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
The aggregate portfolio of actively managed U.S. equity mutual funds is close to the market portfolio, but the high costs of active management show up intact as lower returns to investors. Bootstrap simulations suggest that few funds produce benchmark-adjusted expected returns sufficient to cover their costs. If we add back the costs in fund expense ratios, there is evidence of inferior and superior performance (nonzero true alpha) in the extreme tails of the cross-section of mutual fund alpha estimates.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short Sellers and Financial Misconduct</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Lou, Xiaoxia
We examine whether short sellers detect firms that misrepresent their financial statements, and whether their trading conveys external costs or benefits to other investors. Abnormal short interest increases steadily in the 19 months before the misrepresentation is publicly revealed, particularly when the misconduct is severe. Short selling is associated with a faster time-to-discovery, and it dampens the share price inflation that occurs when firms misstate their earnings. These results indicate that short sellers anticipate the eventual discovery and severity of financial misconduct. They also convey external benefits, helping to uncover misconduct and keeping prices closer to fundamental values.</description><author>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Lou, Xiaoxia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sticks or Carrots? Optimal CEO Compensation when Managers Are Loss Averse</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmann, Ingolf; Maug, Ernst; Spalt, Oliver
This paper analyzes optimal executive compensation contracts when managers are loss averse. We calibrate a stylized principal-agent model to the observed contracts of 595 CEOs and show that this model can explain observed option holdings and high base salaries remarkably well for a range of parameterizations. We also derive and calibrate the general shape of the optimal contract that is increasing and convex for medium and high outcomes and that drops discontinuously to the lowest possible payout for low outcomes. Finally, we identify the critical features of the loss-aversion model that render optimal contracts convex.</description><author>Dittmann, Ingolf; Maug, Ernst; Spalt, Oliver</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Are CEOs Rarely Fired? Evidence from Structural Estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Lucian A.
I evaluate the forced CEO turnover rate and quantify effects on shareholder value by estimating a dynamic model. The model features learning about CEO ability and costly turnover. To fit the observed forced turnover rate, the model needs the average board of directors to behave as if replacing the CEO costs shareholders at least $200 million. This cost mainly reflects CEO entrenchment rather than a real cost to shareholders. The model predicts that shareholder value would rise 3% if we eliminated this perceived turnover cost, all else equal. The model also helps explain the relation between CEO firings, tenure, and profitability.</description><author>Taylor, Lucian A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cost of Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Graham, John R.; Yang, Jie
We use exogenous variation in tax benefit functions to estimate firm-specific cost of debt functions that are conditional on company characteristics such as collateral, size, and book-to-market. By integrating the area between the benefit and cost functions, we estimate that the equilibrium net benefit of debt is 3.5% of asset value, resulting from an estimated gross benefit (cost) of debt equal to 10.4% (6.9%) of asset value. We find that the cost of being overlevered is asymmetrically higher than the cost of being underlevered and that expected default costs constitute only half of the total ex ante costs of debt.</description><author>van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Graham, John R.; Yang, Jie</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Net Benefits to Leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korteweg, Arthur
I estimate the market's valuation of the net benefits to leverage using panel data from 1994 to 2004, identified from market values and betas of a company's debt and equity. The median firm captures net benefits of up to 5.5% of firm value. Small and profitable firms have high optimal leverage ratios, as predicted by theory, but in contrast to existing empirical evidence. Companies are on average slightly underlevered relative to the optimal leverage ratio at refinancing. This result is mainly due to zero leverage firms. I also look at implications for financial policy.</description><author>Korteweg, Arthur</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Conditions and the Puzzles of Credit Spreads and Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hui
I build a dynamic capital structure model that demonstrates how business cycle variation in expected growth rates, economic uncertainty, and risk premia influences firms' financing policies. Countercyclical fluctuations in risk prices, default probabilities, and default losses arise endogenously through firms' responses to macroeconomic conditions. These comovements generate large credit risk premia for investment grade firms, which helps address the credit spread puzzle and the under-leverage puzzle in a unified framework. The model generates interesting dynamics for financing and defaults, including market timing in debt issuance and credit contagion. It also provides a novel procedure to estimate state-dependent default losses.</description><author>Chen, Hui</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Blows the Whistle on Corporate Fraud?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dyck, Alexander; Morse, Adair; Zingales, Luigi
To identify the most effective mechanisms for detecting corporate fraud, we study all reported fraud cases in large U.S. companies between 1996 and 2004. We find that fraud detection does not rely on standard corporate governance actors (investors, SEC, and auditors), but rather takes a village, including several nontraditional players (employees, media, and industry regulators). Differences in access to information, as well as monetary and reputational incentives, help to explain this pattern. In-depth analyses suggest that reputational incentives in general are weak, except for journalists in large cases. By contrast, monetary incentives help explain employee whistleblowing.</description><author>Dyck, Alexander; Morse, Adair; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Fraud and Business Conditions: Evidence from IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Tracy Yue; Winton, Andrew; Yu, Xiaoyun
We examine how a firm's incentive to commit fraud when going public varies with investor beliefs about industry business conditions. Fraud propensity increases with the level of investor beliefs about industry prospects but decreases when beliefs are extremely high. We find that two mechanisms are at work: monitoring by investors and short-term executive compensation, both of which vary with investor beliefs about industry prospects. We also find that monitoring incentives of investors and underwriters differ. Our results are consistent with models of investor beliefs and corporate fraud, and suggest that regulators and auditors should be vigilant for fraud during booms.</description><author>Wang, Tracy Yue; Winton, Andrew; Yu, Xiaoyun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral, Risk Management, and the Distribution of Debt Capacity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rampini, Adriano A.; Viswanathan, S.
Collateral constraints imply that financing and risk management are fundamentally linked. The opportunity cost of engaging in risk management and conserving debt capacity to hedge future financing needs is forgone current investment, and is higher for more productive and less well-capitalized firms. More constrained firms engage in less risk management and may exhaust their debt capacity and abstain from risk management, consistent with empirical evidence and in contrast to received theory. When cash flows are low, such firms may be unable to seize investment opportunities and be forced to downsize. Consequently, capital may be less productively deployed in downturns.</description><author>Rampini, Adriano A.; Viswanathan, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage Choice and Credit Spreads when Managers Risk Shift</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlson, Murray; Lazrak, Ali
We model the debt and asset risk choice of a manager with performance-insensitive pay (cash) and performance-sensitive pay (stock) to theoretically link compensation structure, leverage, and credit spreads. The model predicts that optimal leverage trades off the tax benefit of debt against the utility cost of ex-post asset substitution and that credit spreads are increasing in the ratio of cash-to-stock. Using a large cross-section of U.S.-based corporate credit default swaps (CDS) covering 2001 to 2006, we find a positive association between cash-to-stock and CDS rates, and between cash-to-stock and leverage ratios.</description><author>Carlson, Murray; Lazrak, Ali</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lucky CEOs and Lucky Directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Grinstein, Yaniv; Peyer, Urs
We study the relation between opportunistic timing of option grants and corporate governance failures, focusing on "lucky" grants awarded at the lowest price of the grant month. Option grant practices were designed to provide lucky grants not only to executives but also to independent directors. Lucky grants to both CEOs and directors were the product of deliberate choices, not of firms' routines, and were timed to make them more profitable. Lucky grants are associated with higher CEO compensation from other sources, no majority of independent directors, no outside blockholder on the compensation committee, and a long-serving CEO.</description><author>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Grinstein, Yaniv; Peyer, Urs</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Legacies, Entrenchment, and Strategic Inertia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casamatta, Catherine; Guembel, Alexander
This paper argues that the legacy potential of a firm's strategy is an important determinant of CEO compensation, turnover, and strategy change. A legacy makes CEO replacement expensive, because firm performance can only partially be attributed to a newly employed manager. Boards may therefore optimally allow an incumbent to be entrenched. Moreover, when a firm changes strategy it is optimal to change the CEO, because the incumbent has a vested interest in seeing the new strategy fail. Even though CEOs have no specific skills in our model, legacy issues can explain the empirical association between CEO and strategy change.</description><author>Casamatta, Catherine; Guembel, Alexander</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>False Discoveries in Mutual Fund Performance: Measuring Luck in Estimated Alphas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barras, Laurent; Scaillet, Olivier; Wermers, Russ
This paper develops a simple technique that controls for "false discoveries," or mutual funds that exhibit significant alphas by luck alone. Our approach precisely separates funds into (1) unskilled, (2) zero-alpha, and (3) skilled funds, even with dependencies in cross-fund estimated alphas. We find that 75% of funds exhibit zero alpha (net of expenses), consistent with the Berk and Green equilibrium. Further, we find a significant proportion of skilled (positive alpha) funds prior to 1996, but almost none by 2006. We also show that controlling for false discoveries substantially improves the ability to find the few funds with persistent performance.</description><author>Barras, Laurent; Scaillet, Olivier; Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Habit-Based Explanation of the Exchange Rate Risk Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Verdelhan, Adrien
This paper presents a model that reproduces the uncovered interest rate parity puzzle. Investors have preferences with external habits. Countercyclical risk premia and procyclical real interest rates arise endogenously. During bad times at home, when domestic consumption is close to the habit level, the representative investor is very risk averse. When the domestic investor is more risk averse than her foreign counterpart, the exchange rate is closely tied to domestic consumption growth shocks. The domestic investor therefore expects a positive currency excess return. Because interest rates are low in bad times, expected currency excess returns increase with interest rate differentials.</description><author>Verdelhan, Adrien</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Currency Hedging</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John Y.; Serfaty-De Medeiros, Karine; Viceira, Luis M.
Over the period 1975 to 2005, the U.S. dollar (particularly in relation to the Canadian dollar), the euro, and the Swiss franc (particularly in the second half of the period) moved against world equity markets. Thus, these currencies should be attractive to risk-minimizing global equity investors despite their low average returns. The risk-minimizing currency strategy for a global bond investor is close to a full currency hedge, with a modest long position in the U.S. dollar. There is little evidence that risk-minimizing investors should adjust their currency positions in response to movements in interest differentials.</description><author>Campbell, John Y.; Serfaty-De Medeiros, Karine; Viceira, Luis M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real and Financial Industry Booms and Busts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoberg, Gerard; Phillips, Gordon
We examine how product market competition affects firm cash flows and stock returns in industry booms and busts. Our results show how real and financial factors interact in industry business cycles. In competitive industries, we find that high industry-level stock market valuation, investment, and financing are followed by sharply lower operating cash flows and abnormal stock returns. Analyst estimates are positively biased and returns comove more. In concentrated industries these relations are weak and generally insignificant. Our results are consistent with participants in competitive industries not fully internalizing the negative externality of industry competition on cash flows and stock returns.</description><author>Hoberg, Gerard; Phillips, Gordon</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Competition, Insider Trading, and Stock Market Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peress, Joel
How does competition in firms' product markets influence their behavior in equity markets? Do product market imperfections spread to equity markets? We examine these questions in a noisy rational expectations model in which firms operate under monopolistic competition while their shares trade in perfectly competitive markets. Firms use their monopoly power to pass on shocks to customers, thereby insulating their profits. This encourages stock trading, expedites the capitalization of private information into stock prices and improves the allocation of capital. Several implications are derived and tested.</description><author>Peress, Joel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral Spread and Financial Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liberti, Jose M.; Mian, Atif R.
We show that institutions that promote financial development ease borrowing constraints by lowering the collateral spread and shifting the composition of acceptable collateral towards firm-specific assets. Collateral spread is defined as the difference in collateralization rates between high- and low-risk borrowers. The average collateral spread is large but declines rapidly with improvements in financial development driven by stronger institutions. We also show that the composition of collateralizable assets shifts towards non-specific assets (e.g., land) with borrower risk. However, the shift is considerably smaller in developed financial markets, enabling risky borrowers to use a larger variety of assets as collateral.</description><author>Liberti, Jose M.; Mian, Atif R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Hot Hands Exist among Hedge Fund Managers? An Empirical Evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, Ravi; Malakhov, Alexey; Novikov, Dmitry
In measuring performance persistence, we use hedge fund style benchmarks. This allows us to identify managers with valuable skills, and also to control for option-like features inherent in returns from hedge fund strategies. We take into account the possibility that reported asset values may be based on stale prices. We develop a statistical model that relates a hedge fund's performance to its decision to liquidate or close in order to infer the performance of a hedge fund that left the database. Although we find significant performance persistence among superior funds, we find little evidence of persistence among inferior funds.</description><author>Jagannathan, Ravi; Malakhov, Alexey; Novikov, Dmitry</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Market Declines and Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hameed, Allaudeen; Kang, Wenjin; Viswanathan, S.
Consistent with recent theoretical models where binding capital constraints lead to sudden liquidity dry-ups, we find that negative market returns decrease stock liquidity, especially during times of tightness in the funding market. The asymmetric effect of changes in aggregate asset values on liquidity and commonality in liquidity cannot be fully explained by changes in demand for liquidity or volatility effects. We document interindustry spillover effects in liquidity, which are likely to arise from capital constraints in the market making sector. We also find economically significant returns to supplying liquidity following periods of large drops in market valuations.</description><author>Hameed, Allaudeen; Kang, Wenjin; Viswanathan, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Correlation Risk and Optimal Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, Andrea; Porchia, Paolo; Trojani, Fabio
We develop a new framework for multivariate intertemporal portfolio choice that allows us to derive optimal portfolio implications for economies in which the degree of correlation across industries, countries, or asset classes is stochastic. Optimal portfolios include distinct hedging components against both stochastic volatility and correlation risk. We find that the hedging demand is typically larger than in univariate models, and it includes an economically significant covariance hedging component, which tends to increase with the persistence of variance-covariance shocks, the strength of leverage effects, the dimension of the investment opportunity set, and the presence of portfolio constraints.</description><author>Buraschi, Andrea; Porchia, Paolo; Trojani, Fabio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individualism and Momentum around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chui, Andy C. W.; Titman, Sheridan; Wei, K. C. John
This paper examines how cultural differences influence the returns of momentum strategies. Cross-country cultural differences are measured with an individualism index developed by Hofstede (2001), which is related to overconfidence and self-attribution bias. We find that individualism is positively associated with trading volume and volatility, as well as to the magnitude of momentum profits. Momentum profits are also positively related to analyst forecast dispersion, transaction costs, and the familiarity of the market to foreigners, and negatively related to firm size and volatility. However, the addition of these and other variables does not dampen the relation between individualism and momentum profits.</description><author>Chui, Andy C. W.; Titman, Sheridan; Wei, K. C. John</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Deregulation and Financial Innovation on Consumers: The Case of the Mortgage Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gerardi, Kristopher S.; Rosen, Harvey S.; Willen, Paul S.
We develop a technique to assess the impact of changes in mortgage markets on households, exploiting an implication of the permanent income hypothesis: The higher a household's expected future income, the higher its desired consumption, ceteris paribus. With perfect credit markets, desired consumption matches actual consumption and current spending forecasts future income. Because credit market imperfections mute this effect, the extent to which house spending predicts future income measures the "imperfectness" of mortgage markets. Using micro-data, we find that since the early 1980s, mortgage markets have become less imperfect in this sense, and securitization has played an important role.</description><author>Gerardi, Kristopher S.; Rosen, Harvey S.; Willen, Paul S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time Variation in Liquidity: The Role of Market-Maker Inventories and Revenues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Hendershott, Terrence; Jones, Charles M.; Moulton, Pamela C.; Seasholes, Mark S.
We show that market-maker balance sheet and income statement variables explain time variation in liquidity, suggesting liquidity-supplier financing constraints matter. Using 11 years of NYSE specialist inventory positions and trading revenues, we find that aggregate market-level and specialist firm-level spreads widen when specialists have large positions or lose money. The effects are nonlinear and most prominent when inventories are big or trading results have been particularly poor. These sensitivities are smaller after specialist firm mergers, consistent with deep pockets easing financing constraints. Finally, compared to low volatility stocks, the liquidity of high volatility stocks is more sensitive to inventories and losses.</description><author>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Hendershott, Terrence; Jones, Charles M.; Moulton, Pamela C.; Seasholes, Mark S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Structure as a Strategic Variable: Evidence from Collective Bargaining</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Matsa, David A.
I analyze the strategic use of debt financing to improve a firm's bargaining position with an important supplier-organized labor. Because maintaining high levels of corporate liquidity can encourage workers to raise their wage demands, a firm with external finance constraints has an incentive to use the cash flow demands of debt service to improve its bargaining position with workers. Using both firm-level collective bargaining coverage and state changes in labor laws to identify changes in union bargaining power, I show that strategic incentives from union bargaining appear to have a substantial impact on corporate financing decisions.</description><author>Matsa, David A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of SOX Section 404: Costs, Earnings Quality, and Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iliev, Peter
This paper exploits a natural quasi-experiment to isolate the effects that were uniquely due to the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX): U.S. firms with a public float under $75 million could delay Section 404 compliance, and foreign firms under $700 million could delay the auditor's attestation requirement. As designed, Section 404 led to conservative reported earnings, but also imposed real costs. On net, SOX compliance reduced the market value of small firms.</description><author>Iliev, Peter</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive Compensation and the Maturity Structure of Corporate Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brockman, Paul; Martin, Xiumin; Unlu, Emre
Executive compensation influences managerial risk preferences through executives' portfolio sensitivities to changes in stock prices (delta) and stock return volatility (vega). Large deltas discourage managerial risk-taking, while large vegas encourage risk-taking. Theory suggests that short-maturity debt mitigates agency costs of debt by constraining managerial risk preferences. We posit and find evidence of a negative (positive) relation between CEO portfolio deltas (vegas) and short-maturity debt. We also find that short-maturity debt mitigates the influence of vega- and delta-related incentives on bond yields. Overall, our empirical evidence shows that short-term debt mitigates agency costs of debt arising from compensation risk.</description><author>Brockman, Paul; Martin, Xiumin; Unlu, Emre</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Strength and Product Market Behavior: The Real Effects of Corporate Cash Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fresard, Laurent
This paper shows that large cash reserves lead to systematic future market share gains at the expense of industry rivals. Using shifts in import tariffs to identify exogenous intensification of competition, difference-in-difference estimations support the causal impact of cash on product market performance. Moreover, the analysis reveals that the "competitive" effect of cash is markedly distinct from the strategic effect of debt on product market outcomes. This effect is stronger when rivals face tighter financing constraints and when the number of interactions between competitors is large. Overall, the results suggest that cash policy encompasses a substantial strategic dimension.</description><author>Fresard, Laurent</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and the Corporate Structure of Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Marquez, Robert
We identify different sources of risk as important determinants of banks' corporate structures when expanding into new markets. Subsidiary-based corporate structures benefit from greater protection against economic risk because of affiliate-level limited liability, but are more exposed to the risk of capital expropriation than are branches. Thus, branch-based structures are preferred to subsidiary-based structures when expropriation risk is high relative to economic risk, and vice versa. Greater cross-country risk correlation and more accurate pricing of risk by investors reduce the differences between the two structures. Furthermore, a bank's corporate structure affects its risk taking and affiliate size.</description><author>Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Marquez, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Gap-Filling Theory of Corporate Debt Maturity Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Hanson, Samuel; Stein, Jeremy C.
We argue that time variation in the maturity of corporate debt arises because firms behave as macro liquidity providers, absorbing the supply shocks associated with changes in the maturity structure of government debt. We document that when the government funds itself with more short-term debt, firms fill the resulting gap by issuing more long-term debt, and vice versa. This type of liquidity provision is undertaken more aggressively: (1) when the ratio of government debt to total debt is higher and (2) by firms with stronger balance sheets. Our theory sheds new light on market timing phenomena in corporate finance more generally.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Hanson, Samuel; Stein, Jeremy C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Political Economy of Financial Regulation: Evidence from US State Usury Laws in the 19th Century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benmelech, Efraim; Moskowitz, Tobias J.
Financial regulation was as hotly debated a political issue in the 19th century as it is today. We study the political economy of state usury laws in 19th century America. Exploiting the wide variation in regulation, enforcement, and economic conditions across states and time, we find that usury laws when binding reduce credit and economic activity, especially for smaller firms. We examine the motives of regulation and find that usury laws coincide with other economic and political policies favoring wealthy political incumbents, particularly when they have more voting power. The evidence suggests financial regulation is driven by private interests capturing rents from others rather than public interests protecting the underserved.</description><author>Benmelech, Efraim; Moskowitz, Tobias J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Holdings and Corporate Diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duchin, Ran
This paper studies the relation between corporate liquidity and diversification. The key finding is that multidivision firms hold significantly less cash than stand-alone firms because they are diversified in their investment opportunities. Lower cross-divisional correlations in investment opportunity and higher correlations between investment opportunity and cash flow correspond to lower cash holdings, even after controlling for cash flow volatility. The effects are strongest in financially constrained firms and in well-governed firms, and correspond to efficient fund transfers from low- to high-productivity divisions. Taken together, these results bring forth an efficient link between diversification and corporate liquidity.</description><author>Duchin, Ran</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stapled Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Povel, Paul; Singh, Rajdeep
"Stapled finance" is a loan commitment arranged by a seller in an M&amp;A setting. Whoever wins the bidding contest has the option (not the obligation) to accept this loan commitment. We show that stapled finance increases bidding competition by subsidizing weak bidders, who raise their bids and thereby the price that strong bidders (who are more likely to win) must pay. The lender expects not to break even and must be compensated for offering the loan. This reduces but does not eliminate the seller's benefit. It also implies that stapled finance loans will show poorer performance than other buyout loans.</description><author>Povel, Paul; Singh, Rajdeep</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Human Capital, Bankruptcy, and Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berk, Jonathan B.; Stanton, Richard; Zechner, Josef
We derive the optimal labor contract for a levered firm in an economy with perfectly competitive capital and labor markets. Employees become entrenched under this contract and so face large human costs of bankruptcy. The firm's optimal capital structure therefore depends on the trade-off between these human costs and the tax benefits of debt. Optimal debt levels consistent with those observed in practice emerge without relying on frictions such as moral hazard or asymmetric information. Consistent with empirical evidence, persistent idiosyncratic differences in leverage across firms also result. In addition, wages should have explanatory power for firm leverage.</description><author>Berk, Jonathan B.; Stanton, Richard; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Credit Competition Affect Small-Firm Finance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rice, Tara; Strahan, Philip E.
While relaxation of geographical restrictions on bank expansion permitted banking organizations to expand across state lines, it allowed states to erect barriers to branch expansion. These differences in states' branching restrictions affect credit supply. In states more open to branching, small firms borrow at interest rates 80 to 100 basis points lower than firms operating in less open states. Firms in open states also are more likely to borrow from banks. Despite this evidence that interstate branch openness expands credit supply, we find no effect of variation in state restrictions on branching on the amount that small firms borrow.</description><author>Rice, Tara; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Networking as a Barrier to Entry and the Competitive Supply of Venture Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hochberg, Yael V.; Ljungqvist, Alexander; Lu, Yang
We examine whether strong networks among incumbent venture capitalists (VCs) in local markets help restrict entry by outside VCs, thus improving incumbents' bargaining power over entrepreneurs. More densely networked markets experience less entry, with a one-standard deviation increase in network ties among incumbents reducing entry by approximately one-third. Entrants with established ties to target-market incumbents appear able to overcome this barrier to entry; in turn, incumbents react strategically to an increased threat of entry by freezing out any incumbents who facilitate entry into their market. Incumbents appear to benefit from reduced entry by paying lower prices for their deals.</description><author>Hochberg, Yael V.; Ljungqvist, Alexander; Lu, Yang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information and Incentives Inside the Firm: Evidence from Loan Officer Rotation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hertzberg, Andrew; Liberti, Jose Maria; Paravisini, Daniel
We present evidence that reassigning tasks among agents can alleviate moral hazard in communication. A rotation policy that routinely reassigns loan officers to borrowers of a commercial bank affects the officers' reporting behavior. When an officer anticipates rotation, reports are more accurate and contain more bad news about the borrower's repayment prospects. As a result, the rotation policy makes bank lending decisions more sensitive to officer reports. The threat of rotation improves communication because self-reporting bad news has a smaller negative effect on an officer's career prospects than bad news exposed by a successor.</description><author>Hertzberg, Andrew; Liberti, Jose Maria; Paravisini, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance and Persistence in Institutional Investment Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Busse, Jeffrey A.; Goyal, Amit; Wahal, Sunil
Using new, survivorship bias-free data, we examine the performance and persistence in performance of 4,617 active domestic equity institutional products managed by 1,448 investment management firms between 1991 and 2008. Controlling for the Fama-French (1993) three factors and momentum, aggregate and average estimates of alphas are statistically indistinguishable from zero. Even though there is considerable heterogeneity in performance, there is only modest evidence of persistence in three-factor models and little to none in four-factor models.</description><author>Busse, Jeffrey A.; Goyal, Amit; Wahal, Sunil</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Interdependent and Intertemporal Nature of Financial Decisions: An Application to Cash Flow Sensitivities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gatchev, Vladimir A.; Pulvino, Todd; Tarhan, Vefa
We develop a dynamic multiequation model where firms make financing and investment decisions jointly subject to the constraint that sources must equal uses of cash. We argue that static models of financial decisions produce inconsistent coefficient estimates, and that models that do not acknowledge the interdependence among decision variables produce inefficient estimates and provide an incomplete and potentially misleading view of financial behavior. We use our model to examine whether firms are constrained from accessing capital markets. Unlike static single-equation studies that find firms underinvest given cash flow shortfalls, we conclude that firms maintain investment by borrowing.</description><author>Gatchev, Vladimir A.; Pulvino, Todd; Tarhan, Vefa</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Political Contributions and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Michael J.; Gulen, Huseyin; Ovtchinnikov, Alexei V.
We develop a new and comprehensive database of firm-level contributions to U.S. political campaigns from 1979 to 2004. We construct variables that measure the extent of firm support for candidates. We find that these measures are positively and significantly correlated with the cross-section of future returns. The effect is strongest for firms that support a greater number of candidates that hold office in the same state that the firm is based. In addition, there are stronger effects for firms whose contributions are slanted toward House candidates and Democrats.</description><author>Cooper, Michael J.; Gulen, Huseyin; Ovtchinnikov, Alexei V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Personal Bankruptcy and Credit Market Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dick, Astrid A.; Lehnert, Andreas
We document a link between U.S. credit supply and rising personal bankruptcy rates. We exploit the exogenous variation in market contestability brought on by banking deregulation-the relaxation of entry restrictions in the 1980s and 1990s-at the state level. We find deregulation explains at least 10% of the rise in bankruptcy rates. We also find that deregulation leads to increased lending, lower loss rates on loans, and higher lending productivity. Our findings indicate that increased competition prompted banks to adopt sophisticated credit rating technology, allowing for new credit extension to existing and previously excluded households.</description><author>Dick, Astrid A.; Lehnert, Andreas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Bonds Span Volatility Risk in the US Treasury Market? A Specification Test for Affine Term Structure Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, Torben G.; Benzoni, Luca
We propose using model-free yield quadratic variation measures computed from intraday data as a tool for specification testing and selection of dynamic term structure models. We find that the yield curve fails to span realized yield volatility in the U.S. Treasury market, as the systematic volatility factors are largely unrelated to the cross-section of yields. We conclude that a broad class of affine diffusive, quadratic Gaussian, and affine jump-diffusive models cannot accommodate the observed yield volatility dynamics. Hence, the Treasury market per se is incomplete, as yield volatility risk cannot be hedged solely through Treasury securities.</description><author>Andersen, Torben G.; Benzoni, Luca</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes on Tax-Exempt Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Bhansali, Vineer; Xing, Yuhang
Implicit tax rates priced in the cross section of municipal bonds are approximately two to three times as high as statutory income tax rates, with implicit tax rates close to 100% using retail trades and above 70% for interdealer trades. These implied tax rates can be identified because a portion of secondary market municipal bond trades involves income taxes. After valuing the tax payments, market discount bonds, which carry income tax liabilities, trade at yields around 25 basis points higher than comparable municipal bonds not subject to any taxes. The high sensitivities of municipal bond prices to tax rates can be traced to individual retail traders dominating dealers and other institutions.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Bhansali, Vineer; Xing, Yuhang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Structure, Acquisition Opportunities, and Firm Locations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almazan, Andres; De Motta, Adolfo; Titman, Sheridan; Uysal, Vahap
This paper investigates the relation between firms' locations and their corporate finance decisions. We develop a model where being located within an industry cluster increases opportunities to make acquisitions, and to facilitate those acquisitions, firms within clusters maintain more financial slack. Consistent with our model we find that firms located within industry clusters make more acquisitions, and have lower debt ratios and larger cash balances than their industry peers located outside clusters. We also document that firms in high-tech cities and growing cities maintain more financial slack. Overall, the evidence suggests that growth opportunities influence firms' financial decisions.</description><author>Almazan, Andres; De Motta, Adolfo; Titman, Sheridan; Uysal, Vahap</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The New Game in Town: Competitive Effects of IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsu, Hung-Chia; Reed, Adam V.; Rocholl, Joerg
We analyze the effect of initial public offerings (IPOs) on industry competitors and provide evidence that companies experience negative stock price reactions to completed IPOs in their industry and positive stock price reactions to their withdrawal. Following a successful IPO in their industry, they show significant deterioration in their operating performance. These results are consistent with the existence of IPO-related competitive advantages through the loosening of financial constraints, financial intermediary certification, and the presence of knowledge capital. These aspects of competitiveness are significant in explaining the cross-section of underperformance as well as survival probabilities for competing firms.</description><author>Hsu, Hung-Chia; Reed, Adam V.; Rocholl, Joerg</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Levered Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomes, Joao F.; Schmid, Lukas
This paper revisits the theoretical relation between financial leverage and stock returns in a dynamic world where both corporate investment and financing decisions are endogenous. We find that the link between leverage and stock returns is more complex than static textbook examples suggest, and depends on the investment opportunities available to the firm. In the presence of financial market imperfections, leverage and investment are generally correlated so that highly levered firms are also mature firms with relatively more (safe) book assets and fewer (risky) growth opportunities. A quantitative version of our model matches several stylized facts about leverage and returns.</description><author>Gomes, Joao F.; Schmid, Lukas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Variability of IPO Initial Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lowry, Michelle; Officer, Micah S.; Schwert, G. William
The monthly volatility of IPO initial returns is substantial, fluctuates dramatically over time, and is considerably larger during "hot" IPO markets. Consistent with IPO theory, the volatility of initial returns is higher for firms that are more difficult to value because of higher information asymmetry. Our findings highlight underwriters' difficulty in valuing companies characterized by high uncertainty, and raise serious questions about the efficacy of the traditional firm-commitment IPO process. One implication of our results is that alternate mechanisms, such as auctions, could be beneficial for firms that value price discovery over the auxiliary services provided by underwriters.</description><author>Lowry, Michelle; Officer, Micah S.; Schwert, G. William</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>MORGAN STANLEY-AMERICAN FINANCE ASSOCIATION AWARD FOR EXCELLENCE IN FINANCE 2010</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jensen, Michael C.
nan</description><author>Jensen, Michael C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rank-Order Tournaments and Incentive Alignment: The Effect on Firm Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kale, Jayant R.; Reis, Ebru; Venkateswaran, Anand
We investigate simultaneously the impact of promotion-based tournament incentives for VPs and equity-based (alignment) incentives for VPs and the chief executive officer (CEO) on firm performance. We find that tournament incentives, as measured by the pay differential between the CEO and VPs, relate positively to firm performance. The relation is more positive when the CEO nears retirement and less positive when the firm has a new CEO, and weakens further when the new CEO is an outsider. Our analysis is robust to corrections for endogeneity of all our incentive measures and to several alternative measures of tournament incentives and firm performance.</description><author>Kale, Jayant R.; Reis, Ebru; Venkateswaran, Anand</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Price of Correlation Risk: Evidence from Equity Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Driessen, Joost; Maenhout, Pascal J.; Vilkov, Grigory
We study whether exposure to marketwide correlation shocks affects expected option returns, using data on S&amp;P100 index options, options on all components, and stock returns. We find evidence of priced correlation risk based on prices of index and individual variance risk. A trading strategy exploiting priced correlation risk generates a high alpha and is attractive for CRRA investors without frictions. Correlation risk exposure explains the cross-section of index and individual option returns well. The correlation risk premium cannot be exploited with realistic trading frictions, providing a limits-to-arbitrage interpretation of our finding of a high price of correlation risk.</description><author>Driessen, Joost; Maenhout, Pascal J.; Vilkov, Grigory</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading Costs and Returns for US Equities: Estimating Effective Costs from Daily Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasbrouck, Joel
The effective cost of trading is usually estimated from transaction-level data. This study proposes a Gibbs estimate that is based on daily closing prices. In a validation sample, the daily Gibbs estimate achieves a correlation of 0.965 with the transaction-level estimate. When the Gibbs estimates are incorporated into asset pricing specifications over a long historical sample (1926 to 2006), the results suggest that effective cost (as a characteristic) is positively related to stock returns. The relation is strongest in January, but it appears to be distinct from size effects.</description><author>Hasbrouck, Joel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO Underpricing over the Very Long Run</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chambers, David; Dimson, Elroy
A central measure of the efficiency of the Initial Public Offering (IPO) market is the extent to which issues are underpriced. We present new and comprehensive evidence covering British IPOs since World War I. During the period from 1917 to 1945, public offers were underpriced by an average of only 3.80%, as compared to 9.15% in the period from 1946 to 1986, and even more after the U.K. stock market was deregulated in 1986. The post-WWII rise in underpricing cannot be attributed to changes in firm composition, and occurred in spite of improvements in regulation, disclosure, and the prestige of IPO underwriters.</description><author>Chambers, David; Dimson, Elroy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oil Futures Prices in a Production Economy with Investment Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kogan, Leonid; Livdan, Dmitry; Yaron, Amir
We document a new stylized fact, that the relationship between the volatility of oil futures prices and the slope of the forward curve is nonmonotone and has a V-shape. This pattern cannot be generated by standard models that emphasize storage. We develop an equilibrium model of oil production in which investment is irreversible and capacity constrained. Investment constraints affect firms' investment decisions and imply that the supply elasticity changes over time. Since demand shocks must be absorbed by changes in prices or changes in supply, time-varying supply elasticity results in time-varying volatility of futures prices. Estimating this model, we show it is quantitatively consistent with the V-shape relationship between the volatility of futures prices and the slope of the forward curve.</description><author>Kogan, Leonid; Livdan, Dmitry; Yaron, Amir</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Eat or Be Eaten: A Theory of Mergers and Firm Size</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, Gary; Kahl, Matthias; Rosen, Richard J.
We propose a theory of mergers that combines managerial merger motives with an industry-level regime shift that may lead to value-increasing merger opportunities. Anticipation of these merger opportunities can lead to defensive acquisitions, where managers acquire other firms to avoid losing private benefits if their firms are acquired, or "positioning" acquisitions, where firms position themselves as more attractive takeover targets to earn takeover premia. The identity of acquirers and targets and the profitability of acquisitions depend on the distribution of firm sizes within an industry, among other factors. We find empirical support for some unique predictions of our theory.</description><author>Gorton, Gary; Kahl, Matthias; Rosen, Richard J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of Vertical Integration: Financial Development and Contracting Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acemoglu, Daron; Johnson, Simon; Mitton, Todd
We study the determinants of vertical integration in a new data set of over 750,000 firms from 93 countries. We present a number of theoretical predictions on the interactions between financial development, contracting costs, and the extent of vertical integration. Consistent with these predictions, contracting costs and financial development by themselves appear to have no effect on vertical integration. However, we find greater vertical integration in countries that have both greater contracting costs and greater financial development. We also show that countries with greater contracting costs are more vertically integrated in more capital-intensive industries.</description><author>Acemoglu, Daron; Johnson, Simon; Mitton, Todd</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Taxation and the Direction and Volume of Cross-Border M&amp;As</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huizinga, Harry P.; Voget, Johannes
We show that the parent-subsidiary structure of multinational firms created by cross-border mergers and acquisitions is affected by the prospect of international double taxation. Specifically, the likelihood of parent firm location in a country following a cross-border takeover is reduced by high international double taxation of foreign-source income. At the same time, countries with high international double taxation attract smaller numbers of parent firms. A unilateral elimination of worldwide taxation by the United States is simulated to increase the proportion of parent firms locating in the United States following cross-border mergers and acquisitions from 53% to 58%.</description><author>Huizinga, Harry P.; Voget, Johannes</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Loan Supply, Lender Choice, and Corporate Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leary, Mark T.
This paper explores the relevance of capital market supply frictions for corporate capital structure decisions. To identify this relationship, I study the effect on firms' financial structures of two changes in bank funding constraints: the 1961 emergence of the market for certificates of deposit, and the 1966 Credit Crunch. Following an expansion (contraction) in the availability of bank loans, leverage ratios of bank-dependent firms significantly increase (decrease) relative to firms with bond market access. Concurrent changes in the composition of financing sources lend further support to the role of credit supply and debt market segmentation in capital structure choice.</description><author>Leary, Mark T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Level Playing Fields in International Financial Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morrison, Alan D.; White, Lucy
We analyze the desirability of level playing fields in international financial regulation. In general, level playing fields impose the standards of the weakest regulator upon the best-regulated economies. However, they may be desirable when capital is mobile because they counter a cherry-picking effect that lowers the size and efficiency of banks in weaker economies. Hence, while a laissez faire policy favors the better-regulated economy, level playing fields are good for weaker regulators. We show that multinational banking mitigates the cherry-picking effect, and reduces the damage that a level playing field causes in the better-regulated economy.</description><author>Morrison, Alan D.; White, Lucy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Stock Mergers Create Value for Acquirers ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savor, Pavel G.; Lu, Qi
This paper finds support for the hypothesis that overvalued firms create value for long-term shareholders by using their equity as currency. Any approach centered on abnormal returns is complicated by the fact that the most overvalued firms have the greatest incentive to engage in stock acquisitions. We solve this endogeneity problem by creating a sample of mergers that fail for exogenous reasons. We find that unsuccessful stock bidders significantly underperform successful ones. Failure to consummate is costlier for richly priced firms, and the unrealized acquirer-target combination would have earned higher returns. None of these results hold for cash bids.</description><author>Savor, Pavel G.; Lu, Qi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Immobility and the Home Bias Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; Veldkamp, Laura
Many argue that home bias arises because home investors can predict home asset payoffs more accurately than foreigners can. But why does global information access not eliminate this asymmetry ? We model investors, endowed with a small home information advantage, who choose what information to learn before they invest. Surprisingly, even when home investors can learn what foreigners know, they choose not to: Investors profit more from knowing information others do not know. Learning amplifies information asymmetry. The model matches patterns of local and industry bias, foreign investments, portfolio outperformance, and asset prices. Finally, we propose new avenues for empirical research.</description><author>Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; Veldkamp, Laura</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Options, Product Market Competition, and Asset Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aguerrevere, Felipe L.
We study how competition in the product market affects the link between firms' real investment decisions and their asset return dynamics. In our model, assets in place and growth options have different sensitivities to market wide uncertainty. The strategic behavior of market participants influences the relative importance of these components of firm value. We show that the relationship between the degree of competition and assets' expected rates of return varies with product market demand. When demand is low, firms in more competitive industries earn higher returns, whereas when demand is high firms in more concentrated industries earn higher returns.</description><author>Aguerrevere, Felipe L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor Rights, Enforcement, and Bank Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, Kee-Hong; Goyal, Vidhan K.
We examine whether differences in legal protection affect the size, maturity, and interest rate spread on loans to borrowers in 48 countries. Results show that banks respond to poor enforceability of contracts by reducing loan amounts, shortening loan maturities, and increasing loan spreads. These effects are both statistically significant and economically large. While stronger creditor rights reduce spreads, they do not seem to matter for loan size and maturity. Overall, we show that variation in enforceability of contracts matters a great deal more to how loans are structured and how they are priced.</description><author>Bae, Kee-Hong; Goyal, Vidhan K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Income Risk and Portfolio Choice: An Empirical Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angerer, Xiaohong; Lam, Pok-Sang
This paper investigates the relationship between portfolio choice and labor income risk in the National Longitudinal Survey of Youth 1979 Cohort. Permanent income risk (variability of shocks to income that have permanent effect) significantly reduces the share of risky assets in the household's portfolio, while transitory income risk (variability of shocks with no lasting effect) does not. This result provides strong evidence that households' portfolio choices respond to labor income risks in a manner consistent with economic theory.</description><author>Angerer, Xiaohong; Lam, Pok-Sang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Fund Risk Dynamics: Implications for Performance Appraisal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Whaley, Robert E.
Accurate appraisal of hedge fund performance must recognize the freedom with which managers shift asset classes, strategies, and leverage in response to changing market conditions and arbitrage opportunities. The standard measure of performance is the abnormal return defined by a hedge fund's exposure to risk factors. If exposures are assumed constant when, in fact, they vary through time, estimated abnormal returns may be incorrect. We employ an optimal changepoint regression that allows risk exposures to shift, and illustrate the impact on performance appraisal using a sample of live and dead funds during the period January 1994 through December 2005.</description><author>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Whaley, Robert E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Flow, Consumption Risk, and the Cross-section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi
I link an asset's risk premium to two characteristics of its underlying cash flow: covariance and duration. Using empirically novel estimates of both cash flow characteristics based exclusively on accounting earnings and aggregate consumption data, I examine their dynamic interaction in a two-factor cash flow model and find that they are able to explain up to 82% of the cross-sectional variation in the average returns on size, book-to-market, and long-term reversal-sorted portfolios for the period 1964 to 2002. This finding highlights the importance of fundamental cash flow characteristics in determining the risk exposure of an asset.</description><author>Da, Zhi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Constraints, Debt Capacity, and the Cross-section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hahn, Jaehoon; Lee, Hangyong
Building on a model of corporate investment under collateral constraints, we develop and test a hypothesis on the differential effect of debt capacity on stock returns across financially constrained and unconstrained firms. Consistent with the hypothesis, we find that debt capacity is a significant determinant of stock returns only in the cross-section of financially constrained firms, after controlling for beta, size, book-to-market, leverage, and momentum. The findings suggest that cross-sectional differences in corporate investment behavior arising from financial constraints, predicted by theories of imperfect capital markets and supported by empirical evidence, are reflected in the stock returns of manufacturing firms.</description><author>Hahn, Jaehoon; Lee, Hangyong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and the Declining Impact of Bank Finance on Loan Supply: Evidence from Mortgage Originations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loutskina, Elena; Strahan, Philip E.
Low-cost deposits and increased balance sheet liquidity raise banks' supply of illiquid loans more than loans easily sold or securitized. We exploit the inability of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to purchase jumbo mortgages to identify an exogenous change in liquidity. The volume of jumbo mortgage originations relative to nonjumbo originations increases with bank holdings of liquid assets and decreases with bank deposit costs. This result suggests that the increasing depth of the mortgage secondary market fostered by securitization has reduced the effect of lender's financial condition on credit supply.</description><author>Loutskina, Elena; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Work Ethic, Employment Contracts, and Firm Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ian Carlin, Bruce; Gervais, Simon
We analyze how the work ethic of managers impacts a firm's employment contracts, riskiness, growth potential, and organizational structure. Flat contracts are optimal for diligent managers because they reduce risk-sharing costs, but they attract egoistic agents who shirk and unskilled agents who add no value. Stable, bureaucratic firms with low growth potential are more likely to gain value from managerial diligence. Firms that hire from a virtuous pool of agents are more conservative in their investments and have a horizontal corporate structure. Our theory also yields several testable implications that distinguish it from standard agency models.</description><author>Ian Carlin, Bruce; Gervais, Simon</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Drives the Disposition Effect ? An Analysis of a Long-Standing Preference-Based Explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barberis, Nicholas; Xiong, Wei
We investigate whether prospect theory preferences can predict a disposition effect. We consider two implementations of prospect theory: in one case, preferences are defined over annual gains and losses; in the other, they are defined over realized gains and losses. Surprisingly, the annual gain/loss model often fails to predict a disposition effect. The realized gain/loss model, however, predicts a disposition effect more reliably. Utility from realized gains and losses may therefore be a useful way of thinking about certain aspects of individual investor trading.</description><author>Barberis, Nicholas; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Inattention and Friday Earnings Announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dellavigna, Stefano; Pollet, Joshua M.
Does limited attention among investors affect stock returns ? We compare the response to earnings announcements on Friday, when investor inattention is more likely, to the response on other weekdays. If inattention influences stock prices, we should observe less immediate response and more drift for Friday announcements. Indeed, Friday announcements have a 15% lower immediate response and a 70% higher delayed response. A portfolio investing in differential Friday drift earns substantial abnormal returns. In addition, trading volume is 8% lower around Friday announcements. These findings support explanations of post-earnings announcement drift based on underreaction to information caused by limited attention.</description><author>Dellavigna, Stefano; Pollet, Joshua M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Catastrophic Risk and Credit Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, Mark J.; Moskowitz, Tobias J.
We provide a model of the effects of catastrophic risk on real estate financing and prices and demonstrate that insurance market imperfections can restrict the supply of credit for catastrophe-susceptible properties. Using unique micro-level data, we find that earthquake risk decreased commercial real estate bank loan provision by 22% in California properties in the 1990s, with more severe effects in African-American neighborhoods. We show that the 1994 Northridge earthquake had only a short-term disruptive effect. Our basic findings are confirmed for hurricane risk, and our model and empirical work have implications for terrorism and political perils.</description><author>Garmaise, Mark J.; Moskowitz, Tobias J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk in Dynamic Arbitrage: The Price Effects of Convergence Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kondor, Peter
I develop an equilibrium model of convergence trading and its impact on asset prices. Arbitrageurs optimally decide how to allocate their limited capital over time. Their activity reduces price discrepancies, but their activity also generates losses with positive probability, even if the trading opportunity is fundamentally riskless. Moreover, prices of identical assets can diverge even if the constraints faced by arbitrageurs are not binding. Occasionally, total losses are large, making arbitrageurs' returns negatively skewed, consistent with the empirical evidence. The model also predicts comovement of arbitrageurs' expected returns and market liquidity.</description><author>Kondor, Peter</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium Portfolio Strategies in the Presence of Sentiment Risk and Excess Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dumas, Bernard; Kurshev, Alexander; Uppal, Raman
Our objective is to identify the trading strategy that would allow an investor to take advantage of "excessive" stock price volatility and "sentiment" fluctuations. We construct a general equilibrium "difference-of-opinion" model of sentiment in which there are two classes of agents, one of which is overconfident about a public signal, while still optimizing intertemporally. Overconfident investors overreact to the signal and introduce an additional risk factor causing stock prices to be excessively volatile. Consequently, rational investors choose a conservative portfolio; moreover, this portfolio depends not just on the current price divergence but also on their prediction about future sentiment and the speed of price convergence.</description><author>Dumas, Bernard; Kurshev, Alexander; Uppal, Raman</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sensation Seeking, Overconfidence, and Trading Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinblatt, Mark; Keloharju, Matti
This study analyzes the role that two psychological attributes-sensation seeking and overconfidence-play in the tendency of investors to trade stocks. Equity trading data from Finland are combined with data from investor tax filings, driving records, and mandatory psychological profiles. We use these data, obtained from a large population, to construct measures of overconfidence and sensation seeking tendencies. Controlling for a host of variables, including wealth, income, age, number of stocks owned, marital status, and occupation, we find that overconfident investors and those investors most prone to sensation seeking trade more frequently.</description><author>Grinblatt, Mark; Keloharju, Matti</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do US Firms Hold So Much More Cash than They Used To?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, Thomas W.; Kahle, Kathleen M.; Stulz, Rene M.
The average cash-to-assets ratio for U.S. industrial firms more than doubles from 1980 to 2006. A measure of the economic importance of this increase is that at the end of the sample period, the average firm can retire all debt obligations with its cash holdings. Cash ratios increase because firms' cash flows become riskier. In addition, firms change: They hold fewer inventories and receivables and are increasingly R&amp;D intensive. While the precautionary motive for cash holdings plays an important role in explaining the increase in cash ratios, we find no consistent evidence that agency conflicts contribute to the increase.</description><author>Bates, Thomas W.; Kahle, Kathleen M.; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Media Coverage and the Cross-section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Lily; Peress, Joel
By reaching a broad population of investors, mass media can alleviate informational frictions and affect security pricing even if it does not supply genuine news. We investigate this hypothesis by studying the cross-sectional relation between media coverage and expected stock returns. We find that stocks with no media coverage earn higher returns than stocks with high media coverage even after controlling for well-known risk factors. These results are more pronounced among small stocks and stocks with high individual ownership, low analyst following, and high idiosyncratic volatility. Our findings suggest that the breadth of information dissemination affects stock returns.</description><author>Fang, Lily; Peress, Joel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Contagion from Counterparty Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jorion, Philippe; Zhang, Gaiyan
Standard credit risk models cannot explain the observed clustering of default, sometimes described as "credit contagion." This paper provides the first empirical analysis of credit contagion via direct counterparty effects. We find that bankruptcy announcements cause negative abnormal equity returns and increases in CDS spreads for creditors. In addition, creditors with large exposures are more likely to suffer from financial distress later. This suggests that counterparty risk is a potential additional channel of credit contagion. Indeed, the fear of counterparty defaults among financial institutions explains the sudden worsening of the credit crisis after the Lehman bankruptcy in September 2008.</description><author>Jorion, Philippe; Zhang, Gaiyan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Frailty Correlated Default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffie, Darrell; Eckner, Andreas; Horel, Guillaume; Saita, Leandro
The probability of extreme default losses on portfolios of U. S. corporate debt is much greater than would be estimated under the standard assumption that default correlation arises only from exposure to observable risk factors. At the high confidence levels at which bank loan portfolio and collateralized debt obligation (CDO) default losses are typically measured for economic capital and rating purposes, conventionally based loss estimates are downward biased by a full order of magnitude on test portfolios. Our estimates are based on U. S. public nonfinancial firms between 1979 and 2004. We find strong evidence for the presence of common latent factors, even when controlling for observable factors that provide the most accurate available model of firm-by-firm default probabilities.</description><author>Duffie, Darrell; Eckner, Andreas; Horel, Guillaume; Saita, Leandro</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Attracting Flows by Attracting Big Clients</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren; Schmidt, Breno
We explore a new channel for attracting inflows using a unique data set of corporate 401(k) retirement plans and their mutual fund family trustees. Families secure substantial inflows by being named trustee. We find that family trustees significantly overweight, and are reluctant to sell, their 401(k) client firm's stock. Trustee overweighting is more pronounced when the relationship is more valuable to the trustee family, and is concentrated in those funds receiving the greatest benefit from the inflows. We quantify this flow benefit and find that inclusion in the 401(k) plan has an economically and statistically large, positive effect on inflows.</description><author>Cohen, Lauren; Schmidt, Breno</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Relation between Price and Performance in the Mutual Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gil-Bazo, Javier; Ruiz-Verdu, Pablo
Gruber (1996) drew attention to the puzzle that investors buy actively managed equity mutual funds, even though on average such funds underperform index funds. We uncover another puzzling fact about the market for equity mutual funds: Funds with worse before-fee performance charge higher fees. This negative relation between fees and performance is robust and can be explained as the outcome of strategic fee-setting by mutual funds in the presence of investors with different degrees of sensitivity to performance. We also find some evidence that better fund governance may bring fees more in line with performance.</description><author>Gil-Bazo, Javier; Ruiz-Verdu, Pablo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business Networks, Corporate Governance, and Contracting in the Mutual Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuhnen, Camelia M.
Business connections can mitigate agency conflicts by facilitating efficient information transfers, but can also be channels for inefficient favoritism. I analyze these two effects in the mutual fund industry and find that fund directors and advisory firms that manage the funds hire each other preferentially based on the intensity of their past interactions. I do not find evidence that stronger board-advisor ties correspond to better or worse outcomes for fund shareholders. These results suggest that the two effects of board-management connections on investor welfare-improved monitoring and increased potential for collusion-balance out in this setting.</description><author>Kuhnen, Camelia M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Catering through Nominal Share Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Malcolm; Greenwood, Robin; Wurgler, Jeffrey
We propose and test a catering theory of nominal stock prices. The theory predicts that when investors place higher valuations on low-price firms, managers respond by supplying shares at lower price levels, and vice versa. We confirm these predictions in time-series and firm-level data using several measures of time-varying catering incentives. More generally, the results provide unusually clean evidence that catering influences corporate decisions, because the process of targeting nominal share prices is not well explained by alternative theories.</description><author>Baker, Malcolm; Greenwood, Robin; Wurgler, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-Run Stockholder Consumption Risk and Asset Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malloy, Christopher J.; Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Vissing-Jorgensen, Annette
We provide new evidence on the success of long-run risks in asset pricing by focusing on the risks borne by stockholders. Exploiting microlevel household consumption data, we show that long-run stockholder consumption risk better captures cross-sectional variation in average asset returns than aggregate or nonstockholder consumption risk, and implies more plausible risk aversion estimates. We find that risk aversion around 10 can match observed risk premia for the wealthiest stockholders across sets of test assets that include the 25 Fama and French portfolios, the market portfolio, bond portfolios, and the entire cross-section of stocks.</description><author>Malloy, Christopher J.; Moskowitz, Tobias J.; Vissing-Jorgensen, Annette</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blockholder Trading, Market Efficiency, and Managerial Myopia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex
This paper analyzes how blockholders can exert governance even if they cannot intervene in a firm's operations. Blockholders have strong incentives to monitor the firm's fundamental value because they can sell their stakes upon negative information. By trading on private information (following the "Wall Street Rule"), they cause prices to reflect fundamental value rather than current earnings. This in turn encourages managers to invest for long-run growth rather than short-term profits. Contrary to the view that the U.S.'s liquid markets and transient shareholders exacerbate myopia, I show that they can encourage investment by impounding its effects into prices.</description><author>Edmans, Alex</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reinforcement Learning and Savings Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, James J.; Laibson, David; Madrian, Brigitte C.; Metrick, Andrew
We show that individual investors over-extrapolate from their personal experience when making savings decisions. Investors who experience particularly rewarding outcomes from 401(k) saving-a high average and/or low variance return-increase their 401(k) savings rate more than investors who have less rewarding experiences. This finding is not driven by aggregate time-series shocks, income effects, rational learning about investing skill, investor fixed effects, or time-varying investor-level heterogeneity that is correlated with portfolio allocations to stock, bond, and cash asset classes. We discuss implications for the equity premium puzzle and interventions aimed at improving household financial outcomes.</description><author>Choi, James J.; Laibson, David; Madrian, Brigitte C.; Metrick, Andrew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum, Reversal, and Uninformed Traders in Laboratory Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloomfield, Robert J.; Tayler, William B.; Zhou, Flora
We report the results of three experiments based on the model of Hong and Stein (1999). Consistent with the model, the results show that when informed traders do not observe prices, uninformed traders generate long-term price reversals by engaging in momentum trade. However, when informed traders also observe prices, uninformed traders generate reversals by engaging in contrarian trading. The results suggest that a dominated information set is sufficient to account for the contrarian behavior observed among individual investors, and that uninformed traders may be responsible for long-term price reversals but play little role in driving short-term momentum.</description><author>Bloomfield, Robert J.; Tayler, William B.; Zhou, Flora</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Stock Return Comovements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, Geert; Hodrick, Robert J.; Zhang, Xiaoyan
We examine international stock return comovements using country-industry and country-style portfolios as the base portfolios. We first establish that parsimonious risk-based factor models capture the data covariance structure better than the popular Heston-Rouwenhorst (1994) model. We then establish the following stylized facts regarding stock return comovements. First, there is no evidence for an upward trend in return correlations, except for the European stock markets. Second, the increasing importance of industry factors relative to country factors was a short-lived phenomenon. Third, large growth stocks are more correlated across countries than are small value stocks, and the difference has increased over time.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Hodrick, Robert J.; Zhang, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Manipulation of Executive Stock Option Exercise Strategies: Information Timing and Backdating</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cicero, David C.
I identify three option exercise strategies executives engage in, including (i) exercising with cash and immediately selling the shares, (ii) exercising with cash and holding the shares, and (iii) delivering some shares to the company to cover the exercise costs and holding the remaining shares. Stock price patterns suggest executives manipulate option exercises. They use private information to increase the profitability of all three strategies, and likely backdated some exercise dates in the pre-Sarbanes-Oxley period to enhance the profitability of the latter two strategies, where the executive's company is the only counterparty. Backdating is associated with reporting of internal control weaknesses.</description><author>Cicero, David C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Bayesian's Bubble</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, C. Wei; Xue, Hui
The acceleration of the U.S. productivity growth in the late 1990s suggests a significant advance in technological innovation, making the perceived probability of entering a "new economy" ever increasing. Based on macroeconomic data, we identify a Bayesian investor's belief evolution when facing a possible structural break in the economy. We show that such belief evolution plays a significant role in explaining both the stock market boom and crash during 1998 to 2001. We conclude that a rational investor's uncertainty about the future of the U.S. economy provides an alternative explanation for the late 1990s stock market "bubble.".</description><author>Li, C. Wei; Xue, Hui</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implications of Keeping-Up-with-the-Joneses Behavior for the Equilibrium Cross Section of Stock Returns: International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomez, Juan-Pedro; Priestley, Richard; Zapatero, Fernando
This paper tests the cross-sectional implications of "keeping-up-with-the-Joneses" (KUJ) preferences in an international setting. When agents have KUJ preferences, in the presence of undiversifiable nonfinancial wealth, both world and domestic risk (the idiosyncratic component of domestic wealth) are priced, and the equilibrium price of risk of the domestic factor is negative. We use labor income as a proxy for domestic wealth and find empirical support for these predictions. In terms of explaining the cross-section of stock returns and the size of the pricing errors, the model performs better than alternative international asset pricing models.</description><author>Gomez, Juan-Pedro; Priestley, Richard; Zapatero, Fernando</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Price Is (Almost) Right</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Randolph B.; Polk, Christopher; Vuolteenaho, Tuomo
Most previous research tests market efficiency using average abnormal trading profits on dynamic trading strategies, and typically rejects the joint hypothesis of market efficiency and an asset pricing model. In contrast, we adopt the perspective of a buy-and-hold investor and examine stock price levels. For such an investor, the price level is more relevant than the short-horizon expected return, and betas of cash flow fundamentals are more important than high-frequency stock return betas. Our cross-sectional tests suggest that there exist specifications in which differences in relative price levels of individual stocks can be largely explained by their fundamental betas.</description><author>Cohen, Randolph B.; Polk, Christopher; Vuolteenaho, Tuomo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Rational Expectations Equilibrium with Informative Trading Volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schneider, Jan
A large number of empirical studies find that trading volume contains information about the distribution of future returns. While these studies indicate that observing volume is helpful to an outside observer of the economy it is not clear how investors within the economy can learn from trading volume. In this paper, I show how trading volume helps investors to evaluate the precision of the aggregate information in the price. I construct a model that offers a closed-form solution of a rational expectations equilibrium where all investors learn from (1) private signals, (2) the market price, and (3) aggregate trading volume.</description><author>Schneider, Jan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exponential Growth Bias and Household Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stango, Victor; Zinman, Jonathan
Exponential growth bias is the pervasive tendency to linearize exponential functions when assessing them intuitively. We show that exponential growth bias can explain two stylized facts in household finance: the tendency to underestimate an interest rate given other loan terms, and the tendency to underestimate a future value given other investment terms. Bias matters empirically: More-biased households borrow more, save less, favor shorter maturities, and use and benefit more from financial advice, conditional on a rich set of household characteristics. There is little evidence that our measure of exponential growth bias merely proxies for broader financial sophistication.</description><author>Stango, Victor; Zinman, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Role of Managerial Incentives and Discretion in Hedge Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Daniel, Naveen D.; Naik, Narayan Y.
Using a comprehensive hedge fund database, we examine the role of managerial incentives and discretion in hedge fund performance. Hedge funds with greater managerial incentives, proxied by the delta of the option-like incentive fee contracts, higher levels of managerial ownership, and the inclusion of high-water mark provisions in the incentive contracts, are associated with superior performance. The incentive fee percentage rate by itself does not explain performance. We also find that funds with a higher degree of managerial discretion, proxied by longer lockup, notice, and redemption periods, deliver superior performance. These results are robust to using alternative performance measures and controlling for different data-related biases.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Daniel, Naveen D.; Naik, Narayan Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Hedge Fund Managers Misreport Returns? Evidence from the Pooled Distribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Pool, Veronika K.
We find a significant discontinuity in the pooled distribution of monthly hedge fund returns: The number of small gains far exceeds the number of small losses. The discontinuity is present in live and defunct funds, and funds of all ages, suggesting that it is not caused by database biases. The discontinuity is absent in the 3 months culminating in an audit, suggesting it is not attributable to skillful loss avoidance. The discontinuity disappears when using bimonthly returns, indicating a reversal in fund performance following small gains. This result suggests that the discontinuity is caused at least in part by temporarily overstated returns.</description><author>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Pool, Veronika K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Driven to Distraction: Extraneous Events and Underreaction to Earnings News</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Lim, Sonya Seongyeon; Teoh, Siew Hong
Recent studies propose that limited investor attention causes market underreactions. This paper directly tests this explanation by measuring the information load faced by investors. The investor distraction hypothesis holds that extraneous news inhibits market reactions to relevant news. We find that the immediate price and volume reaction to a firm's earnings surprise is much weaker, and post-announcement drift much stronger, when a greater number of same-day earnings announcements are made by other firms. We evaluate the economic importance of distraction effects through a trading strategy, which yields substantial alphas. Industry-unrelated news and large earnings surprises have a stronger distracting effect.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Lim, Sonya Seongyeon; Teoh, Siew Hong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Gambles in the Stock Market ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Alok
This study shows that the propensity to gamble and investment decisions are correlated. At the aggregate level, individual investors prefer stocks with lottery features, and like lottery demand, the demand for lottery-type stocks increases during economic downturns. In the cross-section, socioeconomic factors that induce greater expenditure in lotteries are associated with greater investment in lottery-type stocks. Further, lottery investment levels are higher in regions with favorable lottery environments. Because lottery-type stocks underperform, gambling-related underperformance is greater among low-income investors who excessively overweight lottery-type stocks. These results indicate that state lotteries and lottery-type stocks attract very similar socioeconomic clienteles.</description><author>Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rewriting History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ljungqvist, Alexander; Malloy, Christopher; Marston, Felicia
We document widespread changes to the historical I/B/E/S analyst stock recommendations database. Across seven I/B/E/S downloads, obtained between 2000 and 2007, we find that between 6,580 (1.6%) and 97,582 (21.7%) of matched observations are different from one download to the next. The changes include alterations of recommendations, additions and deletions of records, and removal of analyst names. These changes are nonrandom, clustering by analyst reputation, broker size and status, and recommendation boldness, and affect trading signal classifications and back-tests of three stylized facts: profitability of trading signals, profitability of consensus recommendation changes, and persistence in individual analyst stock-picking ability.</description><author>Ljungqvist, Alexander; Malloy, Christopher; Marston, Felicia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>First-Order Risk Aversion, Heterogeneity, and Asset Market Outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chapman, David A.; Polkovnichenko, Valery
We examine a wide range of two-date economies populated by heterogeneous agents with the most common forms of nonexpected utility preferences used in finance and macroeconomics. We demonstrate that the risk premium and the risk-free rate in these models are sensitive to ignoring heterogeneity. This follows because of endogenous withdrawal by nonexpected utility agents from the market for the risky asset. This finding is important precisely because these alternative preferences have frequently been proposed as possible resolutions to various asset pricing puzzles, and they have all been examined exclusively in a representative agent framework.</description><author>Chapman, David A.; Polkovnichenko, Valery</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financially Constrained Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Livdan, Dmitry; Sapriza, Horacio; Zhang, Lu
We study the effect of financial constraints on risk and expected returns by extending the investment-based asset pricing framework to incorporate retained earnings, debt, costly equity, and collateral constraints on debt capacity. Quantitative results show that more financially constrained firms are riskier and earn higher expected stock returns than less financially constrained firms. Intuitively, by preventing firms from financing all desired investments, collateral constraints restrict the flexibility of firms in smoothing dividend streams in the face of aggregate shocks. The inflexibility mechanism also gives rise to a convex relation between market leverage and expected stock returns.</description><author>Livdan, Dmitry; Sapriza, Horacio; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing the Tax Benefits from Employee Stock Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Babenko, Ilona; Tserlukevich, Yuri
Employees tend to exercise stock options when corporate taxable income is high, shifting corporate tax deductions to years with higher tax rates. If firms paid employees the same dollar value in wages instead of stock options, the average annual tax bill for large U.S. companies would increase by $12.6 million, or 9.8%. These direct tax benefits of options increase in the convexity of the tax function. In addition, profitable firms can realize indirect tax benefits because stock options increase debt capacity. Although tax minimization is probably not the main motive for option grants, firms with larger potential tax benefits grant more options.</description><author>Babenko, Ilona; Tserlukevich, Yuri</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Target Behavior and Financing: How Conclusive Is the Evidence ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Xin; Dasgupta, Sudipto
The notion that firms have a debt ratio target that is a primary determinant of financing behavior is influential in finance. Yet, how definitive is the evidence ? We address this issue by generating samples where financing is unrelated to a firm's current debt ratio or a target. We find that much of the available evidence in favor of target behavior based on leverage ratio changes can be reproduced for these samples. Taken together, our findings suggest that a number of existing tests of target behavior have no power to reject alternatives.</description><author>Chang, Xin; Dasgupta, Sudipto</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Corporate Propensity to Save</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Riddick, Leigh A.; Whited, Toni M.
Why do corporations accumulate liquid assets ? We show theoretically that intertemporal trade-offs between interest income taxation and the cost of external finance determine optimal savings. Intriguingly, we find that, controlling for Tobin's q, saving and cash flow are negatively related because firms lower cash reserves to invest after receiving positive cash-flow shocks, and vice versa. Consistent with theory, we estimate negative propensities to save out of cash flow. We also find that income uncertainty affects saving more than do external finance constraints. Therefore, contrary to previous evidence, saving propensities reflect too many forces to be used to measure external finance constraints.</description><author>Riddick, Leigh A.; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency Problems at Dual-Class Companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masulis, Ronald W.; Wang, Cong; Xie, Fei
Using a sample of U.S. dual-class companies, we examine how divergence between insider voting and cash flow rights affects managerial extraction of private benefits of control. We find that as this divergence widens, corporate cash holdings are worth less to outside shareholders, CEOs receive higher compensation, managers make shareholder value-destroying acquisitions more often, and capital expenditures contribute less to shareholder value. These findings support the agency hypothesis that managers with greater excess control rights over cash flow rights are more prone to pursue private benefits at shareholders' expense, and help explain why firm value is decreasing in insider excess control rights.</description><author>Masulis, Ronald W.; Wang, Cong; Xie, Fei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Control Rights and Capital Structure: An Empirical Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roberts, Michael R.; Sufi, Amir
We show that incentive conflicts between firms and their creditors have a large impact on corporate debt policy. Net debt issuing activity experiences a sharp and persistent decline following debt covenant violations, when creditors use their acceleration and termination rights to increase interest rates and reduce the availability of credit. The effect of creditor actions on debt policy is strongest when the borrower's alternative sources of finance are costly. In addition, despite the less favorable terms offered by existing creditors, borrowers rarely switch lenders following a violation.</description><author>Roberts, Michael R.; Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explicit versus Implicit Contracts: Evidence from CEO Employment Agreements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gillan, Stuart L.; Hartzell, Jay C.; Parrino, Robert
We report evidence on the determinants of whether the relationship between a firm and its Chief Executive Officer (CEO) is governed by an explicit (written) or an implicit agreement. We find that fewer than half of the CEOs of S&amp;P 500 firms have comprehensive explicit employment agreements. Consistent with contracting theory, explicit agreements are more likely to be observed and are likely to have a longer duration in situations in which the sustainability of the relationship is less certain and where the expected loss to the CEO is greater if the firm fails to honor the agreement.</description><author>Gillan, Stuart L.; Hartzell, Jay C.; Parrino, Robert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictive Systems: Living with Imperfect Predictors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, Lubos; Stambaugh, Robert F.
We develop a framework for estimating expected returns-a predictive system-that allows predictors to be imperfectly correlated with the conditional expected return. When predictors are imperfect, the estimated expected return depends on past returns in a manner that hinges on the correlation between unexpected returns and innovations in expected returns. We find empirically that prior beliefs about this correlation, which is most likely negative, substantially affect estimates of expected returns as well as various inferences about predictability, including assessments of a predictor's usefulness. Compared to standard predictive regressions, predictive systems deliver different expected returns with higher estimated precision.</description><author>Pastor, Lubos; Stambaugh, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Are Buyouts Levered ? The Financial Structure of Private Equity Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Axelson, Ulf; Stroemberg, Per; Weisbach, Michael S.
Private equity funds are important to the economy, yet there is little analysis explaining their financial structure. In our model the financial structure minimizes agency conflicts between fund managers and investors. Relative to financing each deal separately, raising a fund where the manager receives a fraction of aggregate excess returns reduces incentives to make bad investments. Efficiency is further improved by requiring funds to also use deal-by-deal debt financing, which becomes unavailable in states where internal discipline fails. Private equity investment becomes highly sensitive to aggregate credit conditions and investments in bad states outperform investments in good states.</description><author>Axelson, Ulf; Stroemberg, Per; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential Address: Sophisticated Investors and Market Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stein, Jeremy C.
Stock-market trading is increasingly dominated by sophisticated professionals, as opposed to individual investors. Will this trend ultimately lead to greater market efficiency ? I consider two complicating factors. The first is crowding-the fact that, for a wide range of "unanchored" strategies, an arbitrageur cannot know how many of his peers are simultaneously entering the same trade. The second is leverage-when an arbitrageur chooses a privately optimal leverage ratio, he may create a fire-sale externality that raises the likelihood of a severe crash. In some cases, capital regulation may be helpful in dealing with the latter problem.</description><author>Stein, Jeremy C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Getting Out Early: An Analysis of Market Making Activity at the Recommending Analyst's Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Juergens, Jennifer L.; Lindsey, Laura
This paper examines trading volume for Nasdaq market makers around analyst recommendation changes issued by an analyst at the same firm. Using Nasdaq Post-Data, we find a disproportionate increase in market making volume associated with the firm's recommendation changes and evidence of elevated sell volume at the recommending analyst's firm in the 2 days preceding a downgrade. The implications are that the information source matters in determining the placement of trades and that the issuing analyst's firm appears to be rewarded for prereleasing information through increased volume. These findings constitute new evidence of compensation for research production through the market making channel.</description><author>Juergens, Jennifer L.; Lindsey, Laura</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Electing Directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Jie; Garner, Jacqueline L.; Walkling, Ralph A.
Using a large sample of director elections, we document that shareholder votes are significantly related to firm performance, governance, director performance, and voting mechanisms. However, most variables, except meeting attendance and ISS recommendations, have little economic impact on shareholder votes-even poorly performing directors and firms typically receive over 90% of votes cast. Nevertheless, fewer votes lead to lower "abnormal" CEO compensation and a higher probability of removing poison pills, classified boards, and CEOs. Meanwhile, director votes have little impact on election outcomes, firm performance, or director reputation. These results provide important benchmarks for the current debate on election reforms.</description><author>Cai, Jie; Garner, Jacqueline L.; Walkling, Ralph A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making Sense of Cents: An Examination of Firms That Marginally Miss or Beat Analyst Forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhojraj, Sanjeev; Hribar, Paul; Picconi, Marc; Mcinnis, John
This paper examines the performance consequences of cutting discretionary expenditures and managing accruals to exceed analyst forecasts. We show that firms that just beat analyst forecasts with low quality earnings exhibit a short-term stock price benefit relative to firms that miss forecasts with high quality earnings. This trend, however, reverses over a 3-year horizon. Additionally, firms reducing discretionary expenditures to beat forecasts have significantly greater equity issuances and insider selling in the following year, consistent with managers understanding the myopic nature of their actions. Our results confirm survey evidence suggesting managers engage in myopic behavior to beat benchmarks.</description><author>Bhojraj, Sanjeev; Hribar, Paul; Picconi, Marc; Mcinnis, John</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public Information, IPO Price Formation, and Long-Run Returns: Japanese Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kutsuna, Kenji; Smith, Janet Kiholm; Smith, Richard L.
The price formation process of JASDAQ IPOs is more transparent than in the United States. The transparency facilitates analysis of important issues in the IPO literature-why offer prices only partially adjust to public information and adjust more fully to negative information, and why adjustments are related to initial returns. The evidence indicates that early price information conveys the underwriter's commitment to compensate investors for acquiring and/or disclosing information. Offer prices reflect pre-IPO market values of public companies and implicit agreements between underwriters and issuers that originate well before the offering. Underadjustment of offer prices is substantially reversed in the aftermarket.</description><author>Kutsuna, Kenji; Smith, Janet Kiholm; Smith, Richard L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Liquidity and Information Risks Priced in the Treasury Bond Market ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Haitao; Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi; He, Yan
We provide a comprehensive empirical analysis of the effects of liquidity and information risks on expected returns of Treasury bonds. We focus on the systematic liquidity risk of Pastor and Stambaugh as opposed to the traditional microstructure-based measures of liquidity. Information risk is measured by the probability of information-based trading (PIN). We document a strong positive relation between expected Treasury returns and liquidity and information risks, controlling for the effects of other systematic risk factors and bond characteristics. This relation is robust to many empirical specifications and a wide variety of traditional liquidity and informed trading proxies.</description><author>Li, Haitao; Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi; He, Yan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Benefits of Control, Ownership, and the Cross-listing Decision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Lins, Karl V.; Miller, Darius P.; Stulz, Rene M.
This paper investigates how a foreign firm's decision to cross-list on a U.S. stock exchange is related to the consumption of private benefits of control by its controlling shareholders. Theory has proposed that when private benefits are high, controlling shareholders are less likely to choose to cross-list in the United States because of constraints on the consumption of private benefits resulting from such listings. Using several proxies for private benefits related to the control and cash flow ownership rights of controlling shareholders, we find support for this hypothesis with a sample of more than 4,000 firms from 31 countries.</description><author>Doidge, Craig; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Lins, Karl V.; Miller, Darius P.; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Sidedness: Insights into Motives for Trade Initiation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkar, Asani; Schwartz, Robert A.
We infer motives for trade initiation from market sidedness. We define trading as more two-sided (one-sided) if the correlation between the number of buyer- and seller-initiated trades increases (decreases), and assess changes in sidedness (relative to a control sample) around events that identify trade initiators. Consistent with asymmetric information, trading is more one-sided before merger news. Consistent with belief heterogeneity, trading is more two-sided before earnings and macro announcements with greater dispersion in analyst forecasts, and after news with larger announcement surprises. We examine the codeterminacy of sidedness, bid-ask spread, volatility, number of trades, and order imbalance.</description><author>Sarkar, Asani; Schwartz, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor and Corporate Governance: International Evidence from Restructuring Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanassov, Julian; Kim, E. Han
Our results highlight the importance of interaction among management, labor, and investors in shaping corporate governance. We find that strong union laws protect not only workers but also underperforming managers. Weak investor protection combined with strong union laws are conducive to worker-management alliances, wherein poorly performing firms sell assets to prevent large-scale layoffs, garnering worker support to retain management. Asset sales in weak investor protection countries lead to further deteriorating performance, whereas in strong investor protection countries they improve performance and lead to more layoffs. Strong union laws are less effective in preventing layoffs when financial leverage is high.</description><author>Atanassov, Julian; Kim, E. Han</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Entrenched Managers Pay Their Workers More ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cronqvist, Henrik; Heyman, Fredrik; Nilsson, Mattias; Svaleryd, Helena; Vlachos, Jonas
Analyzing a panel that matches public firms with worker-level data, we find that managerial entrenchment affects workers' pay. CEOs with more control pay their workers more, but financial incentives through cash flow rights ownership mitigate such behavior. Entrenched CEOs pay more to employees closer to them in the corporate hierarchy, geographically closer to the headquarters, and associated with conflict-inclined unions. The evidence is consistent with entrenched CEOs paying more to enjoy private benefits such as lower effort wage bargaining and improved social relations with employees. Our results show that managerial ownership and corporate governance can play an important role for employee compensation.</description><author>Cronqvist, Henrik; Heyman, Fredrik; Nilsson, Mattias; Svaleryd, Helena; Vlachos, Jonas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Access to Capital, Capital Structure, and the Funding of the Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, Omer
Based upon a large data set of public and private firms in the United Kingdom, I find that compared to their public counterparts, private firms rely almost exclusively on debt financing, have higher leverage ratios, and tend to avoid external capital markets, leading to a greater sensitivity of their capital structures to fluctuations in performance. I argue that these differences are due to private equity being more costly than public equity. I further examine the private firms subsample to show that private equity is more costly than its public counterpart due to information asymmetry and the desire to maintain control.</description><author>Brav, Omer</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Compensation and Board Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chhaochharia, Vidhi; Grinstein, Yaniv
In response to corporate scandals in 2001 and 2002, major U.S. stock exchanges issued new board requirements to enhance board oversight. We find a significant decrease in CEO compensation for firms that were more affected by these requirements, compared with firms that were less affected, taking into account unobservable firm effects, time-varying industry effects, size, and performance. The decrease in compensation is particularly pronounced in the subset of affected firms with no outside blockholder on the board and in affected firms with low concentration of institutional investors. Our results suggest that the new board requirements affected CEO compensation decisions.</description><author>Chhaochharia, Vidhi; Grinstein, Yaniv</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial Shareholder Activism: Hedge Funds and Other Private Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klein, April; Zur, Emanuel
We examine recent confrontational activism campaigns by hedge funds and other private investors. The main parallels between the groups are a significantly positive market reaction for the target firm around the initial Schedule 13D filing date, significantly positive returns over the subsequent year, and the activist's high success rate in achieving its original objective. Further, both activists frequently gain board representation through real or threatened proxy solicitations. Two major differences are that hedge funds target more profitable firms than other activists, and hedge funds address cash flow agency costs whereas other private investors change the target's investment strategies.</description><author>Klein, April; Zur, Emanuel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Innovation and Growth: Cash Flow, External Equity, and the 1990s R&amp;D Boom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, James R.; Fazzari, Steven M.; Petersen, Bruce C.
The financing of R&amp;D provides a potentially important channel to link finance and economic growth, but there is no direct evidence that financial effects are large enough to impact aggregate R&amp;D. U.S. firms finance R&amp;D from volatile sources: cash flow and stock issues. We estimate dynamic R&amp;D models for high-tech firms and find significant effects of cash flow and external equity for young, but not mature, firms. The financial coefficients for young firms are large enough that finance supply shifts can explain most of the dramatic 1990s R&amp;D boom, which implies a significant connection between finance, innovation, and growth.</description><author>Brown, James R.; Fazzari, Steven M.; Petersen, Bruce C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Share Repurchases and Pay-Performance Sensitivity of Employee Compensation Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Babenko, Ilona
I show that share repurchases increase pay-performance sensitivity of employee compensation and lead to greater employee effort and higher stock prices. Consistent with the model, I find that after repurchases, employees and managers receive fewer stock option and equity grants, and that the market reacts favorably to repurchase announcements when employees have many unvested stock options. Managers are more likely to initiate share repurchases when employees hold a large stake in the firm. Moreover, since employees are forced to bear more risk in firms that repurchase shares, they exercise their stock options earlier and receive higher compensation.</description><author>Babenko, Ilona</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should Investors Bet on the Jockey or the Horse ? Evidence from the Evolution of Firms from Early Business Plans to Public Companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplan, Steven N.; Sensoy, Berk A.; Stromberg, Per
We study how firm characteristics evolve from early business plan to initial public offering (IPO) to public company for 50 venture capital (VC)-financed companies. Firm business lines remain remarkably stable while management turnover is substantial. Management turnover is positively related to alienable asset formation. We obtain similar results using all 2004 IPOs, suggesting that our main results are not specific to VC-backed firms or the time period. The results suggest that, at the margin, investors in start-ups should place more weight on the business ("the horse") than on the management team ("the jockey"). The results also inform theories of the firm.</description><author>Kaplan, Steven N.; Sensoy, Berk A.; Stromberg, Per</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It's SHO Time! Short-Sale Price Tests and Market Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diether, Karl B.; Lee, Kuan-Hui; Werner, Ingrid M.
We examine the effects of the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)-mandated temporary suspension of short-sale price tests for a set of Pilot securities. While short-selling activity increases both for NYSE- and Nasdaq-listed Pilot stocks, returns and volatility at the daily level are unaffected. NYSE-listed Pilot stocks experience more symmetric trading patterns and a slight increase in spreads and intraday volatility after the suspension while there is a smaller effect on market quality for Nasdaq-listed Pilot stocks. The results suggest that the effect of the price tests on market quality can largely be attributed to distortions in order flow created by the price tests themselves.</description><author>Diether, Karl B.; Lee, Kuan-Hui; Werner, Ingrid M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-Water Marks: High Risk Appetites ? Convex Compensation, Long Horizons, and Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Panageas, Stavros; Westerfield, Mark M.
We study the portfolio choice of hedge fund managers who are compensated by high-water mark contracts. We find that even risk-neutral managers do not place unbounded weights on risky assets, despite option-like contracts. Instead, they place a constant fraction of funds in a mean-variance efficient portfolio and the rest in the riskless asset, acting as would constant relative risk aversion (CRRA) investors. This result is a direct consequence of the in(de)finite horizon of the contract. We show that the risk-seeking incentives of option-like contracts rely on combining finite horizons and convex compensation schemes rather than on convexity alone.</description><author>Panageas, Stavros; Westerfield, Mark M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>John, Kose; Litov, Lubomir; Yeung, Bernard
Better investor protection could lead corporations to undertake riskier but value-enhancing investments. For example, better investor protection mitigates the taking of private benefits leading to excess risk-avoidance. Further, in better investor protection environments, stakeholders like creditors, labor groups, and the government are less effective in reducing corporate risk-taking for their self-interest. However, arguments can also be made for a negative relationship between investor protection and risk-taking. Using a cross-country panel and a U.S.-only sample, we find that corporate risk-taking and firm growth rates are positively related to the quality of investor protection.</description><author>John, Kose; Litov, Lubomir; Yeung, Bernard</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dissecting anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
The anomalous returns associated with net stock issues, accruals, and momentum are pervasive; they show up in all size groups (micro, small, and big) in cross-section regressions, and they are also strong in sorts, at least in the extremes. The asset growth and profitability anomalies are less robust. There is an asset growth anomaly in average returns on microcaps and small stocks, but it is absent for big stocks. Among profitable firms, higher profitability tends to be associated with abnormally high returns, but there is little evidence that unprofitable firms have unusually low returns.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset growth and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Michael J.; Gulen, Huseyin; Schill, Michael J.
We test for firm-level asset investment effects in returns by examining the cross-sectional relation between firm asset growth and subsequent stock returns. Asset growth rates are strong predictors of future abnormal returns. Asset growth retains its forecasting ability even on large capitalization stocks. When we compare asset growth rates with the previously documented determinants of the cross-section of returns (i.e., book-to-market ratios, firm capitalization, lagged returns, accruals, and other growth measures), we find that a firm's annual asset growth rate emerges as an economically and statistically significant predictor of the cross-section of U.S. stock returns.</description><author>Cooper, Michael J.; Gulen, Huseyin; Schill, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Back to the beginning: Persistence and the cross-section of corporate capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lemmon, Michael L.; Roberts, Michael R.; Zender, Jaime F.
We find that the majority of variation in leverage ratios is driven by an unobserved time-invariant effect that generates surprisingly stable capital structures: High (low) levered firms tend to remain as such for over two decades. This feature of leverage is largely unexplained by previously identified determinants, is robust to firm exit, and is present prior to the IPO, suggesting that variation in capital structures is primarily determined by factors that remain stable for long periods of time. We then show that these results have important implications for empirical analysis attempting to understand capital structure heterogeneity.</description><author>Lemmon, Michael L.; Roberts, Michael R.; Zender, Jaime F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential address: The cost of active investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>French, Kenneth R.
I compare the fees, expenses, and trading costs society pays to invest in the U.S. stock market with an estimate of what would be paid if everyone invested passively. Averaging over 1980-2006, I find investors spend 0.67% of the aggregate value of the market each year searching for superior returns. Society's capitalized cost of price discovery is at least 10% of the current market cap. Under reasonable assumptions, the typical investor would increase his average annual return by 67 basis points over the 1980-2006 period if he switched to a passive market portfolio.</description><author>French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge fund activism, corporate governance, and firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, Alon; Jiang, Wei; Partnoy, Frank; Thomas, Randall
Using a large hand-collected data set from 2001 to 2006, we find that activist hedge funds in the United States propose strategic, operational, and financial remedies and attain success or partial success in two-thirds of the cases. Hedge funds seldom seek control and in most cases are nonconfrontational. The abnormal return around the announcement of activism is approximately 7%, with no reversal during the subsequent year. Target firms experience increases in payout, operating performance, and higher CEO turnover after activism. Our analysis provides important new evidence on the mechanisms and effects of informed shareholder monitoring.</description><author>Brav, Alon; Jiang, Wei; Partnoy, Frank; Thomas, Randall</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge funds: Performance, risk, and capital formation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fung, William; Hsieh, David A.; Naik, Narayan Y.; Ramadorai, Tarun
We use a comprehensive data set of funds-of-funds to investigate performance, risk, and capital formation in the hedge fund industry from 1995 to 2004. While the average fund-of-funds delivers alpha only in the period between October 1998 and March 2000, a subset of funds-of-funds consistently delivers alpha. The alpha-producing funds are not as likely to liquidate as those that do not deliver alpha, and experience far greater and steadier capital inflows than their less fortunate counterparts. These capital inflows attenuate the ability of the alpha producers to continue to deliver alpha in the future.</description><author>Fung, William; Hsieh, David A.; Naik, Narayan Y.; Ramadorai, Tarun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The selection and termination of investment management firms by plan sponsors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyal, Amit; Wahal, Sunil
We examine the selection and termination of investment management firms by 3,400 plan sponsors between 1994 and 2003. Plan sponsors hire investment managers after large positive excess returns but this return-chasing behavior does not deliver positive excess returns thereafter. Investment managers are terminated for a variety of reasons, including but not limited to underperformance. Excess returns after terminations are typically indistinguishable from zero but in some cases positive. In a sample of round-trip firing and hiring decisions, we find that if plan sponsors had stayed with fired investment managers, their excess returns would be no different from those delivered by newly hired managers. We uncover significant variation in pre- and post-hiring and firing returns that is related to plan sponsor characteristics.</description><author>Goyal, Amit; Wahal, Sunil</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal decentralized investment management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Brandt, Michael W.; Koijen, Ralph S. J.
We study an institutional investment problem in which a centralized decision maker, the Chief Investment Officer (CIO), for example, employs multiple asset managers to implement investment strategies in separate asset classes. The CIO allocates capital to the managers who, in turn, allocate these funds to the assets in their asset class. This two-step investment process causes several misalignments of objectives between the CIO and his managers and can lead to large utility costs for the CIO. We focus on (1) loss of diversification, (2) unobservable managerial appetite for risk, and (3) different investment horizons. We derive an optimal unconditional linear performance benchmark and show that this benchmark can be used to better align incentives within the firm. We find that the CIO's uncertainty about the managers' risk appetites increases both the costs of decentralized investment management and the value of an optimally designed benchmark.</description><author>Van Binsbergen, Jules H.; Brandt, Michael W.; Koijen, Ralph S. J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market liquidity, investor participation, and managerial autonomy: Why do firms go private?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boot, Arnoud W. A.; Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Thakor, Anjan V.
We focus on public-market investor participation to analyze the firm's decision to stay public or go private. The liquidity of public ownership is both a blessing and a curse: It lowers the cost of capital, but also introduces volatility in a firm's shareholder base, exposing management to uncertainty regarding shareholder intervention in management decisions, thereby affecting the manager's perceived decision-making autonomy and curtailing managerial inputs. We extract predictions about how investor participation affects stock price level and volatility and the public firm's incentives to go private, providing a link between investor participation and firm participation in public markets.</description><author>Boot, Arnoud W. A.; Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic links and predictable returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren; Frazzini, Andrea
This paper finds evidence of return predictability across economically linked firms. We test the hypothesis that in the presence of investors subject to attention constraints, stock prices do not promptly incorporate news about economically related firms, generating return predictability across assets. Using a data set of firms' principal customers to identify a set of economically related firms, we show that stock prices do not incorporate news involving related firms, generating predictable subsequent price moves. A long-short equity strategy based on this effect yields monthly alphas of over 150 basis points.</description><author>Cohen, Lauren; Frazzini, Andrea</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Feedback effects and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozdenoren, Emre; Yuan, Kathy
Feedback effects from asset prices to firm cash flows have been empirically documented. This finding raises a question for asset pricing: How are asset prices determined if price affects fundamental value, which in turn affects price ? In this environment, by buying assets that others are buying, investors ensure high future cash flows for the firm and subsequent high returns for themselves. Hence, investors have an incentive to coordinate, which may generate self-fulfilling beliefs and multiple equilibria. Using insights from global games, we pin down investors' beliefs, analyze equilibrium prices, and show that strong feedback leads to higher excess volatility.</description><author>Ozdenoren, Emre; Yuan, Kathy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International cross-listing, firm performance, and top management turnover: A test of the bonding hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lel, Ugur; Miller, Darius P.
We examine a primary outcome of corporate governance, namely, the ability to identify and terminate poorly performing CEOs, to test the effectiveness of U.S. investor protections in improving the corporate governance of cross-listed firms. We find that firms from weak investor protection regimes that are cross-listed on a major U.S. Exchange are more likely to terminate poorly performing CEOs than non-cross-listed firms. Cross-listings on exchanges that do not require the adoption of stringent investor protections (OTC, private placements, and London listings) are not associated with a higher propensity to remove poorly performing CEOs.</description><author>Lel, Ugur; Miller, Darius P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How and When Do Firms Adjust Their Capital Structures toward Targets ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Byoun, Soku
If firms adjust their capital structures toward targets, and if there are adverse selection costs associated with asymmetric information, how and when do firms adjust their capital structures ? We suggest a financing needs-induced adjustment framework to examine the dynamic process by which firms adjust their capital structures. We find that most adjustments occur when firms have above-target (below-target) debt with a financial surplus (deficit). These results suggest that firms move toward the target capital structure when they face a financial deficit/surplus-but not in the manner hypothesized by the traditional pecking order theory.</description><author>Byoun, Soku</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited Attention and the Allocation of Effort in Securities Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corwin, Shane A.; Coughenour, Jay F.
While limited attention has been analyzed in a variety of economic and psychological settings, its impact on financial markets is not well understood. In this paper, we examine individual NYSE specialist portfolios and test whether liquidity provision is affected as specialists allocate their attention across stocks. Our results indicate that specialists allocate effort toward their most active stocks during periods of increased activity, resulting in less frequent price improvement and increased transaction costs for their remaining assigned stocks. Thus, the allocation of effort due to limited attention has a significant impact on liquidity provision in securities markets.</description><author>Corwin, Shane A.; Coughenour, Jay F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Returns and Volatility: Pricing the Short-Run and Long-Run Components of Market Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adrian, Tobias; Rosenberg, Joshua
We explore the cross-sectional pricing of volatility risk by decomposing equity market volatility into short- and long-run components. Our finding that prices of risk are negative and significant for both volatility components implies that investors pay for insurance against increases in volatility, even if those increases have little persistence. The short-run component captures market skewness risk, which we interpret as a measure of the tightness of financial constraints. The long-run component relates to business cycle risk. Furthermore, a three-factor pricing model with the market return and the two volatility components compares favorably to benchmark models.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Rosenberg, Joshua</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Average Returns, B/M, and Share Issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
The book-to-market ratio (B/M) is a noisy measure of expected stock returns because it also varies with expected cashflows. Our hypothesis is that the evolution of B/M, in terms of past changes in book equity and price, contains independent information about expected cashflows that can be used to improve estimates of expected returns. The tests support this hypothesis, with results that are largely but not entirely similar for Microcap stocks (below the 20(th) NYSE market capitalization percentile) and All but Micro stocks (ABM).</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Size Affect Mutual Fund Behavior ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pollet, Joshua M.; Wilson, Mungo
If actively managed mutual funds suffer from diminishing returns to scale, funds should alter investment behavior as assets under management increase. Although asset growth has little effect on the behavior of the typical fund, we find that large funds and small-cap funds diversify their portfolios in response to growth. Greater diversification, especially for small-cap funds, is associated with better performance. Fund family growth is related to the introduction of new funds that hold different stocks from their existing siblings. Funds with many siblings diversify less rapidly as they grow, suggesting that the fund family may influence a fund's portfolio strategy.</description><author>Pollet, Joshua M.; Wilson, Mungo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In Search of Distress Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John Y.; Hilscher, Jens; Szilagyi, Jan
This paper explores the determinants of corporate failure and the pricing of financially distressed stocks whose failure probability, estimated from a dynamic logit model using accounting and market variables, is high. Since 1981, financially distressed stocks have delivered anomalously low returns. They have lower returns but much higher standard deviations, market betas, and loadings on value and small-cap risk factors than stocks with low failure risk. These patterns are more pronounced for stocks with possible informational or arbitrage-related frictions. They are inconsistent with the conjecture that the value and size effects are compensation for the risk of financial distress.</description><author>Campbell, John Y.; Hilscher, Jens; Szilagyi, Jan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the Intertemporal Risk-Return Tradeoff Using the Implied Cost of Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, Lubos; Sinha, Meenakshi; Swaminathan, Bhaskaran
We argue that the implied cost of capital (ICC), computed using earnings forecasts, is useful in capturing time variation in expected stock returns. First, we show theoretically that ICC is perfectly correlated with the conditional expected stock return under plausible conditions. Second, our simulations show that ICC is helpful in detecting an intertemporal risk-return relation, even when earnings forecasts are poor. Finally, in empirical analysis, we construct the time series of ICC for the G-7 countries. We find a positive relation between the conditional mean and variance of stock returns, at both the country level and the world market level.</description><author>Pastor, Lubos; Sinha, Meenakshi; Swaminathan, Bhaskaran</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Geography of Block Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Jun-Koo; Kim, Jin-Mo
Using a large sample of partial block acquisitions, we examine the importance of geographic proximity in corporate governance and target returns. We find that block acquirers have a strong preference for geographically proximate targets and acquirers that purchase shares in such targets are more likely to engage in post-acquisition target governance activities than are remote block acquirers. Moreover, the targets of these acquirers realize higher announcement returns and better post-acquisition operating performance than do targets of other types of acquirers, particularly when they face greater information asymmetries.</description><author>Kang, Jun-Koo; Kim, Jin-Mo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mandatory disclosure and operational risk: Evidence from hedge fund registration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Stephen; Goetzmann, William; Liang, Bing; Schwarz, Christopher
Mandatory disclosure is a regulatory tool intended to allow market participants to assess operational risk. We examine the value of disclosure through the controversial SEC requirement, since overturned, which required major hedge funds to register as investment advisors and file Form ADV disclosures. Leverage and ownership structures suggest that lenders and equity investors were already aware of operational risk. However, operational risk does not mediate flow-performance relationships. Investors either lack this information or regard it as immaterial. These findings suggest that regulators should account for the endogenous production of information and the marginal benefit of disclosure to different investment clienteles.</description><author>Brown, Stephen; Goetzmann, William; Liang, Bing; Schwarz, Christopher</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overconfidence, CEO Selection, and Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goel, Anand M.; Thakor, Anjan V.
We develop a model that shows that an overconfident manager, who sometimes makes value-destroying investments, has a higher likelihood than a rational manager of being deliberately promoted to CEO under value-maximizing corporate governance. Moreover, a risk-averse CEO's overconfidence enhances firm value up to a point, but the effect is nonmonotonic and differs from that of lower risk aversion. Overconfident CEOs also underinvest in information production. The board fires both excessively diffident and excessively overconfident CEOs. Finally, Sarbanes-Oxley is predicted to improve the precision of information provided to investors, but to reduce project investment.</description><author>Goel, Anand M.; Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Structure, Internal Capital Markets, and the Boundaries of the Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mathews, Richmond D.; Robinson, David T.
We study how the creation of an internal capital market (ICM) can invite strategic responses in product markets that, in turn, shape firm boundaries. ICMs provide ex post resource flexibility, but come with ex ante commitment costs. Alternatively, stand-alones possess commitment ability but lack flexibility. By creating flexibility, integration can sometimes deter a rival's entry, but commitment problems can also invite predatory capital raising. These forces drive different organizational equilibria depending on the integrator's relation to the product market. Hybrid organizational forms like strategic alliances can sometimes dominate integration by offering some of its benefits with fewer strategic costs.</description><author>Mathews, Richmond D.; Robinson, David T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Investors Overweight Personal Experience ? Evidence from IPO Subscriptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaustia, Markku; Knuepfer, Samuli
We find a strong positive link between past IPO returns and future subscriptions at the investor level in Finland. Our setting allows us to trace this effect to the returns personally experienced by investors; the effect is not explained by patterns related to the IPO cycle, or wealth effects. This behavior is consistent with reinforcement learning, where personally experienced outcomes are overweighted compared to rational Bayesian learning. The results provide a microfoundation for the argument that investor sentiment drives IPO demand. The paper also contributes to understanding how popular investment styles develop, and has implications for the marketing of financial products.</description><author>Kaustia, Markku; Knuepfer, Samuli</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Directors' ownership in the US mutual fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Qi; Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei
This paper empirically investigates directors' ownership in the mutual fund industry. Our results show that, contrary to anecdotal evidence, a significant portion of directors hold shares in the funds they oversee. Ownership patterns are broadly consistent with an optimal contracting equilibrium. That is, ownership is positively and significantly correlated with most variables that are predicted to indicate greater value from directors' monitoring. For example, directors' ownership is more prevalent in actively managed funds and in funds with lower institutional ownership. We also show considerable heterogeneity in ownership across fund families, suggesting family-wide policies play an important role.</description><author>Chen, Qi; Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Making of an Investment Banker: Stock Market Shocks, Career Choice, and Lifetime Income</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oyer, Paul
I show that stock market shocks have important and lasting effects on the careers of MBAs. Stock market conditions while MBA students are in school have a large effect on whether they go directly to Wall Street upon graduation. Further, starting on Wall Street immediately upon graduation causes a person to be more likely to work there later and to earn, on average, substantially more money. The empirical results suggest that investment bankers are largely "made" by circumstance rather than "born" to work on Wall Street.</description><author>Oyer, Paul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trusting the stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guiso, Luigi; Sapienza, Paola; Zingales, Luigi
We study the effect that a general lack of trust can have on stock market participation. In deciding whether to buy stocks, investors factor in the risk of being cheated. The perception of this risk is a function of the objective characteristics of the stocks and the subjective characteristics of the investor. Less trusting individuals are less likely to buy stock and, conditional on buying stock, they will buy less. In Dutch and Italian micro data, as well as in cross-country data, we find evidence consistent with lack of trust being an important factor in explaining the limited participation puzzle.</description><author>Guiso, Luigi; Sapienza, Paola; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"You Can Enter but You Cannot Leave...": US Securities markets and foreign firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marosi, Andras; Massoud, Nadia
Although a number of prior papers have argued the benefits to foreign firms of cross-listing their shares in the U.S., the number of foreign firms exiting U.S. capital markets has been increasing. This has occurred despite the difficulties foreign firms face in deregistering from the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). This paper examines the reasons underlying this trend. One of our main findings is that the passage of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act has reduced the net benefits of a U.S. listing and registration, particularly for smaller foreign firms with lower trading volume and stronger insider control.</description><author>Marosi, Andras; Massoud, Nadia</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-asset speculation in stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernhardt, Dan; Taub, Bart
In practice, heterogeneously informed speculators combine private information about multiple stocks with information in prices, taking into account how their trades influence the inferences of other speculators via prices. We show how this speculation causes prices to be more correlated than asset fundamentals, raising price volatility. The covariance structure of asset fundamentals drives that of prices, while the covariance structure of liquidity trade drives that of order flows. We characterize how speculator profits vary with the distributions of information and liquidity trade across assets and speculators, and relate the cross-asset factor structure of order flows to that of returns.</description><author>Bernhardt, Dan; Taub, Bart</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default and recovery implicit in the term structure of sovereign CDS spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Jun; Singleton, Kenneth J.
This paper explores the nature of default arrival and recovery implicit in the term structures of sovereign CDS spreads. We argue that term structures of spreads reveal not only the arrival rates of credit events (lambda(Q)), but also the loss rates given credit events. Applying our framework to Mexico, Turkey, and Korea, we show that a single-factor model with lambda(Q) following a lognormal process captures most of the variation in the term structures of spreads. The risk premiums associated with unpredictable variation in lambda(Q) are found to be economically significant and co-vary importantly with several economic measures of global event risk, financial market volatility, and macroeconomic policy.</description><author>Pan, Jun; Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Marketwide private information in stocks: Forecasting currency returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; De Francisco, Eva; Marques, Luis B.
We present a model of equity trading with informed and uninformed investors where informed investors trade on firm-specific and marketwide private information. The model is used to identify the component of order flow due to marketwide private information. Estimated trades driven by marketwide private information display little or no correlation with the first principal component in order flow. Indeed, we find that co-movement in order flow captures variation mostly in liquidity trades. Marketwide private information obtained from equity market data forecasts industry stock returns, and also currency returns.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; De Francisco, Eva; Marques, Luis B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of financial flexibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gamba, Andrea; Triantis, Alexander
We develop a model that endogenizes dynamic financing, investment, and cash retention/payout policies in order to analyze the effect of financial flexibility on firm value. We show that the value of financing flexibility depends on the costs of external financing, the level of corporate and personal tax rates that determine the effective cost of holding cash, the firm's growth potential and maturity, and the reversibility of capital. Through simulations, we demonstrate that firms facing financing frictions should simultaneously borrow and lend, and we examine the nature of dynamic debt and liquidity policies and the value associated with corporate liquidity.</description><author>Gamba, Andrea; Triantis, Alexander</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The real determinants of asset sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Liu
I develop a dynamic structural model in which a firm makes rational decisions to buy or sell assets in the presence of productivity shocks. By identifying equilibrium asset prices, the model also examines the aggregate asset sales activity over the business cycle. It shows that changes in productivity, rather than productivity levels, affect decisions: Firms with rising productivity buy assets and firms with falling productivity downsize ("rising buys falling"). As such, industries in which firms have less persistent and more volatile productivity experience greater asset reallocation. Using plant-level data from Longitudinal Research Database (LRD), I find strong support for the model's predictions.</description><author>Yang, Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collective risk management in a flight to quality episode</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caballero, Ricardo J.; Krishnamurthy, Arvind
Severe flight to quality episodes involve uncertainty about the environment, not only risk about asset payoffs. The uncertainty is triggered by unusual events and untested financial innovations that lead agents to question their worldview. We present a model of crises and central bank policy that incorporates Knightian uncertainty. The model explains crisis regularities such as market-wide capital immobility, agents' disengagement from risk, and liquidity hoarding. We identify a social cost of these behaviors, and a benefit of a lender of last resort facility. The benefit is particularly high because public and private insurance are complements during uncertainty-driven crises.</description><author>Caballero, Ricardo J.; Krishnamurthy, Arvind</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Bank Financial Constraints and Firm Access to External Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paravisini, Daniel
I exploit the exogenous component of a formula-based allocation of government funds across banks in Argentina to test for financial constraints and underinvestment by local banks. Banks are found to expand lending by $0.66 in response to an additional dollar of external financing. Using novel data to measure risk and return on marginal lending, I show that the profitability of lending does not decline and total borrower debt increases during lending expansions, holding investment opportunities constant. Overall, financial shocks to constrained banks are found to have a quick, persistent, and amplified effect on the aggregate supply of credit.</description><author>Paravisini, Daniel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign banks in poor countries: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Detragiache, Enrica; Tressel, Thierry; Gupta, Poonam
We study how foreign bank penetration affects financial sector development in poor countries. A theoretical model shows that when domestic banks are better than foreign banks at monitoring soft information customers, foreign bank entry may hurt these customers and worsen welfare. The model also predicts that credit to the private sector should be lower in countries with more foreign bank penetration, and that foreign banks should have a less risky loan portfolio. In the empirical section, we test these predictions for a sample of lower income countries and find support for the theoretical model.</description><author>Detragiache, Enrica; Tressel, Thierry; Gupta, Poonam</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does financing impact investment? The role of debt covenants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Roberts, Michael R.
We identify a specific channel (debt covenants) and the corresponding mechanism (transfer of control rights) through which financing frictions impact corporate investment. Using a regression discontinuity design, we show that capital investment declines sharply following a financial covenant violation, when creditors use the threat of accelerating the loan to intervene in management. Further, the reduction in investment is concentrated in situations in which agency and information problems are relatively more severe, highlighting how the state-contingent allocation of control rights can help mitigate investment distortions arising from financing frictions.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Roberts, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dog that did not bark: Insider trading and crashes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marin, Jose M.; Olivier, Jacques P.
This paper documents that at the individual stock level, insiders' sales peak many months before a large drop in the stock price, while insiders' purchases peak only the month before a large jump. We provide a theoretical explanation for this phenomenon based on trading constraints and asymmetric information. A key feature of our theory is that rational uninformed investors may react more strongly to the absence of insider sales than to their presence (the "dog that did not bark" effect). We test our hypothesis against competing stories, such as insiders timing their trades to evade prosecution.</description><author>Marin, Jose M.; Olivier, Jacques P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buyer-supplier relationships and the stakeholder theory of capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Shantanu; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Kim, Yungsan
Firms in bilateral relationships are likely to produce or procure unique products-especially when they are in durable goods industries. Consistent with the arguments of Titman and Titman and Wessels, such firms are likely to maintain lower leverage. We compile a database of firms' principal customers (those that account for at least 10% of sales or are otherwise considered important for business) from the Business Information File of Compustat and find results consistent with the predictions of this theory.</description><author>Banerjee, Shantanu; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Kim, Yungsan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>