<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Banking &amp; Finance7</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Causes and consequences of short-term institutional herding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kremer, Stephanie; Nautz, Dieter
This paper provides new evidence on the causes and consequences of herding by institutional investors. Using a comprehensive database of every transaction made by financial institutions in the German stock market, we show that institutions exhibit herding behavior on a daily basis. Herding intensity depends on stock characteristics including past returns and volatility. Return reversals indicate a destabilizing impact of herds on stock prices in the short term. Results from panel regressions suggest that herding is mainly unintentional and partly driven by the use of similar risk models. Our findings confirm the importance of macro-prudential aspects for banking regulation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kremer, Stephanie; Nautz, Dieter</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging structured credit products during the credit crisis: A horse race of 10 models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ascheberg, Marius; Bick, Bjoern; Kraft, Holger
Pricing and hedging structured credit products poses major challenges to financial institutions. This paper puts several valuation approaches through a crucial test: How did these models perform in one of the worst periods of economic history, September 2008, when Lehman Brothers went under? Did they produce reasonable hedging strategies? We study several bottom-up and top-down credit portfolio models and compute the resulting delta hedging strategies using either index contracts or a portfolio of single-name CDS contracts as hedging instruments. We compute the profit-and-loss profiles and assess the performances of these hedging strategies. Among all 10 pricing models that we consider the Student-t copula model performs best. The dynamical generalized-Poisson loss model is the best top-down model, but this model class has in general problems to hedge equity tranches. Our major finding is however that single-name and index CDS contracts are not appropriate instruments to hedge CDO tranches. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ascheberg, Marius; Bick, Bjoern; Kraft, Holger</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>House prices, bank instability, and economic growth: Evidence from the threshold model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Huiran; Wang, Chun
This paper examines the effects of house prices on bank instability when gauged at various levels of income growth. Bank stability may respond differently to house price changes or deviations from fundamental values in an economic boom environment than in a bust circumstance. A threshold estimation technique developed by Hansen (1999) is applied to a panel of 286 U.S. Metropolitan Statistical Areas (MSAs) over the period 1990Q1-2010Q4. We consider two house price indicators: the house price changes and the house price deviations from long-run equilibrium. The results suggest the existence of income growth threshold effects in the relationship between house prices and bank instability. Specifically, there are two income growth thresholds when using the house price changes and one income growth threshold when the house price deviations are applied. Robustness results using the non-MSAs sample from 1995Q1 to 2010Q4 provide further evidence of income growth threshold effects. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pan, Huiran; Wang, Chun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oil price dynamics, macro-finance interactions and the role of financial speculation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morana, Claudio
What is the role of financial speculation in determining the real oil price? We find that while macroeconomic shocks have been the main real oil price upward driver since mid-1980s, financial shocks have sizably contributed since early 2000s as well, and at a much larger extent since mid-2000s. Even though financial shocks contribute 44% out of the 65% real oil price increase over the period 2004-2010, the third oil price shock is a macro-finance episode: macroeconomic shocks actually largely account for the 2007-2008 oil price swing. While we then find support to the demand side view of real oil price determination, we however also find a much larger role for financial shocks than previously noted in the literature. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Morana, Claudio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multi-stage product development with exploration, value-enhancing, preemptive and innovation options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koussis, Nicos; Martzoukos, Spiros H.; Trigeorgis, Lenos
We provide a real options framework for the analysis of product development that incorporates research and exploration actions, product attribute value-enhancing actions with uncertain outcome, as well as preemption and innovation options. We derive two-stage analytic formulas and propose a general multi-period solution using a numerical lattice approach. Our analysis reveals that exploration actions are more important when the project is out or at-the-money (near zero NPV) and less important for high project values. In a multi-stage setting, exploration actions are important even for in-the-money projects, when follow-on actions exist that can enhance the expected value of the project. With path-dependency, early actions are more valuable since they enhance the impact or reduce the cost of subsequent actions. Preemptive controls affecting rare event (jump) frequency and innovations that introduce positive jumps are more valuable for firms with higher frequency of competitive threats involving low volatility. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koussis, Nicos; Martzoukos, Spiros H.; Trigeorgis, Lenos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting metal prices: Do forecasters herd?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pierdzioch, Christian; Ruelke, Jan-Christoph; Stadtmann, Georg
We analyze more than 20,000 forecasts of nine metal prices at four different forecast horizons. We document that forecasts are heterogeneous and report that anti-herding appears to be a source of this heterogeneity. Forecaster anti-herding reflects strategic interactions among forecasters that foster incentives to scatter forecasts around a consensus forecast. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pierdzioch, Christian; Ruelke, Jan-Christoph; Stadtmann, Georg</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic hedge fund portfolio construction: A semi-parametric approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, Richard D. F.; Mazibas, Murat
In this article, we evaluate alternative optimization frameworks for constructing portfolios of hedge funds. We compare the standard mean-variance optimization model with models based on CVaR, CDaR and Omega, for both conservative and aggressive hedge fund investment strategies. In order to implement the CVaR, CDaR and Omega optimization models, we propose a semi-parametric methodology, which is based on extreme value theory, copula and Monte Carlo simulation. We compare the semi-parametric approach with the standard, non-parametric approach, used to compute CVaR, CDaR and Omega, and the benchmark parametric approach, based on both static and dynamic mean-variance optimization. We report two main findings. The first is that the CVaR, CDaR and Omega models offer a significant improvement in terms of risk-adjusted portfolio performance over the parametric mean-variance model. The second is that semi-parametric estimation of the CVaR, CDaR and Omega models offers a very substantial improvement over non-parametric estimation. Our results are robust to the choice of target return, risk limit and estimation sample size. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harris, Richard D. F.; Mazibas, Murat</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting asset pricing under habit formation in an overlapping-generations economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Sei-Wan; Krausz, Joshua; Nam, Kiseok
By incorporating habit formation into an overlapping-generations economy, we show that the middle-aged consumers' savings decision has a substantial impact on the equity premium. The higher incentive for savings for the middle-aged, resulting from the habit formation preference, causes an even higher demand for bonds and a lower demand for equity, which eventually generates a lower risk-free rate and a higher required return for holding equity than does the framework of non-habit forming models. Calibration results verify that the habit formation setting, together with an OLG framework is capable of yielding lower bond returns and higher equity returns than the standard CRRA utility models, and the borrowing constraint imposed on the young-aged consumers amplifies the positive effect of habit formation on the equity premium. The findings imply that habit formation preferences within the overlapping-generations framework under the borrowing-constrained economy can provide a more improved explanation of the equity premium puzzle. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Sei-Wan; Krausz, Joshua; Nam, Kiseok</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Scale economies and input price elasticities in microfinance institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartarska, Valentina; Shen, Xuan; Mersland, Roy
We evaluate the efficiency of microfinance institutions (MFIs) using a structural approach which also captures these institutions' outreach and sustainability objectives. We estimate economies of scale and input price elasticities for lending-only and deposit-mobilizing MFIs using a large sample of high-quality panel data. The results confirm conjectures that improvements in efficiency can come from the growth or consolidations of MFIs, as we find substantial increasing returns to scale for all but profitability-focused deposit-mobilizing MFIs. Our results support the existence of a trade-off between outreach and sustainability. All inputs are inelastic substitutes, but we find differences in own-price elasticities in lending-only and deposit-mobilizing MFIs. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hartarska, Valentina; Shen, Xuan; Mersland, Roy</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A perspective on the symptoms and causes of the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cabral, Ricardo
Prior to the 2007-2008 financial crisis, banking sector profits were very high but the profitability of financial intermediation was poor. Using a novel model of banking, this article argues that the high profits were achieved through balance sheet expansion and growing default, liquidity, and term risk mismatches between assets and liabilities. As a result, large banks' financial leverage rose as they became less liquid, setting the conditions for a systemic banking crisis. This article argues that the increase in financial leverage was possible due to misguided changes in the regulatory framework, specifically, the Basel I capital accord and reductions in reserve requirements. Finally, this article overviews and assesses the policy response in the aftermath of the crisis. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cabral, Ricardo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The evolution of cost-productivity and efficiency among US credit unions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wheelock, David C.; Wilson, Paul W.
Advances in information-processing technology have eroded the advantages of small scale and proximity to customers that traditionally enabled small lenders to thrive. Nonetheless, the membership and market share of US credit unions have increased, though their average size has also risen. We investigate changes in the efficiency and productivity of US credit unions during 1989-2006 by benchmarking the performance of individual firms against an estimated order-alpha quantile lying "near" the efficient frontier. We construct a cost analog of the Malmquist productivity index, which we decompose to estimate changes in cost and scale efficiency, and changes in technology. We find that cost-productivity fell on average across all credit unions but especially among smaller credit unions. Smaller credit unions confronted a shift in technology that increased the minimum cost required to produce given amounts of output. All but the largest credit unions also became less scale efficient over time. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wheelock, David C.; Wilson, Paul W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Static hedging and pricing American knock-in put options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, San-Lin; Shih, Pai-Ta; Tsai, Wei-Che
This paper extends the static hedging portfolio (SHP) approach of Derman et al. (1995) and Carr et al. (1998) to price and hedge American knock-in put options under the Black-Scholes model and the constant elasticity of variance (CEV) model. We use standard European calls (puts) to construct the SHPs for American up-and-in (down-and-in) puts. We also use theta-matching condition to improve the performance of the SHP approach. Numerical results indicate that the hedging effectiveness of a hi-monthly SHP is far less risky than that of a delta-hedging portfolio with daily rebalance. The numerical accuracy of the proposed method is comparable to the trinomial tree methods of Ritchken (1995) and Boyle and Tian (1999). Furthermore, the recalculation time (the term is explained in Section 1) of the option prices is much easier and quicker than the tree method when the stock price and/or time to maturity are changed. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, San-Lin; Shih, Pai-Ta; Tsai, Wei-Che</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset financing with credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golbeck, Steven; Linetsky, Vadim
This paper develops a model for the unified valuation of all forms of real asset financing, such as bank loans, leases, securitization vehicles, and credit guarantees, secured by assets that generate a stochastic service flow to the operator, or a rental stream to the lessor, and depreciate over a finite economic life to their scrap value. Examples include mobile equipment, such as aircraft, railroad equipment, ships, trucks and trailers, as well as energy generation assets, heavy factory equipment and construction equipment. In the event of obligor default, after a repossession delay and incurring costs of repossession, maintenance, re-marketing and re-deployment, the lender repossesses the asset and sells it on the secondary market and is, thus, subject to the risk of decline in the market value of the asset. The model we develop in this paper treats all forms of asset financing in a unified fashion as contingent claims on the collateral asset and the credit of the borrower. As an application, we estimate the collateral asset model on historical secondary market data for aircraft values and calibrate the financing model to the Enhanced Equipment Trust Certificates (EETCs) issued in 2007 by Continental Airlines and secured by a fleet of new aircraft. We then apply the calibrated model to value private market financing, including bank loans, leases, and credit guarantees, consistently with the capital market financing, and assess the impact of repossession delays on credit spreads. This analysis leads to a policy insight suggesting that bankruptcy laws limiting asset repossession delays lead to lower costs of asset financing. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Golbeck, Steven; Linetsky, Vadim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buyback behavior of initial public offering firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Ho, Kim Wai; Huang, Chia-Wei; Wang, Yanzhi
We examine the motives behind the share repurchase decisions of initial public offering (IPO) firms by studying the stock and operating performance after the IPO date. We find that IPO firms that announce repurchases within 3 years of WO dates exhibit poorer long-run abnormal operating performance than other IPO firms. These IPO firms also experience poorer stock return performance and downward analyst forecast revisions. Moreover, these firms show intensive insider selling transactions after the IPO date. These results for IPO announcing repurchase firms are consistent with the misleading hypothesis, which suggests that these IPO firms mislead investors by announcing repurchases as false signals. 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Ho, Kim Wai; Huang, Chia-Wei; Wang, Yanzhi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity commonality in commodities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marshall, Ben R.; Nguyen, Nhut H.; Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat
We examine liquidity commonality in commodity futures markets. Using data from 16 agricultural, energy, industrial metal, precious metal, and livestock commodities, we show there is a strong systematic liquidity factor in commodities. Liquidity commonality was present in 1997-2003 when commodity prices were relatively stable and during the recent boom. There is some support for both "supply-side" and "demand-side" explanations for this commonality. We find no evidence of a consistent link between stock and commodity liquidity in general. Energy commodities appear to provide a better hedge against equity market liquidity risk than the other commodity families. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marshall, Ben R.; Nguyen, Nhut H.; Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank dividends, risk, and regulatory regimes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kanas, Angelos
This paper investigates the relation between bank dividends and bank risk over the period 1984-2011, and assesses the existence of risk-taking and risk-shifting in the US commercial banking sector subject to regulatory regime changes. The introduction of PCA in 1992 and TARP in 2008 constitute significant regulatory regime changes, and provide the necessary framework to explore whether regime-dependent risk-shifting or risk-taking is present. We find strong evidence of risk-shifting and risk-taking over the post-PCA regime spanning the period 1992-2008. We interpret this evidence as indication of ineffectiveness of PCA in controlling risk-taking and risk-shifting. The finding of risk-taking just prior to the recent financial crisis suggests that risk-taking may be a factor contributing to this crisis. As risk-taking and risk-shifting are important aspects of bank behavior (Basel Committee on Banking Supervision, 2009), these results are of interest to bank regulators and important to Basel III. (C) 2012 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kanas, Angelos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-term asset tail risks in developed and emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Straetmans, Stefan; Candelon, Bertrand
A power law typically governs the tail decay of financial returns but the constancy of the so-called tail index which dictates the tail decay remains relatively unexplored. We study the finite sample properties of some recently proposed endogenous tests for structural change in the tail index. Given that the finite sample critical values strongly depend on the tail parameters of the return distribution we propose a bootstrap-based version of the structural change test. Our empirical application spans developed and emerging financial asset returns. Somewhat surprisingly, emerging stock market tails are not more inclined to structural change than their developed counterparts. Emerging currency tails, on the contrary, do exhibit structural shifts in contrast to developed currencies. Our results suggest that extreme value theory (EVT) applications in hedging tail risks can assume stationary tail behavior over long time spans provided one considers portfolios that solely consist of stocks or bonds. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Straetmans, Stefan; Candelon, Bertrand</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of sovereign default risk in EMU member countries and its determinants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eichler, Stefan; Maltritz, Dominik
We analyze the determinants of sovereign default risk of EMU member states using government bond yield spreads as risk indicators. We focus on default risk for different time spans indicated by spreads for different maturities. Using a panel framework we analyze whether there are different drivers of default risk for different maturities. We find that lower economic growth and larger openness increase default risk for all maturities. Higher indebtedness only increases short-term risk, whereas net lending, trade balance and interest rate costs only drive long-term default risk. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eichler, Stefan; Maltritz, Dominik</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Brazilian retail banking and the 2008 financial crisis: Were the government-controlled banks that important?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pereira, Claudiney M.; Maia-Filho, Luiz F.
We revisit the interest rate pass-through effect using weekly retail banking data from May 2006 to March 2010. Our choice of data avoids caveats of previous studies concerning excessive data aggregation and the estimation of how fast changes in benchmark interest rates impact those charged on short-term loans in Brazil. Our analysis focuses on four large retail banks - two of them privately owned and run, two of them government-controlled - before and after September 2008. They account for 60% of the total credit supplied by retail banks. Results indicate that government control over two of the largest banks, supposedly an asset for crisis management, may have had higher welfare costs than assumed. We find no evidence of asymmetry in adjustments of retail rates charged by private and government-controlled banks. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pereira, Claudiney M.; Maia-Filho, Luiz F.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A statistical model of speculative bubbles, with applications to the stock markets of the United States, Japan, and China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asako, Kazumi; Liu, Zhentao
It is common knowledge that the more prices deviate from fundamentals, the more likely it is for prices to reverse. Taking this into account, we propose a simple statistical model to identify speculative bubbles in financial markets. Through the estimates of the time varying parameters, including transition probabilities, we can identify when and how newly born bubbles grow and burst over time. The model can be estimated by recursive computations, which require a huge storage capacity for standard computers. For this reason, we introduce an approximation in the computation, maintaining the recursive nature of our estimation technique. We then apply this model to the stock markets of the United States, Japan, and China, estimate its parameters and the probabilities of a bubble crash, and obtain several interesting results: the time series data of the stock price bubble show an inherently non-stationary development and the probability of a bubble crash indeed increases as the stock price becomes too high or too low. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asako, Kazumi; Liu, Zhentao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Availability, recency, and sophistication in the repurchasing behavior of retail investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nofsinger, John R.; Varma, Abhishek
When determining a stock to buy, Strahilevitz et al. (2011) demonstrate that individual investors often repurchase a stock previously traded for a profit as a learning process. When evaluating a decision, people use the most available information that comes to mind. We posit that the most recently sold stocks are the most salient. Our analysis reveals that the presence of another more recently sold stock decreases a household's propensity to repurchase a different stock by 23%. This recency effect dominates the impact of prior profitability on the repurchasing decision. The repurchase activity of investors appears to be suboptimal, partially due to commission costs and under-diversification of portfolios, which is magnified for households repurchasing at higher frequencies. More sophisticated investors demonstrate less of this behavior. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nofsinger, John R.; Varma, Abhishek</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rewards for downside risk in Asian markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alles, Lakshman; Murray, Louis
Distributional properties of emerging market returns may impact on investor ability and willingness to diversify. Investors may also place greater weighting on downside losses, compared to upside gains. Using individual equities in a range of emerging Asian markets, we investigate the potential contribution of downside risk measures to explain asset pricing in these markets. As realized returns are used as a proxy for expected returns, we separately examine conditional returns in upturn and downturn periods, in order to successfully identify risk and return relationships. Results indicate that co-skewness and downside beta are priced by investors. Further testing confirms a separate premium for each measure, confirming that they capture different aspects of downside risk. Robustness tests indicate that, when combined with other risk measures, both retain their explanatory power. Tests also indicate that co-skewness may be the more robust measure. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alles, Lakshman; Murray, Louis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal liquidity risk, financial bullwhip effects, and corporate bond yield spreads: Supply chain perspectives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Tsung-Kang; Liao, Hsien-Hsing; Kuo, Hui-Ju
This study explores internal liquidity risk (ILR) and financial bullwhip effects on corporate bond yield spreads along supply chain counterparties by employing American market data from year 1997 to 2008. This study finds that the ILRs of suppliers and customers positively affect a firm's bond yield spreads and the effects of customers' ILRs are greater. This research also finds a financial bullwhip effect that the ILR effect becomes greater upwardly along the supply chain counterparties. The results are robust when controlling for well-known spread determinant variables. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Tsung-Kang; Liao, Hsien-Hsing; Kuo, Hui-Ju</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The real effect of banking crises: Finance or asset allocation effects? Some international evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandez, Ana I.; Gonzalez, Francisco; Suarez, Nuria
This paper analyzes whether the decline in economic growth that follows a banking crisis occurs because of a reduction in the amount of credit available (finance effect) or a worsening in the allocation of investable resources (asset allocation effect). We use a sample of more than 2500 industrial firms in 18 developed and developing countries that experienced 19 systemic banking crises between 1989 and 2007. The results indicate that banking crises negatively affect firms' intangible investments, which intensifies the economic downturn. The negative growth effect produced by the worsening of the investment allocation is stronger in countries with highly developed financial systems and institutions. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fernandez, Ana I.; Gonzalez, Francisco; Suarez, Nuria</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial literacy and consumer credit portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Disney, Richard; Gathergood, John
We use survey data from a sample of UK households to analyse the relationship between financial literacy and consumer credit portfolios. We show that individuals who borrow on consumer credit exhibit worse financial literacy than those who do not. Borrowers with poor financial literacy hold higher shares of high cost credit (such as home collected credit, mail order catalogue debt and payday loans) than those with higher literacy. We also show that individuals with poor financial literacy are more likely to lack confidence when interpreting credit terms, and to exhibit confusion over financial concepts. They are also less likely to engage in behaviour which might help them to improve their awareness of the credit market. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Disney, Richard; Gathergood, John</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Access to information and international portfolio allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thapa, Chandra; Paudyal, Krishna; Neupane, Suman
We examine whether foreign equity holdings of portfolio investors depend on the level of information accessibility between the investors' home and host countries. Using a comprehensive data set, alternative measures of information accessibility and robust analytical techniques, we show that differences in access to cross-country information significantly influence investors' portfolio allocation decisions. Furthermore, the results suggest that for a given level of access to information, investors prefer to invest more in countries with a higher quality of legal/macro-institutions. Finally, the findings also confirm that the implications of information accessibility are more pronounced when markets are turbulent. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thapa, Chandra; Paudyal, Krishna; Neupane, Suman</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonparametric correlation models for portfolio allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aslanidis, Nektarios; Casas, Isabel
This article proposes time-varying nonparametric and semiparametric estimators of the conditional cross-correlation matrix in the context of portfolio allocation. Simulations results show that the nonparametric and semiparametric models are best in DGPs with substantial variability or structural breaks in correlations. Only when correlations are constant does the parametric DCC model deliver the best outcome. The methodologies are illustrated by evaluating two interesting portfolios. The first portfolio consists of the equity sector SPDRs and the MP 500, while the second one contains major currencies. Results show the nonparametric model generally dominates the others when evaluating in-sample. However, the semiparametric model is best for out-of-sample analysis. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aslanidis, Nektarios; Casas, Isabel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International income risk-sharing and the global financial crisis of 2008-2009</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balli, Faruk; Basher, Syed Abul; Balli, Hatice Ozer
We examine the impact of the global financial crisis on the degree of international income and consumption risk-sharing among industrial economies using returns on cross-border portfolio holdings (e.g., debt, equity, FDI). We split the returns from the net foreign holdings as receipts (inflows) and payments (outflows) to investigate which of the two sides exhibited the greater resilience for income risk-sharing during the recent crisis. First, we find that debt delivered better risk-sharing than equity, mainly reflecting the deficit deterioration in EMU countries during the post-crisis period. FDI, by contrast, did not correspond to noticeable risk diversification. Second, separating output shocks into positive and negative components reveals that debt holding receipts (equity liability payments) performed better under negative (positive) realizations of the shock variable. Third, the unwinding of capital flows resulted in a sharp fall in income dis-smoothing via the debt liability channel in the new EU countries. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balli, Faruk; Basher, Syed Abul; Balli, Hatice Ozer</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-term persistence in hybrid mutual fund performance: The role of style-shifting abilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herrmann, Ulf; Scholz, Hendrik
Our study analyzes the performance of hybrid mutual funds. Based on two extended Carhart models we determine total fund performance by comparing fund returns to investable fund-specific style benchmarks. Using daily returns and a quarterly measurement interval, we present an innovative return-based approach to decompose total performance into in-quarter abnormal performance and style-shifting performance. In addition, we split total style-shifting performance into active and passive components. In this context, we confirm possible benefits of these performance measures by analyzing several simulated investment strategies. Our empirical study covers 520 hybrid mutual funds from 10/1998 to 12/2009 and shows that hybrid mutual funds (i) do not outperform their benchmarks on average, (ii) partially show positive in-quarter abnormal performance and style-shifting abilities, and (iii) exhibit short-term persistence in in-quarter abnormal performance but not in style-shifting abilities. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Herrmann, Ulf; Scholz, Hendrik</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alternative bankruptcy prediction models using option-pricing theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charitou, Andreas; Dionysiou, Dionysia; Lambertides, Neophytos; Trigeorgis, Lenos
We examine the empirical properties of the theoretical Black-Scholes-Merton (BSM) bankruptcy model. We evaluate the predictive ability of various existing modifications of the BSM model and extend prior studies by estimating volatility directly from market-observable returns on firm value. We show that parsimonious models using our direct market-observable volatility estimate perform better than alternative, more sophisticated, models. Our findings suggest the adoption of simpler modelling approaches relying on market data when implementing the BSM model. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Charitou, Andreas; Dionysiou, Dionysia; Lambertides, Neophytos; Trigeorgis, Lenos</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return sign forecasts based on conditional risk: Evidence from the UK stock market index</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chevapatrakul, Thanaset
Recent theoretical works have found a link between return sign forecastability and conditional volatility. This paper compares the predictive performance of the conditional country risk and the conditional residual risk in forecasting the direction of change in the return on the UK stock market index. The conditional country risk and the conditional residual risk are estimated using the bivariate BEKK-GARCH technique and the direction of change in the UK stock market index is modelled using the binary logit approach. Both the in-sample and the out-of-sample predictions suggest that, as a predictor, the conditional residual risk is superior to the conditional country risk. Our findings support the residual risk model while contradicting the traditional capital asset pricing model (CAPM). Moreover, our tactical asset allocation simulations show that when the conditional residual risk is used in conjunction with multiple-threshold trading strategies to guide the investment decisions, the actively managed portfolio achieves greater returns than the return on a buy and hold portfolio. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chevapatrakul, Thanaset</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improvements in loss given default forecasts for bank loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guertler, Marc; Hibbeln, Martin
An accurate forecast of the parameter loss given default (LCD) of loans plays a crucial role for risk-based decision making by banks. We theoretically analyze problems arising when forecasting LGDs of bank loans that lead to inconsistent estimates and a low predictive power. We present several improvements for LCD estimates, considering length-biased sampling, different loan characteristics depending on the type of default end, and different information sets according to the default status. We empirically demonstrate the capability of our proposals based on a-data set of 69,985 defaulted bank loans. Our results are not only important for banks, but also for regulators, because neglecting these issues leads to a significant underestimation of capital requirements. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guertler, Marc; Hibbeln, Martin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A behavioral explanation of the value anomaly based on time-varying return reversals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Soosung; Rubesam, Alexandre
We investigate the dynamics of the value anomaly in order to identify the driving forces of the anomaly. We show that the large positive value-minus-growth portfolio returns are explained by an over-reaction (under-reaction) to the positive (negative) market movements in short, specific time periods, during which the average returns of value-minus-growth portfolios are more than 2% a month. We propose an explanation based on behavioral biases: the dynamics of the value anomaly reflect the increased speed of return reversals subsequent to overreaction. Two conditions that increase the return reversals are proposed: when investors respond to public signals asymmetrically or when public signals become noisy. Our empirical results reveal that the value anomaly is explained by either one of these two channels. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hwang, Soosung; Rubesam, Alexandre</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Drivers of holding period firm-level returns in private equity-backed buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Valkama, Petri; Maula, Markku; Nikoskelainen, Erkki; Wright, Mike
We extend the research on the drivers of holding period firm-level returns in private equity (PE)-backed buyouts by examining deal-, industry-, and macroeconomic-level drivers and their interaction. To conduct our study, we use a comprehensive and hand-collected dataset covering exited buyouts in the UK between 1995-2004, and we control for sample selection and investment risk. Our study shows that governance variables generally have a limited role in driving value creation but that use of a ratchet is positively related to both equity and enterprise value returns; we also find that leverage has a positive impact on median and top-quartile equity returns. Moreover, returns are driven by the size of the buyout and the acquisitions made during the holding period. With respect to macroeconomic and industry level factors, industry growth particularly drives buyout returns. However, the effect of industry growth is not uniform; its influence is particularly strong in insider-driven and divisional buyouts, in addition to top-quartile transactions. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Valkama, Petri; Maula, Markku; Nikoskelainen, Erkki; Wright, Mike</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do sovereign credit default swaps represent a clean measure of sovereign default risk? A factor model approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Badaoui, Saad; Cathcart, Lara; El-Jahel, Lina
In this study, we use a factor model in order to decompose sovereign Credit Default Swaps (CDS) spreads into default, liquidity, systematic liquidity and correlation components. By calibrating the model to sovereign CDSs and bonds we are able to present a better decomposition and a more accurate measure of spread components. Our analysis reveals that sovereign CDS spreads are highly driven by liquidity (55.6% of default risk and 44.32% of liquidity) and that sovereign bond spreads are less subject to liquidity frictions and therefore could represent a better proxy for sovereign default risk (73% of default risk and 26.86% of liquidity). Furthermore, our model enables us to directly study the effect of systematic liquidity and flight-to-liquidity risks on bond and CDS spreads through the factor sensitivity matrix. We find that these risks do have an influence on the default intensity and they contribute significantly to spread movements. Finally, our empirical results advance the idea that the increase in the CDS spreads observed during the crisis period was mainly due to a surge in liquidity rather than to an increase in the default intensity. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Badaoui, Saad; Cathcart, Lara; El-Jahel, Lina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of labor unions on investment-cash flow sensitivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yan-Shing; Chen, I.-Ju
This paper empirically examines how labor unions affect investment-cash flow sensitivity using samples from the US covering the period of 1984-2009. We find a significant positive union effect using a q model of investment. The capital expenditures of firms are 1.71 times more sensitive to internal cash flows when unionization rates increase one standard deviation from the mean. This effect holds when we control for other proxies of financial constraints. In addition, unionized firms are associated with lower cash-cash flow sensitivity, which suggests that the higher investment-cash flow sensitivity in unionized firms is primarily driven by the incentive of these firms to reduce liquidity and enhance bargaining power against the union. We also show that the above union effects become more pronounced during labor contract negotiation years. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Yan-Shing; Chen, I.-Ju</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncertainty avoidance, risk tolerance and corporate takeover decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frijns, Bart; Gilbert, Aaron; Lehnert, Thorsten; Tourani-Rad, Alireza
In this paper, we examine the role of national culture in corporate takeover decisions, by arguing that managerial risk tolerance (a combination of risk aversion and risk perception), at the national level, is a cultural trait and affects the expected net synergies CEOs require. We propose a theoretical framework that links CEO risk tolerance to the expected net synergies. We empirically show that CEOs of firms located in countries with lower levels of risk tolerance, measured by Hofstede's (1980; 2001) uncertainty avoidance score, require higher premiums on takeovers, and show that uncertainty avoidance plays a greater role in relatively large takeovers. Additional testing reveals that CEOs from high uncertainty avoiding nations engage less in cross-border/cross-industry takeovers, suggesting that uncertainty avoidance captures more the CEO's risk perception than his/her risk aversion. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frijns, Bart; Gilbert, Aaron; Lehnert, Thorsten; Tourani-Rad, Alireza</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market liquidity in the financial crisis: The role of liquidity commonality and flight-to-quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roesch, Christoph G.; Kaserer, Christoph
We examine the dynamics and the drivers of market liquidity during the financial crisis, using a unique volume-weighted spread measure. According to the literature we find that market liquidity is impaired when stock markets decline, implying a positive relation between market and liquidity risk. Moreover, this relationship is the stronger the deeper one digs into the order book. Even more interestingly, this paper sheds further light on so far puzzling features of market liquidity: liquidity commonality and flight-to-quality. We show that liquidity commonality varies over time, increases during market downturns, peaks at major crisis events and becomes weaker the deeper we look into the limit order book. Consistent with recent theoretical models that argue for a spiral effect between the financial sector's funding liquidity and an asset's market liquidity, we find that funding liquidity tightness induces an increase in liquidity commonality which then leads to market-wide liquidity dry-ups. Therefore our findings corroborate the view that market liquidity can be a driving force for financial contagion. Finally, we show that there is a positive relationship between credit risk and liquidity risk, i.e., there is a spread between liquidity costs of high and low credit quality stocks, and that in times of increased market uncertainty the impact of credit risk on liquidity risk intensifies. This corroborates the existence of a flight-to-quality or flight-to-liquidity phenomenon also on the stock markets. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roesch, Christoph G.; Kaserer, Christoph</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Self attribution bias of the CEO: Evidence from CEO interviews on CNBC</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Y. Han
Self attribution bias (SAB, hereafter) is a mechanism that engenders overconfidence by attributing good performance to one's ability and bad performance to bad luck or the environment (Gervais and Odean, 2001). Using the transcripts of CEO interviews on CNBC, we measure the SAB of the CEO. Consistent with the prediction by Gervais et al. (2011) and Goel and Thakor (2008), we find concave non-linear relation between SAB and the market response to acquisition announcements. We also find that the CEOs with SAB are more likely to be fired and more sensitively to performance, especially under stronger governance regime of Sarbanes Oxley Act (SOX). Our results are robust after controlling for the selection bias to be in the CNBC interview. We consider and rule out alternative explanations, such as journalists' impact on governance and CEO's narcissism. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Y. Han</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy law and corporate investment decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tarantino, Emanuele
Major European countries have recently adopted bankruptcy codes that strengthen entrepreneurs' power to renegotiate outstanding liabilities. Renegotiation in bankruptcy allows lenders to increase recovery rates, however it also weakens the contract's ability to solve the moral hazard problem embedded in the production project. Hinging on this trade-off, I show in which circumstances a soft bankruptcy law that resembles Chapter 11 in the balance of lenders' and entrepreneur's rights encourages the choice of investments that privilege the achievement of long-term results. However, I also show that, in contrast to the common wisdom, soft bankruptcy can lead to the choice of investments that are biased towards the achievement of short-term outcomes. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tarantino, Emanuele</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity compensation and the sensitivity of research and development to financial market frictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Connor, Matthew; Rafferty, Matthew; Sheikh, Aamer
When financial market frictions exist, executives may have to decide which investment activities to reduce when internal funds decrease. Expenditures on research and development (R&amp;D) may be particularly vulnerable because of the long-term nature of innovative activity. We find that equity compensation is associated with lower levels of firm R&amp;D expenditures. Rewarding executives to incur more risk has little effect on R&amp;D expenditures, but rewarding executives for higher returns reduces R&amp;D expenditures and makes R&amp;D expenditures more sensitive to financial market frictions. In contrast, cash compensation reduces the sensitivity of R&amp;D expenditures to financial market frictions. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>O'Connor, Matthew; Rafferty, Matthew; Sheikh, Aamer</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of distressed economies on the EU sovereign market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Groba, Jonatan; Lafuente, Juan A.; Serrano, Pedro
Financially distressed economies inside the European Union (EU) are being blamed for producing a general increase in borrowing costs. This article analyzes the channels of default risk transmission within the EU countries using the information content in the sovereign Credit Default Swap (CDS) market. We proceed in two directions. First, we test the existence of cross-border volatility effects between the central and the peripheral EU countries. Second, we explore the effect of distressed economies on the default and risk premium constituents of sovereign default swaps. We show a significant volatility spillover from distressed to central European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) economies. This causality pattern leads to a significant impact on the default swap risk premia. On average, the risk premium accounts for approximately 42% of central EMU spreads and 56% of the spreads for those countries outside of the EMU. The peripheral risk also affects the default component of central economies, although its impact is lower. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Groba, Jonatan; Lafuente, Juan A.; Serrano, Pedro</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Greasing the wheels of bank lending: Evidence from private firms in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yunling; Liu, Ming; Su, Jun
Bribery, rather than firm performance, largely determines the extent to Which private firms access bank credit in China. Bribery enables an economic outcome whereby firms with better economic performance are awarded larger loans. These firms also pay more in terms of bribes. Although satisfactory firm performance does determine whether firms can access loans, it does so only for loans originated by the big-four banks. For loans originated by smaller banks, performance is not essential for firms to secure loan access. Our evidence sheds light on the surprising finding of earlier studies that Chinese banks use commercial logic in their lending practices despite being endowed with a weak institutional framework. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Yunling; Liu, Ming; Su, Jun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Emerging markets and heavy tails</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibragimov, Marat; Ibragimov, Rustam; Kattuman, Paul
Emerging countries are held to be subject to more frequent and more pronounced external and internal shocks than their developed counter-parts. This suggests that key variables pertaining to their markets, including their exchange rates, will be marked by greater likelihood of extreme observations and large fluctuations. We focus on the hypothesis that compared to developed country exchange rates, emerging country exchange rates will be more pronouncedly heavy-tailed. We find support for the hypothesis using recently proposed robust tail index estimation methods which, in particular, perform well under heavy-tailed dependent GARCH processes that are often used for modeling exchange rates. According to the estimation results reported in the paper, variances may be infinite for several emerging country exchange rates. Tail index values zeta = p is an element of (2.6,2.8) appear to be at the dividing boundary between the two sets of countries: while the moments of order p is an element of (2.6,2.8) are finite for most of the developed country exchange rates, they may be (or are) infinite for most of the emerging country exchange rates. We also study the impact of the on-going financial and economic crisis, and find that heavy-tailedness properties of most exchange rates did not change significantly with the onset of the crisis. At the same time, some foreign exchange markets have experienced structural changes in their heavy-tailedness properties during the crisis. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ibragimov, Marat; Ibragimov, Rustam; Kattuman, Paul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International diversification gains and home bias in banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia-Herrero, Alicia; Vazquez, Francisco
This paper studies international diversification in banking, exploiting a bank-level dataset that covers the operations of 38 global banks and their subsidiaries overseas during 1995-2004. The paper finds that banks with a larger share of assets allocated to subsidiaries in emerging market countries were able to attain higher risk-adjusted returns. These gains were somewhat reduced by the concentration of bank subsidiaries in specific geographical regions, which is typical of the observed international expansion strategies. The paper also finds a substantial home bias in the international allocation of bank assets relative to the results of a mean-variance portfolio optimization model. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garcia-Herrero, Alicia; Vazquez, Francisco</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The light and dark side of TARP</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farruggio, Christian; Michalak, Tobias C.; Uhde, Andre
This paper empirically investigates the impact of the first announcement of TARP, the announcement of revised TARP, respective capital infusions under TARP-CPP and capital repayments on changes in share-holder value and the risk exposure of supported US banks. Our analysis reveals a light and a dark side of TARP. While announcements as well as capital repayments may provoke positive wealth effects and a decrease in bank risk, equity capital injections to banks are observed to be a severe impediment to restore market confidence and financial stability. Furthermore, while TARP announcements and capital injections may increase systemic risk, no significant effect on systemic risk is found for capital repayments. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Farruggio, Christian; Michalak, Tobias C.; Uhde, Andre</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership change, institutional development and performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana; Stiglitz, Joseph E.
This paper conducts a cross-country empirical study of the impact of institutions and agency conflicts on ownership reforms and their implications for changes in performance and efficiency. We examine two main questions. First, we evaluate the effects of certain property rights and institutional quality measures on performance and efficiency. We find that property rights and contracting rights protections contribute to stronger post-privatization performance. Second, we ask whether sectors undergoing changes from state to private ownership exhibit better or worse performance than sectors remaining public. We find an insignificant effect of privatization in ordinary least squares estimates and a negative short-term effect after correcting for endogeneity of privatization decisions that disappears in the long run, consistent with recently privatized enterprises facing short-run costs of restructuring and the challenges of mitigating agency and expropriation concerns. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana; Stiglitz, Joseph E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sudden crash or long torture: The timing of market reactions to operational loss events</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biell, Lis; Muller, Aline
An emerging literature investigating market responses to operational loss announcements concludes that financial markets tend usually to overreact to loss events. This overreaction is commonly interpreted as reputational damage. We revisit this issue by focusing on the timing of markets' reactions and highlight two variables: the start and the speed of stock markets' responses. It appears that when operational losses are caused by internal fraud the negative market reaction materializes earlier and faster. Industry sectors and prevailing market conditions influence the timing of market reactions as well. Our empirical findings reveal moreover that a higher initial grading of the company is associated with a later stock market reaction to the announcement. While the relative magnitude and the length of markets' overreactions is positively correlated to the concomitant downgrading our study shows that overreaction magnitudes are also strongly correlated to our estimate of the total duration of the reaction. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Biell, Lis; Muller, Aline</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capturing the risk premium of commodity futures: The role of hedging pressure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basu, Devraj; Miffre, Joelle
We construct long-short factor mimicking portfolios that capture the hedging pressure risk premium of commodity futures. We consider single sorts based on the open interests of hedgers or speculators, as well as double sorts based on both positions. The long-short hedging pressure portfolios are priced cross-sectionally and present Sharpe ratios that systematically exceed those of long-only benchmarks. Further tests show that the hedging pressure risk premiums rise with the volatility of commodity futures markets and that the predictive power of hedging pressure over cross-sectional commodity futures returns is different from the previously documented forecasting power of past returns and the slope of the term structure. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Basu, Devraj; Miffre, Joelle</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of the interbank network structure on contagion and common shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Georg, Co-Pierre
This paper proposes a dynamic multi-agent model of a banking system with central bank. Banks optimize a portfolio of risky investments and riskless excess reserves according to their risk, return, and liquidity preferences. They are linked via interbank loans and face stochastic deposit supply. Comparing different interbank network structures, it is shown that money-centre networks are more stable than random networks. Evidence is provided that the central bank stabilizes interbank markets in the short run only. Systemic risk via contagion is compared with common shocks and it is shown that both forms of systemic risk require different optimal policy responses. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Georg, Co-Pierre</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The political economy of international integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucey, Brian M.
nan</description><author>Lucey, Brian M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why does shareholder protection Matter for abnormal returns after reported insider purchases and sales?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fidrmuc, Jana P.; Korczak, Adriana; Korczak, Piotr
We use a unique data set of more than 240,000 reported insider transactions across 15 European countries and the USA to analyze the link between country-level shareholder protection and abnormal returns following insider trades. We show that abnormal returns after insider transactions are positively correlated with country-level shareholder protection against expropriation by corporate insiders, which supports the information-content hypothesis. Market reaction to insider purchases increases with shareholder protection because shareholder protection enhances the transparency and trustworthiness of insiders' actions, and limits possibilities for direct profit diversion, so that more information is eventually reflected in stock prices. For insider sales, shareholder protection decreases their negative information content. We conjecture that this is due to the effect of greater transparency and trustworthiness strengthening the diversification and liquidity reasons for selling in better shareholder protection countries. We find limited support for the rent-extraction hypothesis that conjectures that shareholder protection is associated with insider trading dollar profits. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fidrmuc, Jana P.; Korczak, Adriana; Korczak, Piotr</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board composition and operational risk events of financial institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Tawei; Hsu, Carol
We investigate the relation between board composition and operational risk events of financial institutions in the period from 1996 to 2010. Drawing from corporate governance literature, we consider the impact of board characteristics on the likelihood of operational risk events. Overall, our findings suggest that board size is negatively and non-linearly associated with the possibility of operational risk events. For the event types of "Clients, Products, and Business Practices," and "Internal Fraud and External Fraud," firms with a higher proportion of independent directors are less likely to suffer from fraud or failure to comply with professional obligations to clients. Our results on age and tenure heterogeneity also indicate that having a more diverse board can have an adverse impact on the board monitoring function. These results can shed new light on board demographics and operational risk management in financial institutions. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Tawei; Hsu, Carol</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When active fund managers deviate from their peers: Implications for fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta-Mukherjee, Swasti
This paper proposes that the extent to which mutual fund managers' beliefs deviate from the ex ante unobservable representative beliefs of their peers contains information about their skill. A new measure based on portfolio allocations, peer deviation, is used to capture a fund manager's divergence from the contemporaneously unobservable beliefs of her peers. The portfolio based on representative beliefs of a group of managers investing in similar assets outperforms passive benchmarks, indicating that they reflect informed beliefs. Fund managers who simultaneously arrive at portfolio selections which, in hindsight, are close to those implied by representative beliefs possess ex ante more skill and exhibit future outperformance. Copycat strategies replicating lagged portfolio holdings implied by representative beliefs outperform the actual portfolio holdings of funds that deviate most, but the outperformance dissipates after two quarters. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gupta-Mukherjee, Swasti</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectations of future income and real exchange rate movements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hayat, Aziz; Ganiev, Bahodir; Tang, Xueli
We show that changes in expectations of future income driven by exogenous factors (such as the discovery of oil and an increase in global demand for natural resources) can cause movements in the real exchange rate (RER) in excess of, and sometimes even in the opposite direction to, what one would expect given the changes in current income. We provide both a theoretical model and empirical evidence of this. In particular, we show that the signing of numerous production sharing agreements (PSAs) between the government of Azerbaijan and foreign oil companies in 1994-1998 fueled expectations of higher future incomes, resulting in a considerable appreciation of the RER. Some of these PSAs subsequently failed or ran into difficulties, which led to a downward revision of expected future income and a depreciation of the RER in 1999-2003, even though the current income started to rise, due to an increase in the current oil revenue. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hayat, Aziz; Ganiev, Bahodir; Tang, Xueli</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of the dimensions of social performance on firm risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouslah, Kais; Kryzanowski, Lawrence; M'Zali, Bouchra
This paper examines the impact of the individual dimensions of social performance (SP) on firm risk (total and idiosyncratic) using 16,599 firm-year observations over the period 1991-2007. We find that firm risk for S&amp;P500 members is positively affected by Employee, Diversity, and Corporate Governance concerns. On the other hand, Community (Diversity) strengths negatively (positively) affect their risk. As to non-S&amp;P500 members, firm risk is positively affected by Employee concerns and Diversity strengths. However, firm risk of non-S&amp;P500 members is negatively affected by Environment strengths. The direction of causation between firm risk and SP depends on the dimension examined. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bouslah, Kais; Kryzanowski, Lawrence; M'Zali, Bouchra</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk contributions: A credit portfolio approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Puzanova, Natalia; Duellmann, Klaus
We put forward a framework for measuring systemic risk and attributing it to individual banks. Systemic risk is coherently measured as the expected loss to depositors and investors when a systemic event occurs. The risk contributions are calculated so as to ensure a full risk allocation among institutions. Applying our methodology to a panel of 54-86 of the world's major commercial banks for a 13-year time span with monthly frequency not only allows us to closely match the list of G-SIBs; we can also use individual risk contributions to compute bank-specific surcharges: systemic capital charges as well as countercyclical buffers. We therefore address both dimensions of systemic risk - cross-sectional and time-series - in a single integrated approach. As the analysis of risk drivers confirms, the main focus of macroprudential supervision should be on a solid capital base throughout the financial cycle and de-correlation of banks' asset values. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Puzanova, Natalia; Duellmann, Klaus</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On portfolio optimization: Imposing the right constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Behr, Patrick; Guettler, Andre; Miebs, Felix
We reassess the recent finding that no established portfolio strategy outperforms the naively diversified portfolio, 1/N, by developing a constrained minimum-variance portfolio strategy on a shrinkage theory based framework. Our results show that our constrained minimum-variance portfolio yields significantly lower out-of-sample variances than many established minimum-variance portfolio strategies. Further, we observe that our portfolio strategy achieves higher Sharpe ratios than 1/N, amounting to an average Sharpe ratio increase of 32.5% across our six empirical datasets. We find that our constrained minimum-variance strategy is the only strategy that achieves the goal of improving the Sharpe ratio of 1/N consistently and significantly. At the same time, our developed portfolio strategy achieves a comparatively low turnover and exhibits no excessive short interest. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Behr, Patrick; Guettler, Andre; Miebs, Felix</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial freedom and bank efficiency: Evidence from the European Union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chortareas, Georgios E.; Girardone, Claudia; Ventouri, Alexia
This paper investigates the dynamics between the financial freedom counterparts of the economic freedom index drawn from the Heritage Foundation database and bank efficiency levels. We rely on a large sample of commercial banks operating in the 27 European Union member states over the 2000s. After estimating bank-specific efficiency scores using Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA), we develop a truncated regression model combined with bootstrapped confidence intervals to test our main hypotheses. Results suggest that the higher the degree of an economy's financial freedom, the higher the benefits for banks in terms of cost advantages and overall efficiency. Our results also show that the effects of financial freedom on bank efficiency tend to be more pronounced in countries with freer political systems in which governments formulate and implement sound policies and higher quality governance. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chortareas, Georgios E.; Girardone, Claudia; Ventouri, Alexia</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sustainable growth rate, optimal growth rate, and optimal payout ratio: A joint optimization approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hong-Yi; Gupta, Manak C.; Lee, Alice C.; Lee, Cheng-Few
This study investigates the investment decision and dividend policy jointly from a non-steady state to a steady state. We extend Higgins' (1977, 1981, 2008) sustainable growth rate model and develop a dynamic model which jointly optimizes the growth rate and payout ratio. We optimize the firm value to obtain the optimal growth rate in terms of a logistic equation and find that the steady state growth rate can be used as the benchmark for the mean-reverting process of the optimal growth rate. We also investigate the specification error of the mean and variance of dividend per share when introducing the stochastic growth rate. Empirical results support the mean-reverting process of the growth rate and the importance of covariance between the profitability and the growth rate in determining dividend payouts. The intertemporal behavior of the covariance may shed some light on the fact of disappearing dividends over decades. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Hong-Yi; Gupta, Manak C.; Lee, Alice C.; Lee, Cheng-Few</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulate one service, tame the entire market: Credit cards in Turkey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akin, Guzin Gulsun; Aysan, Ahmet Faruk; Borici, Denada; Yildiran, Levent
In credit card markets banks provide both payment and credit services. Two regulations were recently enacted in the Turkish credit card market: one on payment services in 2005 and the other on credit services in 2006. By employing the well-known Panzar and Rosse (1982, 1987) method and a unique quarterly data set for 21 Turkish banks between 2002 and 2008, we investigate the extent of banks' market power in the Turkish credit card market before and after the regulations. Unlike most of the existing literature, which considers competition and regulation for either credit or payment services and ignores the externalities between them, we consider the entire market by taking both services into account. Fixed effects estimations reveal that banks enjoyed collusive oligopoly power before the regulations. Although the first regulation did not have much impact, the second led to rises in both banks' total revenues and competition in the entire market. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akin, Guzin Gulsun; Aysan, Ahmet Faruk; Borici, Denada; Yildiran, Levent</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO risk incentives and firm performance following R&amp;D increases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shen, Carl Hsin-han; Zhang, Hao
In this study we analyze how CEO risk incentives affect the efficiency of research and development (R&amp;D) investments. We examine a sample of 843 cases in which firms increase their R&amp;D investments by an economically significant amount over the period of 1995-2006. We find that firms with higher sensitivity of CEO compensation portfolio value to stock volatility (vega) are more likely to have large increases in R&amp;D investments. More importantly, we find that high-vega firms experience lower abnormal stock returns and lower operating performance compared to their low-vega counterparts following the R&amp;D increases. Our main results hold in a variety of robustness tests. The results are consistent with the conjecture that high-vega compensation portfolios may induce managers to overinvest in inefficient R&amp;D projects and therefore hurt firm performance. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shen, Carl Hsin-han; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of external financing costs on investment timing and sizing decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nishihara, Michi; Shibata, Takashi
We develop a dynamic model in which a firm exercises an option to expand production on either a small or large scale with cash reserves and costly external funds. An intermediate level of cash reserves, which is insufficient for the large-scale investment but sufficient for the small-scale investment, provides an incentive for the firm to invest early in the small-scale project. These results fill the gap between two types of results: (i) empirical findings of a U-shaped relation between the investment volume and internal funds and (ii) empirical predictions of a U-shaped relation between the investment timing and internal funds. In addition, our results have real-world implications for investment in alternative projects. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nishihara, Michi; Shibata, Takashi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public information arrival: Price discovery and liquidity in electronic limit order markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Riordan, Ryan; Storkenmaier, Andreas; Wagener, Martin; Zhang, S. Sarah
How information is translated into market prices is still an open question. This paper studies the impact of newswire messages on intraday price discovery, liquidity, and trading intensity in an electronic limit order market. We take an objective ex ante measure of the tone of a message to study the impacts of positive, negative, and neutral messages on price discovery and trading activity. As expected, we find higher adverse selection costs around the arrival of newswire messages. Negative messages are associated with higher adverse selection costs than positive or neutral messages. Liquidity increases around positive and neutral messages and decreases around negative messages. Available order book depth as well as the trading intensity increases around all news. Our results suggest that market participants possess different information gathering and processing capabilities and that negative news messages are particularly informative and induce stronger market reactions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Riordan, Ryan; Storkenmaier, Andreas; Wagener, Martin; Zhang, S. Sarah</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of macro-economic surprises on carry trade activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hutchison, Michael; Sushko, Vladyslav
Can official news and policy announcements affect foreign exchange speculation? A widespread speculative strategy in foreign exchange markets is carry trade. This paper explores the links between macroeconomic news and foreign exchange options to identify macro-economic fundamentals most relevant to the pricing of downside risk - measured by risk reversals options contracts - to carry trade activity. Focusing primarily on the Japanese yen carry trade, we identify a significant impact of macro-economic surprises on dollar/yen risk reversals. The effect is sizeable, with news related to bilateral trade balance of particular concern. Moreover, there is a close link between risk reversals and speculative futures positions in Japanese yen. This allows us to quantify a substantial effect of macro-economic news on carry trade activity, with the cost of hedging as the transmission mechanism. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hutchison, Michael; Sushko, Vladyslav</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Margining in derivatives markets and the stability of the banking sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gibson, Rajna; Murawski, Carsten
We investigate the effects of margining, a widely-used mechanism for attaching collateral to derivatives contracts, on derivatives trading volume, default risk, and on the welfare in the banking sector. First, we develop a stylized banking sector equilibrium model to develop some basic intuition of the effects of margining. We find that a margin requirement can be privately and socially sub-optimal. Subsequently, we extend this model into a dynamic simulation model that captures some of the essential characteristics of over-the-counter derivatives markets. Contrarily to the common belief that margining always reduces default risk, we find that there exist situations in which margining increases default risk, reduces aggregate derivatives' trading volume, and has an ambiguous effect on welfare in the banking sector. The negative effects of margining are exacerbated during periods of market stress when margin rates are high and collateral is scarce. We also find that central counterparties only lift some of the inefficiencies caused by margining. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gibson, Rajna; Murawski, Carsten</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disentangling the effect of jumps on systematic risk using a new estimator of integrated co-volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Kent; Liu, Junwei; Liu, Zhi
We propose a new threshold-pre-averaging realized estimator for the integrated co-volatility of two assets using non-synchronous observations with the simultaneous presence of microstructure noise and jumps. We derive a noise-robust Hayashi-Yoshida estimator that allows for very general structure of jumps in the underlying process. Based on the new estimator, different aspects and components of co-volatility are compared to examine the effect of jumps on systematic risk using tick-by-tick data from the Chinese stock market during 2009-2011. We find controlling for jumps contributes significantly to the beta estimation and common jumps mostly dominate the jump's effect, but there is also evidence that idiosyncratic jumps may lead to significant deviation. We also find that not controlling for noise and jumps in previous realized beta estimations tend to considerably underestimate the systematic risk. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Kent; Liu, Junwei; Liu, Zhi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A revisit to the dependence structure between the stock and foreign exchange markets: A dependence-switching copula approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Yi-Chiuan; Wu, Jyh-Lin; Lai, Yi-Hao
This paper develops a dependence-switching copula model to examine dependence and tail dependence for four different market statuses, namely, rising-stocks/appreciating-currency, falling-stocks/depreciating-currency, rising-stocks/depreciating-currency, and falling-stocks/appreciating-currency. The model is then applied to daily stock returns and exchange rate changes for six major industrial countries over the 1990-2010 period. The dependence and tail dependence among the above four market statuses are asymmetric for most countries in the negative correlation regime, but symmetric in the positive correlation regime. These results enrich the findings in the existing literature and suggest that analyzing cross-market linkages within a time-invariant copula framework may not be appropriate. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Yi-Chiuan; Wu, Jyh-Lin; Lai, Yi-Hao</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The disposition effect and investor experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da Costa, Newton; Goulart, Marco; Cupertino, Cesar; Macedo, Jurandir; Da Silva, Sergio
We examine whether investing experience can dampen the disposition effect, that is, the fact that investors seem to hold on to their losing stocks to a greater extent than they hold on to their winning stocks. To do so, we devise a computer program that simulates the stock market. We use the program in an experiment with two groups of subjects, namely experienced investors and undergraduate students (the inexperienced investors). As a control procedure, we consider random trade decisions made by robot subjects. We find that though both human subjects show the disposition effect, the more experienced investors are less affected. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Da Costa, Newton; Goulart, Marco; Cupertino, Cesar; Macedo, Jurandir; Da Silva, Sergio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does board structure in banks really affect their performance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pathan, Shams; Faff, Robert
We study whether board structure (board size, independence and gender diversity) in banks relates to performance. Using a broad panel of large US bank holding companies over the period 1997-2011, we find that both board size and independent directors decrease bank performance. Although gender diversity improves bank performance in the pre-Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) period (1997-2002), the positive effect of gender diminishes in both the post-SOX (2003-2006) and the crisis periods (2007-2011). Finally, we show that board structure is particularly relevant for banks with low market power, if they are immune to the threat of external takeover and/or they are small. Our two-step system generalised method of moments estimation accounts for endogeneity concerns (simultaneity, reverse causality and unobserved heterogeneity). The findings are robust to a wide range of other sensitivity checks including alternative proxies for bank performance. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pathan, Shams; Faff, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment and financing constraints in China: Does working capital management make a difference?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ding, Sai; Guariglia, Alessandra; Knight, John
We use a panel of over 116,000 Chinese firms of different ownership types over the period 2000-2007 to analyze the linkages between investment in fixed and working capital and financing constraints. We find that those firms characterized by high working capital display high sensitivities of investment in working capital to cash flow (WKS) and low sensitivities of investment in fixed capital to cash flow (FKS). We then construct and analyze firm-level FKS and WKS measures and find that, despite severe external financing constraints, those firms with low FKS and high WKS exhibit the highest fixed investment rates. This suggests that an active management of working capital may help firms to alleviate the effects of financing constraints on fixed investment. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ding, Sai; Guariglia, Alessandra; Knight, John</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changes in cash holdings around the S&amp;P 500 additions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brisker, Eric R.; Colak, Goenuel; Peterson, David R.
We analyze the changes in cash holding policies of S&amp;P 500 firms from before to after their inclusion in the index. One year after inclusion, their mean industry-adjusted cash holdings decline by nearly 32% from the year before inclusion. Several factors explain this decline. The precautionary motive for cash subsides due to these firms becoming more visible, less uncertain, and less constrained to raise cheap external capital. Corporate governance deteriorates after inclusion due to increased managerial entrenchment, which leads to a reduction in cash as suggested by the free cash flow hypothesis. Most index firms face diminishing investment opportunities and decreasing capital expenditures, which implies a lesser need for cash holdings related to the transaction motive. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brisker, Eric R.; Colak, Goenuel; Peterson, David R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting mutual fund performance evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angelidis, Timotheos; Giamouridis, Daniel; Tessaromatis, Nikolaos
Mutual fund manager excess performance should be measured relative to their self-reported benchmark rather than the return of a passive portfolio with the same risk characteristics. Ignoring the self-reported benchmark results in different measurement of stock selection and timing components of excess performance. We revisit baseline empirical evidence fund performance evaluation utilizing stock selection and timing measures that incorporate the self-reported benchmark. We introduce a new factor exposure based approach for measuring the - static and dynamic - timing capabilities of mutual fund managers. We overall conclude that current studies are likely to be misstating skill because they ignore the managers' self-reported benchmark in the performance evaluation process. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Angelidis, Timotheos; Giamouridis, Daniel; Tessaromatis, Nikolaos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge fund liquidity and performance: Evidence from the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schaub, Nic; Schmid, Markus
We investigate how share restrictions affect hedge fund performance in crisis and non-crisis periods. Consistent with prior research, we find that in the pre-crisis period more illiquid funds generate a share illiquidity premium compensating investors for limited liquidity. In the crisis period, this share illiquidity premium turns into an illiquidity discount. Hedge funds with more stringent share restrictions invest more heavily in illiquid assets. While share restrictions enable funds to manage illiquid assets effectively in the pre-crisis period, they seem insufficient to ensure effective management of illiquid portfolios in the crisis. In a crisis period, funds holding illiquid portfolios experience lower returns and alphas, also when share restrictions are controlled for. Funds with an asset-liability mismatch perform particularly poorly and experience the strongest outflows. Share restrictions are also a proxy for incentives as investors cannot immediately withdraw their money after poor performance. We show that higher incentive fees can offset the share illiquidity discount in the crisis period. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schaub, Nic; Schmid, Markus</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation and systemic risk consequences of bank opacity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Jeffrey S.; Lee, Wayne Y.; Yeager, Timothy J.
We examine the effects of opacity on bank valuation and synchronicity in bank equity returns over the years 2000-2006 prior to the 2007 financial crisis. As expected, investments in opaque assets are more profitable than investments in transparent assets, and taking profitability into account, have larger valuation discounts relative to transparent assets. The valuation discounts on opaque asset investments decline over the 2000-2006 period only to be followed by a sharp reversal in 2007. The decline is coincident with a rise in bank equity share prices, decrease in transparent asset holdings by banks, and greater return synchronicity - evidence consistent with a feedback effect. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jones, Jeffrey S.; Lee, Wayne Y.; Yeager, Timothy J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rescue packages and bank lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brei, Michael; Gambacorta, Leonardo; von Peter, Goetz
This paper examines whether the rescue measures adopted during the global financial crisis helped to sustain the supply of bank lending. The analysis proposes a setup that allows testing for structural shifts in the bank lending equation, and employs a novel dataset covering large international banks headquartered in 14 major advanced economies for the period 1995-2010. While stronger capitalisation sustains loan growth in normal times, banks during a crisis can turn additional capital into greater lending only once their capitalisation exceeds a critical threshold. This suggests that recapitalisations may not translate into greater credit supply until bank balance sheets are sufficiently strengthened. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brei, Michael; Gambacorta, Leonardo; von Peter, Goetz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset liquidity, corporate investment, and endogenous financing costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flor, Christian Riis; Hirth, Stefan
We analyze how the liquidity of real and financial assets affects corporate investment. The trade-off between liquidation costs and underinvestment costs implies that low-liquidity firms exhibit negative investment sensitivities to liquid funds, whereas high-liquidity firms have positive sensitivities. If real assets are not divisible in liquidation, firms with high financial liquidity optimally avoid external financing and instead cut new investment. If real assets are divisible, firms use external financing, which implies a lower sensitivity. In addition, asset redeployability decreases the investment sensitivity. Our findings demonstrate that asset liquidity is an important determinant of corporate investment. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Flor, Christian Riis; Hirth, Stefan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incomplete information, idiosyncratic volatility and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berrada, Tony; Hugonnier, Julien
When investors have incomplete information, expected returns, as measured by an econometrician, deviate from those predicted by standard asset pricing models by including a term that is the product of the stock's idiosyncratic volatility and the investors' aggregated forecast errors. If investors are biased this term generates a relation between idiosyncratic volatility and expected stocks returns. Relying on forecast revisions from IBES, we construct a new variable that proxies for this term and show that it explains a significant part of the empirical relation between idiosyncratic volatility and stock returns. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berrada, Tony; Hugonnier, Julien</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ironing out the kinks in executive compensation: Linking incentive pay to average stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Yisong S.
Traditional stock option grant is the most common form of incentive pay in executive compensation. Applying a principal-agent analysis, we find this common practice suboptimal and firms are better off linking incentive pay to average stock prices. Among other benefits, averaging reduces volatility by about 42%, making the incentive pay more attractive to risk-averse executives. Holding the cost of the option grant to the firm constant, Asian stock options are more cost effective than traditional stock options and provide stronger incentives to increase stock price. More importantly, the improvement is achieved with little impact on the option grant's risk incentives (after adjusting for option cost). Finally, averaging also improves the value and incentive effects of indexed stock options. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tian, Yisong S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity uncertainty and intermediation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lazopoulos, Ioannis
The paper performs a welfare comparison between demand deposit and equity contracts in the presence of intrinsic aggregate uncertainty. In this framework, the welfare dominance of deposit contracts emerges under corner preferences. It is shown that aggregate uncertainty creates high price volatility of ex-dividend equity claims traded in a secondary market and the resulting consumption allocations offer less risk-sharing opportunities to risk-averse consumers than tailor-made deposit contracts. The contingency of early payoffs on depositors' withdrawal order reinforces the welfare performance of deposit contracts, whereas costly liquidation of productive long-term investments deteriorates their welfare performance relative to equity contracts. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lazopoulos, Ioannis</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No-arbitrage Near-Cointegrated VAR(p) term structure models, term premia and GDP growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jardet, Caroline; Monfort, Alain; Pegoraro, Fulvio
The recent macro-finance literature does not agree either about the empirical properties of the expectation part and of the term premium on long-term bonds or about the importance or even the direction of the relationship between the term premium and future economic activity. This paper proposes a two-step approach to handle both problems. First, in a VAR setting, we extract a reliable measure of the term premium by means of averaging estimator techniques aiming at optimally solving prediction problems when highly persistent processes are present and, thus, providing a so called Near-Cointegrated VAR(p) approach. Second, we analyze the dynamic response of GDP to shocks to the term premium by using the New Information Response Function concept. As far as the first problem is concerned, we find that the NCVAR-based term premium measure is rather stable and counter-cyclical, as suggested by interest rates survey-based estimation of yield curve models and by its risk compensation role. Regarding the second problem, we find that an increase in the long-term spread caused by the term premium induces two effects on future economic activity: the impact is negative for short horizons (less than 1 year), whereas it is positive for longer ones. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jardet, Caroline; Monfort, Alain; Pegoraro, Fulvio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market incompleteness and the equity premium puzzle: Evidence from state-level data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, Kris; Pallage, Stephane; Robe, Michel A.
This paper investigates the importance of market incompleteness by comparing the rates of risk aversion estimated from complete and incomplete markets environments. For the incomplete-markets case, we use consumption data for the 50 US states. We find that the rate of risk aversion under the incomplete-markets setup is much lower. Furthermore, including the second and third moments of the cross-sectional distribution of consumption growth in the pricing kernel lowers the estimate of risk aversion. These findings suggest that market incompleteness ought to be seen as an important component of solutions to the equity premium puzzle. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacobs, Kris; Pallage, Stephane; Robe, Michel A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio optimization in the presence of dependent financial returns with long memory: A copula based approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubaker, Heni; Sghaier, Nadia
In this paper, we seek to examine the effect of the presence of long memory on the dependence structure between financial returns and on portfolio optimization. First, we focus on the dependence structure using copulas. To select the best copula, in addition to the goodness of fit tests, we employ a graphical method based on visual comparison of the fitted copula density and the smoothed copula density estimated by wavelets. Moreover, we check the stability of the copula parameter. The empirical results show that the long memory affects the dependence structure. Second, we analyze the impact of this dependence structure on the optimal portfolio. We propose a new approach based on minimizing the Conditional Value at Risk and assuming that the dependence structure is modeled by the copula parameter. The empirical results show that our approach outperforms the traditional minimizing variance approach, where the dependence structure is represented by the linear correlation coefficient. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubaker, Heni; Sghaier, Nadia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product market competition and credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Hsing-Hua; Lee, Han-Hsing
This study theoretically and empirically investigates effects of product market competition on credit risk. We first develop a real-options-based structural model in a homogeneous oligopoly and show that credit spreads are positively related to the number of firms in an industry. The disparity of firm size in an industry is relevant to both product market competition and credit risk, and we therefore extend the model to an asymmetric duopoly case. In particular, we demonstrate that credit spreads of relatively small (large) firms within an industry are positively (negatively) related to Herfindahl-Hirschman index, and the relative firm size in an industry is an important determinant of credit risk. The models' implications are empirically scrutinized by a reduced-form hazard model and generally supported. By performing out-of-sample analyses, the results demonstrate that firm size together with the interaction terms between intra-industry firm size dummies and competition intensity can effectively predict default. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Hsing-Hua; Lee, Han-Hsing</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio selection: An extreme value approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DiTraglia, Francis J.; Gerlach, Jeffrey R.
We show theoretically that lower tail dependence (chi). a measure of the probability that a portfolio will suffer large losses given that the market does, contains important information for risk-averse investors. We then estimate chi for a sample of DJIA stocks and show that it differs systematically from other risk measures including variance, semi-variance, skewness, kurtosis, beta, and coskewness. In out-of-sample tests, portfolios constructed to have low values of chi outperform the market index, the mean return of the stocks in our sample, and portfolios with high values of chi. Our results indicate that chi is conceptually important for risk-averse investors, differs substantially from other risk measures, and provides useful information for portfolio selection. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>DiTraglia, Francis J.; Gerlach, Jeffrey R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics of retail-bank branching in Antwerp (Belgium) 1991-2006: Evidence from micro-geographic data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huysentruyt, Marieke; Lefevere, Eva; Menon, Carlo
We exploit a comprehensive new panel dataset on retailbank branch locations in 233 neighborhoods (local markets) in the metropolitan area of Antwerp to describe (i) how between 1991 and 2006 the patterns of bank presence, entry, exit and choice deeply evolve and (ii) whether and how changes in these "on the ground" patterns systematically diverge across Antwerp's different, highly segregated neighborhoods. We show that over the 15-year period under study entry and exit dynamics substantially intensify, the level change in branch desert grows significantly, and bank choice markedly declines; and that between 1996 and 2001, these changes are robustly associated with the neighborhood average income. In doing so, we advance a new technique for generating spatial measures that both minimize the discretization bias and can be reliably linked to neighborhoods. We demonstrate that the resulting measures are indeed more precise than traditional count measures. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huysentruyt, Marieke; Lefevere, Eva; Menon, Carlo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seasonality and the valuation of commodity options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Back, Janis; Prokopczuk, Marcel; Rudolf, Markus
Price movements in many commodity markets exhibit significant seasonal patterns. However, given an observed futures price, a deterministic seasonal component at the price level is not relevant for the pricing of commodity options. In contrast, this is not true for the seasonal pattern observed in the volatility of the commodity price. Analyzing an extensive sample of soybean, corn, heating oil and natural gas options, we find that seasonality in volatility is an important aspect to consider when valuing these contracts. The inclusion of an appropriate seasonality adjustment significantly reduces pricing errors in these markets and yields more improvement in valuation accuracy than increasing the number of stochastic factors. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Back, Janis; Prokopczuk, Marcel; Rudolf, Markus</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Control considerations, creditor monitoring, and the capital structure of family firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmid, Thomas
In this paper, I analyze the motives moving founders and their families to influence the capital structure decision. For this, I complement detailed corporate governance information for Germany with data from other countries. The results for the German bank-based financial system contradict prior findings for other institutional environments. According to these results, family firms in Germany rely less heavily on debt than non-family firms. Less surprisingly, the opposite holds true for the international dataset. Different empirical tests indicate that this puzzling result can be explained by control considerations. Founders and their families use the capital structure to optimize their control over the firm. However, whether family firms rely more or less on debt depends on the level of creditor monitoring in an institutional environment. These findings emphasize that control considerations of major shareholders are important-although often overlooked-determinants of the capital structure. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schmid, Thomas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modelling sovereign credit spreads with international macro-factors: The case of Brazil 1998-2009</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Zhuoshi; Spencer, Peter
This paper develops a macro-finance model of the Brazilian economy and its sovereign debt markets that allows for domestic and international macroeconomic influences as well as swings in investor confidence. It finds significant evidence of common trends in the US and Brazilian economies and bond markets as well as spillover effects from US inflation and business cycles to the Brazilian economy. The US Fed Funds rate influences Brazilian sovereign spreads, as do Brazilian inflation and policy rates. The Brazilian confidence factor dominates the behavior of the spreads during periods of crisis and we find that it also has a powerful effect on the level and volatility of macroeconomic variables. These results suggest that the macro-finance approach could throw light upon the behavior of other economies that are troubled by sovereign risk. (C) 2012 Bank of England. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Zhuoshi; Spencer, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price discovery and trade fragmentation in a multi-market environment: Evidence from the MTS system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caporale, Guglielmo Maria; Girardi, Alessandro
This paper proposes new metrics for the process of price discovery on the main electronic trading platform for euro-denominated government securities. Analysing price data on daily transactions for 107 bonds over a period of 27 months, we find a greater degree of price leadership of the dominant market when our measures (as opposed to the traditional price discovery metrics) are used. We also present unambiguous evidence that a market's contribution to price discovery is crucially affected by the level of trading activity. The implications of these empirical findings are discussed in the light of the debate about the possible restructuring of the regulatory framework for the Treasury bond market in Europe. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caporale, Guglielmo Maria; Girardi, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Turkish bank efficiency: Bayesian estimation with undesirable outputs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Assaf, A. George; Matousek, Roman; Tsionas, Efthymios G.
This paper analyzes the productivity and efficiency of Turkish banks from 2002 to 2010. We obtained estimates of efficiency, productivity growth and efficiency growth using a Bayesian stochastic frontier approach and focused on accounting for Non-Performing Loans (NPLs) for use in our model. Specifically, we introduce NPLs as a bad output in an input distance function, and estimate a system of non-linear equations subject to endogeneity. We confirm that the productivity growth of Turkish banks was positive over the period of this study, which was mainly due to the improvement in technology, while efficiency growth continued to be negative over the same period. Methodologically, we also prove that not accounting for NPLs in estimating the frontier model might seriously distort the efficiency and productivity results. The study also provides measures of shadow prices for NPL and discusses the results in terms of several interesting trends in Turkish banking. Finally, the paper provides efficiency and productivity comparisons between domestic and foreign banks. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Assaf, A. George; Matousek, Roman; Tsionas, Efthymios G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The world price of jump and volatility risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Driessen, Joost; Maenhout, Pascal
We study international integration of markets for jump and volatility risk, using index option data for the main global markets. To explain the cross-section of expected option returns we focus on return-based multi-factor models. For each market separately, we provide evidence that volatility and jump risk are priced risk factors. There is little evidence, however, of global unconditional pricing of these risks. We show that UK and US option markets have become increasingly interrelated, and using conditional pricing models generates some evidence of international pricing. Finally, the benefits of diversifying jump and volatility risk internationally are substantial, but declining. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Driessen, Joost; Maenhout, Pascal</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge funds, CDOs and the financial crisis: An empirical investigation of the "Magnetar trade"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maehlmann, Thomas
The so called Magnetar trade (a kind of capital structure arbitrage on the US housing market, using CDS and synthetic CDOs, and exploiting rating-dependent mispricing of risk) has gained a high publicity due to a Pulitzer Prize awarded media story from two journalists of ProPublica (an online news outlet). The story essentially claimed that the mortgage investment strategy of the hedge fund Magnetar during the period between 2006 and mid 2007 was based on a desire to construct CDO deals with riskier assets so that they could place bets that portions of their own deals would fail. This paper provides several pieces of evidence in line with the argument that tranches from Magnetar-sponsored CDOs present overly risky investments. However, investors and rating agencies appear to have adjusted their required spread levels and ratings to reflect this higher riskiness, at least to some extent. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maehlmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure, executive compensation, and investment efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisdorfer, Assaf; Giaccotto, Carmelo; White, Reilly
This paper examines how the similarity between the executive compensation leverage ratio and the firm leverage ratio affects the quality of the firm's investment decisions. A larger leverage gap (i.e., a bigger difference between these two ratios) leads to more investment distortions. Managers with more debt-like compensation components tend to under-invest, whereas managers with larger equity-based compensation engage more in over-investment. Furthermore, investment distortion is likely to increase the equity (debt) value when compensation leverage is lower (higher) than firm leverage. These findings suggest that managers can deviate from an optimal investment policy to increase the value of their portfolio, and that a lower leverage gap can reduce agency costs. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eisdorfer, Assaf; Giaccotto, Carmelo; White, Reilly</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring time-varying financial market integration: An unobserved components approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Tino; Pozzi, Lorenzo
We measure the time-varying degree of world stock market integration of five developed countries (Germany, France, UK, US, and Japan) over the period 1970:1-2011:10. Time-varying financial market integration of each country is measured through the conditional variances of the country-specific and common international risk premiums in equity excess returns. The country-specific and common risk premiums and their conditional variances are estimated from a latent factor decomposition through the use of state space methods that allow for GARCH errors. Our empirical results suggest that stock market integration has increased over the period 1970:1-2011:10 in all countries but Japan. And while there is a structural increase in stock market integration in four out of five countries, all countries also exhibit several shorter periods of disintegration (reversals), i.e. periods in which country-specific shocks play a more dominant role. Hence, stock market integration is measured as a dynamic process that is fluctuating in the short run while gradually increasing in the long run. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Tino; Pozzi, Lorenzo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Islamic vs. conventional banking: Business model, efficiency and stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Demirguec-Kunt, Asli; Merrouche, Ouarda
How different are Islamic banks from conventional banks? Does the recent crisis justify a closer look at the Sharia-compliant business model for banking? When comparing conventional and Islamic banks, controlling for time-variant country-fixed effects, we find few significant differences in business orientation. There is evidence however, that Islamic banks are less cost-effective, but have a higher intermediation ratio, higher asset quality and are better capitalized. We also find large cross-country variation in the differences between conventional and Islamic banks as well as across Islamic banks of different sizes. Furthermore, we find that Islamic banks are better capitalized, have higher asset quality and are less likely to disintermediate during crises. The better stock performance of listed Islamic banks during the recent crisis is also due to their higher capitalization and better asset quality. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Demirguec-Kunt, Asli; Merrouche, Ouarda</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Staggered boards, corporate opacity and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duru, Augustine; Wang, Dechun; Zhao, Yijiang
We explore the effect of corporate opacity on the relation between staggered boards and firm value. We find that through mitigating takeover pressure, staggered boards become increasingly beneficial to firm value as opacity increases. In addition, we document that staggered boards reduce value only in transparent firms. Additional tests indicate that, as opacity increases, staggered boards bear an increasingly positive relation to research and development and CEO pay-performance sensitivity. Taken together, these results suggest that corporate opacity affects the value impact of takeover protection. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duru, Augustine; Wang, Dechun; Zhao, Yijiang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does foreign institutional ownership increase return volatility? Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhian; Du, Jinmin; Li, Donghui; Ouyang, Rui
This paper investigates the impact of foreign institutional ownership on firm-level stock return volatility in China, based on our study of a sample of 1458 firms between 1998 and 2008. The empirical results show that share ownership by foreign institutions (both financial and non-financial) increases firm-level stock return volatility, even after controlling for a complete ownership structure, firm size, turnover, and leverage, and correcting for potential endogeneity problems. However, the results also show that foreign individual shareholdings reduce volatility. Furthermore, we document a positive relationship between domestic shareholdings (individual, institutional, and governmental) and firm-level stock return volatility. Empirical results with interaction terms show that foreign institutional ownership increases firm-level return volatility by strengthening the positive impact of liquidity on volatility. The volatility reduction effect of foreign individual ownership is attenuated by government ownership suggests a poor governance environment as a result of the involvement of the Chinese government. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Zhian; Du, Jinmin; Li, Donghui; Ouyang, Rui</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International portfolio selection with exchange rate risk: A behavioural portfolio theory perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Chonghui; Ma, Yongkai; An, Yunbi
This paper analyzes international portfolio selection with exchange rate risk based on behavioural portfolio theory (BPT). We characterize the conditions under which the BPT problem with a single foreign market has an optimal solution, and show that the optimal portfolio contains the traditional mean-variance efficient portfolio without consideration of exchange rate risk, and an uncorrelated component constructed to hedge against exchange rate risk. We illustrate that the optimal portfolio must be mean-variance efficient with exchange rate risk, while the same is not true from the perspective of local investors unless certain conditions are satisfied. We further establish that international portfolio selection in the BPT with multiple foreign markets consists of two sequential decisions. Investors first select the optimal BPT portfolio in each market, overlooking covariances among markets, and then allocate funds across markets according to a specific rule to achieve mean-variance efficiency or to minimize the loss in efficiency. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Chonghui; Ma, Yongkai; An, Yunbi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic loan modification: An options-based response to strategic default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, Sanjiv R.; Meadows, Ray
This paper presents a parsimonious barrier model for the optimal principal reset in a loan modification, thereby maximizing the loan value to the lender bank and minimizing the likelihood of strategic foreclosure by the homeowner. Writing down the loan-to-value (LTV) ratio will reduce the present value of future payments on the loan, but will also reduce the probability of default, thereby saving foreclosure losses. The optimal trade-off of these two countervailing effects will pinpoint the optimal LTV at which the loan must be reset. We present a simple barrier option decomposition of the loan value that makes the optimization of LTV easy to implement. An extension of the model is shown to account for varying growth rate assumptions about house prices. The model in this paper specifically accounts for the homeowner's willingness to pay, and uses the framework to model shared-appreciation mortgages (SAMs). (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Das, Sanjiv R.; Meadows, Ray</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commonalities in investment strategy and the determinants of performance in mutual fund mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Namvar, Ethan; Phillips, Blake
This paper examines the determinants of cross-sectional variation in post-merger mutual fund performance. Mergers between funds with similar management objectives, as reflected by average portfolio book-to-market ratio, price-earnings ratio, beta and market capitalization values, outperform mergers between funds with dissimilar strategies. This superior performance transcends lower portfolio rebalancing costs which might be realized between merging funds which hold more assets in common. These results suggest that mutual fund mergers create collaborative benefits between funds with similar strategies. We also examine if fund governance structures influence the fund pairing process, testing if stronger fund oversight mitigates pairing mismatches. We find that less independent boards of trustees and boards with higher compensation are related to greater strategic mismatches between funds. These results suggest that more entrenched boards are more tolerant of fund mismatches which benefit the investment company, yet are not in investor's best interests. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Namvar, Ethan; Phillips, Blake</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of FDICIA internal controls on bank risk taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Justin Yiqiang; Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lobo, Gerald J.; Mathieu, Robert
The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act (FDICIA) of 1991 was designed, among other things, to introduce risk-based deposit insurance, increase capital requirements, and improve banks' internal controls. Of particular interest in this study are the requirements for annual audit and reporting of management's and auditor's assessment of the effectiveness of internal control for banks with $500 million or more in total assets (raised to $1 billion in 2005). We study the impact of these requirements on banks' risk-taking behavior prior to the recent financial crisis and the consequent implications for bank failure and financial trouble during the crisis period. Using a sample of 1138 banks, we provide evidence that banks required to comply with the FDICIA internal control requirements have lower risk taking in the pre-crisis period. Specifically, the volatility of net interest margin, the volatility of earnings, and Z score show less risk-taking behavior. Furthermore, these banks are less likely to experience failure and financial trouble during the crisis period. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jin, Justin Yiqiang; Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lobo, Gerald J.; Mathieu, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What determines corporate pension fund risk-taking strategy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>An, Heng; Huang, Zhaodan; Zhang, Ting
Corporate sponsors of defined benefit pension plans generally assume low investment risk when they have low funding ratios and high default risk, consistent with the risk management hypothesis. However, for financially distressed sponsors and sponsors that freeze, terminate, or convert defined benefit to defined contribution plans, the risk-shifting incentive (moral hazard) dominates. Pension fund risk-taking is also affected by labor unionization and sponsor incentives to maximize tax benefits, restore financial slack, and justify the accounting choices of pension assumptions. Sponsors shift toward an aggressive risk strategy when their pension plans emerge from underfunding, bankruptcy risk is reduced, or marginal tax rate decreases. Overall, we show that corporate sponsors adopt a dynamic risk-taking strategy in their pension fund investments. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>An, Heng; Huang, Zhaodan; Zhang, Ting</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial systemic risk: Taxation or regulation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masciandaro, Donato; Passarelli, Francesco
This paper describes financial systemic risk as a pollution issue. Free riding leads to excess risk production. This problem may be solved, at least partially, either by financial regulation or by taxation. From a normative viewpoint, taxation is superior in many respects. However, reality shows that financial regulation is adopted more frequently. This paper makes a positive, politico-economic argument. If the majority chooses regulation, the level is likely to be too harsh. If it chooses taxation, then the level is likely to be too low. Due to regressive effects, a tax on financial transactions receives low support from a majority of low polluting portfolio owners. The same kind of majority may strategically choose regulation in order to burden the minority with a larger share of the cost of reducing systemic risk. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Masciandaro, Donato; Passarelli, Francesco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fuzzy logic, trading uncertainty and technical trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gradojevic, Nikola; Gencay, Ramazan
From the market microstructure perspective, technical analysis can be profitable when informed traders make systematic mistakes or when uninformed traders have predictable impacts on price. However, chartists face a considerable degree of trading uncertainty because technical indicators such as moving averages are essentially imperfect filters with a nonzero phase shift. Consequently, technical trading may result in erroneous trading recommendations and substantial losses. This paper presents an uncertainty reduction approach based on fuzzy logic that addresses two problems related to the uncertainty embedded in technical trading strategies: market timing and order size. The results of our high-frequency exercises show that 'fuzzy technical indicators' dominate standard moving average technical indicators and filter rules for the Euro-US dollar (EUR-USD) exchange rates, especially on high-volatility days. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gradojevic, Nikola; Gencay, Ramazan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of sovereign rating actions on bank ratings in emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williams, Gwion; Alsakka, Rasha; ap Gwilym, Owain
This paper analyses the effects of sovereign rating actions on the credit ratings of banks in emerging markets, using a sample from three global rating agencies across 54 countries for 1999-2009. Despite widespread attention to sovereign ratings and bank ratings, no previous study has investigated the link in this manner. We find that sovereign rating upgrades (downgrades) have strong effects on bank rating upgrades (downgrades). The impact of sovereign watch status on bank rating actions is much weaker and often insignificant. The sensitivity of banks' ratings to sovereign rating actions is affected by the countries' economic and financial freedom and by macroeconomic conditions. Ratings of banks with different ownership structures are all influenced strongly by the sovereign rating, with some variation depending on the countries' characteristics. Emerging market bank ratings are less likely to follow sovereign rating downgrades during the recent financial crisis period. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Williams, Gwion; Alsakka, Rasha; ap Gwilym, Owain</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multinational banking and the international transmission of financial shocks: Evidence from foreign bank subsidiaries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jeon, Bang Nam; Olivero, Maria Pia; Wu, Ji
Using bank-level data on 368 foreign subsidiaries of 68 multinational banks in 47 emerging economies during 1994-2008, we present consistent evidence that internal capital markets in multinational banking contribute to the transmission of financial shocks from parent banks to foreign subsidiaries. We find that internal capital markets transmit favorable and adverse shocks by affecting subsidiaries' reliance on their own internal funds for lending. We also find that the transmission of financial shocks varies across types of shocks; is strongest among subsidiaries in Central and Eastern Europe, followed by Asia and Latin America; is global rather than regional; and becomes more conspicuous in recent years. We also explore various conditions under which the international transmission of financial shocks via internal capital markets in multinational banking is stronger, including the subsidiaries' reliance on funds from their parent bank, the subsidiaries' entry mode, and the capital account openness and banking market structure in host countries. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jeon, Bang Nam; Olivero, Maria Pia; Wu, Ji</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit spread interdependencies of European states and banks during the financial crisis (vol 36, pg 3444, 2012)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alter, Adrian; Schueler, Yves S.
nan</description><author>Alter, Adrian; Schueler, Yves S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign currency borrowing by small firms in emerging markets: When domestic banks intermediate dollars</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mora, Nada; Neaime, Simon; Aintablian, Sebouh
This paper investigates what induces small firms in an emerging market economy to borrow dollar credit from domestic banks. Our data are from a unique survey of firms in Lebanon. The findings complement studies of large firms with foreign currency loans from foreign lenders. Exporters, naturally hedged against currency risk, are more likely to incur dollar debt. Firms also partly hedge themselves by passing currency risk to customers and suppliers. Less opaque firms with easily verifiable collateral and higher net worth are more likely to access dollar credit. Firms reliant on formal financing (banks and supplier credit) are more likely to contract dollar debt than firms reliant on informal financing (family, friends and moneylenders). Bank relationships, however, do not increase the dollar debt likelihood. And finally, profitable firms are less likely to have dollar debt. Information frictions and limited collateral, therefore, constrain dollar credit even when it is intermediated domestically. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mora, Nada; Neaime, Simon; Aintablian, Sebouh</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The expectations hypothesis: New hope or illusory support?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jitmaneeroj, Boonlert; Wood, Andrew
Recent studies of the expectations hypothesis of the term structure (EHTS) find evidence in favor of the EHTS using post 1980s US data. This has been attributed to the relative macro stability of this period and greater market efficiency. Using a panel of forecasts for 3-month interest rates for ten countries we test separately for EHTS and rational expectations. Assuming rational expectations holds we find support for the EHTS is illusory due to an off-setting time-varying term premia and non-rational expectations. Previous forecast-based studies suggest biased expectations tend to reinforce the effect of a time varying term premium. This change can be understood in the context of Fama's (2006) argument that markets tend to underestimate future spot rates during periods of long-run increases and overestimate during declines. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jitmaneeroj, Boonlert; Wood, Andrew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting the size premium over different time horizons</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zakamulin, Valeriy
In this paper, we provide evidence that the small stock premium is predictable both in-sample and out-of-sample through the use of a set of lagged macroeconomic variables. We find that it is possible to forecast the size premium over time horizons that range from one month to one year. We demonstrate that the predictability of the size premium allows a portfolio manager to generate an economically and statistically significant active alpha. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zakamulin, Valeriy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inference in asset pricing models with a low-variance factor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shang, Hua
This paper concerns with the effects of including a low-variance factor in an asset pricing model. When a low-variance factor is present, the commonly applied Fama-MacBeth two-pass regression procedure is very likely to yield misleading results. Local asymptotic analysis and simulation evidence indicate that the risk premiums corresponding to all factors are very likely to be unreliably estimated. Moreover, t-and F-statistics are less likely to detect whether the risk premiums are significantly different from zero. We recommend Kleibergen's (2009) FAR statistic when there is a low-variance factor included in an asset pricing model. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shang, Hua</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reject inference in consumer credit scoring with nonignorable missing data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buecker, Michael; van Kampen, Maarten; Kraemer, Walter
We generalize an empirical likelihood approach to deal with missing data to a model of consumer credit scoring. An application to recent consumer credit data shows that our procedure yields parameter estimates which are significantly different (both statistically and economically) from the case where customers who were refused credit are ignored. This has obvious implications for commercial banks as it shows that refused customers should not be ignored when developing scorecards for the retail business. We also show that forecasts of defaults derived from the method proposed in this paper improve upon the standard ones when refused customers do not enter the estimation data set. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buecker, Michael; van Kampen, Maarten; Kraemer, Walter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal capital markets and the partial adjustment of leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fier, Stephen G.; McCullough, Kathleen A.; Carson, James M.
Prior literature provides support both for the existence of target capital structures and internal capital markets (ICM). The issue of whether firms use internal capital markets to reduce deviations from target capital structures, however, has yet to be examined. We provide the first empirical evidence of a link between deviations from target leverage and ICM activity. Based on data that allow us to trace intragroup capital market transactions for property-casualty insurers, our findings provide the first joint evidence that affiliated insurance companies have target leverage ratios and that ICM activity is used to manage deviations from target leverage. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fier, Stephen G.; McCullough, Kathleen A.; Carson, James M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing securities with multiple risks: A case of exchangeable debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mateti, Ravi S.; Hegde, Shantaram P.; Puri, Tribhuvan
Building on the work of Das and Sundaram (2007), we develop a widely applicable model to price securities subject to interest rate, equity, and default risks and use it to price exchangeable bonds. The extension features a trivariate recombining lattice instead of the original model's bivariate recombining lattice. We also show how to estimate some critical non-observable inputs to implement the model by using current market data so that the model's prices reflect current market information. We test the model on a sample of exchangeable bonds to determine the model's empirical performance. Besides exchangeable bonds, we can also use the model to price securities such as reverse exchangeable bonds, bonds exchangeable to indexes, and bonds exchangeable to commodities. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mateti, Ravi S.; Hegde, Shantaram P.; Puri, Tribhuvan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock return volatility, operating performance and stock returns: International evidence on drivers of the 'low volatility' anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dutt, Tanuj; Humphery-Jenner, Mark
This study highlights the link between stock return volatility, operating performance, and stock returns. Prior studies suggest that there is a 'low volatility' anomaly, where firms with a low stock return volatility out-perform firms with a high stock return volatility. This paper confirms that low volatility stocks earn higher returns than high volatility stocks in emerging markets and developed markets outside of North America. We also show that low volatility stocks have higher operating returns and this might explain why low volatility stocks earn higher stock returns. These results provide a partial explanation for the 'low volatility effect' that is independent from the existence of market anomalies or per se inefficiencies that might otherwise drive a low volatility effect. We emphasize the importance of controlling for stock return volatility when analyzing operating performance and stock performance. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dutt, Tanuj; Humphery-Jenner, Mark</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choosing how to pay: The influence of foreign backgrounds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kosse, Anneke; Jansen, David-Jan
Is having a foreign background a relevant factor in choosing between payment instruments in consumer point-of-sale transactions after migration? We analyze this question using a unique diary survey in which both participants with a Dutch and a foreign background documented their daily purchases. We present several pieces of evidence suggesting that foreign backgrounds still influence the choice between payment instruments after migration to the Netherlands. For instance, we find that first-generation migrants from a number of countries that can be seen as cash-oriented are more likely to use cash in the Netherlands. At the same time, second-generation migrants have similar payment habits as individuals with a Dutch background. This finding suggests that payment behavior is not passed on between generations, but affected by host country payment habits. Finally, we suggest that, in this context, special information campaigns to increase debit card usage will not have clear net social benefits. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kosse, Anneke; Jansen, David-Jan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CVaR sensitivity with respect to tail thickness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoyanov, Stoyan V.; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Fabozzi, Frank J.
The sensitivity of a risk measure with respect to the parameters of the hypothesized distribution is a useful tool in investigating the impact of marginal rebalancing decisions on the portfolio return distribution and also in the analysis of the asymptotic variability of the risk estimator. We calculate the relative importance of the conditional value-at-risk (CVaR) sensitivity with respect to tail thickness and scale of the portfolio return distribution in the case of regularly varying tails and in the case of exponential and faster-than-exponential decay. We discuss the implications for asset return modeling and the asymptotic variability of the risk estimator. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stoyanov, Stoyan V.; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A leverage ratio rule for capital adequacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jarrow, Robert
This paper studies the economic foundations for maximum leverage ratio capital adequacy rules. The paper makes three contributions to the literature. First, we show how to determine the maximum leverage ratio such that the probability of insolvency is less than some predetermined quantity. Two, we show that a leverage ratio rule controls for the same risks as does a Value-at-Risk (VaR) capital adequacy rule. Third, we argue that leverage ratio rules are better than VaR rules because they are more intuitive and easier to compare across firms. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real exchange rate adjustment in European transition countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maican, Florin G.; Sweeney, Richard J.
In single-equation tests, real exchange rates show mean reversion for nine of 10 Central and Eastern European transition countries for the period January 1993 to December 2005. Because of the shift from controlled to market economies and accompanying crises, failed policy regimes and changes in exchange rate regimes, unit root tests for transition countries often require allowance for structural changes. Accounting for structural breaks gives substantially faster mean-reversion speeds than those found for major industrialized countries. These fast adjustment speeds are plausible: Transition countries had perhaps 10 years to make unprecedented adjustments required for accession to the European Union. A number of papers have applied non-linear models to the Central and Eastern European countries. This paper investigates four non-linear models and compares them with piece-wise linear break models. The break models appear superior in detecting mean reversion for the Central and Eastern European transition countries. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maican, Florin G.; Sweeney, Richard J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of technical defaults on dividend policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bulan, Laarni; Hull, Tyler
This paper examines how loan covenant violations impact firm dividend policy. Using contract-level loan data for nonfinancial firms in the US, this study provides evidence that the occurrence of a covenant violation significantly increases the likelihood of a dividend reduction in the subsequent quarter. Moreover, we show that the degree of creditor-shareholder conflict and firm financial constraints are important determinants of dividend cuts upon technical default. Additionally, this paper finds the tendency of dividend cuts upon technical default weakened after the repeal of the Glass-Steagall Act. These findings suggest that loan covenants serve a critical role in mitigating creditor-shareholder conflicts. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bulan, Laarni; Hull, Tyler</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The interest group theory of financial development: Evidence from regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hauner, David; Prati, Alessandro; Bircan, Cagatay
We use a new dataset of de jure measures of trade, capital account, product market, and domestic financial regulation for 91 countries from 1973 to 2005 to test Rajan and Zingales's (2003) interest group theory of financial development. In line with the theory, we find strong evidence that trade liberalization is a leading indicator of domestic financial liberalization. This result is robust to the use of different data frequencies (annual, 5-year intervals), estimation methods (OLS, 2SLS, system GMM) and a check for non-linear effects. However, in contrast to the theory, we do not find consistent evidence of an effect of capital account liberalization. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hauner, David; Prati, Alessandro; Bircan, Cagatay</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are banks too big to fail or too big to save? International evidence from equity prices and CDS spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Huizinga, Harry
Deteriorating public finances around the world raise doubts about countries' abilities to bail out their largest banks. For an international sample of banks, this paper investigates the impact of bank size and government deficits on bank stock prices and CDS spreads. We find that a bank's market-to-book value is negatively related to the size of its liabilities-to-GDP ratio, especially in countries running large public deficits. CDS spreads appear to decrease with stronger public finances. These results suggest that systemically important banks can increase their value by downsizing or splitting up, especially if they are located in countries with weak public finances. We document that banks' average liabilities-to-GDP ratio reached a peak in 2007 before a significant drop in 2008, which could reflect these private incentives to downsize. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Huizinga, Harry</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Management quality and the cost of debt: Does management matter to lenders?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rahaman, Mohammad M.; Al Zaman, Ashraf
This paper investigates the effect of organizational capital, typified by various management practices within a firm, on the cost of external debt financing. Using a sample of medium-sized manufacturing firms in the US, we find that better management practices enhance a firm's external financing capacity by lowering the firm's cost of bank loans. We do not find any evidence that the lower loan cost of a high-quality-management firm is associated with more restrictive non-price contract terms such as greater collateral requirements and stricter covenants. These results suggest that banks explicitly take into account the risk arising from poor management practices when pricing and designing debt contracts. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rahaman, Mohammad M.; Al Zaman, Ashraf</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the role of the estimation error in prediction of expected shortfall</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lonnbark, Carl
In the estimation of risk measures such as Value at Risk and Expected shortfall relatively short estimation windows are typically used rendering the estimation error a possibly non-negligible component. In this paper we build upon previous results for the Value at Risk and discuss how the estimation error comes into play for the Expected Shortfall. We identify two important aspects where it may be of importance. On the one hand there is in the evaluation of predictors of the measure. On the other there is in the interpretation and communication of it. We illustrate magnitudes numerically and emphasize the practical importance of the latter aspect in an empirical application with stock market index data. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lonnbark, Carl</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can position limits restrain 'rogue' trading?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>ap Gwilym, Rhys; Ebrahim, M. Shahid
This paper studies the imposition of position limits on commodity futures from the perspective of curbing excessive speculation and thus manipulation. We present a simple general equilibrium model in a static rational expectations framework and agent heterogeneity to illustrate that excessive speculation serves to enrich other agents at the expense of the speculator. Position limits, on the contrary, are not only superfluous, but also counter-productive, as they exacerbate market power and lead to a deterioration in efficiency. Position limits not only reduce social welfare but also cannot restrain market manipulation. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>ap Gwilym, Rhys; Ebrahim, M. Shahid</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank stability and managerial compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Gang; Elyasiani, Elyas
We investigate the relationship between insolvency risk and executive compensation for BHCs over the 1992-2008 period. We employ CEO compensation sensitivity to risk (vega) and pay-share inequality between the CEO and other executives as measures of compensation and employ a system model to account for the endogeneity problem between vega and risk. Five main results are obtained. First, CEO compensation sensitivity to risk of BHCs has risen in response to deregulation to resemble those of the industrial firms. Second, higher vegas lead to greater bank instability. Third, the association between bank stability and managerial compensation is bi-directional; higher vegas induce greater risk and vice versa. Fourth, BHCs in the next to the largest-size group increase CEO vegas the most and have the strongest potential to create instability. Fifth, increased pay-share inequality has effects opposite to those of the increase in vega; greater pay-share inequality is associated with greater stability. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bai, Gang; Elyasiani, Elyas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk and diversification across European banks and insurers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Slijkerman, Jan Frederik; Schoenmaker, Dirk; de Vries, Casper G.
The mutual and cross company exposures to fat-tail distributed risks determine the potential impact of a financial crisis on banks and insurers. We examine the systemic interdependencies within and across the European banking and insurance sectors during times of stress by means of extreme value analysis. While insurers exhibit a slightly higher interdependency in comparison with banks, the interdependency across the two sectors turns out to be considerably lower. This suggests that downside risk can be lowered through financial conglomeration. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Slijkerman, Jan Frederik; Schoenmaker, Dirk; de Vries, Casper G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank capital buffer and portfolio risk: The influence of business cycle and revenue diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shim, Jeungbo
The relationship between macroeconomic developments and bank capital buffer and portfolio risk adjustments is relevant to assess the efficacy of newly created countercyclical buffer requirements. Using the U.S. bank holding company data over the period 1992:Q1-2011:Q3, we find a negative relationship between the business cycle and capital buffer. Our results offer some support for the Basel III agreements that countercyclical capital buffer in the banking sector is necessary to help the performance of the real economy during recessions. We find a robust evidence of inverse relationship between business cycle and bank default risk. Our analysis provides evidence of diversification benefits. The probability of insolvency risk decreases for diversified banks and banks with high revenue diversity achieve capital savings. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shim, Jeungbo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic loan defaults and coordination: An experimental analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trautmann, Stefan T.; Vlahu, Razvan
This paper experimentally studies the impact of bank and borrower fundamentals on loan repayment. We find that solvent borrowers are more likely to default strategically when the bank's expected strength is low, although loan repayment is a Pareto dominant Nash equilibrium. Borrowers are also less likely to repay when other borrowers' expected repayment capacity is low, regardless of banks' fundamentals. We show that changes in expectations about bank and borrower fundamentals change the risk dominance properties of the borrowers' coordination problem, and that these changes subsequently explain strategic defaults. For the individual borrower, loss aversion and negative past experiences reduce repayment, suggesting that bank failure can be contagious in times of distress. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Trautmann, Stefan T.; Vlahu, Razvan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of banks around the receipt and repayment of TARP funds: Over-achievers versus under-achievers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornett, Marcia Millon; Li, Lei; Tehranian, Hassan
In this paper, we look at how the pre-crisis health of banks is related to the probability of receiving and repaying TARP capital. We find that financial performance characteristics that are related to the probability of receiving TARP funds differ for the healthiest ("over-achiever") versus the least healthy ("under-achiever") banks. We find that TARP under-achievers have some, but not consistent, weaknesses in income production. These banks also are experiencing liquidity issues as customers, shut out of public debt markets, get bank loans through drawdowns of loan commitments. Unlike TARP under-achievers, TARP over-achievers' loans are performing well. Yet, liquidity issues (from low levels of liquid assets and core deposits and drawdowns of loan commitments) hurt the abilities of these banks to continue their lending. Differences between under-achiever and over-achiever banks are also found for repayment and deadbeat TARP banks. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cornett, Marcia Millon; Li, Lei; Tehranian, Hassan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital inflows and asset prices: Evidence from emerging Asia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tillmann, Peter
The withdrawal of foreign capital from emerging countries at the height of the recent financial crisis and its quick return sparked a debate about the impact of capital flow surges on asset markets. This paper addresses the response of property prices to an inflow of foreign capital. For that purpose we estimate a panel VAR on a set of Asian emerging market economies, for which the waves of inflows were particularly pronounced, and identify capital inflow shocks based on sign restrictions. Our results suggest that capital inflow shocks have a significant effect on the appreciation of house prices and equity prices. Capital inflow shocks account for - roughly - twice the portion of overall house price changes they explain in OECD countries. We also address cross-country differences in the house price responses to shocks, which are most likely due to differences in the monetary policy response to capital inflows. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tillmann, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The investment strategies of publicly sponsored venture capital funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buzzacchi, Luigi; Scellato, Giuseppe; Ughetto, Elisa
This paper investigates the effects of public ownership on the investment strategy of hybrid VC funds. We exploit a unique dataset containing data for all of the venture capital funds in Europe that received financial support from the European Investment Fund (EIF) during the years 1998-2007. The dataset includes 179 VC funds that invested in 2482 companies. We find that the level of public ownership shows a weak negative correlation with the likelihood of observing a write-off and that a higher public share is associated with a longer duration for the investment. The latter effect is more relevant for those investments that generate intermediate financial returns. The results are robust to the introduction of controls at the target firm level and for financial market conditions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buzzacchi, Luigi; Scellato, Giuseppe; Ughetto, Elisa</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The structure and degree of dependence: A quantile regression approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baur, Dirk G.
The copula function defines the degree of dependence and the structure of dependence. This paper proposes an alternative framework to decompose the dependence using quantile regression. We demonstrate that the methodology provides a detailed picture of dependence including asymmetric and non-linear relationships. In addition, changes in the degree or structure of dependence can be modeled and tested for each quantile of the distribution. The empirical part applies the framework to three different sets of financial time-series and demonstrates substantial differences in dependence patterns among asset classes and through time. The analysis of 54 global equity markets shows that detailed information about the structure of dependence is crucial to adequately assess the benefits of diversification in normal times and crisis times. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baur, Dirk G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating non-linear serial and cross-interdependence between financial assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Righi, Marcelo Brutti; Ceretta, Paulo Sergio
This paper proposes an approach based on copula families to determine shape and magnitude of non-linear serial and cross-interdependence between returns and volatilities of financial assets. It is evident the predominance of the student's t copula in returns relationships. Association in tails is generally larger than the absolute. There is a fast decrease in association along time, but even after 5 days, there is still dependence between returns. For volatilities, Joe copula predominates in estimated bivariate relationships fit. Clayton copula rotated 180 degrees (survival), Gumbel, BB6 and BB8 copulas also fit some relationships. The magnitude of lagged associations is larger for risks than returns. Persistence in the dependences is very high, and decreases very little after the first lag. The tail dependence has larger values than the absolute in most relationships. We present a practical application of the proposed approach, based on optimal investment allocation and risk prediction. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Righi, Marcelo Brutti; Ceretta, Paulo Sergio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan managers' trust and credit access for SMEs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moro, Andrea; Fink, Matthias
Research on relationship lending pays only marginal attention to the role of loan managers' trust in the managers of SMEs. Trust literature suggests that trust reduces agency costs. Thus, trust is expected to be positively related to the amount of short-term credit granted and negatively related to SMEs' risk of being credit constrained. Results from six banks characterised by a German culture and three banks characterised by an Italian culture suggest that this is indeed the case: SMEs that enjoy a high level of trust from loan managers obtain more credit and are less credit constrained. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moro, Andrea; Fink, Matthias</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US presidential elections and implied volatility: The role of political uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goodell, John W.; Vahamaa, Sami
This paper focuses on the effects of political uncertainty and the political process on implied stock market volatility during US presidential election cycles. Using monthly Iowa Electronic Markets data over five elections, we document that stock market uncertainty, as measured by the VIX volatility index, increases along with positive changes in the probability of success of the eventual winner. The association between implied volatility and the election probability of the eventual winner is positive even after controlling for changes in overall election uncertainty. These findings indicate that the presidential election process engenders market anxiety as investors form and revise their expectations regarding future macroeconomic policy. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goodell, John W.; Vahamaa, Sami</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining share price disparity with parameter uncertainty: Evidence from Chinese A- and H-shares</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Tsz-Kin; Hui, Cho-Hoi; Li, Ka-Fai
The price disparity between the A- and H-share markets for dual-listed firms in China is one of the most intriguing puzzles in the Mainland and Hong Kong financial markets. In this paper, we revisit this price disparity puzzle using the channel of parameter uncertainty. In the presence of information asymmetry and market segmentation, investors have different views on a firm's asset volatility, and hence different valuations of the same reference firm. We estimate a structural model for equity pricing using a Bayesian approach, in which the uncertainty of investor model parameters is represented by the posterior standard deviation of the firm's asset volatility. Our regression analysis shows that in addition to other market-based and macro factors, parameter uncertainty explains variations in price disparity. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, Tsz-Kin; Hui, Cho-Hoi; Li, Ka-Fai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection and cash holdings: Evidence from US cross-listing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Ying; Elkinawy, Susan; Jain, Pankaj K.
This paper examines (i) whether the level of firms' cash holdings differ depending on the strength of investor protection, (ii) whether excess cash holdings are valued more with better investor protection, and (iii) whether cross-listed firms that improve investor protection through "bonding" hold relatively more cash than non-cross-listed firms. We analyze 1405 ADR firms and their corresponding matched firms from 39 different countries and document that ADR firms have significantly higher cash holdings relative to their non-cross-listed peers, especially in recent years. The increase in cash holdings is much higher for emerging market firms because of their transition from particularly poor home country investor protection and accounting standards before cross-listing to much higher standards after cross-listing. In addition, firms with level III ADR listing, which represents the strongest investor protection, have higher cash holdings relative to other types of ADR firms. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Ying; Elkinawy, Susan; Jain, Pankaj K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How cross-listings from an emerging economy affect the host market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Qian; Tong, Wilson H. S.; Zhang, Xin
We study the impact of mainland Chinese listings in Hong Kong on the quality and development of the Hong Kong equity market. At the macro-level, we find that the increasing presence of mainland Chinese stocks in Hong Kong increases the size, trading volume, and its link with the China and world markets but reduces the overall volatility of the Hong Kong stock market. At the firm level, the increase affects the market quality, resulting in lower turnover rate, higher Amihud illiquidity ratio, and higher spread for non-mainland Chinese firms. Furthermore, such an increase in presence causes Hong Kong stocks to move in a more synchronized way and reduces these firms investment sensitivity to stock price movement, implying deterioration in the information environment. As a whole, the increasing presence of Chinese companies in Hong Kong brings benefits to the Hong Kong market, yet not without cost. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Qian; Tong, Wilson H. S.; Zhang, Xin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information immobility, industry concentration, and institutional investors' performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fedenia, Mark; Shafer, Sherrill; Skiba, Hilla
This paper examines foreign institutional investors' portfolio allocation and performance in US securities. We test how information immobility, proxied by information barriers between the investors' home markets and the US, influences portfolio strategies. Consistent with theoretical predictions, foreign institutional investors' total investment in the US is negatively related to information immobility. Similarly, information immobility is a significant driver of portfolio under-diversification across industries. Industry concentration has declined over time, consistent with declining search costs. Industry-concentrated portfolios outperform more diversified portfolios for both foreign and US institutional investors. Concentration especially helps institutional investors with the easiest access to information. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fedenia, Mark; Shafer, Sherrill; Skiba, Hilla</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring systemic importance of financial institutions: An extreme value theory approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gravelle, Toni; Li, Fuchun
This paper proposes a set of market-based measures on the systemic importance of a financial institution or a group of financial institutions, each designed to capture different aspects of systemic importance of financial institutions. Multivariate extreme value theory approach is used to estimate these measures. Using six big Canadian banks as the proxy for Canadian banking sector, we apply these measures to identify systemically important banks in Canadian banking sector and major risk contributors from international financial institutions to Canadian banking sector. The empirical evidence reveals that (i) the top three banks, RBC Financial Group, TD Bank Financial Group, and Scotiabank, are more systemically important than other banks, while we also find that the size of a financial institution should not be considered as a proxy of systemic importance; (ii) compared to the European and Asian banks, the crashes of the U.S. banks, on average, are the most damaging to Canadian banking sector, while the risk contribution to the Canadian banking sector from Asian banks is quite lower than that from banks in the U.S. and euro area; (iii) the risk contribution to Canadian banking sector exhibits "home bias", that is, cross-country risk contribution tends to be smaller than domestic risk contribution. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gravelle, Toni; Li, Fuchun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of institutional investors in public-to-private transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bajo, Emanuele; Barbi, Massimiliano; Bigelli, Marco; Hillier, David
In Italy, as in many other European countries, listed firms will normally go dark through controlling owner-initiated tender offers. We find that institutional investors play a central role in the bid process and can protect minority shareholders from being frozen out in the bid. Specifically, tender offers are less likely to succeed when a firm has institutional investors in its ownership structure. When public-to-private offers are accepted, bid premiums are significantly greater if a financial institution (particularly when it is foreign, independent or activist) has a stake in the firm. We explore the effect of a number of hitherto unexplored factors on the takeover premium and find that shareholder agreements facilitate public-to-private acquisitions. Other factors, such as a threat to merge the target if the bid fails, or external validation of the offer price, have no impact on either the likelihood of delisting or the premium paid by the bidder. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bajo, Emanuele; Barbi, Massimiliano; Bigelli, Marco; Hillier, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The efficacy of regulatory intervention: Evidence from the distribution of informed option trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Ronald C.; Reeb, David M.; Zhang, Yuzhao; Zhao, Wanli
A substantive body of equity-market academic research documents an extensive range of costs arising from the SEC's October 2000 adoption of strictures on selective disclosure and insider trading; suggesting an unusual outcome, specifically, an increase in informed trading. We investigate the efficacy of the SEC's regulations by examining informed trading in an attractive setting for exploiting private information; the options market. Using data on the S&amp;P 1500 industrial firms, our analysis indicates that about 38% of firms exhibited symptoms of informed option trading prior to regulatory intervention. After regulatory intervention, we observe that only 19% of firms show symptoms of informed trading. In additional testing of ADR firms - explicitly exempt from complying with Reg FD, we find no evidence of a change in informed option trading from pre- to post-regulation; suggesting that the SEC's strictures on US firms led a to a significant reduction in informed option trading. Notably, our proxies for large shareholder and financial analyst access are associated with the largest decreases in informed option trading. In developing a unique measure of informed trading based on option market data, we provide evidence on the efficacy of security regulation in limiting informed trading. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anderson, Ronald C.; Reeb, David M.; Zhang, Yuzhao; Zhao, Wanli</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the basis risk of index-linked hedging strategies using multivariate extreme value theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kellner, Ralf; Gatzert, Nadine
This paper studies the empirical quantification of basis risk in the context of index-linked hedging strategies. Basis risk refers to the risk of non-payment of the index-linked instrument, given that the hedger's loss exceeds some critical level. The quantification of such risk measures from empirical data can be done in various ways and requires special consideration of the dependence structure between the index and the company's losses as well as the estimation of the tails of a distribution. In this context, previous literature shows that extreme value theory can be superior to traditional methods with respect to estimating quantile risk measures such as the value at risk. Thus, the aim of this paper is to conduct an empirical analysis of basis risk using multivariate extreme value theory and extreme value copulas to estimate the underlying risk processes and their dependence structure in order to obtain a more adequate picture of basis risk associated with index-linked hedging strategies. Our results emphasize that the application of extreme value theory leads to better fits of the tails of the marginal distributions in the considered stock price sample and that traditional methods in regard to estimating marginal distributions tend to overestimate basis risk, while basis risk can in contrast be higher when taking into account extreme value copulas. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kellner, Ralf; Gatzert, Nadine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding merger incentives and outcomes in the US mutual fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Minjung
This paper examines the incentives of acquirers and targets in the merger market. Using data on acquisitions among mutual fund management companies from 1991 to 2004, I estimate a two-sided matching model of the merger market jointly with equations representing merger outcomes. According to the empirical investigation, although the desire to achieve a sufficient scale to attract investors is a key driver for mergers, some mergers seem to be driven by objectives other than shareholder value maximization. I find that companies that are potentially prone to misaligned incentives between owners and managers are more acquisitive than others, yet have significantly worse post-merger operating performance. I also find that these acquirers, despite their higher willingness to pay for targets, are not any more likely to match with high-quality targets, potentially due to targets' incentive to avoid bad organizations. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Park, Minjung</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting the return distribution using high-frequency volatility measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hua, Jian; Manzan, Sebastiano
The aim of this paper is to forecast (out-of-sample) the distribution of financial returns based on realized volatility measures constructed from high-frequency returns. We adopt a semi-parametric model for the distribution by assuming that the return quantiles depend on the realized measures and evaluate the distribution, quantile and interval forecasts of the quantile model in comparison to a benchmark GARCH model. The results suggest that the model outperforms an asymmetric GARCH specification when applied to the S&amp;P 500 futures returns, in particular on the right tail of the distribution. However, the model provides similar accuracy to a GARCH (1,1) model when the 30-year Treasury bond futures return is considered. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hua, Jian; Manzan, Sebastiano</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-term hedge fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Slavutskaya, Anna
Hedge fund returns are often explained using linear factor models such as Fung and Hsieh (2004). However, since most hedge funds live only for 3 years, these linear regressions are subject to over-parameterization. I improve the out-of-sample accuracy of the linear factor model by combining cross-sectional and time series information for groups of hedge funds with similar investment strategies. The additional cross-sectional information allows more accurate estimates of risk exposures. I also propose a trading strategy based on this methodology for extracting substantially larger risk-adjusted returns. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Slavutskaya, Anna</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>VIX option pricing and CBOE VIX Term Structure: A new methodology for volatility derivatives valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Yueh-Neng
This study integrates CBOE VIX Term Structure and VIX futures to simplify VIX option pricing in multifactor models. Exponential and hump volatility functions with one- to three-factor models of the VIX evolution are used to examine their pricing for VIX options across strikes and maturities. The results show that using exponential volatility functions presents an effective choice as pricing models for VIX calls, whereas hump volatility functions provide efficient out-of-sample valuation for most VIX puts, in particular with deep in-the-money and deep out-of-the-money. Pricing errors for calls can be further reduced with a two-factor model. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Yueh-Neng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markets, financial stability and governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-listing and pricing efficiency: The informational and anchoring role played by the reference price</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Eric C.; Luo, Yan; Ren, Jinjuan
When a firm cross-lists its shares in segmented markets, the price of the first issued share, as a reference, plays both an informational and anchoring role in pricing the second issued share. We develop a model illustrating the dual-role. Empirically, we examine a group of Chinese firms that first issue foreign shares and then domestic A-shares, for which the anchoring effect adds to the A-share underpricing. Consistent with the model predictions, we find that the A-share underpricing is positively related to the difference in costs of capital in the two segmented markets, and that this positive association is weaker when participants are less likely to resort to the anchoring heuristic and when the A-share valuation involves less uncertainty. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Eric C.; Luo, Yan; Ren, Jinjuan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing innovations in consumption growth: A re-evaluation of the recursive utility model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xiao, Yuchao; Faff, Robert; Gharghori, Philip; Min, Byoung-Kyu
We re-evaluate the cross-sectional asset pricing implications of the recursive utility function of Epstein and Zin (1989, 1991), using innovations in future consumption growth in our tests. Our empirical specification helps explain the size, value and momentum effects. Specifically, we find that (i) the beta associated with news about consumption growth has a systematic pattern: beta decreases along the size dimension and increases along the book-to-market and momentum dimensions, (ii) innovation in consumption growth is significantly priced in asset returns using both the Fama and MacBeth (1973) and the stochastic discount factor approaches, and (iii) the model performs better than both the CAPM and Fama-French model. (C) 2012 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Xiao, Yuchao; Faff, Robert; Gharghori, Philip; Min, Byoung-Kyu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The components of the illiquidity premium: An empirical analysis of US stocks 1927-2010</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hagstromer, Bjorn; Hansson, Bjorn; Nilsson, Birger
This paper implements a conditional version of the liquidity adjusted CAPM (LCAPM). The conditional LCAPM allows for a time-varying decomposition of the total illiquidity premium into a level component and three risk components. The estimated average annual total illiquidity premium for US stocks 19272010 is 1.74-2.08%, which is substantially lower than in most previous studies. The contributions from illiquidity level and illiquidity risk are 1.25-1.28% and 0.46-0.83%, respectively. Of the three illiquidity risk components, risk related to the hedging of wealth shocks is the most important, while commonality risk is the least important. The illiquidity premia are clearly time-varying, with peaks in downturns and crises, but with no general tendency to decrease over time. The level premium and the risk premium are significantly positively correlated, at around 0.35; indicating that in periods of turbulence both illiquidity cost and illiquidity risk premia tend to be high. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hagstromer, Bjorn; Hansson, Bjorn; Nilsson, Birger</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reprint of: Stock salience and the asymmetric market effect of consumer sentiment news (Reprinted from Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, vol 36, pg 3289-3301, 2012)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhtar, Shumi; Faff, Robert; Oliver, Barry; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
We document asymmetric announcement effects of consumer sentiment news on United States stock and stock futures markets. While a negative market effect occurs upon the release of bad sentiment news, there is no market reaction for the counterpart good news. This supports the "negativity effect" hypothesis. Notably, this effect seems most likely to occur in salient stocks, which is consistent with the availability heuristic. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akhtar, Shumi; Faff, Robert; Oliver, Barry; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effectiveness of position limits: Evidence from the foreign exchange futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Ya-Kai; Chen, Yu-Lun; Chou, Robin K.; Gau, Yin-Feng
This study considers the effects of the relative size of hedger and speculator open interests and the potential impact of implementing position limits on the price discovery process in both JPY-USD and EUR-USD futures markets. Hedging trading exerts a negative impact, regardless of its size, on price discovery in futures markets. Hedgers are less likely to be information motivated, so their trading uniformly delays the price discovery process. However, there is a positive and nonlinear impact of speculators' trade size on price discovery, the contribution of which depends on the relative size of the speculative open interest. Contrary to conventional wisdom among regulators, speculative trading does not harm the market in terms of market efficiency; as long as the percentage of speculators' open interest is below an endogenously determined threshold (approximately 20% for EUR-USD and 16.3% for JPY-USD), speculative trading even improves futures market efficiency. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Ya-Kai; Chen, Yu-Lun; Chou, Robin K.; Gau, Yin-Feng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>SAFE: An early warning system for systemic banking risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oet, Mikhail V.; Bianco, Timothy; Gramlich, Dieter; Ong, Stephen J.
This paper builds on existing microprudential and macroprudential early warning systems (EWSs) to develop a new, hybrid class of models for systemic risk that incorporates the structural characteristics of the financial system and a feedback amplification mechanism. The models explain financial stress using both public and proprietary supervisory data from systemically important institutions, regressing institutional imbalances using an optimal lag method. The Systemic Assessment of Financial Environment (SAFE) EWS monitors microprudential information from the largest bank holding companies to anticipate the buildup of macroeconomic stresses in the financial markets. To mitigate inherent uncertainty, SAFE develops a set of medium-term forecasting specifications that gives policymakers enough time to take ex-ante policy action and a set of short-term forecasting specifications for verification and adjustment of supervisory actions. This paper highlights the application of these models to stress testing and policy. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oet, Mikhail V.; Bianco, Timothy; Gramlich, Dieter; Ong, Stephen J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A market-based approach to sector risk determinants and transmission in the euro area</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saldias, Martin
In a panel data framework applied to Portfolio Distance-to-Default series of corporate sectors in the euro area, this paper evaluates systemic and idiosyncratic determinants of default risk and examines how distress is transferred in and between the financial and corporate sectors since the early days of the euro. This approach takes into account observed and unobserved common factors and the presence of different degrees of cross-section dependence in the form of economic proximity. This paper contributes to the financial stability literature with a contingent claims approach to a sector-based analysis with a less dominant macro focus while being compatible with existing stress-testing methodologies in the literature. A disaggregated analysis of the different corporate and financial sectors allows for a more detailed assessment of specificities in terms of risk profile, i.e. heterogeneity of business models, risk exposures and interaction with the rest of the macro environment. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Saldias, Martin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International financial integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucey, Brian
nan</description><author>Lucey, Brian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking crises: An equal opportunity menace</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reinhart, Carmen M.; Rogoff, Kenneth S.
The historical frequency of banking crises is similar in advanced and developing countries, with quantitative parallels in both the run-ups and the aftermath. We establish these regularities using a dataset spanning from the early 1800s to the present. Banking crises weaken fiscal positions, with government revenues invariably contracting. Three years after a crisis central government debt increases by about 86%. The fiscal burden of banking crisis extends beyond the cost of the bailouts. We find that systemic banking crises are typically preceded by asset price bubbles, large capital inflows and credit booms, in rich and poor countries alike. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Reinhart, Carmen M.; Rogoff, Kenneth S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pandemics of the poor and banking stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lagoarde-Segot, Thomas; Leoni, Patrick L.
We first develop a theoretical model that shows that the likelihood of a collapse of the banking industry of a developing country increases, as the joint prevalence of large pandemics such as AIDS and malaria increases. We also show that the optimal bank reserves increase as the prevalence increases. In the empirical part of the paper, we consider a large dataset of developing countries, and we exhibit a causality effect from combined prevalence to deposit turnover, as well as causality effect from an increase of combined prevalence to an increase in bank reserves. Those empirical facts therefore support our theoretical findings. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lagoarde-Segot, Thomas; Leoni, Patrick L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The regulator's trade-off: Bank supervision vs. minimum capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buck, Florian; Schliephake, Eva
We develop a simple model of banking regulation with two policy instruments: minimum capital requirements and the supervision of domestic banks. The regulator faces a trade-off: high capital requirements cause a drop in the banks' profitability, whereas strict supervision reduces the scope of intermediation and is costly for taxpayers. We show that a mix of both instruments minimises the costs of preventing the collapse of financial intermediation. Once we allow for cross-border banking, the optimal policy is not feasible. If domestic supervisory effort is not observable, our model predicts a race to the bottom in capital requirement regulation. Therefore, countries are better off by harmonising regulation on an international standard. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buck, Florian; Schliephake, Eva</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impacts of standard monetary and budgetary policies on liquidity and financial markets: International evidence from the credit freeze crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gagnon, Marie-Helene; Gimet, Celine
This paper evaluates the domestic and international impacts of lowering short-term interest rates and increasing budget spending on several indicators of liquidity, volatility, credit and economic activity. Data from the 2003-2011 period in the United States, the Euro zone and Canada were used to develop two SVAR models for assessing the national effectiveness and the international spillovers of monetary and budgetary policies during the credit freeze crisis. While monetary policies caused a temporary decrease in volatility and increase in liquidity in North American stock markets, the shocks were mainly domestic and ineffective at generating liquidity in the banking sector. In contrast, government spending shocks had a positive impact on credit and consumption, especially in Europe and Canada. Moreover, budgetary policies also had a positive international spillover effect on consumption and credit, especially for smaller economies such as Canada. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gagnon, Marie-Helene; Gimet, Celine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of credit in the Great Moderation: A multivariate GARCH approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grydaki, Maria; Bezemer, Dirk
During the Great Moderation, financial innovation in the US increased the size and scope of credit flows supporting the growth of wealth. We hypothesize that spending out of wealth came to finance a wider range of GDP components such that it smoothed GDP. Both these trends combined would be consistent with a decrease in the volatility of output. We suggest testable implications in terms of both growth of credit and output and volatility of growth. In a multivariate GARCH framework, we test this view for home mortgages and residential investment. We observe unidirectional causality in variance from total output, residential investment and non-residential output to mortgage lending before, but not during the Great Moderation. These findings are consistent with a role for credit dynamics in explaining the Great Moderation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grydaki, Maria; Bezemer, Dirk</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Granger-causality in peripheral EMU public debt markets: A dynamic approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomez-Puig, Marta; Sosvilla-Rivero, Simon
Our research aims to analyze the possible existence of Granger-causal relationships in the behavior of public debt issued by peripheral member countries of the European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU), with special emphasis on the recent episodes of crisis triggered in the eurozone sovereign debt markets since 2009. With this goal in mind, we make use of a database of daily frequency of yields on 10-year government bonds issued by five EMU countries (Greece, Ireland, Italy, Portugal and Spain), covering the entire history of the EMU from its inception on I January 1999 until 31 December 2010. In the first step, we explore the pair-wise Granger-causal relationship between yields, both for the whole sample and for changing subsamples of the data, in order to capture the possible time-varying causal relationship. This approach allows us to detect episodes of significant increase in Granger-causality between yields on bonds issued by different countries. In the second step, we study the determinants of these episodes, analyzing the role played by different factors, paying special attention to instruments that capture the total national debt (domestic and foreign) in each country. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gomez-Puig, Marta; Sosvilla-Rivero, Simon</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneity of the determinants of euro-area sovereign bond spreads; what does it tell us about financial stability?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Georgoutsos, Dimitris A.; Migiakis, Petros M.
In this paper, we assess the movements of euro area sovereign bond yield spreads vis-a-vis the German Bund as processes specified across different levels of volatility and subject to movements in asset prices and economic conditions. The determinants we use are grouped into domestic and euro-area aggregates, thus allowing us to derive results on their relative explanatory power and compare them across time and the spectrum of countries. We find that volatility influences the deterministic processes of the euro area sovereign spreads and that identical determinants have effects on spreads that vary considerably across countries. Furthermore, we find that variables reflecting investment confidence conditions and perceptions for the upcoming economic activity are significant determinants and their significance remains, to a large extent, even when controlling for fiscal variables. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Georgoutsos, Dimitris A.; Migiakis, Petros M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Eurozone needs exit rules</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahrholz, Christian; Wojcik, Cezary
This study argues that the key issue for defining and solving the Eurozone's (EZ) difficulties lies in readjusting the relationship between the centre and the periphery of the EZ. Our argument proceeds in two steps. Firstly, the basic finance problem of a centre-periphery system is captured by a threat game with complete but imperfect information. To get close to the essence of the current EZ sovereign debt crisis we analyse to what extent a 'troubled' periphery member can negotiate a bailout from the centre due to the existence of a negative externality arising from its potential default. Secondly, we analyse how establishing 'exit rules' would shift the centre-periphery relationship in a way that safeguards the stability of the EZ. We demonstrate that such rules may help limit the scope for brinkmanship whereby fiscal problems in one member state create a negative externality for the rest of the EZ. We then discuss key policy implications concerning financial aspects of the centre-periphery relationship within the EZ. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fahrholz, Christian; Wojcik, Cezary</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic factor Value-at-Risk for large heteroskedastic portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aramonte, Sirio; Rodriguez, Marius del Giudice; Wu, Jason
We propose a methodology that can efficiently measure the Value-at-Risk (VaR) of large portfolios with time-varying volatility and correlations by bringing together the established historical simulation framework and recent contributions to the dynamic factor models literature. We find that the proposed methodology performs well relative to widely used VaR methodologies, and is a significant improvement from a computational point of view. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aramonte, Sirio; Rodriguez, Marius del Giudice; Wu, Jason</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing rainfall futures at the CME</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cabrera, Brenda Lopez; Odening, Martin; Ritter, Matthias
Many business people such as farmers and financial investors are affected by indirect losses caused by scarce or abundant rainfall. Because of the high potential of insuring rainfall risk, the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME) began trading rainfall derivatives in 2011. Compared to temperature derivatives, however, pricing rainfall derivatives is more difficult. In this article, we propose to model rainfall indices via a flexible type of distribution, namely the normal-inverse Gaussian distribution, which captures asymmetries and heavy-tail behaviour. The prices of rainfall futures are computed by employing the Esscher transform, a well-known tool in actuarial science. This approach is flexible enough to price any rainfall contract and to adjust theoretical prices to market prices by using the calibrated market price of risk. The empirical analysis is conducted with US precipitation data and CME futures data providing first results on the market price of risk for rainfall derivatives. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cabrera, Brenda Lopez; Odening, Martin; Ritter, Matthias</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary policy transmission in vector autoregressions: A new approach using central bank communication</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neuenkirch, Matthias
In this paper, we study the role played by central bank communication in monetary policy transmission. We employ the Swiss Economic Institute's Monetary Policy Communicator to measure the future stance of the European Central Bank's monetary policy. Our results indicate, first, that communication has an influence on inflation (expectations) similar to that of actual target rate changes. Communication also plays a noticeable role in the transmission of monetary policy to output. Consequently, future work on monetary policy transmission should incorporate both a short-term interest rate and a communication indicator. A second finding is that the monetary policy transmission mechanism changed during the financial crisis as the overall effect of monetary policy on (expected) inflation and output is weaker and of shorter duration during this period compared to the overall sample period. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Neuenkirch, Matthias</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market reaction to fed funds rate surprises: State dependence and the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kontonikas, Alexandros; MacDonald, Ronald; Saggu, Aman
This paper examines the response of US stock returns to Federal Funds rate (FFR) surprises between 1989 and 2012, focusing on the impact of the recent financial crisis. We find that outside the crisis period, stock prices increased as a response to unexpected FFR cuts. State dependence is identified with stocks exhibiting larger increases when interest rate easing coincided with recessions, bear markets, and tightening credit conditions. However, an important structural shift occurred during the crisis, changing the stocks' response to FFR shocks and the nature of state dependence. Throughout the crisis period, stocks did not react positively to unexpected FFR cuts, which were interpreted as signals of worsening future economic conditions. This triggered a rebalancing of investment portfolios away from falling equities and towards safe-haven assets. Our results highlight the severity of the crisis and the ineffectiveness of conventional monetary policy close to the zero lower bound. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kontonikas, Alexandros; MacDonald, Ronald; Saggu, Aman</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are modern financial systems shaped by state antiquity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, James B.
We demonstrate that existing differences in financial development between countries can be explained by the cumulative variations in their levels of state experience since 1 AD. This dimension of early historical development has not been considered so far in studies that analyze the determinants of financial development. The estimation allows for all major theories established in the literature as possible explanations for the disparity of financial development across the globe. Significance of state antiquity is robust to the use of alternative indicators of financial development, the consideration of different lengths and periods of statehood, and controlling for a range of variables or country characteristics. Our results highlight the important role of statehood in propelling financial system development, and thus provide some support to the view that historically determined differences in the early-start developmental advantage provide the basis for explaining the fundamental sources of variations in financial development between countries today. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, James B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting forecast errors through joint observation of earnings and revenue forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henderson, Brian J.; Marks, Joseph M.
We propose a simple method to infer the forecast error associated with quarterly estimates of earnings and revenue before the firm announces realized earnings and revenue. The method uses estimates of the profit margin implied by an analyst's forecasts of both earnings and revenue to identify forecasts that are likely to be optimistic or pessimistic. The ability to anticipate forecast error permits a trading strategy that exploits the average market reaction following positive and negative earnings and revenue surprises. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Henderson, Brian J.; Marks, Joseph M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and static hedging of American-style options under the jump to default extended CEV model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ruas, Joao Pedro; Dias, Jose Carlos; Vidal Nunes, Joao Pedro
This paper prices (and hedges) American-style options through the static hedge approach (SHP) proposed by Chung and Shih (2009) and extends the literature in two directions. First, the SHP approach is generalized to the jump to default extended CEV UDCEV) model of Carr and Linetsky (2006), and plain-vanilla American-style options on defaultable equity are priced. The robustness and efficiency of the proposed pricing solutions are compared with the optimal stopping approach offered by Nunes (2009), under both the JDCEV framework and the nested constant elasticity of variance (CEV) model of Cox (1975), using different elasticity parameter values. Second, the early exercise boundary near expiration is derived under the JDCEV model. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ruas, Joao Pedro; Dias, Jose Carlos; Vidal Nunes, Joao Pedro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stakeholder rights and economic performance: The profitability of nonprofits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bohren, Oyvind; Josefsen, Morten G.
This paper explores whether ownership matters in a fundamental sense by comparing the performance of stockholder-owned firms with the much less analyzed nonprofit firms. No stakeholder has residual cash flow rights in nonprofit firms, and the control rights are held by customers, employees, and community citizens. Accounting for differences in size and risk and comparing only firms in the same industry, we find that stockholder-owned firms do not outperform nonprofit firms. This result is consistent with the notin that the monitoring function of stockholders may be successfully replaced by other mechanisms. We find evidence that product market competition may play this role as a substitute monitoring mechanism. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bohren, Oyvind; Josefsen, Morten G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do people save in cash? Distrust, memories of banking crises, weak institutions and dollarization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stix, Helmut
The paper analyzes why households hold sizeable shares of their assets in cash at home rather than at banks a phenomenon that is widespread in many economies but for which information is scarce. Using survey data from ten Central, Eastern and Southeastern European countries, I document the relevance of this behavior and show that cash preferences cannot be fully explained by whether people are banked or unbanked. The analysis reveals that a lack of trust in banks, memories of past banking crises and weak tax enforcement are important factors. Moreover, cash preferences are stronger in dollarized economies where a "safe" foreign currency serves as a store of value. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stix, Helmut</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing with heterogeneous beliefs and relative performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Shiyang; Qiu, Zhigang; Shang, Qi; Tang, Ke
We propose an equilibrium asset pricing model in which agents with heterogeneous beliefs care about relative performance. We find that the concern with relative performance leads agents to trade more similarly, a development that has two effects. First, similar trading directly decreases volatility. Second, similar trading decreases the impact of dominant agents. The second effect dominates the first when agents expect large differences between their final performances, and vice versa when agents expect small differences between their final performances. Compared with the case in which agents are unconcerned about relative performance, the stock return volatility is higher when the second effect dominates, and lower when the first effect dominates. This paper also demonstrates that the concern about relative performance influences investors' holdings, stock prices and risk premia. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Shiyang; Qiu, Zhigang; Shang, Qi; Tang, Ke</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting stock returns: A regime-switching combination approach and economic links</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Xiaoneng; Zhu, Jie
This paper introduces a regime-switching combination approach to predict excess stock returns. The approach explicitly incorporates model uncertainty, regime uncertainty, and parameter uncertainty. The empirical findings reveal that the regime-switching combination forecasts of excess returns deliver consistent out-of-sample forecasting gains relative to the historical average and the Rapach et al. (2010) combination forecasts. The findings also reveal that two regimes are related to the business cycle. Based on the business cycle explanation of regimes, excess returns are found to be more predictable during economic contractions than during expansions. Finally, return forecasts are related to the real economy, thus providing insights on the economic sources of return predictability. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhu, Xiaoneng; Zhu, Jie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Basel III Net Stable Funding Ratio and bank net interest margins</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>King, Michael R.
The Net Stable Funding Ratio (NSFR) is a new Basel Ill liquidity requirement designed to limit funding risk arising from maturity mismatches between bank assets and liabilities. This study explains the NSFR and estimates this ratio for banks in 15 countries. Banks below the ratio need to increase stable sources of funding and to reduce assets requiring funding. The most cost-effective strategies to meet the NSFR are to increase holdings of higher-rated securities and to extend the maturity of wholesale funding. These changes reduce net interest margins by 70-88 basis points on average, or around 40% of their year-end 2009 values. Universal banks with diversified funding sources and high trading assets are penalized most by the NSFR. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>King, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do banks price discriminate spatially? Evidence from small business lending in local credit markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bellucci, Andrea; Borisov, Alexander; Zazzaro, Alberto
In this paper we explore the effects of bank-borrower physical proximity on price and non-price aspects of small business lending in local credit markets. Along the price dimension, our analysis reveals that interest rates increase with bank-borrower distance and decrease with the distance between borrower and other competing banks. Along the quantity dimension, we observe that more distant borrowers are more likely to experience binding credit limits. We also show that the quantity effects of bank-borrower distance are concentrated among less transparent firms. Our findings are consistent with pricing based on marginal costs that reflect information-based factors, and are in contrast to the established paradigm, where banks adopt spatial discriminatory pricing rules when lending to small-sized enterprises. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bellucci, Andrea; Borisov, Alexander; Zazzaro, Alberto</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond bankruptcy: Does the US bankruptcy code provide a fresh start to entrepreneurs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mathur, Aparna
This paper assesses the extent to which the US bankruptcy system is effective in providing small businesses a "fresh start" after a bankruptcy filing. I use data from the 1993, 1998 and 2003 National Survey of Small Business Finances to explore how firms fare after a bankruptcy filing. On the positive side, previously bankrupt firms are not any more burdened than the average small firm by problems relating to profitability, cash flow, health insurance costs, or taxes. Further, the fact that these firms are surviving several years after the filing is itself a testament to the efficient functioning of the US bankruptcy system. It suggests that the bankruptcy system goes a long way toward helping businesses recover after a bankruptcy filing. However, the one area of concern that persists after a filing is financing or credit access. In general, these firms have a nearly 24 percentage point higher likelihood of being denied a loan and are charged interest rates that are more than 1 percentage point higher than those charged to other businesses. A bankruptcy affects all types of financing, even trade credit, which is a significant form of lending between businesses. In fact, it appears that firms with a bankruptcy record are rationed out of the market, with all types of loans being denied at significantly higher rates than other firms. Further, my results show that bankruptcy leads to a class of discouraged borrowers who are significantly less likely to even apply for a loan. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mathur, Aparna</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign credit spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese
The paper develops a structural credit risk model to study sovereign credit risk and the dynamics of sovereign credit spreads. The model features endogenous default and recovery rates that both depend on the interaction between domestic output fluctuations and global macroeconomic conditions. We show that sovereigns choose to default at higher levels of economic output once global macroeconomic conditions are bad. This yields to default rates and credit spreads that are substantially higher compared to normal times. We derive closed-form expressions for sovereign debt values and default times and focus on the dynamics of sovereign credit spreads. As opposed to standard theories of sovereign debt, this paper's structural model generates much richer default patterns and non-linearities through regime-shifts in the global macroeconomic environment. Moreover, changes in the global environment reveal the interconnectedness of the financial system. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns and option activity over the option-expiration week for S&amp;P 100 stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stivers, Chris; Sun, Licheng
For S&amp;P 100 stocks, we find that the weekly returns over option-expiration (OE) weeks (a month's third-Friday week) tend to be high, relative to: (1) the third-Friday weekly returns of other stocks with less option activity, (2) the own stock's other weekly returns, (3) the risk, based on asset-pricing alphas. For these same stocks, a month's fourth-Friday weekly returns underperform modestly. We suggest the following two avenues are likely partial contributors towards understanding these return patterns: (1) delta-hedge rebalancing by option market makers, with a reduction in short-stock hedge positions over the OE week, and (2) declining risk perceptions over the OE week, as measured by option-derived implied volatilities. Our findings suggest option activity can induce reliable patterns in the weekly returns of option-active large-cap stocks. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stivers, Chris; Sun, Licheng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transatlantic systemic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trapp, Monika; Wewel, Claudio
In this paper we study systemic risk for the US and Europe. We show that banks' exposures to common risk factors are crucial for systemic risk. We come to this conclusion by first showing that relations between US and European banks are smaller than within each region. We then show that European banks react more strongly to the onset of the financial crisis than US banks. Regarding the consequences of systemic risk, we show that dependence between the banking sector and a wide range of real sectors is limited. Our results imply that regulators and supervisors should address international bank dependencies arising from common risk factors, while recessions in real sectors due to bank defaults should be a secondary concern. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Trapp, Monika; Wewel, Claudio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk premia: Exact solutions vs. log-linear approximations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lundtofte, Frederik; Wilhelmsson, Anders
We derive exact expressions for the risk premia for general distributions in a Lucas economy and show that the errors when using log-linear approximations can be economically significant when the shocks are nonnormal. Assuming growth rates are Normal Inverse Gaussian (NIG) and fitting the distribution to the data used in Mehra and Prescott (1985), the coefficient of relative risk aversion required to match the equity premium is more than halved compared to the finding in their article. We also consider a standard long-run risk model and, by comparing our exact solutions to the log-linear approximations, we show that the approximation errors are substantial, especially for high levels of risk aversion. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lundtofte, Frederik; Wilhelmsson, Anders</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Smiles all around: FX joint calibration in a multi-Heston model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Col, Alvise; Gnoatto, Alessandro; Grasselli, Martino
We introduce a novel multi-factor Heston-based stochastic volatility model, which is able to reproduce consistently typical multi-dimensional FX vanilla markets, while retaining the (semi)-analytical tractability typical of affine models and relying on a reasonable number of parameters. A successful joint calibration to real market data is presented together with various in- and out-of-sample calibration exercises to highlight the robustness of the parameters estimation. The proposed model preserves the natural inversion and triangulation symmetries of FX spot rates and its functional form, irrespective of choice of the risk-free currency. That is, all currencies are treated in the same way. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Col, Alvise; Gnoatto, Alessandro; Grasselli, Martino</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The differential effects of classified boards on firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, Seoungpil; Shrestha, Keshab
Classified boards actually benefit firms that have low monitoring costs and greater needs for advisory services. Previous literature has emphasized the entrenchment effect of classified boards. However, we find that this adverse impact of classified boards can be offset or even superseded by the potential benefits of board classification for firms who hope to benefit from the advisory services of their independent directors. We show that firms with greater advising needs appoint more outside directors with diverse attributes and expertise, qualifications that enhance the ability to provide useful advice to managers. Furthermore, in such firms, board classification is associated with higher performance sensitivity of forced CEO turnover and better acquisition performance. Conversely, in firms with high monitoring costs, board classification hurts managerial equity-based incentives and risk-taking incentives. These findings suggest how and through which channels classified boards engender the differential effects on firm value. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahn, Seoungpil; Shrestha, Keshab</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign ceilings "lite"? The impact of sovereign ratings on corporate ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borensztein, Eduardo; Cowan, Kevin; Valenzuela, Patricio
Although credit rating agencies have gradually moved away from a policy of never rating a corporation above the sovereign (the 'sovereign ceiling'), it appears that sovereign credit ratings remain a significant determinant of corporate credit ratings. We examine this link using data for advanced and emerging economies over the period of 1995-2009. Our main result is that a sovereign ceiling continues to affect the rating of corporations. The results also suggest that the influence of a sovereign ceiling on corporate ratings remains particularly significant in countries where capital account restrictions are still in place and with high political risk. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Borensztein, Eduardo; Cowan, Kevin; Valenzuela, Patricio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relationship between the frequency of news release and the information asymmetry: The role of uninformed trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sankaraguruswamy, Srinivasan; Shen, Jianfeng; Yamada, Takeshi
This paper shows that the degree of information asymmetry is lower for firms with more frequent news releases. The relation holds for various measures of information asymmetry such as the probability of information-based trading (PIN), permanent price impact, and adverse selection component of bid-ask spread, even after adjusting for endogeneity between news release and information asymmetry. By decomposing the PIN into intensities of uninformed and informed trades, similarly to Brown and Hillegeist (2007), we find that intensity of uninformed trading increases much more than that of informed trading for firms with more frequent news releases. As a result, information asymmetry, as is measured by PIN, decreases for such firms due to the large increase in the intensity of uninformed trading. Our findings highlight not only the importance of news releases in leveling the playing field of investors but also the role of uninformed investors in reducing trading cost due to information asymmetry. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sankaraguruswamy, Srinivasan; Shen, Jianfeng; Yamada, Takeshi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Attendance of board meetings and company performance: Evidence from Taiwan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chou, Hsin-I.; Chung, Huimin; Yin, Xiangkang
This paper empirically investigates board meeting attendance and its effects on the performance of Taiwanese listed corporations. Directors with higher qualifications attend board meetings more often by themselves. The ownership of the largest shareholder of a company also has a positive effect on director's own meeting attendance. High meeting attendance by directors themselves can enhance a firm's performance but high attendance by their representatives has an adverse effect. Independence of directors or a board is also positively associated with firm performance. These results largely hold even when the sample is decomposed to count for different ownership structures and director types. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chou, Hsin-I.; Chung, Huimin; Yin, Xiangkang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage risk and the turnover anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chou, Pin-Huang; Huang, Tsung-Yu; Yang, Hung-Jeh
A strong turnover premium exists such that stocks with lower turnover have higher future returns in the 5 years following their formation than those with higher turnover. This turnover premium cannot be explained by existing asset-pricing models, a risk-based liquidity factor, or anomalies such as size, book-to-market ratio, or momentum. Further analysis indicates that the turnover premium is greater for stocks with higher idiosyncratic volatility, higher transaction costs, lower institutional ownership, and lower investor sophistication, which implies it is consistent with the mispricing explanation based on arbitrage risk. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chou, Pin-Huang; Huang, Tsung-Yu; Yang, Hung-Jeh</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial contagion in the laboratory: The cross-market rebalancing channel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cipriani, Marco; Gardenal, Gloria; Guarino, Antonio
We present the results of the first experimental study of financial markets contagion. We develop a model of financial contagion amenable to be tested in the laboratory. In the model, contagion happens because of cross-market rebalancing, a channel for transmission of shocks across markets first studied by Kodres and Pritsker (2002). Theory predicts that, because of portfolio rebalancing, a negative shock in one market transmits itself to the others, as investors adjust their portfolio allocations. The theory is supported by the experimental results. The price observed in the laboratory is close to that predicted by theory, and strong contagion effects are observed. The results are robust across different market structures. Moreover, as theory predicts, lower asymmetric information in a ("developed") financial market increases the contagion effects in ("emerging") markets. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cipriani, Marco; Gardenal, Gloria; Guarino, Antonio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A general closed-form spread option pricing formula</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caldana, Ruggero; Fusai, Gianluca
We propose a new accurate method for pricing European spread options by extending the lower bound approximation of Bjerksund and Stensland (2011) beyond the classical Black-Scholes framework. This is possible via a procedure requiring a univariate Fourier inversion. In addition, we are also able to obtain a new tight upper bound. Our method provides also an exact closed form solution via Fourier inversion of the exchange option price, generalizing the Margrabe (1978) formula. The method is applicable to models in which the joint characteristic function of the underlying assets forming the spread is known analytically. We test the performance of these new pricing algorithms performing numerical experiments on different stochastic dynamic models. Crown Copyright (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caldana, Ruggero; Fusai, Gianluca</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product differentiation and efficiencies in the retail banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Mian; Yuan, Yuan
We empirically quantify the welfare implications of bank entry in the United States between 2000 and 2008. We use a fully structural framework that combines a differentiated demand model with an endogenous product model to investigate the market outcomes. We find no evidence for under- or over-entry. Compared with the socially efficient outcome, there is a mild welfare loss resulting from banks entering wrong locations in product space. Compared with the observed outcome, consumer surplus drops by 20-38% and bank profits decline by 48-59% when banks are homogeneous. Therefore product differentiation significantly improves welfare under free entry. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dai, Mian; Yuan, Yuan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comprehensive long-term analysis of S&amp;P 500 index additions and deletions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Kalok; Kot, Hung Wan; Tang, Gordon Y. N.
We investigate the long-term effects of S&amp;P 500 index additions and deletions on a sample of stocks from 1962 to 2003 and find a significant long-term price increase for both added and deleted stocks, with deleted stocks outperforming added stocks. The long-term price increase for added stocks can be attributed to increases in institutional ownership, liquidity, and analyst coverage, and a decrease in the shadow cost in the long-term. However, while deletion has no significant effect on analyst coverage and shadow cost, we find a rebound in the institutional ownership and liquidity of deleted stocks. The difference in the long-term price increase of added and deleted stocks can be explained by analyst coverage and operating performance. Crown Copyright (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Kalok; Kot, Hung Wan; Tang, Gordon Y. N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Front-running of mutual fund fire-sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dyakov, Teodor; Verbeek, Marno
We show that a real-time trading strategy which front-runs the anticipated forced sales by mutual funds experiencing extreme capital outflows generates an alpha of 0.5% per month during the 1990-2010 period. The abnormal return stems from selling pressure among stocks that are below the NYSE mean size and cannot be attributed to the arrival of public information. While the largest stocks also exhibit downward price pressure, their prices revert before the front-running strategy can detect it. The duration of the anticipated selling pressure has decreased from about a month in the 1990s to about two weeks in the most recent decade. Our results suggest that publicly available information of fund flows and holdings exposes mutual funds in distress to predatory trading. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dyakov, Teodor; Verbeek, Marno</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting EUR-USD implied volatility: The case of intraday data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dunis, Christian; Kellard, Neil M.; Snaith, Stuart
This study models and forecasts the evolution of intraday implied volatility on an underlying EUR-USD exchange rate for a number of maturities. To our knowledge we are the first to employ high frequency data in this context. This allows the construction of forecasting models that can attempt to exploit intraday seasonalities such as overnight effects. Results show that implied volatility is predictable at shorter horizons, within a given day and across the term structure. Moreover, at the conventional daily frequency, intraday seasonality effects can be used to augment the forecasting power of models. The type of inefficiency revealed suggests potentially profitable trading models. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dunis, Christian; Kellard, Neil M.; Snaith, Stuart</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return decomposition and the Intertemporal CAPM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maio, Paulo
The Intertemporal CAPM (ICAPM) from Merton (1973) has had a strong impact in empirical asset pricing leading to numerous multifactor models. This paper shows that the explanatory power of the ICAPM application by Campbell and Vuolteenaho (2004) relies critically on the computation of Dimson (1979) covariances (betas). If one employs the standard factor covariances (excluding lagged factors), the two-factor ICAPM has virtually no explanatory power for the average returns of the 25 size/book-to-market portfolios. More specifically, it is the covariance with the lagged innovation in one of the state variables (the value spread) that drives the explanatory power of the model. These results are inconsistent with the central economic intuition from the ICAPM. By specifying a more general version of the ICAPM, the fit of the model improves relative to the Campbell and Vuolteenaho (2004) model. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maio, Paulo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and initial public offering underpricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hahn, TeWhan; Ligon, James A.; Rhodes, Heather
Using eight measures of liquidity, and addressing the potential endogeneity of initial returns, we find underpricing generally increases the secondary market liquidity of IPOs over the first year of trading, irrespective of the horizon over which liquidity is measured. For two model specifications over the eight measures, fifteen regressions display signs consistent with higher underpricing increasing liquidity and thirteen of these are statistically significant. We also find higher initial returns are significantly negatively correlated with the probability of informed trade. Furthermore, the liquidity effects of underpricing survive the lockup date, suggesting they are not quickly dissipated. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hahn, TeWhan; Ligon, James A.; Rhodes, Heather</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan collateral and financial reporting conservatism: Chinese evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Jeff Zeyun; Lobo, Gerald J.; Wang, Yanyan; Yu, Lisheng
We examine the relation between the use of collateral and financial reporting conservatism for a sample of Chinese firms. In the absence of flexibility in risk pricing through interest rates and strong contract enforcement in China, we find that lenders reduce collateral requirements from more conservative borrowers and that this negative relation is significantly moderated by borrowers' poor credit quality and low asset tangibility. Our finding that conservatism can result in a tangible benefit in the form of lower collateral requirements indicates that lenders value financial reporting conservatism. However, the benefit from financial reporting conservatism is muted as lenders become more concerned about borrowers' default risk or ability to pledge tangible assets as collateral against loans. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Jeff Zeyun; Lobo, Gerald J.; Wang, Yanyan; Yu, Lisheng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the importance of indirect banking vulnerabilities in the Eurozone</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bicu, Andreea; Candelon, Bertrand
This paper investigates banking and sovereign distress in the Eurozone and the importance of direct and indirect financial exposures. We use BIS cross-border banking claims to link member states in a GVAR framework and jointly model sectoral CDS premia. Based on balance sheet positions of an intermediate debtor country, we calculate indirect exposures and asses how the level of interconnectedness is impacted when indirect links are accounted for. We notice a general slowdown in financial integration and a reduction in cross-border assets in the hope of limiting international contagion. By differentiating between direct and indirect links, we show that the impact of reduced weights on core member states is mostly insignificant and that deleveraging strategies are not generally able to successfully reduce risk. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bicu, Andreea; Candelon, Bertrand</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>