<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Banking &amp; Finance9</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Political connection and cost of debt: Some Malaysian evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bliss, Mark A.; Gul, Ferdinand A.
This paper investigates the association between Malaysian politically connected (PCON) firms and the cost of debt. We extend previous research that finds Malaysian PCON firms are perceived as being of higher risk by the market, and by audit firms, by providing evidence that lenders also perceive these firms as being of higher risk. We also find that PCON firms have a significantly (1) higher extent of leverage, (2) higher likelihood of reporting a loss, (3) higher likelihood of having negative equity, and (4) higher likelihood of being audited by a big audit firm. We suggest that PCON firms are charged higher interest rates by lenders as a result of efficient contracting given their higher inherent risks. Additionally, we find that CEO duality present in PCON firms is perceived by lenders as being more risky, and that a higher proportion of independent directors on the audit committee mitigate this perceived risk. (C) 2012 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bliss, Mark A.; Gul, Ferdinand A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board quality and the cost of debt capital: The case of bank loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fields, L. Paige; Fraser, Donald R.; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
We analyze the relation between comprehensive measures of board quality and the cost as well as the non-price terms of bank loans. We show that firms that have higher quality boards with a greater advisory presence borrow at lower interest rates. This relation exists even after controlling for ownership structure, CEO compensation policy, and shareholder protection, as well as the size and financial characteristics of the borrower and of the loan. We also show evidence that board quality and other governance characteristics influence the likelihood that loans have covenant requirements, but the relations differ by covenant type. When we combine the direct and indirect costs of bank loans we find that firms with large,, independent, experienced, and diverse boards and lower institutional ownership borrow more cheaply. Overall, the evidence indicates that board quality impacts the cost of bank debt. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fields, L. Paige; Fraser, Donald R.; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local financial development and growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kendall, Jake
Using unique, district-level, economic growth data, I investigate the connection between banking sector development, human capital, and economic growth in Indian districts. Disaggregate data helps avoid many of the omitted variable problems that plague similar cross-country studies. The data show districts to be financially constrained by the lack of local banking sector development, and the relationship may be non-linear. For districts in the sample, moving from the 75th percentile of credit/net domestic product to the 25th percentile implies an average loss of 4% in growth over the 1990s decade. The data also shows that human capital deepening can reduce the financial constraint. In a district at the 25th literacy percentile, the implied growth loss due to a constrained banking sector is twice as large as in a district at the 75th literacy percentile. The results are robust to the inclusion of various controls and changes in specification. (C) 2012 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kendall, Jake</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cojumping: Evidence from the US Treasury bond and futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dungey, Mardi; Hvozdyk, Lyudmyla
The basis between spot and future prices will be affected by jump behavior in each asset price, challenging intraday hedging strategies. Using formal cojumping tests this paper considers the cojumping behavior of spot and futures prices in high frequency US Treasury data. Cojumping occurs most frequently at shorter maturities and higher sampling frequencies. We find that the probability of cojumping is altered by the presence of an anticipated macroeconomic news announcement. The probability of cojumping is particularly affected by news surprises in non-farm payrolls, CPI, GDP and retail sales. However, the two cojumping tests are also more likely to provide contradictory results in the presence of surprises in non-farm payrolls. On these occasions the market does not clearly signal its short term pricing behavior. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dungey, Mardi; Hvozdyk, Lyudmyla</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pitfalls in VAR based return decompositions: A clarification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engsted, Tom; Pedersen, Thomas Q.; Tanggaard, Carsten
We analyze the pitfalls involved in VAR based return decompositions. First, we show that recent criticism of such decompositions is misplaced and builds on invalid VAR models and erroneous interpretations. Second, we derive the requirements needed for VAR decompositions to be valid. A crucial - but often neglected - requirement is that the asset price needs to be included as a state variable in the VAR. In equity return decompositions this requirement is equivalent to including the dividend-price ratio in the VAR. Finally, we clarify the intriguing issue of the role of the residual component in return decompositions. In a properly specified first-order VAR, it makes no difference whether cash flow news or discount rate news is backed out residually, and it makes no difference whether both news components are computed directly or one of them is backed out residually. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Engsted, Tom; Pedersen, Thomas Q.; Tanggaard, Carsten</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are good-news firms riskier than bad-news firms?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Min, Byoung-Kyu; Kim, Tong Suk
This paper examines the relative risk of good-news firms, i.e., those with high standardized unexpected earnings (SUE), and bad-news (low SUE) firms using a stochastic discount factor approach. We find that a stochastic discount factor constructed from a set of basis assets helps explain post-earnings-announcement drift (PEAD). The risk exposures on the pricing kernel increase monotonically from the lowest to highest SUE sorted portfolios. Specifically, good-news firms always have higher risk exposures than bad-news firms in both 10 SUE sorted portfolios and 25 size and SUE sorted portfolios. However, the estimated expected risk premium is too small to explain the observed magnitude of returns on the PEAD strategy. Our risk adjustment can explain only about one-fourth of the total magnitude of the average realized return to the PEAD strategy. As a result, the average risk-adjusted returns of earnings momentum strategies are mostly positive and significant. Overall, our results support the view that at least some portion of the returns to the earnings momentum strategies examined represent compensation for bearing increased risk. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Min, Byoung-Kyu; Kim, Tong Suk</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common information asymmetry factors in syndicated loan structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Champagne, Claudia; Coggins, Frank
This paper provides a comprehensive study of the syndicate structure and its relationship to information asymmetry and loan spread by using principal component analysis on a large set of 40 structure-related variables. A total of six structure components are identified and related to syndicate quality, syndicate members' heterogeneity or share concentration, lead arranger's characteristics, lead lender's or syndicate's location, lender-borrower relationships, and lead institution type. In multivariate settings, all six components are significant determinants of loan spread, either directly or indirectly through their impact on other components. Lead share retention, previous lender-borrower relationships and syndicate quality are shown to be bilaterally related to loan spread. Structure components differ regionally, which can provide an explanation for the European pricing discount observed in the literature. An Asian discount is observed and cannot be explained by structure differences. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Champagne, Claudia; Coggins, Frank</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Acquisition valuations of withdrawn IPOs: When IPO plans turn into mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lian, Qin; Wang, Qiming
We examine the acquisition valuations of withdrawn-IPOs private targets that are acquired after they file and then withdraw their IPOs to examine how IPO registration and withdrawal affect valuations of withdrawn-IPOs in their subsequent mergers. We find that these "almost public" withdrawn-IPOs sell at a significant acquisition premium relative to comparable pure private targets that never file IPO registration and at acquisition valuations similar to comparable public targets. The premium persists only for withdrawn-IPOs that are acquired before their IPO withdrawals after other factors are controlled for. These findings confirm that there is a significantly positive (negative) valuation impact of IPO registration (IPO withdrawal) on withdrawn-IPOs' subsequent acquisitions. The two effects offset each other for withdrawn-IPOs that are acquired after their IPO withdrawals. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Lian, Qin; Wang, Qiming</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using industry momentum to improve portfolio performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Behr, Patrick; Guettler, Andre; Truebenbach, Fabian
Minimum-variance portfolios, which ignore the mean and focus on the (co)variances of asset returns, outperform mean-variance approaches in out-of-sample tests. Despite these promising results, minimum-variance policies fail to deliver a superior performance compared with the simple 1/N rule. In this paper, we propose a parametric portfolio policy that uses industry return momentum to improve portfolio performance. Our portfolio policies outperform a broad selection of established portfolio strategies in terms of Sharpe ratio and certainty equivalent returns. The proposed policies are particularly suitable for investors because portfolio turnover is only moderately increased compared to standard minimum-variance portfolios. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Behr, Patrick; Guettler, Andre; Truebenbach, Fabian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Being a foreigner among domestic banks: Asset or liability?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claessens, Stijn; van Horen, Neeltje
Do foreign banks perform better than domestic banks? The existing literature has come up with different answers, in part as data coverage has varied and often been limited. Studying the performance of foreign relative to domestic banks in many countries between 1999 and 2006, we find that the answer importantly depends on a number of factors. Specifically, foreign banks tend to perform better when from a high income country and when regulation in the host country is relatively weak. They also perform better when larger and having a bigger market share. Foreign banks from home countries with the same language and similar regulation as the host country also perform better. Geographical closeness, however, does not improve performance. These findings show that it is important to control for heterogeneity among foreign banks when studying their performance and help reconcile some contradictory results found in the literature. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Claessens, Stijn; van Horen, Neeltje</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Level, slope, curvature of the sovereign yield curve, and fiscal behaviour</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Afonso, Antonio; Martins, Manuel M. F.
We study fiscal behaviour and the sovereign yield curve in the US and Germany. We obtain the latent factors, level, slope and curvature, with the Kalman filter, and use them in a VAR with macro, fiscal and financial stress variables. In the US, fiscal shocks generate an immediate response of the short-end of the yield curve, associated with monetary policy, lasting 6-8 quarters, followed by a response of the whole yield curve lasting 3 years. with an implied elasticity of long-term yields of 80% for the government debt shock and 48% for the budget balance shock. In Germany, fiscal shocks have entailed no significant reactions of the yield curve shape and no response of the monetary policy interest rate, notably after 1999; only in the case of debt shocks there is a short-lived decrease in the medium-end of the yield curve in the following 2nd and 3rd quarters. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Afonso, Antonio; Martins, Manuel M. F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lending competition and credit availability for new firms: Empirical study with the price cost margin in regional loan markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ogura, Yoshiaki
In this paper, I present statistical evidence of the impact of lending competition on credit availability for new firms. A discrete-time duration analysis with respect to the years from the start-up to the first loan approval by a commercial bank or a cooperative bank, which is collected from survey data in Japan, shows that the higher price cost margin (PCM) of banks, which reflects the existence of a quasi-rent for a bank, improves the credit availability for younger firms. Additional analysis to detect the regional determinants of the PCM of banks shows that the share of larger banks in each local credit market has a negative and significant impact on the PCM. In light of the existing empirical finding that smaller banks are more likely to provide relationship banking, these findings provide indirect evidence for the hypothesis that the intensity of relationship banking in each local credit market increases the PCM and this encourages banks to extend a loan to new firms so that they can pre-empt the opportunity to establish lending relationships that are expected to yield such quasi-rents. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ogura, Yoshiaki</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric dynamics of stock price continuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Alex YiHou
This paper finds that the dynamics of stock price continuation are asymmetrical, in terms of both business cycles and past performances. During times of recession, stock returns are explained differently for past losers and winners; the level of credit quality dominates the return dynamics for extreme losers, while levels of information-based trading activity and information ambiguity contribute to winners' medium-term returns. Such asymmetry is proposed as the source of insignificant profits achieved using conventional momentum strategies. On the other hand, in times of expansion, conventional asset pricing factors are found to affect stock returns with a dependence on the level of credit quality; this suggests that more profitable momentum strategies remain to be discovered. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Alex YiHou</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the relationship between concentration of prospect theory/mental accounting investors, cointegration, and momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhootra, Ajay; Hur, Jungshik
We examine the role of cointegration between stock prices and their estimated fundamental values in 'return momentum. We find that the positive relationship between capital gains overhang and future stock returns in Grinblatt and Han (2005) is significantly stronger among the "non-cointegrated" group of stocks as compared with the "cointegrated" group of stocks. Further, for the cointegrated stocks, the, slower the speed of adjustment to the cointegrating equilibrium, the greater (smaller) is the future return of stocks with unrealized capital gains (losses). These findings are robust to various firm characteristics, including firm size, book-to-market ratio, past returns, idiosyncratic volatility, dispersion in analysts' earnings forecasts, turnover, individual investor ownership, and industry returns. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhootra, Ajay; Hur, Jungshik</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investors' distraction and strategic repricing decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Navone, Marco
In this paper I analyze investors' reactions to changes in the expense ratios of equity mutual funds. I show that investment flows' response to fees cannot be fully explained by looking at investors' performance sensitivity. While performance sensitivity monotonically increases with past performance, price sensitivity does not: investors who buy top past performers seem to be "distracted" by the fund's previous return and pay relatively little attention to the expense ratios. Moreover price sensitivity increases with fund visibility while performance sensitivity decreases, and while looking at data from 1986 to 2006 no discernible trend can be observed in the average performance sensitivity, price sensitivity strongly increases due to the dramatic increase in the availability of mutual funds' information for retail investors. Finally I show that investment companies strategically time their repricing decisions in order to exploit time variations in price and performance sensitivities, and that fund governance quality affects the degree to which investment companies engage in this opportunistic behavior. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Navone, Marco</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of trade credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Lobez, Frederic; Statnik, Jean-Christophe
During 1992-2007, suppliers financed almost 10% of the total assets of US listed firms. This intensive usage of trade credit is puzzling in the light of its high (implicit) costs. By arguing that trade credit use provides valuable information to outside investors, we first derive a theoretical model that predicts a positive correlation between trade credit use and the quality of the firm's investments. Then, using several proxies for firm's investment quality (Z-score, return on assets, and long-run abnormal returns), we show that this prediction receives strong support from a large sample of US firms. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Lobez, Frederic; Statnik, Jean-Christophe</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When are path-dependent payoffs suboptimal?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kassberger, Stefan; Liebmann, Thomas
Generalizing a result by Cox and Leland (2000) and Vanduffel et al. (2009), this note shows that risk-averse investors with fixed planning horizon prefer path-independent payoffs in any financial market, if the pricing kernel is a function of the underlying's price at the end of the planning horizon. Generally, for every payoff which is not a function of the pricing kernel, there is a more attractive alternative that depends solely on the pricing kernel at the end of the planning horizon. (C) 2011 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kassberger, Stefan; Liebmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A stochastic frontier approach to modelling financial constraints in firms: An application to India</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhaumik, Sumon Kumar; Das, Pranab Kumar; Kumbhakar, Subal C.
We propose the use of stochastic frontier approach to modelling financial constraints of firms. The main advantage of the stochastic frontier approach over the stylised approaches that use pooled OLS or fixed effects panel regression models is that we can not only decide whether or not the average firm is financially constrained, but also estimate a measure of the degree of the constraint for each firm and for each time period, and also the marginal impact of firm characteristics on this measure. We then apply the stochastic frontier approach to a panel of Indian manufacturing firms, for the 1997-2006 period. In our application, we highlight and discuss the aforementioned advantages, while also demonstrating that the stochastic frontier approach generates regression estimates that are consistent with the stylised intuition found in the literature on financial constraint and the wider literature on the Indian credit/capital market. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhaumik, Sumon Kumar; Das, Pranab Kumar; Kumbhakar, Subal C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Household portfolio choices, health status and health care systems: A cross-country analysis based on SHARE</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atella, Vincenzo; Brunetti, Marianna; Maestas, Nicole
Health risk is increasingly viewed as an important form of background risk that affects household portfolio decisions. However, its role might be mediated by the presence of a protective full-coverage national health service that could reduce households' probability of incurring current and future out-of-pocket medical expenditures. We use SHARE data to study the influence of current health status and future health risk on the decision to hold risky assets, across ten European countries with different health systems, each offering a different degree of protection against out-of-pocket medical expenditures. We find robust empirical evidence that perceived health status matters more than objective health status and, consistent with the theory of background risk, health risk affects portfolio choices only in countries with less protective health care systems. Furthermore, portfolio decisions consistent with background risk models are observed only with respect to middle-aged and highly-educated investors. (C) 2012 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Atella, Vincenzo; Brunetti, Marianna; Maestas, Nicole</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank connections, corporate investment and crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Espenlaub, Susanne; Khurshed, Arif; Sitthipongpanich, Thitima
Against the backdrop of a severe financial crisis and extensive restructuring of the financial sector, we investigate the evolution and determinants of connections between firms and banks, and the impact of bank connections on corporate investment. Our study examines Thai non-financial companies during 1995-2000, a period straddling the East Asian Financial Crisis of 1997-1998. Before the crisis, bank-connections are common and associated with significantly lower sensitivity of corporate investment to internal cash flow. After the crisis, and following substantial changes in bank ownership and governance due to financial-sector reforms and restructuring, far fewer firms are bank-connected and connections no longer affect investment-cash flow sensitivity. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Espenlaub, Susanne; Khurshed, Arif; Sitthipongpanich, Thitima</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Combining equilibrium, resampling, and analyst's views in portfolio optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barros Fernandes, Jose Luiz; Haas Ornelas, Jose Renato; Martinez Cusicanqui, Oscar Augusto
This paper proposes the use of a portfolio optimization methodology which combines features of equilibrium models and investor's views as in Black and Litterman (1992), and also deals with estimation risk as in Michaud (1998). In this way, our combined methodology is able to meet the needs of practitioners for stable and diversified portfolio allocations, while it is theoretically grounded on an equilibrium framework. We empirically test the methodology using a comprehensive sample of developed countries fixed income and equity indices, as well as sub-samples stratified by geographical region, time period, asset class and risk level. In general, our proposed combined methodology generates very competitive portfolios when compared to other methodologies, considering three evaluation dimensions: financial efficiency, diversification, and allocation stability. By generating financially efficient, stable, and diversified portfolio allocations, our methodology is suitable for long-term investors such as Central Banks and Sovereign Wealth Funds. (C) 2011 Elsevier BY. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barros Fernandes, Jose Luiz; Haas Ornelas, Jose Renato; Martinez Cusicanqui, Oscar Augusto</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroenvironmental determinants of operational loss severity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cope, Eric W.; Piche, Mark T.; Walter, John S.
We investigate the relationships between the severity of operational loss events reported in the banking sector and various regulatory, legal, geographical, and economic indicators. Based on a data sample of over 57,000 losses incurred in more than 130 countries reported by the Operational Riskdata exchange (ORX) consortium, we identify the most relevant exposure indicators for losses in four Basel 11 event categories: Internal Fraud; External Fraud; Employment Practices and Workplace Safety; and Clients, Products and Business Practices. We find evidence of significant correlations between Internal Fraud and constraints on executive power and the prevalence of insider trading. Clients, Products and Business Practices losses are significantly related to securities and shareholder protection laws, restrictions on banking activity, supervisory power, and the prevalence of insider trading. Other event types are sensitive to per-capita GDP and a governance index. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cope, Eric W.; Piche, Mark T.; Walter, John S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of illiquidity premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kempf, Alexander; Korn, Olaf; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese
We investigate the term structure of bond market illiquidity premia and show that the term structure varies greatly over time. Short and long end are strictly separated suggesting that different economic factors drive different parts of the term structure. We propose a stylized theoretical model which implies that current trading needs of investors determine the short end. The long-term risk of being forced to liquidate bond positions determines the long end. Empirical evidence supports these predictions. While short-term liquidation risk captured by asset market volatilities drives the short end, the long end depends on the long-term economic outlook. (C) 2011 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kempf, Alexander; Korn, Olaf; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Characteristic-based mean-variance portfolio choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hjalmarsson, Erik; Manchev, Petar
We study empirical mean-variance optimization when the portfolio weights are restricted to be direct functions of underlying stock characteristics such as value and momentum. The closed-form solution to the portfolio weights estimator shows that the portfolio problem in this case reduces to a mean-variance analysis of assets with returns given by single-characteristic strategies (e.g., momentum or value). In an empirical application to international stock return indexes, we show that the direct approach to estimating portfolio weights clearly beats a naive regression-based approach that models the conditional mean. However, a portfolio based on equal weights of the single-characteristic strategies performs about as well, and sometimes better, than the direct estimation approach, highlighting again the difficulties in beating the equal-weighted case in mean-variance analysis. The empirical results also highlight the potential for 'stock-picking' in international indexes using characteristics such as value and momentum with the characteristic-based portfolios obtaining Sharpe ratios approximately three times larger than the world market. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hjalmarsson, Erik; Manchev, Petar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance of technical analysis in growth and small cap segments of the US equity market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shynkevich, Andrei
A large universe of technical trading rules applied to a set of technology industry and small cap sector portfolios over the 1995-2010 period yields superior predictability after adjusting for data snooping bias in the first half of the sample period and delivers statistically significant profits for a number of portfolios when the transaction cost is assumed to be of small to moderate size. Technical analysis is not able to outperform the buy-and-hold approach for any portfolio in the set in the second half of the sample period. The finding that the short-term return predictability becomes much weaker in the more recent period suggests that the underlying segments of the equity market have become more efficient over time. The fact that mechanical trading strategies have been futile after adjusting for data snooping bias for two samples of portfolios where technical analysis is most anticipated to succeed suggests that it is unlikely to have delivered abnormal returns in any other segment of the domestic equity market in the last decade. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shynkevich, Andrei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option-implied volatility factors and the cross-section of market risk premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Junye
The main goal of this paper is to study the cross-sectional pricing of market volatility. The paper proposes that the market return, diffusion volatility, and jump volatility are fundamental factors that change the investors' investment opportunity set. Based on estimates of diffusion and jump volatility factors using an enriched dataset including S&amp;P 500 index returns, index options, and VIX, the paper finds negative market prices for volatility factors in the cross-section of stock returns. The findings are consistent with risk-based interpretations of value and size premia and indicate that the value effect is mainly related to the persistent diffusion volatility factor, whereas the size effect is associated with both the diffusion volatility factor and the jump volatility factor. The paper also finds that the use of market index data alone may yield counter-intuitive results. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Junye</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dual class IPOs: A theoretical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Jiao, Yawen
We consider an incumbent who wishes to sell equity to outsiders at an IPO to implement his firm's project. He may be talented (lower cost of effort, comparative advantage in project-implementation) or untalented. The project may have high (intrinsically more valuable, but showing less signs of success in the near-term) or low near-term uncertainty. Under a single class share structure, the incumbent has a greater chance of losing control to potential rivals if he undertakes the project with high near-term uncertainty, since outsiders may vote for the rival if they believe the project is not progressing well. A dual class share structure allows the incumbent to have enough votes to prevail against any rival, but may be misused by untalented incumbents to dissipate value. Our results help to explain firms' choices between dual class and single class IPOs and the post-IPO operating performance of dual class versus single class firms. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Jiao, Yawen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Models of the yield curve and the curvature of the implied forward rate function</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yallup, Peter J.
We examine several alternative models of the UK gilt yield curve using daily data for the period 12 July 1996-10 February 2010. We select the best models according to two criteria: low out of sample errors in pricing bonds and low curvature of the implied forward rate curve function. We suggest additions to some of the models that significantly improve their performance. Some of the new models out perform those typically used by the central banks. In particular this paper suggests that the model used by the Canadian Central Bank which both outperforms other models and is particularly easy to estimate, is well suited to the UK gilt market. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yallup, Peter J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Libor manipulation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abrantes-Metz, Rosa M.; Kraten, Michael; Metz, Albert D.; Seow, Gim S.
On May 29, 2008 the Wall Street journal published an article alleging that several global banks were reporting Libor quotes significantly lower than those implied by prevailing credit default swap (CDS) spreads. While acknowledging that the "analysis doesn't prove that banks are lying or manipulating Libor," it nevertheless conjectures that these banks may "have been low-balling their borrowing rates to avoid looking desperate for cash." In this paper we compare Libor with other short-term borrowing rates, analyze individual bank quotes, and compare these individual quotes to CDS spreads and market capitalization data during three periods: 1/1/07-8/8/07 (Period 1), 8/9/07-4/16/08 (Period 2), and 4/17/08-5/30/08 (Period 3). We find some anomalous individual quotes, but the evidence is inconsistent with a material manipulation of the US dollar 1-month Libor rate. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abrantes-Metz, Rosa M.; Kraten, Michael; Metz, Albert D.; Seow, Gim S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing American interest rate options under the jump-extended constant-elasticity-of-variance short rate models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beliaeva, Natalia; Nawalkha, Sanjay
This paper demonstrates how to value American interest rate options under the jump-extended constant-elasticity-of-variance (CEV) models. We consider both exponential jumps (see Duffle et al., 2000) and log-normal jumps (see Johannes, 2004) in the short rate process. We show how to superimpose recombining multinomial jump trees on the diffusion trees, creating mixed jump-diffusion trees for the CEV models of short rate extended with exponential and lognormal jumps. Our simulations for the special case of jump-extended Cox, Ingersoll, and Ross (CIR) square root model show a significant computational advantage over the Longstaff and Schwartz's (2001) least-squares regression method (ISM) for pricing American options on zero-coupon bonds. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beliaeva, Natalia; Nawalkha, Sanjay</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IMF programs, financial and real sector performance, and the Asian crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kutan, Ali M.; Muradoglu, Gulnur; Sudjana, Brasukra G.
This paper has three objectives. First, using a richer and more comprehensive set of IMF-related news than previous studies, we examine the impact of IMF-related news on both financial and real stock sector returns in Indonesia during the Asian crisis. Second, we draw lessons about financial and real sectoral patterns of adjustment in crisis countries, including whether and how IMF programs facilitate this adjustment. Third, we explore the interplay between IMF actions in crisis countries and the actions and responses of local authorities. To do so, not only do we account for the impact of news regarding IMF policy actions but also the government's reaction to them and willingness to implement such policies, and the public sentiment about the implemented IMF programs and government policies. We discuss the policy implications of the findings. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kutan, Ali M.; Muradoglu, Gulnur; Sudjana, Brasukra G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate co-movements, global factors and the long end of the term spread</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Byrne, Joseph P.; Fazio, Giorgio; Fiess, Norbert
The decoupling of US short and long interest rates has been a distinctive feature of the 2000s. We employ recent advances in panel econometrics to document this disconnect for industrial countries and link it to a global latent factor in long term rates. We investigate whether international forces, such as global inflation, global output, or the global savings glut may be behind this global latent factor. The savings glut is the most likely contender, suggesting that reserve accumulation and a search for yield from emerging markets has lowered long rates internationally, driving a wedge between domestic short and long rates. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Byrne, Joseph P.; Fazio, Giorgio; Fiess, Norbert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure and executive compensation contract design: A theoretical and empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Hsuan-Chu; Chou, Ting-Kai; Wang, Wen-Gine
Compensation contracts including incentive instruments not only provide executives with positive incentives to increase shareholder wealth, but also create a negative value-dilution effect for existing shareholders. This study investigates this dilemma by conducting a benefit-cost analysis under a proposed structural form valuation framework. Our design mechanism shows that, given their firms' current capital structure, shareholders are always capable of designing an optimal compensation contract to maximize their wealth. Due to the different research issue and assumptions, unlike findings of most previous studies, our model proposes that in a firm with a higher leverage ratio shareholders should provide a contract with higher incentive intensity for managers, and this proposition is supported by the empirical analyses which examine the sample of S&amp;P index firms over the period 1992-2006 after adopting an updated fixed effects model. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Hsuan-Chu; Chou, Ting-Kai; Wang, Wen-Gine</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distress risk premia in expected stock and bond returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Andrew Jianzhong
Prior studies find that shareholders' strategic actions over debtholders are significant for stock prices but not for bond prices. I find that for firms with private and public debt, strategic default has no significant effect on distress risk premia in expected stock or bond returns, suggesting that the dispersion of bondholders greatly weakens the shareholder advantage effect. The shareholder advantage effect on stock prices is only significant for firms with only private debt and to some degree affected by the dispersion of stockholders and complexity in capital structure. Overall, renegotiation friction helps explain the cross-sectional implications of strategic default for stock and bond prices. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhang, Andrew Jianzhong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are excess returns on China's Treasury bonds so predictable? The role of the monetary system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, Longzhen; Tian, Shu; Zhang, Chu
It is well documented that the time-varying bond excess returns can be explained by predetermined variables such as information in the term structure and macro economic variables. Recent studies suggest that demand and supply of bonds influence bond excess returns. We extend the literature and find that monetary system attributes affect return dynamics in the bond market. By introducing a theoretical model to forecast excess returns on Treasury bonds in the context of China's unique monetary system, this paper attributes the predicted components of bond excess returns mainly to the inflexible term structures of official interest rates set by China's central bank. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fan, Longzhen; Tian, Shu; Zhang, Chu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information content of repurchase signals: Tangible or intangible information?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liang, Woan-lih
The outperformance of repurchasing firms with a high book-to-market (B/M) ratio is usually explained by investors' undervaluation of the firm's past performance. However, several studies suggest that the underestimation of future intangible value may explain the high return associated with the share repurchase. To better understand the actual information content of repurchases, I decompose the BIM ratio into past tangible information and future intangible information and find that repurchase signals an undervaluation of the intangible return. In addition, I investigate several potential proxies for intangible information R&amp;D expenses, intangible assets, and future operating performance. My results show that intangible information signals the undervaluation of future operating performance. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liang, Woan-lih</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convertible securities in merger transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Finnerty, John D.; Jiao, Jie; Yan, An
This paper provides a rationale for the use of convertible securities as the medium of exchange in corporate change-of-control transactions. We argue that convertible securities can resolve the information asymmetry about the bidder's value while at the same time mitigating the information asymmetry about the target's value. In contrast, deals with cash or stock can only address one information asymmetry or the other but not both. Empirically, we find that a bidder is more likely to offer convertible securities, rather than all cash or all stock, when both the bidder and its target face large asymmetric information problems. We also find that both bidders and targets in convertible deals enjoy positive abnormal stock returns around takeover announcements. These findings provide empirical support for the use of convertible securities to resolve the double-sided asymmetric information problem. Finally, we find that bidder returns in convertible deals are larger than in all-cash and all-stock deals, but that target returns in convertible deals are smaller than in all-cash and all-stock deals. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Finnerty, John D.; Jiao, Jie; Yan, An</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Two to tangle: Financial development, political instability and economic growth in Argentina</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campos, Nauro F.; Karanasos, Menelaos G.; Tan, Bin
This paper studies the impact of financial liberalization on economic growth. It contributes to this literature by using an innovative econometric methodology and a unique data set of historical series. It presents power ARCH estimates for Argentina for the period from 1896 to 2000. The main results show that the long-run effect of financial liberalization on economic growth is positive while the short-run effect is negative, albeit substantially smaller. Interestingly, we find that financial development affects growth only directly, that is, not through growth volatility. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campos, Nauro F.; Karanasos, Menelaos G.; Tan, Bin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changes to mutual fund risk: Intentional or mean reverting?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cullen, Grant; Gasbarro, Dominic; Monroe, Gary S.; Zumwalt, J. Kenton
An empirical issue is whether a mutual fund's change in intertemporal risk is intentional or arises from risk mean reversion. Our methodology uses actual fund trades to identify funds that actively change risk Funds that are statistically identified as trading to change return variance or tracking error variance do not exhibit risk mean reversion. Mostly, funds trade to reduce risk and, in particular, tracking error variance. This is most evident for funds that previously attained a low tracking error variance. We find no evidence of a relation between past performance and intended changes to return variance or tracking error variance. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cullen, Grant; Gasbarro, Dominic; Monroe, Gary S.; Zumwalt, J. Kenton</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial crises in efficient markets: How fundamentalists fuel volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szafarz, Ariane
When a financial crisis breaks out, speculators typically get the blame whereas fundamentalists are presented as the safeguard against excessive volatility. This paper proposes an asset pricing model where two types of rational traders coexist: short-term speculators and long-term fundamentalists, both sharing the same information set. In this framework, excess volatility not only exists, but is actually fueled by fundamental trading. Consequently, efficient markets are more volatile with a few speculators than with many speculators. Regulators should therefore be aware that efforts to limit rational speculation might, surprisingly, end up increasing volatility. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Szafarz, Ariane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contingent convertibles. Solving or seeding the next banking crisis?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koziol, Christian; Lawrenz, Jochen
A recent proposal to enhance banking stability recommends the use of contingent convertibles (CoCos). Since these hybrid securities are mandatorily converted into equity when banks are in need of a recapitalization, they are credited for reducing banks' likelihood of financial distress. In this paper, we show within a continuous-time framework that this allegedly beneficial impact hinges critically on the assumption of complete contracts. If contracts are incomplete in the sense that manager-owners enjoy discretion over the risk of the investment program, our analysis shows that CoCo bonds always distort risk taking incentives. Our main contribution is to demonstrate that there exist conditions under which Coco bond financing increases investors' wealth, but also increases the bank's probability of financial distress, so that the banking system as a whole will be destabilized. Thus, individually rational decisions can have systemically undesirable outcomes. Further results indicate that CoCos should be used only in conjunction with devices to control risk shifting incentives. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koziol, Christian; Lawrenz, Jochen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit rating dynamics in the presence of unknown structural breaks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xing, Haipeng; Sun, Ning; Chen, Ying
In many credit risk and pricing applications, credit transition matrix is modeled by a constant transition probability or generator matrix for Markov processes. Based on empirical evidence, we model rating transition processes as piecewise homogeneous Markov chains with unobserved structural breaks. The proposed model provides explicit formulas for the posterior distribution of the time-varying rating transition generator matrices, the probability of structural break at each period and prediction of transition matrices in the presence of possible structural breaks. Estimating the model by credit rating history, we show that the structural break in rating transitions can be captured by the proposed model. We also show that structural breaks in rating dynamics are different for different industries. We then compare the prediction performance of the proposed and time-homogeneous Markov chain models. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xing, Haipeng; Sun, Ning; Chen, Ying</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Great Recession: US dynamics and spillovers to the world economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bagliano, Fabio C.; Morana, Claudio
This paper provides an empirical investigation of both the within-US and international channels of transmission of macroeconomic and financial shocks by means of a 50-country macroeconometric model (estimated over the 1980-2009 period), including measures of excess liquidity and financial fragility, specifically designed in order to evaluate the relevance of the boom-bust credit cycle view put forward as an interpretation of the recent "Great Recession" episode. We find that such a view is consistent with the empirical evidence. Moreover, concerning the real effects of financial shocks within the US, we detect stronger evidence of an asset prices channel, rather than a liquidity channel. Concerning the spillovers to the world economy, we find that while financial disturbances are transmitted to foreign countries through US house and stock price dynamics, as well as excess liquidity creation, the trade channel is the key trasmission mechanism of real shocks. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bagliano, Fabio C.; Morana, Claudio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed or speculative: Short selling analyst recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blau, Benjamin M.; Wade, Chip
Christophe et al. (2010) find evidence of abnormal short activity prior to analyst downgrades and argue that short sellers may be violating SEC insider-trading laws by trading on information obtained from analysts about upcoming downgrades. However, observing abnormal shorting prior to downgrades is not tantamount to determining that short sellers are trading on tips from analysts unless shorting is abnormally low prior to upgrades. This paper revisits this issue. While we observe abnormal shorting prior to downgrades, we also find markedly higher shorting prior to upgrades. In fact, the short-selling patterns surrounding both downgrades and upgrades are remarkably symmetric indicating that short sellers during the pre-recommendation period are not unusually informed about the direction of upcoming recommendation changes. If anything, our findings indicate that short selling prior to analyst recommendations is more likely speculative than informed. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blau, Benjamin M.; Wade, Chip</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash holdings in private firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bigelli, Marco; Sanchez-Vidal, Javier
Evidence from a wide sample of Italian private firms shows that cash holdings are significantly related with smaller size, higher risk and lower effective tax rates, therefore supporting predictions from the trade-off model. More cash is also held by firms with longer cash conversion cycles and lower financing deficits, as predicted by the financing hierarchy theory. Reported evidence also shows that dividend payments are associated with more cash holdings, and both bank debt and net working capital represent good cash-substitutes. When controlling for macroeconomic and industry factors, some variables lose their significance, but the general findings are confirmed. Finally, cash-rich companies are found to be more profitable, to pay more dividends and to invest more in a medium-term future horizon. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bigelli, Marco; Sanchez-Vidal, Javier</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the rise and decline of the Japanese main bank system: The changing effects of bank rent extraction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Xueping; Yao, Jun
This paper shows how main bank rent extraction affects corporate decisions about investment and financing during financial regulatory reform. Our model predicts that limited loanable funds can initially contain main bank controlled overinvestment, even when new equity is available to the firm. Abundant funds facilitate overinvestment to the detriment of firm profitability. A shift of control rights back to the firm due to financial deregulation produces an "equity for upside potential and bank debt for downside risk" bias against the banks. A stock market and real estate boom in Japan made it harder than ever for the banks to diversify risk. The insights from this analysis help explain why Japan's main bank system was beneficial in the (capital constrained) postwar period but became harmful during the (capital abundant and even bubbly) 1980s. and why the adverse shocks of the post-deregulation 1990s had such severe effects on the banking system. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Xueping; Yao, Jun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of macroeconomic news on metal futures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elder, John; Miao, Hong; Ramchander, Sanjay
This paper uses intra-day data for the period 2002 through 2008 to examine the intensity, direction, and speed of impact of US macroeconomic news announcements on the return, volatility and trading volume of three important commodities - gold, silver and copper futures. We find that the response of metal futures to economic news surprises is both swift and significant, with the 8:30 am set of announcements - in particular, nonfarm payrolls and durable goods orders - having the largest impact. Furthermore, announcements that reflect an unexpected improvement in the economy tend to have a negative impact on gold and silver prices; however, they tend to have a positive effect on copper prices. In comparison, realized volatility and volume for all three metals are positively influenced by economic news. Finally, there is evidence that several news announcements exert an asymmetric impact on market activity variables. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elder, John; Miao, Hong; Ramchander, Sanjay</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of strategic interaction on earnings expectations associated with corporate product strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chen, Po-Jung; Lin, Wen-Chun
We examine how strategic interaction in an industry influences the earnings expectations of financial analysts with regard to new product strategies. We find that following announcement of new products, analysts revise earnings forecasts upward more for announcing firms competing in low-strategic interaction industries than for firms competing in high-strategic interaction industries. For value-enhancing (value-reducing) product strategies, earnings forecast revisions are more favorable for rivals competing under a high (low) degree of strategic interaction than for rivals competing under a low (high) degree of strategic interaction. Overall empirical evidence indicates that the nature of strategic competition within the industry is important in assessing the market expectations of earnings for new product announcers and their rivals. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chen, Po-Jung; Lin, Wen-Chun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Yes, dividends are disappearing: Worldwide evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fatemi, Ali; Bildik, Recep
This study examines the patterns in payout policies worldwide. Utilizing data from a sample of more than 17,000 companies from 33 different countries, we find evidence in support of a significant worldwide decline in the propensity to pay dividends. Most of the decline is due to the payout policies of smaller and less profitable firms with comparatively more investment opportunities. We find that larger firms, those with higher profitability, and firms with low growth opportunities have a greater propensity to pay dividends. The proportion of dividend payers varies substantially across industries as well. However, the proportion of firms paying dividends has declined over time, even after firms' characteristics have been controlled for. Moreover, aggregate dividends are highly concentrated in that they are paid only by a small group of firms. Our findings indicate that there has been a significant decline in the average dividend payout ratios over the years. The decline in the mean dividend payout ratios as well as the proportion of payers is much more pronounced in civil law countries. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fatemi, Ali; Bildik, Recep</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fast profits: Investor sentiment and stock returns during Ramadan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bialkowski, Jedrzej; Etebari, Ahmad; Wisniewski, Tomasz Piotr
Observed by more than 1.5 billion Muslims, Ramadan is one of the most celebrated religious traditions in the world. We investigate stock returns during Ramadan for 14 predominantly Muslim countries over the years 1989-2007. The results show that stock returns during Ramadan are significantly higher and less volatile than during the rest of the year. No discernible declines in market liquidity are recorded. We find these results consistent with a notion that Ramadan positively affects investor psychology, as it promotes feelings of solidarity and social identity among Muslims world-wide, leading to optimistic beliefs that extend to investment decisions. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bialkowski, Jedrzej; Etebari, Ahmad; Wisniewski, Tomasz Piotr</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcies of small firms and lending relationship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shimizu, Katsutoshi
This paper empirically investigates the role played by relatively small banks in the Japanese local credit market. We test the hypothesis that small banks enhance the recovery rate from the financial distress and reduce the bankruptcy ratio of small firms. Empirical evidence suggests that small banks specialize more in relationship loans to small firms. However, this expertise is limited to the loans to unincorporated firms or those with a very small number of employees. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shimizu, Katsutoshi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Higher co-moments and asset pricing on London Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kostakis, Alexandros; Muhammad, Kashif; Siganos, Antonios
This study examines the asset pricing implications of preferences over the higher moments of returns' distributions. We show that in a market populated by risk-averse, prudent and temperate investors, firms whose returns exhibit negative coskewness or positive cokurtosis should yield higher premia relative to counterpart firms with positive coskewness and negative cokurtosis respectively. These theoretical predictions are empirically tested using a comprehensive dataset of shares listed on the London Stock Exchange during the period 1986-2008. Our empirical results confirm that coskewness and cokurtosis premia are genuinely priced in the UK market, over and above what covariance risk, size, value and momentum factors can explain. We also show that a theoretically motivated, higher co-moment asset pricing model has significant explanatory ability over the cross-section of coskewness and cokurtosis portfolio returns. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kostakis, Alexandros; Muhammad, Kashif; Siganos, Antonios</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-country analysis of secular cash trends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iskandar-Datta, Mai E.; Jia, Yonghong
This study documents a pronounced secular upward trend in cash holdings which is almost systemic across seven industrialized countries over 1991-2008, with France exhibiting a modest rise and Japan a substantial decline. However, the driving forces underlying the cash pattern are not uniform across countries. While the evolution in firm characteristics necessitated elevated cash balances, the time-varying firm attributes explain the cash trend only in Canada, France, UK and the US. The agency motive plays a role in the rise in cash balances in Germany. Our analysis highlights that the functioning of the financial system is crucial to corporate cash policy as Australia's cash pattern is driven by shallow private credit markets that curbed cash reserves earlier on and the decelerating cash trend in Japan is ascribed to financial reforms. While there is a degree of commonality in the determinants of cash policies, we find some divergence in cash practices. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Iskandar-Datta, Mai E.; Jia, Yonghong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comparative study of the probability of default for global financial firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Camara, Antonio; Popova, Ivilina; Simkins, Betty
This article presents a modification of Merton's (1976) ruin option pricing model to estimate the implied probability of default from stock and option market prices. To test the model, we analyze all global financial firms with traded options in the US and focus on the subprime mortgage crisis period. We compare the performance of the implied probability of default from our model to the expected default frequencies based on the Moody's KMV model and agency credit ratings by constructing cumulative accuracy profiles (CAP) and the receiver operating characteristic (ROC). We find that the probability of default estimates from our model are equal or superior to other credit risk measures studied based on CAP and ROC. In particular, during the subprime crisis our model surpassed credit ratings and matched or exceeded KMV in anticipating the magnitude of the crisis. We have also found some initial evidence that adding off-balance-sheet derivatives exposure improves the performance of the KMV model. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Camara, Antonio; Popova, Ivilina; Simkins, Betty</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Perspectives on international and corporate finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucey, Brian M.
nan</description><author>Lucey, Brian M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The politics of financial development: The role of interest groups and government capabilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becerra, O.; Cavallo, E.; Scartascini, C.
Although financial development is good for long-term growth, not all countries pursue policies that render full financial development. This paper builds on an extensive political economy literature to construct a theoretical model showing that the intensity of opposition to financial development by incumbents depends on both their degree of credit dependency and the role of governments in credit markets. Empirical evidence for this claim is provided, and the results suggest that lower opposition to financial development leads to an effective increase in credit markets' development only in those countries that have high government capabilities. Moreover, improvements in government capabilities have a significant impact on credit market development only in those countries where credit dependency is high (thus, opposition is low). This paper therefore contributes to this rich literature by providing a unified account of credit market development that includes two of its main determinants, traditionally considered in isolation. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Becerra, O.; Cavallo, E.; Scartascini, C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political crises and the stock market integration of emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frijns, Bart; Tourani-Rad, Alireza; Indriawan, Ivan
This paper investigates the role of political crises in explaining the degree of stock market integration in emerging markets over the period 1991-2006. Using the International Crisis Behavior database, which contains detailed information on political crises around the world, and employing data on more than 15,500 firms, we assess whether political crises affect stock market integration in 19 emerging markets in South and East Asia, Latin America, and Central and Eastern Europe. We conclude that crises with certain characteristics generally reduce the level of stock market integration in these regions. In particular, the beginning of a political crisis, its severity, the involvement of the US in the conflict, and the number of parties involved in a crisis all have impacts on the level of stock market integration in these markets. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frijns, Bart; Tourani-Rad, Alireza; Indriawan, Ivan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Missing elements in US financial reform: A Kubler-Ross interpretation of the inadequacy of the Dodd-Frank Act</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kane, Edward J.
The success of any treatment plan depends on how completely the problems it targets have been diagnosed. The precrisis bubble in securitization can be traced to incentive conflict that allows national safety nets to subsidize leveraged risk-taking. Safety-net subsidies encouraged regulation-induced innovations that enabled firms to take hard-to-monitor risks and to make themselves politically, administratively, and economically difficult for government officials to fail and unwind. This paper summarizes the incentive conflicts that led creditors and internal and external supervisors to short-cut and outsource due diligence. The Dodd-Frank strategy of reform does not adequately acknowledge or address these conflicts. The key step needed is to develop an effective statistical metric for measuring the ex ante value of safety-net support in the aggregate and at individual institutions. To accomplish this, government and industry need to rethink the informational obligations that insured financial institutions and their regulators owe to taxpayers as de facto investors and to change the way that information on industry balance sheets and risk exposures is reported, verified, and used. Without reforms in the practical duties imposed on industry and governmental officials and in the way these duties are enforced, financial safety nets will continue to expand and their expansion will undermine financial stability by generating large rewards for creative and aggressive risk-takers that are smart enough to cash in their share of safety-net benefits before they evaporate. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kane, Edward J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of earnout as acquisition payment currency and bidder's value gains</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barbopoulos, Leonidas; Sudarsanam, Sudi
We examine the wealth effects of a comprehensive sample of UK bidders offering contingent payment, or earnout, as consideration for their acquisitions. We show that bidders using earnout generate significantly higher announcement and post-acquisition value gains than bidders using non-earnout currencies (such as cash, stock exchange, or mixed payments). We construct a logistic model to predict when it is optimal for a bidder to offer earnout. We show that bidders offering earnout optimally enjoy significantly higher announcement and post-acquisition gains than bidders offering non-earnout currencies, consistent with our model of the choice of the optimal method of payment. Overall, we provide robust evidence that earnout is an effective payment mechanism to mitigate valuation risk to acquirers, and also enhances acquirer value during the announcement and post-acquisition periods. Our paper contributes to the broader literature on how corporate acquirers use payment currency to manage information asymmetry and the attendant valuation risk. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barbopoulos, Leonidas; Sudarsanam, Sudi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can VAR models capture regime shifts in asset returns? A long-horizon strategic asset allocation perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guidolin, Massimo; Hyde, Stuart
It is often suggested that through a judicious choice of predictors that track business cycles and market sentiment, simple vector autoregressive (VAR) models could produce optimal strategic portfolio allocations that hedge against the bull and bear dynamics typical of financial markets. However, a distinct literature exists that shows that nonlinear econometric frameworks, such as Markov switching (MS), are also natural tools to compute optimal portfolios in the presence of stochastic good and bad market states. In this paper we examine whether simple VARs can produce portfolio rules similar to those obtained under MS, by studying the effects of expanding both the order of the VAR and the number/selection of predictor variables included. In a typical stock-bond strategic asset allocation problem, we compute the out-of-sample certainty equivalent returns for a wide range of VARs and compare these measures of performance with those typical of nonlinear models for a long-horizon investor with constant relative risk aversion. We conclude that most VARs cannot produce portfolio rules, hedging demands, or (net of transaction costs) out-of-sample performances that approximate those obtained from equally simple nonlinear frameworks. We also compute the improvement in realized performance that may be achieved adopting more complex MS models and report this may be substantial in the case of regime switching ARCH. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guidolin, Massimo; Hyde, Stuart</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital incentives and adequacy for securitizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roesch, Daniel; Scheule, Harald
This paper analyzes the capital incentives and adequacy of financial institutions for asset portfolio securitizations. The empirical analysis is based on US securitization rating and impairment data. The paper finds that regulatory capital rules for securitizations may be insufficient to cover implied losses during economic downturns such as the Global Financial Crisis. In addition, the rating process of securitizations provides capital arbitrage incentives for financial institutions and may further reduce regulatory capital requirements. These policy-relevant findings assume that the ratings assigned by rating agencies are correct and can be used to build a test for the ability of Basel capital regulations to cover downturn losses. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roesch, Daniel; Scheule, Harald</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short selling of ADRs and foreign market short-sale constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blau, Benjamin M.; Van Ness, Robert A.; Warr, Richard S.
We examine the effect of home market short-sale constraints on securities that also trade in other countries that have more liberal short-sale rules. In particular, we focus on the case of ADRs traded in the US, as in some cases, the home markets of these ADRs prohibit short selling. We find that short sellers more heavily trade ADRs from countries where short selling is prohibited than from markets where short selling is allowed. Furthermore, we find that the greater levels of short selling in ADRs with binding home-market constraints is driven by stocks with greater dispersion of investors' opinion, low fundamentals-to-price ratios, and recent price increases. Our results support the hypothesis that short sellers target ADRs with home market short-sale constraints because these ADRs are more often subject to temporary misvaluation. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blau, Benjamin M.; Van Ness, Robert A.; Warr, Richard S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do premiums paid for bank M&amp;As reflect? The case of the European Union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hagendorff, Jens; Hernando, Ignacio; Nieto, Maria J.; Wall, Larry D.
We analyze the takeover premiums paid for a sample of domestic and cross-border bank takeovers in the European Union between 1997 and 2007. We find that acquiring banks value profitable, high-growth and low risk targets. We also find that the strength of bank regulation and supervision as well as deposit insurance regimes in Europe have measurable effects on takeover pricing. Stricter bank regulatory regimes and stronger deposit insurance schemes lower the takeover premiums paid by acquiring banks. This result, presumably in anticipation of higher compliance costs, is driven by domestic deals. Similar qualitative results are found for both the entire sample and the sample of publicly traded targets. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hagendorff, Jens; Hernando, Ignacio; Nieto, Maria J.; Wall, Larry D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading frequency and volatility clustering</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xue, Yi; Gencay, Ramazan
Volatility clustering, with autocorrelations of the hyperbolic decay rate, is unquestionably one of the most important stylized facts of financial time series. This paper presents a market microstructure model that is able to generate volatility clustering with hyperbolically decaying autocorrelations via traders with multiple trading frequencies, using Bayesian information updates in an incomplete market. The model illustrates that signal extraction, which is induced by multiple trading frequencies, can increase the persistence of the volatility of returns. Furthermore, we show that the volatility of the underlying time series of returns varies greatly with the number of traders in the market. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xue, Yi; Gencay, Ramazan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price discovery and volatility spillovers in the European Union emissions trading scheme: A high-frequency analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rittler, Daniel
This paper models the relationship of European Union Allowance spot- and futures-prices within the second commitment period of the European Union emissions trading scheme. Based on high-frequency data, we analyze the transmission of information in first and second conditional moments. To reveal long-run price discovery, we compute common factor weights of Schwarz and Szakmary (1994) and information shares of Hasbrouck (1995) based on estimated coefficients of a VECM. To analyze the short-run dynamics, we perform Granger-causality tests. We identify the futures market to be the leader of the long-run price discovery process, whereas the informational role of the futures market increases over time. In addition, we employ a version of the UECCC-GARCH model as introduced by Conrad and Karanasos (2010) to analyze the volatility transmission structure. The volatility analysis indicates a close relationship between the volatility dynamics of both markets, whereas in particular we observe spillovers from the futures to the spot market. As a whole the investigation reveals that the futures market incorporates information first and then transfers the information to the spot market. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rittler, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of implied skewness and kurtosis changes prior to earnings announcements for stock and option returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diavatopoulos, Dean; Doran, James S.; Fodor, Andy; Peterson, David R.
We use option prices to examine whether changes in stock return skewness and kurtosis preceding earnings announcements provide information about subsequent stock and option returns. We demonstrate that changes in jump risk premiums can lead to changes in implied skewness and kurtosis and are also associated with the mean and variability of the stock price response to the earnings announcement. We find that changes in both moments have strong predictive power for future stock returns, even after controlling for implied volatility. Additionally, changes in both moments predict call returns, while put return predictability is primarily linked to changes in skewness. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Diavatopoulos, Dean; Doran, James S.; Fodor, Andy; Peterson, David R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital requirements and bank behavior in the UK: Are there lessons for international capital standards?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, William B.; Osborne, Matthew
The financial crisis prompted widespread interest in developing a better understanding of how capital regulation drives bank behavior. This paper uses a unique, comprehensive database of regulatory capital requirements on all UK banks to examine their effects on capital, lending and balance sheet management behavior. We find that capital requirements that include firm-specific, time-varying add-ons set by supervisors affect banks' desired capital ratios and that resulting adjustments to capital and lending depend on the gap between actual and target ratios. We use these results to measure the effects of a capital regime that includes features similar to those embedded in the UK framework. Our results suggest that countercyclical capital requirements may be less effective in slowing credit activity when banks can readily satisfy them with lower-quality (lower-costing) capital elements versus higher-quality common equity. Given the size of the UK banking sector and the global nature of many of the largest institutions in the UK banking sector, the results have implications for the ongoing debate surrounding the design and calibration of international capital standards. Crown Copyright (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Francis, William B.; Osborne, Matthew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral and its substitutes in emerging markets' lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkhoff, Lukas; Neuberger, Doris; Rungruxsirivorn, Ornsiri
Due to opaque information and weak enforcement in emerging loan markets, the need for collateral is high, whereas borrowers lack adequate assets to pledge as collateral. How is this puzzle solved? We find for a representative sample from Northeast Thailand that indeed most loans do not include any tangible assets as collateral. Instead, lenders enforce collateral-free loans through third-party guarantees and relationship lending, but also through modifying loan terms, such as reducing loan size. Guarantees are the relatively most important substitute, they reduce collateral requirements independently of relationship lending and they are more often used by formal financial institutions. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Menkhoff, Lukas; Neuberger, Doris; Rungruxsirivorn, Ornsiri</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross-section of mutual fund fee dispersion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iannotta, Giuliano; Navone, Marco
In this paper, we empirically analyze the factors affecting the cross section of mutual fund fee dispersion. In the context of equity mutual funds, fee dispersion stems primarily from the heterogeneity of products, clienteles and production functions. However, the relevant theory predicts that search costs can also generate fee dispersion. By controlling for observable sources of heterogeneity, we find that fee dispersion decreases with fund size and age, as well as with the amount of assets under management of the investment company. In addition, we find lower levels of fee dispersion for funds that charge marketing and distribution fees. Although we cannot rule out the possibility that these factors are a proxy for some unobserved source of heterogeneity, our results are also consistent with the theoretical prediction that search costs positively affect fee dispersion. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Iannotta, Giuliano; Navone, Marco</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International diversification: An extreme value approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chollete, Loran; de la Pena, Victor; Lu, Ching-Chih
International diversification has costs and benefits, depending on the degree of asset dependence. We study international diversification with two dependence measures: correlations and extreme dependence. We discover that dependence has typically increased over time, and document mixed evidence on heavy tails in individual countries. Moreover, we uncover three additional findings related to dependence. First, the timing of downside risk differs depending on the region. Surprisingly, recent Latin American returns exhibit little downside risk. Second, Latin America exhibits a great deal of correlation complexity. Third, according to the empirical results, correlation does not vary with returns, but extreme dependence does vary monotonically with regional returns. Our results are consistent with a tradeoff between international diversification and systemic risk. They also suggest international limits to diversification, and that international investors demand some compensation for joint downside risk during extreme events. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chollete, Loran; de la Pena, Victor; Lu, Ching-Chih</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product markets and corporate investment: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akdogu, Evrim; MacKay, Peter
Investment patterns often associated with agency and information problems can emerge as rational responses to product-market rivalry. We illustrate this result when industry players make simultaneous or sequential investment decisions in the face of two negative externalities. One externality arises when all competing firms invest, thus eroding the gains to investment accruing to any one firm. Another externality arises when some firms do not invest and lose out to rivals who do invest. The value of investment therefore depends on the investment's intrinsic merits and the actions of all competitors. Our analysis can rationalize investment patterns that might appear suboptimal when such externalities are ignored. For instance, our simultaneous model can justify investment levels that might otherwise be interpreted as under- or over-investment. Our sequential model shows that value-maximizing firms might optimally herd in their investment decisions. We present evidence supporting key aspects of both the simultaneous and sequential models. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akdogu, Evrim; MacKay, Peter</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An improved estimation method and empirical properties of the probability of informed trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yan, Yuxing; Zhang, Shaojun
We report evidence that boundary solutions can cause a bias in the estimate of the probability of informed trading (PIN). We develop an algorithm to overcome this bias and use it to estimate PIN for nearly 80,000 stock-quarters between 1993 and 2004. We obtain two sets of PIN estimates by using the factorized likelihood functions in both Easley, Hvidkjaer, and O'Hara (EHO, 2010) and Lin and Ke (LK, 2011), respectively. We find that the estimate based on the EHO factorization is systematically smaller than the estimate based on the LK factorization, meaning that there is a downward bias associated with the EHO factorization. In addition, we find that boundary solutions appear with a very high frequency when the LK factorization is used. Thus it is necessary to use the LK factorization together with the algorithm in this paper. At last, we document several interesting empirical properties of PIN. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yan, Yuxing; Zhang, Shaojun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>National culture and corporate debt maturity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zheng, Xiaolan; El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.
We investigate the influence of national culture on corporate debt maturity choice. Based on the framework of Williamson, we argue that culture located in social embeddedness level can shape contracting environments by serving as an informal constraint that affects human actors' incentives and choices in market exchange. We therefore expect national culture to be related to debt maturity structure after controlling for legal, political, financial, and economic institutions. Using Hofstede's four cultural dimensions (uncertainty avoidance, collectivism, power distance, and masculinity) as proxies for culture, and using a sample of 114,723 firm-years from 40 countries over the 1991-2006 period, we find robust evidence that firms located in countries with high uncertainty avoidance, high collectivism, high power distance, and high masculinity tend to use more short-term debt. We interpret our results as consistent with the view that national culture helps explain cross-country variations in the maturity structure of corporate debt. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zheng, Xiaolan; El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio selection with qualitative input</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiarawongse, Anant; Kiatsupaibul, Seksan; Tirapat, Sunti; Van Roy, Benjamin
We formulate a mean-variance portfolio selection problem that accommodates qualitative input about expected returns anti provide an algorithm that solves the problem. This model and algorithm can be used, for example, when a portfolio manager determines that one industry will benefit more from a regulatory change than another but is unable to quantify the degree of difference. Qualitative views are expressed in terms of linear inequalities among expected returns. Our formulation builds on the Black-Litterman model for portfolio selection. The algorithm makes use of an adaptation of the hit-and-run method for Markov chain Monte Carlo simulation. We also present computational results that illustrate advantages of our approach over alternative heuristic methods for incorporating qualitative input. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiarawongse, Anant; Kiatsupaibul, Seksan; Tirapat, Sunti; Van Roy, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accruals quality and analyst coverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lobo, Gerald J.; Song, Minsup; Stanford, Mary
We provide evidence that analyst coverage increases as accruals quality decreases. This finding is consistent with the services of financial analysts becoming more valuable and in greater demand as accruals provide weaker signals about future cash flows. Further, it is accruals quality associated with innate uncertainty in the firm's operating environment that attracts analysts even after controlling for operating uncertainty associated with cash flow and stock return volatility. This suggests that low quality accruals provide an opportunity for analysts to benefit from generating private information. Consistent with analysts providing compensating information, we find that forecasts for firms with lower accruals quality contain more private information. (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Lobo, Gerald J.; Song, Minsup; Stanford, Mary</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial advisors: A case of babysitters?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hackethal, Andreas; Haliassos, Michael; Jappelli, Tullio
We use two data sets, one from a large brokerage and another from a major bank, to ask: (i) whether financial advisors are more likely to be matched with poorer, uninformed investors or with richer and experienced investors; (ii) how advised accounts actually perform relative to self-managed accounts: (iii) whether the contribution of independent and bank advisors is similar. We find that advised accounts offer on average lower net returns and inferior risk-return tradeoffs (Sharpe ratios). Trading costs contribute to outcomes, as advised accounts feature higher turnover, consistent with commissions being the main source of advisor income. Results are robust to controlling for investor and local area characteristics. The results apply with stronger force to bank advisors than to independent financial advisors, consistent with greater limitations on bank advisory services. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hackethal, Andreas; Haliassos, Michael; Jappelli, Tullio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gravity and culture in foreign portfolio investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Raj; Kearney, Colm; Lucey, Brian
Using panel regression estimates from the IMF's CPIS survey of foreign debt and equity portfolios across 174 originating and 50 destination countries from 2001 to 2007, we clarify the role of culture and extend the set of cultural variables that have been investigated in gravity models of foreign portfolio investment (FPI). Incorporating Hofstede's cultural dimensions of individualism, masculinity, power distance and uncertainty avoidance, we show how cultural traits in both originating and destination countries, as well as the cultural distances that separate them, interact with geographic distance and other gravity variables to determine global FPI patterns. We find hitherto unreported effects and show that while gravity always deters FPI, aspects of culture and cultural distance can offset this by supporting FPI. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, Raj; Kearney, Colm; Lucey, Brian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overbidding in fixed rate tenders: The role of exposure risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ewerhart, Christian; Cassola, Nuno; Valla, Natacha
The fixed rate tender is one of the main procedures used by central banks in the implementation of their monetary policies. While academic research has largely dismissed the procedure owing to its tendency to encourage overbidding, central banks such as the ECB and the Bank of England have continued using it. We investigate this apparent conflict by considering an auction-theoretic setting with private information about declining marginal valuations. Since overbidding entails exposure risk, an equilibrium may exist even if bids are costless and the intended volume is pre-announced. In fact, the allotment quota may be strictly below one with certainty. Also with adaptive expectations, overbidding need not escalate. However, the resulting allocation is typically inefficient. Empirical proxies of exposure risk are significant in both euro and sterling operations. Our findings have implications, in particular, for the potential reintroduction of pro rata allotment in the main refinancing operations of the Eurosystem. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ewerhart, Christian; Cassola, Nuno; Valla, Natacha</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of time value in convertible bond call policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bajo, Emanuele; Barbi, Massimiliano
Since the seminal work of Ingersoll (1977b) the optimal time in which a firm should redeem its outstanding convertible bonds has received large attention by the financial literature. Several studies have put forward a number of possible costs and benefits for a firm if it interrupts the life of its convertible bonds prior to their contractual maturity. However, in this paper we argue that the managerial decision to call back a convertible bond is mainly driven by a fundamental variable almost neglected up until now: the time value extraction from bondholders' conversion option. Accordingly, we propose a measure for the effective convenience of calling which we define as net time value advantage and we show, using a survival analysis, that it is more effective than previously proposed measures in explaining the firms' observed call policy. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bajo, Emanuele; Barbi, Massimiliano</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting the incentive effects of executive stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tang, Chun-Hua
We develop a multiperiod framework to evaluate the incentive effects of executive stock options (ESOs). For a given increase in the grant-date firm stock price (and a concurrent increase in return volatility), the increment of total value at the vesting date acts as a proxy for the incentive effects of ESOs. If the option is attached to the existing contract without adjusting cash compensation, we suggest that a firm should not always fix the strike price to the grant-date stock price; instead, the strike price should vary with the length of the vesting period. We also show that, compared with at-the-money options, restricted stock generates greater incentives to increase stock prices in some scenarios, especially when equity-based awards are vested early. If the vesting period is long, the firm could grant options instead of restricted stock to maximize incentives. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tang, Chun-Hua</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A unique "T+1 trading rule" in China: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Ming; Li, Zhan; Tu, Zhiyong
Unique to the world, China adopts a "T + 1 trading rule", which prevents investors from selling stocks bought on the same day. We develop a dynamic price manipulation model to study the effects of the "T + 1 trading rule". Compared to the "T + 0 trading rule", which allows investors to buy and sell the same stocks during the same day, we show that the "T + 1 trading rule" reduces the total trading volume and price volatility, and improves the trend chasers' welfare when trend-chasing is strong. An empirical test using data on China's B-share stock market supports the model's theoretical predictions. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guo, Ming; Li, Zhan; Tu, Zhiyong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Chaebol-affiliated analysts: Conflicts of interest and market responses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, Kyojik Roy; Mantecon, Tomas; Altintig, Z. Ayca
Some Korean business groups, or chaebols, have a large stake in securities firms that issue analysts' reports on their member companies. This structure is unique in that industrial companies and securities firms are affiliated and operate within the same group. We investigate the informational content of earnings forecasts, stock recommendations and target prices made by the chaebol-affiliated analysts, using data collected between 2000 and 2008. The chaebol analysts tend to make more optimistic earnings forecasts for the member companies. The mean EPS forecast error (5.36%) of the affiliated analysts for the same chaebol company are significantly larger than that (3.23%) of other chaebol and independent analysts. The chaebol analysts also assign better recommendations by almost one level and set target prices 2.5% higher to the member companies after controlling for company and analyst characteristics. These results are consistent with the hypothesis that chaebol analysts' reports are biased by conflicts of interest. Stock market reactions do not differ in response to announcements of stock recommendations issued by affiliated vs. non-affiliated analysts. This suggests that capital markets do not recognize the conflicts of interest inherent in chaebol analysts' reports. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Song, Kyojik Roy; Mantecon, Tomas; Altintig, Z. Ayca</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order flow, bid-ask spread and trading density in foreign exchange markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Shikuan; Chien, Chih-Chung; Chang, Ming-Jen
This paper examines the implications of market microstructure for foreign exchange markets. We argue that the usual order flow model needs to be recast in broader terms to incorporate the transaction costs of liquidity and the limitation of price discovery through order flows that involve low trading density currencies. Using a daily data set, we find that order flows are inadequate when it comes to explaining the changes in the low trading density currencies. Alternatively, within the high trading density, both order flows and bid-ask spreads significantly affect the foreign exchange rate returns. Our findings suggest that the order flow model is better at incorporating these microstructure effects except for some currencies with a very high level of trading density. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Shikuan; Chien, Chih-Chung; Chang, Ming-Jen</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management and auditor specialization in the post-sox era: An examination of the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeBoskey, David Gregory; Jiang, Wei
This study examines the impact of auditor specialization on bank loan loss provisions for a large cross-section of US banks for the period 2002-2006. We find a positive relationship between earning (before provision) and loan loss provision, suggesting that bank managers use LLP to smooth earnings in the post-SOX period. However, this relationship is significantly moderated by audit industry expertise, providing strong evidence that industry specialization constrains income smoothing. In further analysis, we find some evidence that auditor specialization is more effective in reducing potentially incoming-increasing earnings management. Our results hold after controlling for self-selection bias and are robust to alternative measures of industry specialization. Overall, our findings support the conclusion that audit industry expertise plays an effective monitoring role in constraining management's discretionary accounting choices. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeBoskey, David Gregory; Jiang, Wei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of unconventional monetary policy on the market for collateral: The case of the French bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avouyi-Dovi, Sanvi; Idier, Julien
We consider the channel consisting in transferring the credit risk associated with refinancing operations between financial institutions to market participants. In particular, we analyze liquidity and volatility premia on the French government debt securities market, since these assets are used as collateral both in the open market operations of the ECB and on the interbank market. In our time-varying transition probability Markov-switching (TVTP-MS) model, we highlight the existence of two regimes. In one of them, which we refer to as the conventional regime, monetary policy neutrality is verified; in the other, which we dub the unconventional regime, monetary policy operations lead to volatility and liquidity premia on the collateral market. The existence of these conventional and unconventional regimes highlights some asymmetries in the conduct of monetary policy. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avouyi-Dovi, Sanvi; Idier, Julien</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolios in disguise? Window dressing in bond fund holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ortiz, Cristina; Luis Sarto, Jose; Vicente, Luis
This paper builds on the limited body of research on window dressing by bond mutual funds. Our monthly bias-free sample allows us to undertake a more comprehensive study than is possible with the quarterly data traditionally employed in otherwise similar studies. We test window dressing in a straightforward manner using monthly undisclosed portfolios, which makes it possible to compare changes in public debt allocations around quarterly disclosures. Our results support the hypothesis that window dressing patterns vary with market conditions. We also conduct thorough tests that indicate the significant influence of fund size on window dressing. Individual analyses provide evidence that this cosmetic practice is not a widespread behaviour in the Spanish bond fund industry. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ortiz, Cristina; Luis Sarto, Jose; Vicente, Luis</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The 1/N investment strategy is optimal under high model ambiguity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pflug, Georg Ch; Pichler, Alois; Wozabal, David
The 1/N investment strategy, i.e. the strategy to split one's wealth uniformly between the available investment possibilities, recently received plenty of attention in the literature. In this paper, we demonstrate that the uniform investment strategy is rational in situations where an agent is faced with a sufficiently high degree of model uncertainty in the form of ambiguous loss distributions. More specifically, we use a classical risk minimization framework to show that, for a broad class of risk measures, as the uncertainty concerning the probabilistic model increases, the optimal decisions tend to the uniform investment strategy. To illustrate the theoretical results of the paper, we investigate the Markowitz portfolio selection model as well as Conditional Value-at-Risk minimization with ambiguous loss distributions. Subsequently, we set up a numerical study using real market data to demonstrate the convergence of optimal portfolio decisions to the uniform investment strategy. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pflug, Georg Ch; Pichler, Alois; Wozabal, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and capital allocations of diversified firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chen, I.-Ju
We examine how various aspects of corporate governance structures affect the capital allocation inefficiency that drives the value discounts of diversified firms. Diversified firms with more effective internal or external governance mechanisms experience more efficient investment allocations at both the firm and segment levels and show less of a diversification discount. The efficiency of the investment allocation process is better for diversified firms with high board independence, low board busyness, high institutional ownership, high outside director ownership, high CEO equity-based pay, high audit quality, and strong shareholder rights. The results hold after controlling for other potential influences. Our evidence suggests that corporate governance considerations are important in assessing the relation between investment efficiency and firm value for diversified firms. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chen, I.-Ju</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are emerging market indicators of vulnerability to financial crises decoupling from global factors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Felices, Guillermo; Wieladek, Tomasz
This paper assesses the extent to which common factors underlie indicators of vulnerability to financial crises in emerging market economies (EMEs) and whether this link is changing over time. We use a Bayesian dynamic common factor model to estimate their common component in a sample of up to 41 countries including both developed as well as emerging economies. This permits us to interpret the component in common to both of them as a global factor. We introduce time variation into the model to investigate whether indicators are decoupling from global factors over time. While decoupling can be observed in a few cases, the exposure to global factors in most countries tends to fluctuate around the mean. Broadly speaking then, the answer is no. Crown Copyright (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Felices, Guillermo; Wieladek, Tomasz</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A systematic approach to multi-period stress testing of portfolio credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Thomas; Jandacka, Martin; Mencia, Javier; Summer, Martin
We propose a new method for analysing multi-period stress scenarios for portfolio credit risk more systematically than in current macro stress tests. The plausibility of a scenario is quantified by its distance from an average scenario. For a given level of plausibility, we search systematically for the most adverse scenario. This ensures that no plausible scenario will be missed. We show how this method can be applied to some models already in use by practitioners. While worst case search requires numerical optimisation we show that we can work with reasonably good linear approximations to the portfolio loss function. This makes systematic multi-period stress testing computationally efficient and easy to implement. Applying our approach to data from the Spanish loan register we show that, compared to standard stress test procedures, our method identifies more harmful scenarios that are equally plausible. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Breuer, Thomas; Jandacka, Martin; Mencia, Javier; Summer, Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank discrimination, holding bank ownership, and economic consequences: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Zhengfei; Zhu, Jigao; Zhang, Weining
This paper finds that compared with Chinese state-owned firms, non-state-owned firms have a greater propensity to hold significant ownership in commercial banks. These results are consistent with the notion that because non-state-owned firms are more likely to suffer bank discrimination for political reasons, they tend to address their financing disadvantages by building economic bonds with banks. We also find that among non-state-owned firms, those that hold significant bank ownership have lower interest expenses, and are less likely to increase cash holdings but more likely to obtain short-term loans when the government monetary policy is tight. These results suggest that the firms building economic bonds with banks can enjoy benefits such as lower financial expenses and better lending terms during difficult times. Finally, we find that non-state-owned firms with significant bank ownership have better operating performance. Overall, we find that firms can reduce discrimination through holding bank ownership. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lu, Zhengfei; Zhu, Jigao; Zhang, Weining</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do industries matter in explaining stock returns and asset-pricing anomalies?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chou, Pin-Huang; Ho, Po-Hsin; Ko, Kuan-Cheng
Industry returns cannot be explained fully by well-known asset pricing models. This study reveals that common factors extracted from industry returns carry significant risk premiums that go beyond the explanatory power of size, book-to-market (BM) ratios, and momentum. In particular, this study shows that (1) the small-firm effect is significant only for firms whose market capitalization is below their industry average; (2) the BM effect is an intra-industry phenomenon; (3) a one-year momentum effect is significant only for firms whose BM ratio is smaller than the industry average and limited to non-January months; and (4) there is seasonality in all effects that cannot be explained by risk-based asset-pricing models. Neither rational nor behavioral theories alone can explain industry returns, and it is perhaps too hasty to attribute asset pricing anomalies to a single driving force. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chou, Pin-Huang; Ho, Po-Hsin; Ko, Kuan-Cheng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Another look at trading costs and short-term reversal profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Groot, Wilma; Huij, Joop; Zhou, Weili
Several studies report that abnormal returns associated with short-term reversal investment strategies diminish once trading costs are taken into account. We show that the impact of trading costs on the strategies' profitability can largely be attributed to excessively trading in small cap stocks. Limiting the stock universe to large cap stocks significantly reduces trading costs. Applying a more sophisticated portfolio construction algorithm to lower turnover reduces trading costs even further. Our finding that reversal strategies generate 30-50 basis points per week net of trading costs poses a serious challenge to standard rational asset pricing models. Our findings also have important implications for the understanding and practical implementation of reversal strategies. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Groot, Wilma; Huij, Joop; Zhou, Weili</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The joint response of stock and foreign exchange markets to macroeconomic surprises: Using US and Japanese data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mun, Kyung-Chun
This paper investigates the joint response of stock and foreign exchange (FX) market returns to macroeconomic surprises, employing a system method of estimation that allows for the cross-country and cross-market interaction for asset returns and risk premia. Using US and Japanese data, we find that US stock markets are asymmetrically responsive to domestic developments in output growth and interest rates but are not influenced by macroeconomic surprises from Japan. The surprise in the FX market seems to affect stock markets in the US and Japan, respectively. In particular, we find that the interest rate surprise in the US and inflation surprise in Japan tend to overstate the impact that these surprises would have on the respective stock market. The impact of the surprises would appear smaller if macroeconomic developments induced by the FX market were incorporated into the model. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mun, Kyung-Chun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The response of the external finance premium in Asian corporate bond markets to financial characteristics, financial constraints and two financial crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mizen, Paul; Tsoukas, Serafeim
Empirical investigation of the external finance premium has been conducted on the margin between internal finance and bank borrowing or equities but little attention has been given to corporate bonds, especially for the emerging Asian market. In this paper, we hypothesize that balance sheet indicators of creditworthiness could affect the external finance premium for bonds as they do for premia in other markets. Using bond-specific and firm-specific data for China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Korea, Philippines, Singapore and Thailand during 1995-2009 we find that firms with better financial health face lower external finance premia in all countries. When we introduce firm-level heterogeneity, we show that financial variables appear to be both statistically and quantitatively more important for financially constrained firms. Finally, when we examine the effects of the 1997-1998 Asian crisis and the 2007-2009 global financial crisis, we find that the sensitivity of the premium is greater for constrained firms during the Asian crisis compared to other times. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mizen, Paul; Tsoukas, Serafeim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corruption, growth, and governance: Private vs. state-owned firms in Vietnam</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, Thuy Thu; van Dijk, Mathijs A.
We provide a firm-level analysis of the relation between corruption and growth for private firms and state-owned enterprises (SOEs) in Vietnam. We obtain three different measures of the perceived corruption severity from a 2005 survey among 741 private firms and 133 SOEs. We find that corruption hampers the growth of Vietnam's private sector, but is not detrimental for growth in the state sector. We document significant differences in the corruption severity across 24 provinces in Vietnam that can be explained by the quality of provincial public governance (such as the costs of new business entry, land access, and private sector development policies). Our results suggest that corruption may harm economic growth because it favors the state sector at the expense of the private sector and that improving the quality of local public governance can help to mitigate corruption and stimulate economic growth. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nguyen, Thuy Thu; van Dijk, Mathijs A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign bank entry, credit allocation and lending rates in emerging markets: Empirical evidence from Poland</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degryse, Hans; Hayrylchyk, Olena; Jurzyk, Emilia; Kozak, Sylwester
Earlier studies have documented that foreign banks charge lower lending rates and interest spreads than domestic banks. We hypothesize that this may stem from the superior efficiency of foreign entrants that they decide to pass onto borrowers ("performance hypothesis"), but could also reflect a different loan allocation with respect to borrower transparency, loan maturity and currency ("portfolio composition hypothesis"). We are able to differentiate between the above hypotheses thanks to a novel dataset containing detailed bank-specific information for the Polish banking industry. Our findings demonstrate that banks differ significantly in terms of portfolio composition and we attest to the "portfolio composition hypothesis" by showing that, having controlled for portfolio composition, there are no differences in lending rates between banks. (C) 2012 International Monetary Fund. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Degryse, Hans; Hayrylchyk, Olena; Jurzyk, Emilia; Kozak, Sylwester</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial crisis, structure and reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Gu, Xian; Kowalewski, Oskar
In this study, we examine the relationship between the structure of financial systems and financial crises. Using cross-country data on financial structures and crises, we find that there is a significant short-term reversal in development of the banking sector and the stock market during both bank crises and market crashes, with the corporate bond market moving in the same direction as bank credit. However, the results are significant for countries with market-based financial systems but not for countries with bank-based financial systems. Emerging markets have mainly bank-based financial systems, which may explain why these markets require more time to recover from economic downturns after a financial crisis. Therefore, we argue that governments should emphasize a balanced financial system structure as it helps countries to recover from financial crises more quickly compared with countries that lack such balanced structures. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Gu, Xian; Kowalewski, Oskar</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do return prediction models add economic value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cenesizoglu, Tolga; Timmermann, Allan
We compare statistical and economic measures of forecasting performance across a large set of stock return prediction models with time-varying mean and volatility. We find that it is very common for models to produce higher out-of-sample mean squared forecast errors than a model assuming a constant equity premium, yet simultaneously add economic value when their forecasts are used to guide portfolio decisions. While there is generally a positive correlation between a return prediction model's out-of-sample statistical performance and its ability to add economic value, the relation tends to be weak and only explains a small part of the cross-sectional variation in different models' economic value. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cenesizoglu, Tolga; Timmermann, Allan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing interest rate risk: Stochastic volatility in the term structure of government bond yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hautsch, Nikolaus; Ou, Yangguoyi
We propose a Nelson-Siegel type interest rate term structure model where the underlying yield factors follow autoregressive processes with stochastic volatility. The factor volatilities parsimoniously capture risk inherent to the term structure and are associated with the time-varying uncertainty of the yield curve's level, slope and curvature. Estimating the model based on US government bond yields applying Markov chain Monte Carlo techniques we find that the factor volatilities follow highly persistent processes. We show that yield factors and factor volatilities are closely related to macroeconomic state variables as well as the conditional variances thereof. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hautsch, Nikolaus; Ou, Yangguoyi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size and earnings volatility of US bank holding companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Haan, Jakob; Poghosyan, Tigran
We examine whether bank earnings volatility depends on bank size. Using quarterly data for bank holding companies in the United States for the period 1995Q1-2010Q3 and controlling for the quality of management, leverage, and diversification, we find that bank size reduces return volatility. However, the effect is non-linear: when bank size exceeds a certain threshold (about US$5 billion) size is positively related to earnings volatility. The recent financial crisis decreased the threshold beyond which the impact of size on volatility turns positive. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Haan, Jakob; Poghosyan, Tigran</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of information sharing between lenders on access to credit, cost of credit, and loan performance - Evidence from a credit registry introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Behr, Patrick; Sonnekalb, Simon
Using a rich dataset from a commercial bank in Albania, we utilize the introduction of a public credit registry by the Albanian central bank in January 2008 as a natural experiment to analyze the effect of information sharing between lenders on (1) access to credit, (2) cost of credit, and (3) loan performance. Our results suggest that information sharing by means of a credit registry does not affect access to or cost of credit, but improves loan performance. Specifically, loans granted after the introduction of the credit registry are 3% points less likely of turning problematic, representing a 35% reduction of the overall sample average arrear probability. We further find that the effect is more pronounced for repeat borrowers and in areas, where competition is weak. This indicates that information sharing among lenders improves loan performance mainly by disciplining borrowers to repay in their concern about future access to credit. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Behr, Patrick; Sonnekalb, Simon</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday technical analysis of individual stocks on the Tokyo Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yamamoto, Ryuichi
This paper conducts an intraday technical analysis of individual stocks listed on the Nikkei 225. In addition to the price-based technical rules popularly examined in the literature, we uniquely propose and statistically investigate technical rules that utilize information regarding (1) the order-flow imbalance and (2) the order-book imbalance. Technical analysis using the imbalance-based trading rules is motivated by the evidence presented first in this paper that short-term returns can be predicted from the information regarding the order-flow and order-book imbalances for more than half of Nikkei 225-listed stocks. However, we demonstrate that no strategies, including limit order trading where trading signals are derived from the order-book imbalance, beat the buy-and-hold strategy within our sample. The results imply that past prices and demand/supply imbalances do not contribute to profiting in intraday trading and that non-execution and picking-off risks are too large for limit order trading to be profitable in our sample. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yamamoto, Ryuichi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund flows, expected returns, and the real economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jank, Stephan
This paper investigates the relation between mutual fund flows and the real economy. The findings of this paper support the theory that the positive co-movement of flows into equity funds and stock market returns is explained by a common response to macroeconomic news. Variables that predict the real economy as well as the equity premium - in particular dividend-price ratio, default spread, relative T-Bill rate and consumption-wealth ratio - are related to fund flows and can account for the correlation of flows and market returns. Furthermore, consistent with the information-response hypothesis, mutual fund flows are forward-looking and predict real economic activity. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jank, Stephan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the cost of capital with basis assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Stephen J.; Lajbcygier, Paul; Wong, Woon Weng
Instead of using industry groups or asset pricing models to estimate the cost of capital we propose using risk equivalent classes known as basis assets. A basis asset is constructed by grouping firms together whose returns indicate they share a common risk exposure, which in theory permits a precise and accurate expected return estimate. Thus, knowing to which basis asset a firm belongs, the firm's cost of capital can be obtained. Empirically, we show that basis assets lead to superior cost of capital estimates when compared with widely used industry groupings. This means we are no longer reliant on asset pricing models or industry groups to estimate the cost of capital of a firm. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Stephen J.; Lajbcygier, Paul; Wong, Woon Weng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are there arbitrage gaps in the UK gilt strips market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armitage, Seth; Chakravarty, Shanti P.; Hodgkinson, Lynn; Wells, Jo
Evidence in financial markets of an opportunity for pure arbitrage, and therefore a violation of the law of one price, is considered an anomaly to be noted. This paper reports an apparent violation of the law of one price between UK government gilts and their separately traded principal and coupon strips over a sample period of nearly 14 years. There are persistent price differences, and hence opportunities for arbitrage, after allowance for the bid-ask spread; the strips package tends to be overpriced in relation to the corresponding gilt. The price differences may, in part, be due to a lack of liquidity and stale prices in the strips market. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Armitage, Seth; Chakravarty, Shanti P.; Hodgkinson, Lynn; Wells, Jo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst following, staggered boards, and managerial entrenchment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiraporn, Pornsit; Chintrakarn, Pandej; Kim, Young S.
We use agency theory to explore how analyst coverage is influenced by the managerial entrenchment associated with the staggered board. The evidence suggests that firms with staggered boards attract significantly larger analyst following. We also document that firms with staggered boards experience less information asymmetry. Staggered boards insulate managers from the discipline of the takeover market. Entrenched managers are well-protected by the staggered board and have fewer incentives to conceal information, resulting in less information asymmetry. The more transparent information environment facilitates the analyst's job. As a consequence, more analysts are attracted to firms with staggered boards. We also document the beneficial role of analyst coverage in improving firm value. Our results confirm the notion that analysts, as information intermediaries, provide oversight over management and thus help alleviate agency conflicts. The positive effect of analyst coverage, however, is severely reduced when the firm has a staggered board in place. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiraporn, Pornsit; Chintrakarn, Pandej; Kim, Young S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic value, competition and financial distress in the European banking system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cipollini, Andrea; Fiordelisi, Franco
In this paper we examine the impact of a large number of factors at the bank level (liquidity and credit risks, asset size, income diversification and market power), at the industry level (banking concentration) and macro-level (real GDP growth) on bank financial distress using an unbalanced panel of 308 European commercial banks between 1996 and 2009. The observations falling below a given threshold of the empirical distribution of the Shareholder Value Ratio proxy bank financial distress. We employ a panel probit regression and, given the presence of overlapping data giving rise to residual autocorrelation, we use the Bertschek and Lechner (1998) robust estimator of the covariance matrix of parameters. We show that credit risk, liquidity risk and bank market power are the most influential determinants of distressed Shareholder Value Ratio. Finally we evaluate the model out-sample forecasting performance over the 2008-2009 crisis period. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cipollini, Andrea; Fiordelisi, Franco</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility dynamics for the S&amp;P 500: Further evidence from non-affine, multi-factor jump diffusions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaeck, Andreas; Alexander, Carol
We apply Markov chain Monte Carlo methods to time series data on S&amp;P 500 index returns, and to its option prices via a term structure of VIX indices, to estimate 18 different affine and non-affine stochastic volatility models with one or two variance factors, and where jumps are allowed in both the price and the instantaneous volatility. The in-sample fit to the VIX term structure shows that the second (stochastic long-term volatility) factor is required to fit the VIX term structure. Out-of-sample tests on the fit to individual option prices, as well as in-sample tests, show that the inclusion of jumps is less important than allowing for non-affine dynamics. The estimation and testing periods together cover more than 21 years of daily data. Crown Copyright (C) 2012 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaeck, Andreas; Alexander, Carol</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate taxes, strategic default, and the cost of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nejadmalayeri, Ali; Singh, Manohar
The current US tax code's loss carry provisions provide implicit tax subsidies to financially troubled firms. Since shareholders ultimately decide when to announce bankruptcy, such tax subsidies can incentivize them to strategically postpone default. Therefore, corporate taxation can influence corporate cost of debt. Using a large panel of corporate bonds, we find supporting evidence: credit spreads become smaller as tax loss carries grow larger. In contrast, tax shields such as depreciation, which limit loss carry gains, lead to wider spreads. Interestingly, when stockholders hold greater bargaining power - due to large managerial ownership - larger corporate tax shields lead to even narrower credit spreads. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nejadmalayeri, Ali; Singh, Manohar</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum, contrarian, and the January seasonality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yao, Yaqiong
This paper reexamines the apparent success of two prominent stock trading strategies: long-term contrarian and intermediate-term momentum. The paper demonstrates that long-term contrarian is entirely attributable to the classic January size effect, rather than to investor overreaction, as argued by De Bondt and Thaler (1985). Further, the paper also resolves the Novy-Marx (2011) concern about whether return autocorrelation "is really momentum" by demonstrating that the superior performance of intermediate-term momentum is due to strong January seasonality in the cross-section of returns. The implications are that long-term contrarian must be considered largely illusory, and intermediate-term momentum must take account of annual seasonalities in returns. (c) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yao, Yaqiong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stakeholder conflicts and dividend policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bohren, Oyvind; Josefsen, Morten G.; Steen, Pal E.
This paper compares the dividend policy of owner-controlled firms with that of firms where the owners are a minority relative to non-owner employees, customers, and community citizens. We find that regardless of whether owners or non-owners control the firm, the strong stakeholder uses the dividend payout decision to mitigate rather than to intensify the conflict of interest with the weak stakeholder. Hence, the higher the potential agency cost as reflected in the firm's stakeholder structure, the more the actual agency cost is reduced by the strong stakeholder's dividend payout decision. These findings are consistent with a dividend policy in which opportunistic power abuse in stakeholder conflicts is discouraged by costly consequences for the abuser at a later stage. Indirect evidence supports this interpretation. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bohren, Oyvind; Josefsen, Morten G.; Steen, Pal E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overnight public information, order placement, and price discovery during the pre-opening period</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz; Giang, Huong; Pham, Peter Kien
This study examines the impact of corporate news announcements released overnight on price discovery during the pre-opening period in the Australian Securities Exchange. Our results suggest that the presence of these announcements increases the efficiency of indicative opening prices and that the intensity of these announcements significantly influences the aggressiveness of pre-opening orders. Using earnings announcements to compare the speed of price adjustments in response to overnight and daytime information of a homogeneous type, we find that prices respond immediately to overnight news upon the commencement of trading, whereas adjustments based on trading-hours news tend not to be instantaneous. Overall, our evidence highlights the important role of the pre-opening period in price discovery and the prospect of further enhancing this role by timing the release of public information to occur during non-trading hours. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz; Giang, Huong; Pham, Peter Kien</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational expectations, changing monetary policy rules, and real exchange rate dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Shiu-Sheng; Chou, Yu-Hsi
This paper reexamines the explanatory power of Taylor rule fundamentals for real exchange rate determination. We assume the agents know the time-varying parameters in central bank policy rules. The empirical results suggest that a monetary policy rule with regime switching is better able to explain the real Deutschemark/dollar exchange rate from 1976 to 1998 compared with a fixed-regime monetary policy rule. The findings show the importance of accounting for the expectation formation effect in changing policy rules as emphasized by the Lucas critique. Ignoring these effects can undermine the value of the rational expectations models. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Shiu-Sheng; Chou, Yu-Hsi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity crisis, financial integration and global financial stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The future and dynamics of global systemically important banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
The purpose of this paper is to analyse some of the issues associated with supervision and regulation of global systemically important banks, G-SIB. The paper highlights the importance of managing liquidity risk and creating a global financial system that can minimise regulatory arbitrage by large financial institutions. The paper argues that, unlike some industries such as the airline industry in which risk has been contained and yet the size and capacity of aircrafts have increased, in the banking system, less progress has been made to contain financial risk and allow large banks to expand their global activities. The paper argues that G-SIB are able to continue remaining large provided that a globally integrated financial system ensures effective global supervision of these large banks. The paper compares the US banking crises in the 19th century and the subsequent emergence of the US Federal Reserve System to the possibility of establishing a world central bank and a global supervisory board. Such new global institutions will have the capacity to reduce regulatory arbitrage, increase effective supervision, reduce systemic and liquidity risk and create a more stable global financial system. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate expectations and uncertainty during ECB Governing Council days: Evidence from intraday implied densities of 3-month EURIBOR</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vergote, Olivier; Gutierrez, Josep Maria Puigvert
This paper analyses changes in short-term interest rate expectations and uncertainty during ECB Governing Council days. For this purpose, it extends the estimation of risk-neutral probability density functions up to tick frequency. In particular, the non-parametric estimator of these densities, which is based on fitting implied volatility curves, is applied to estimate intraday expectations of 3-month EURIBOR 3 months ahead. Estimates of the noise impact on the statistical moments of the densities enhance the interpretation. In addition, the paper assesses the impact of the ECB communication during Governing Council days. The results show that the whole density may react to the communication and that such repositioning of market participants' expectations will contain information beyond that of changes in the consensus view already observed in forward rates. The results also point out the relevance of the press conference in providing extra information and triggering an adjustment process for interest rate expectations. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vergote, Olivier; Gutierrez, Josep Maria Puigvert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial contagion and the real economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baur, Dirk G.
This paper studies the spread of the Global Financial Crisis of 2007-2009 from the financial sector to the real economy by examining ten sectors in 25 major developed and emerging stock markets. The analysis tests different channels of financial contagion across countries and sectors and finds that the crisis led to an increased co-movement of returns among financial sector stocks across countries and between financial sector stocks and real economy stocks. The results demonstrate that no country and sector was immune to the adverse effects of the crisis limiting the effectiveness of portfolio diversification. However, there is clear evidence that some sectors in particular Healthcare, Telecommunications and Technology were less severely affected by the crisis. (c) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baur, Dirk G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When more is less: Using multiple constraints to reduce tail risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Gordon J.; Baptista, Alexandre M.; Yan, Shu
Financial institutions suffered large trading losses during the 2007-2009 global financial crisis. These losses cast doubt on the effectiveness of regulations and risk management systems based on a single Value-at-Risk (VaR) constraint. While some researchers have recommended using Conditional Value-at-Risk (CVaR) to control tail risk, VaR remains popular among practitioners and regulators. Accordingly, our paper examines the effectiveness of multiple VaR constraints in controlling CVaR. Under certain conditions, we theoretically show that they are more effective than a single VaR constraint. Furthermore, we numerically find that the maximum CVaR permitted by the constraints is notably smaller than with a single constraint. These results suggest that regulations and risk management systems based on multiple VaR constraints are more effective in reducing tail risk than those based on a single VaR constraint. (c) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, Gordon J.; Baptista, Alexandre M.; Yan, Shu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Will tighter futures price limits decrease hedge effectiveness?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dark, Jonathan
The events triggered by the Global Financial Crisis (GFC) have led to calls for the regulation of financial markets. Given that regulation may involve opportunity costs, this paper examines whether tighter futures price limits can reduce the effectiveness of a futures hedge. We propose a new model that uncovers the underlying spot-futures dynamics when futures prices are subject to limits. We use the model to determine the maximum number of limit days that can occur before minimum variance hedging outcomes are adversely affected. Application of this model to the US soybean and corn markets reveals that existing limits do not reduce hedge effectiveness. If the frequency of limit days increases from current levels of 1% to approximately 3-4%, conventional hedging approaches will experience economically and statistically significant increases in portfolio variance. These results are important for hedgers, clearing houses and regulators in light of the recent calls for derivatives regulation. (c) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dark, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reprint of Investors' distraction and strategic repricing decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Navone, Marco
In this paper I analyze investors' reactions to changes in the expense ratios of equity mutual funds. I show that investment flows' response to fees cannot be fully explained by looking at investors' performance sensitivity. While performance sensitivity monotonically increases with past performance, price sensitivity does not: investors who buy top past performers seem to be "distracted" by the fund's previous return and pay relatively little attention to the expense ratios. Moreover price sensitivity increases with fund visibility while performance sensitivity decreases, and while looking at data from 1986 to 2006 no discernible trend can be observed in the average performance sensitivity, price sensitivity strongly increases due to the dramatic increase in the availability of mutual funds' information for retail investors. Finally I show that investment companies strategically time their repricing decisions in order to exploit time variations in price and performance sensitivities, and that fund governance quality affects the degree to which investment companies engage in this opportunistic behavior. (c) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Navone, Marco</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing the US residential asset through the rent flow: A cross-sectional study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goswami, Gautam; Tan, Sinan
The paper explores how the standard consumption-CAPM fares in pricing housing returns and regional rental income streams in a cross-section of regions. In particular, we estimate the Euler equations associated with the gross housing returns inclusive of price appreciations and rents jointly for several metropolitan areas of the US. The representative agent has a Constant Relative Risk Aversion (CRRA) utility. The rent growth is allowed to depend on the business cycle. When biannual data from 1978 to 2007 is used, the parameter estimates are reasonable, and the model is not rejected. Large standard errors indicate uninformative estimates. The implied price rent ratio time series averages are similar to the data; however the model misses the boom-bust pattern in the prices. The model significantly understates the average and the variance of the price appreciations. Results are robust to allowing housing consumption directly in the utility function or using the Epstein-Zin-Weil utility. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goswami, Gautam; Tan, Sinan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does liquidity risk explain low firm performance following seasoned equity offerings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bilinski, Pawel; Liu, Weimin; Strong, Norman
A seasoned equity offering (SEO) can improve a firm's stock liquidity and lower its cost of capital. This paper examines whether SEO firms achieve a liquidity gain and the sources of this gain. It explores the role of liquidity risk in explaining SEO long-run performance. The evidence shows that SEO firms experience significant post-issue improvements in liquidity and reductions in liquidity risk. Size and book-to-market matching fails to control for these liquidity effects, generating the low long-term post-SEO performance documented in the literature. After adjusting for liquidity risk, SEO firms show normal long-term performance. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bilinski, Pawel; Liu, Weimin; Strong, Norman</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Daily pricing of emerging market sovereign CDS before and during the global financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fender, Ingo; Hayo, Bernd; Neuenkirch, Matthias
In this paper, we study the determinants of daily spreads for emerging market sovereign credit default swaps (CDSs) over the period April 2002-December 2011. Using GARCH models, we find, first, that daily CDS spreads for emerging market sovereigns are more related to global and regional risk premia than to country-specific risk factors. This result is particularly evident during the second subsample (August 2007-December 2011), where neither macroeconomic variables nor country ratings significantly explain CDS spread changes. Second, measures of US bond, equity, and CDX High Yield returns, as well as emerging market credit returns, are the most dominant drivers of CDS spread changes. Finally, our analysis suggests that CDS spreads are more strongly influenced by international spillover effects during periods of market stress than during normal times. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fender, Ingo; Hayo, Bernd; Neuenkirch, Matthias</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Day and night returns of Chinese ADRs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Hui; Yang, Jiawen
Are the returns of Chinese American Depositary Receipts (ADR) more affected by the US market or their underlying home market? We separate Chinese ADR daily returns into day and night returns to investigate the different market effects on ADR pricing. We compare "homeless" ADRs to home-based or crosslisted ADRs to see if they are affected differently by market factors. We find the night returns of Chinese ADRs are significantly affected by their home market (either the Hong Kong market or mainland China market) daily returns and the US market night returns. The US day returns appear to be the most significant pricing factor for the day returns of Chinese ADRs. The homeless ADRs are more affected by the US market and less affected by their home market compared to the cross-listed ADRs. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Hui; Yang, Jiawen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government ownership and corporate governance: Evidence from the EU</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borisova, Ginka; Brockman, Paul; Salas, Jesus M.; Zagorchev, Andrey
The ongoing global financial crisis has led to the largest increase in state intervention since the Great Depression. Direct government ownership in publicly-traded corporations has increased dramatically since 2008. How will this increase in public ownership affect the governance of these erstwhile private companies? We examine the impact of government ownership on corporate governance using a sample of firms from the European Union, a region that is relatively familiar with active government participation. Our main finding is that government ownership is associated with lower governance quality. We further show that while government intervention is negatively related to governance quality in civil law countries, it is positively related to governance quality in common law countries. Finally, we find that the preferential voting rights of golden shares are especially damaging to governance quality. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Borisova, Ginka; Brockman, Paul; Salas, Jesus M.; Zagorchev, Andrey</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are convertible bond announcements associated with increasingly negative issuer stock returns? An arbitrage-based explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duca, Eric; Dutordoir, Marie; Veld, Chris; Verwijmeren, Patrick
While convertible offerings announced between 1984 and 1999 induce average abnormal stock returns of -1.69%, convertible announcement effects over the period 2000-2008 are more than twice as negative (-4.59%). We hypothesize that this evolution is attributable to a shift in the convertible bond investor base from long-only investors towards convertible arbitrage funds. These funds buy convertibles and short the underlying stocks, causing downward price pressure. Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that the differences in announcement returns between the Traditional Investor period (1984-1999) and the Arbitrage period (2000-September 2008) disappear when controlling for arbitrage-induced short selling associated with a range of hedging strategies. Post-issuance stock returns are also in line with the arbitrage explanation. Average announcement effects of convertibles issued during the Global Financial Crisis are even more negative (-9.12%), due to a combination of short-selling price pressure and issuer, issue, and macroeconomic characteristics associated with these offerings. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duca, Eric; Dutordoir, Marie; Veld, Chris; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk, macroprudential policy frameworks, monitoring financial systems and the evolution of capital adequacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnold, Bruce; Borio, Claudio; Ellis, Luci; Moshirian, Fariborz
This paper analyses various issues that need to be tackled when promoting financial stability, reviewing the progress made in certain key areas and the remaining challenges. It explores the measurement of systemic risk and of individual institutions' contribution to it. It discusses aspects of macroprudential frameworks. including how the countercyclical capital buffer envisaged in Basel III takes into account the properties of the financial cycle and the strengths and weaknesses of macro-stress tests. It analyses some of the challenges of how best to monitor financial systems and the broader economy in order to detect signs of vulnerability that might lead to future bouts of financial instability and of how to set prudential policy accordingly. And it discusses the evolution of capital adequacy standards and the new emphasis on liquidity standards in international regulation. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arnold, Bruce; Borio, Claudio; Ellis, Luci; Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do interbank customer relationships exist? And how did they function in the crisis? Learning from Italy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Affinito, Massimiliano
Using 11 years of monthly Italian bank-by-bank data, this paper correlates the bilateral amounts and the identity of each interbank borrower and lender with a long list of explanatory variables. The results show that interbank customer relationships, i.e. stable and strong relationships between pairs of borrowing and lending banks, do exist in Italy, that they persist over time, and that they functioned well during the crisis, enabling the healthier banks to provide and the troubled ones to receive funds. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Affinito, Massimiliano</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management, corporate governance, and bank performance in the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aebi, Vincent; Sabato, Gabriele; Schmid, Markus
The recent financial crisis has raised several questions with respect to the corporate governance of financial institutions. This paper investigates whether risk management-related corporate governance mechanisms, such as for example the presence of a chief risk officer (CRO) in a bank's executive board and whether the CRO reports to the CEO or directly to the board of directors, are associated with a better bank performance during the financial crisis of 2007/2008. We measure bank performance by buy-and-hold returns and ROE and we control for standard corporate governance variables such as CEO ownership, board size, and board independence. Most importantly, our results indicate that banks, in which the CRO directly reports to the board of directors and not to the CEO (or other corporate entities), exhibit significantly higher (i.e., less negative) stock returns and ROE during the crisis. In contrast, standard corporate governance variables are mostly insignificantly or even negatively related to the banks' performance during the crisis. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aebi, Vincent; Sabato, Gabriele; Schmid, Markus</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit risk transfer in U.S. commercial banks: What changed during the 2007-2009 crisis?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bedendo, Mascia; Bruno, Brunella
Following the debate on the role of credit risk transfer (CRT) in exacerbating the 2007-2009 crisis, this paper investigates the usage and effects of loan sales, securitization, and credit derivatives in U.S. commercial banks over the last decade, with special emphasis on the financial crisis. We find that in times of severe funding constraints, the need to raise financial resources becomes the principal incentive behind CRT. We document some beneficial effects of CRT on the economy, since the funds released through CRT are subsequently invested by banks to sustain credit supply, also in recession. However, we report higher overall riskiness in banks that engage intensively in loans sales and securitization, which translates into higher default rates during the crisis. Interestingly, the benefits and drawbacks of CRT are much stronger for loan sales and securitization than for credit derivatives. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bedendo, Mascia; Bruno, Brunella</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relationship between banking market competition and risk-taking: Do size and capitalization matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tabak, Benjamin M.; Fazio, Dimas M.; Cajueiro, Daniel O.
This paper addresses the effects of bank competition on the risk-taking behaviors of banks in 10 Latin American countries between 2003 and 2008. We conduct our empirical approach in two steps. First, we estimate the Boone indicator, which is a measure of competition. We then regress this measure and other explanatory variables on the banking "stability inefficiency" derived simultaneously from the estimation of a stability stochastic frontier. Unlike previous findings, this paper concludes that competition affects risk-taking behavior in a non-linear way as both high and low competition levels enhance financial stability, while we find the opposite effect for average competition. In addition, bank size and capitalization are essential factors in explaining this relationship. On the one hand, the larger a bank is, the more it benefits from competition. On the other hand, a greater capital ratio is advantageous for banks that operate in collusive markets, while capitalization only enhances the stability of larger banks under high and average competition. These results are of extreme importance when considering bank regulations, especially in light of the recent turmoil in the global financial markets. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tabak, Benjamin M.; Fazio, Dimas M.; Cajueiro, Daniel O.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade credit, cash holdings, and financial deepening: Evidence from a transitional economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Wenfeng; Rui, Oliver M.; Wu, Chongfeng
This paper investigates the effect of financial deepening on the relationship between trade credit and cash holdings among Chinese listed firms. We first document an asymmetric effect of trade payables and receivables on cash holdings, in that firms hold an additional $0.71 of cash for every $1 of credit payable but use $1 of receivables as a substitute for only $0.15 of cash. We then find that firms in regions with higher levels of financial deepening hold less cash for payables while substituting more receivables for cash. A more highly developed financial sector helps firms to better use trade credit as a short-term financing instrument. Finally, we find that the ratio at which receivables are substituted for cash increased following the implementation of the new receivables pledge policy in 2007, which allowed firms to use receivables as security for loans. This policy event represents an exogenous shock that mitigates the endogeneity concern. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Wenfeng; Rui, Oliver M.; Wu, Chongfeng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International corporate finance and governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kabir, Rezaul
nan</description><author>Kabir, Rezaul</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Best-performing US mutual fund families from 1993 to 2008: Evidence from a novel two-stage DEA model for efficiency decomposition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Premachandra, I. M.; Zhu, Joe; Watson, John; Galagedera, Don U. A.
When analyzing relative performance, especially at the institutional level, the traditional data envelopment analysis (DEA) models do not recognize vastly different and important activities as separate functions and therefore cannot identify which function may be the main source of inefficiency. We propose a novel two-stage DEA model that decomposes the overall efficiency of a decision-making unit into two components and demonstrate its applicability by assessing the relative performance of 66 large mutual fund families in the US over the period 1993-2008. By decomposing the overall efficiency into operational management efficiency and portfolio management efficiency components, we reveal the best performers, the families that deteriorated in performance, and those that improved in their performance over the sample period. We also make frontier projections for poorly performing mutual fund families and highlight how the portfolio managers have managed their funds relative to the others during financial crisis periods. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Premachandra, I. M.; Zhu, Joe; Watson, John; Galagedera, Don U. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk, Basel III, global financial stability and regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnold, Bruce R.; Borio, Claudio; Ellis, Luci; Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Arnold, Bruce R.; Borio, Claudio; Ellis, Luci; Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stress testing credit risk: The Great Depression scenario</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Varotto, Simone
By employing Moody's corporate default and rating transition data spanning the last 90 years we explore how much capital banks should hold against their corporate loan portfolios to withstand historical stress scenarios. Specifically, we will focus on the worst case scenario over the observation period, the Great Depression. We find that migration risk and the length of the investment horizon are critical factors when determining bank capital needs in a crisis. We show that capital may need to rise more than three times when the horizon is increased from 1 year, as required by current and future regulation, to 3 years. Increases are still important but of a lower magnitude when migration risk is introduced in the analysis. Further, we find that the new bank capital requirements under the so-called Basel 3 agreement would enable banks to absorb Great Depression-style losses. But, such losses would dent regulatory capital considerably and far beyond the capital buffers that have been proposed to ensure that banks survive crisis periods without government support. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Varotto, Simone</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market-specific and currency-specific risk during the global financial crisis: Evidence from the interbank markets in Tokyo and London</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fukuda, Shin-ichi
This paper investigates how international money markets reflected credit and liquidity risk during the global financial crisis. After matching the currency denomination, we examine how the Tokyo Interbank Offered Rate (TIBOR) was synchronized with the London Interbank Offered Rate (LIBOR). We find remarkably asymmetric responses in market-specific and currency-specific risk during the crisis. The regression results suggest that market-specific credit risk increased the difference across markets, whereas liquidity risk caused the difference across currency denominations. They also support the view that liquidity shortage of the US dollar occurred in international money markets during the crisis. Coordinated central bank liquidity provisions were useful in reducing the liquidity shortage of the US dollar, but their effectiveness was asymmetric across markets. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fukuda, Shin-ichi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking risk and regulation: Does one size fit all?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klomp, Jeroen; de Haan, Jakob
Using data for more than 200 banks from 21 OECD countries for the period 2002-2008, we examine the impact of bank regulation and supervision on banking risk using quantile regressions. In contrast to most previous research, we find that banking regulation and supervision has an effect on the risks of high-risk banks. However, most measures for bank regulation and supervision do not have a significant effect on low-risk banks. As banking risk and bank regulation and supervision are multi-faceted concepts, our measures for both concepts are constructed using factor analysis. (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Klomp, Jeroen; de Haan, Jakob</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-horizon regulation for long-term investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shi, Zhen; Werker, Bas J. M.
We study the effects of imposing repeated short-horizon regulatory constraints on long-term investors. We show that Value-at-Risk and Expected Shortfall constraints, when imposed dynamically, lead to similar optimal portfolios and wealth distributions. We also show that, in utility terms, the costs of imposing these constraints can be sizeable. For a 96% funded pension plan, both an annual Value-at-Risk constraint and an annual Expected Shortfall constraint can lead to an economic cost of about 2.5-3.8% of initial wealth over a 15-year horizon. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shi, Zhen; Werker, Bas J. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Going overboard? On busy directors and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cashman, George D.; Gillan, Stuart L.; Jun, Chulhee
The literature disagrees on the link between so-called busy boards (where many independent directors hold multiple board seats) and firm performance. Some argue that busyness certifies a director's ability and that such directors are value enhancing. Others argue that "over-boarded" directors are ineffective and detract from firm value. We find evidence that (1) the disparate results in prior work stem from differences in both sample composition and empirical design, (2) on balance the results suggest a negative association between board busyness and firm performance, and (3) the inclusion of firm fixed effects dramatically affects the conclusions drawn from, and the explanatory power of, multivariate analyses. we also explore alternative empirical definitions of what constitutes a busy director and find that commonly used proxies for busyness perform well relative to more complex alternatives. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cashman, George D.; Gillan, Stuart L.; Jun, Chulhee</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity risk and stock returns around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liang, Samuel Xin; Wei, John K. C.
The recent global financial crisis demonstrates that market liquidity is a prominent systematic risk globally. We find that local liquidity risk, in addition to the local market, value and size factors, demands a systematic premium across stocks in 11 developed markets. This local pricing premium is smaller in countries where the country-level corporate boards are more effective and where there are less insider trading activities. We also discover that global liquidity risk is a significant pricing factor across all developed country market portfolios after controlling for global market, value, and size factors. The contribution of this risk to the return on a country market portfolio is economically and statistically significant within and across regions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liang, Samuel Xin; Wei, John K. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock salience and the asymmetric market effect of consumer sentiment news</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhtar, Shumi; Faff, Robert; Oliver, Barry; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
We document asymmetric announcement effects of consumer sentiment news on United States stock and stock futures markets. While a negative market effect occurs upon the release of bad sentiment news, there is no market reaction for the counterpart good news. This supports the "negativity effect" hypothesis. Notably, this effect seems most likely to occur in salient stocks, which is consistent with the availability heuristic. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akhtar, Shumi; Faff, Robert; Oliver, Barry; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO compensation, family control, and institutional investors in Continental Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Croci, Ettore; Gonenc, Halit; Ozkan, Neslihan
This paper investigates the impact of family control and institutional investors on CEO pay packages in Continental Europe, using a dataset of 754 listed firms with 3731 firm-year observations from 14 countries during 2001-2008. We find that family control curbs the level of CEO total and cash compensation, and the fraction of equity-based compensation. Moreover, we do not observe a significant effect of family control on the excess level of total and cash compensation. This evidence indicates that controlling families do not use CEO compensation to expropriate wealth from minority shareholders. We show that institutional ownership is associated with higher levels of CEO cash and total compensation in Continental Europe, especially in family firms. Also, foreign institutional investors have a positive and significant impact on CEO compensation level. Finally, results indicate that institutional investors affect CEO pay structure: they increase the use of equity-based compensation in both family and non-family firms. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Croci, Ettore; Gonenc, Halit; Ozkan, Neslihan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market concentration and the likelihood of financial crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bretschger, Lucas; Kappel, Vivien; Werner, Therese
According to theory, market concentration affects the likelihood of a financial crisis in different ways. The "concentration-stability" and the "concentration-fragility" hypotheses suggest opposing effects operating through specific channels. Using data of 160 countries for the period 1970-2009, this paper empirically tests these indirect effects of financial market structure. We set up a simultaneous system in order to jointly estimate financial stability and the relevant channel variables as endogenous variables. Our findings provide support for the assumption of channel effects in general and both the concentration-stability and the concentration-fragility hypothesis in particular. The effects are found to vary between high and low income countries. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bretschger, Lucas; Kappel, Vivien; Werner, Therese</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Classified boards, the cost of debt, and firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Dong
This paper documents that classified boards substantially reduce the cost of debt. The evidence is not consistent with the argument that bondholders benefit from board classification because they are concerned about hostile takeovers. Instead, the results suggest that the lessened concern for takeovers associated with a classified board structure reduces managerial risk-taking, and increases managerial incentive for financial disclosure, with both effects inuring to bondholders' benefit. Consistent with prior literature, classified boards on average are associated with a lower firm performance. However, under the circumstances that the agency conflict between shareholders and bondholders is severe, the performance effect of classified boards appears benign. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Dong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downside risk aversion, fixed-income exposure, and the value premium puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baltussen, Guido; Post, Gerrit T.; Van Vliet, Pim
The value premium is relatively small for investors with a material fixed-income exposure, such as insurance companies and pension funds, especially when they are downside-risk-averse. Value stocks are less attractive to these investors because they offer a relatively poor hedge against poor bond returns. This result arises for plausible, medium-term evaluation horizons of around one year. Our findings cast doubt on the practical relevance of the value premium for these investors and reiterate the importance of the choice of the relevant test portfolio, risk measure and investment horizon in empirical tests of market portfolio efficiency. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baltussen, Guido; Post, Gerrit T.; Van Vliet, Pim</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial literacy, information flows, and caste affiliation: Empirical evidence from India</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boente, Werner; Filipiak, Ute
This paper empirically investigates the relevance of social interaction and caste affiliation for individual awareness of financial instruments and investment behavior of households in India. The results of our empirical analysis, which is based on a large scale survey on saving patterns of Indians, suggest a positive relationship between financial literacy and social interaction. However, especially backward caste people living in regions with a large fraction of backward castes have a lower probability of being aware of various financial instruments. In contrast, we find only weak empirical evidence for a direct effect of caste affiliation and social interaction on investment behavior. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boente, Werner; Filipiak, Ute</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-frequency financial data modeling using Hawkes processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chavez-Demoulin, V.; McGill, J. A.
Intraday Value-at-Risk (VaR) is one of the risk measures used by market participants involved in high-frequency trading. High-frequency log-returns feature important kurtosis (fat tails) and volatility clustering (extreme log-returns appear in clusters) that VaR models should take into account. We propose a marked point process model for the excesses of the time series over a high threshold that combines Hawkes processes for the exceedances with a generalized Pareto distribution model for the marks (exceedance sizes). The conditional approach features intraday clustering of extremes and is used to calculate instantaneous conditional VaR. The models are backtested on real data and compared to a competitor approach that proposes a nonparametric extension of the classical peaks-over-threshold method. Maximum likelihood estimation is computationally intensive; we use a differential evolution genetic algorithm to find adequate starting values for the optimization process. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chavez-Demoulin, V.; McGill, J. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm growth type and capital structure persistence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Xueping; Yeung, Chau Kin Au
We find that growth type (identified by a two-way sort on firm initial market-to-book ratio and asset tangibility) can parsimoniously predict significantly dispersed and persistently distinct future leverage ratios. Growth type is persistent; growth-type-sorted cross-sections of corporate fundamental variables (such as tangible versus intangible investment style) are also meaningfully persistent. As economic and market conditions improve, low growth type firms are keener to issue new debt than equity, whereas high growth type firms are least likely to issue debt and keenest to issue equity. These findings demonstrate that firms rationally invest and seek financing in a manner compatible with their growth types. Consistent with a generalized Myers-Majluf framework, growth type compatibility enables distinct growth types and hence specifications of market imperfection or informational environments to persist. Growth type is apparently a fundamental factor for capital structure persistence. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Xueping; Yeung, Chau Kin Au</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit spread interdependencies of European states and banks during the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alter, Adrian; Schueler, Yves S.
We investigate the interdependence of the default risk of several Eurozone countries (France, Germany, Italy, Ireland, the Netherlands, Portugal, and Spain) and their domestic banks during the period between June 2007 and May 2010, using daily credit default swaps (CDS). Bank bailout programs changed the composition of both banks' and sovereign balance sheets and, moreover, affected the linkage between the default risk of governments and their local banks. Our main findings suggest that in the period before bank bailouts the contagion disperses from bank credit spreads into the sovereign CDS market. After bailouts, a financial sector shock affects sovereign CDS spreads more strongly in the short run. However, the impact becomes insignificant in the long term. Furthermore, government CDS spreads become an important determinant of banks' CDS series. The interdependence of government and bank credit risk is heterogeneous across countries, but homogeneous within the same country. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alter, Adrian; Schueler, Yves S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms issue private equity repeatedly? On the motives and information content of multiple PIPE offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Floros, Ioannis V.; Sapp, Travis R. A.
This study examines why private equity issues tend to be a repeated source of financing for public firms. We test the recent operational needs theory of public equity issuance within the context of repeated private equity issues. We find that repeated PIPE issuers burn through cash quickly and do not reach the standards of information transparency or profitability needed for a successful public equity offering. This has implications for investor composition and the market response to a PIPE. Initial PIPE offerings are characterized by substantial diversity in investor type. In successive transactions firms increasingly rely upon hedge funds, who extract greater price discounts and more often require cash flow rights as opposed to control rights. As firms select a path of repeated PIPEs to raise funds, successive issues become uninformative to the market. We conclude that, for small public firms, the same motive underlies public equity offerings and repeated private equity offerings-an acute need for cash. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Floros, Ioannis V.; Sapp, Travis R. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-term wholesale funding and systemic risk: A global CoVaR approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lopez-Espinosa, German; Moreno, Antonio; Rubia, Antonio; Valderrama, Laura
We use the CoVaR approach to identify the main factors behind systemic risk in a set of large international banks. We find that short-term wholesale funding is a key determinant in triggering systemic risk episodes. In contrast, we find weaker evidence that either size or leverage contributes to systemic risk within the class of large international banks. We also show that asymmetries based on the sign of bank returns play an important role in capturing the sensitivity of system-wide risk to individual bank returns. Since short-term wholesale funding emerges as the most relevant systemic factor, our results support the Basel Committee's proposal to introduce a net stable funding ratio, penalizing excessive exposure to liquidity risk. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lopez-Espinosa, German; Moreno, Antonio; Rubia, Antonio; Valderrama, Laura</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What happens after corporate default? Stylized facts on access to credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonfim, Diana; Dias, Daniel A.; Richmond, Christine
In this paper, we investigate what happens to firms after they default on their bank loans. We approach this question by establishing a set of stylized facts concerning the evolution of corporate default and its resolution, focusing on access to credit after default. Using a unique dataset from Portugal, we observe that half of the corporate default episodes last 5 quarters. Most firms continue to have access to credit immediately after resolving default, though only a minority has access to new loans. Firms have more difficulties in regaining access to credit if they are small, if their default was long and severe, if they borrow from only one bank or if they default with their main lender. Further, half of the defaulting firms record another default in the future. We observe that firms with repeated defaults are, on average, smaller and experience longer and more severe defaults. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bonfim, Diana; Dias, Daniel A.; Richmond, Christine</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An alternative three-factor model for international markets: Evidence from the European Monetary Union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ammann, Manuel; Odoni, Sandro; Oesch, David
In this paper, we construct the three-factor model introduced by Chen et al. (2010) for a European sample covering 10 countries from the European Monetary Union and the period from 1990 to 2006. Two key findings result. First, we show that the properties of the European factors are comparable to those of the US factors. Second, we show that the alternative three-factor model's explanatory power is either equal or superior to the explanatory power of traditional models when applied to five commonly known stock market anomalies. Our results thus suggest the use of international versions of the Chen et al. (2010) factor model in addition to traditional factor models in international empirical finance research. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ammann, Manuel; Odoni, Sandro; Oesch, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset allocation: How much does model choice matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branger, Nicole; Hansis, Alexandra
This paper analyzes the optimal portfolio decision of a CRRA investor in models with stochastic volatility and stochastic jumps. The investor follows a buy-and-hold strategy in the stock, the money market account, and one additional derivative. We show that both the type of the model and the structure of the risk premia have a significant impact on the optimal portfolio, on the utility gain from having access to derivatives, and on whether the investor prefers to trade OTM or ATM options. We also show that model mis-specification results in significant utility losses. Omitting jumps in volatility can be devastating, in particular if the investor chooses the seemingly optimal OTM put options. A misestimation of the structure of the risk premia has a less devastating effect, but can still lead to a loss of around 4% in the annual certainty equivalent return. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Branger, Nicole; Hansis, Alexandra</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Productivity and efficiency at large and community banks in the US: A Bayesian true random effects stochastic distance frontier analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, Guohua; Zhang, Xiaohui
This paper compares the productivity and efficiency of large banks and community banks in the United States over the period 1997-2006. This comparison is performed by estimating a true random effects stochastic distance frontier model-a model that is capable of disentangling unobserved heterogeneity from inefficiency-within a Bayesian framework. We find that failure to consider unobserved heterogeneity results in a misleading ranking of banks and mismeasured technical efficiency, productivity growth, and returns to scale. Our results show that, compared with community banks, large banks have experienced much higher productivity growth and higher levels of returns to scale. Our estimates of total factor productivity growth show a clear downward trend for both large and community banks, and our decomposition of the output-distance-function-based Divisia productivity index indicates that technical change is the driving force behind this trend. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Feng, Guohua; Zhang, Xiaohui</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Granularity adjustment for mark-to-market credit risk models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gordy, Michael B.; Marrone, James
The impact of undiversified idiosyncratic risk on value-at-risk and expected shortfall can be approximated analytically via a methodology known as granularity adjustment (GA). In principle, the GA methodology can be applied to any risk-factor model of portfolio risk. Thus far, however, analytical results have been derived only for simple models of actuarial loss, i.e., credit loss due to default. We demonstrate that the GA is entirely tractable for single-factor versions of a large class of models that includes all the commonly used mark-to-market approaches. Our approach covers both finite ratings-based models and models with a continuum of obligor states. We apply our methodology to CreditMetrics and KMV Portfolio Manager, as these are benchmark models for the finite and continuous classes, respectively. Comparative statics of the GA reveal striking and counterintuitive patterns. We explain these relationships with a stylized model of portfolio risk. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Gordy, Michael B.; Marrone, James</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal portfolios with minimum capital requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santos, Andre A. P.; Nogales, Francisco J.; Ruiz, Esther; Van Dijk, Dick
We propose a novel approach to active risk management based on the recent Basel II regulations to obtain optimal portfolios with minimum capital requirements. In order to avoid regulatory penalties due to an excessive number of Value-at-Risk (VaR) violations, capital requirements are minimized subject to a given number of violations over the previous trading year. Capital requirements are based on the recent Basel II amendments to account for the 'stressed' VaR, that is, the downside risk of the portfolio under extreme adverse market conditions. An empirical application for two portfolios involving different types of assets and alternative stress scenarios demonstrates that the proposed approach delivers an improved balance between capital requirement levels and the number of VaR exceedances. Furthermore, the risk-adjusted performance of the proposed approach is superior to that of minimum-VaR and minimum-stressed VaR portfolios. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Santos, Andre A. P.; Nogales, Francisco J.; Ruiz, Esther; Van Dijk, Dick</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bounds on the autocorrelation of admissible stochastic discount factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chretien, Stephane
We show how to use asset market data to restrict the admissible region for the first-order autocorrelation of the stochastic discount factor (SDF). We interpret this statistic as a measure of a model's economic time variation across two periods. Estimating bounds for nominal and real SDFs at monthly and quarterly frequencies, we find that the admissible autocorrelations are significantly negative, but greater than -0.02, implying that the bounds impose a strong restriction on candidate SDFs. We illustrate the relevancy of these findings by showing that some widely used consumption-based models are misspecified with respect to the autocorrelation bound. Finally, we examine the implications of our results for the admissibility of linear factor models and the appropriateness of empirical pricing factors. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chretien, Stephane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The week-of-the-year effect: Evidence from around the globe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Tamir; Yagil, Joseph
This study investigates another calendar anomaly the literature does not yet address - the week-of-the-year (WOY) effect. Using the weekly returns on the stock market indexes of 20 countries worldwide, for a period that ends in December 2010, the findings demonstrate that returns in Week 44, which starts on October 29 and ends on November 4, are positive in 19 of the 20 countries, and in 18 of them, it is also statistically significant. In contrast, the returns for Week 43, which starts on October 22 and ends on October 28, are negative in 19 of the 20 countries, and statistically significant for most of the countries. We also apply an investment strategy derived from these findings to a prediction period (2009-2010), and find that this strategy beats the simple buy-and-hold policy by a substantial margin. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Levy, Tamir; Yagil, Joseph</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banning short sales and market quality: The UK's experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marsh, Ian W.; Payne, Richard
We study the effects that the ban on short sales of shares in financial firms introduced in late 2008 and removed early 2009 had on the microstructure and the quality of UK equity markets. We show that the ban did nothing to affect order flows: financial stocks were being more aggressively sold off than their peers pre-ban and this situation persisted through the ban period. Trading volume in financials was massively reduced, however. The ban decimated order book liquidity for financials. The deterioration was symmetric, affecting the limit buy and limit sell side of the order book equally. Finally we show that, through the period of the ban, markets for financial stocks were substantially less efficient and that the role of the trading process in aiding price discovery was greatly reduced. The effects identified above were largely reversed once the ban was lifted. The persistence of the deterioration in market quality and liquidity though the relatively long-lasting UK ban on short selling suggests that other major market developments such as the TARP program were not responsible since these were concentrated in the early half of the ban. We thus argue that the short selling ban was responsible for detrimental effects on the quality of UK equity markets and that, far from being stabilising, the ban exacerbated problems in valuing UK financial stocks. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marsh, Ian W.; Payne, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-Gaussian diversification: When size matters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desmoulins-Lebeault, Francois; Kharoubi-Rakotomalala, Cecile
Classical portfolio theory informs investors that they should have a large number of assets in their portfolios in order to diversify risk. We show that the non-Gaussian features of stock return distribution may not allow for this risk protection in times of crisis. Moreover, we demonstrate empirically that, if investors are risk-averse and consider higher order moments, they have numerous incentives not to diversify their portfolios fully. This is caused by the evolution of both large losses and asymmetry of returns when the numbers of assets in a portfolio change. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Desmoulins-Lebeault, Francois; Kharoubi-Rakotomalala, Cecile</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New measures of monetary policy surprises and jumps in interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leon, Angel; Sebestyen, Szabolcs
We propose new surprise measures to characterise two important dimensions of monetary policy. Our measures outperform the traditional monetary shocks in explaining variation of interest rates in the event-study framework. We also study the extent to which the ECB caused jumps in euro area interest rates. The new surprises still prevail upon the traditional ones. Jumps play a great role in the variation of interest rates and the ECB induced several jumps with its decisions, but its predictability has improved over time. We find that, although the surprise measures become somewhat distorted due to money market tensions during the financial turmoil, our model still provides an interesting insight into interest rate behaviour throughout the crisis. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leon, Angel; Sebestyen, Szabolcs</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of reputation on analysts' conflicts of interest: Hot versus cold markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, Daniel; Clarke, Jonathan; Cooney, John
During periods of high IPO underpricing, unaffiliated all-star analysts from high reputation banks issue fewer strong-buy recommendations while unaffiliated all-star analysts from low reputation banks do not change their level of optimism. In contrast, unaffiliated non-star analysts from both high and low reputation banks issue more strong-buy recommendations. Consistent with the results on analyst optimism, the market reacts more favorably to strong-buy recommendations by unaffiliated all-star analysts from high reputation banks than other unaffiliated analysts during high IPO underpricing periods. Finally, we find that unaffiliated non-star analysts from low reputation banks reduce their coverage following an SEO if they are not selected as a part of the managing syndicate. Collectively, our results indicate that during periods of high IPO underpricing unaffiliated analysts face conflicts of interest, but personal-level reputation, and to a lesser extent bank-level reputation, plays a role in reducing this bias. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bradley, Daniel; Clarke, Jonathan; Cooney, John</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Income diversification and risk: Does ownership matter? An empirical examination of Indian banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pennathur, Anita K.; Subrahmanyam, Vijaya; Vishwasrao, Sharmila
We examine the impact of ownership on income diversification and risk for Indian banks over the period 2001-2009. We investigate both the determinants of non-interest income and the impact of diversification on various profitability and insolvency risk measures for public sector, private domestic, and foreign banks. We document that ownership does matter in the pursuit of non-interest income. Relative to private domestic banks, public sector banks earn significantly less fee-income, while foreign banks report higher fee income. Public sector banks with higher levels of governmental ownership are significantly less likely to pursue non-interest income sources. Fee-based income significantly reduces risk, measured by profitability variables, for public sector banks. Default risk is also reduced for these banks. From a regulatory perspective, it appears that diversification benefits India's public sector banks. Our research has implications for the changes in the risk profile for banks in emerging banking markets pursuing non-interest revenue sources. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pennathur, Anita K.; Subrahmanyam, Vijaya; Vishwasrao, Sharmila</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are corporate bond market returns predictable?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Yongmiao; Lin, Hai; Wu, Chunchi
This paper examines the predictability of corporate bond returns using the transaction-based index data for the period from October 1, 2002 to December 31, 2010. We find evidence of significant serial and cross-serial dependence in daily investment-grade and high-yield bond returns. The serial dependence exhibits a complex nonlinear structure. Both investment-grade and high-yield bond returns can be predicted by past stock market returns in-sample and out-of-sample, and the predictive relation is much stronger between stocks and high-yield bonds. By contrast, there is little evidence that stock returns can be predicted by past bond returns. These findings are robust to various model specifications and test methods, and provide important implications for modeling the term structure of defaultable bonds. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Yongmiao; Lin, Hai; Wu, Chunchi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are mutual fund fees excessive?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, John C.; Mansi, Sattar A.; Nishikawa, Takeshi
There is a long running debate over whether competition in the mutual fund industry limits the ability of investment advisors to charge fees that are disproportionate to the services they provide. We posit that disproportionately high fees are prevalent in funds with multiple share classes and those with weak governance structures. Using a comprehensive sample of index mutual funds for the from 1998 to 2007, we find that internal governance mechanisms matter primarily for funds with relatively small share classes where investors often face increased search costs and/or restricted access to competitive mutual funds. Additionally, we find that funds managed by publicly held sponsors are associated with disproportionately higher fee spreads (about 28 basis points). The results are robust to the inclusion of board characteristics, share class structure, and investment objectives. Overall, our findings suggest that competition and agency considerations are important determinants in the pricing of mutual funds. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, John C.; Mansi, Sattar A.; Nishikawa, Takeshi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond the Sharpe ratio: An application of the Aumann-Serrano index to performance measurement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Homm, Ulrich; Pigorsch, Christian
We propose a performance measure that generalizes the Sharpe ratio. The new performance measure is monotone with respect to stochastic dominance and consistently accounts for mean, variance and higher moments of the return distribution. It is equivalent to the Sharpe ratio if returns are normally distributed. Moreover, the two performance measures are asymptotically equivalent as the underlying distributions converge to the normal distribution. We suggest a parametric and a non-parametric estimator for the new performance measure and provide an empirical illustration using mutual funds and hedge funds data. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Homm, Ulrich; Pigorsch, Christian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option trading: Information or differences of opinion?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choy, Siu Kai; Wei, Jason
This paper investigates the motive of option trading. We show that option trading is mostly driven by differences of opinion, a finding different from the current literature that attempts to attribute option trading to information asymmetry. Our conclusion is based on three pieces of empirical evidence. First, option trading around earnings announcements is speculative in nature and mostly dominated by small, retail investors. Second, around earnings announcements, the pre-announcement abnormal turnovers of options seem to predict the post-announcement abnormal stock returns. However, once we control for the pre-announcement stock returns, the predictability completely disappears, implying that option traders simply take cues from the stock market and turn around to speculate in the options market. Third, cross-section and time-series regressions reveal that option trading is also significantly explained by differences of opinion. While informed trading is present in stocks, it is not detected in options. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choy, Siu Kai; Wei, Jason</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting the performance of hedge fund styles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Olmo, Jose; Sanso-Navarro, Marcos
This article predicts the relative performance of hedge fund investment styles using time-varying conditional stochastic dominance tests. These tests allow for the construction of dynamic trading strategies based on nonparametric density forecasts of hedge fund returns. During the recent financial turmoil, our tests predict a superior performance for the Global Macro investment style compared with the other strategies of 'Directional Traders'. The Dedicated Short Bias investment style is stochastically dominated by the other directional styles. These results are confirmed by simple nonparametric tests constructed from realized excess returns. Further, by utilizing a cross-validation method for optimal bandwidth parameter selection, we discover the factors that have predictive power regarding the density of hedge fund returns. We observe that different factors have forecasting power for different regions of the returns distribution and, more importantly, that the Fung and Hsieh factors have power not only for describing the risk premium but also, if appropriately exploited, for density forecasting. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Olmo, Jose; Sanso-Navarro, Marcos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational and behavioral motives to trade: Evidence from reinvestment of dividends and tender offer proceeds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaustia, Markku; Rantapuska, Elias
We provide evidence of households' stock market trading in response to clearly identifiable positive cash flow shocks: dividend payments and tender offer proceeds. Transaction cost motives appear important, and there is some support for rational portfolio rebalancing and life cycle considerations as well. Households' tendency to reinvest is low, even for large and unexpected dividend payments. This is consistent with a default choice bias, and is not due to dividend clientele effects. Reinvestment of tender offer proceeds is significantly higher, controlling for other important factors. This is consistent with mental accounting, i.e., cash flows from different sources are treated differently. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaustia, Markku; Rantapuska, Elias</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downside risk of international stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galsband, Victoria
This paper investigates the downside risk exposure of international stock returns in 14 major industrialized economies around the world. For the period 1975-2010, we find that differences in returns on value and growth portfolios can be rationalized by assets' reagibilities to market's downside shocks. International value stocks are particularly sensitive to market's permanent downside shocks, while international growth stocks are particularly sensitive to market's temporary downside shocks. In line with recent evidence for the US, risk associated with unfavorable changes in market's cash-flow innovations carries a premium which is pervasive and statistically significant. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Galsband, Victoria</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real options and earnings-based bonus compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Hsing-Hua; Huang, Hongming; Shih, Pai-Ta
This study extends the works of Mauer and Sarkar (2005) and Andrikopoulos (2009) by incorporating a regime-dependent earnings-based bonus into managerial compensation. Examining the individual effects of ownership shares and earnings-based bonus compensation, we find that the former provides managers with incentives to issue debt, whereas the latter induces the opposite result, although consistent impacts are found for the two types of compensation on both agency costs and the optimal investment decisions of managers. When managerial compensation comprises both ownership shares and an earnings-based bonus, there are significant differences in the effects of these two types of performance compensation on managers' optimal investment and financing decisions, agency costs, optimal debt ratios and credit spreads, as a result of the specific interactions between the investment and financing decisions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Hsing-Hua; Huang, Hongming; Shih, Pai-Ta</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The sources of bank productivity growth in China during 2002-2009: A disaggregation view</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Tzu-Pu; Hu, Jin-Li; Chou, Ray Yeutien; Sun, Lei
This study investigates the sources of bank productivity growth in China over the period 2002-2009. In order to perform this research, we propose an advanced index - input slack-based productivity index (ISP) - a model that disaggregates total factor productivity growth into each input productivity change. Funds, capital, and employees are chosen as the inputs, whereas loans and other earning assets are outputs in this study. Our results show that technological gains transcend the efficiency regressions and result in total factor productivity growth. More specifically, technical progress in capital productivity reveals the dominant force behind the total factor technical change and productivity improvement. In addition, this paper uses these disaggregation terms to find out the competitive advantages and disadvantages of input usages for each Chinese bank. These findings indicate that the ISP index provides more insights than traditional total factor productivity indices. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Tzu-Pu; Hu, Jin-Li; Chou, Ray Yeutien; Sun, Lei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting government bond yields with large Bayesian vector autoregressions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carriero, Andrea; Kapetanios, George; Marcellino, Massimiliano
We propose a new approach to forecasting the term structure of interest rates, which allows to efficiently extract the information contained in a large panel of yields. In particular, we use a large Bayesian Vector Autoregression (BVAR) with an optimal amount of shrinkage towards univariate AR models. The optimal shrinkage is chosen by maximizing the Marginal Likelihood of the model. Focusing on the US, we provide an extensive study on the forecasting performance of the proposed model relative to most of the existing alternative specifications. While most of the existing evidence focuses on statistical measures of forecast accuracy, we also consider alternative measures based on trading schemes and portfolio allocation. We extensively check the robustness of our results, using different datasets and Monte Carlo simulations. We find that the proposed BVAR approach produces competitive forecasts, systematically more accurate than random walk forecasts, even though the gains are small. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carriero, Andrea; Kapetanios, George; Marcellino, Massimiliano</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal tax-timing and asset allocation when tax rebates on capital losses are limited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marekwica, Marcel
This article studies the portfolio problem with realization-based capital gain taxation when limited amounts of losses qualify for tax rebate payments, as is the case under current US tax law. When the tax rate applicable to realized losses exceeds that on realized capital gains, it can be optimal to realize capital gains immediately and pay capital gain taxes to regain the option to use potential future losses against a higher tax rate. This incentive adds an entirely new and as yet unstudied dimension to the portfolio problem. It causes risk averse investors to hold more equity and attain higher welfare levels than is the case when trading under a tax system that seeks to collect the same amount of taxes, but does not allow for tax rebate payments. This is because the benefit to these investors from having their losses subsidized is greater than the suffering from having profits taxed at a higher rate. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marekwica, Marcel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership and technical efficiency of microfinance institutions: Empirical evidence from Latin America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Servin, Roselia; Lensink, Robert; van den Berg, Marrit
By using stochastic frontier analysis, this article examines the technical efficiency of different types of microfinance institutions in Latin America. In particular, it tests whether differences in technical efficiency, both intra- and interfirm, can be explained by differences in ownership. With a focus on non-governmental organizations, cooperatives and credit unions, non-bank financial intermediaries, and banks, the data set contains 1681 observations from a panel of 315 institutions operating in 18 Latin American countries. The results show that non-governmental organizations and cooperatives have much lower interfirm and intrafirm technical efficiencies than non-bank financial intermediaries and banks, which indicates the importance of ownership type for technical efficiency. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Servin, Roselia; Lensink, Robert; van den Berg, Marrit</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transparency in IPO mechanism: Retail investors' participation, IPO pricing and returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neupane, Suman; Poshakwale, Sunil S.
Using data from the transparent Indian IPO setting, the paper examines retail investors' participation, their influence on IPO pricing and the returns they make on IPO investment. The transparency in the mechanism, which allows investors to observe prior investors' participation, leads to demand which is concentrated at either one or two points of the offer price range. Analysis of investors' demand during the offer period shows that the participation of retail investors is significantly influenced by the participation of institutional investors. We examine IPO pricing and find that favourable demand by retail investors is positively associated with a high IPO price even after controlling for demand by institutional investors. Further, we find that due to aggressive bidding by overconfident investors, retail investors are, on average, unlikely to make positive allocation weighted initial returns even in a setting where they do not have to compete with institutional investors. Retail investors, however, can earn significant positive allocation weighted initial returns if they limit their participation in IPOs with above average institutional investors' demand. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Neupane, Suman; Poshakwale, Sunil S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A decision-theoretic foundation for reward-to-risk performance measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schuhmacher, Frank; Eling, Martin
In this paper we prove that partial-moments-based performance measures (e.g., Omega, Kappa, upside-potential ratio, Sortino-Satchell ratio, Farinelli-Tibiletti ratio), value-at-risk-based performance measures (e.g., VaR ratio, CVaR ratio, Rachev ratio, generalized Rachev ratio), and other admissible performance measures are a strictly increasing function in the Sharpe ratio. The theoretical basis of this result is the location and scale property and two other plausible and mild conditions. Our result provides a decision-theoretic foundation for all these frequently used performance measures. Moreover, it might explain the empirical finding that all these measures typically lead to very similar rankings. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schuhmacher, Frank; Eling, Martin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>False discoveries in volatility timing of mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Sangbae; In, Francis
This paper examines the volatility timing of US mutual funds by controlling the false discovery rate to find out how many funds are truly countercyclical (procyclical) timing funds. Empirical results show that, given the whole universe of our sample funds, the percentages of countercyclical and procyclical volatility timing funds are about equal. We also find that while the standard approach, which simply counts the number of significant positive (negative) timing coefficients, does not incorporate false discoveries in volatility timing, it provides quite accurate volatility timing results. Finally, we find that the performance measures for an equally weighted portfolio of procyclical timing funds are greater than for an equally weighted portfolio of countercyclical timing funds in the in-sample test, consistent with our expectation that procyclical timers earn higher returns because they take on more risk. However, the countercyclical timing portfolio outperforms the procyclical timing portfolio in the out-of-sample test. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Sangbae; In, Francis</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed trading, information uncertainty, and price momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yifan; Zhao, Huainan
In this paper we investigate the effects of informed trading (PIN) and information uncertainty in determining price momentum. We find that trading strategies based on buying high-uncertainty good-news stocks and shorting high-uncertainty bad-news stocks work well when limited to high-PIN stocks, while stocks with low-PIN do not exhibit price continuations, even when the uncertainty level of those stocks is high. In contrast, momentum returns are always significant for high-PIN stocks, irrespective of information uncertainty. Overall, we show that the informed trading effect is both independent of and stronger than that of information uncertainty in determining price momentum. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Yifan; Zhao, Huainan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multimarket trading and corporate bond liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Petrasek, Lubomir
Global bonds are international securities traded and settled efficiently in multiple markets. This paper examines global bonds to evaluate the effects of multimarket trading on corporate bond liquidity and pricing. The results show that global bonds are significantly more liquid than similar-sized domestic bonds of the same issuers, and their liquidity advantage is reflected in higher market valuations. These findings support microstructure models that predict a positive relation between the number of potential investors and liquidity in over-the-counter markets, and help explain the increasing use of global bonds by corporate issuers. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Petrasek, Lubomir</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing with partial-moments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anthonisz, Sean A.
I bridge the current pricing kernel framework with the early partial-moment pricing models of the beta framework, thereby reconciling and clarifying these bodies of literature. I argue for the inclusion of powers of min and max functions within a generalized kernel, and form a generalized beta model. Polynomial kernels and the kernel underpinning the partial-moment analogue of the Sharpe-Lintner CAPM are nested. I derive the partial-moment analogue to the Black CAPM, thus completing a theoretical parallelism, and compare the kernel-implied and canonical risk-neutral probabilities. A new model involving both lower and upper partial-moments, accommodating various kernel shapes present in the literature, is developed in the context of preference regularity conditions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anthonisz, Sean A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sophistication and risk taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Dreu, Jan; Bikker, Jacob A.
Using investment policy data of 857 Dutch pension funds during 1999-2006, we develop three indicators of investor sophistication. The indicators show that pension funds' strategic portfolio choices are often based on coarse and less sophisticated approaches. First, most pension funds round strategic asset allocations to the nearest multiple of 5%, similar to age heaping in demographic and historical studies. Second, many pension funds invest little or nothing in alternative, more complex asset classes, resulting in limited asset diversification. Third, many pension funds favor regional investments and as such do not fully employ the opportunities of international risk diversification. Our indicators are correlated with pension fund size, in line with the expectation that smaller pension funds are generally less sophisticated than large pension funds. Using the indicators for investor sophistication, we show that less sophisticated pension funds tend to opt for investment strategies with less risk. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Dreu, Jan; Bikker, Jacob A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incorporating risk input into the analysis of bank productivity: Application to the Taiwanese banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Ku-Hsieh
This study reappraises banks' productivity by using 42 Taiwanese banks during 1999-2007 as observations. It introduces an input-oriented generalized metafrontier Malmquist productivity index (I-gMMPI), while considering the latent effect of risk-taking behavior in the analytic framework. We learn that public and private banks should face separate short-term technological frontiers, while the econometric model considering risk input can portray banks' operating frontiers better. Moreover, neglecting the influence of risk input would bring about distortions of efficiency, technology and TFP dynamic estimations for banks; meanwhile, the degree of scale economies would also be overestimated. The paper concludes that neglecting the risk-taking essence in bank performance evaluation is equal to allowing banks to barter risk-bearing as the term for further output growth. Consequently, the potential cost is that banks may excessively aggrandize their scales of business, implying the possibility of another financial crisis. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Ku-Hsieh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification and risk-adjusted performance: A quantile regression approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Bong Soo; Li, Ming-Yuan Leon
The effect of diversification on firm performance has been debated. We reexamine the effect using a sample of 44,248 observations of non-financial US firms for the 1997-2009 period employing the quantile regression approach. Our empirical results show that the effect of diversification on firm performance is not homogeneous across various quantile levels: the diversification discount (premium) shows up in firms with high (low) RoE quantiles. Further, we find that diversification affects firm risk as well. Therefore, we consider a risk-adjusted performance measure and find that both diversification discount and premium disappear, which is consistent with the risk-return trade-off principle. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Bong Soo; Li, Ming-Yuan Leon</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Parameter uncertainty in portfolio selection: Shrinking the inverse covariance matrix</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kourtis, Apostolos; Dotsis, George; Markellos, Raphael N.
The estimation of the inverse covariance matrix plays a crucial role in optimal portfolio choice. We propose a new estimation framework that focuses on enhancing portfolio performance. The framework applies the statistical methodology of shrinkage directly to the inverse covariance matrix using two non-parametric methods. The first minimises the out-of-sample portfolio variance while the second aims to increase out-of-sample risk-adjusted returns. We apply the resulting estimators to compute the minimum variance portfolio weights and obtain a set of new portfolio strategies. These strategies have an intuitive form which allows us to extend our framework to account for short-sale constraints, transaction costs and singular covariance matrices. A comparative empirical analysis against several strategies from the literature shows that the new strategies often offer higher risk-adjusted returns and lower levels of risk. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kourtis, Apostolos; Dotsis, George; Markellos, Raphael N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intertemporal capital budgeting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roper, Andrew H.; Ruckes, Martin E.
This paper analyzes the optimal capital budgeting mechanism when divisional managers are privately informed about the arrival of future investment projects. Consistent with field study evidence, an optimal allocation mechanism can include a stipulation that a capital request for discretionary investment will be declined with positive probability in the period after a significant investment was made even though this is ex post suboptimal. The model derives a number of empirical predictions regarding capital budgeting and the investment of financially constrained firms. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roper, Andrew H.; Ruckes, Martin E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank profitability during recessions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolt, Wilko; de Haan, Leo; Hoeberichts, Marco; van Oordt, Maarten R. C.; Swank, Job
This paper contributes to the literature on the relation between bank profitability and economic activity. When allowing for stronger co-movement of bank profit with economic activity during deep recessions, we find a much larger impact of output growth on bank profitability than commonly found in the literature. Among the different components of bank profit, loan losses are the main driver of this result. We also find long-term interest rates in previous years to be important determinants of bank profit in times of high economic growth. Our findings are robust to the use of aggregate or individual bank data. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bolt, Wilko; de Haan, Leo; Hoeberichts, Marco; van Oordt, Maarten R. C.; Swank, Job</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rehabilitating the role of active management for pension funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aglietta, Michel; Briere, Marie; Rigot, Sandra; Signori, Ombretta
Pension fund returns can be decomposed into different sources, including market movements, asset allocation policy, and active portfolio management. We use a unique database covering the asset allocations of US defined-benefit pension funds for the period 1990-2008, and we test the role of each factor in explaining their returns. Our results shed new light on pension funds' sources of performance. While the previous literature emphasized that policy allocation accounts for the bulk of returns, leaving little room for active management, we show that taking explicit account of market movement can change the results significantly. Although active management plays a minor role in global asset allocation, its role is predominant in explaining returns to individual asset classes, whether traditional or alternative. This paper rehabilitates the contribution of active management as a source of performance for pension funds, at least at the asset class level. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aglietta, Michel; Briere, Marie; Rigot, Sandra; Signori, Ombretta</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State uncertainty in stock markets: How big is the impact on the cost of equity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Yufeng
We propose a novel Bayesian framework to incorporate uncertainty about the state of the market. Among others, one advantage of the framework is the ability to model a large collection of time-varying parameters simultaneously. When we apply the framework to estimate the cost of equity we find economically significant effects of state uncertainty. A state-independent pricing model overestimates the cost of equity by about 4% per annum for a utility firm and by as much as 3% for industries. We also observe that the expected return, volatility, risk loading, and pricing error all display state-dependent dynamics that coincide with the business cycle. More interestingly, the forecasted market and Fama-French factor risk premiums can predict the future real GDP growth rate even though the model does not use any macroeconomic variables, which suggests that the proposed Bayesian framework captures the state-dependent dynamics well. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Han, Yufeng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of big-bank presence on the profit efficiency of small banks in rural markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cyree, Ken B.; Spurlin, W. Paul
Because big banks could impact competition in rural markets, we investigate the effects of big-bank presence on the performance of rural, small banks. When competing against a big bank, rural one-county banks operate at lower levels of profit efficiency, but with higher ROA and increased levels of interest and fee income from loans. Lower profit efficiency and higher returns in the rural markets suggest that big banks possess market power in rural markets and that they can extract rents to earn higher returns with lower than average profit efficiency. Therefore, small banks in rural markets should not fear large competitors. Conversely, customers who rely on loans from rural, small banks are negatively impacted by higher rates and fees on loans when a big bank is present in the market. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cyree, Ken B.; Spurlin, W. Paul</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio frontiers with restrictions to tracking error volatility and value at risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Palomba, Giulio; Riccetti, Luca
Asset managers are often given the task of restricting their activity by keeping both the value at risk (VaR) and the tracking error volatility (TEV) under control. However, these constraints may be impossible to satisfy simultaneously because VaR is independent of the benchmark portfolio. The management of these restrictions is likely to affect portfolio performance and produces a wide variety of scenarios in the risk-return space. The aim of this paper is to analyse various interactions between portfolio frontiers when risk managers impose joint restrictions upon TEV and VaR. Specifically, we provide analytical solutions for all the intersections and we propose simple numerical methods when such solutions are not available. Finally, we introduce a new portfolio frontier. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Palomba, Giulio; Riccetti, Luca</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the choice of estimator matter when forecasting returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Westerlund, Joakim; Narayan, Paresh Kumar
While the literature concerned with the predictability of stock returns is huge, surprisingly little is known when it comes to role of the choice of estimator of the predictive regression. Ideally, the choice of estimator should be rooted in the salient features of the data. In case of predictive regressions of returns there are at least three such features; (i) returns are heteroskedastic, (ii) predictors are persistent, and (iii) regression errors are correlated with predictor innovations. In this paper we examine if the accounting of these features in the estimation process has any bearing on our ability to forecast future returns. The results suggest that it does. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Westerlund, Joakim; Narayan, Paresh Kumar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do bank acquirers want? Evidence from worldwide bank M&amp;A targets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caiazza, Stefano; Clare, Andrew; Pozzolo, Alberto Franco
What drives bankers to create larger and larger, often multinational banking groups? In this paper we investigate whether the targets in cross-border bank M&amp;As are materially different from those banks targeted in domestic M&amp;A deals. The main message of this paper is that, with few exceptions, domestic and foreign investors target similar banks. In particular, and contrary to what one might expect, bank size does not have a different effect on the probability of being a domestic or a cross-border target, instead it has a positive and highly significant effect in both cases. We find that the main differences between national and international M&amp;As are the characteristics of the countries where the banks operate. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caiazza, Stefano; Clare, Andrew; Pozzolo, Alberto Franco</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Funding liquidity and equity liquidity in the subprime crisis period: Evidence from the ETF market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiu, Junmao; Chung, Huimin; Ho, Keng-Yu; Wang, George H. K.
Using index and financial exchange-traded funds (ETFs), this study explores the relation between funding liquidity and equity liquidity during the subprime crisis period. Our empirical results show that a higher degree of funding illiquidity leads to an increase in bid-ask spread and a reduction in both market depth and net buying imbalance. Such findings indicate that an increase in funding liquidity can improve equity liquidity, with a stronger effect for the financial ETFs than for the index ETFs. Our study provides a better overall understanding of the effect of the liquidity-supplier funding constraint during the subprime crisis period. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiu, Junmao; Chung, Huimin; Ho, Keng-Yu; Wang, George H. K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An international CAPM for partially integrated markets: Theory and empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arouri, Mohamed El Hedi; Nguyen, Duc Khuong; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara
This article proposes a theoretical testable capital asset pricing model for partially segmented markets. We establish that if some investors do not hold all international assets because of direct and/or indirect barriers, the world market portfolio is not efficient and the traditional international CAPM must be augmented by a new factor reflecting the local risk undiversifiable internationally. We also introduce a suitable framework to test this model empirically. Using a sample of six emerging markets and three mature markets, we find that the degree of stock market integration varies through time and that most of the sample emerging markets have become more integrated in the recent years. The local risk premium for emerging markets represents the most important component of the total risk premium, but its relative importance has decreased recently. Differently, the total risk premium for developed countries is largely driven by global factors. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arouri, Mohamed El Hedi; Nguyen, Duc Khuong; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why newly listed firms become acquisition targets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De, Soumendra; Jindra, Jan
We study the operating, financial, and ownership structure characteristics of newly listed firms which become acquisition targets shortly after their initial public offerings. We examine whether such firms get acquired because of their successful performance or as an alternative to delisting. We find that firms, which do relatively well in terms of operating as well as stock performance and attract institutional investor interest, draw the attention of acquirers. Furthermore, we observe that investments made by newly listed target firms do not destroy shareholder value and have comparable profitability to investments made by newly listed firms which grow by acquisitions. Overall, firms acquired shortly after listing are on a growth trajectory similar to that of surviving firms. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De, Soumendra; Jindra, Jan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What explains the investment growth anomaly?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prombutr, Wikrom; Phengpis, Chanwit; Zhang, Ying
We examine if an existing asset pricing model in an unconditional or conditional setting can explain the investment growth anomaly, as represented by higher returns on stocks of the firms with lower growth in capital expenditures. Our results indicate that the conditional Fama-French 3-factor model that allows factor loadings to be time-varying and further linked to firm-level characteristics and the business cycle can explain the anomaly. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Prombutr, Wikrom; Phengpis, Chanwit; Zhang, Ying</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>