<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Banking &amp; Finance2</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>The relation between religiosity and private bank outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cantrell, Brett W.; Yust, Christopher G.
We examine the effect of headquarters' local religiosity on private bank outcomes. Religiosity is associated with lower risk-taking for public banks, but the unique features of private banks may result in a different effect for private banks. We find religiosity is associated with greater asset risk-taking. At the same time, however, religiosity, is negatively associated with solvency risk and return on asset (ROA) volatility and is associated with higher ROAs and fewer failures. We reconcile these results by finding banks in areas with higher religiosity recognize larger fees from providing additional banking services, likely due to relationships formed from more risky lending. As a result, these banks are more (less) likely to realize extreme positive (negative) performance. We also find religiosity is associated with lower earnings management and increased conservatism. Collectively, our results confirm private banks are unique and religiosity can have a significant, and nuanced, effect on bank outcomes. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cantrell, Brett W.; Yust, Christopher G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's the value of a TBTF guaranty? Evidence from the G-SII designation for insurance companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dewenter, Kathryn L.; Riddick, Leigh A.
We document average abnormal stock returns of 14% for international insurance firms designated as Global Systemically Important Insurers (G-SII). These gains are associated with a fall in average default probability of 15.6%, and statistically weak and economically marginal increases in expected asset risk. Over the same event window, identical measures for other large insurance firms show no significant changes in equity returns or implied asset risk, but an increase in default probability of 27%. These results suggest that G-SII investors still perceive a net gain from TBTF protection, despite new compliance requirements and costs. Our evidence also suggests that these gains are driven primarily from reductions in default probability, as results are consistent with investor expectations that the new regulatory regime will limit moral hazard effects from the guaranty. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dewenter, Kathryn L.; Riddick, Leigh A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of supranational banking supervision on the financial sector: Event study evidence from Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loipersberger, Florian
This paper investigates how the introduction of the Single Supervisory Mechanism, the European Union's implementation of harmonized banking supervision, has affected the banking sector in Europe. I perform an event study on banks' stock returns and find evidence for small but significant positive effects. A potential hypothesis for this result is the fact that a single supervisory authority can take spillover effects between countries into account and is therefore able to stabilize the European banking sector. Splitting the sample by an indicator for supervisory power, an indicator for corruption, and by debt/GDP reveals that the positive impact of the SSM was stronger for banks in countries that perform poorly with respect to these measures. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loipersberger, Florian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Herding in analysts' recommendations: The role of media</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frijns, Bart; Huynh, Thanh D.
This study investigates the impact of media on analysts' herding behavior when making stock recommendations. We find three main results. First, we find that analysts herd less when stocks are covered more in the media. Second, when the firm has negative media sentiment, analysts tend to herd more. Third, higher disagreement in the media is associated with a higher tendency to herd among analysts. These findings are robust to the confounding effect of news flows on returns as well as to alternative explanations. In addition, we find that the effect of media on the herding behavior is conditional on analyst characteristics. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frijns, Bart; Huynh, Thanh D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizational structure, risk-based capital requirements, and the sales of downgraded bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Erin P.; Lai, Gene C.; Ma, Qingzhong
Using bond downgrades as external shocks to life insurers' asset risk, we document several findings of the impact of organizational structure and risk factors on investment risk taking. First, we find that mutual insurers and widely-held stock insurers are more likely to sell downgraded bonds than are closely-held stock insurers. Second, we find evidence that insurers are less likely to sell downgraded bonds that remain in the same rating class than bonds downgraded to a lower rating class. The result implies that insurers sell downgraded bonds mainly because of additional capital charge is imposed, not because of downgrade itself. In other words, risk factors in risk-based capital regulation do matter on life insurers' investment risk taking. Finally, we find that life insurers might be reluctant to sell downgraded bonds at fire-sale prices during the 2008-2009 financial crisis. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lu, Erin P.; Lai, Gene C.; Ma, Qingzhong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Excess reserves, monetary policy and financial volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Primus, Keyra
This paper examines the real and financial effects of reserves in a Dynamic Stochastic General Equilibrium (DSGE) model with monopoly banking and credit market imperfections. The framework explicitly accounts for the fact that commercial banks hold excess reserves and they incur costs in holding these assets. The model also accounts for imperfect substitutability between bank funding sources and it shows that this feature is an important channel through which reserve requirement shocks can affect real variables. Numerical experiments show that an increase in reserve requirements creates a countercyclical effect for real economic activity. The results also indicate that the combination of an augmented Taylor rule which responds to excess reserves and a countercyclical reserve requirement rule is optimal to mitigate macroeconomic and financial volatility associated with liquidity shocks. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Primus, Keyra</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Surprised or not surprised? The investors' reaction to the comprehensive assessment preceding the launch of the banking union</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carboni, Marika; Fiordelisi, Franco; Ricci, Ornella; Lopes, Francesco Saverio Stentella
Did the Comprehensive Assessment (CA), preceding the Single Supervisory Mechanism (SSM) launch in Europe, achieve its aims of producing new valuable information for the market? We show that the CA achieved the goal of increasing transparency: investors were able to detect weak banks at the announcement of the procedure (23rd October 2013), but gained full information on the amount of the capital shortfall only at the disclosure of the results (26th October 2014). Furthermore, at the official launch of the SSM (4th November 2014), banks under direct European Central Bank (ECB) supervision registered a more negative market reaction with respect to banks maintaining their national supervisors. Using a regression model including possible confounders and allowing for treatment effect heterogeneity, this negative reaction is confirmed. These findings suggest that, at least in the short run, investors penalized banks subject to direct ECB supervision, probably because of the fear of regulatory inconsistencies. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carboni, Marika; Fiordelisi, Franco; Ricci, Ornella; Lopes, Francesco Saverio Stentella</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accounting for banks, capital regulation and risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Jing
This paper examines risk-taking incentives in banks under different accounting regimes in presence of capital regulation. In the model the bank jointly determines the capital issuance and investment policy. Given an exogenous minimum capital requirement, lower-of-cost-or-market accounting is the most effective regime that induces the bank to issue more excess equity capital above the minimum required level and implement less risky investment policy. However, the disciplining role of lower-of-cost-or-market accounting may discourage the bank from exerting project discovery effort ex-ante. From the regulator's perspective, the accounting regime that maximizes the social welfare is determined by a tradeoff between the social cost of capital regulation and the efficiency of the bank's project discovery efforts. When the former effect dominates, the regulator prefers lower-of-cost-or-market accounting; when the latter effect dominates, the regulator may prefer other regimes. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Jing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The international effect of managerial social capital on the cost of equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferris, Stephen P.; Javakhadze, David; Rajkovic, Tijana
We examine the effect of managerial social capital on the firm's cost of equity capital. We argue that social ties alleviate information asymmetry and agency problems, which in turn leads to a decrease in the cost of equity. Using a large panel of companies from 52 countries over the period 1999-2012, we document that social capital inversely affects the cost of equity. Our evidence suggests that the association between social capital and the cost of equity capital is stronger in underdeveloped financial markets and those characterized by weak legal protection. The marginal effect of social capital is also stronger for constrained firms with profitable investment opportunities. Our results are robust to alternative model specifications and tests for endogeneity. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferris, Stephen P.; Javakhadze, David; Rajkovic, Tijana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>One-sided performance measures under Gram-Charlier distributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leon, Angel; Moreno, Manuel
We derive closed-form expressions for risk measures based on partial moments by assuming the Gram-Charlier (GC) density for stock returns. As a result, the lower partial moment (LPM) measures can be expressed as linear functions on both skewness and excess kurtosis. Under this framework, we study the behavior of portfolio rankings with performance measures based on partial moments, that is, both Farinelli-Tibiletti (FT) and Kappa ratios. Contrary to previous results, significant differences are found in ranking portfolios between the Sharpe ratio and the FT family. We also obtain closed-form expressions for LPMs under the semi non-parametric (SNP) distribution which allows higher flexibility than the GC distribution. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leon, Angel; Moreno, Manuel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of the European sovereign debt crisis on banks stocks. Some evidence of shift contagion in Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allegret, Jean-Pierre; Raymond, Helene; Rharrabti, Houda
This paper analyzes the influence of the recent European sovereign debt crisis on banks' equity returns for 15 countries. Our data span the period December 14th 2007 - March 8th 2013 that encompasses several episodes of economic and financial turmoil since the collapse of the subprime credit market. Our contribution to the literature is twofold. First, we use an explicit multifactor model of equity returns extended with a sovereign risk factor. Second, we adopt a Smooth Transition Regression (STR) framework that allows for an endogenous definition of crisis periods and captures the changes in parameters associated with shift contagion. We find that the negative impact of the European sovereign debt crisis on banks' equity returns has been mostly confined to European banks, whereas U.S. banks appear to be unharmed by its direct impact and may even have benefited from it. Besides, we find some evidence of shift contagion across Europe. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allegret, Jean-Pierre; Raymond, Helene; Rharrabti, Houda</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of simultaneous company defaults using a shot noise process</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Egami, M.; Kevkhishvili, R.
During the subprime mortgage crisis, it became apparent that practical models, such as the one-factor Gaussian copula, had underestimated company default correlations. Complex models that attempt to incorporate default dependency are difficult to implement in practice. In this study, we develop a model for a company asset process, based on which we calculate simultaneous default probabilities using an option-theoretic approach. In our model, a shot noise process serves as the key element for controlling correlations among companies' assets. The risk factor driving the shot noise process is common to all companies in an industry but the shot noise parameters are assumed company-specific; therefore, every company responds differently to this common risk factor. Our model gives earlier warning of financial distress and predicts higher simultaneous default probabilities than commonly used geometric Brownian motion asset model. It is also computationally simple and can be extended to analyze any finite number of companies. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Egami, M.; Kevkhishvili, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do locals know better? A comparison of the performance of local and foreign institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro; Pereira, Joao Pedro; Pires, Pedro
We compare the performance of local versus foreign institutional investors using a comprehensive data set of equity holdings in 32 countries during the 2000-2010 period. We find that foreign institutions perform as well as local institutions on average, but only domestic institutions show a trading pattern consistent with an information advantage. Our results suggest a smart-money effect of local institutions in countries subject to higher information asymmetry, non-English speaking countries, countries with less efficient stock markets, with poor investor protection, or high levels of corruption. The local advantage is more pronounced in periods of market turmoil and in illiquid stocks. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro; Pereira, Joao Pedro; Pires, Pedro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sentiment, flight-to-quality, and corporate bond comovement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bethke, Sebastian; Gehde-Trapp, Monika; Kempf, Alexander
We examine the dynamics of bond correlation using a broad sample of US corporate bonds, and document that bond correlation varies heavily over time. We attribute this variation in bond correlation to variation in risk factor correlation reflecting time-varying flight-to-quality behavior of investors. We show that risk factor correlation increases when investor sentiment worsens, i.e., corporate bond investors exhibit stronger flight-to-quality when their sentiment is bad. Thus, bad investor sentiment leads to flight to-quality behavior and, ultimately, high bond correlation. Very good sentiment, in contrast, can cause risk factor correlation and bond correlation to be negative. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bethke, Sebastian; Gehde-Trapp, Monika; Kempf, Alexander</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The synchronization of credit cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Meller, Barbara; Metiu, Norbert
This paper proposes a simple econometric procedure to test for the synchronization of credit cycles. Using a century of data for 14 advanced economies, we find that credit cycle synchronization dropped in the early 1920s from initially relatively high levels. Between the 1920s and the 1970s synchronization was overall low and concentrated within five, predominantly regional, clusters. However, synchronization has significantly increased in the post-Bretton Woods era and has become less associated with geographic proximity: Australia, Denmark, France, Italy, Japan, Norway, Spain, Switzerland, the UK, and the US form a single major credit cycle cluster since the 1970s. A smaller cluster is formed by Canada, the Netherlands, and Sweden, while the German credit cycle follows a distinct path. Using logistic regressions, we find that the synchronization of credit and business cycles go hand in hand. Our findings are especially relevant for the international coordination of macroprudential policy, as well as to spur and inform further analysis on credit cycle dynamics. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Meller, Barbara; Metiu, Norbert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash holdings between public and private insurers - a partial adjustment approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xie, Xiaoying; Wang, Yuling; Zhao, Guiqin; Lu, Weili
Cash holdings of financial institutions, especially private firms, have been understudied in existing literature. This paper fills that gap by examining the cash holdings of US property-liability insurers in order to analyze the difference in cash holdings and cash adjustments between public and private stock insurers and between mutual and stock insurers within the private insurer category. We find that public insurers hold much less cash than private stock insurers, which differs from the findings for non-financial firms. Additionally, we find that mutual insurers hold less cash than private stock insurers. Public insurers adjust their cash holdings much faster toward their target cash levels than private stock insurers do when facing an extreme cash shortfall, but their adjustment speed is indifferent from that of private stock insurers when both having excess cash. Mutual insurers are able to adjust cash holdings slightly faster than private stock insurers when there is an extreme cash shortfall but are indifferent in adjustment speed from private stock insurers when having excess cash in hand. Overall, our results are more consistent with the financing frictions hypothesis of cash holdings and are inconsistent with the owner-manager agency problems of free cash flow. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xie, Xiaoying; Wang, Yuling; Zhao, Guiqin; Lu, Weili</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Announcing the announcement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boulland, Romain; Dessaint, Olivier
What drives investors' attention? We study how far in advance earnings calendars are pre-announced and find that investors are more attentive to earnings news when such details are disclosed well ahead of time. This variation in investors' attention affects short-run and long-run stock returns, thereby creating incentives for firms to strategically pre-announce the report date on short notice when the earnings news is bad. Consistent with this idea, firms pre-announce their report dates well ahead of time when earnings are good and do it at the very last moment when earnings are bad. A trading strategy that exploits such variations yields abnormal returns of 1.5% per month. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boulland, Romain; Dessaint, Olivier</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resolution of financial distress under agency frictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moreno-Bromberg, Santiago; Vo, Quynh-Anh
We introduce, in a dynamic-contracting framework with moral hazard, the possibility of recapitalization as an alternative to liquidation when a firm is distressed. This is achieved by considering a risk-averse agent and by allowing (but not requiring) the latter to inject additional capital into the firm when necessary. We show that firm recapitalization may arise in an optimal, long-term contract. As a consequence, we find that there are two mechanisms at a firm's disposal so as to deal with financial difficulties: one corresponds to a recapitalization process, the other to a liquidation one. The choice of mechanism is based on a cost-benefit analysis. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moreno-Bromberg, Santiago; Vo, Quynh-Anh</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unfolded risk-return trade-offs and links to Macroeconomic Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Xiaochun
A general partial risk-return relation is derived based on return decomposition to allowing for the effect of time-varying skewness and kurtosis on the risk-return trade-off. Empirically estimated for 12 international financial markets, the proposed risk-return trade-off is significantly positive even after controlling for time-varying higher moments. Moreover, the stochastic dominance test reveals that modeling time-varying skewness significantly lowers the level of the risk-return trade-off. More importantly, the empirical evidence shows that the risk-return trade-off is countercyclical in the U.S. markets, consistent with the theoretical habit-formation model of Campbell and Cochrane (1999), whereas the risk-return trade-offs in European and emerging markets appear to be procyclical over a 12-month horizon, but countercyclical for a shorter horizon of 3 months. Finally, common macroeconomic variables can significantly explain risk return trade-off dynamics. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Xiaochun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Starting on the wrong foot: Seasonality in mutual fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Stephen J.; Sotes-Paladino, Juan; Wangd, Jiaguo; Yao, Yaqiong
We document a systematic seasonal component in the aggregate underperformance of active mutual funds. At the aggregate level, active funds underperform the market and other passive benchmarks only in the first month of a quarter. This intra-quarter performance seasonality holds across fund sizes and investment styles. The pattern is consistent with short-term stock return reversal effects along with aggregate window-dressing and, to a lesser extent, NAV-inflation practices around quarter-ends. We find marginal or no evidence of microstructure biases, fund investor flows, or cash distributions as sources of this seasonality. Our findings highlight new features of the active management underperformance puzzle. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Stephen J.; Sotes-Paladino, Juan; Wangd, Jiaguo; Yao, Yaqiong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of prepayment penalties in mortgage loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beltratti, Andrea; Benetton, Matteo; Gavazza, Alessandro
We study the effect of mortgage prepayment penalties on borrowers' prepayments and delinquencies by exploiting a 2007 reform in Italy that reduced penalties on outstanding mortgages and banned penalties on newly-issued mortgages. Using a unique dataset of mortgages issued by a large Italian lender, we provide evidence that: 1) before the reform, mortgages issued to riskier borrowers included larger penalties; 2) higher prepayment penalties decreased borrowers' prepayments; and 3) higher prepayment penalties did not affect borrowers' delinquencies. Moreover, we find suggestive evidence that prepayment penalties affected mortgage pricing, as well as prepayments and delinquencies through borrowers' mortgage selection at origination, most notably for riskier borrowers. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beltratti, Andrea; Benetton, Matteo; Gavazza, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation of diversified banks: New evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guerry, Nicolas; Wallmeier, Martin
This paper reconsiders the effect of diversification on bank valuation. Our objective is to provide new evidence based on a unified estimation framework that places particular emphasis on separating the effects of diversification (specialised banks vs. diversified banks) from those of bank type (investment banks vs. commercial banks). Consistent with prior studies, we find a significant diversification discount at the end of the 1990s. Our main finding is that it decreases over time and practically vanishes after the financial crisis. We do not find support for the hypothesis that the diversification effect is influenced by geographical or regulatory factors. The valuation impact of bank characteristics varies over time, particularly in the financial crisis, but this structural break does not explain the observed decrease of the diversification discount. We show that the pre-crisis discount is considerably smaller in a robust regression, which in part is driven by banks with a large share of non-interest income. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guerry, Nicolas; Wallmeier, Martin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal delta hedging for options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hull, John; White, Alan
As has been pointed out by a number of researchers, the normally calculated delta does not minimize the variance of changes in the value of a trader's position. This is because there is a non-zero correlation between movements in the price of the underlying asset and movements in the asset's volatility. The minimum variance delta takes account of both price changes and the expected change in volatility conditional on a price change. This paper determines empirically a model for the minimum variance delta. We test the model using data on options on the S&amp;P 500 and show that it is an improvement over stochastic volatility models, even when the latter are calibrated afresh each day for each option maturity. We also present results for options on the S&amp;P 100, the Dow Jones, individual stocks, and commodity and interest-rate ETFs. (C) 2017 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hull, John; White, Alan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Funding liquidity and bank risk taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khan, Muhammad Saifuddin; Scheule, Harald; Wu, Eliza
This study examines the relationship between funding liquidity and bank risk taking. Using quarterly data for U.S. bank holding companies from 1986 to 2014, we find evidence that banks having lower funding liquidity risk as proxied by higher deposit ratios, take more risk. A reduction in banks' funding liquidity risk increases bank risk as evidenced by higher risk-weighted assets, greater liquidity creation and lower Z-scores. However, our results show that bank size and capital buffers usually limit banks from taking more risk when they have lower funding liquidity risk. Moreover, during the Global Financial Crisis banks with lower funding, liquidity risk took less risk. The findings of this study have implications for bank regulators advocating greater liquidity and capital requirements for banks under Basel III. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khan, Muhammad Saifuddin; Scheule, Harald; Wu, Eliza</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk evaluations with robust approximate factor models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chou, Ray Yeutien; Yen, Tso-Jung; Yen, Yu-Min
Approximate factor models and their extensions are widely used in economic analysis and forecasting due to their ability to extracting useful information from a large number of relevant variables. In these models, candidate predictors are typically subject to some common components. In this paper we propose a new method for robustly estimating the approximate factor models and use it in risk assessments. We consider a class of approximate factor models in which the candidate predictors are additionally subject to idiosyncratic large uncommon components such as jumps or outliers. By assuming that occurrences of the uncommon components are rare, we develop an estimation procedure to simultaneously disentangle and estimate the common and uncommon components. We then use the proposed method to investigate whether risks from the latent factors are priced for expected returns of Fama and French 100 size and book-to-market ratio portfolios. We find that while the risk from the common factor is priced for the 100 portfolios, the risks from the idiosyncratic factors are not. However, we find that model uncertainty risks of the idiosyncratic factors are priced, suggesting that with effective diversifications, only the predictable idiosyncratic risks can be reduced, but the unpredictable ones may still exist. We also illustrate how the proposed method can be adopted on evaluating value at risk (VaR) and find it can "delivery comparable results as the conventional methods on VaR evaluations. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chou, Ray Yeutien; Yen, Tso-Jung; Yen, Yu-Min</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impacts of Net Stable Funding Ratio requirement on Banks' choices of debt maturity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wei, Xu; Gong, Yaxian; Wu, Ho-Mou
In this paper, we study the impacts of the Net Stable Funding Ratio (NSFR) requirement on banks' choices of debt maturity and asset structures, with consequences for banks' profitability and social welfare. We develop a model in which the manager of a bank determines both debt maturity structure (short-term vs. long-term debt) and asset composition (cash vs. risky assets). To address the incongruence of goals between the bank manager and the bank stakeholders, in our model we assume that the manager receives only a proportion of the bank's profit in her pay schedule. We demonstrate that the optimal choices of the manager regarding debt maturity and asset structure lead to socially inefficient (second-best) outcomes because the manager internalizes only part of the social benefit. We then study the implications of the NSFR requirement on the manager's choices and demonstrate that the NSFR requirement can enhance social welfare and reach an efficient (first-best) outcome, if a sufficiently low weight of short-term debt as available stable funding is required by regulation. Further, we find that under the same conditions the NSFR requirement reduces banks' use of short-term financing and thus increases the probability of banks' survival and profits from the ex ante point of view, while it decreases banks' profits from the ex post point of view, since it reduces the threshold for banks' survival. Our main results have some interesting empirical implications: under certain conditions, the NSFR requirement may reduce both bank failures and banks' observed profits. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wei, Xu; Gong, Yaxian; Wu, Ho-Mou</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real effects of bank capital regulations: Global evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deli, Yota D.; Hasan, Iftekhar
We examine the effect of the full set of bank capital regulations (capital stringency) on loan growth, using bank-level data for a maximum of 125 countries over the period 1998-2011. Contrary to standard theoretical considerations, we find that overall capital stringency only has a weak negative effect on loan growth. In fact, this effect is completely offset if banks hold moderately high levels of capital. Interestingly, the components of capital stringency that have the strongest negative effect on loan growth are those related to the prevention of banks to use as capital borrowed funds and assets other than cash or government securities. In contrast, compliance with Basel guidelines in using Basel-and credit-risk weights has a much less potent effect on loan growth. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Deli, Yota D.; Hasan, Iftekhar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The liquidity impact on firm values: The evidence of Taiwan's banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Ren-Raw; Yang, Tung-Hsiao; Yeh, Shih-Kuo
Liquidity plays an important role in financial markets, especially during a financial crisis. New Basel III regulatory framework highlights the importance of liquidity risk management implemented by financial institutions. Moreover, updated International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) require the improvements about fair value measurements and reinforce existing principles for disclosures about the liquidity risk associated with financial instruments. Using the liquidity discount model of Chen (2012), we are able to empirically classify Taiwan's financial institutions into three liquidity categories: safe, crisis contagious and vulnerable. Our findings can serve as an early warning signal for liquidity calamity. In addition, we investigate what factors affect firm-specific liquidity discounts for these institutions and conduct a sub period analysis, which examines whether there is significant liquidity discounts changes before and after the 2008 financial crisis. We find that liquidity discounts change substantially during the financial crisis. Furthermore, we find that liquidity discounts can be attributed to some firm -specific performance. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Ren-Raw; Yang, Tung-Hsiao; Yeh, Shih-Kuo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity creation through efficient M&amp;As: A viable solution for vulnerable banking systems? Evidence from a stress test under a panel VAR methodology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baltas, Konstantinos N.; Kapetanios, George; Tsionas, Efthymios; Izzeldin, Marwan
According to the "cost efficiency - liquidity creation" hypothesis (CELCH), introduced in this paper, a rise in a bank's cost efficiency level increases its liquidity creation. By employing a novel stress test scenario under a panel VAR methodology, the CELCH and the direction of causality between liquidity creation and cost efficiency are tested. Moreover, using new measures of liquidity creation (Berger and Bouwman, 2009), the question of whether potential bank mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As) can enhance liquidity creation and generate additional credit channels in the economy is addressed. The robustness of potential consolidation scenarios are evaluated and compared through the use of new "half-life" measures (Chortareas and Kapetanios, 2013). In line with CELCH, the positive impact of cost efficiency on liquidity creation is shown. The empirical evidence further suggests that potential consolidation activity can enhance the flow of credit in the economy. Bank shocks seem to have the most persistent effect on both liquidity creation and cost efficiency. Finally, doubts are cast on the strategies followed by policy authorities regarding the recent wave of M&amp;As in the banking sector. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baltas, Konstantinos N.; Kapetanios, George; Tsionas, Efthymios; Izzeldin, Marwan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shadows in the Sun: Crash risk behind Earnings Transparency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hung, Shengmin; Qiao, Zheng
Prior studies suggest that earnings and non-earnings information can be complementary to each other (Lundholm, 1988). Given the co-existence of both components, a lack of non-earnings information can end up boosting earnings explanatory power on returns in certain circumstances, producing spuriously high earnings transparency (ET) in Barth et al. (2013). This scenario is plausible when insiders are motivated to exploit their information advantage and discretionarily alter non-mandatory disclosure strategy. Conditional on higher insider trading profit, we uncover a positive relation between the firm-specific earnings transparency and crash risk. In addition, the above relation is more pronounced with respect to selling and profitable insider transactions. Overall, we demonstrate a potential dark side of high earnings explanatory power on stock returns, conditional on higher likelihood of non-earnings information hoarding. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hung, Shengmin; Qiao, Zheng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reprint of: The asymmetric effect of international swap lines on banks in emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andries, Alin Marius; Fischer, Andreas M.; Yesin, Pinar
This paper investigates the effect of international swap lines on stock returns using data from banks in emerging markets. The analysis first shows that swap lines by the Swiss National Bank (SNB) had a positive impact on bank stocks in Central and Eastern Europe. It then highlights the importance of individual bank characteristics in identifying the asymmetric effect of swap lines on bank stocks. Bank level evidence suggests that stock prices of local and less-well capitalized banks as well as banks with high foreign currency exposures and high reliance on short-term funding responded more strongly to SNB swap lines. This new evidence is consistent with the view that swap lines not only enhanced market liquidity but also reduced risks associated with micro-prudential issues. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andries, Alin Marius; Fischer, Andreas M.; Yesin, Pinar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reprint of: Central bank collateral frameworks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nyborg, Kjell G.
This paper seeks to inform about a feature of monetary policy that is largely overlooked, yet occupies a central role in modern monetary and financial systems, namely central bank collateral frameworks. Their importance can be understood by the observation that the money at the core of these systems, central bank money, is injected into the economy on terms, not defined in a market, but by the collateral frameworks and interest rate policies of central banks. Using the collateral framework of the Eurosystem as a basis of illustration and case study, the paper brings to light the functioning, reach, and impact of collateral frameworks. A theme that emerges is that collateral frameworks may have distortive effects on financial markets and the wider economy. They can, for example, bias the private provision of real liquidity and thereby also the allocation of resources in the economy as well as contribute to financial instability. Evidence is presented that the collateral framework in the euro area promotes risky and illiquid collateral and, more generally, impairs market forces and discipline. The paper also emphasizes the important role of ratings and government guarantees in the Eurosystem's collateral framework. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nyborg, Kjell G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flight-to-quality, economic fundamentals, and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaul, Aditya; Kayacetin, Nuri Volkan
We find that the order flow differential (OFD), a flight-to-quality measure constructed as the difference between large- and small-cap stock order flows, strongly and negatively forecasts output growth and interest rates in the U.S. The predictive ability of OFD for future macroeconomic fundamentals is robust to the inclusion of return factors and business cycle predictors, and it is thus a state variable candidate in the spirit of Merton (1973). Consistent with this view, we document that OFD commands a statistically significant negative risk premium in cross-sectional asset pricing tests. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaul, Aditya; Kayacetin, Nuri Volkan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does a manager's gender matter when accessing credit? Evidence from European data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moro, Andrea; Wisniewski, Tomasz Piotr; Mantovani, Guido Massimiliano
Firms can be credit constrained either because a loan has been denied by the lender or because they decide not to apply for such a loan due to expected rejection. Using a large sample of European small and medium enterprises, we investigate the relationship between gender and credit constraints. Although no evidence is found that financial institutions are biased against female managers, female-run firms are less likely to file a loan application, as they anticipate being rejected. As a consequence, firms managed by women obtain less bank financing. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moro, Andrea; Wisniewski, Tomasz Piotr; Mantovani, Guido Massimiliano</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposit competition and loan markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arping, Stefan
Less-intense competition for deposits, by mitigating banks' incentive to take excessive risks, is traditionally believed to lead to lower non-performing loan (NFL) ratios and more-stable banks. This paper revisits this proposition in a model with borrower moral hazard in which banks' NPL ratios depend endogenously on their loan pricing. In relatively uncompetitive loan markets, less-fierce competition for deposits (i.e., lower deposit rates) leads to lower loan rates and, thus, safer loans. In more-competitive markets, the opposite can occur: As banks' deposit-repayment burdens decline, they become less eager to risk-shift; this softens competition for risky loans, leading to higher loan rates and, ultimately, riskier loans. Overall, the model predicts a hump-shaped relationship between banks' pricing power in deposit markets and their NPL ratios. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arping, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The interbank network across the global financial crisis: Evidence from Italy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Affinito, Massimiliano; Pozzolo, Alberto Franco
This study examines the effects of the global financial crisis (GFC) on interbank market connectivity using network analysis. More specifically, using data on Italian banks' bilateral interbank positions between 1998 and 2013, we analyze the impact of the following events on each bank's network centrality: the liquidity crisis in August 2007, the collapse of Lehman Brothers in September 2008, Eurosystem's long term refinancing operations (LTROs) between 2009 and 2012, the sovereign debt crisis in July 2011, and the announcement of Outright Monetary Transactions (OMT) in 2012. The results show that the 2007 liquidity crisis and especially the collapse of Lehman Brothers are associated with a marked reduction of the relative interconnectedness of the Italian banking sector (i.e., a shift in the distribution of banks' centrality to the left, away from the most connected bank). In the following years, the system progressively recovered its initial patterns of integration among banks, which coincided with the main Eurosystem's monetary policy interventions. However, the average outcome conceals different results across banks, depending on their characteristics and initial positions within the system. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Affinito, Massimiliano; Pozzolo, Alberto Franco</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do board interlocks increase innovation? Evidence from a corporate governance reform in India</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helmers, Christian; Patnam, Manasa; Rau, P. Raghavendra
We examine the effect of board interlocks on patenting and R&amp;D spending for publicly traded companies in India. We exploit a corporate governance reform to address the endogeneity of board interlocks through exogenous changes mandated by the reform requiring a subset of firms to adjust their board structure. We rely on two difference-in-differences frameworks, comparing firms affected by the reform to unaffected firms as well as comparing within the set of firms that did not have to adjust their board structure those that still experienced an exogenous increase of their network size as a result of the reform to those that did not experience a change in their network size. We find that board interlocks have significant positive effects on both R&amp;D and patenting. The evidence suggests that the impact on R&amp;D is induced by information transmission through interlocks. The effect on patenting is driven by firms extending patent protection by patenting inventions abroad that they have already patented in India. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Helmers, Christian; Patnam, Manasa; Rau, P. Raghavendra</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rewarding risk-taking or skill? The case of private equity fund managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buchner, Axel; Wagner, Niklas F.
We examine whether typical private equity fund compensation contracts reward excessive risk-taking rather than managerial skill. Our analysis is based on a novel model of investment value, cash flows, and fee dynamics of private equity funds. Given the embedded option-like fee components, our results demonstrate that fund managers indeed have an incentive for excessive risk-taking when only fee income from the current fund is considered. However, when managers also consider potential compensation from follow-on funds, their risk-taking incentives depend on their individual skill levels, and skilled managers will have an incentive to reduce fund risk. We also show that managers must generate substantial abnormal returns in order to compensate investors for the given fee components. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buchner, Axel; Wagner, Niklas F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of bancassurance on efficiency and profitability of banks: Evidence from the banking industry in Taiwan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peng, Jin-Lung; Jeng, Vivian; Wang, Jennifer L.; Chen, Yen-Chih
We set out in this study to investigate whether bancassurance business leads to improvements in the efficiency and profitability of banks. We examine the positive impacts on the system using actual data provided by a unique database on banks engaging in bancassurance business in Taiwan between 2004 and 2012. Our results reveal that banks with greater involvement in bancassurance business generally tend to experience improvements in their efficiency, and thus also accrue greater profits. Our empirical results provide evidence to support that bancassurance business offers substantial benefits for banks, ultimately leading to an increase in shareholder value. Finally, our results also reveal that the adoption of a diversification strategy in bancassurance can impact bank performance. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Peng, Jin-Lung; Jeng, Vivian; Wang, Jennifer L.; Chen, Yen-Chih</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An approximate multi-period Vasicek credit risk model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia-Cespedes, Ruben; Moreno, Manuel
Financial institutions and regulators usually measure credit risk only over a one-year time horizon. Hence, current statistical models can generate closed-form expressions for the one-year loss distribution. Losses over longer horizons are considered using scenario analysis or Monte Carlo simulation. This paper proposes a simple multi-period credit risk model and uses Taylor expansion approximations to estimate the multi-period loss distribution. In this paper we extend the currently available second-order Taylor expansion approximations to credit risk with a third-order term and we use this new approximation to obtain the loss distribution in the multi-period framework. Our results show that the approximation is more accurate under recessions or for portfolios with high probability of default. We also show that, in general, the effect of this third-order adjustment is quite small. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garcia-Cespedes, Ruben; Moreno, Manuel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value-added role of industry specialist advisors in M&amp;As</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, Michael; Walter, Terry S.; Yawson, Alfred; Zhang, Huizhong
This paper examines the value-added role of industry specialist advisors in M&amp;As. We find that compared to non-industry specialists, advisors specializing in the target industry help acquirers garner higher announcement returns. However, there is no significant difference in acquirer returns between advisors specializing in the acquirer industry and non-industry specialists. The choice of a specialist advisor in the target industry benefits acquirers most when there is significant information asymmetry surrounding the targets. Moreover, the bulk of value creation comes from small- to medium-sized financial advisors, rather than large, top-tier investment banks. Finally, our results suggest that advisors specializing in the target industry add value mainly through their ability to help acquirers purchase targets at a lower price. (C)2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Graham, Michael; Walter, Terry S.; Yawson, Alfred; Zhang, Huizhong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign stress and SMEs' access to finance: Evidence from the ECB's SAFE survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferrando, Annalisa; Popov, Alexander; Udell, Gregory F.
We study the effect of sovereign stress on SMEs' capital structure using restricted-access data from the European Central Bank. We find that during the sovereign debt crisis, and controlling for borrowers' quality, firms in stressed countries became more likely to be denied credit, to be credit rationed, and to face higher loan rates. Less creditworthy firms were not more likely to become credit constrained, suggesting no flight to quality in lending. We also find that in order to make up for the decline in bank credit firms in stressed countries began relying considerably more on retained earnings and government subsidies. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferrando, Annalisa; Popov, Alexander; Udell, Gregory F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mapping heat in the US financial system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aikman, David; Kiley, Michael; Lee, Seung Jung; Palumbo, Michael G.; Warusawitharana, Missaka
We provide a framework for assessing the build-up of vulnerabilities to the U.S. financial system. We collect forty-six indicators of financial and balance-sheet conditions, cutting across measures of valuation pressures, nonfinancial borrowing, and financial-sector health. We place the data in economic categories, track their evolution, and develop an algorithmic approach to monitoring vulnerabilities that can complement the more judgmental approach of most official-sector organizations. Our approach picks up rising imbalances in the U.S. financial system through the mid-2000s, presaging the financial crisis. We also highlight several statistical properties of our approach: most importantly, our summary measures of system-wide vulnerabilities lead the credit-to-GDP gap (a key gauge in Basel III and related research) by a year or more. Thus, our framework may provide useful information for setting macroprudential policy tools such as the countercyclical capital buffer. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Aikman, David; Kiley, Michael; Lee, Seung Jung; Palumbo, Michael G.; Warusawitharana, Missaka</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation and the evolution of firm-level liquid assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Curtis, Chadwick C.; Garin, Julio; Mehkari, M. Saif
This paper shows that inflation has been an important determinant of firm-level liquid asset holdings. Liquid assets as a share of total assets- the cash ratio - for U.S. corporations steadily declined from the 1960s to the early 1980s, and has since steadily increased. Our empirical analysis finds that inflation is a key factor accounting for these changes. We show that these liquid asset holdings are imperfectly hedged against inflation. Hence, changes in inflation alter the real value of a firm's liquid asset portfolio causing them to readjust these balances. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Curtis, Chadwick C.; Garin, Julio; Mehkari, M. Saif</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and static hedging of American-style options under the jump to default extended CEV model (vol 37, pg 4059, 2013)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vidal Nunes, Joao Pedro; Ruas, Joao Pedro; Dias, Jose Carlos
This errata corrects an error in Ruas et al. (2013, Equation 27) and updates the numerical results contained in Ruas et al. (2013, Tables 4 and 5). The material provided here is meant to be read strictly in conjunction with Ruas et al. (2013). (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vidal Nunes, Joao Pedro; Ruas, Joao Pedro; Dias, Jose Carlos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank liquidity creation and real economic output</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Sedunov, John
We find that bank liquidity creation (LC) is statistically and economically significantly positively related to real economic output (GDP). This is robust to using instrumental variables and many robustness checks. LC also beats bank assets in "horse races." On-balance sheet LC matters more for small banks and off balance sheet LC matters more for large banks. Small bank LC generates more GDP per dollar than large bank LC, but large bank LC matters more overall because large banks provide much more LC than small banks. The LC-output relation is strongest in bank-dependent industries, consistent with the hypothesized transmission mechanism. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Sedunov, John</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reading between the ratings: Modeling residual credit risk and yield overlap</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Charles; Fuh, Cheng-Der; Kao, Chu-Lan Michael
Credit ratings group firms by risk, yet yields are shown to overlap between firms of adjacent ratings. We model this by considering the residual risk arising from differences in the parameters of each firm's value process for firms with the same rating. To do so, our framework simultaneously incorporates jump default with Markov-governed likelihoods and continuous defaults in a default-barrier framework. We provide closed-form approximations for expected default time and tail probabilities, and empirically fit the S-shaped yield curve, intra-rating spread, and inter-rating overlap. Results are robust to time period, rating system, sub-rating, and common characteristics such as liquidity. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chang, Charles; Fuh, Cheng-Der; Kao, Chu-Lan Michael</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variance risk in commodity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prokopczuk, Marcel; Symeonidis, Lazaros; Simen, Chardin Wese
We analyze the variance risk of commodity markets. We construct synthetic variance swaps and find significantly negative realized variance swap payoffs in most markets. We find evidence of commonalities among the realized payoffs of commodity variance swaps. We also document comovements between the realized payoffs of commodity, equity and bond variance swaps. Similar results hold for expected variance swap payoffs. Furthermore, we show that both realized and expected commodity variance swap payoffs are distinct from the realized and expected commodity futures returns, indicating that variance risk is unspanned by commodity futures. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Prokopczuk, Marcel; Symeonidis, Lazaros; Simen, Chardin Wese</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate uncertainty and the supply of credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Valencia, Fabian
This paper presents a model in which a bank can exhibit self-insurance with loan supply contracting when uncertainty increases. This prediction is tested with U.S. commercial banks, where identification is achieved by looking at differential effects according to banks' capital-to-assets ratio (CAR). Increases in uncertainty reduce the supply of credit, more so for banks with lower levels of CAR. These results are weaker for large banks, and are robust to controlling for monetary policy, to different measures of uncertainty, and to breaking the dataset in subsamples. Quantitatively, the effect of uncertainty shocks on credit supply is about as important as that of monetary policy shocks. (C) 2017 International Monetary Fund. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Valencia, Fabian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real options in finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, Bart M.
Although the academic literature on real options has grown enormously over the past three decades, the adoption of formal real option valuation models by practitioners appears to be lagging. Yet, survey evidence indicates that managers' decisions are near optimal and consistent with real option theory. We critically review real options research and point out its strengths and weaknesses. We discuss recent contributions published in this issue of the journal and highlight avenues for future research. We conclude that, in some ways, academic research in real options has catching up to do with current practice. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lambrecht, Bart M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate liquidity and dividend policy under uncertainty (Reprinted from Journal of Banking and Finance, vol 75, pg 200-214, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koussis, Nicos; Martzoukos, Spiros H.; Trigeorgis, Lenos
We examine optimal liquidity (retained earnings) and dividend choice incorporating debt financing with risk of default and bankruptcy costs as well as growth options under revenue uncertainty. We revisit the conditions for dividend policy irrelevancy and the broader role of retained earnings and dividends. Retained earnings have a net positive impact on firm value in the presence of growth options, high external financing costs and low default risk. High levels of retained earnings enhance debt capacity but have a negative effect on equity value due to the likelihood of losing accumulated cash balances in case of default, unless offset by high external financing costs. Opposite directional effects of retained earnings on equity and debt create a U-shaped relation with firm value. The framework is extended to analyze management-shareholder conflicts, demonstrating that managers accumulate higher than optimal cash. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Koussis, Nicos; Martzoukos, Spiros H.; Trigeorgis, Lenos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leaders, followers, and equity risk premiums in booms and busts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goto, Makoto; Nishide, Katsumasa; Takashima, Ryuta
We study an investment problem in which two asymmetric firms face competition and the regime characterizing the economic condition follows a Markov switching process. We derive the value functions and investment thresholds of the leader and follower. The option value of regime uncertainty is found to be quite important for the investment decision of firms. We also show the relationship between the equity risk premium and the economic cycle that has not been done in previous studies, which proxy economic conditions by the level of demand or other state variables. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goto, Makoto; Nishide, Katsumasa; Takashima, Ryuta</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real options with ex-post division of the surplus</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pennings, Enrico
This paper examines a real option model where two vertically related firms are involved in a specific investment project that is subject to an uncertain payoff. While ex-post bargaining between a seller and a buyer leads to underinvestment by the seller in a standard model where timing of the seller's investment is exogenous, we show that this need not be the case when the seller's timing of investment is endogenous. However, bargaining with a buyer leads to excessive waiting. More severe holdup and higher uncertainty will lead to vertical integration of activities to avoid timing inefficiencies. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pennings, Enrico</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic technology adoption and hedging under incomplete markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leippold, Markus; Stromberg, Jacob
We investigate the implications of technological innovation and non-diversifiable risk on entrepreneurial entry and optimal portfolio choice. In a real options model where two risk-averse individuals strategically decide on technology adoption, we show that the impact of non-diversifiable risk on the option timing decision is ambiguous and depends on the frequency of technological change. Compared to the complete market case, non-diversifiable risk may accelerate or delay the optimal investment decision. Moreover, strategic considerations regarding technology adoption play a central role for the entrepreneur's optimal portfolio choice in the presence of non-diversifiable risk. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leippold, Markus; Stromberg, Jacob</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The odd notion of "reversible investment"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, Graham A.; Cairns, Robert D.
Irreversible investment and the attendant concept of real-option value have been well discussed. Complete reversibility has been frequently invoked but less studied, especially for the case of lumpy investment typically considered in capital budgeting. We examine a simple lumpy investment problem for the full range, from complete irreversibility to completely reversibility, with a focus on the latter. The optimal stopping rules under complete reversibility are to invest when the project generates enough net cash flow to cover Jorgenson's opportunity cost of investment and to disinvest when it does not. Given the static nature of these rules, net present value as a timing criterion under reversibility is not pertinent. Investments that are partially reversible have much in common with completely irreversible investments but nothing in common with completely reversible investments. The case of reversible investment provides a foil for understanding that the distinguishing feature of investment as treated in corporate finance is that it entails at least some irreversibility. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Davis, Graham A.; Cairns, Robert D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reprint of: Stopping contagion with bailouts: Micro-evidence from Pennsylvania bank networks during the panic of 1884</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Haelim Park; Bluedorn, John C.
Using a newly constructed historical dataset on the Pennsylvania state banking system, detailing the amounts of "due-froms" on a debtor bank-by-debtor bank basis, we investigate the effects of the Panic of 1884 and subsequent private sector-orchestrated bailout of systemically important banks (SIBs) on the broader banking sector. We find evidence that Pennsylvania banks with larger direct interbank exposures to New York City changed the composition of their asset holdings, shifting from loans to more liquid assets and reducing their New York City correspondent deposits in the near-term. Over the long-term though, only the lower correspondent deposits effect persisted. Our findings show that the banking turmoil in New York City impacted more exposed interior banks, but that bailouts of SIBs by the New York Clearing House likely short-circuited a full-scale banking panic. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Anderson, Haelim Park; Bluedorn, John C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reprint of: Thawing frozen capital markets and backdoor bailouts: Evidence from the Fed's liquidity programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helwege, Jean; Boyson, Nicole M.; Jindra, Jan
During the subprime crisis, the Federal Reserve introduced several emergency liquidity programs as supplements to the discount window (DW): TAF, PDCF, and TSLF. Using data on loans to large commercial banks and primary dealers, we find that the programs were used by relatively few institutions and thus provided limited relief to banks that relied on short-term debt markets. Although usage increased after Lehman's bankruptcy, most commercial banks avoided the DW and TAF. We also find that the programs were more often used by failed European banks than by healthy US banks, likely because these loans are expensive relative to private market funds. Our results also show that usage of PDCF and TSLF programs, while higher, was more often used by primary dealers in weaker financial position. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Helwege, Jean; Boyson, Nicole M.; Jindra, Jan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of TARP on the propagation of real estate shocks: Evidence from geographically diversified banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jang, Karen Y.
This study examines the effect of TARP on the propagation of real estate shocks via geographically diversified banks in the U.S. I find that TARP money provided for banks exposed to distressed areas (i.e., "affected" banks) was positively associated with small business loan originations in "non-distressed" areas (i.e., counties with smaller real estate shocks), mitigating the shock transmission. In addition, the bailout funds facilitated "affected" banks' faster return to their pre-crisis level of franchise value. Overall, the marginal benefit of TARP funds seems to have been greater for "affected" TARP banks. I conclude that this policy helped "affected" banks cleanse/strengthen their balance sheets and recapitalize, which paved the way for increased lending. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jang, Karen Y.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading restrictions and firm dividends: The share lockup expiration experience in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Hongyan; Song, Zhihui; Nofsinger, John R.; Wang, Yuyue
Chinese firms experienced a substantial reduction in nontradable shares following the Split-Share Structure Reform that began in 2005. The decrease in nontradable shares, or increase in share tradability, is associated with a decline in the firms' cash dividend payouts. The positive association is attenuated in firms with fewer financial constraints, only weakly affected by firm governance, and not affected by investment opportunities or controlling shareholder type. The results highlight the fact that firms disgorge cash to compensate shareholders for trading restrictions and conclude that dividends persist when firms have easier access to external financing. These findings are robust to alternative definitions of nontradable shares, after controlling for firm fixed effects and omitted changing firm characteristics. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fang, Hongyan; Song, Zhihui; Nofsinger, John R.; Wang, Yuyue</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection, taxation and dividend policy: Long-run evidence, 1838-2012</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moortgat, Leentje; Annaert, Jan; Deloof, Marc
We investigate whether investor protection and taxation legislation affect dividend policy, using a unique sample of all Belgian firms listed on the Brussels Stock Exchange between 1838 and 2012. Investor protection was very weak in Belgium before World War 1, but gradually improved over time. Dividend taxation was introduced only in 1920. While it is generally believed that investor protection and taxation affect dividend policy, we find that dividend policy has been remarkably stable over time, even after controlling for firm characteristics. Changes in investor protection and taxation legislation seem to have had little impact on dividend policy. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moortgat, Leentje; Annaert, Jan; Deloof, Marc</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Absorptive capacity, technology spillovers, and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oh, Jong-Min
In the presence of potential technology spillovers, I demonstrate that a firm's absorptive capacity (AC), as proxied by R&amp;D investments, is crucial to benefit from spillovers. I find that higher AC firms, when exposed to large potential spillovers, exhibit stronger future real outcomes (cite-weighted patents and operating performance) and market value. Importantly, however, this value-relevant information does not appear to be immediately incorporated into stock prices, leading to high future abnormal stock returns for firms with high AC and spillover exposure. Furthermore, the undervaluation is most pronounced among low investor attention stocks, suggesting that limited attention contributes to the undervaluation. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oh, Jong-Min</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of payday lending restrictions on liquor sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cuffe, Harold E.; Gibbs, Christopher G.
We exploit a change in lending laws to estimate the causal effect of restricting access to payday loans on liquor sales. Leveraging lender- and liquor store-level data, we find that the changes reduce sales, with the largest decreases at stores located nearest to payday lenders. By focusing on states with state run liquor monopolies, we account for endogenous supply-side variables that are typically unobserved. Further analysis of consumer-level data indicates that the lending restrictions reduce alcohol expenditures without affecting total household spending. This is consistent with a distinct relationship between payday lending access and alcohol purchases, and suggests that present biased motivations underlie some loan use. The finding is significant because it shows that payday loan access is associated with unproductive borrowing, and directly links payday loan access to public health issues. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cuffe, Harold E.; Gibbs, Christopher G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-sharing, market imperfections, asset prices: Evidence from China's stock market liberalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Marc K.; Kwok, Simon
We examine the roles of risk-sharing and other factors in stock price revaluation during a recent liberalization episode in China. Consistent with the theoretical prediction that liberalizations reduce systematic risk, we find that risk-sharing explains approximately one-fourth of the price revaluation of investible stocks during the eight-month window between reform announcement and implementation. The firm specific information generated by the reform is more efficiently priced into stocks that have a higher degree of market liquidity, information transparency, and informed trading. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Marc K.; Kwok, Simon</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It's all in the name: Mutual fund name changes after SEC Rule 35d-1</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Espenlaub, Susanne; ul Haq, Imtiaz; Khurshed, Arif
We study how investors respond to 'superficial' mutual-fund name changes that occur for no fundamental reasons. We find that such name changes remain widespread even after regulation to curb potentially misleading name changes (SEC Rule 35d-1). Superficial changes are more widespread than previously studied 'misleading' changes that are not accompanied by corresponding portfolio adjustments reflecting the investment style suggested by the new name. Superficial changes appear to be driven by managerial incentives. Investors react to superficial changes with increased fund flows but appear to gain no benefit through improved performance or lower fees. On the contrary, name-change funds underperform as a group. Our findings highlight inefficiencies in the mutual-fund market and hold important implications for the stakeholders involved. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Espenlaub, Susanne; ul Haq, Imtiaz; Khurshed, Arif</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysing the determinants of insolvency risk for general insurance firms in the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caporale, Guglielmo Maria; Cerrato, Mario; Zhang, Xuan
This paper estimates a reduced-form model to assess the insolvency risk of General Insurance (GI) firms in the UK. In comparison to earlier studies, it uses a much larger sample including 30 years of data for 515 firms, and also considers a much wider set of possible determinants of insolvency risk. The empirical results suggest that macroeconomic and firm-specific factors both play important roles. Other key findings are the following: insolvency risk varies across firms depending on their business lines; there is default clustering in the GI industry; different reinsurance levels also affect the insolvency risk of insurance firms. The implications of these findings for regulators of GI firms under the newly launched Solvency II are discussed. (C) 2017 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Caporale, Guglielmo Maria; Cerrato, Mario; Zhang, Xuan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment fluctuations and the predictability of currency returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nucera, Federico
We investigate whether unemployment fluctuations generate predictability in the cross-section of currency excess returns. We find that currencies with lower growth in the unemployment rate appreciate while currencies with higher growth in the unemployment rate depreciate. As a result, an investment strategy that involves investing in the former and short selling of the latter produces positive and sizable excess returns. Asset pricing tests show that the predictability is not driven by exposure to traditional risk factors such as global equity risk, global foreign exchange volatility risk, and downside risk but is related instead to an idiosyncratic unemployment risk. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nucera, Federico</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial overconfidence over time: Foresight, hindsight, and insight of investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Merkle, Christoph
Financial overconfidence leads to increased trading activity, higher risk taking, and less diversification. In a panel survey of online brokerage clients in the UK, we ask for stock market and portfolio expectations and derive several overconfidence measures from the responses. Overconfidence is identified in the sample in various forms. By matching survey data with participants' transactions and portfolio holdings, we find an influence of overplacement on trading activity, of overprecision and overestimation on diversification, and of overprecision and overplacement on risk taking. We explore the evolution of overconfidence over time and identify a role of past success and hindsight on subsequent investor overconfidence in line with learning to be overconfident. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Merkle, Christoph</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of the crude oil futures curve: Inventory, consumption and volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nikitopoulos, Christina Sklibosios; Squires, Matthew; Thorp, Susan; Yeung, Danny
Since 2008, the WTI oil futures curve has been positively sloped for extended periods. We test whether changes in inventory alone can explain this atypically long contango. To do this, we estimate monthly VARs of the CME WTI oil futures spread and OECD and U.S. inventory in line with standard theory, and add petroleum consumption and implied volatility to the vector of endogenous variables. When we model the futures spread as one continuous series, results confirm two-way causation between inventory and the futures curve, as predicted by the theory of storage. However when we separate negative and positive futures spreads we find that: two-way causation between the futures spread and U.S. inventory breaks down; shocks to OECD petroleum consumption cause more negative spreads and shocks to U.S. consumption cause more positive spreads in addition to inventory-driven changes; and increases in volatility directly raise positive spreads. These new causal channels have become significant since 2008 and can be related to higher inventory, inelastic supply of oil and uncertainty about global economic conditions. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nikitopoulos, Christina Sklibosios; Squires, Matthew; Thorp, Susan; Yeung, Danny</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market price of risk of the variance term structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dotsis, George
In this paper I examine the market price of risk of the variance term structure. To this end, the S&amp;P 500 option implied variance term structure is used as a proxy for aggregate variance risk. Principal component analysis shows that time variation in the variance term structure over the 1996-2012 period can be explained mainly by two factors which capture changes in the level and slope. The market price of risk of each factor is estimated in the cross-section of stock returns. The slope of the variance term structure is the most significant factor in the cross-section of stocks returns and carries a negative risk premium. The slope factor has also some predictive ability over long horizon equity returns. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dotsis, George</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are correlations constant? Empirical and theoretical results on popular correlation models in finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Zeno; Fuess, Roland; Glueck, Thorsten
Multivariate GARCH models have been designed as an extension of their univariate counterparts. Such a view is appealing from a modeling perspective but imposes correlation dynamics that are similar to time varying volatility. In this paper, we argue that correlations are quite different in nature. We demonstrate that the highly unstable and erratic behavior that is typically observed for the correlation among financial assets is to a large extent a statistical artifact. We provide evidence that spurious correlation dynamics occur in response to financial events that are sufficiently large to cause a structural break in the time series of correlations. A measure for the autocovariance structure of conditional correlations allows us to formally demonstrate that the volatility and the persistence of daily correlations are not primarily driven by financial news but by the level of the underlying true correlation. Our results indicate that a rolling window sample correlation is often a better choice for empirical applications in finance. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, Zeno; Fuess, Roland; Glueck, Thorsten</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparative statics and portfolio choices under the phantom decision model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iwaki, Hideki; Osaki, Yusuke
This study characterizes attitudes toward uncertainty in the phantom decision model introduced by lzhakian and lzhakian (2015) and conducts a comparative statics analysis to examine how changes in phantom uncertainty and phantom aversion affect portfolio choices. First, "phantom averse" and "more phantom -averse" are defined in a manner that differs from lzhakian and lzhakian (2015). Assuming that utility functions have realization forms, the above notions are characterized by the shapes of their reduction components. For the portfolio choice problem that consists of one safe asset and one phantom asset, we derive sufficient conditions under which changes in phantom uncertainty and phantom aversion monotonically decrease the investment in the phantom asset. Some familiar concepts in expected utility theory are extended to the framework of the phantom decision model. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Iwaki, Hideki; Osaki, Yusuke</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of sovereign rating changes on the activity of European banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drago, Danilo; Gallo, Raffaele
We verify the effects of sovereign rating revisions on the activity of European banks, in terms of their regulatory capital ratio, profitability, liquidity, and lending supply. First, we find that a sovereign downgrade has a significant impact, primarily on capital ratios and lending supply. In contrast, upgrades do not have a significant impact, indicating an asymmetric effect of sovereign rating changes. Second, we find that three transmission channels (assets channel, funding channel, and rating channel) explain a relevant part of the impact of a sovereign downgrade. Finally, we find strong evidence that the rating-based regulation affects all measures of the activity of domestic banks, causing negative externalities for financial institutions. Our results hold also controlling for sovereign risk, estimating a GMM system, and employing an instrumental variable approach. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Drago, Danilo; Gallo, Raffaele</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Human vs. high-frequency traders, penny jumping, and tick size</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mahmoodzadeh, Soheil; Gencay, Ramazan
This paper examines changes in market quality resulting from the smaller tick size of the interbank foreign exchange market. Coupled with the lower tick size, the special composition of traders and their order placement strategies created a suitable environment for high-frequency traders (HFT's) to implement sub-penny jumping strategy to front-run human traders. We show that the spread declined following the introduction of decimal pip pricing. However, benefits of spread reduction were mostly absorbed by the HFT's. Market depths were also significantly reduced with the occupation of the top of the order book by HFT's. This new environment changed the market maker-market taker composition between different traders and altered price impacts of the order flows. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mahmoodzadeh, Soheil; Gencay, Ramazan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest margins and bank regulation in Central America and the Caribbean</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Birchwood, Anthony; Brei, Michael; Noel, Dorian M.
This paper examines empirically the determinants of bank interest margins in Central America and the Caribbean over the period 1998-2014. A particular focus is set on the impact of differences in the regulatory environment and market structure across countries in explaining the interest margins of individual banks. Our results suggest that bank market power, operating costs, credit risk, and liquid asset holdings increase the margin between loan and deposit rates, while increased income diversification and GDP growth are associated with lower loan-deposit spreads. When considering information on banking regulation, we find strong evidence to support our main hypothesis that improvements in market quality and liberalization have a significant effect on interest margins. More specifically, reductions in entry requirements to banking, higher involvement of foreign banks, and increased financial statement transparency are associated with significant reductions in interest margins. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Birchwood, Anthony; Brei, Michael; Noel, Dorian M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do bond credit ratings lead to excess comovement?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Raffestin, Louis
We investigate whether non-fundamental comovement results from investors using credit ratings to group assets into different "styles". We find that bonds that join a new rating class start comoving more with the bonds in this class, even when fundamental factors suggest otherwise. We show that this co-movement effect varies according to the nature of the bond considered, and the modalities of the rating action. Downgrades have a larger impact than upgrades, and rating reviews matter as much as actual movements. Finally, rating changes between grades BBB and BB, which lead bonds to be reclassified as either "high-yield" or "investment grade" assets, seem to be of particular importance. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Raffestin, Louis</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The case for herding is stronger than you think</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bohl, Martin T.; Branger, Nicole; Trede, Mark
In this paper, we challenge the often implemented herding measure by Chang et al. (2000). They regress the cross-sectional absolute deviation of returns on the absolute and squared excess market return. A coefficient on the squared excess market return significantly smaller than zero is interpreted as evidence for herding. However, we show that the true coefficient is positive under the null hypothesis of no herding. Hence, their test is biased against finding evidence in favour of herding. Empirical examinations for the S&amp;P 500 and the EuroStoxx 50 confirm the misleading implications of Chang, Cheng and Khorana's measure, while our modified test provides clear-cut evidence for herding behaviour. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bohl, Martin T.; Branger, Nicole; Trede, Mark</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shortability and asset pricing model: Evidence from the Hong Kong stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Min; Li, Xiao-Ming; Qin, Yafeng
This study explores how the violation of free short selling assumption affects the performance of CAPM and the Fama-French three-factor model, as existing studies show that short-sales constraints affect asset pricing of the stocks. Using data from the Hong Kong Stock Market which has unique regulations on short selling, we conduct both time-series and cross-sectional regression analyses to evaluate the performance of the two models under the short-sales-constraints and the no-constraints market environment. The two models perform much worse in the former environment than in the latter, indicating a significant impact of the short sales constraints on the explanatory power of the models. We then augment the two models with a shortability-mimicking factor. Our results show that the factor has a significant power in explaining both time-series and cross-sectional variation in the size-B/M portfolio returns. The addition of the factor to the two models considerably increases their overall performance. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bai, Min; Li, Xiao-Ming; Qin, Yafeng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do banks adjust to changing input prices? A dynamic analysis of US commercial banks before and after the crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spierdijk, Laura; Shaffer, Sherrill; Considine, Tim
The 2000-2013 period was characterized by substantial regulatory, monetary and technological change, especially after the onset of the global financial crisis. This study assesses the total impact of these policy shifts and technological changes on U.S. commercial banks' short-run and long-run substitution elasticities. An endogenous-break test divides the sample into a pre-crisis period and a (post-) crisis period. During the former period, banks' inputs tend to be inelastic substitutes. After the onset of the crisis, particularly the long-run substitutability of most input factors decreases to even lower levels due to changes in both cost technology and economic conditions. At the same time, banks' response to input price changes becomes more sluggish. Hence, especially after the onset of the crisis, banks have little flexibility regarding input factor usage and are thus sensitive to input price changes from a cost perspective. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Spierdijk, Laura; Shaffer, Sherrill; Considine, Tim</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-sample equity premium predictability and sample split-invariant inference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolev, Gueorgui I.; Karapandza, Rasa
For a comprehensive set of 21 equity premium predictors we find extreme variation in out-of-sample predictability results depending on the choice of the sample split date. To resolve this issue we propose reporting in graphical form the out-of-sample predictability criteria for every possible sample split, and two out-of-sample tests that are invariant to the sample split choice. We provide Monte Carlo evidence that our bootstrap-based inference is valid. The in-sample, and the sample split invariant out-of-sample mean and maximum tests that we propose, are in broad agreement. Finally we demonstrate how one can construct sample split invariant out-of-sample predictability tests that simultaneously control for data mining across many variables. (C) 2016 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kolev, Gueorgui I.; Karapandza, Rasa</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of the term auction facility on the London interbank offered rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McAndrews, James; Sarkar, Asani; Wang, Zhenyu
The Term Auction Facility (TAF), the first auction-based liquidity initiative by the Federal Reserve during the global financial crisis, was aimed at improving conditions in the dollar money market and bringing down the significantly elevated London interbank offered rate (Libor). The effectiveness of this innovative policy tool is crucial for understanding the role of the central bank in financial stability, but academic studies disagree on the empirical evidence of the TAF effect on Libor. We show that the disagreement arises from mis-specifications of econometric models. Regressions using the daily level of the Libor-OIS spread as the dependent variable miss either the permanent or temporary TAF effect, depending on whether the dummy variable indicates the events of the TAF or the regimes before and after an TAF event. Those regressions also suffer from the unit-root problem and produce unreliable test statistics. By contrast, regressions using the daily change in the Libor-OIS spread are robust to the persistence of the TAF effect and the unit-root problem, consistently producing reliable evidence that the downward shifts of the Libor-OIS spread were associated with the TAF. The evidence indicates the efficacy of the TAF in helping the interbank market to relieve liquidity strains. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McAndrews, James; Sarkar, Asani; Wang, Zhenyu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>House prices, consumption and the role of non-Mortgage debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kartashova, Katya; Tomlin, Ben
This paper evaluates the strength of the relationship between house prices and consumption, through the use of debt. Whereas the existing literature has largely studied the effects of house prices on homeowner total or mortgage debt, we focus on the non-mortgage component of household borrowing, using Canadian household-level data for 1999-2007. We rely on variation in regional house prices, homeownership status and age to establish the relationship between house prices and non-mortgage debt. Then, using direct information on debt uses, we determine that house price growth was associated with a non-trivial fraction of concurrent aggregate non-housing consumption growth. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kartashova, Katya; Tomlin, Ben</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does bank competition reduce cost of credit? Cross-country evidence from Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fungacova, Zuzana; Shamshur, Anastasiya; Weili, Laurent
Despite the extensive debate on the effects of bank competition on economic welfare and growth, only a handful of single-country studies deal with the impact of bank competition on the cost of credit. We contribute to the literature by investigating the impact of bank competition on the cost of credit in a cross-country setting. Using a panel of firms from 20 European countries covering the period 2001-2011, we consider a broad set of measures of bank competition, including two structural measures (Herfindahl-Hirschman index and CR5), and two non-structural indicators (Lerner index and H-statistic). We find that bank competition increases the cost of credit and observe that the positive influence of bank competition is stronger for smaller companies. Our findings accord with the information hypothesis, whereby a lack of competition incentivizes banks to invest in soft information and conversely increased competition raises the cost of credit. This positive impact of bank competition is however influenced by the institutional and economic framework, as well as by the crisis. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fungacova, Zuzana; Shamshur, Anastasiya; Weili, Laurent</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity index variance: Evidence from flexible parametric jump-diffusion models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaeck, Andreas; Rodrigues, Paulo; Seeger, Norman J.
This paper analyzes a wide range of flexible drift and diffusion specifications of stochastic-volatility jump-diffusion models for daily S&amp;P 500 index returns. We find that model performance is driven almost exclusively by the specification of the diffusion component whereas the drift specifications is of second-order importance. Further, the variance dynamics of non-affine models resemble popular non parametric high-frequency estimates of variance, and their outperformance is mainly accumulated during turbulent market regimes. Finally, we show that jump diffusion models yield more reliable estimates for the expected return of variance swap contracts. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaeck, Andreas; Rodrigues, Paulo; Seeger, Norman J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gini-type measures of risk and variability: Gini shortfall, capital allocations, and heavy-tailed risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Furman, Edward; Wang, Ruodu; Zitikis, Ricardas
We introduce and explore Gini-type measures of risk and variability, and develop the corresponding economic capital allocation rules. The new measures are coherent, additive for co-monotonic risks, convenient computationally, and require only finiteness of the mean. To elucidate our theoretical considerations, we derive closed-form expressions for several parametric families of distributions that are of interest in insurance and finance, and further apply our findings to a risk portfolio of a bancassurance company. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Furman, Edward; Wang, Ruodu; Zitikis, Ricardas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risky lending: Does bank corporate governance matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faleye, Olubunmi; Krishnan, Karthik
We study the effect of bank governance on risk-taking in commercial lending. Banks with more effective boards are less likely to lend to riskier borrowers. This effect is restricted to periods of distress in the banking industry and is stronger at banks with board-level credit committees. Banks with more effective boards are less likely to lend to riskier borrowers right after the Russian default, which exogenously imposed distress conditions on U.S. banks. Thus, value-maximizing banks appear to ration credit to riskier borrowers precisely when such firms might be credit-constrained, suggesting that bank governance regulations may have potential unintended consequences. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faleye, Olubunmi; Krishnan, Karthik</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The q-factors and expected bond returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franke, Benedikt; Mueller, Sebastian; Mueller, Sonja
This study provides new insight into the recent debate on profitability and investment patterns in the cross-section of expected returns. Relying on implied risk premia of U.S. corporate bonds, we document a strong negative relation between exposure to the profitability factor and cost of debt. We do not observe a robust relation between exposure to the investment factor and cost of debt. Our findings are consistent with profitability being a risk factor, but suggest that high profitability implies lower (and not higher) risk. Because the market portfolio consists of all risky assets including corporate bonds, our findings challenge a risk-based explanation for the profitability and investment patterns in stock returns. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Franke, Benedikt; Mueller, Sebastian; Mueller, Sonja</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government ownership and exposure to political uncertainty: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhou, Zhengyi
The government of China started its anti-corruption campaign in December 2012. Since then, more than 600 government officials have been investigated. We regard the investigations involving senior officials as signals of increased political uncertainty. Focusing on these events, we study how firms' exposure to political uncertainty varies with government ownership. It is found that the stock performance of private firms is worse on the event days than in normal times, whereas state-owned enterprises (SOEs) suffer less from the events. Moreover, the event-day effects are not quickly reversed in the post-event periods. Among SOEs, the negative impact of the events also decreases with government ownership. The evidence indicates that government ownership mitigates firms' exposure to political uncertainty. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhou, Zhengyi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do all new brooms sweep clean? Evidence for outside bank appointments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kick, Thomas; Nehring, Inge; Schertler, Andrea
Banks in bad financial shape are more likely to appoint executive directors from the outside than those in good shape. It is, however, not clear whether all of these appointments necessarily lead to the desired turnaround. We analyze the performance effects of new board members with external boardroom experience (outsiders) by distinguishing between good and bad managerial abilities of executives based on either ROA or risk-return efficiency of their previous employers. Our results show that banks appointing bad outsiders underperform other banks while those appointing good outsiders do so to a lesser extent. The performance differentials are highly pronounced in high-risk banks and in the post-crisis period. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kick, Thomas; Nehring, Inge; Schertler, Andrea</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday online investor sentiment and return patterns in the US stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Renault, Thomas
We implement a novel approach to derive investor sentiment from messages posted on social media before we explore the relation between online investor sentiment and intraday stock returns. Using an extensive dataset of messages posted on the microblogging platform StockTwits, we construct a lexicon of words used by online investors when they share opinions and ideas about the bullishness or the bearishness of the stock market. We demonstrate that a transparent and replicable approach significantly outperforms standard dictionary-based methods used in the literature while remaining competitive with more complex machine learning algorithms. Aggregating individual message sentiment at half-hour intervals, we provide empirical evidence that online investor sentiment helps forecast intraday stock index returns. After controlling for past market returns, we find that the first half-hour change in investor sentiment predicts the last half-hour S&amp;P 500 index ETF return. Examining users' self-reported investment approach, holding period and experience level, we find that the intraday sentiment effect is driven by the shift in the sentiment of novice traders. Overall, our results provide direct empirical evidence of sentiment-driven noise trading at the intraday level. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Renault, Thomas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of monetary policy on corporate bonds under regime shifts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guidolin, Massimo; Orlov, Alexei G.; Pedio, Manuela
We study the effects of a conventional monetary expansion, quantitative easing, and the maturity extension program on corporate bond yields using impulse response functions obtained from flexible models with regimes. Using a three-state Markov switching model with time-homogeneous vector autoregressive (VAR) coefficients that emerges from a systematic model specification search, we find that unconventional policies may have been generally expected to decrease both corporate yields and spreads. However, even though the sign of the responses is the one desired by policymakers, the size of the estimated effects depends on the assumptions regarding the decline in long-term Treasury yields caused by unconventional policies, on which considerable uncertainty remains. Further tests based on yield spreads and a variable that measures inflation expectations show that, in the crisis regime, unconventional monetary policies do not produce any perverse effects on expected inflation. These results prove robust to adopting a framework that allows VAR coefficients to break, to imposing coefficient restrictions that increase parsimony, and to a range of different ordering schemes that identify shocks in alternative ways. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guidolin, Massimo; Orlov, Alexei G.; Pedio, Manuela</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do foreign banks take more risk? Evidence from emerging economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Minghua; Wu, Ji; Jeon, Bang Nam; Wang, Rui
This paper addresses the impact of foreign ownership on the risk-taking behavior of banks. Using bank level panel data of more than 1300 commercial banks in 32 emerging economies during 2000-2013, we find that foreign owned banks take on more risk than their domestic counterparts. We further examine several factors that may potentially contribute to foreign banks' differentiated riskiness from four perspectives, namely, foreign banks' informational disadvantages, agency problems, the contagious effect of parent banks' financial conditions and the disparity between home and host markets. We find supportive evidence that these factors play a significant role in affecting foreign banks' risk-taking. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chen, Minghua; Wu, Ji; Jeon, Bang Nam; Wang, Rui</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An evaluation of bank measures for market risk before, during and after the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Brien, James; Szerszen, Pawel J.
We study the performance and behavior of Value at Risk measures used by a number of large U.S. banks before, during and after the financial crisis. Alternative benchmark VaR measures, including GARCH-based measures, are estimated directly from the banks' trading revenues to explain the bank VaR performance results. While overly conservative in both the pre-crisis and post-crisis periods, bank VaR exceedances were excessive and clustered in the crisis period. This contrasted with mostly unbiased benchmark HS and GARCH VaRs in the pre-crisis and post-crisis periods, and vastly superior GARCH-based VaR performance in the crisis period with lower exceedance rates and no exceedance clustering. Our results document the bank VaRs very slow adjustment to changing market conditions and their systematic bias in all studied periods. Our results indicate that bank VaRs could be improved by the use of models with time-varying volatility, and built on banks' knowledge of their current positions. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>O'Brien, James; Szerszen, Pawel J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign credit rating determinants: A comparison before and after the European debt crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reusens, Peter; Croux, Christophe
This paper compares the importance of different sovereign credit rating determinants over time, using a sample of 90 countries for the years 2002-2015. Applying the composite marginal likelihood approach, we estimate a multi-year ordered probit model for each of the three major credit rating agencies. After the start of the European debt crisis in 2009, the importance of the financial balance, the economic development and the external debt increased substantially and the effect of eurozone membership switched from positive to negative. In addition, GDP growth gained a lot of importance for highly indebted sovereigns and government debt became much more important for countries with a low GDP growth rate. These findings provide empirical evidence that the credit rating agencies changed their sovereign credit rating assessment after the start of the European debt crisis. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Reusens, Peter; Croux, Christophe</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The power of the pen reconsidered: The media, CEO human capital, and corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Baixiao; McConnell, John J.; Xu, Wei
By examining the post-retirement outside board seats held by former CEOs of S&amp;P 1500 firms, we find that CEOs' post-retirement outside board memberships are influenced by the level and the tone of media coverage given to the CEOs' firms while the CEOs were "on the job." These results provide evidence of a direct economic link between media coverage of CEOs' performance today and CEOs' future opportunity sets. These results lend support to the proposition that the media can play a role in corporate governance by influencing the value of CEOs' human capital. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Baixiao; McConnell, John J.; Xu, Wei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which market integration measure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billio, M.; Donadelli, M.; Paradiso, A.; Riedel, M.
This paper compares the dynamics of the financial integration process as described by different empirical approaches. To this end, a wide range of measures accounting for several dimensions of integration is employed. In addition, we evaluate the performance of each measure by relying on an established international finance result, i.e., increasing financial integration leads to declining international portfolio diversification benefits. Using monthly equity market data for three different country groups (i.e., developed markets, emerging markets, developed plus emerging markets) and a dynamic indicator of international portfolio diversification benefits, we find that (i) all measures give rise to a very similar long-run integration pattern; (ii) the standard correlation explains variations in diversification benefits as well or better than more sophisticated measures. These findings are robust to a battery of robustness checks. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Billio, M.; Donadelli, M.; Paradiso, A.; Riedel, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option pricing under time-varying risk-aversion with applications to risk forecasting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kiesel, Ruediger; Rahe, Florentin
We present a two-factor option-pricing model, which parsimoniously captures the difference in volatility persistences under the historical and risk-neutral probabilities. The model generates an S-shaped pricing kernel that exhibits time-varying risk aversion. We apply our model for two purposes. First, we analyze the risk preference implied by S&amp;P500 index options during 2001-2009 and find that risk-aversion level strongly increases during stressed market conditions. Second, we apply our model for Value-at-Risk (VaR) forecasts during the subprime crisis period and find that it outperforms several leading VaR models. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kiesel, Ruediger; Rahe, Florentin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust and stock price crash risk: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xiaorong; Wang, Steven Shuye; Wang, Xue
This paper examines the impact of social trust on stock price crash risk. Social trust measures the level of mutual trust among the members of a society. Using a large sample of Chinese listed firms for the 2001-2015 period, we find that firms headquartered in regions of high social trust tend to have smaller crash risks. This result is robust to a battery of sensitivity tests and is more prominent for State-Owned Enterprises (SOEs), for firms with weak monitoring, and for firms with higher risk-taking. Moreover, we observe that firms in regions of high social trust are associated with higher accounting conservatism and fewer financial restatements. Our study suggests that social trust is an important variable that is omitted in the literature investigating the predictors of stock price crashes. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Xiaorong; Wang, Steven Shuye; Wang, Xue</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political connection of financial intermediaries: Evidence from China's IPO market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Donghua; Guan, Yuyan; Zhang, Tianyu; Zhao, Gang
Using a sample of Chinese Initial Public Offerings (IPOs) from 2006 to 2011, we document that politically connected (PC) underwriters increase the likelihood of clients' IPO applications being approved by the Chinese Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC). We further show that PC underwriters charge premium underwriting fees. Consistent with the rent-seeking argument, we find that minority shareholders' interests may be impaired as indicated by post-IPO underperformance. We do not detect significant differences in the underpricing of IPO deals underwritten by PC versus non-PC investment banks. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chen, Donghua; Guan, Yuyan; Zhang, Tianyu; Zhao, Gang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The composition of CMBS risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christopoulos, Andreas D.
This paper identifies the put-option, liquidity availability proportion, and shadow liquidity risk premia embedded within commercial mortgage backed securities (CMBS) using reduced form and structural generalization models. These risk values are then interpreted as trading signals which are tested with automated trading strategies that buy undervalued and sell overvalued CMBS from November 2007 through June 2015. All three signals generate substantial positive trading profits in testing for the reduced form model but not for the structural generalization. The risk signals constructed independently of market pricing provide more profitable automated trading insights than those constructed from interactions between modeled risk measures and market spreads. In my tests of the information content of the risk signals with respect to future macroeconomic indicators, I find statistically significant evidence in keeping with recent studies. While I cannot reject CMBS efficiency, this paper's disclosure of new risk measures, the profitability of automated strategies based on those risk measures, and the statistical significance of their forward guidance capabilities, together contributes to our understanding of CMBS risk and the credit spread puzzle debate. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christopoulos, Andreas D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Central bank collateral frameworks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nyborg, Kjell G.
This paper seeks to inform about a feature of monetary policy that is largely overlooked, yet occupies a central role in modern monetary and financial systems, namely central bank collateral frameworks. Their importance can be understood by the observation that the money at the core of these systems, central bank money, is injected into the economy on terms, not defined in a market, but by the collateral frameworks and interest rate policies of central banks. Using the collateral framework of the Eurosystem as a basis of illustration and case study, the paper brings to light the functioning, reach, and impact of collateral frameworks. A theme that emerges is that collateral frameworks may have distortive effects on financial markets and the wider economy. They can, for example, bias the private provision of real liquidity and thereby also the allocation of resources in the economy as well as contribute to financial instability. Evidence is presented that the collateral framework in the euro area promotes risky and illiquid collateral and, more generally, impairs market forces and discipline. The paper also emphasizes the important role of ratings and government guarantees in the Eurosystem's collateral framework. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nyborg, Kjell G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do extreme returns matter in emerging markets? Evidence from the Chinese stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nartea, Gilbert V.; Kong, Dongmin; Wu, Ji
Recent evidence in the U.S. and Europe indicates that stocks with high maximum daily returns in the previous month, perform poorly in the current month. We investigate the presence of a similar effect in the emerging Chinese stock markets with portfolio-level analysis and firm-level Fama MacBeth cross-sectional regressions. We find evidence of a MAX effect similar to the U.S. and European markets. However, contrary to U.S. and European evidence, the MAX effect in China does not weaken much less reverse the anomalous idiosyncratic volatility (IV) effect. Both the MAX and IV effects appear to independently coexist in the Chinese stock markets. Interpreted together with the strong evidence of risk-seeking behaviour among Chinese investors, our results partially support the suggestion that the negative MAX effect is driven by investor preference for stocks with lottery-like features. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nartea, Gilbert V.; Kong, Dongmin; Wu, Ji</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stopping contagion with bailouts: Micro-evidence from Pennsylvania bank networks during the panic of 1884</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Haelim Park; Bluedorn, John C.
Using a newly constructed historical dataset on the Pennsylvania state banking system, detailing the amounts of "due-froms" on a debtor bank-by-debtor bank basis, we investigate the effects of the Panic of 1884 and subsequent private sector-orchestrated bailout of systemically important banks (SIBs) on the broader banking sector. We find evidence that Pennsylvania banks with larger direct interbank exposures to New York City changed the composition of their asset holdings, shifting from loans to more liquid assets and reducing their New York City correspondent deposits in the near-term. Over the long-term though, only the lower correspondent deposits effect persisted. Our findings show that the banking turmoil in New York City impacted more exposed interior banks, but that bailouts of SIBs by the New York Clearing House likely short-circuited a full-scale banking panic. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Anderson, Haelim Park; Bluedorn, John C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Thawing frozen capital markets and backdoor bailouts: Evidence from the Fed's liquidity programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helwege, Jean; Boyson, Nicole M.; Jindra, Jan
During the subprime crisis, the Federal Reserve introduced several emergency liquidity programs as supplements to the discount window (DW): TAF, PDCF, and TSLF. Using data on loans to large commercial banks and primary dealers, we find that the programs were used by relatively few institutions and thus provided limited relief to banks that relied on short-term debt markets. Although usage increased after Lehman's bankruptcy, most commercial banks avoided the DW and TAF. We also find that the programs were more often used by failed European banks than by healthy US banks, likely because these loans are expensive relative to private market funds. Our results also show that usage of PDCF and TSLF programs, while higher, was more often used by primary dealers in weaker financial position. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Helwege, Jean; Boyson, Nicole M.; Jindra, Jan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider trading, stock return volatility, and the option market's pricing of the information content of insider trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiang, Chin-Han; Chung, Sung Gon; Louis, Henock
We find strong evidence that net insider selling is positively associated with future stock return volatility, consistent with insider selling increasing outside investors' uncertainty. The positive effect of net insider selling is significantly stronger when the volatility is measured around the earnings announcement. Apparently, option prices do not fully reflect the information content of insider trading for future volatility. More specifically, we find no evidence that option traders adjust the implied volatility for the insider trading effect in a timely manner. Consequently, net insider selling is significantly associated with future option straddle returns and delta neutral returns. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chiang, Chin-Han; Chung, Sung Gon; Louis, Henock</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Actively managed mutual funds holding passive investments: What do ETF positions tell us about mutual fund ability?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sherrill, D. Eli; Shirley, Sara E.; Stark, Jeffrey R.
We provide the first in-depth examination of exchange-traded funds (ETFs) within actively managed mutual fund (AMMF) portfolios to better understand why AMMFs make substantial investments in passive ETFs. We examine the association between holding ETF positions and AMMF performance, as well as indirect measures of performance, including market timing, flow management, and cash holdings. We find that over one-third of AMMFs take an ETF position between 2004 and 2015. Our results indicate that AMMFs allocating large portions of their portfolio to ETFs perform worse, by between 0.41% and 1.63% annually using various performance measures. These AMMFs also exhibit worse market timing and hold more cash. In contrast, AMMFs that hold ETFs in small amounts have similar characteristics to non-user AMMFs. Therefore, the act of holding an ETF does not signal inferior ability, however, taking large ETF positions does. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sherrill, D. Eli; Shirley, Sara E.; Stark, Jeffrey R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank opacity and the efficiency of stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blau, Benjamin M.; Brough, Tyler J.; Griffith, Todd G.
Prior research argues that the process of intermediation is opaque and produces uncertainty about the riskiness of banks, which may adversely affect the efficiency of bank stock prices. Using the Hou and Moskowitz (2005) measure of price delay, which captures the inefficiency of stock prices, we test for, and find evidence supporting the idea that opacity is positively associated with price delay. Bank stocks have markedly higher delay than similar non-bank stocks. This higher level of delay is driven, in part, by market-based measures of informational opacity as well as the asset composition of the bank's balance sheet. Combined, our findings suggest that bank opacity reduces the efficiency of financial markets. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blau, Benjamin M.; Brough, Tyler J.; Griffith, Todd G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric information and the death of ABS CDOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beltran, Daniel O.; Cordell, Larry; Thomas, Charles P.
A key feature of the 2007 financial crisis is that for many securities trading had ceased; where trading did occur, market prices were well below intrinsic values, especially for ABS CDOs. One explanation is that information had been asymmetric, with sellers having better information than buyers. We first show the information advantages sellers had over buyers in both the issuance of CDOs and, through vertical integration, performance of the CDO collateral that could well have disrupted trading after the onset of the crisis. Using a "workhorse" model for pricing securities under asymmetric information and a novel dataset, we show how adverse selection could explain why the bulk of these securities either traded at significant discounts or did not trade at all. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Beltran, Daniel O.; Cordell, Larry; Thomas, Charles P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cyclicality of SME lending and government involvement in banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Behr, Patrick; Foos, Daniel; Norden, Lars
Recent regulatory efforts aim at lowering the cyclicality of bank lending because of its potentially detrimental effects on financial stability and the real economy. We investigate the cyclicality of SME lending of local banks with versus without a public mandate, controlling for location, size, loan maturity, capitalization, funding structure, liquidity, profitability, and credit demand-side factors. The public mandate is set by local governments and stipulates a sustainable provision of financial services to local customers and a deviation from strict profit maximization. We find that banks with a public mandate are 25% less cyclical than other local banks. The result is credit supply-side driven and especially strong for public mandate banks with high liquidity and stable deposit funding. Our findings have implications for the bank structure, financial stability and the finance-growth nexus in a local context. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Behr, Patrick; Foos, Daniel; Norden, Lars</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does corporate social responsibility affect mutual fund performance and flows?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>El Ghoul, Sadok; Karoui, Aymen
We use an asset-weighted composite corporate social responsibility (CSR) fund score to study the effects of CSR on fund performance and flows. Compared to low-CSR funds, high-CSR funds display poorer performance, stronger performance persistence, a weaker performance-flow relationship, and comparable persistence in flows. These findings are consistent with investors in high-CSR funds deriving utility from non-performance attributes. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>El Ghoul, Sadok; Karoui, Aymen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the effects of unconventional monetary policy and low interest rates on pension fund risk incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubaker, Sabri; Gounopoulos, Dimitrios; Nguyen, Duc Khuong; Paltalidis, Nikos
This study quantifies the effects of persistently low interest rates near to the zero lower bound and unconventional monetary policy on pension fund risk incentives in the United States. Using two structural vector autoregressive (VAR) models and a counterfactual scenario analysis, the results show that monetary policy shocks, as identified by changes in Treasury yields following changes in the central bank's target interest rates, lead to a substantial increase in pension funds' allocation to equity assets. Notably, the shift from bonds to equity securities is greater during the period where the US Federal Reserve launched unconventional monetary policy measures. Additional findings show a positive correlation between pension fund risk-taking, low interest rates and the decline in Treasury yields across both well-funded and underfunded public pension plans, which is thus consistent with a structural risk-shifting incentive. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubaker, Sabri; Gounopoulos, Dimitrios; Nguyen, Duc Khuong; Paltalidis, Nikos</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign risk and the impact of crisis: Evidence from Latin America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Batten, Jonathan A.; Gannon, Gerard L.; Thuraisamy, Kannan S.
We utilize the default by Argentina in 2001 and the Global Financial Crisis in 2008, as natural experiments, to monitor the complex interactions between sovereign bonds when subjected to endogenous and exogenous shocks. By forming pairs of Latin American sovereign bonds, bundled into similar maturity class, the analysis highlights the complex nature of risk shifting, and the temporal nature of the volatility transmission and sharing mechanisms in the lead up to, and after, a crisis period. The results show that shorter maturity groups and longer maturity groups behave in fundamentally different ways in terms of volatility transmission, while one or two leading countries act as regional benchmarks. The dynamics are consistent with temporal but segmented investor preferences, with the arrival of crisis contributing to a breakdown in the previous relationships. In addition, there is additional economic benefit from utilizing knowledge of the volatility structure underlying the historic transmission channels to improve the portfolio outcomes of market participants. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Batten, Jonathan A.; Gannon, Gerard L.; Thuraisamy, Kannan S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Federal reserve's policy, global equity markets, and the local monetary policy stance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chortareas, Georgios; Noikokyris, Emmanouil
This paper examines the extent to which local monetary policy stance determines the strength of US monetary policy international transmission to global equities. Using a sample of 35 countries, we document that US monetary policy surprises exert significant inverse effects on global equity returns. Our results suggest that countries whose policy rates are brought into line with that of the US are less sensitive to US monetary policy shocks only when they have a high and intermediate level of cross-border financial linkages, and only when they have a low and intermediate level of exchange rate volatility. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chortareas, Georgios; Noikokyris, Emmanouil</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Granularity in banking and growth: Does financial openness matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bremus, Franziska; Buch, Claudia M.
We explore the impact of large banks and of financial openness for aggregate growth. Large banks matter because of granular effects: if markets are very concentrated in terms of the size distribution of banks, idiosyncratic shocks at the bank-level do not cancel out in the aggregate but can affect macroeconomic outcomes. Financial openness may affect GDP growth in and of itself, and it may also influence concentration in banking and thus the impact of bank-specific shocks for the aggregate economy. To test these relationships, we use different measures of de jure and de facto financial openness in a panel dataset for 79 countries and the years 1996-2009. Our research has three main findings: First, bank -level shocks significantly impact upon GDP. Second, financial openness tends to lower GDP growth. Third, granular effects tend to be stronger in financially closed economies. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bremus, Franziska; Buch, Claudia M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Central banks and macroeconomic policy choices: Relaxing the trilemma</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Steiner, Andreas
Macroeconomic policy choices in open economies are constrained by the trilemma according to which the objectives of exchange rate stability, monetary independence and capital mobility cannot be attained jointly. This paper shows that foreign exchange interventions provide an effective instrument to relax the trilemma. An active reserve policy allows central banks to pursue independent monetary and exchange rate policies when the capital account is liberalised. We use the framework of the portfolio balance model to show that exchange market interventions may substitute for capital controls. Both allow a country to achieve the other two objectives of the trilemma. Our empirical analysis of a large country panel data set covering the period 1970-2010 confirms this theoretical insight: the weighted sum of the three trilemma objectives increases in the degree of foreign exchange market intervention. The capacity to relax the trilemma constraint has increased over time and has been most effective in emerging markets. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Steiner, Andreas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms engage in selective hedging? Evidence from the gold mining industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adam, Tim R.; Fernando, Chitru S.; Salas, Jesus M.
The widespread practice of managers speculating by incorporating their market views into firms' hedging programs ("selective hedging") remains a puzzle. Using a 10-year sample of North American gold mining firms, we find no evidence that selective hedging is more prevalent among firms that are believed to possess an information advantage. In contrast, we find strong evidence that selective hedging is more prevalent among financially constrained firms, suggesting that this practice is driven by asset substitution motives. We detect weak relationships between selective hedging and some corporate governance measures but find no evidence of a link between selective hedging and managerial compensation. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adam, Tim R.; Fernando, Chitru S.; Salas, Jesus M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A two-factor cointegrated commodity price model with an application to spread option pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farkas, Walter; Gourier, Elise; Huitema, Robert; Necula, Ciprian
In this paper, we propose an easy-to-use yet comprehensive model for a system of cointegrated commodity prices. While retaining the exponential affine structure of previous approaches, our model allows for an arbitrary number of cointegration relationships. We show that the cointegration component allows capturing well-known features of commodity prices, i.e., upward sloping (contango) and downward sloping (backwardation) term-structures, smaller volatilities for longer maturities and an upward sloping correlation term structure. The model is calibrated to futures price data of ten commodities. The results provide compelling evidence of cointegration in the data. Implications for the prices of futures and options written on common commodity spreads (e.g., spark spread and crack spread) are thoroughly investigated. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Farkas, Walter; Gourier, Elise; Huitema, Robert; Necula, Ciprian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial contagion risk and the stochastic discount factor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piccotti, Louis R.
I provide evidence that financial contagion risk is an important source of the equity risk premium. Banks' contributions to aggregate financial contagion are estimated in a state space framework and linked to systemic risk. Greater bank connectedness today leads to increased systemic risk 3-12 months later. More contagious banks earn significantly greater risk-adjusted returns than less contagious ones and the tradable high contagion-minus-low contagion bank portfolio is priced in the cross-section of stock returns. Stocks that co -move more strongly with contagious banks have greater expected returns. These results are robust to factor model specification, test assets, and time period considered. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Piccotti, Louis R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stockpiling cash when it takes time to build: Exploring price differentials in a commodity boom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hansen, Erwin; Wagner, Rodrigo
Some projects take time to build or are slow to yield cash flows. This may impact the dynamics of investment and liquidity management, although few studies test their financial implications. We exploit the peculiar advantages of copper mines as a laboratory to identify cash-flow sensitivities. In this context, investment decisions depend on the expectations of the long run price of the commodity, while the spread between the spot price and this long run expectations shifts current cash-flows. For this study we compiled a sample of copper firms between 2002 and 2012. We do not find significant effects of cash flow on current capital expenditures, but we do observe a systematic cash flow sensitivity of cash holdings, meaning that some of these transitory earnings are retained as liquidity. This cash stockpiling is stronger among financially constrained firms. In a context of time-to-build, our findings support financial theories emphasizing the salience of cash as buffer stock for liquidity in preparation for future investment opportunities. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hansen, Erwin; Wagner, Rodrigo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Life-cycle effects in small business finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ylhainen, Ilkka
This paper studies the life-cycle profiles of small firms' cost and use of credit using a panel of Finnish firms. The choice of method matters for the conclusions drawn about the relationship between firm age and financing costs; the cross-sectional age profiles of financing costs are hump-shaped and consistent with hold-up theories, whereas methods that control for cohort fixed effects demonstrate that the financing costs decrease monotonically as the firms mature. The life-cycle profiles of the use of credit also indicate that firms are more dependent on financial intermediaries in the early periods of their lives. Furthermore, the cohorts born during recessions pay higher financing costs and use smaller amounts of bank loans, even after their creditworthiness is controlled for. The recession cohort effect appears to be more related to the experience of starting-up the firm in the recession than to the CEOs growing up in a recession during their early adulthood. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ylhainen, Ilkka</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate earnings and stock market returns: The good, the bad, and the state-dependent</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zolotoy, Leon; Frederickson, James R.; Lyon, John D.
Prior research documents a negative aggregate earnings -returns relation. In contrast, we posit that the sign of the relation varies, depending upon the macroeconomic and financial market conditions that exist in the earnings announcement quarter. We argue that the existing macroeconomic and financial market conditions influence market participants' frame of reference, which in turn affects whether they interpret aggregate earnings surprises to be informative about the expected inflation component of the discount rate, the market risk premium component of the discount rate, or aggregate future cash flows. Consistent with this, we find that the sign of the aggregate earnings-returns relation changes numerous times across our sample period. We also find that market participants interpret aggregate earnings to be informative about changes in expected inflation (market risk premium) when the sign of the aggregate earnings returns relation is negative (positive). Finally, we identify macroeconomic and financial market conditions under which the aggregate earnings-returns relation is more (less) likely to be negative (positive). (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zolotoy, Leon; Frederickson, James R.; Lyon, John D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of governance on bank liquidity creation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diaz, Violeta; Huang, Ying
This paper examines the impact of internal bank governance on bank liquidity creation in the U.S. before, during and after the 2007-2009 financial crisis. Using bank holding company level data, we analyze whether better-governed banks create higher levels of liquidity. We find that this effect is positive and significant but only for large bank holding companies. Further analysis reveals that specific internal governance categories: CEO education, compensation structure, progressive practices, and ownership have a significant effect on bank liquidity. However, this positive effect occurs mostly during the crisis period, and for large banks that are also high liquidity creators. Finally, we find that the effect of governance on liquidity creation increases during the crisis period. These findings are robust even while controlling for liquidity measures, bank size, and endogeneity problems between governance and liquidity creation. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Diaz, Violeta; Huang, Ying</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The structure of the global reinsurance market: An analysis of efficiency, scale, and scope</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biener, Christian; Eling, Martin; Jia, Ruo
We estimate economies of scale and scope as well as cost and revenue efficiency to explain the structure of the global reinsurance market, where large reinsurers dominate but both diversified and specialized reinsurers are competitive. The costs and benefits of size and product diversification are particularly relevant to the reinsurance industry, as risk diversification is central to the industry's business model. We find that reinsurers with total assets less than USD 2.9 billion exhibit scale economies, while those with total assets greater than USD 15.5 billion do not. Large reinsurers are characterized by high cost efficiency, while small reinsurers exhibit superior efficiency only when specialized. Large reinsurers also exhibit revenue scope economies when operating both life and nonlife reinsurance. Moreover, the evidence is in line with the efficient structure hypothesis: cost-efficient reinsurers can charge lower prices without sacrificing profitability. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Biener, Christian; Eling, Martin; Jia, Ruo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance volatility, information availability, and disclosure reforms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fu, Renhui; Gao, Fang; Kim, Yong H.; Qiu, Buhui
Using the 2002 Sarbanes-Oxley reform as an exogenous disclosure shock, we find that high, relative to low, volatility firms opt for lower levels of information availability pre reform and experience increases in information availability, CEO turnover-to-performance sensitivity, myopic behavior, CEO compensation with a structure tilted towards more cash pay, and a reduction in firm value post the reform. Our findings suggest that mandating high levels of information availability across the board increases managerial evaluation risk and produces additional agency costs for firms with volatile performance. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fu, Renhui; Gao, Fang; Kim, Yong H.; Qiu, Buhui</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Liquidity Coverage Ratio and security prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuhrer, Lucas Marc; Mueller, Benjamin; Steiner, Luzian
What is the added value of a security which qualifies as a "high-quality liquid asset" (HQLA) under the Basel III "Liquidity Coverage Ratio" (LCR)? In this paper, we quantify the added value in terms of yield changes and, as suggested by Stein (2013), call it "HQLA premium". To do so, we exploit the introduction of the LCR in Switzerland as a unique quasi-natural experiment and we find evidence for the existence of an HQLA premium in the order of 4 basis points. Guided by theoretical considerations, we claim that the HQLA premium is state dependent and argue that our estimate is a lower bound measure. Furthermore, we discuss the implications of an economically significant HQLA premium. Thereby, we contribute to a better understanding of the LCR and its implications for financial markets. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fuhrer, Lucas Marc; Mueller, Benjamin; Steiner, Luzian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition in the credit rating Industry: Benefits for investors and issuers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morkoetter, Stefan; Stebler, Roman; Westerfeld, Simone
We empirically investigate the benefits of multiple ratings not only at issuance of debt instruments but also during the subsequent monitoring phase. Using a record of monthly credit rating migration data on all U.S. residential mortgage-backed securities rated by Standard &amp; Poor's, Moody's, and Fitch between 1985 and 2012 (154,600 tranches), our results provide empirical evidence that rating agencies put more effort in rating and outlook revisions when tranches have assigned multiple ratings. Furthermore, we see that in the case of multiple ratings, agencies do a better job in discriminating tranches with respect to default risk. On the downside, we observe a shift in collateral towards senior tranches and incentives for issuers to engage in rating shopping activities, but find no evidence that rating agencies exploit such behavior to attract more rating business. Our results contribute to the literature on information production of credit ratings and extend the perspective to the monitoring period after issuance. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Morkoetter, Stefan; Stebler, Roman; Westerfeld, Simone</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The asymmetric effect of international swap lines on banks in emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andries, Alin Marius; Fischer, Andreas M.; Yesin, Pinar
This paper investigates the effect of international swap lines on stock returns using data from banks in emerging markets. The analysis first shows that swap lines by the Swiss National Bank (SNB) had a positive impact on bank stocks in Central and Eastern Europe. It then highlights the importance of individual bank characteristics in identifying the asymmetric effect of swap lines on bank stocks. Bank level evidence suggests that stock prices of local and less-well capitalized banks as well as banks with high foreign currency exposures and high reliance on short-term funding responded more strongly to SNB swap lines. This new evidence is.consistent with the view that swap lines not only enhanced market liquidity but also reduced risks associated with micro-prudential issues. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andries, Alin Marius; Fischer, Andreas M.; Yesin, Pinar</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate liquidity and dividend policy under uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koussis, Nicos; Martzoukos, Spiros H.; Trigeorgis, Lenos
We examine optimal liquidity (retained earnings) and dividend choice incorporating debt financing with risk of default and bankruptcy costs as well as growth options under revenue uncertainty. We revisit the conditions for dividend policy irrelevancy and the broader role of retained earnings and dividends. Retained earnings have a net positive impact on firm value in the presence of growth options, high external financing costs and low default risk. High levels of retained earnings enhance debt capacity but have a negative effect on equity value due to the likelihood of losing accumulated cash balances in case of default, unless offset by high external financing costs. Opposite directional effects of retained earnings on equity and debt create a U-shaped relation with firm value. The framework is extended to analyze management-shareholder conflicts, demonstrating that managers accumulate higher than optimal cash. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koussis, Nicos; Martzoukos, Spiros H.; Trigeorgis, Lenos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Semi-analytical valuation for discrete barrier options under time-dependent Levy processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lian, Guanghua; Zhu, Song-Ping; Elliott, Robert J.; Cui, Zhenyu
Simple analytical solutions for the prices of discretely monitored barrier options do not yet exist in the literature. This paper presents a semi-analytical and fully explicit solution for pricing discretely monitored barrier options when the underlying asset is driven by a general Levy process. The explicit formula only involves elementary functions, and the Greeks are also explicitly available with little additional computation. By performing a 2-transform, we reduce the valuation problem to an integral equation. This equation is solved analytically with the solution expressed in terms of a Fourier cosine series. We then manage to analytically carry out the 2-transform inversion, and obtain a semi-analytical formula for pricing discrete barrier options. We establish the theoretical error bound and analyze the convergence order of our method. Numerical implementation demonstrates that our numerical results are accurate and efficient, and match up with the results from the benchmark methods in the literature. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lian, Guanghua; Zhu, Song-Ping; Elliott, Robert J.; Cui, Zhenyu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank capital in the crisis: It's not just how much you have but who provides it</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garel, Alexandre; Petit-Romec, Arthur
Bank capital is the cornerstone of bank regulation and is considered a key determinant of a bank's ability to withstand economic shocks. In the area of bank capital regulation, the general view is that more bank capital is better, irrespective of who provides it. In this paper, we investigate whether the investment horizon of bank capital providers matters for bank performance during the recent financial crisis. We observe that banks with more short-term investor ownership have worse stock returns during the crisis. Further exploration suggests that this is partially because banks with higher short-term investor ownership took more risk prior to the crisis but mainly because they experienced higher selling pressure during the crisis. Our results confirm the economic benefit of bank capital in helping banks to perform better during crises. However, when we decompose bank capital by the nature of its providers, we show that more capital is associated with worse performance when it is provided by short-term institutional investors. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garel, Alexandre; Petit-Romec, Arthur</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic volatility: An indicator of noise trading?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aabo, Tom; Pantzalis, Christos; Park, Jung Chul
We investigate the market efficiency implications of firm-specific return variation measured by absolute idiosyncratic volatility. We find that the absolute idiosyncratic volatility (the variance of the residual from an asset-pricing model) displays a positive and robust relationship to mispricing, which reflects an increasing role of noise traders. Previous literature has produced similar - or opposing - results. We deepen our understanding of the previous conflicting results by showing that (1) market volatility by itself is associated with mispricing, (2) absolute idiosyncratic volatility is associated with mispricing even when controlling for market volatility, (3) the strength of the association between absolute idiosyncratic volatility and mispricing depends on the level of market volatility, and (4) absolute and relative measures of idiosyncratic volatility have opposing associations with mispricing. Our findings contribute to the existing literature by reconciling the mixed results for the relationship between idiosyncratic volatility and mispricing displayed in the previous literature. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aabo, Tom; Pantzalis, Christos; Park, Jung Chul</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information in CDS spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Norden, Lars
We investigate how public and private information affects corporate CDS spreads prior to rating announcements. First, CDS spreads of firms with high news intensity change significantly earlier and more strongly prior to negative rating announcements than those of firms with low news intensity. Second, the contents of daily corporate news significantly influence the direction in which the CDS spreads move. Third, CDS spreads change more strongly for firms with more bank relationships and days with no news but large abnormal CDS spread changes are more frequent prior to negative rating announcements than prior to positive ones. The study provides new evidence on the informational efficiency of the CDS market, the impact of credit rating announcements, and insider trading. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Norden, Lars</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>1-share orders and trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, Ryan L.; Roseman, Brian S.; Van Ness, Bonnie F.; Van Ness, Robert
1-share trades are the most common odd lot trade size, accounting for 9.62% of all odd lot transactions and 3.65% of all trades on NASDAQ in 2012. While 50.41% of 1-share trades result from broken orders, 34.89% of 1-share trades are intentional. We provide substantial evidence that traders use 1-share trades to "ping" for hidden liquidity. In particular, our results indicate that 1-share trades are disproportionately aggressive and also execute against hidden liquidity more than any other odd lot trade size. We also find a relative increase in trading immediately following a 1-share trade. Our results are in line with Clark-Joseph (2014), who suggests that traders may use small, unprofitable trades to detect information from other traders. Specifically, 1-share trades represent the minimum cash outlay necessary to trade, while simultaneously producing the smallest possible effects on a market maker's inventory, and in turn, a security's price. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Davis, Ryan L.; Roseman, Brian S.; Van Ness, Bonnie F.; Van Ness, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Slow diffusion of information and price momentum in stocks: Evidence from options markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhuo; Lu, Andrea
This paper investigates the source of price momentum in the stock market using information from options markets. We provide direct evidence of the gradual information diffusion model in Hong and Stein (1999): momentum profits are larger for stocks whose information diffuses slowly into the stock market. We exploit the options markets to identify stocks with slow information diffusion speed. As informed traders trade options to realize the information that has not been fully incorporated in the stock price, we are able to enhance the momentum strategy by selecting winner/loser stocks with high growth/large drop in call option implied volatility. Our empirical strategy generates a risk-adjusted alpha of 1.8% per month over the 1996-2011 period, during which the simple momentum strategy fails to perform. The results are robust to the impact of earnings announcement, transaction costs, industry concentration, and choice of options' moneyness and time-to-maturity. Finally, our finding is not driven by existing stock- or option-related characteristics that are known to improve momentum. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Zhuo; Lu, Andrea</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge fund politics and portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeVault, Luke; Sias, Richard
Consistent with the well-documented relation between political orientation and psychological traits, hedge funds' political orientations are related to their portfolio decisions. Relative to politically conservative hedge funds, politically liberal hedge funds exhibit a preference for smaller stocks, less mature companies, volatile stocks, unprofitable companies, non-dividend paying companies, and lottery-type securities. Politically liberal hedge funds are also more likely to enter new positions or fully exit existing positions, and make larger adjustments to their U.S. equity market exposure. Our results suggest that psychological characteristics can influence the portfolio decisions of even those at the very top of the financial sophistication ladder. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeVault, Luke; Sias, Richard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Index portfolio and welfare analysis under heterogeneous beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Xue-Zhong; Shi, Lei
With a growing popularity of index funds, we adopt a differences-in-opinion, general equilibrium framework to examine theoretically whether investors are better off with an index portfolio than active investing. In contrary to the conventional view, we find that, even for an active investor with the most accurate belief, switching to an index portfolio can significantly improve his expected ex-post welfare when the active investors have incorrect beliefs or face incomplete information. Moreover, the welfare improvement becomes more substantial when the active investors are more risk averse. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Xue-Zhong; Shi, Lei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Looking behind mortgage delinquencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mocetti, Sauro; Viviano, Eliana
Delinquency rates for mortgages originated before and after the financial crisis are examined using a novel and large panel obtained by merging data from tax records and credit registers. First, we estimate the selection into the mortgage market using an exogenous index of local credit supply as exclusion restriction. Second, controlling for selection we estimate the impact of income shocks on the delinquency rate. We find that since 2008 the selection process has led to the halving of the delinquency rate. Conditional on the creation of a new mortgage, job losses nearly double the delinquency risk; estimates uncorrected for selection are severely downward biased. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mocetti, Sauro; Viviano, Eliana</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The joint cross-sectional variation of equity returns and volatilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gonzalez-Urteaga, Ana; Rubio, Gonzalo
This paper analyzes the determinants of the simultaneous cross-sectional variation of return and volatility risk premia. Independently of the model specification employed, the estimated risk premium associated with the default premium beta is always positive and statistically different from zero. Moreover, the risk premium of the market volatility risk premium beta is negative and statistically significant. However, both risk factors are priced economically and statistically differently in the volatility and return segments of the market. On average, common factors in both segments explain 90% of the variability of volatility risk premium portfolios, but only 65% of the variability of equity return portfolios. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gonzalez-Urteaga, Ana; Rubio, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discrete-time option pricing with stochastic liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leippold, Markus; Scharer, Steven
Classical option pricing theories are usually built on the law of one price, neglecting the impact of market liquidity that may contribute to significant bid-ask spreads. Within the framework of conic finance, we develop a stochastic liquidity model, extending the discrete-time constant liquidity model of Madan (2010). With this extension, we can replicate the term and skew structures of bid-ask spreads typically observed in option markets. We show how to implement such a stochastic liquidity model within our framework using multidimensional binomial trees and we calibrate it to call and put options on the S&amp;P 500. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leippold, Markus; Scharer, Steven</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank productivity growth and convergence in the European Union during the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degl'Innocenti, Marta; Kourtzidis, Stavros A.; Sevic, Zeljko; Tzeremes, Nickolaos G.
This paper examines the bank productivity growth and integration process for the 28 EU countries during three main phases of the financial crisis: the U.S. subprime crisis (2007-2008), the global financial crisis (2009-2010) and the sovereign debt crisis (2010-2012). We extend the Malmquist Productivity Index by applying an additive two-stage DEA model. This allows us to explore the sources of growth in different stages of production. Furthermore, we assess the integration of European banks by analyzing the beta-convergence and sigma-convergence of the two-stage Productivity Index. Our results show a productivity growth during the U.S. subprime crisis, but a consistent decline during the global financial crisis. The loss of competitiveness of the European banking system is due to the drop in growth of the performance stage and technical change. Finally, we find a strong convergence pattern during the financial crisis, mainly driven by the catch up process of some Eastern countries and the drop in performance of Western countries. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Degl'Innocenti, Marta; Kourtzidis, Stavros A.; Sevic, Zeljko; Tzeremes, Nickolaos G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling systemic risk and dependence structure between oil and stock markets using a variational mode decomposition-based copula method</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mensi, Walid; Hammoudeh, Shawkat; Shahzad, Syed Jawad Hussain; Shahbaz, Muhammad
This study combines the variational mode decomposition (VMD) method and static and time-varying symmetric and asymmetric copula functions to examine the dependence structure between crude oil prices and major regional developed stock markets (S&amp;P500, stoxx600, DWI and TSX indexes) during bear, normal and bull markets under different investment horizons. Furthermore, it analyzes the upside and downside short-and long-run risk spillovers between oil and stock markets by quantifying three market risk measures, namely the value at risk (VaR), conditional VaR (CoVaR) and the delta CoVaR (6.CoVaR). The results show that there is a tail dependence between oil and all stock markets for the raw return series. By considering time horizons, we show that there is an average dependence between the considered markets for the short-run horizons. However, the tail dependence is also found for the long-run horizons between the oil and stock markets, with the exception of the S&amp;P500 index which exhibits average dependence with the oil market. Moreover, we find strong evidence of up and down risk asymmetric spillovers from oil to stock markets and vice versa in the short-and long run horizons. Finally, the market risk spillovers are asymmetric over the time and investment horizons. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mensi, Walid; Hammoudeh, Shawkat; Shahzad, Syed Jawad Hussain; Shahbaz, Muhammad</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate social responsibility and CEO confidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McCarthy, Scott; Oliver, Barry; Song, Sizhe
This study examines the relationship between firm corporate social responsibility (CSR) and CEO confidence. Research shows that CSR has a hedging feature. Research also shows that more confident CEOs underestimate firm risks, which, in turn, leads them to undertake relatively less hedging. Consistent with this, we find that CEO confidence is negatively related to the level of CSR. Closer analysis shows that this effect is stronger in the institutional aspects of CSR, such as community and workforce diversity, rather than in the technical aspects of CSR, such as corporate governance and product quality. Our results are robust to different competing explanations, including narcissism, which refers in this context to CEOs who engage in CSR to attract attention and alternative proxies for CSR and CEO confidence. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McCarthy, Scott; Oliver, Barry; Song, Sizhe</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special purpose entities and bank loan contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Jeong-Bon; Song, Byron Y.; Wang, Zheng
In this study, we show that a firm's use of special purpose entities (SPEs) is associated with unfavorable loan contract terms, including higher loan rates, collateral requirements, and restrictive covenants. Further analyses suggest that the association between the use of SPEs and unfavorable loan contract terms is primarily due to the increase in the information risk faced by lenders, as firm managers can easily use SPEs to manipulate earnings and hide losses. Specifically, we find that the use of SPEs has a more pronounced effect on increasing the cost of loans and causing more stringent non-price loan terms when managers have a stronger incentive to manipulate earnings and when banks have less knowledge about the SPE sponsor firms due to the lack of prior lending relationship. In addition, we find that the use of SPEs is associated with a greater likelihood of accounting restatements and greater information asymmetry between inside managers and outside capital suppliers. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Jeong-Bon; Song, Byron Y.; Wang, Zheng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Delaware CEOs get fired?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, Murali; Pritchard, A. C.
Critics have charged that state competition in corporate law, which Delaware dominates, leads to a "race to the bottom" making management unaccountable. We argue that Delaware corporate law attracts firms with particular financial and governance characteristics. We find that Delaware attracts growth firms in industries with more takeover activity. Delaware firms have smaller boards, and their directors are paid more and serve on more boards. In addition, Delaware firms attract greater institutional ownership. We also provide a bottom-line test of the race-to-the-bottom hypothesis by examining forced CEO turnover. After controlling for differences in firm characteristics, we find that firms incorporated in Delaware are more likely to terminate CEOs. We also find that that termination decision is less sensitive to poor performance. Overall, we see no clear pattern supporting the "race to the bottom" hypothesis. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jagannathan, Murali; Pritchard, A. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information environment and earnings management of dual class firms around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Ting; Zaiats, Nataliya
This study examines the information environment and earnings management of dual class firms. Motivated by the pronounced entrenchment phenomenon at dual class firms due to divergence between voting and cash flow rights, we are interested in whether dual class firms adopt corporate disclosure choices that imply greater opacity as well as employ judgment in financing reporting to misguide the outside shareholders about the firm's true performance. Based on a sample of 12,672 firms from 19 countries during 1994-2010, we find that dual class status is associated with poorer information environment and increased accrual-based earnings management, consistent with the notion that managers of dual class firms exhibit incentives to conceal private control benefits from the outside shareholders. Results further suggest that dual class ownership structure weakens the mitigating impact of investor protection on earnings management. Following unification, firms experience an improvement in information environment and a decrease in earnings manipulation. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Ting; Zaiats, Nataliya</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When time is not on our side: The costs of regulatory forbearance in the closure of insolvent banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cole, Rebel A.; White, Lawrence J.
In this paper, we empirically estimate the costs of delay in the FDIC's closures of 433 commercial banks between 2007 and 2014 based upon a counterfactual closure regime. We find that the costs of delay could have been as high as $18.5 billion, or 37% of the FDIC's estimated costs of closure of $49.8 billion. We think that these findings call for a more aggressive stance by bank regulators with respect to the provisions for loan losses and write-downs of banks' non-performing assets. More aggressive (and earlier) provisions and write-downs, or adoption of a capital ratio that penalizes nonperforming loans, would allow the concept of "prompt corrective action" (PCA) to play the role that it was meant to play in reducing FDIC losses from insolvent banks. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cole, Rebel A.; White, Lawrence J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of business diversification on asset risk-taking: Evidence from the US property-liability insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Che, Xin; Liebenberg, Andre P.
We investigate the effect of line-of-business diversification on asset risk-taking in the U.S. property liability industry. The coordinated risk management hypothesis (Schrand and Unal, 1998) implies a negative relation between underwriting risk and investment risk. Consistent with this hypothesis we find that diversified insurers take more asset risk than non-diversified insurers, and that the degree of asset risk-taking is positively related to diversification extent. Our results are robust to corrections for potential endogeneity bias, selectivity bias, and alternative diversification and asset risk measures. We also provide event study evidence that further supports the coordinated risk management hypothesis. Specifically, we find that when a focused firm diversifies, it increases its asset risk relative to firms that remain focused, and when a diversified firm refocuses, it reduces its asset risk relative to firms that remain diversified. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Che, Xin; Liebenberg, Andre P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of bank capital on lending: Does liquidity matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Dohan; Sohn, Wook
This paper uses a sample of quarterly observations of insured US commercial banks to examine whether the effect of bank capital on lending differs depending upon the level of bank liquidity. We find that the effect of an increase in bank capital on credit growth, defined as growth rate of net loans and unused commitments, is positively associated with the level of bank liquidity only for large banks and that this positive relationship has been more substantial during the recent financial crisis period. This result suggests that bank capital exerts a significantly positive effect on lending only after large banks retain sufficient liquid assets. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Dohan; Sohn, Wook</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Don't lapse into temptation: a behavioral explanation for policy surrender</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nolte, Sven; Schneider, Judith C.
Many policyholders surrender their life insurance policies early, leading to substantial monetary losses for private households. Surrender can be explained rationally if it constitutes the last resort providing liquidity in the event of an urgent need of cash. Yet we find clear evidence in German panel data that for more than half of all surrendered contracts investors had cheaper options available to provide the required liquidity. This finding demonstrates that there must be other factors influencing this important life decision. We provide a behavioral explanation, focusing on the role of individual decision heuristics, financial literacy, and financial advice. In particular, we show that financial literacy and financial advice can mitigate the behavioral temptation to lapse, while the tendency to rely on heuristics increases lapse probability. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nolte, Sven; Schneider, Judith C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are all odd-lots the same? Odd-lot transactions by order submission and trader type</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Hardy; Van Ness, Bonnie F.; Van Ness, Robert A.
We study odd-lot trading and determine if an odd-lot trade results from odd-lot orders or if odd-lots are a result of orders broken into multiple trades. We confirm that odd-lot transactions contribute to price discovery. Our finding that odd-lot transactions contain substantial information is not being driven by orders that are originally larger than 100 shares and subsequently divided into odd-lot transactions. We further find that odd-lot transactions resulting from odd-lot orders add more to price discovery than odd-lot transactions resulting from orders for 100 or more shares. Additionally, we find that more price contribution occurs when non-high frequency traders trade in an odd-lot transaction. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Johnson, Hardy; Van Ness, Bonnie F.; Van Ness, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum spillover from stocks to corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haesen, Daniel; Houweling, Patrick; van Zundert, Jeroen
We investigate and improve momentum spillover from stocks to corporate bonds, i.e. the phenomenon that past winners in the equity market are future winners in the corporate bond market. We find that a momentum spillover strategy exhibits strong structural and time-varying default risk exposures that cause a drag on the profitability of the strategy and lead to large drawdowns if the market cycle turns from a bear to a bull market. By ranking companies on their firm-specific equity return, instead of their total equity return, the default risk exposures halve, the Sharpe ratio doubles and the drawdowns are substantially reduced. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Haesen, Daniel; Houweling, Patrick; van Zundert, Jeroen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The stability of short-term interest rates pass-through in the euro area during the financial market and sovereign debt crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avouyi-Dovi, S.; Horny, G.; Sevestre, P.
We analyse the dynamics of the pass-through of banks' marginal cost to bank lending rates over the 2008 crisis and the euro area sovereign debt crisis in France, Germany, Greece, Italy, Portugal and Spain. We measure banks' marginal cost by their rate on new deposits, contrary to the literature that focuses on money market rates. This allows us to account for banks' risks. We focus on the interest rate on new short-term loans granted to non-financial corporations in these countries. Our analysis is based on an error-correction approach that we extend to handle the time-varying long-run relationship between banks' lending rates and, banks' marginal cost, as well as stochastic volatility. Our application is based on a harmonised monthly database from January 2003 to October 2014. We estimate the model within a Bayesian framework, using Markov Chain Monte Carlo methods (MCMC). We reject the view that the transmission mechanism is permanent over time. The long-run relationship moved with the sovereign debt crises to a new one, with a slower pass-through and higher bank lending rates. Its developments are heterogeneous from one country to the other. Impediments to the transmission of monetary rates depend on the heterogeneity in banks marginal costs and therefore, its risks. We also find that rates to small firms increase compared to large firms in a few countries. Using a VAR model, we show that overall, the effect of a shock on the rate of new deposits on the unexpected variances of new loans has been less important since 2010. These results confirm the slowdown in the transmission mechanism. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avouyi-Dovi, S.; Horny, G.; Sevestre, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic portfolio optimization with ambiguity aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Jinqing; Jin, Zeyu; An, Yunbi
This paper investigates portfolio selection in the presence of transaction costs and ambiguity about return predictability. By distinguishing between ambiguity aversion to returns and to return predictors, we derive the optimal dynamic trading rule in closed form within the framework of Garleanu and Pedersen (2013), using the robust optimization method. We characterize its properties and the unique mechanism through which ambiguity aversion impacts the optimal robust strategy. In addition to the two trading principles documented in Garleanu and Pedersen (2013), our model further implies that the robust strategy aims to reduce the expected loss arising from estimation errors. Ambiguity-averse investors trade toward an aim portfolio that gives less weight to highly volatile return-predicting factors, and loads less on the securities that have large and costly positions in the existing portfolio. Using data on various commodity futures, we show that the robust strategy outperforms the corresponding non-robust strategy in out-of-sample tests. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhang, Jinqing; Jin, Zeyu; An, Yunbi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do local banking market structures matter for SME financing and performance? New evidence from an emerging economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, Iftekhar; Jackowicz, Krzysztof; Kowalewski, Oskar; Kozlowski, Lukasz
This paper investigates the relationship between local banking structures and SMEs' access to debt and performance. Using a unique dataset on bank branch locations in Poland and firm-, county-, and bank-level data, we conclude that a strong position for local cooperative banks facilitates access to bank financing, lowers financial costs, boosts investments, and favours growth for SMEs. Moreover, counties in which cooperative banks hold a strong position are characterized by a more rapid pace of new firm creation. The opposite effects appear in the majority of cases for local banking markets dominated by foreign-owned banks. Consequently, our findings are important from a policy perspective because they show that foreign bank entry and industry consolidation may raise valid concerns for SME prospects in emerging economies. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasan, Iftekhar; Jackowicz, Krzysztof; Kowalewski, Oskar; Kozlowski, Lukasz</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do individual short-sellers make money? Evidence from Korea</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Shu-Feng; Lee, Kuan-Hui; Woo, Min-Cheol
We use a proprietary trade-and account-level dataset of short sales to investigate the profitability of individual investors short-selling in the Korean stock market from August 1, 2007, to May 31, 2010. Using actual data on short-covering transactions, we find that the average profit is 26,810 Korean won (roughly USD 24.4) per trade per hour, and about 44% of shorted trades are covered within a day. We also find that the profitability of short-selling decreases as the hours-to-cover increases. Account-level analyses show that investors who sell short more firms make higher profits than those who sell short fewer firms and that the profitability of short-selling is persistent. We attribute the profitability to short-sellers' ability to exploit short-run price reversals and information processing skills. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Wang, Shu-Feng; Lee, Kuan-Hui; Woo, Min-Cheol</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial penalties and bank performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koster, Hannes; Pelster, Matthias
This paper investigates the impact of financial penalties on the profitability and stock performance of banks. Using a unique dataset of 671 financial penalties imposed on 68 international listed banks over the period 2007 to 2014, we find a negative relation between financial penalties and pre-tax profitability but no relation with after-tax profitability. This result is explained by tax savings, as banks are allowed to deduct specific financial penalties from their taxable income. Moreover, our empirical analysis of the stock performance shows a positive relation between financial penalties and buy-and-hold returns, indicating that investors are pleased that cases are closed, that the banks successfully manage the consequences of misconduct, and that the financial penalties imposed are smaller than the accrued economic gains from the banks' misconduct. This argument is supported by the positive abnormal returns accompanying on the announcement of a financial penalty. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koster, Hannes; Pelster, Matthias</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit cycles and capital flows: Effectiveness of the macroprudential policy framework in emerging market economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fendoglu, Salih
I assess the effectiveness of macroprudential policy tools in containing credit cycles per se or the impact of portfolio inflows on the cycles in major emerging market economies. The results show that borrower-based tools, measures with a domestic focus, and domestic reserve requirements are particularly effective. The findings are, in most cases, stronger for the recent period during which most of the macroprudential actions are undertaken, and generally hold for alternative definitions of credit cycle, the monetary policy stance, and portfolio inflows. Weaker results emerge for financial-institutions-based or foreign-currency related macroprudential tools. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fendoglu, Salih</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downturn LGD modeling using quantile regression</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kruger, Steffen; Rosch, Daniel
Literature on Losses Given Default (LGD) usually focuses on mean predictions, even though losses are extremely skewed and bimodal. This paper proposes a Quantile Regression (QR) approach to get a comprehensive view on the entire probability distribution of losses. The method allows new insights on covariate effects over the whole LGD spectrum. In particular, middle quantiles are explainable by observable covariates while tail events, e.g., extremely high LGDs, seem to be rather driven by unobservable random events. A comparison of the QR approach with several alternatives from recent literature reveals advantages when evaluating downturn and unexpected credit losses. In addition, we identify limitations of classical mean prediction comparisons and propose alternative goodness of fit measures for the validation of forecasts for the entire LGD distribution. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kruger, Steffen; Rosch, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of non-interest income on bank risk in Australia (vol 73, pg 16, 2016)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williams, Barry
nan</description><author>Williams, Barry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do oil futures prices predict stock returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiang, I.-Hsuan Ethan; Hughen, W. Keener
This paper explores stock return predictability by exploiting the cross-section of oil futures prices. Motivated by the principal component analysis, we find the curvature factor of the oil futures curve predicts monthly stock returns: a 1% per month increase in the curvature factor predicts 0.4% per month decrease in stock market index return. This predictive pattern is prevailing in non-oil industry portfolios, but is absent for oil-related portfolios. The in- and out-of-sample predictive power of the curvature factor for non-oil stocks is robust and outperforms many other predictors, including oil spot prices. The predictive power of the curvature factor comes from its ability to forecast supply-side oil shocks, which only affect non-oil stocks and are hedged by oil-related stocks. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiang, I.-Hsuan Ethan; Hughen, W. Keener</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Helping hands or grabbing hands? An analysis of political connections and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Carl R.; Li, Yingqi; Luo, Danglun; Zhang, Ting
We construct a unique political connection index to capture variations in the strength of firm political relations in China. The index incorporates various channels through which a firm's executives, chairperson, directors, and other senior officers are politically connected with government officials and bureaucrats. Overall, there is a negative relation between our index and firm value for the full sample, but such negative relation mainly exists for state-owned enterprises (SOEs) and it becomes positive for non-SOEs. Furthermore, close examination shows an inverted U-shaped relation between political connections and firm value for the full sample in general and for non-SOEs in particular: Firm value increases initially at a lower level of connections and then begins to decrease at a higher level. The findings are consistent with the different business objectives and motivations of SOEs and non-SOEs in seeking political connections. Finally, our findings are robust after controlling for potential endogeneity and using an alternative headcount index construction method. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Carl R.; Li, Yingqi; Luo, Danglun; Zhang, Ting</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the impact of monetary policy announcements: The importance of language and surprises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smales, L. A.; Apergis, N.
Monetary policy announcements have a significant impact on financial market liquidity. This study provides a novel perspective on the factors driving this relationship in the market for 10-year Treasury note futures: Target rate surprises and the complexity of the monetary policy statement language are important determinants. Differences of opinion resulting from interpretation of complex language appear to result in more trading volume despite relatively low levels of liquidity (a negative liquidity-volume relationship), while large target rate surprises reduce trading activity (a positive liquidity-volume relationship). The dynamic changes over time, as unconventional polices are adopted by monetary authorities and, high frequency traders become more pervasive. Central bankers may aid market liquidity by minimizing surprises, and issuing statements that are easier to understand (with shorter sentences and more familiar words). (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Smales, L. A.; Apergis, N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and disentanglement of American puts in the hyper-exponential jump-diffusion model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leippold, Markus; Vasiljevic, Nikola
We analyze American put options in a hyper-exponential jump-diffusion model. Our contribution is threefold. Firstly, by following a maturity randomization approach, we solve the partial integro-differential equation and obtain a tight lower bound for the American option price. Secondly, our method allows to disentangle the contributions of jumps and diffusion for the early exercise premium. Finally, using American-style options on the S&amp;P 100 index from January 2007 until December 2012, we estimate various hyper-exponential specifications and investigate the implications for option pricing and jump diffusion disentanglement. We find that jump risk accounts for a large part of the early exercise premium. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leippold, Markus; Vasiljevic, Nikola</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>ATM foreign fees and cash withdrawals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Magnac, Thierry
We evaluate the impact of "foreign" fees paid by consumers on their cash withdrawals at automatic teller machines (henceforth ATMs). These so called foreign fees are paid when consumers withdraw cash from ATMs which are not owned by their home bank. We take advantage of a natural experiment whereby (non linear) foreign ATM fees in one specific bank became suddenly applicable at one point in time. We also use this experiment to evaluate the substitutions between foreign ATM withdrawals and other home ATM or desk withdrawals as well as with payments by card. Using panel data on accounts, we first estimate average treatment effects on the treated before carrying on with the estimation of a simple structural model. The latter procedure allows us to compute the counterfactual impacts of changing the schedule of foreign fees. Impacts are sizeable on bank profits and consumer welfare. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Magnac, Thierry</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial literacy, present bias and alternative mortgage products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gathergood, John; Weber, Jorg
Choosing a mortgage is one of the most important financial decisions made by a household. Financial innovation has given rise to more complex mortgage products with back-loaded payments, known as 'Alternative Mortgage Products' (AMPS), or 'Interest-Only Mortgages'. Using a specially designed question module in a representative survey of UK mortgage holders, we investigate the effect of consumer financial sophistication on the decision to choose an AMP instead of a standard repayment mortgage. We show poor financial literacy and present bias raise the likelihood of choosing an AMP. Financially literate individuals are also more likely to choose an Adjustable Rate Mortgage (ARM), suggesting they avoid paying the term premium of a fixed rate mortgage. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gathergood, John; Weber, Jorg</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate investment and bank-dependent borrowers during the recent financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buca, Andra; Vermeulen, Philip
We use the recent financial crisis period to analyse the effect of bank credit tightening on firm investment. We derive a new set of credit tightening indexes from the ECB Bank Lending Survey. Combining these with annual balance sheet data from Germany, France, Italy, Spain, Belgium and Portugal, we exploit the heterogeneity in the dependence on bank finance of different industries to identify real effects of credit tightening. We show that in response to tightening, investment falls substantially more in bank dependent industries. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buca, Andra; Vermeulen, Philip</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividends, earnings, and predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moller, Stig V.; Sander, Magnus
We show that the dividend yield and earnings yield jointly are strong predictors of dividend growth. We motivate the joint specification with a theoretical model and show how omitting the earnings yield biases the dividend yield coefficient towards zero, explaining why the dividend yield by itself is a poor predictor of dividend growth. Our empirical results are robust in pre- and post-war U.S. data, in recessions and expansions, in international data, and when controlling for additional predictors. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moller, Stig V.; Sander, Magnus</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interbank interest rates: Funding liquidity risk and XIBOR basis spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallitschke, Janek; Seifried; Seifried, Frank Thomas
This article presents a theoretical model for interbank money market (XIBOR) rates that endogenously generates the basis spreads that characterize post-crisis fixed income markets: XIBOR-OIS spreads, tenor basis spreads, and the forward basis. Our approach is based on an explicit modeling of interbank cash transactions where interbank credit and liquidity risk are factored in. The framework of this article offers a consistent, arbitrage-free explanation for the emergence of basis spreads. We also demonstrate that funding liquidity is a key determinant of post-crisis XIBOR rates and, in particular, tenor basis spreads. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gallitschke, Janek; Seifried; Seifried, Frank Thomas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Temperature shocks and the cost of equity capital: Implications for climate change perceptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balvers, Ronald; Du, Ding; Zhao, Xiaobing
Financial market information can provide an objective assessment of losses anticipated from temperature changes. In an APT model in which temperature shocks are a systematic risk factor, the risk premium is significantly negative, loadings for most assets are negative, and asset portfolios in more vulnerable industries have stronger negative loadings on a temperature shock factor. Weighted average increases in the cost of equity capital attributed to uncertainty about temperature changes are 0.22 percent, implying a present value loss of 7.92 percent of wealth. These costs represent a new channel that may contribute to cost of climate change assessment. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balvers, Ronald; Du, Ding; Zhao, Xiaobing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives investment-cash flow sensitivity around the World? An asset tangibility Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz; Nanda, Vikram; Vadilyev, Alexander; Zhang, Bohui
Motivated by ongoing debates on investment-cash flow sensitivity (ICFS) and its documented decline and disappearance in the U.S., we investigate the determinants of ICFS. Using firm-level data across 41 countries for the 1993-2013 period, we document an important role of asset tangibility in explaining the patterns in ICFS. Asset tangibility affects ICFS through two channels: investment intensity and cash flow persistence. As the share of tangible capital, investment and cash flow persistence has fallen in developed economies, ICFS has declined. In contrast, as developing economies operate with more tangible capital, have higher investment rates and more persistent cash flows, their ICFS is more stable. The results support our explanation of ICFS as a reflection of capital (investment) intensity and income predictability, rather than a measure of financial constraints. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz; Nanda, Vikram; Vadilyev, Alexander; Zhang, Bohui</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Divergence of sentiment and stock market trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siganos, Antonios; Vagenas-Nanos, Evangelos; Verwijmeren, Patrick
This paper introduces the concept of divergence of sentiment to the behavioral finance literature. We measure the distance between people with positive and negative sentiment on a daily basis for 20 countries by using data from status updates on Facebook. The prediction is that a higher divergence of sentiment leads to more diverging views on prospects and risks, and thus to more diverging views on the value of a stock. In line with this prediction, divergence of sentiment is positively related to trading volume. We further predict and find a positive relation between divergence of sentiment and stock price volatility. The observed relations are stronger when individual investors are more likely to trade. We compare the effect of our country-specific measures to a global measure of divergence of sentiment. We find that the separate effects of country-specific and global divergence measures depend on a country's level of market integration. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Siganos, Antonios; Vagenas-Nanos, Evangelos; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do fund managers increase risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ha, Yeonjeong; Ko, Kwangsoo
This paper examines the relationship between the increase in fund risk and subsequent cash flows. We attempt to test the hypothesis that an increase in fund risk actually increases the net flows of equity funds, which is a basic assumption of risk shifting. We find that a change in fund risk has a positive and convex relationship with the fund's net flows. The effect of risk changes on net flows is a natural consequence of its effects on inflows and outflows. This paper's empirical results are robust to return frequency, fund age, and fund size. Our findings create incentives for managers to shift risk as documented in the mutual fund literature. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ha, Yeonjeong; Ko, Kwangsoo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of bank and nonbank provider locations on household use of financial transaction services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goodstein, Ryan M.; Rhine, Sherrie L. W.
We examine the influence that geographic proximity to bank branches and nonbank financial providers has on use of financial transaction services among U.S. households. We specify a bivariate probit model of bank account ownership and nonbank transaction product use to reflect the joint nature of these choices, and estimate the model on a large, nationally representative dataset. Our results indicate that households with reasonable geographic access to bank branches are more likely to have a bank account and less likely to use nonbank transaction products. The influence of bank and nonbank provider locations is fairly modest overall, although effects are bigger for households that are more likely to be on the margin of bank account ownership. Even among such households, however, the effects of bank and nonbank provider locations on financial transaction services use are not as large as those associated with key household-level attributes, such as income, education, or race. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Goodstein, Ryan M.; Rhine, Sherrie L. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Style drift: Evidence from small-cap mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Charles; Iliev, Peter; Velthuis, Raisa
This paper documents that small-cap mutual funds allocate on average 27% of their portfolio to mid- and large-cap stocks. We find that larger and older small-cap funds are more likely to hold mid- and large cap stocks, consistent with funds straying from their objective over time. Funds that invest heavily in mid- and large-cap stocks expose their investors to unanticipated risks but investors do not experience higher abnormal returns or performance persistence overall. These funds did outperform their peers by 3% annually in the most recent period between January 2003 and March 2010. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cao, Charles; Iliev, Peter; Velthuis, Raisa</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of the consistency of banks' internal ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berg, Tobias; Koziol, Philipp
Internal ratings-based models are used for a variety of important bank and regulatory decisions. Thus, model risk - the potential for different models to provide different probability-of-default (PD) estimates - is of crucial importance. Using a comprehensive German credit registry dataset from 40 banks and 17,000 corporate borrowers from 2008-2012, we assess the consistency of internal PD estimates across banks. We find three main results. First, the variability of PD estimates for the same borrower across banks is large. Second, bank fixed effects explain 5% of the variation in PD estimates across banks, while 95% of the variation is idiosyncratic. For the 10 largest banks in our sample, reported regulatory capital ratios would change by a maximum of +/- 10%, equivalent to approximately 1 percentage point, when using average risk weights from all banks instead of risk weights based on banks' individual PD estimates. Third, we explore various bank characteristics that explain the size of bank fixed effects. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berg, Tobias; Koziol, Philipp</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Network, market, and book-based systemic risk rankings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van de Leur, Michiel C. W.; Lucas, Andre; Seeger, Norman J.
We investigate the information content of stock correlation based network measures for systemic risk rankings, such as SIFIRank (based on Google's PageRank). Using European banking data, we show that SIFIRank is empirically equivalent to a ranking based on average pairwise stock correlations as developed in this paper. The correlation based network measures complement currently available alternative systemic risk ranking methods based on book or market values. A further analytical investigation shows that the value-added appears to be mainly attributable to pairwise cross-sectional heterogeneity rather than to more subtle network relations and feedback loops. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>van de Leur, Michiel C. W.; Lucas, Andre; Seeger, Norman J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The location of financial sector FDI: Tax and regulation policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Merz, Julia; Overesch, Michael; Wamser, Georg
This paper analyzes how corporate taxation and regulatory requirements affect the location of financial sector FDI. We use novel information on new financial services entities established by multinational firms in 83 host countries. We find a negative effect of host country taxes on the probability of choosing a particular host location. We can also confirm a significant influence of the regulatory environment. For example, stricter (equity) capital requirements negatively affect location probabilities. Our empirical approach allows us to provide new insight in how a policy measure of a given country affects other countries by estimating cross-country tax and regulation elasticities. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Merz, Julia; Overesch, Michael; Wamser, Georg</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does working in a finance profession affect mortgage delinquency?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Chomsisengphet, Souphala; Zhang, Yunqi
This paper uses a dataset from a leading American subprime lender, which contains detailed information on borrower and loan characteristics. We find that financial professionals are less likely to become delinquent. This effect cannot be explained by borrower characteristics, such as income, education, loan terms, property characteristics, geographic effects, or strategic default. We also find variation in the effect of working in a financial profession across borrowers of different ages and income levels. We discuss explanations for these results. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Chomsisengphet, Souphala; Zhang, Yunqi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple blockholders, power, and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basu, Nilanjan; Paeglis, Imants; Rahnamaei, Mohammad
Using a comprehensive sample of US firms we show that most of them have multiple blockholders whose presence and ownership stakes lead to a significant difference between ownership and power. This difference matters. First, we find that insider power (ownership) is negatively (positively) related to firm value. Second, we show that outsider power is positively related to firm value. Our direct blockholder-level measure of power explains firm value over and above the explanatory power of firm-level measures used in the literature (such as the number of blockholders and the dispersion of their ownership stakes). (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Basu, Nilanjan; Paeglis, Imants; Rahnamaei, Mohammad</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Too-international-to-fail? Supranational bank resolution and market discipline</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gornicka, Lucyna A.; Zoican, Marius A.
Supranational resolution of insolvent banks does not necessarily improve welfare. Supranational regulators are more inclined to bail-out banks indebted towards international creditors because they take into account cross-border contagion. When banks' creditors are more likely to be bailed out, market discipline decreases and risk-taking by indebted banks increases. Depending on the trade-off between giving the right incentives ex ante and limiting contagion ex post, both a national and a supranational resolution framework can be optimal. In particular, if market discipline is low under both national and supranational resolution mechanisms, supranational resolution improves welfare as it stimulates interbank trade. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gornicka, Lucyna A.; Zoican, Marius A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal Stochastic Volatility: Implications for the pricing of commodity options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arismendi, Juan C.; Back, Janis; Prokopczuk, Marcel; Paschke, Raphael; Rudolf, Markus
Many commodity markets contain a strong seasonal component not only at the price level, but also in volatility. In this paper, the importance of seasonal behavior in the volatility for the pricing of commodity options is analyzed. We propose a seasonally varying long-run mean variance process that is capable of capturing empirically observed patterns. Semi-closed-form option valuation formulas are derived. We then empirically study the impact of the proposed Seasonal Stochastic Volatility Model on the pricing accuracy of natural gas futures options traded at the New York Mercantile Exchange (NYMEX) and corn futures options traded at the Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT). Our results demonstrate that allowing stochastic volatility to fluctuate seasonally significantly reduces pricing errors for these contracts. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arismendi, Juan C.; Back, Janis; Prokopczuk, Marcel; Paschke, Raphael; Rudolf, Markus</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The level effect of bank lending standards on business lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van der Veer, Koen J. M.; Hoeberichts, Marco M.
Do tightenings of bank lending standards permanently reduce bank lending? We construct a measure of a bank's level of lending standards using micro-data from the sample of banks participating in the Eurosystem Bank Lending Survey in The Netherlands and show that this level measure affects business lending. The level effect is statistically robust and economically relevant; a one point tightening reduces a bank's quarterly growth rate of business lending by about half a percentage point until bank lending standards are eased. This level effect of bank lending standards helps to explain low bank lending growth after a period of prolonged tightening as well as high bank lending growth in a period of prolonged easing. As such, the analysis provides another potential indicator for macroprudential policy. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>van der Veer, Koen J. M.; Hoeberichts, Marco M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market volatility and business cycle: Evidence from linear and nonlinear causality tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choudhry, Taufiq; Papadimitriou, Fotios I.; Shabi, Sarosh
This paper investigates the relationship between stock market volatility and the business cycle in four major economies, namely the US, Canada, Japan and the UK. We employ both linear and nonlinear bivariate causality tests and we further conduct a multivariate analysis to explore possible spillover effects across countries. Our results suggest that there is a bidirectional causal relationship between stock market volatility and the business cycle within each country and additionally reveal that the recent financial crisis plays an important role in this context. Finally, we identify a significant impact of the US on the remaining markets. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choudhry, Taufiq; Papadimitriou, Fotios I.; Shabi, Sarosh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does deposit insurance retard the development of non-bank financial markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergbrant, Mikael C.; Campbell, Kaysia T.; Hunter, Delroy M.; Owers, James E.
Whether, and how, the introduction of deposit insurance affects non-bank financial market development depends on whether banks and non-bank financial markets are substitutes or complements and theory has conflicting views. Using data on 134 countries over a 28-year period and several identification strategies we find that the introduction of deposit insurance retards the equity market, the non-bank depositaries sector, and the banking sector when law and order is weak. While strong law and order mitigates this effect, it does not lead to a positive outcome for all markets. For non-bank financial markets, the effect is greater in the long run so that while deposit insurance increases banking sector development in the long run, it retards non-bank financial markets regardless of the level of law and order. Finally, several design features exacerbate the negative outcomes. Our results have important policy implications for implementing or altering deposit insurance schemes. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bergbrant, Mikael C.; Campbell, Kaysia T.; Hunter, Delroy M.; Owers, James E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the buck stop here? A comparison of withdrawals from money market mutual funds with floating and constant share prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Witmer, Jonathan
Recent reform proposals call for an elimination of the constant net asset value (NAV) or "buck" in money market mutual funds to reduce the occurrence of runs. Outside the United States, there are several countries that have money market mutual funds with and without constant NAVs. Using daily data on individual fund flows from these countries, this paper evaluates whether the reliance on a constant NAV is associated with higher fund redemptions. The data suggest that funds with a constant NAV experienced more negative net flows during the period of the run on the Reserve Primary Fund, even after controlling for measures of fund risk and risk aversion. However, I do not find convincing support for the hypothesis that the effect of sponsor strength on fund flows was stronger for constant NAV money market funds. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Witmer, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do banks actively manage their liquidity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeYoung, Robert; Jang, Karen Y.
We test whether and how U.S. commercial banks actively managed their liquidity positions between 1992 and 2012, prior to the implementation of the Basel III liquidity rules. On average, the data are consistent with a liquidity management regime in which banks targeted the traditional loans-to-core deposits (LTCD) ratio. Perhaps surprisingly, the data are also consistent on average with the net stable funding ratio (NSFR), a regulatory liquidity ratio that was not formally introduced by the Bank for International Settlements until 2010. We find evidence of LTCD and (implicit) NSFR targeting at banks of all sizes, but concordance is strongest for small banks and weakest for so-called SIFI banks. As banks increase in size, they set lower liquidity targets often in violation of the coming Basel III standards but manage those targets more efficiently. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeYoung, Robert; Jang, Karen Y.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and hedging of derivatives in contagious markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kokholm, Thomas
It is well documented that stock markets are contagious. A negative shock to one market increases the probability of adverse shocks to other markets. We model this contagion effect by including mutually exciting jump processes in the dynamics of the indexes' log-returns. On top of this we add a stochastic volatility component to the dynamics. It is important to take the contagion effect into account if derivatives written on a basket of assets are to be priced or hedged. Due to the affine model specification the joint characteristic function of the log-returns is known analytically, and for two specifications we detail how the model can be calibrated efficiently to option prices. In total we calibrate over an extended period of time the specifications to options data on four US stock indexes, and show how the models achieve satisfactory pricing errors. We study the effect of contagion on multi-asset derivatives prices and show how for certain derivatives the impact is heavy. Moreover, we derive hedge ratios for European put and call options and perform a numerical experiment, which illustrates the impact of contagious jumps on option prices and hedge ratios. Mutually exciting processes have been analyzed for multivariate intensity modeling for the purpose of credit derivatives pricing, but have not been used for pricing/hedging options on equity indexes. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kokholm, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of bank relationships when firms are financially distressed</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoewer, Daniel
Banks are better suited than other financing partners to process information in order to make efficient liquidations. But their ability depends on bank characteristics and incentives. In addition, the strength of the main bank relationship influences the bank's ability to make efficient liquidations. I study the effect of bank characteristics and bank relationships in situations where firms are financially distressed. Do the chances of a financially distressed firm to improve or to close depend on the bank? Does the survival of a financially distressed firm depend on its main bank relationship? Using German data from 2000-2013, I analyze the effect of a bank's organizational complexity, non-performing customers, and the strength of main bank relationships at the bank and firm level. I find that high shares of non-performing clients provide negative incentives. Banks can make more efficient liquidations if they are regionally active and have close relationships with the firm. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hoewer, Daniel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The MAX effect: An exploration of risk and mispricing explanations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhong, Angel; Gray, Philip
This paper studies the role that risk and mispricing play in the negative relation between extreme positive returns and future returns. We document a strong 'MAX effect' in Australian equities over 1991-2013 that is robust to risk adjustment, controlling for other influential stock characteristics and, importantly, manifests in a partition of the 500 largest stocks. While there is no evidence that MAX proxies for sensitivity to risk, the findings are highly consistent with a mispricing explanation. Adapting the recent methodological innovation of Stambaugh et al. (2015) to classify stocks by their degree of mispricing, we show that the MAX effect concentrates amongst the most-overpriced stocks but actually reverses amongst the most-underpriced stocks. Consistent with arbitrage asymmetry, the magnitude of the MAX effect amongst overpriced stocks exceeds that amongst underpriced stocks, leading to the overall negative relation that has been well documented. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhong, Angel; Gray, Philip</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional stock ownership and firms' cash dividend policies: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Firth, Michael; Gao, Jin; Shen, Jianghua; Zhang, Yuanyuan
Agency theory suggests that outside shareholders prefer higher dividend payouts in order to reduce the free cash flows of firms that are under the insiders' control. Our study investigates the effects of mutual funds, typically the most important and influential type of outside shareholder, on firms' dividend payouts in China during the period from 2003 to 2011. We find that mutual funds influence firms to pay higher cash dividends. The results are consistent with the predictions from exit theory. The effects are more pronounced in firms controlled by state and regional governments and in firms with relatively higher free cash flows. We also find evidence that the mutual funds' effects are stronger when their investment horizon is longer and the ownership interest is larger. Other institutional investors, such as banks, insurance companies, and securities companies have a lower exit threat and do not have an influence on firms' cash dividend payments or financial performances. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Firth, Michael; Gao, Jin; Shen, Jianghua; Zhang, Yuanyuan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The evolution of debt policies: New evidence from business startups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanssens, Juergen; Deloof, Marc; Vanacker, Tom
We investigate the evolution of entrepreneurial firms' debt policies over a period of 15 years after startup, considering leverage, debt specialization, debt maturity and debt granularity. Our analysis is based on a unique sample covering all non-financial Belgian firms founded between 1996 and 1998. We find that the debt policy of entrepreneurial firms is remarkably stable over time. The debt policy in the initial year of operation is a very important determinant of future debt policies, even after controlling for traditional contemporaneous determinants. The founder-CEO has an important impact on the stability of debt policies: the influence of initial debt policies on future debt policies is significantly reduced when the founder-CEO is replaced or when (s)he dies. Combined, our findings support imprinting theory. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanssens, Juergen; Deloof, Marc; Vanacker, Tom</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The informational content of the embedded deflation option in TIPS</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grishchenko, Olesya V.; Vanden, Joel M.; Zhang, Jianing
We estimate the value of the embedded option in U.S. Treasury Inflation-Protected Securities (TIPS). The embedded option value exhibits time variation that is correlated with periods of deflationary expectations. We construct embedded option explanatory variables that are statistically and economically significant for explaining future inflation, even in the presence of traditional inflation variables such as lagged inflation, the gold return, the crude oil return, the VIX return, liquidity, surveys, and the yield spread between nominal Treasuries and TIPS. After conducting robustness tests, we conclude that the TIPS embedded option contains useful information for future inflation. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grishchenko, Olesya V.; Vanden, Joel M.; Zhang, Jianing</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When does the stock market listen to economic news? New evidence from copulas and news wires</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Medovikov, Ivan
We study association between macroeconomic news and stock market returns using the statistical theory of copulas, and a new comprehensive measure of news based on textual review and classification of news wires. We find the impact of economic news on equity returns to be nonlinear and asymmetric. In particular, controlling for economic conditions and surprises associated with releases of economic data, we find that the market reacts strongly and negatively to the most unfavourable macroeconomic news, but appears to largely discount the good news. Further, the most-unfavorable news creates price drift, and we document that selling stocks short in the wake of unusually-bad news yields annual abnormal gross returns greater than four percent. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Medovikov, Ivan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adverse selection, market access, and inter-market competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoffmann, Peter
This paper investigates the role of informed trading in a fragmented financial market under the absence of inter-market price priority. Due to frictions in traders' market access, liquidity providers on alternative trading platforms can be exposed to an increased adverse selection risk. As a consequence, the main market will dominate (display better quotes) frequently albeit charging considerably higher transaction fees. The empirical analysis of a dataset of trading in French and German stocks suggests that trades on Chi-X Europe, a low-cost trading platform, carry significantly more private information than those executed in the Primary Markets. Consistent with our theory, we find a negative relationship between the competitiveness of Chi-X Europe's quotes and this excess adverse selection risk faced by liquidity providers in the cross-section. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hoffmann, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A new approach to statistical arbitrage: Strategies based on dynamic factor models of prices and their performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Focardi, Sergio M.; Fabozzi, Frank J.; Mitov, Ivan K.
Statistical arbitrage strategies are typically based on models of returns. We introduce a new statistical arbitrage strategy based on dynamic factor models of prices. Our objective in this paper is to exploit the mean-reverting properties of prices reported in the literature. We do so because, to capture the same information using a return-based factor model, a much larger number of lags would be needed, leading to inaccurate parameter estimation. To empirically test the relative performance of return-based and price based models, we construct portfolios (long -short, long-only, and equally weighted) based on the forecasts generated by two dynamic factor models. Using the stock of companies included in the S&amp;P 500 index for constructing portfolios, the empirical analysis statistically tests the relative forecasting performance using the Diebold-Mariano framework and performing the test for statistical arbitrage proposed by Hogan et al. (2004). Our results show that prices allow for significantly more accurate forecasts than returns and pass the test for statistical arbitrage. We attribute this finding to the mean-reverting properties of stock prices. The high level of forecasting accuracy using price-based factor models has important theoretical and practical implications. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Focardi, Sergio M.; Fabozzi, Frank J.; Mitov, Ivan K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of global bank lending: Evidence from bilateral cross-country data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aysun, Uluc; Hepp, Ralf
This paper finds that factors determined outside of a country, at the quarterly frequency and especially after 2008, are more closely related to the global bank loans it receives. These loans are generally more stable when global banks face more competition and have a higher presence in the recipient country. We obtain our results by using bilateral lending data from 15 countries and a unique methodology to identify and compare the independent effects of external and internal factors. We identify theoretical mechanisms that can explain our empirical findings and draw more detailed inferences for competition and global bank presence by solving a simple model of global banking. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aysun, Uluc; Hepp, Ralf</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial distress and the Malaysian dual baking system: A dynamic slacks approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wanke, Peter; Azad, Md Abul Kalam; Barros, Carlos Pestana
This paper presents an efficiency assessment of the Malaysian dual banking system using the Dynamic Slacks Based Model (DSBM) in order to assess the evolution of Malaysian Banks' potential input-saving/output-increase from 2009 to 2013. More precisely, DSBM is used first in a two-stage approach to assess the relative efficiency of Malaysian Islamic and conventional banks by emulating the CAMEL rating systems. Then, in the second stage, Monte Carlo Markov Chain (MCMC) methods applied to generalized linear mixed models (GLMM) are combined with DSBM results as part of an attempt to produce a model for banking performance assessment with effective predictive ability. Results indicate higher inefficiency levels and slacks in Islamic banks when compared to conventional ones. Furthermore, when the scope of analysis is the group of Malaysian Islamic banks, the efficiency levels of foreign banks are lower compared to their national counterparts, suggesting regulatory and cultural barriers. Policy implications are derived. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wanke, Peter; Azad, Md Abul Kalam; Barros, Carlos Pestana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency momentum, carry trade, and market illiquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Orlov, Vitaly
This study empirically examines the effect of equity market illiquidity on the excess returns of currency momentum and carry trade strategies. Results show that equity market illiquidity explains the evolution of currency momentum strategy payoffs, but not carry trade. Returns on currency momentum are low following months of high equity market illiquidity. However, in the recent decade, illiquidity positively predicts the associated payoffs. The findings withstand various robustness checks and are economically significant, approximating in value to one-third of average monthly profits. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Orlov, Vitaly</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early-stage entrepreneurial financing: A signaling perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Jin-Hyuk; Wagman, Liad
We analyze an entrepreneur's choice between angel and venture capital (VC) financing in a competitive investment market, where the entrepreneur seeks to maintain his ownership share as well as equity value. The key to our analysis is the idea that a negative signal is inferred by the market if an inside investor chooses not to follow on a subsequent investment. We first show that When ventures are ex-ante identical, entrepreneurs retain higher ownership shares by financing with angel investors who commit to not participate in a future round. When entrepreneurs are ex-ante heterogeneous, there is a separating equilibrium where entrepreneurs with higher (lower) likelihoods of success choose VC financing (angel financing) in the first round. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Jin-Hyuk; Wagman, Liad</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit spread variability in the US business cycle: The Great Moderation versus the Great Recession</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hollander, Hylton; Liu, Guangling
This paper identifies the prevailing financial factors that influence credit spread variability and shows how they affected the U.S. business cycle during the 1990-91 and 2001 recessions of the Great Moderation period (1984-2006) and the Great Recession of 2007-09. To do this, we develop and estimate a dynamic general equilibrium model in which financial intermediation and equity assets play a central role. Over the three recession periods, we find that bank market power (sticky rate adjustments and loan rate markups) played a significant role in the credit spread variability that disrupted the U.S. business cycle. Equity prices exacerbate movements in credit spreads through the financial accelerator channel, but cannot be regarded as one of the main driving forces of credit spread variability. Across the three periods, we observe a remarkable decline in the influence of technology and monetary policy shocks. The influence of loan-to-value ratio shocks declined after the 1990-91 recession, while the bank capital requirement shock exacerbated and prolonged credit spread variability over the 2007-09 recession. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hollander, Hylton; Liu, Guangling</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effect of the Basel Accord capital requirements on the loan-loss provisioning practices of Australian banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cummings, James R.; Durrani, Kassim J.
There are two distinct regimes for bank provisioning in Australia: a forward-looking model for regulatory purposes and an incurred loss model for financial reporting. This study examines the former using a unique but confidential database. We find evidence that: (i) banks increase provisions in anticipation of future lending growth, (ii) banks allocate part of surplus capital above regulatory requirements to pre-fund future credit losses through provisions, and (iii) banks allocate part of higher earnings for the same purpose. These results suggest that bank managers use their discretion in setting provisions to dampen the impact of fluctuations in credit market conditions on their lending activities. For internal ratings-based banks, results suggest that the revised Basel framework allowing these banks to estimate expected losses using their own credit risk models may come at a cost of reduced general provisions. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cummings, James R.; Durrani, Kassim J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>