<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Economic Literature1</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>The Seven Secrets of Germany: Economic Resilience in an Era of Global Turbulence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burda, Michael C.
nan</description><author>Burda, Michael C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>War by Other Means: Geoeconomics and Statecraft</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Early, Bryan R.
nan</description><author>Early, Bryan R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Too Little, Too Late: The Quest to Resolve Sovereign Debt Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wilson, John O. S.
nan</description><author>Wilson, John O. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>150 Years of ObamaCare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goodman-Bacon, Andrew
nan</description><author>Goodman-Bacon, Andrew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Food Security and Scarcity: Why Ending Hunger Is So Hard</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thorbecke, Erik
nan</description><author>Thorbecke, Erik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding Art Markets: Inside the World of Art and Business</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Throsby, David
nan</description><author>Throsby, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Music and Capitalism: A History of the Present</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Connolly, Marie
nan</description><author>Connolly, Marie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ontology, Methodological Individualism, and the Foundations of the Social Sciences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sugden, Robert
This is a review essay based on a critical assessment of The Ant Trap: Rebuilding the Foundations of the Social Sciences by Brian Epstein. Epstein argues that models in the social sciences are inadequate because they are based on a false ontology of methodological individualism, and proposes a new model of social ontology. I examine this model and point to flaws in it. More generally, I argue against Epstein's methodological approach, which treats social ontology as prior to social scientific modeling and as certifying the "building blocks" that modelers then use. I argue that modelers can legitimately shape the building blocks for their own models.</description><author>Sugden, Robert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Econometrics of Matching Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiappori, Pierre-Andre; Salanie, Bernard
Many questions in economics can be fruitfully analyzed in the framework of matching models. Until recently, empirical work has lagged far behind theory in this area. This review reports on recent developments that have considerably expanded the range of matching models that can be taken to the data. A leading theme is that in such two-sided markets, knowing the observable characteristics of partners alone is not enough to credibly identify the relevant parameters. A combination of richer data and robust, theory-driven restrictions is required. We illustrate this on leading applications.</description><author>Chiappori, Pierre-Andre; Salanie, Bernard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contagion in Financial Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glasserman, Paul; Young, H. Peyton
The recent financial crisis has prompted much new research on the interconnectedness of the modern financial system and the extent to which it contributes to systemic fragility. Network connections diversify firms' risk exposures, but they also create channels through which shocks can spread by contagion. We review the extensive literature on this issue, with the focus on how network structure interacts with other key variables such as leverage, size, common exposures, and short-term funding. We discuss various metrics that have been proposed for evaluating the susceptibility of the system to contagion and suggest directions for future research.</description><author>Glasserman, Paul; Young, H. Peyton</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State and Development: The Need for a Reappraisal of the Current Literature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bardhan, Pranab
This essay tries to bring out some of the complexities that are overlooked in the usual treatment of the state in the institutional economics literature and supplement the latter with a discussion of some alternative approaches to looking at the possible developmental role of the state. It refers to a broader range of development goals (including the structural transformation of the economy) and focuses on problems like the resolution of coordination failures and collective-action problems, the conflicting issues of commitment and accountability and the need for balancing the trade-offs they generate, some ingredients of state capacity and political coalition building usually missed in the literature, the possible importance of rent sharing in a political equilibrium, the advantages and problems of political centralization and decentralization, and the multidimensionality of state functions that may not be addressed by markets or private firms.</description><author>Bardhan, Pranab</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding African Poverty Over the Longue Duree: A Review of Africa's Development in Historical Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McMillan, Margaret
The sixteen essays edited and synthesized by Emmanuel Akyeampong, Robert H. Bates, Nathan Nunn, and James A. Robinson contribute significantly to our understanding of the following questions: (1) When did Africa become poor?; (2) Why did Africa become poor?; and (3) Why has Africa remained poor? Although these questions are impossible to answer in a definitive way, the partial explanations offered in this book are insightful and thought provoking and are summarized in this article. However, they also rest primarily on economic and political arguments. The importance of geography, which is mostly not explored in these essays, is reviewed in the final section of this article.</description><author>McMillan, Margaret</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Review of Making Money: Coin, Currency, and the Coming of Capitalism by Christine Desan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roberds, William
In the eighteenth century, the Bank of England revolutionized money through its large-scale introduction of circulating banknotes. The consequences of this revolution are felt even today. In Making Money: Coin, Currency, and the Coming of Capitalism, Christine Desan argues that this legendary transformation was not a one-off event, but a culmination of long-standing trends within the English monetary tradition. This review concedes Desan's point, but calls attention to other factors that were equally critical to the Bank's success: exceptional business and political acumen, active suppression of competitors, and lots of good luck. The importance of these factors is evidenced by the failure of attempted copycat institutions in other countries.</description><author>Roberds, William</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Current Federal Reserve Policy under the Lens of Economic History: A Review Essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williamson, Stephen D.
This review essay reviews the volume edited by Owen Humpage, Current Federal Reserve Policy under the Lens of Economic History: Essays to Commemorate the Federal Reserve System's Centennial, and provides a broader perspective on central-banking issues. The papers in the Humpage volume address various aspects of central banking history, money, and private banking, with a focus on putting recent Fed policies in perspective. The topics covered include the role of the central bank as lender of last resort, the effects of open-market operations versus central-bank lending, central-bank independence, the political economy of monetary unions, financial crises, the effects of unconventional monetary policies, commodity monies, and the Canadian financial system as a natural experiment.</description><author>Williamson, Stephen D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Review of Political Order and Inequality: Their Foundations and Their Consequences by Carles Boix</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alesina, Alberto
Political Order and Inequality: Their Foundations and Their Consequences argues that geography, technology, and wars determined the formation of a ruling class, inequality, and institutional development, rather than the other way around. Institutions are not a cause but a consequence. This relatively short book covers an enormous amount of material. I have sympathy for the basic idea of the book, but in some parts I would have liked to see more detailed evidence, especially on the more recent history and the Industrial Revolution.</description><author>Alesina, Alberto</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolutionary Games in Natural, Social, and Virtual Worlds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nachbar, John
nan</description><author>Nachbar, John</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revealed Preference Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Varian, Hal R.
nan</description><author>Varian, Hal R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Crude Look at the Whole: The Science of Complex Systems in Business, Life, and Society</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foley, Duncan K.
nan</description><author>Foley, Duncan K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Poverty and Social Exclusion: New Methods of Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiappero-Martinetti, Enrica
nan</description><author>Chiappero-Martinetti, Enrica</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Job Skills and Minority Youth: New Program Directions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Matthew T.
nan</description><author>Johnson, Matthew T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Handbook of the Economics and Political Economy of Transition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ericson, Richard E.
nan</description><author>Ericson, Richard E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Price of Oil</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bachmeier, Lance
nan</description><author>Bachmeier, Lance</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Re-Imagining Economic Sociology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ody-Brasier, Amandine
nan</description><author>Ody-Brasier, Amandine</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Palgrave Handbook of Economics and Language</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiswick, Barry R.
nan</description><author>Chiswick, Barry R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bourgeois Equality: How Ideas, Not Capital or Institutions, Enriched the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milgate, Murray
nan</description><author>Milgate, Murray</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Constitutional Money: A Review of the Supreme Court's Monetary Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desan, Christine
nan</description><author>Desan, Christine</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Judaism in Transition: How Economic Choices Shape Religious Tradition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckstein, Zvi
nan</description><author>Eckstein, Zvi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing Markets and the Economy: Risk, Regulation, and Policy: Essays in Honor of Karl E. Case</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gottlieb, Joshua D.
nan</description><author>Gottlieb, Joshua D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Natural Capital: Valuing Our Planet</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Groom, Ben
nan</description><author>Groom, Ben</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Water Pricing Experiences and Innovations, vol 9</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Debaere, Peter
nan</description><author>Debaere, Peter</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Great Depression in Latin America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chu, David S. C.
nan</description><author>Chu, David S. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Marriage Motive: A Price Theory of Marriage: How Marriage Markets Affect Employment, Consumption, and Savings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Apps, Patricia
nan</description><author>Apps, Patricia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Happiness and the Law</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adler, Matthew D.
nan</description><author>Adler, Matthew D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Busted Sanctions: Explaining Why Economic Sanctions Fail</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lowenberg, Anton D.
nan</description><author>Lowenberg, Anton D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Many Is Too Many? The Progressive Argument for Reducing Immigration into the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wright, Greg C.
nan</description><author>Wright, Greg C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Knowledge Capital of Nations: Education and the Economics of Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lindahl, Mikael
nan</description><author>Lindahl, Mikael</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Medicare and Medicaid at 50: America's Entitlement Programs in the Age of Affordable Care</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maestas, Nicole
nan</description><author>Maestas, Nicole</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Our Days Became Numbered: Risk and the Rise of the Statistical Individual</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stapleford, Thomas
nan</description><author>Stapleford, Thomas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Practical Guide to Price Index and Hedonic Techniques</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sichel, Daniel E.
nan</description><author>Sichel, Daniel E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Culture and Institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alesina, Alberto; Giuliano, Paola
A growing body of empirical work measuring different types of cultural traits has shown that culture matters for a variety of economic outcomes. This paper focuses on one specific aspect of the relevance of culture: its relationship to institutions. We review work with a theoretical, empirical, and historical bent to assess the presence of a two-way causal effect between culture and institutions.</description><author>Alesina, Alberto; Giuliano, Paola</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural Econometric Models, vol 31</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williams, Benjamin
nan</description><author>Williams, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stress for Success: A Review of Timothy Geithner's Financial Crisis Memoir</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, Gary
Timothy Geithner's memoir of the financial crisis of 2007-08-Stress Test: Reflections on Financial Crises-is an important historical document offering details of how policies were formed and implemented during the crisis, showing the political constraints, and offering lessons for future crises. Walter Bagehot's classic rule for fighting crises-that the central bank should lend against good collateral at a high rate-is passive and incomplete. Geithner argues for the use of overwhelming force to reestablish confidence. Also, although the Federal Reserve's new crisis lending programs needed to be anonymous so as not to reveal weak banks' identities-"stigma"-the stress tests during the crisis did reveal information that may have been useful in reestablishing confidence.</description><author>Gorton, Gary</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Immigration and Globalization: A Review Essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borjas, George J.
This essay revisits the argument that the removal of worldwide immigration restrictions would induce a very large increase in world GDP. The recent books Exodus: How Migration is Changing Our World by Paul Collier and The Price of Rights: Regulating International Labor Migration by Martin Ruhs raise a number of questions about the underlying economic model. The essay shows how these concerns can greatly attenuate the predicted gains.</description><author>Borjas, George J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial and Macroeconomic Connectedness: A Network Approach to Measurement and Monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atalay, Enghin
nan</description><author>Atalay, Enghin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cambridge History of "Capitalism"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Temin, Peter
This review essay of the two-volume Cambridge History of Capitalism (2014), edited by Larry Neal and Jeffrey G. Williamson, is divided into three parts. First, I describe three chapters from the second volume that I recommend for all economists to add depth to their understanding of the world economy today. Robert C. Allen analyzes the world distribution of income; Randall Morck and Bernard Yeung discuss the history of business groups; and Peter Lindert surveys private and public programs to help the poor. In each case, they analyze historical backgrounds that illuminate current issues. Second, I criticize the definition of capitalism used in these volumes as too expansive to be useful. I argue that this definition mars the essays in first volume by stimulating a fruitless search for capitalism in the millennium before the Industrial Revolution. Third, I describe the essays in this reference work starting from the most recent and ending with those about antiquity.</description><author>Temin, Peter</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tiger Parenting and American Inequality: An Essay on Chua and Rubenfeld's The Triple Package: How Three Unlikely Traits Explain the Rise and Fall of Cultural Groups in America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lundberg, Shelly
The role of culture in the creation and persistence of racial and ethnic inequalities has been the focus of considerable controversy in the social sciences. In The Triple Package: How Three Unlikely Traits Explain the Rise and Fall of Cultural Groups in America, a new book intended for a popular audience, "tiger mom" Amy Chua and Jed Rubenfeld argue that relatively successful ethnic, religious, and national origin groups in the United States possess a common set of culturally determined traits that drive this success: a sense of group superiority, individual insecurity, and good impulse control. The book is an unscholarly romp through fields of ethnic stereotypes and immigrant anxiety that relies on anecdote, rather than data, and that ignores the selectivity of immigrant flows. In their insistence on the need for the whole triple package, however, the authors raise issues relevant to current research on noncognitive skills-that there are important trait-environment interactions in the determinants of economic success, and that the source and impact of aspirations deserves greater attention.</description><author>Lundberg, Shelly</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Long Way Coming: Designing Centralized Markets with Privately Informed Buyers and Sellers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loertscher, Simon; Marx, Leslie M.; Wilkening, Tom
We discuss the economics literature relevant to the design of centralized two-sided market mechanisms for environments in which both buyers and sellers have private information. The existing literature and the history of spectrum auctions, including the incentive auction currently being designed by the FCC, can be employed to analyze such mechanisms. We compare the revenue-efficiency trade-off in an environment with private information on one side of the market versus the trade-off with private information on both sides of the market; we provide an impossibility theorem for the efficient allocation of goods using a deficit-free mechanism when there is private information on both sides of the market; we discuss practical deficit-free mechanisms for various environments with two-sided private information; and we provide a synthesis to guide market design efforts and related research going forward.</description><author>Loertscher, Simon; Marx, Leslie M.; Wilkening, Tom</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Longer-term Consequences of the Great Recession on the Lives of Europeans.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spilimbergo, Antonio
nan</description><author>Spilimbergo, Antonio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Keynes: Useful Economics for the World Economy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galbraith, James K.
nan</description><author>Galbraith, James K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Racial Realism: A Review Essay on John Skrentny's After Civil Rights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lang, Kevin
In his valuable contribution, After Civil Rights, John Skrentny shows that in many sectors of the labor market, race is used in ways that were unanticipated when the 1964 Civil Rights Act was enacted. With separate chapters on the professions and business, the public sector, media and entertainment, and the low-skill market, he demonstrates that the new racial realism is widespread, generally has some justification from social scientific research, and is usually inconsistent with judicial decisions. I review the racially realistic practices (racial matching, increasing diversity, racial signaling, and racial characteristics) and discuss their implications for labor economics and for policy. (JEL J15, J24, J71, J81, K31)</description><author>Lang, Kevin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting Samuelson's Foundations of Economic Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Backhouse, Roger E.
Paul Samuelson's Foundations of Economic Analysis played a major role in defining how economic theory was undertaken for many years after the Second World War. This paper fills out Samuelson's account of the book's origins and corrects some details, making clear his debt to E. B. Wilson and establishes that turning the thesis into a book was a long process. The contents of the book and its reception are then reviewed. (JEL A22, B20, B31)</description><author>Backhouse, Roger E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Research on Teaching Economics to Undergraduates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allgood, Sam; Walstad, William B.; Siegfried, John J.
This survey summarizes the main research findings about teaching economics to undergraduates. After briefly reviewing the history of research on undergraduate economic education, it discusses the status of the economics major-numbers and trends, goals, coursework, outcomes, and the principles courses. Some economic theory is used to explain the likely effects of pedagogical decisions of faculty and the learning choices that students make. Major results from empirical research are reviewed from the professor perspective on such topics as teaching methods, online technology, class size, and textbooks. Studies of student learning are discussed in relation to study time, grades, attendance, math aptitude, and cheating. The last section discusses changes in the composition of faculty who teach undergraduate economics and effects from changes in instructional technology and then presents findings from the research about measuring teaching effectiveness and the value of teacher training. (JEL A22, I23, J44)</description><author>Allgood, Sam; Walstad, William B.; Siegfried, John J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Industrial Organization of Health-Care Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaynor, Martin; Ho, Kate; Town, Robert J.
The U.S. health-care sector is large and growing-health-care spending in 2011 amounted to $ 2.7 trillion and 18 percent of GDP. Approximately half of health-care output is allocated via markets. In this paper, we analyze the industrial organization literature on health-care markets, focusing on the impact of competition on price, quality, and treatment decisions for health-care providers and health insurers. We conclude with a discussion of research opportunities for industrial organization economists, including opportunities created by the U.S. Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. (JEL J15, J24, J71, J81, K31)</description><author>Gaynor, Martin; Ho, Kate; Town, Robert J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Repeated Games</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cripps, Martin W.
nan</description><author>Cripps, Martin W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The United States in a Warming World: The Political Economy of Government, Business, and Public Responses to Climate Change</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, David L.
nan</description><author>Kelly, David L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Environmental Markets: A Property Rights Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harstad, Bard
nan</description><author>Harstad, Bard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Moral Hazard in Health Insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zanjani, George
nan</description><author>Zanjani, George</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Philosophy, Politics and Economics of Finance in the 21st Century: From Hubris to Disgrace</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sergi, Bruno S.
nan</description><author>Sergi, Bruno S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strained Relations: US Foreign-Exchange Operations and Monetary Policy in the Twentieth Century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frieden, Jeffry
nan</description><author>Frieden, Jeffry</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>History of Islamic Economic Thought: Contributions of Muslim Scholars to Economic Thought and Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nienhaus, Volker
nan</description><author>Nienhaus, Volker</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning from Failure: A Review of Peter Schuck's Why Government Fails So Often: And How It Can Do Better</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, David M.; Peart, Sandra J.
Peter Schuck catalogs an overwhelming list of US government failures. He points to both structural problems (culture and institutions) and incentives. Despairing of cultural change, Schuck focuses on incentives. He relies on Charles Wolf 's theory of nonmarket failures in which "internalities" replace the heavily-studied market failure from externalities (Wolf 1979). Internalities are evidence of a discord between the public goals by which a program is defended and the private goals of its administrators. What might economists contribute? We suggest that economists have neglected internalities because they take group goals as exogenously determined and we defend an alternative tradition in which group goals are endogenously determined.</description><author>Levy, David M.; Peart, Sandra J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of The Age of Sustainable Development by Jeffrey Sachs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahn, Matthew E.
How does economic science inform the study of sustainable development? In his new book, Jeffrey D. Sachs analyzes the challenges of achieving economic growth while protecting the environment and achieving an equitable distribution of resources. This review presents an overview of this ambitious book with special emphasis on the role of the objectives of local and national leaders and their incentives to pursue the sustainability agenda. Given the huge migration to cities now playing out in the developing world, special attention is paid to the role of urbanization as a cause of sustainability opportunities and challenges.</description><author>Kahn, Matthew E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Communicating Uncertainty in Official Economic Statistics: An Appraisal Fifty Years after Morgenstern</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manski, Charles F.
Federal statistical agencies in the United States and analogous agencies elsewhere commonly report official economic statistics as point estimates, without accompanying measures of error. Users of the statistics may incorrectly view them as error free or may incorrectly conjecture error magnitudes. This paper discusses strategies to mitigate misinterpretation of official statistics by communicating uncertainty to the public. Sampling error can be measured using established statistical principles. The challenge is to satisfactorily measure the various forms of nonsampling error. I find it useful to distinguish transitory statistical uncertainty, permanent statistical uncertainty, and conceptual uncertainty. I illustrate how each arises as the Bureau of Economic Analysis periodically revises GDP estimates, the Census Bureau generates household income statistics from surveys with nonresponse, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics seasonally adjusts employment statistics. I anchor my discussion of communication of uncertainty in the contribution of Oskar Morgenstern (1963a), who argued forcefully for agency publication of error estimates for official economic statistics.</description><author>Manski, Charles F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Beveridge Curve: A Survey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elsby, Michael W. L.; Michaels, Ryan; Ratner, David
Important progress has been made in economists' understanding of the Beveridge curve, from its measurement to its expression in canonical labor market models. Yet enduring puzzles remain. Chief among these are the empirical role of vacancies in the recruitment process; the amplitude, comovement, and persistence of cyclical unemployment-vacancy dynamics; and the sources of lateral shifts in the Beveridge curve. The synthesis of these themes identifies several priorities for ongoing research, including the role of entry costs into vacancy creation in shaping Beveridge dynamics; the cyclicality of search intensity, both off and on the job, and its relation to participation and job-to-job transitions; the theory and measurement of mismatch; and the sources of hysteresis in unemployment flows.</description><author>Elsby, Michael W. L.; Michaels, Ryan; Ratner, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Health and the Economy in the United States from 1750 to the Present</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Costa, Dora L.
I discuss the health transition in the United States, bringing new data to bear on health indicators and investigating the changing relationship between health, income, and the environment. I argue that scientific advances played an outsize role and that health improvements were largest among the poor. Health improvements were not a precondition for modern economic growth. The gains to health are largest when the economy has moved from "brawn" to "brains" because this is when the wage returns to education are high, leading the healthy to obtain more education. More education may improve use of health knowledge, producing a virtuous cycle.</description><author>Costa, Dora L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distribution and Growth after Keynes: A Post-Keynesian Guide.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harvey, John
nan</description><author>Harvey, John</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Collective Goods, Voluntary Contributions, and Fundraising.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buchholz, Wolfgang
nan</description><author>Buchholz, Wolfgang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing the Euro Area Debt Crisis.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Razin, Assaf
nan</description><author>Razin, Assaf</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vanity Economics: An Economic Exploration of Sex, Marriage and Family.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertocchi, Graziella
nan</description><author>Bertocchi, Graziella</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Experimenting with Social Norms: Fairness and Punishment in Cross-Cultural Perspective.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, Jeffrey V.
nan</description><author>Butler, Jeffrey V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Food Price Volatility.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tarp, Finn
nan</description><author>Tarp, Finn</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Super Golfonomics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flood, Robert
nan</description><author>Flood, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Microsoft Antitrust Cases: Competition Policy for the Twenty-First Century.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rubinfeld, Daniel
nan</description><author>Rubinfeld, Daniel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Immigrant Networks and Social Capital.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sabatini, Fabio
nan</description><author>Sabatini, Fabio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Long Shadow: Family Background, Disadvantaged Urban Youth, and the Transition to Adulthood.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foley, Kelly
nan</description><author>Foley, Kelly</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Rise and Decline of Faculty Governance: Professionalization and the Modern American University</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Robert A.
nan</description><author>Becker, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Science, Economics, and Politics of Global Climate Change: A Review of The Climate Casino by William Nordhaus</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jaffe, Adam B.; Kerr, Suzi
The problem of global climate change presents overwhelming factual, analytical, and normative challenges. Nordhaus surveys this terrain bravely and mostly successfully. He explains the scientific/economic consensus that the planet is warming, that people are responsible, that the consequences are bad, and that immediate action is benefit/cost justified. He also discusses the efficient policy response, and the challenges of achieving coordinated global action. His approach is mostly that of standard neoclassical economics, and some of the limitations of that paradigm in this context are not addressed. But overall, The Climate Casino provides an excellent self-contained introduction to the subject.</description><author>Jaffe, Adam B.; Kerr, Suzi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade Unions in Western Europe: Hard Times, Hard Choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Budd, John W.
nan</description><author>Budd, John W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Legacies of the War on Poverty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Watson, Tara
nan</description><author>Watson, Tara</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insurance and Behavioral Economics: Improving Decisions in the Most Misunderstood Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendren, Nathaniel
nan</description><author>Hendren, Nathaniel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Conflict: Theory and Empirical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anbarci, Nejat
nan</description><author>Anbarci, Nejat</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Index Number Problem: Construction Theorems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balk, Bert M.
nan</description><author>Balk, Bert M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advanced Introduction to the Austrian School of Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garrison, Roger W.
nan</description><author>Garrison, Roger W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Documents Related to John Maynard Keynes, Institutionalism at Chicago &amp; Frank H. Knight, vol 31-B</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burczak, Theodore
nan</description><author>Burczak, Theodore</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Secrets of Economics Editors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moffitt, Robert
nan</description><author>Moffitt, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Angus Deaton's The Great Escape: Health, Wealth, and the Origins of Inequality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weil, David N.
This book explores the relationship between the material standard of living and health, both across countries and over time. Above all, Deaton is interested in the question of whether income growth contributes significantly to better health. His answer is no: saving lives in poor countries is not expensive, and there are many episodes of massive health improvements in the absence of income growth. As an alternative, he argues that the cross-sectional correlation between health and income is induced by variation in institutional quality, while over time, parallel improvements in income and health have been a result of advancing knowledge.</description><author>Weil, David N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of William Easterly's The Tyranny of Experts: Economists, Dictators, and the Forgotten Rights of the Poor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, Carol
William Easterly marshals yet another brilliant critique of established development policies, with a focus on the experts' excessive focus on state-led policies and goals (a la Myrdal) and ignorance of bottom-up solutions, including technology and individual rights (a la Hayek). It suggests a world where success occurs in spite of nation-states. Yet not all bottom-up leads to success, and the worst disasters, as in civil violence, occur where states fail. Easterly highlights the important links between success and individual freedom and opportunity. He fails to note that myriad impoverished individuals cannot exercise these freedoms due to low expectations or compromised rights.</description><author>Graham, Carol</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jon Elster's Securities against Misrule: Juries, Assemblies, Elections: A Review Essay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Austen-Smith, David
The standard economic approach to designing institutions for collective decision making recognizes individuals' strategically rational motivations for misrepresentation and asks how best, given an objective function, to design a set of incentives and constraints to internalize or negate such motivations. Securities Against Misrule offers, in the author's phrase, an "essay in persuasion" to the effect that such an approach is fundamentally misguided. Instead, Elster argues for a behavioral approach centered on designing institutions for good decision making, rather than good outcomes, by individuals whose actions are chronically subject to emotional, self-interested, and prejudicial distortions.</description><author>Austen-Smith, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robert E. Lucas Jr.'s Collected Papers on Monetary Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sargent, Thomas J.
This paper is a critical review of and a reader's guide to a collection of papers by Robert E. Lucas, Jr. about fruitful ways of using general equilibrium theories to understand measured economic aggregates. These beautifully written and wisely argued papers integrated macroeconomics, microeconomics, finance, and econometrics in ways that restructured big parts of macroeconomic research.</description><author>Sargent, Thomas J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Envirodevonomics: A Research Agenda for an Emerging Field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenstone, Michael; Jack, B. Kelsey
Environmental quality in many developing countries is poor and generates substantial health and productivity costs. However, the few existing measures of marginal willingness to pay (MWTP) for environmental quality improvements indicate low valuations by affected households. This paper argues that this seeming paradox is the central puzzle at the intersection of environmental and development economics: Given poor environmental quality and high health burdens in developing countries, why is MWTP seemingly so low? We develop a conceptual framework for understanding this puzzle and propose four potential explanations for why environmental quality is so poor: (1) due to low income levels, individuals value increases in income more than marginal improvements in environmental quality; (2) the marginal costs of environmental quality improvements are high; (3) political economy factors undermine efficient policymaking; and (4) market failures such as weak property rights and missing capital markets distort MWTP for environmental quality. We review the literature on each explanation and discuss how the framework applies to climate change, which is perhaps the most important issue at the intersection of environment and development economics. The paper concludes with a list of promising and unanswered research questions for the emerging sub-field of "envirodevonomics."</description><author>Greenstone, Michael; Jack, B. Kelsey</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency Politics: The Political Economy of Exchange Rate Policy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Benjamin J.
nan</description><author>Cohen, Benjamin J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavioral Contract Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koszegi, Botond
This review provides a critical survey of psychology-and-economics ("behavioral-economics") research in contract theory. First, I introduce the theories of individual decision making most frequently used in behavioral contract theory, and formally illustrate some of their implications in contracting settings. Second, I provide a more comprehensive (but informal) survey of the psychology-and-economics work on classical contract-theoretic topics: moral hazard, screening, mechanism design, and incomplete contracts. I also summarize research on a new topic spawned by psychology and economics, exploitative contracting, that studies contracts designed primarily to take advantage of agent mistakes.</description><author>Koszegi, Botond</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News-Driven Business Cycles: Insights and Challenges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beaudry, Paul; Portier, Franck
There is a widespread belief that changes in expectations may be an important independent driver of economic fluctuations. The news view of business cycles offers a formalization of this perspective. In this paper we discuss mechanisms by which changes in agents' information, due to the arrival of news, can cause business cycle fluctuations driven by expectational change, and we review the empirical evidence aimed at evaluating their relevance. In particular, we highlight how the literature on news and business cycles offers a coherent way of thinking about aggregate fluctuations, while at the same time we emphasize the many challenges that must be addressed before a proper assessment of the role of news in business cycles can be established.</description><author>Beaudry, Paul; Portier, Franck</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>F. A. Hayek and the Modern Economy: Economic Organization and Activity.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horwitz, Steven
nan</description><author>Horwitz, Steven</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Defending the History of Economic Thought.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herfeld, Catherine
nan</description><author>Herfeld, Catherine</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mechanism and Causality in Biology and Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>LeRoy, Stephen
nan</description><author>LeRoy, Stephen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Review of Peter Temin's The Roman Market Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Velde, Francois
Herein, I review Peter Temin's book, The Roman Market Economy, and take the occasion to alert economists to the exciting work that is being done and could be done in the economic history of the ancient world.</description><author>Velde, Francois</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's the Future of Public Higher Education? A Review Essay on Gary C. Fethke and Andrew J. Policano's Public No More: A New Path to Excellence for America's Public Universities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ehrenberg, Ronald G.
Gary Fethke and Andrew Policano's book Public No More: A New Path to Excellence for America's Public Universities paints a picture of a future for public research universities that is very different than what many people will want to see. Their message is that the financial and governance models under which public universities have operated have broken down and that new models are required. While I do not always agree with their prescriptions, I argue that private research universities face many of the same issues as their public counterparts and that this book deserves to be widely read by all people concerned with the future of American higher education.</description><author>Ehrenberg, Ronald G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Ethics of Efficient Markets and Commons Tragedies: A Review of John Broome's Climate Matters: Ethics in a Warming World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nordhaus, William
What are the ethical implications of our contributions to global warming on an individual level? In his extended essay, John Broome analyzes the moral implications of our imposing damages on future generations through our greenhouse-gas emissions. He argues that we as individuals owe restitution to those who are in the future damaged by these unjust acts. He suggests that restitution can be accomplished by completely offsetting emissions and thereby having a zero carbon footprint. This review examines the force of his arguments and suggests that offsetting emissions on an individual basis is an imperfect substitute for collective action or more encompassing contributions to those hurt by our externalities.</description><author>Nordhaus, William</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategy in History and (versus?) in Economics: A Review of Lawrence Freedman's Strategy: A History</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dixit, Avinash
This essay reviews Lawrence Freedman's book Strategy: A History. The main themes-definitions, strategies in war, business, politics, and revolutions-are overviewed. The value of game-theoretic thinking for practical strategy is assessed. A critical discussion of some concepts and dichotomies emphasized by Freedman, e. g., strategy is governed by the starting point, not the end point, and of the role of stories and scripts in strategy, follows.</description><author>Dixit, Avinash</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Macroeconomics of Trend Inflation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ascari, Guido; Sbordone, Argia M.
Most macroeconomic models for monetary policy analysis are approximated around a zero inflation steady state, but most central banks target an inflation rate of about 2 percent. Many economists have recently proposed even higher inflation targets to reduce the incidence of the zero lower bound constraint on monetary policy. In this survey, we show that the conduct of monetary policy should be analyzed by appropriately accounting for the positive trend inflation targeted by policymakers. We first review empirical research on the evolution and dynamics of U.S. trend inflation and some proposed new measures to assess the volatility and persistence of trend-based inflation gaps. We then construct a Generalized New Keynesian model that accounts for a positive trend inflation. In this model, an increase in trend inflation is associated with a more volatile and unstable economy and tends to destabilize inflation expectations. This analysis offers a note of caution regarding recent proposals to address the existing zero lower bound problem by raising the long-run inflation target.</description><author>Ascari, Guido; Sbordone, Argia M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Game-Changer: Game Theory and the Art of Transforming Strategic Situations.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brooks, Ben
nan</description><author>Brooks, Ben</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond GDP: Measuring Welfare and Assessing Sustainability.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asheim, Geir B.
nan</description><author>Asheim, Geir B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Price Response to New Information: The Effects of Conservatism Bias and Representativeness Heuristic.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Jianfeng
nan</description><author>Yu, Jianfeng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mixed Fortunes: An Economic History of China, Russia, and the West.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milanovic, Branko
nan</description><author>Milanovic, Branko</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Power to the People: Energy in Europe over the Last Five Centuries.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fouquet, Roger
nan</description><author>Fouquet, Roger</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nature in the Balance: The Economics of Biodiversity.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weitzman, Martin L.
nan</description><author>Weitzman, Martin L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US Energy Policy and the Pursuit of Failure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckaus, Richard S.
nan</description><author>Eckaus, Richard S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Of Medicines and Markets: Intellectual Property and Human Rights in the Free Trade Era.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wright, Brian Davern
nan</description><author>Wright, Brian Davern</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Global Debt Crisis: Haunting U. S. and European Federalism.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Troiano, Ugo
nan</description><author>Troiano, Ugo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The House of Rothschild in Spain, 1812-1941.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Irigoin, Alejandra
nan</description><author>Irigoin, Alejandra</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Creation of Inequality: How Our Prehistoric Ancestors Set the Stage for Monarchy, Slavery, and Empire.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smith, Eric Alden
nan</description><author>Smith, Eric Alden</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The People's Network: The Political Economy of the Telephone in the Gilded Age.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nonnenmacher, Tomas
nan</description><author>Nonnenmacher, Tomas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Baseball on Trial: The Origin of Baseball's Antitrust Exemption.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zimbalist, Andrew
nan</description><author>Zimbalist, Andrew</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>American Railroads: Decline and Renaissance in the Twentieth Century.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pagano, Anthony M.
nan</description><author>Pagano, Anthony M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Information Security and Privacy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenstein, Shane
nan</description><author>Greenstein, Shane</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reflections on Judging.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Teitelbaum, Joshua C.
nan</description><author>Teitelbaum, Joshua C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax Systems.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albouy, David
nan</description><author>Albouy, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Review Essay on Charles F. Manski's Public Policy in an Uncertain World: Analysis and Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geweke, John
Public policy setting often involves quantitative choices with quantitative outcomes. Yet unqualified statements about the precise consequences of alternative choices characterize much of the policy analysis bearing on these decisions. Public Policy in an Uncertain World: Analysis and Decisions by Charles F. Manski characterizes and richly illustrates the nature of this unwarranted certitude. It details specific constructive alternatives on which the economics profession has achieved varying degrees of consensus. Those in our profession charged with the education of future policy analysts should consider using it and how to round out its presentation of decision making from their own perspective.</description><author>Geweke, John</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Great American City: Chicago and the Enduring Neighborhood Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartley, Daniel
nan</description><author>Hartley, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Keys to the City: How Economics, Institutions, Social Interactions, and Politics Shape Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ioannides, Yannis M.
nan</description><author>Ioannides, Yannis M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Importance of Financial Literacy: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lusardi, Annamaria; Mitchell, Olivia S.
This paper undertakes an assessment of a rapidly growing body of economic research on financial literacy. We start with an overview of theoretical research, which casts financial knowledge as a form of investment in human capital. Endogenizing financial knowledge has important implications for welfare, as well as policies intended to enhance levels of financial knowledge in the larger population. Next, we draw on recent surveys to establish how much (or how little) people know and identify the least financially savvy population subgroups. This is followed by an examination of the impact of financial literacy on economic decision making in the United States and elsewhere. While the literature is still young, conclusions may be drawn about the effects and consequences of financial illiteracy and what works to remedy these gaps. A final section offers thoughts on what remains to be learned if researchers are to better inform theoretical and empirical models as well as public policy.</description><author>Lusardi, Annamaria; Mitchell, Olivia S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Evidence on Inflation Expectations in the New Keynesian Phillips Curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mavroeidis, Sophocles; Plagborg-Moller, Mikkel; Stock, James H.
We review the main identification strategies and empirical evidence on the role of expectations in the New Keynesian Phillips curve, paying particular attention to the issue of weak identification. Our goal is to provide a clear understanding of the role of expectations that integrates across the different papers and specifications in the literature. We discuss the properties of the various limited-information econometric methods used in the literature and provide explanations of why they produce conflicting results. Using a common dataset and a flexible empirical approach, we find that researchers are faced with substantial specification uncertainty, as different combinations of various a priori reasonable specification choices give rise to a vast set of point estimates. Moreover, given a specification, estimation is subject to considerable sampling uncertainty due to weak identification. We highlight the assumptions that seem to matter most for identification and the configuration of point estimates. We conclude that the literature has reached a limit on how much can be learned about the New Keynesian Phillips curve from aggregate macroeconomic time series. New identification approaches and new datasets are needed to reach an empirical consensus.</description><author>Mavroeidis, Sophocles; Plagborg-Moller, Mikkel; Stock, James H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuing Climate Change Mitigation: Applying Stated Preferences in the Presence of Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fezzi, Carlo
nan</description><author>Fezzi, Carlo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>One Billion Hungry: Can We Feed the World?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Timmer, C. Peter
nan</description><author>Timmer, C. Peter</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cuba under Raul Castro: Assessing the Reforms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Betancourt, Roger R.
nan</description><author>Betancourt, Roger R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The New Science of Cities by Michael Batty: The Opinion of an Economist</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thisse, Jacques-Francois
Cities are the cradle of a wide range of cultural, social, and technological innovations that are at the heart of modern economic growth and development. Half of humanity today lives in cities but, until the last two decades, economists have paid much less attention to cities than have other social scientists. By contrast, geographers have long studied the role of cities in human affairs. Michael Batty, a distinguished scholar in the field of human geography, has recently written The New Science of Cities, a synthesis of his work and of some other prominent urban geographers. A review of his book is the first objective of this essay. The second is to discuss and compare the tools and concepts developed by urban economists with those of urban geographers in the hope of triggering a fruitful debate between those two groups of social scientists.</description><author>Thisse, Jacques-Francois</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Giving Kids a Fair Chance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loken, Katrine V.
nan</description><author>Loken, Katrine V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From Divergence to Convergence: Reevaluating the History Behind China's Economic Boom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandt, Loren; Ma, Debin; Rawski, Thomas G.
China's long-term economic dynamics pose a formidable challenge to economic historians. The Qing Empire (1644-1911), the world's largest national economy before 1800, experienced a tripling of population during the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries with no signs of diminishing per capita income. While the timing remains in dispute, a vast gap emerged between newly rich industrial nations and China's lagging economy in the wake of the Industrial Revolution. Only with an unprecedented growth spurt beginning in the late 1970s did this great divergence separating China from the global leaders substantially diminish, allowing China to regain its former standing among the world's largest economies. This essay develops an integrated framework for understanding that entire history, including both the divergence and the recent convergent trend. We explain how deeply embedded political and economic institutions that contributed to a long process of extensive growth before 1800 subsequently prevented China from capturing the benefits associated with the Industrial Revolution. During the twentieth century, the gradual erosion of these historic constraints and of new obstacles erected by socialist planning eventually opened the door to China's current boom. Our analysis links China's recent development to important elements of its past, while using recent success to provide fresh perspectives on the critical obstacles undermining earlier modernization efforts, and their eventual removal.</description><author>Brandt, Loren; Ma, Debin; Rawski, Thomas G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Flourishing Economist: A Review Essay on Edmund Phelps's Mass Flourishing: How Grassroots Innovation Created Jobs, Challenge, and Change</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mokyr, Joel
In his recent Mass Flourishings, Edmund Phelps makes a strong and eloquent plea for a more dynamic economy, which he sees not only as a key for economic performance, but also as necessary for what he calls "the good life." This review essay evaluates those claims in the light of economic history.</description><author>Mokyr, Joel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rethinking the Principles of Bank Regulation: A Review of Admati and Hellwig's The Bankers' New Clothes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Myerson, Roger B.
In an important new book, Anat Admati and Martin Hellwig raise broad critical questions about bank regulation. These questions are reviewed and discussed here, with a focus on how the problems of maintaining a stable financial system depend on fundamental problems of information and incentives in financial intermediation. It is argued that financial regulatory reforms can be reliably effective only when their basic principles are understood by informed citizens, and that Admati and Hellwig's book is a major contribution toward this goal, as it clearly lays out the essential case for requiring banks to have more equity.</description><author>Myerson, Roger B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Remembering Inflation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ireland, Peter N.
nan</description><author>Ireland, Peter N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value Solutions in Cooperative Games</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edhan, Omer
nan</description><author>Edhan, Omer</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Chronicles from the Field: The Townsend Thai Project</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glewwe, Paul
nan</description><author>Glewwe, Paul</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimation and Inference in Nonparametric Frontier Models: Recent Developments and Perspectives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martins-Filho, Carlos
nan</description><author>Martins-Filho, Carlos</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cuban Economists on the Cuban Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Betancourt, Roger R.
nan</description><author>Betancourt, Roger R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Rediscovery of Classical Economics: Adaptation, Complexity and Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dosi, Giovanni
nan</description><author>Dosi, Giovanni</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Emotions and Consumption Behaviour</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckel, Catherine C.
nan</description><author>Eckel, Catherine C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankers, Bureaucrats, and Central Bank Politics: The Myth of Neutrality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masciandaro, Donato
nan</description><author>Masciandaro, Donato</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Politics and Foreign Direct Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajan, Ramkishen S.
nan</description><author>Rajan, Ramkishen S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Crises, 1929 to the Present</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Temesvary, Judit
nan</description><author>Temesvary, Judit</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Bubbles: Financial Crises and the Failure of American Democracy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sylla, Richard
nan</description><author>Sylla, Richard</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Political Economy of Human Happiness: How Voters' Choices Determine the Quality of Life</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, Carol
nan</description><author>Graham, Carol</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Immigration and Labor Market Mobility in Israel, 1990 to 2009</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sauer, Robert M.
nan</description><author>Sauer, Robert M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Bretton Woods Transcripts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Richard N.
nan</description><author>Cooper, Richard N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prometheus Shackled: Goldsmith Banks and England's Financial Revolution after 1700</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murphy, Anne L.
nan</description><author>Murphy, Anne L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Addressing Global Environmental Externalities: Transaction Costs Considerations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Libecap, Gary D.
Is there a way to understand why some global environmental externalities are addressed effectively, whereas others are not? The transaction costs of defining the property rights to mitigation benefits and costs is a useful framework for such analysis. This approach views international cooperation as a contractual process among country leaders to assign those property rights. Leaders cooperate when it serves domestic interests to do so. The demand for property rights comes from those who value and stand to gain from multilateral action. Property rights are supplied by international agreements that specify resource access and use, assign costs and benefits including outlining the size and duration of compensating transfer payments, and determining who will pay and who will receive them. Four factors raise the transaction costs of assigning property rights: (i) scientific uncertainty regarding mitigation benefits and costs; (ii) varying preferences and perceptions across heterogeneous populations; (iii) asymmetric information; and (iv) the extent of compliance and new entry. These factors are used to examine the role of transaction costs in the establishment and allocation of property rights to provide globally valued national parks, implement the Convention on the International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora, execute the Montreal Protocol to manage emissions that damage the stratospheric ozone layer, set limits on harvest of highly-migratory ocean fish stocks, and control greenhouse gas emissions.</description><author>Libecap, Gary D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Limits of Inference with Theory: A Review of Wolpin (2013)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rust, John
This essay reviews Kenneth I. Wolpin's (2013) monograph The Limits of Inference without Theory, which arose from lectures he presented at the Cowles Foundation in 2010 in honor of Tjalling Koopmans. While I readily agree with Wolpin's basic premise that empirical work that eschews the role of economic theory faces unnecessary self-imposed limits relative to empirical work that embraces and tries to test and improve economic theory, it is important to be aware that the use of economic theory is not a panacea. I point out that there are also serious limits to inference with theory: 1) there may be no truly "structural" (policy invariant) parameters, a key assumption underpinning the structural econometric approach that Wolpin and the Cowles Foundation have championed; 2) there is a curse of dimensionality that makes it very difficult for us to elucidate the detailed implications of economic theories, which is necessary to empirically implement and test these theories; 3) there is an identification problem that makes it impossible to decide between competing theories without imposing ad hoc auxiliary assumptions (such as parametric functional form assumptions); and 4) there is a problem of multiplicity and indeterminacy of equilibria that limits the predictive empirical content of many economic theories. I conclude that though these are very challenging problems, I agree with Wolpin and the Cowles Foundation that economists have far more to gain by trying to incorporate economic theory into empirical work and test and improve our theories than by rejecting theory and presuming that all interesting economic issues can be answered by well-designed controlled, randomized experiments and assuming that difficult questions of causality and evaluation of alternative hypothetical policies can be resolved by simply allowing the "data to speak for itself."</description><author>Rust, John</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Manufacturing Morals: The Values of Silence in Business School Education</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornell, Nicolas
nan</description><author>Cornell, Nicolas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Oxford Handbook of Post-Keynesian Economics, vol 1. Theory and Origins</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pressman, Steven
nan</description><author>Pressman, Steven</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Oxford Handbook of Post-Keynesian Economics, vol 2. Critiques and Methodology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pressman, Steven
nan</description><author>Pressman, Steven</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Econophysics of Agent-Based Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>LeBaron, Blake
nan</description><author>LeBaron, Blake</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economy of Words: Communicative Imperatives in Central Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fligstein, Neil
nan</description><author>Fligstein, Neil</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Food Security and Sociopolitical Stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alderman, Harold
nan</description><author>Alderman, Harold</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size, Risk, and Governance in European Banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaufman, George G.
nan</description><author>Kaufman, George G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Crisis in Retrospect: Explanations by Great Economists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colander, David
nan</description><author>Colander, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Behavior of Federal Judges: A Theoretical and Empirical Study of Rational Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayres, Ian
nan</description><author>Ayres, Ian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing Wimbledon: The Power of Statistics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wooders, John
nan</description><author>Wooders, John</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shaping Jazz: Cities, Labels, and the Global Emergence of an Art Form</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horrace, William C.
nan</description><author>Horrace, William C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Run to the Pennant: A Multiple Equilibria Approach to Professional Sports Leagues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Solow, John
nan</description><author>Solow, John</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Made in the USA: The Rise and Retreat of American Manufacturing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Syverson, Chad
nan</description><author>Syverson, Chad</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Staying Afloat: Risk and Uncertainty in Spanish Atlantic World Trade, 1760-1820</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thomson, James
nan</description><author>Thomson, James</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cities of Commerce: The Institutional Foundations of International Trade in the Low Countries, 1250-1650</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roessner, Philipp Robinson
nan</description><author>Roessner, Philipp Robinson</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>River of Dark Dreams: Slavery and Empire in the Cotton Kingdom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wright, Gavin
nan</description><author>Wright, Gavin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Oxford Handbook of the Russian Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pyle, William
nan</description><author>Pyle, William</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Do We Learn from the Weather? The New Climate-Economy Literature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dell, Melissa; Jones, Benjamin F.; Olken, Benjamin A.
A rapidly growing body of research applies panel methods to examine how temperature, precipitation, and windstorms influence economic outcomes. These studies focus on changes in weather realizations over time within a given spatial area and demonstrate impacts on agricultural output, industrial output, labor productivity, energy demand, health, conflict, and economic growth, among other outcomes. By harnessing exogenous variation over time within a given spatial unit, these studies help credibly identify (i) the breadth of channels linking weather and the economy, (ii) heterogeneous treatment effects across different types of locations, and (iii) nonlinear effects of weather variables. This paper reviews the new literature with two purposes. First, we summarize recent work, providing a guide to its methodologies, datasets, and findings. Second, we consider applications of the new literature, including insights for the "damage function" within models that seek to assess the potential economic effects of future climate change.</description><author>Dell, Melissa; Jones, Benjamin F.; Olken, Benjamin A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Perspectives on Emotions in Finance: The Sociology of Confidence, Fear and Betrayal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grosskopf, Brit
nan</description><author>Grosskopf, Brit</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Choice between Formal and Informal Intellectual Property: A Review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hall, Bronwyn; Helmers, Christian; Rogers, Mark; Sena, Vania
We survey the economic literature, both theoretical and empirical, on the choice of intellectual property protection by firms. Our focus is on the trade-offs between using patents and disclosing versus the use of secrecy, although we also look briefly at the use of other means of formal intellectual property protection.</description><author>Hall, Bronwyn; Helmers, Christian; Rogers, Mark; Sena, Vania</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Changing Role of Government in Financing Health Care: An International Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stabile, Mark; Thomson, Sarah
This paper explores the changing role of government involvement in health care financing policy outside the United States. It provides a review of the economics literature in this area to elucidate the implications of recent policy changes on efficiency, costs, and quality. Our review reveals that there has been some convergence in policies adopted across countries to improve financing incentives and encourage efficient use of health services. In the case of risk pooling, all countries with competing pools experience similar difficulties with selection and are adopting more sophisticated forms of risk adjustment. In the case of hospital competition, the key drivers of success appear to be what is competed on and measurable, rather than whether the system is public or private. In the case of both the success of performance-related pay for providers and issues resulting from wait times, evidence differs within and across jurisdictions. However, the evidence does suggest that some governments have effectively reduced wait times when they have chosen explicitly to focus on achieving this goal. Many countries are exploring new ways of generating revenues for health care to enable them to cope with significant cost growth, but there is little evidence to suggest that collection mechanisms alone are effective in managing the cost or quality of care.</description><author>Stabile, Mark; Thomson, Sarah</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Return of "Patrimonial Capitalism": A Review of Thomas Piketty's Capital in the Twenty-First Century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milanovic, Branko
Capital in the Twenty-First Century by Thomas Piketty provides a unified theory of the functioning of the capitalist economy by linking theories of economic growth and functional and personal income distributions. It argues, based on the long-run historical data series, that the forces of economic divergence (including rising income inequality) tend to dominate in capitalism. It regards the twentieth century as an exception to this rule and proposes policies that would make capitalism sustainable in the twenty-first century.</description><author>Milanovic, Branko</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jacob Viner: Lectures in Economics 301</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fiorito, Luca; Nerozzi, Sebastiano
nan</description><author>Fiorito, Luca; Nerozzi, Sebastiano</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Michal Kalecki: An Intellectual Biography: Vol 1, Rendezvous in Cambridge 1899-1939</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Assous, Michael
nan</description><author>Assous, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Great Depression of the 1930s: Lessons for Today</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jaremski, Matthew
nan</description><author>Jaremski, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Other Welfare: Supplemental Security Income and US Social Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daly, Mary C.
nan</description><author>Daly, Mary C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government Failure: Society, Markets and Rules</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vogelsang, Ingo
nan</description><author>Vogelsang, Ingo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Open Budgets: The Political Economy of Transparency, Participation, and Accountability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hodess, Robin
nan</description><author>Hodess, Robin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cartels, Competition and Public Procurement: Law and Economics Approaches to Bid Rigging</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pinto, Brijesh P.; Williams, Michael A.
nan</description><author>Pinto, Brijesh P.; Williams, Michael A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Paying Out-of-Pocket for Drugs, Diagnostics and Medical Services: A Study of Households in Three Indian States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levine, David I.
nan</description><author>Levine, David I.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Biological Consequences of Socioeconomic Inequalities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Urzua, Sergio
nan</description><author>Urzua, Sergio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Out of Print: Newspapers, Journalism and the Business of News in the Digital Age</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>George, Lisa M.
nan</description><author>George, Lisa M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Electricity Markets: Theory and Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McRae, Shaun
nan</description><author>McRae, Shaun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Casinonomics: The Socioeconomic Impacts of the Casino Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinols, Earl L.
nan</description><author>Grinols, Earl L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Climate Economics: The State of the Art</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McKibbin, Warwick
nan</description><author>McKibbin, Warwick</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disasters and the Networked Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hallegatte, Stephane
nan</description><author>Hallegatte, Stephane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arctic Economics in the 21st Century: The Benefits and Costs of Cold</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, Michael A.
nan</description><author>Goldstein, Michael A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Korean Political and Economic Development: Crisis, Security, and Institutional Rebalancing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Root, Hilton L.
nan</description><author>Root, Hilton L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nine Facts about Top Journals in Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Card, David; DellaVigna, Stefano
How has publishing in top economics journals changed since 1970? Using a data set that combines information on all articles published in the top-five journals from 1970 to 2012 with their Google Scholar citations, we identify nine key trends. First, annual submissions to the top-five journals nearly doubled from 1990 to 2012. Second, the total number of articles published in these journals actually declined from 400 per year in the late 1970s to 300 per year most recently. As a result, the acceptance rate has fallen from 15 percent to 6 percent, with potential implications for the career progression of young scholars. Third, one journal, the American Economic Review, now accounts for 40 percent of top-five publications, up from 25 percent in the 1970s. Fourth, recently published papers are on average three times longer than they were in the 1970s, contributing to the relative shortage of journal space. Fifth, the number of authors per paper has increased from 1.3 in 1970 to 2.3 in 2012, partly offsetting the fall in the number of articles per year. Sixth, citations for top-five publications are high: among papers published in the late 1990s, the median number of Google Scholar citations is 200. Seventh, the ranking of journals by citations has remained relatively stable, with the notable exception of the Quarterly Journal of Economics, which climbed from fourth place to first place over the past three decades. Eighth, citation counts are significantly higher for longer papers and those written by more coauthors. Ninth, although the fraction of articles from different fields published in the top five has remained relatively stable, there are important cohort trends in the citations received by papers from different fields, with rising citations to more recent papers in Development and International, and declining citations to recent papers in Econometrics and Theory. (JEL A14)</description><author>Card, David; DellaVigna, Stefano</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Six Decades of Top Economics Publishing: Who and How?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hamermesh, Daniel S.
Presenting data on all full-length articles in the three top general economics journals for one year in each decade 1960s-2010s, I analyze changes in patterns of coauthorship, age structure and methodology, and their possible causes. The distribution of number of authors has shifted steadily rightward. In the last two decades, the fraction of older authors has almost quadrupled. Top journals are publishing many fewer papers that represent pure theory, regardless of subfield, somewhat less empirical work based on publicly available data sets, and many more empirical studies based on data collected by the author(s) or on laboratory or field experiments. (JEL A14)</description><author>Hamermesh, Daniel S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Power and Economic Policy: Theory, Analysis, and Empirical Applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Gorter, Harry
nan</description><author>de Gorter, Harry</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncertainty Measures for Economics Journal Impact Factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stern, David I.
Academic economists appear to be intensely interested in rankings of journals, institutions, and individuals. Yet there is little discussion of the uncertainty associated with these rankings. To illustrate the uncertainty associated with citations-based rankings, I compute the standard error of the impact factor for all economics journals with a five-year impact factor in the 2011 Journal Citations Report. I use these to derive confidence intervals for the impact factors as well as ranges of possible rank for a subset of thirty journals. I find that the impact factors of the top two journals are well defined and set these journals apart in a clearly defined group. An elite group of 9-11 mainstream journals can also be fairly reliably distinguished. The four bottom ranked journals are also fairly clearly set apart. For the remainder of the distribution, confidence intervals overlap and rankings are quite uncertain. (JEL A14)</description><author>Stern, David I.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Craft of Economics: Lessons from the Heckscher-Ohlin Framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Markusen, James R.
nan</description><author>Markusen, James R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Schelling's Game Theory: How to Make Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massey, Cade
nan</description><author>Massey, Cade</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Saving for Retirement: Intention, Context, and Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sunden, Annika
nan</description><author>Sunden, Annika</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inequality and Instability: A Study of the World Economy Just Before the Great Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milanovic, Branko
nan</description><author>Milanovic, Branko</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preference, Value, Choice, and Welfare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sugden, Robert
nan</description><author>Sugden, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade Policy Disaster: Lessons from the 1930s</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evenett, Simon J.
nan</description><author>Evenett, Simon J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuing an Entrepreneurial Enterprise</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thurik, Roy
nan</description><author>Thurik, Roy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>China's Remarkable Economic Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holz, Carsten A.
nan</description><author>Holz, Carsten A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does What You Export Matter? In Search of Empirical Guidance for Industrial Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levchenko, Andrei A.
nan</description><author>Levchenko, Andrei A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Rate and Direction of Inventive Activity Revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grover, David
nan</description><author>Grover, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>