<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Portfolio Management2</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Explanations for the Volatility Effect: An Overview Based on the CAPM Assumptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blitz, David; Falkenstein, Eric; van Vliet, Pim
The capital asset pricing model (CAPM) predicts a positive relation between risk and return, but empirical studies find that the actual relation is flat, or even negative. This article provides a broad overview of explanations for this volatility effect and categorizes each explanation according to the CAPM assumption to which it relates. Various explanations relate to investor behavior that is rational, given exogenous incentive structures or constraints, which may explain why the volatility effect has been so persistent over time. The authors argue that, although the CAPM may be bad at explaining reality, addressing the reasons for its failure could actually be a normative arbitrage opportunity.</description><author>Blitz, David; Falkenstein, Eric; van Vliet, Pim</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-Frequency Runs and Flash-Crash Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aldridge, Irene
This article describes research into the short-term nature of movements in price data. The study's key finding is that asset returns do not evolve at the Gaussian increments commonly assumed by continuous pricing models. Instead, prices exhibit strong autocorrelation, often resulting in predictable one-directional sequences, or runs. These runs are more pronounced ahead of market crashes. Identifying these runs can help predict impending flash crashes as much as a day before a crash. The research further contributes to asset pricing and derivatives literature by deriving discreet and continuous closed-form expressions for the probability of flash crashes.</description><author>Aldridge, Irene</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting US Bond Returns: A Practitioner's Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mylnikov, George
This article presents a practitioner's view of the evidence on the predictability of U.S. bond returns, using forward rates found in the academic literature. The author examines this evidence from a dual perspective: statistical and economic. He finds that the regressions of monthly returns of U.S. Treasury futures on the set of three forward rates, with one-, five- and ten-year expirations, are statistically viable. An implementation of these forecasts as an investment strategy shows that it is historically profitable on a risk-adjusted basis. Furthermore, the author demonstrates the importance of the dual approach to assessing predictability, by providing an example of a slightly modified version of the main model that is more intuitive, more parsimonious, and statistically more robust, yet it fails to exhibit better economic performance.</description><author>Mylnikov, George</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recent Trends in Equity Portfolio Construction Analytics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pachamanova, Dessislava A.; Fabozzi, Frank J.
Portfolio analytics is critical for identifying investment opportunities, keeping portfolios aligned with investment objectives, and monitoring portfolio risk and performance. Analytics-based portfolio management lets investment managers filter information quickly, take advantage of statistical arbitrage opportunities, and deal with inefficiencies, such as transaction costs incurred during trading and tax consequences of investment decisions. This article reviews some widely used approaches to portfolio analytics, discussing new trends in metrics, modeling approaches, and portfolio analytics system design. Topics include stock screening, text analytics, traditional and new uses for factor models, investment methodologies of recent interest (such as smart beta), new visualization and analytics features available from vendors and open source software, and cloud-based solutions for data management and analysis.</description><author>Pachamanova, Dessislava A.; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Risk Management Using the Lorenz Curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shalit, Haim
This article presents a methodology for using the Lorenz curve in financial economics. Most of the recent quantitative risk measures that abide by the rules of second-degree stochastic dominance, such as Gini's mean difference and conditional value at risk, are associated with the Lorenz curve. With financial data, the Lorenz curve is easy to calculate, because it requires sorting asset returns in ascending order. A financial analyst can derive the statistics necessary to carry out a study of risk analysis and establish a set of efficient and most-preferred portfolios for all risk-averse investors.</description><author>Shalit, Haim</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility versus Tail Risk: Which One Is Compensated in Equity Funds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xiong, James X.; Idzorek, Thomas M.; Ibbotson, Roger G.
nan</description><author>Xiong, James X.; Idzorek, Thomas M.; Ibbotson, Roger G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend-Price Ratios and Stock Returns: International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornell, Bradford
nan</description><author>Cornell, Bradford</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making Better (Investment) Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Robert C.
nan</description><author>Jones, Robert C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance Attribution of Options: Defining Single-Stock Option Exposures and Understanding the Brinson-Fachler Effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morgan, Stuart
nan</description><author>Morgan, Stuart</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Tax Option in Municipal Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalotay, Andrew; Howard, C. Douglas
nan</description><author>Kalotay, Andrew; Howard, C. Douglas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Do Sovereign Spreads Say About Expected Defaults and Devaluations? An Application to the European Sovereign Debt Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durham, J. Benson
nan</description><author>Durham, J. Benson</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Return/Volatility Trade-Off of Distressed Corporate Debt Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altman, Edward I.; Gonzalez-Heres, Jose F.; Chen, Ping; Shin, Steven S.
nan</description><author>Altman, Edward I.; Gonzalez-Heres, Jose F.; Chen, Ping; Shin, Steven S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Allocation: A New Investment Paradigm?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amenc, Noel; Martellini, Lionel
nan</description><author>Amenc, Noel; Martellini, Lionel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Distribution Decision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bierman, Harold
nan</description><author>Bierman, Harold</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Alpha Be Captured by Risk Premia?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bender, Jennifer; Hammond, P. Brett; Mok, William
nan</description><author>Bender, Jennifer; Hammond, P. Brett; Mok, William</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Traditional Optimization Is Not Optimal for Leverage-Averse Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, Bruce I.; Levy, Kenneth N.
nan</description><author>Jacobs, Bruce I.; Levy, Kenneth N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation Hedging with International Equities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roedel, Maximilian
nan</description><author>Roedel, Maximilian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When to Sell Apple and the NASDAQ? Trading Bubbles with a Stochastic Disorder Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shiryaev, A. N.; Zhitlukhin, M. V.; Ziemba, W. T.
nan</description><author>Shiryaev, A. N.; Zhitlukhin, M. V.; Ziemba, W. T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Trading Strategy to Profit from Overly Aggressive Downward Earnings Guidance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billingsley, Randall S.; Resnick, Bruce G.
nan</description><author>Billingsley, Randall S.; Resnick, Bruce G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Drivers of Predicted Beta</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Jackson; Menchero, Jose
The authors present a methodology for attributing an asset's or portfolio's predicted beta to an underlying set of factors. The approach's foundation rests on the concept of factor beta, which represents the beta of a factor portfolio with respect to the market portfolio. This analysis gives investors important insights into the drivers of predicted beta for a particular portfolio. The authors also study the cross-sectional dispersion of stock-level predicted betas. They show that the dispersion can be decomposed into contributions from individual factors. This framework provides valuable insight into how factor volatilities and correlations affect observed differences in stocks' predicted betas.</description><author>Wang, Jackson; Menchero, Jose</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dark Side of Passive Investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blitz, David
nan</description><author>Blitz, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Es-cape-ing from Overvalued Sectors: Sector Selection Based on the Cyclically Adjusted Price-Earnings (CAPE) Ratio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bunn, Oliver; Staal, Arne; Zhuang, Ji; Lazanas, Anthony; Ural, Cenk; Shiller, Robert
This article explores the effectiveness of the cyclically adjusted price-earnings (CAPE) ratio to detect over- or undervaluation of sectors within the U.S. economy. The authors modify the original notion of the ratio from several empirical studies by John Campbell and Robert Shiner, not only to ensure unifolln corporate payout policies, but also to allow comparisons across the sectors' potentially differing accounting standards and varying growth expectations. Considering sector-level CAPE information back to the early 1980s, the authors translate the CAPE-based valuation signals into a sector rotation strategy, whose long-term value nature is complemented by a supplemental momentum adjustment, in order to eliminate value traps. The performance enhancement associated with the CAPE-based sector rotation extends to European sectors as an out-of-sample test.</description><author>Bunn, Oliver; Staal, Arne; Zhuang, Ji; Lazanas, Anthony; Ural, Cenk; Shiller, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Low-Risk Investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Walkshausl, Christian
This article comprehensively examines the performance, investment behavior, and co-movement of minimum-volatility, low-volatility, and low-beta strategies in international markets. First, the authors identify the significant over-weighting of non-cyclical stocks from the consumer staples and utilities sectors, relative to the market, as one of the main, industry-specific return drivers of all low-risk strategies. Second, minimum-volatility, low-volatility, and low-beta strategies produce similarly substantial and statistically significant CAPM and three-factor model alphas in the segments of developed markets and emerging markets over the complete sample period, before and after the recent financial crisis. However, during the crisis, there was no significant outperformance, though low-risk strategies could keep risk down. All low-risk strategies share general commonalities with small-cap and value strategies, except in the European market, where they resemble growth strategies. Third, minimum-volatility, low-volatility, and low-beta strategies generally exhibit large and significant co-movements across and within markets. The authors do not find compelling evidence that one strategy generally dominates another. They conclude that minimum-volatility, low-volatility, and low-beta strategies are equally beneficial for participating in low-risk investing around the world.</description><author>Walkshausl, Christian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option-Implied Volatilities and Stock Returns: Evidence from Industry-Neutral Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Xiaoquan; Pong, Eddie S. Y.; Shackleton, Mark B.; Zhang, Yuanyuan
Recent studies demonstrate the profitability of stock portfolios constructed according to implied volatility measures inferred from option prices. This article examines industry effects on such portfolios' performance. Results show that quintile portfolios constructed using volatility skew and volatility spread are subject to substantial industry effects, which are particularly strong during market turbulence. The authors form industry-neutral portfolios and compare their performances to those of frill-universe portfolios that do not consider industry exposure. Results show significant improvement when portfolio strategies are implemented in an industry-neutral manner, based on either volatility skew or volatility spread.</description><author>Liu, Xiaoquan; Pong, Eddie S. Y.; Shackleton, Mark B.; Zhang, Yuanyuan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return Dynamics of Index-Linked Bond Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koivu, Matti; Pennanen, Teemu
Bond returns are known to exhibit mean reversion, auto-correlation, and other dynamic properties that differentiate them from stock returns. Index-linked bonds bring in further characteristics that complicate the task of modeling returns over time. Such models are essential, however, in strategic portfolio analysis and quantitative risk management. This article shows that the modeling of index-linked bond portfolios can be reduced to statistical modeling of the portfolio's yield to maturity and the underlying index. For these quantities, many well-established models already exist. Using historical data from 12 different markets, the authors show that the two risk factors consistently explain more than 98% of monthly return variations over the past decade, including the recent financial crisis.</description><author>Koivu, Matti; Pennanen, Teemu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Tax Management of Municipal Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalotay, Andrew
Municipal bonds are held in taxable accounts because the interest is tax-exempt, but gains and losses are subject to complex tax treatment. The author explains how selling at a loss when the market value falls below the investor's tax basis can improve after-tax performance. The hold value, which can differ substantially from the market price, is a key part of calculating the potential benefit from sale. The difference between the sale proceeds and the hold value shows the benefit of selling. If the benefit is positive, the question is whether to act now or wait for a possibly better opportunity. The answer lies in the transaction's tax efficiency, which compares the benefit captured to the value of the tax option (i.e., the right to take a tax loss at any time). The latter's value depends on interest-rate volatility and transaction costs. The author recommends selling only if the benefit captures a high percentage of the forfeited tax option (i.e., if the tax efficiency is sufficiently high).</description><author>Kalotay, Andrew</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coming Up Short: Managing Underfunded Portfolios in an LDI-ES Framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, Sanjiv; Kim, Seoyoung; Statman, Meir
The authors present a liability-directed investment (LDI) rebalancing framework that is based on expected shortfall (ES), denoted as LDI-ES, to prescribe remedies for an underfunded portfolio. Investors endowed with some current wealth optimize their target wealth at the end of N periods, subject to their tolerance for shortfalls from that target wealth. The authors contrast LDI-ES rebalancing with fixed-proportions rebalancing, in which portfolio allocations are rebalanced to ratios, such as 60:40, at the beginning of each of N periods. They consider critical issues of underfunding, in which no portfolio can meet the shortfall constraint, as well as the effectiveness of portfolio infusions in resolving underfunded situations relative to other measures, such as increasing risk, cutting back on target liabilities or goals, and extending the portfolio horizon.</description><author>Das, Sanjiv; Kim, Seoyoung; Statman, Meir</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Donation Risk and Optimal Endowment Portfolio Allocations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blanchett, David
An endowment is only one component of the total economic worth of a charitable organization. Other assets, such as real estate, donation revenue, and program service fees generally represent a larger portion of the total wealth of a charity yet are often ignored in the endowment optimization process. This article provides evidence that changes in charitable donations, referred to as donation risk, have statistically significant exposures to different asset classes and risk factors. Through a series of portfolio optimizations it is determined that the optimal allocation for an endowment varies materially for different compositions of total wealth. These findings suggest that narrowly focused portfolio optimization routines that ignore donation risk are insufficient, and that a holistic definition of wealth is necessary to build truly efficient endowment portfolios.</description><author>Blanchett, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Higher-Frequency Analysis of Low-Frequency Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mallinger-Dogan, Mickael; Szigety, Mark C.
Low-frequency data present significant challenges to investors because infrequent observations lead to imperfect intra-period understandings of market behavior, which in turn frustrate risk management and portfolio monitoring. Nowhere is this phenomenon more vexing than in portfolios that include both liquid and illiquid investments, whose low-frequency reporting compromises an investor's ability to form a holistic portfolio perspective. The authors examine the consequences of this issue and evaluate two methodologies for interpolating low-frequency data to facilitate use in higher-frequency settings. Through a numerical study, they determine that the decision to use one methodology over another or whether to interpolate at all is context-dependent, and illustrate the effect of higher-frequency interpolation on risk evaluation, attribution, and other common risk measures.</description><author>Mallinger-Dogan, Mickael; Szigety, Mark C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tesla: Anatomy of a Run-Up</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornell, Bradford; Damodaran, Aswath
This article presents a detailed anatomy of the nearly sevenfold run-up in the price of Tesla stock between March 22, 2013 and February 26, 2014, and attempts to determine the role played by investor sentiment. Tesla offers a unique opportunity in this context because the run-up was on the order of magnitude experienced by some of the most volatile technology stocks, but Tesla operates in an industry automotive manufacturing and a potential industry battery construction that are mature and populated by established competitors. This makes it possible to construct discounted cash flow valuation models that are anchored to established fundamentals. On the basis of these models, in conjunction with a detailed event study and analysis of institutional stock holdings and short-sales data, the authors conclude that the run-up cannot be explained as a rational reaction to fundamental information. Instead, they conclude that, at the end of the run-up, the stock was overvalued by approximately 150%. In their view, the case study provides support for the assertion by Lawrence Summers that price and rational value can diverge significantly for prolonged periods of time.</description><author>Cornell, Bradford; Damodaran, Aswath</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cost of Asset Allocation in Equity Market: How Much Do Investors Lose Due to Bad Asset Class Design?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Woo Chang; Lee, Yongjae; Lee, Yoon Hak
Many investors employ asset allocation, even though most are not really concerned about how their asset classification schemes affect investment performance. This article extensively examines the two most widely employed within-stock classifications: styles and industry classification. In order to explicitly measure current classifications' performance levels, the authors introduce the concept of optimal asset classification, which provides the upper performance limit of any classification scheme. They find that style and industry classification are very costly. Furthermore, factor analysis reveals that the immediate cause of exorbitant cost lies in the method on which classification focuses.</description><author>Kim, Woo Chang; Lee, Yongjae; Lee, Yoon Hak</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Concentration and the Geometry of Co-Movement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phoa, Wesley
Understanding correlations and how they change over time is an important aspect of investing. But large correlation matrices are difficult or impossible to grasp intuitively. This article describes a method for transforming a correlation matrix into a point cloud in space, in which two points are close if the corresponding assets are highly correlated, and vice versa. Latent structures in the correlation matrix can thus be visualized geometrically. The method also provides an intuitive way to visualize how the correlation matrix changes over time, and can be used to derive quantitative measures of portfolio concentration.</description><author>Phoa, Wesley</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How to Represent Mark-to-Market Possibilities with the General Portfolio Selection Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Markowitz, Harry M.
nan</description><author>Markowitz, Harry M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobsen, Brian
nan</description><author>Jacobsen, Brian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Standing Out From the Crowd: Measuring Crowding in Quantitative Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cahan, Rochester; Luo, Yin
One of the most frequently cited criticisms of quantitative investing has been the charge that everyone uses the same factors and models. In other words, the popular strategies of the last few decades, such as value and momentum, have become crowded, leaving little room for investors to generate alpha. But is this actually true? The authors propose an empirical framework for measuring crowdedness, and use this to study the crowding in common systematic strategies.</description><author>Cahan, Rochester; Luo, Yin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Private Fund-Based Portfolios: A Search for Rebalancing Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szigety, Mark C.
Private fund-based portfolios present significant exposureand liquidity-management challenges, because committing new funds and conducting secondary sales both have complex relationships to eventual exposure levels and net cash flows. This article presents a framework for evaluating candidate rebalancing strategies within the context of organizational objectives and concerns. It explicitly acknowledges the usefulness of secondary sales, and of modeling cash flows as stochastic processes. The author finds that simple commitment and sales rules that essentially depend only on distance from the target work reasonably well, but that the precise formulation of these rules depends on the specific situation. Institutions that value adherence to policy targets over other concerns will gravitate toward a rebalancing strategy that involves highly responsive commitment and sales rates, both when starting from zero and when overallocated. But for institutions that are less concerned with adherence to policy targets, optimal rebalancing strategies depend on the formulation of the initial problem. In cases of overallocation, even these patient organizations may need highly responsive sales rules to correct the overexposure within a reasonable time.</description><author>Szigety, Mark C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the Diversification Benefit of Frontier Markets Realizable by Mean-Variance Investors? The Evidence of Investable Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Dave; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Yang, J. Jimmy
The authors investigate whether the diversification benefits of frontier markets are realizable. They focus on investable frontier exchange-traded funds (ETFs) and their corresponding indices. Their analysis includes directly measuring the economic benefits of frontier-market diversification, as well as considering frontier-market trading dynamics. Evidence indicates that frontier markets offer diversification benefits through their risk-reducing potential. The authors find that frontier market volatility tends to be largely idiosyncratic, which supports the risk-reducing role of frontier markets. Their comparison of funds and indices indicates that, to the extent that frontier-market indices offer hypothetical benefits, traders can obtain these benefits by using investable funds.</description><author>Berger, Dave; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Yang, J. Jimmy</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Devil in HML's Details</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asness, Clifford; Frazzini, Andrea
In this article the authors challenge the standard method for measuring value that is used in academic work on factor pricing. The standard method uses lagged book data to calculate book-to-price (B/P) at portfolio formation. It aligns price data using the same lag, ignoring recent price movements. The authors propose two simple alternatives that use more timely price data; they then construct portfolios based on the different measures for a U.S. sample (from 1950 to 2011) and a global sample (from 1983 to 2011). They show that B/P ratios based on more timely prices better forecast true, unobservable B/P ratios at fiscal year-end. Value portfolios based on the timeliest measures earn statistically significant alphas, ranging between 305 and 378 basis points per year, versus the standard method.</description><author>Asness, Clifford; Frazzini, Andrea</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings Quality Revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bender, Jennifer; Nielsen, Frank
Earnings quality as an investment signal has been popular among equity portfolio managers for the last decade. The basic idea behind this accruals anomaly is that stocks with high and increasing accruals tend to have low earnings quality, while stocks with low and decreasing accruals tend to have high earnings quality. The earnings quality signal stopped working in the mid-2000s, but has staged a remarkable rebound since the end of 2008. The authors evaluate whether earnings quality is a true alpha signal, a risk factor, or both. They find that, in the periods when the signal worked, the strategy was largely driven by stock selection, suggesting that earnings quality is indeed an alpha signal. The authors also find that earnings quality is not a good risk factor, in that it does not have high statistical significance when regressed cross-sectionally on returns, along with other well-known risk factors, and is not very volatile over time. Overall, their results indicate that earnings quality may be that rare example of a pure alpha factor.</description><author>Bender, Jennifer; Nielsen, Frank</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which Component of Treasury Yields Belongs in Equity Valuation Models? An Application to the S&amp;P 500</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durham, J. Benson
Given a relaxation of the expectations hypothesis of interest rates and an estimate of the term premium, the remaining assumption that anticipated distant-horizon nominal expected short rates and projected earnings growth are equivalent implies novel cash-flow-based valuation models for shares. For example, an application of a simple dividend-discount framework to the S&amp;P 500, under 600 alternative specifications (to avoid data mining), using a sample from January 1987 through January 2012, fits the data well. It suggests that the model errors correct; it also suggests the argument that estimated forward Treasury term premiums, not yields, belong in the discount factor.</description><author>Durham, J. Benson</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Surprising Alpha From Malkielfs Monkey and Upside-Down Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnott, Robert D.; Hsu, Jason; Kalesnik, Vitali; Tindall, Phil
Recent index literature is replete with innovations that are based on quantitative strategies and predicated on sensible investment beliefs. Empirical studies confirm that these strategies deliver economically large and statistically significant excess returns over cap-weighted market benchmarks in nearly all regions and countries, over long periods of time. In this article, the authors show that inverting these poitfolio-construction algorithms does not reverse the out-performance. Indeed, the upside-down strategies often outperform the originals. This paradoxical result is driven by the phenomenon that seemingly unrelated, non-value-based strategies and their inverted counterparts often have unintended and almost unavoidable value and small-cap tilts. Even Burt Malkiel's legendary blindfolded monkey, throwing darts at the Wall Street Journal's stock page, would produce a portfolio with a substantial value- and small-cap bias that would have historically outperformed the S&amp;P 500. The value and small-cap tilts stem from the fact that non-price-based weighting schemes sever the link between a company's share price and its weight in the portfolio. Clearly, the inverted strategy of a non-price-weighted strategy is still a non-price-weighted strategy, would consequently have a value and small-cap tilt, and would therefore have outperformed historically.</description><author>Arnott, Robert D.; Hsu, Jason; Kalesnik, Vitali; Tindall, Phil</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is There Alpha in Institutional Emerging-Market Equity Funds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Wenling
Can active fund managers outperform the passive index in the global emerging-markets equity arena? To answer this question, the author delineates emerging-market fund strategies and applies multifactor approaches to a unique data set, consisting of institutional emerging-market managers' returns from Russell Investments. This analysis produced five major findings from January 1997 to June 2011: 1) product varieties have proliferated in this asset class; 2) active management can work in this asset class, but investors have relied more on research to hire good managers; 3) value managers tend to have higher alphas historically, but the supply of value managers is smaller than that of growth-or market-oriented managers; 4) price momentum, valuation, Asia, and the resources sector are key risk drivers; and 5) active risks from this asset class are still present, so it's important to diversify across multiple strategies and styles to mitigate unwanted risks. Alphas are obtainable, but they are not free.</description><author>Lin, Wenling</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Create or Buy: A Comparative Analysis of Liquidity and Transaction Costs for Selected US ETFs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borkovec, Milan; Serbin, Vitaly
Examining 12 popular exchange-traded funds (ETFs), the authors find that ETFs and common stocks exhibit qualitatively different liquidity and cost characteristics. The limit order book for ETFs is deeper than that of common stocks, with similar daily share volume, price, spread, and volatility characteristics, especially at price levels immediately surrounding the prevailing mid-quote. The differences in trading mechanisms and liquidity provision between ETFs and common stocks affect transaction costs. In order to reflect these differences, an appropriate transaction cost model should be properly calibrated and parameterized. It should also consolidate the entire ETF liquidity accessible on the secondary market and through the creation/redemption procedure. The authors demonstrate that considering cost estimates for trading ETFs' underlying constituents provides additional clarity about an ETF's true cost. Their comparison of ETF and basket costs, in conjunction with a look at creation/redemption fees, indicates the need for monitoring relative ETF liquidity, as the optimal switching points between trading an ETF and creating/redeeming vary widely across ETFs and trading styles.</description><author>Borkovec, Milan; Serbin, Vitaly</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fundamentally Weighted Global Small Companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bull, Peter M.
The author presents an empirical analysis into the issue of universe definition for a fundamentally weighted, global small-company equity strategy. Consistent with previous research on fundamental indexing for large companies, the author confirms the performance advantages of weighting securities by fundamental measures of company size, as opposed to market capitalization, for a variety of global small-company strategies. Beyond these results, the author provides evidence that small-company strategies that define their universe by market capitalization criteria, in the manner of traditional small-cap indices, enjoy a performance advantage over those that use fundamental-ranking criteria. Although this improvement in risk-adjusted performance is accompanied by marginally increased total risk and turnover, rudimentary adjustments to the market cap-defined universe counteract both effects.</description><author>Bull, Peter M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Innovation and Portfolio Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Abby Joseph
nan</description><author>Cohen, Abby Joseph</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity Trading in the Fast Lane: The Staccato Alternative</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwartz, Robert A.; Wu, Liuren
nan</description><author>Schwartz, Robert A.; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Frictional Costs of Diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scherer, Bernd
nan</description><author>Scherer, Bernd</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Deeper Causes of the Financial Crisis: Mortgages Alone Cannot Explain It</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelson, Mark
Losses on U.S. residential mortgage loans are too small to explain the magnitude of the 2008 financial crisis. Total losses, including both losses realized to date and those yet to be realized, should fall in the range of $750 billion to $2 trillion. The global magnitude of the crisis is significantly larger, probably in the range of $5 trillion to $15 trillion, depending on the measuring approach. This implies that losses on residential mortgage loans cannot be the main cause of the crisis. They can only be a trigger that unleashed the true causes. The failure (or near failure) of a significant number of major financial firms suggests that high leverage and strong risk appetites were important immediate causes of the crisis. However, explaining the sources of high leverage and strong risk appetites requires probing for deeper causes that developed over a longer period. This article proposes deeper causes that include securities firms' conversion from partnerships to corporations, the 30-year deregulation trend, the quant movement, the spread of risk-taking culture throughout the financial industry, and globalization.</description><author>Adelson, Mark</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Moves Stock Prices: Another Look</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornell, Bradford
In 1989, Culter, Poterba, and Summers published an article examining the extent to which ex post movements in aggregate stock prices could be attributed to the arrival of news. They concluded that most of the 50 largest movements in the S&amp;P 500 could not be matched with any convincing explanation for why future profits or discount rates might have changed. Since 1989, there has been an explosion in information technology, enhanced market regulation, and stock-trading innovation, as well as the introduction of new, equity-related financial products. The author explores whether Culter, Poterba, and Summers's conclusion still holds, and reports that it is intact. If anything, the mystery has deepened, because the size of unexplained market movements has grown.</description><author>Cornell, Bradford</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do You Know What's in Your Benchmark?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crawford, Steven; Hansen, James; Price, Richard
nan</description><author>Crawford, Steven; Hansen, James; Price, Richard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing Under Inflation Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crawford, George; Liew, Jim Kyung-Soo; Marks, Andrew
nan</description><author>Crawford, George; Liew, Jim Kyung-Soo; Marks, Andrew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Tortoise and the Hare: Risk Premium versus Alternative Asset Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bird, Ron; Liem, Harry; Thorp, Susan
nan</description><author>Bird, Ron; Liem, Harry; Thorp, Susan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity-Driven Dynamic Asset Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xiong, James X.; Sullivan, Rodney N.; Wang, Peng
nan</description><author>Xiong, James X.; Sullivan, Rodney N.; Wang, Peng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Embedded Tax Liabilities and Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Turvey, Phillip A.; Basu, Anup K.; Verhoeven, Peter
nan</description><author>Turvey, Phillip A.; Basu, Anup K.; Verhoeven, Peter</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minimum-Variance Portfolios Based on Covariance Matrices Using Implied Volatilities: Evidence from the German Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mostowfi, Mehdi; Stier, Carolin
This article compares the performance of minimum-variance portfolios based on four different covariance matrix estimators, using daily return data from the German stock market. To assess whether investing in ex ante minimum-variance portfolios is a recommendable way to achieve efficient portfolios in accordance with Markowitz's mean-variance optimization, the authors benchmark the four portfolios' performance against the German stock index DAX, which also determines the investable universe. This is the first study that uses not only historical volatility and covariance data, but also implied volatilities from the stock options market to estimate the covariance matrix. The article also analyzes how results change when the shrinkage method, suggested by Ledoit and Wolf in a 2003 article published in this journal, is applied to both the historical and the implied volatility estimators. The authors demonstrate that all minimum-variance portfolios outperform the DAX index. The implied-volatility estimator, modified by the shrinkage method, offered the best results in terms of volatility, return, and efficiency ratio. In contrast to previous empirical results, applying the shrinkage method to the historical sample covariance matrix yields little benefit, if any. However, applying the shrinkage method to the implied-volatility estimator significantly improves the quality of the covariance estimation, resulting in improved performance from the minimum-variance portfolio.</description><author>Mostowfi, Mehdi; Stier, Carolin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Blind Side: Managing Downside Risk in Corporate Defined-Benefit Plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sheikh, Abdullah Z.; Sun, Jianxiong
Following the recession of the early 2000s, defined benefit corporate pension plans faced dramatic funding challenges. They had barely recovered before the recession of 2008 to 2009 sent funding ratios tumbling once again. Many plan sponsors must now make larger contributions than they originally budgeted, in order to bring their plans back to full funding. This article aims to deepen the current discussion of risk reduction in the context of defined benefit plans It investigates two key issues. First, its authors analyze the effect of non-normality of asset returns on a defined benefit pension plan's liabilities. They argue that analytical frameworks that assume normality can lead to an underestimation of downside risk, a concern with regard to contributions. Second, the authors develop a multi-dimensional risk-management framework for managing contribution risk.</description><author>Sheikh, Abdullah Z.; Sun, Jianxiong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage Aversion, Efficient Frontiers, and the Efficient Region</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, Bruce I.; Levy, Kenneth N.
This article proposes to augment portfolio theory and mean-variance optimization to incorporate investors' aversion to leverage. The authors suggest a specification for leverage aversion that captures the unique risks of leverage. They also introduce mean-variance leverage-efficient frontiers, compare them with conventional mean-variance-efficient frontiers, and develop a mean-variance leverage-efficient region. Their analysis shows that leverage aversion can have a large effect on an investor's portfolio choice.</description><author>Jacobs, Bruce I.; Levy, Kenneth N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Parity, Maximum Diversification, and Minimum Variance: An Analytic Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, Roger; de Silva, Harindra; Thorley, Steven
Analytic solutions to risk parity, maximum diversification, and minimum variance portfolios provide useful perspectives about their construction and composition. Individual asset weights depend on both systematic and idiosyncratic risk in all three risk-based portfolios, but systematic risk eliminates many investable assets in long-only, constrained, maximum-diversification, and minimum-variance portfolios. On the other hand, risk-parity portfolios include all investable assets, and idiosyncratic risk has little effect on weight magnitude. The algebraic forms for optimal asset weights derived in this article yield generalizable properties of risk-based portfolios, in contrast to empirical simulations that employ a specific set of historical returns, proprietary risk models, and multiple constraints. These analytic solutions reveal precisely how various kinds of predicted risk affect the relative magnitude of security weights in each type of risk-based portfolio construction.</description><author>Clarke, Roger; de Silva, Harindra; Thorley, Steven</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size Rotation in the US Equity Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miller, Keith L.; Ooi, Chee; Li, Hong; Giamouridis, Daniel
In this article, Miller, Ooi, Lee, and Giamouridis develop a hybrid model that relies on the nonlinear classification decision tree (DT) approach, and also on multivariate predictive regressions, to help implement a size rotation strategy in the U.S. equity markets. They derive an investment prediction with a two-stage algorithm. In the first stage, they use a decision tree to determine whether large-cap or small-cap stocks will outperform in the subsequent quarter. In the second stage, the authors use a multiple linear regression model to predict whether large-cap stocks will outperform or underperform small-cap stocks in the next quarter. A binary variable obtained from the first stage of the analysis-the DT model-is a key variable in the second-stage model. The authors find that a size rotation strategy based on the proposed hybrid model outperforms strategies based on the constituent models, as well as alternative strategies investigated in other studies.</description><author>Miller, Keith L.; Ooi, Chee; Li, Hong; Giamouridis, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Book-to-Market and the Cross-Section of Expected Returns in International Stock Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret; Fabozzi, Frank J.
Individual stocks' expected return estimates are a key input for equity selection models. A 2008 study by Eugene Fama and Kenneth French found evidence that past changes in book equity and price contain independent information about expected cash flows that can be used to improve estimates of expected returns. This study focuses on international stock markets and re-examines whether the origins of the book-to-market ratio (BM), in terms of past changes in book equity and price, enhance the estimates of expected returns provided by BM alone. Examining all stocks, as well as subcategories of microcap, small, large, and all-but-microcap stocks trading in the United Kingdom, Germany, France, Italy, Canada, and Japan, the authors find that recent changes in book equity and price are more relevant than more distant changes in enhancing estimates of expected future cash flows and expected future returns. Their tests also show that changes in book equity say much more about expected stock returns than price changes do.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incorporating Linkers in a Global Government Bond Risk Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Jong, Marielle
Many governments around the world now issue inflation-protected securities, or linkers, alongside conventional nominal bonds. This extends the fixed-income investment universe. Investors may not know how to build these new securities into a bond-risk model that captures overall global-price covariance. The author studies this question through the international capital asset pricing model approach, which decomposes risk into a global systematic component and a local specific component. The challenge is to fit a linear factor model onto the triangular relationship that exists between the nominal bond yields, the inflation-linked bond yields, and yield spreads called the inflation break-even rates. The author's model provides a consistent view of risk for internationally invested portfolios containing nominal bonds, linkers, and/or inflation swaps.</description><author>de Jong, Marielle</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is There Value in Valuation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fridson, Martin; Finnerty, John D.
It seems self-evident to many investors that valuation is the key to picking winners in a sector-rotation strategy. The authors' analysis of quality tiers within the high-yield bond market casts doubt on that premise. The market's direction exerts such a big influence on relative returns that limited room remains for valuation to have an impact. In light of the authors' findings in the speculative-grade debt market, value-oriented investors in other asset categories may also need to rethink their assumptions.</description><author>Fridson, Martin; Finnerty, John D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification Across Time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayres, Ian; Nalebuff, Barry
Young people who buy stock on margin and reduce their equity exposure as they age can reduce lifetime portfolio risk. For example, an initially leveraged portfolio produces the same mean accumulation as a constant 74% stock allocation with a 21% smaller standard deviation. Since the means are equal, the reduced volatility doesn't depend on the equity premium. A leveraged life-cycle strategy also lets investors come closer to their utility-maximizing equity allocation. Monte Carlo simulations show that the gains continue even with equity premiums well below historical levels.</description><author>Ayres, Ian; Nalebuff, Barry</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Constant-Volatility Framework for Managing Tail Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hocquard, Alexandre; Ng, Sunny; Papageorgiou, Nicolas
Since Lehman Brothers collapsed in 2008, tail-risk hedging has become an increasingly important concern for investors. Traditional approaches, such as purchasing options or variance swaps as insurance, are often expensive, illiquid, and result in a substantial drag on performance. A more prudent, cost-effective way to maintain a constant risk exposure is to actively manage portfolio exposure according to the prevailing volatility level within underlying assets. The authors implement a robust methodology based on Dybvig's payoff distribution model to target a constant level of volatility and normalize monthly returns. This approach to portfolio and risk management can help investors obtain their desired risk exposures over both short and longer time frames, reduce exposure to tail risk, and in general increase portfolios' risk-adjusted performance.</description><author>Hocquard, Alexandre; Ng, Sunny; Papageorgiou, Nicolas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introducing Leverage Aversion into Portfolio Theory and Practice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, Bruce I.; Levy, Kenneth N.
nan</description><author>Jacobs, Bruce I.; Levy, Kenneth N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Four Modes of Practical Risk Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhansali, Vineer
nan</description><author>Bhansali, Vineer</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility, Correlation, and Diversification in a Multi-Factor World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roll, Richard
In a multi-factor world, diversification benefits do not generally depend on correlation. Investors can restructure portfolios to align factor sensitivities. This implies that diversification benefits depend only on the idiosyncratic volatility that remains after restructuring. Similarly, the risk reduction that follows adding an asset to an existing portfolio does not depend on the asset's correlation with the portfolio. These implications evince the fundamental importance of measuring the underlying factors and estimating factor sensitivities for every asset. Other researchers have investigated several methods for measuring factors. An easy-to-implement general method involves specifying a group of heterogeneous indexes or traded portfolios. Exchange-traded funds (ETFs) could be well suited to this purpose.</description><author>Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and Portfolio Choice: A Unified Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kinlaw, Will; Kritzman, Mark; Turkington, David
The authors propose a simple analytical construct for incorporating liquidity into portfolio choice. In cases where investors deploy liquidity to raise a portfolio's expected utility beyond its original expected utility, the authors attach a shadow asset to tradable assets. In cases where investors deploy liquidity to prevent a portfolio's expected utility from falling, the authors attach a shadow liability to assets that are not tradable. This construct lets investors determine the optimal allocation to illiquid assets. Alternatively, investors can use this construct to estimate the premium an illiquid asset requires, or the degree to which they must benefit from liquidity in order to justify forgoing investment in illiquid assets. This approach improves on other methods of incorporating liquidity into portfolio choice in four fundamental ways. First, it mirrors what actually occurs within a portfolio. Second, it maps units of liquidity onto units of expected return and risk, so that investors can analyze liquidity within the same context as other portfolio decisions. Third, it distinguishes absolute illiquidity from partial illiquidity and lets investors address these attributes within a single, unifying framework. Fourth, it recognizes that liquidity serves not only to meet demands for capital, but to exploit opportunities as well, thus revealing that investors bear an illiquidity cost to the extent that any fraction of a portfolio is immobile.</description><author>Kinlaw, Will; Kritzman, Mark; Turkington, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Digital Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, Sanjiv R.
Digital assets are investments with binary returns: their pay-offs are either very large or very small. The author explores the features of optimal portfolios of digital assets, such as venture investments, credit assets, and lotteries. These portfolios comprise correlated assets with joint Bernoulli distributions and have substantial skews and kurtosis. The intuitions of mean-variance analysis do not carry over to these portfolios. Using a simple, standard, fast recursion technique to generate a portfolio's return distribution, the author derives investor guidelines for constructing digital-asset portfolios. Das finds that digital portfolios perform better when their assets are homogeneous in size but heterogeneous in the assets' probability of success.</description><author>Das, Sanjiv R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond Market Price Discovery: Clarity Through the Lens of an Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tucker, Matthew; Laipply, Stephen
Fixed-income exchange-traded funds (ETFs) are bond portfolios that trade on a stock exchange. They present a unique opportunity to compare the valuation of fixed-income securities on exchange-driven and over-the-counter (OTC) markets. Tucker and Laipply quantify the price discovery properties of fixed-income ETFs, focusing in particular on the speed at which the ETF and OTC bond markets reflect new price information. They find that fixed-income ETF price movements can potentially serve as a leading signal for subsequent OTC bond market movements (as proxied by bond market indices), especially when volatility is high. The authors also explore potential trading strategies that capitalize on this dynamic.</description><author>Tucker, Matthew; Laipply, Stephen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the 60-40 Stock-Bond Pension Fund Rule Wise?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ziemba, William T.
Pension funds typically suggest the 60-40 stock-bond rule to lower risk, as bonds tend to rise during stock market declines. However, U.S. investment returns have depended on the presidential party in power, and returns in the last two years of all administrations exceed those in the first two years. The strategies using small-cap stocks with Democrats and intermediate bonds or large-cap stocks with Republicans yields final wealth of about six times the large-cap index, 50% more than small caps and more than twenty times the 60-40 mix since 1942.</description><author>Ziemba, William T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Disparity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kritzman, Mark
Investors seek to grow their wealth over time and avoid large draw-downs along the way, but these goals conflict. A policy portfolio serves as an expression of how investors balance these conflicting goals. A policy portfolio that maintains constant asset weights, however, experiences significant inter-temporal disparity in its risk profile, thereby defeating the purpose for which it is intended. This article offers evidence of inter-temporal risk disparity and shows how investors can use measures of intrinsic poitfolio fragility and extrinsic market fragility to stabilize a portfolio's risk profile.</description><author>Kritzman, Mark</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Low-Volatility Investing: Balancing Total Risk and Active Risk Considerations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghayur, Khalid; Heaney, Ronan; Platt, Stephen
Low-volatility strategies have been shown to offer significant total risk and drawdown reduction without sacrificing returns, compared to the market. However, low-risk strategies also involve an inherent trade-off between total risk and active risk (or tracking error). Existing passive alternatives for capturing low-risk strategies emphasize total risk reduction at the expense of high and uncontrolled active risk. The article discusses a new approach for capturing abnormal risk-related payoffs at targeted active-risk levels, using a transparent, rules-based approach. This proposed approach lets investors strike a better trade-off between total risk and active risk, and implement low-volatility investing within the constraints of their active-risk budgets.</description><author>Ghayur, Khalid; Heaney, Ronan; Platt, Stephen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Carrier Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kusiak, Steven
In recent years, the demand for passive investment products in hard-to-replicate asset classes, or exotic betas, has grown faster than financial services firms' capacity to engineer such products. Full replication of exotic betas is usually impossible or too costly. For example, it is particularly difficult to obtain passive exposure to small-cap equity indices or to alternative asset classes, such as private equity with liquid instruments. The carrier portfolio provides a novel response to this outstanding issue. Unlike methods that require a covariance matrix (or factor model) and solve the usual tracking-error quadratic program, the carrier portfolio relies on a linear program that directly takes into account each return observation and minimizes the total absolute exposure of the underlying assets. Hence, the method does not require assumptions about the return data's statistical distribution, is amenable to very large-scale optimization problems involving thousands of assets, and can handle problems for which the number of assets is greater than the number of return observations. As a result, the carrier portfolio tends to better track various financial benchmarks with fewer investment vehicles and simplifies the process of creating such portfolios across large numbers of potential investments.</description><author>Kusiak, Steven</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liability-Driven Investment With Downside Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Chen, Bingxu; Sundaresan, Suresh
The authors develop a liability-driven investment framework that incorporates downside risk penalties for not meeting liabilities. The shortfall between the asset and liabilities can be valued as an option that swaps the value of the endogenously determined optimal portfolio for the value of the liabilities. The optimal portfolio selection exhibits endogenous risk aversion and, as the funding ratio deviates from the fully funded case in both directions, effective risk aversion decreases. When funding is low, the manager swings for the fences to take on risk, betting on the chance that liabilities can be covered. Over-funded plans also can afford to take on more risk, as liabilities are already well covered and so invest aggressively in risky securities.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Chen, Bingxu; Sundaresan, Suresh</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Pricing and Market Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jarrow, Robert
This article dispels the common belief that option pricing and market efficiency are independent concepts, only weakly related at best. It shows that risk-neutral valuation, the standard approach for pricing derivatives, is true if (and only if) the market for the underlying asset is efficient with respect to the information set generating the price process's evolution. The article explores implications of this insight for standard derivative-pricing models, including the need to test for asset price bubbles before using such models.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading Volatility: At What Cost?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Whaley, Robert E.
Volatility trading is in vogue. Launched in January 2009, exchange-traded products (ETPs) linked to the CBOE Market Volatility Index (VIX) have enamored no small number of traders, judging by the billions of dollars invested in these new products. The reason is unclear. The most popular VIX ETPs are not suitable buy-and-hold investments and are virtually guaranteed to lose money over time. Indeed, since product launch, ETPs linked to the S&amp;P 500 VIX short-term futures indices have chalked up losses of nearly $4 billion. Yet the market continues to grow. This article describes these products, explaining how and why they lose money.</description><author>Whaley, Robert E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Clairvoyant Discount Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnott, Robert D.; Li, Feifei; Warren, Geoffrey J.
In 2009, Arnott, Li, and Sherrerd asked how a clairvoyant investor-an investor who can see the future cash flows that a company will deliver to its shareholders and an eventual resale price-would have valued individual stocks. By examining past share prices in the context of subsequent dividends, the authors garnered insights into how well market prices predict future company success (impressively well) and how correctly the market prices growth versus value (impressively badly). This article reverses the analysis, computing the discount rate a clairvoyant investor must accept to justify the current price. The goal is to gain insight into the extent to which variations in expected returns may explain pricing. These "clairvoyant discount rates" fall in a distribution that sheds new light on value and size effects. A shockingly low discount rate, often lower than the cash yield, must apply for the richest growth stocks to justify their historical valuations. The size effect is not driven by a higher average return for small companies, but by a handful of extreme outliers. These results cast doubt on the notion that the size and value effects can be a result of cross-sectional differences in discount rates in an efficient market.</description><author>Arnott, Robert D.; Li, Feifei; Warren, Geoffrey J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Discovery: The Economic Function of a Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alan, Nazli Sila; Schwartz, Robert A.
This article defines an exchange according to its primary function: establishing shares' trading prices. After establishing the public goods property of an exchange-produced price, the article stresses that price discovery is a complex process that depends on market structure. Recognizing that the quality of price discovery can be inferred from the magnitude of intraday price volatility, the authors display intraday volatility for a sample of DOW stocks, show how volatility decreased for NASDAQ stocks following the institution of NASDAQ's calls in 2004, and trace the broader evolution of intraday volatility from 1993 to 2011.</description><author>Alan, Nazli Sila; Schwartz, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Big Money in Boston": The Commercialization of the Mutual Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bogle, John C.
Over the course of his six-decade-plus career, Vanguard founder John C. Bogle has witnessed-and been an active participant in-sweeping changes in the mutual fund industry. In the early days, "Boston Trustees" usually managed a single fund, with a focus on the long-term, prudent investment, and stewardship. Today the industry is dominated by giant financial conglomerates running fund supermarkets, focused on short-term, more aggressive strategies, and salesmanship. Four major changes drove this change in the mutual fund culture: 1) The industry's incredible growth. 2) Aggressive, high-risk investment strategies. 3) Product proliferation. And 4) conglomeratization. Yet one innovation stood firm against that rising tide-the index fund. In recent years, investor cash inflows have poured into "passively-managed" index funds while "actively-managed" equity funds have endured substantial outflows.</description><author>Bogle, John C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Strategy and Structure Take Center Stage: "How, What, Where, and When?" Replace "Why?"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clayton, Jim; Fabozzi, Frank J.; Giliberto, S. Michael; Gordon, Jacques N.; Liang, Youguo; MacKinnon, Greg; Mansour, Asieh
Real estate has become more accepted as a basic building block of a well-diversified institutional portfolio over the past decade. The debate around the question "Why Real Estate?" has largely been put to rest. The most relevant research questions about the asset class now revolve around more detailed issues in optimal allocations under different situations and in light of new trends, and also around details of how implementation of a real estate allocation (i.e. the actual investments made) should be done and how it affects the risk/return characteristics of the final portfolio. The relevant new trends in the industry and the associated research questions are discussed.</description><author>Clayton, Jim; Fabozzi, Frank J.; Giliberto, S. Michael; Gordon, Jacques N.; Liang, Youguo; MacKinnon, Greg; Mansour, Asieh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Susan Hudson-Wilson: A Rising Tide That Lifted the Commercial Real Estate Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poutasse, Doug; Wilkerson, Bret
The institutional real estate industry lost one of its leading figures in 2013, Susan Hudson-Wilson. A successful entrepreneur, respected industry leader, and influential researcher, Hudson-Wilson had a profound impact on the industry, including as a member of the editorial board of the special real estate issues of The Journal of Portfolio Management. The authors review her career and legacy.</description><author>Poutasse, Doug; Wilkerson, Bret</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Global Perspective on Pension Fund Investments in Real Estate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andonov, Aleksandar; Kok, Nils; Eichholtz, Piet
Real estate is the third-largest asset class for institutional investors, but research into the performance of pension fund investments in real estate is scant. This article employs a unique set of data, the CEM database, to study the real estate investment approach, cost, and performance for a global panel of almost a thousand pension funds. The results show that smaller pension funds invest primarily in direct real estate, through external managers and fund-of-funds, and are likely to disregard listed property companies in their real estate allocation. Larger pension funds are more likely to invest in real estate internally, exhibit lower costs, and achieve higher net returns. Internal real estate investment management is associated with lower costs and disproportionally higher returns. Finally, we document that U.S. pension plans' real estate investments significantly underperform both their benchmarks and their foreign peers.</description><author>Andonov, Aleksandar; Kok, Nils; Eichholtz, Piet</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>After the Fall: Real Estate in the Mixed-Asset Portfolio in the Aftermath of the Global Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lizieri, Colin
The global financial crisis led some investors to question the benefits of real estate as a risk diversifier in mixed asset portfolios as falling real estate capital values coincided with the bear market in equities: private real estate appeared not to deliver diversification when it was most needed. An analysis of UK private real estate returns, corrected for appraisal effects using a regime-based filtering process confirms that the relationship between real estate and other financial assets is time-varying: but suggests that there remain strong benefits from including commercial real estate in the mixed asset portfolio.</description><author>Lizieri, Colin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is There a Real Estate Allocation Puzzle?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Ping; Lin, Zhenguo; Liu, Yingchun
The wide disagreement between academics and practitioners with regard to the optimal real estate allocation in the mixed-asset portfolio is a long standing puzzle. Extensive research focusing on "fine-tuning" the application of Modern Portfolio Theory (MPT) has been unable to reach any consensus. This article develops an alternative portfolio theory that extends the MPT to accommodate the unique characteristics such as (1) real estate is subject to significant liquidity risk, (2) real estate return distribution is not independent and identically-distributed, and (3) real estate has high transaction cost. Using real world data, the model produces optimal real estate allocation that is much lower than previously suggested by the literature and is in fact quite in line with the reality of institutional portfolios.</description><author>Cheng, Ping; Lin, Zhenguo; Liu, Yingchun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Price per Pound and Replacement Cost: The Effects of Q on Office Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nordby, Hans; Taylor, Michael
Despite the reality that price versus replacement cost, or Tobin's Q, is commonly used in making commercial real estate investment decisions, its efficacy has not been widely explored academically. Nordby and Taylor address this by examining the relationship between Q and office construction starts and pricing trends. By using CoStar property and land transaction sale price data and RSMeans construction cost data from 2000 to 2012, the authors are able to construct comprehensive national and market-level Q indices. The results indicate a strong relationship between Q and investment in office properties. The authors also find that this relationship differs across markets and is generally related to the level of barriers to construction present in these markets.</description><author>Nordby, Hans; Taylor, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Closer Look at Co-Movements in Global Office Rents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Suran, Luciana
Do office rents across the globe move together? This is a question that should concern not just investors in real estate but also corporate occupiers with offices across regions and countries. This analysis investigates the existence of co-movements across global office markets by performing principal components analysis on a unique dataset of prime office rents in 32 global office markets. Results suggest that while rents in most markets appear to be driven by a common factor, regional and other differences persist, suggesting potential for diversification.</description><author>Suran, Luciana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Financial Leverage in the Performance of Private Equity Real Estate Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alcock, Jamie; Baum, Andrew; Colley, Nicholas; Steiner, Eva
We study a unique data set in order to examine the performance of a sample of 169 global private equity real estate investment funds across the core, value-add and opportunistic investment style categories over the most recent property cycle (2001-2011). We employ a multi-factor asset pricing model to measure the impact on the funds' total excess returns of the underlying real estate market, managerial skill measured by Jensen's alpha, leverage and, for the first time, managerial skill as it relates to timing leverage decisions to anticipated future market trends. We find evidence consistent with the hypotheses that i) fund performance is almost directly proportional to the return on the underlying real estate market, ii) there is evidence for systematic underperformance as measured by Jensen's alpha, possibly related to market frictions, iii) leverage cannot be viewed as a long-term strategy to enhance performance, and iv) timing leverage choices to the expected future market environment does not appear to add significantly to fund excess returns.</description><author>Alcock, Jamie; Baum, Andrew; Colley, Nicholas; Steiner, Eva</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commercial Real Estate Risk Management with Derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fabozzi, Frank J.; Stanescu, Silvia; Tunaru, Radu
Helping managers to gauge the interaction between commercial property prices and interest rates for commercial property and CMBS portfolios.</description><author>Fabozzi, Frank J.; Stanescu, Silvia; Tunaru, Radu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Searching for a Common Factor in Public and Private Real Estate Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Nabar, Neil; Wald, Samuel J.
We introduce a methodology to estimate common real estate returns and cycles across public and private real estate markets. We first place REIT indices and direct real estate-NCREIF appraisal-based and transaction-based indices (NPI and NTBI)-on a comparable basis by adjusting for leverage and sector. We extract a common real estate factor, which is allowed to be persistent, from all these markets. Individual real estate indices load on this common factor and they also are driven by persistent, idiosyncratic shocks. The common real estate factor is procyclical and has low correlations with standard systematic factors from public markets. Short-run idiosyncratic deviations from the common real estate factor load on several capital market factors for REITs and on liquidity factors for direct real estate.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Nabar, Neil; Wald, Samuel J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and the Supply Cycle: Evidence from the REIT Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Packer, Frank; Riddiough, Timothy; Shek, Jimmy
We analyze securitized equity interests in commercial property (the so-called listed REIT market), with a particular focus on the U.S. experience. We begin by observing that there is a strong negative relationship between new commercial property construction activity and the growth of the U.S. REIT market. Based on this and other relevant factors, we conjecture that an important reason for the muted commercial property supply response during the early and mid-2000s was the "civilizing influence" of the REIT sector. A formal test of the conjecture suggests that the REIT market indeed moderated supply outcomes in the U.S. Relationships between the REIT market and new construction activity are generally weaker in other analyzed countries, where we attribute these findings to structural differences. We conclude that attention to structural detail is essential in order to maximize the benefits associated with creating a transparent and liquid market for securitized investment interests.</description><author>Packer, Frank; Riddiough, Timothy; Shek, Jimmy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the Impact of Real Estate on Target Date Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Esrig, Dave; Kolasa, Susan; Cerreta, Luigi
Defined benefit (DB) plans have used direct real estate in their asset allocations for forty years. Defined contribution (DC) plan sponsors are using the shift to asset allocation funds as an opportunity to do the same We found that if direct properties were added to target date funds over the past four decades, DC participants in these funds would have experienced substantially improved risk-adjusted performance.</description><author>Esrig, Dave; Kolasa, Susan; Cerreta, Luigi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managed Volatility Strategies: Applications to Investment Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dopfel, Frederick E.; Ramkumar, Sunder R.
Managed volatility strategies adjust asset allocation dynamically in anticipation of, or in response to extreme market volatility. This implies that during periods of market stress, investors can rebalance to a risk budget as an investment policy option, rather than strictly adhering to current practices that rebalance back to fixed portfolio weights. We measure the advantages of managed volatility with a multi-period model and find that the benefits increase with an investor's ability to forecast market volatility beyond historical relationships. The practical application for investors is that a more flexible and dynamic investment policy may result in better investment outcomes.</description><author>Dopfel, Frederick E.; Ramkumar, Sunder R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Risk-Parity Managers at Risk Parity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Edward
Risk parity has become an accepted investment strategy, to some degree. Its main advantage is its use of risk allocation, as opposed to the capital allocation used by the traditional asset allocation approach. A balanced risk allocation provides true diversification; therefore risk parity should deliver better risk-adjusted return over time. Despite the acceptance and the fact that the term "risk parity" has been in use for almost ten years, the investment community seems confused about risk parity's true definition. Is it just a quantitative risk-budgeting technique? Is it about operational leverage? Or is it about high exposures to fixed income and low exposures to equities? In this paper, the author aims to define the principle of risk parity investing. He then examines a sample of risk parity managers, using the return-based style analysis pioneered by William Sharpe. The results show that, according to the defined principle, a number of risk parity managers in our sample are not using true risk parity.</description><author>Qian, Edward</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Markowitz Wrong? Investment Lessons from the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Statman, Meir
nan</description><author>Statman, Meir</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Delusions of Grandeur</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferguson, Robert
nan</description><author>Ferguson, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Comparison of the Mean-Variance-Leverage Optimization Model and the Markowitz General Mean-Variance Portfolio Selection Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, Bruce I.; Levy, Kenneth N.
nan</description><author>Jacobs, Bruce I.; Levy, Kenneth N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional-Grade Risk Management Policy: Is It Possible in Practice?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Halpern, Jeffrey; Liew, Jim K.
nan</description><author>Halpern, Jeffrey; Liew, Jim K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Surprising Implications of the Lehman Default for Derivatives and Structured Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niculescu, Peter
nan</description><author>Niculescu, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Death of Diversification Has Been Greatly Exaggerated</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ilmanen, Antti; Kizer, Jared
Diversification is famously referred to as the only "free lunch" in investing, but it has been under assault since the 2007-2009 global financial crisis, when virtually all long-only asset classes moved down together. Ilmanen and Kizer argue that the attacks are undeserved. Most investors were never as diversified as they thought they were, and there is ample room for improvement by shifting the focus from asset class diversification to factor diversification. They show that diversification into and across factors has been much more effective in reducing portfolio volatility and market directionality than asset class diversification. The benefits are greatest for long short investing, which requires shorting and leverage but are also meaningful in a long-only context.</description><author>Ilmanen, Antti; Kizer, Jared</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk On/Risk Off</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Wai
The phrase "risk on/risk off" may now be ingrained in the vernacular of global investors. Lee attempts to crystallize what risk on/risk off really means by analyzing an extreme state of the market when the correlation of all assets is perfect. He derives a set of normative results of how assets should behave in relation to the investment opportunity set. Although his results do not provide guidance on the interpolation between a given state and the extreme state of perfect correlation, Lee believes that his analysis can serve as a compass for the investment decision-making process in the event that investors believe the market is moving toward or away from a risk-on/risk-off environment. Lee discusses the investment implications in relation to the risk parity portfolio, global asset allocation, and active portfolio management.</description><author>Lee, Wai</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effectiveness of Asset Classes in Hedging Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia-Feijoo, Luis; Jensen, Gerald R.; Johnson, Robert R.
Garcia-Feijoo, Jensen, and Johnson evaluate the effectiveness of several asset classes in the hedging of portfolio risk over the 1970-2010 period. Of the alternative assets examined, commodities offer the greatest diversification potential due to their very low correlation with stock and bond returns. Furthermore, while the diversification benefits of many asset classes diminish during periods of extreme market movements, the benefits of commodities remain strong. Overall, they find robust support for the hedging potential of commodities, but they present three caveats to this view. First, relative to the other commodities, industrial metals offer much less diversification potential for equity investors. Second, commodities serve as considerably more effective hedges during periods when Federal Reserve monetary policy is tight (i.e., when inflationary concerns are elevated). Third, relative to the other commodities, precious metals provide equity investors with a more consistent hedge across alternative inflationary environments.</description><author>Garcia-Feijoo, Luis; Jensen, Gerald R.; Johnson, Robert R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demystifying Equity Risk-Based Strategies: A Simple Alpha plus Beta Description</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Carvalho, Raul Leote; Lu, Xiao; Moulin, Pierre
In this article, de Carvalho, Lu, and Moulin consider five risk-based strategies: equally weighted, equal-risk budget, equal-risk contribution, minimum variance, and maximum diversification. All five strategies can be well described by exposure to the market-cap index and to four simple factors: low beta, small cap, low residual volatility, and value.This finding, in their view, is a major contribution to the understanding of such strategies and provides a simple framework to compare them. All except the equal-weighted strategy are defensive and have lower volatility than the market-cap index. Equal-weighted is exposed to small-cap stocks. Equal-risk budget and equal-risk contribution are exposed to small-cap and to low-beta stocks.These three have a high correlation of excess returns, and their portfolios largely overlap.Their portfolios invest in all stocks available and have both a low turnover and low tracking error relative to the market-cap index. The minimum variance and maximum diversification strategies primarily have exposure to low-beta stocks.These two strategies are the most defensive, invest in much the same stocks, and have high tracking error and turnover.</description><author>de Carvalho, Raul Leote; Lu, Xiao; Moulin, Pierre</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversifying the Diversifiers and Tracking the Tracking Error: Outperforming Cap-Weighted Indices with Limited Risk of Underperformance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amenc, Noel; Goltz, Felix; Lodh, Ashish; Martellini, Lionel
A number of quantitative or fundamental weighting schemes have been shown to produce robust outperformance with respect to standard cap-weighted equity indices over long time periods. Over periods ranging from a few months to a few years, however, such alternative weighting schemes can generate substantial downside risk relative to cap-weighted indices, which would be a source of concern for most investment managers or chief investment officers. In this article, the authors focus on two reasonable proxies for well-diversified, efficient frontier portfolios, namely, the maximum Sharpe ratio (MSR) portfolio and the global minimum volatility (GMV) portfolio. They address the question of how to use these building blocks to design an improved equity benchmark while satisfying target levels of average and extreme tracking error with respect to cap-weighted indices.The authors find that robust proxies for the GMV portfolio provide defensive exposure to equity that does well in adverse market conditions, while robust proxies for MSR portfolios provide greater access to the upside of equity markets. Because the relative performance of these two diversification approaches depends on market conditions, they expect a combination of both approaches to lead to a smoother conditional performance and higher probability of outperformance of the cap-weighted index, an intuition that is confirmed in empirical tests. Empirical analysis also suggests that "diversifying the diversifiers" still leads to high levels of relative downside risk, in particular when the performance of cap-weighted indices is unusually strong. In this context, the authors introduce an explicit relative risk control mechanism designed to reduce the consequences of severe short-term underperformance with respect to the cap-weighted index and confirm through out-of-sample empirical tests that "tracking the tracking error" would allow investors to achieve better access to outperformance per unit of extreme relative risk taken. Overall, the results reported in this article suggest that it is possible to achieve robust outperformance versus cap-weighted indices by diversifying model risk and by controlling relative risk compared to the cap-weighted indices.</description><author>Amenc, Noel; Goltz, Felix; Lodh, Ashish; Martellini, Lionel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's Wrong with Today's Economics? The Current Crisis Calls for an Approach to Economics Rooted More on Data Than on Rationality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Focardi, Sergio M.; Fabozzi, Frank J.
Focardi and Fabozzi argue that current mainstream economics is not a science in the sense of the physical sciences, and they draw some conclusions from the point of view of asset management. Their key point is that economics as embodied in the general equilibrium theories describes an idealized rational economic world as opposed to one based on empirical data. Although this argument has already been made, it has been virtually ignored by economists.The current crisis, however, requires an economic understanding anchored on a solid empirical basis. The authors review a number of facts, including the following: 1) market efficiency is a quantitative concept, with efficiency defined in terms of the magnitude of realistic profit opportunities; 2) the dynamic vector-like nature of inflation challenges current theories about inflation and the generation of money, making growth path-dependent; 3) economic conservation laws are key to understanding growth; and 4) a market economy cannot support an unbounded level of wealth and income inequality because they become a destabilizing factor. The overall lesson for asset management is that economics matters and that the culture of pure speculation would be replaced profitably for society as a whole with a true culture of investment.</description><author>Focardi, Sergio M.; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification Return and Leveraged Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Edward
It is widely accepted that portfolio rebalancing adds diversification return to fixed-weight portfolios, but this is only true for long-only unleveraged portfolios. Qian provides analytical results regarding portfolio rebalancing and the associated diversification returns for different kinds of portfolios including long-only, long-short, and leveraged. He shows that portfolio rebalancing is linked to underlying portfolio dynamics. For long-only unleveraged portfolios, rebalancing amounts to a mean-reverting strategy, and the diversification return is always non-negative. But for short (or inverse) and leveraged portfolios, portfolio rebalancing on the top-down level amounts to a trend-following strategy that detracts from diversification return. Qian analyzes diversification returns of risk parity portfolios and shows that the diversification return of a leveraged long-only portfolio can generally be decomposed into two parts, both of which are related to a scaled unleveraged portfolio. The first part is the positive diversification return from rebalancing among individual assets at the bottom-up level, which is amplified by leverage. The second part is the negative diversification return caused by the leverage of the overall portfolio. His numerical examples show that diversification return is, in general, positive for leveraged risk parity portfolios when the leverage ratio is not too high. In addition, he shows that low correlations between different assets are crucial in achieving positive diversification return and reducing portfolio turnover for risk parity portfolios.</description><author>Qian, Edward</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Owners versus Asset Managers: Agency Costs and Asymmetries of Information in Alternative Assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anson, Mark
Agency theory is about striking the right balance between principals and their agents. In any agency relationship, the motives and desires of the agent may be different from that of the principal. For public corporations, agency theory is often called corporate governance. There is a growing awareness, however, that agency theory also applies to the investment management industry in which asset owners delegate the caretaking of their investments to asset managers. The potential misalignment of interests between asset owners and asset managers can lead to four agency costs: asymmetry of skill or alpha, asymmetry of incentives, asymmetry of liquidity, and asymmetry of risk taking.</description><author>Anson, Mark</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysts' Earnings Forecast, Recommendation, and Target Price Revisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldman, Ronen; Livnat, Joshua; Zhang, Yuan
This study examines the immediate and delayed market responses to revisions in analyst forecasts of earnings, target prices, and recommendations. Consistent with prior literature, revisions in earnings forecasts are positively and significantly associated with short-term market returns around the revisions. However, Feldman, Livnat, and Zhang show that short-term market returns around target price revisions and recommendation changes are even stronger. They also find superior future performance (return drift) for portfolios that use information from all three types of revisions to those using information from only one of the three types of revisions.</description><author>Feldman, Ronen; Livnat, Joshua; Zhang, Yuan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Great Investors: Their Methods, Results, and valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gergaud, Olivier; Ziemba, William T.
Gergaud and Ziemba discuss the records of some great investors and hedge fund managers. The investors' graphs of wealth over time lead to a search for smooth monotone paths and a fair way to evaluate superior as opposed to average investors. Some investors prefer high long-run growth and accept bumps rather than smooth wealth paths and lower growth. These include some Kelly criterion investors such as Buffett, Keynes, and Soros who have concentrated portfolios with few asset positions. In 2005 Ziemba proposed a modification, following an earlier proposal by Ziemba and Schwartz in 1991, of the ordinary normal distribution based Sharpe ratio to evaluate right-skewed great investor portfolios. This measure only counts losses and is useful in evaluating superior investors such as the Renaissance Medallion hedge fund, which has a high rating by the modified downside symmetric Sharpe ratio (DSSR) as opposed to having only a modest rating with the ordinary Sharpe ratio. Using the University of Massachusetts hedge fund database, Gergaud and Ziemba discuss some funds with superior records and from their evaluation learn more about the properties of the DSSR. and the modified downside symmetric information ratio.</description><author>Gergaud, Olivier; Ziemba, William T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Naked Short Selling and Market Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boulton, Thomas J.; Braga-Alves, Marcus V.
Boulton and Braga-Alves study persistent failures to deliver (fails) to better understand naked short sellers' trading strategies, their ability to profit from their trades, and the market's reaction to information about their activities. Contrary to recent claims that naked short sellers are momentum traders who drive down stock prices, they find that returns are typically positive just prior to periods of increased naked short selling that result in persistent fails and that returns generally remain positive for several weeks afterward. Their results also suggest that stocks that experience persistent fails are susceptible to short squeezes as shares move from a normal state in which short exposure is established by borrowing and selling to a hard-to-borrow state in which fails become a more attractive option for establishing short exposure.</description><author>Boulton, Thomas J.; Braga-Alves, Marcus V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantifying the Variance Risk Premium in VIX Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barnea, Amir; Hogan, Reed
Barnea and Hogan use synthetically created variance swaps onVIX futures to quantify the variance risk premium inVIX options.The results of this methodology suggest that the average premium is 3.26%, meaning that the realized variance onVIX futures is, on average, less than the variance implied by the swap rate.This premium does not vary with time or the level of the swap rate as much as premiums in other asset classes. A negative risk premium implies that VIX option strategies that are net credit should be profitable.</description><author>Barnea, Amir; Hogan, Reed</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting Yield Curves with Survey Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Jack Clark; Hua, Jian
In recent years, affine term structure models have provided alternatives to the expectations hypothesis and have become very popular in the finance literature. In particular, the widely accepted dynamic Nelson-Siegel model employs ingenious measures of the level, slope, and curvature of the yield curve that captured the attention of Francis and Hua. They supplement the dynamic Nelson-Siegel model with the Federal Reserve's Survey of Professional Forecasters data. Because these data utilize information from dozens of professional forecasters who study numerous macroeconomic variables, the author's wanted to see if this information-rich supplementary data could be used to improve the interest rate forecasting models for out-of-sample forecasts for Treasury bond maturities ranging from three months to 10 years that extend from three months to one year into the future.</description><author>Francis, Jack Clark; Hua, Jian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Analysis of Exchange-Traded Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buetow, Gerald W.; Henderson, Brian J.
Exchange-traded funds (ETFs) provide investors with a single, tradable security for gaining exposure to an index that presumably proxies for an asset class. In the U.S. alone, ETF assets under management have grown to nearly $900 billion. Buetow and Henderson analyze ETF returns to evaluate how closely ETF prices replicate exposures to their benchmark indices. The authors' analysis highlights practical considerations that influence index replication. On average, an ETF closely tracks its benchmark index. An ETF that tracks an index composed of less liquid securities exhibits a larger tracking error, and an ETF that tracks an index composed of less liquid, or non-U.S., securities exhibits a greater correlation (relative to the benchmark index) with a U.S. equity index, suggesting that the diversification benefits of these ETFs are less than is implied by the return properties of the benchmark index.</description><author>Buetow, Gerald W.; Henderson, Brian J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hunting for Alpha Hunters in the Currency Jungle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pojarliev, Momtchil; Levich, Richard M.
nan</description><author>Pojarliev, Momtchil; Levich, Richard M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toward Determining Systemic Importance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kinlaw, Will; Kritzman, Mark; Turkington, David
Kinlaw, Kritzman, and Turkington introduce a methodology for measuring systemic importance. Investors care about systemic them to events importance because this knowledge may enable assess their portfolio's vulnerability to particular and, if warranted, to pursue defensive strategies. Policymakers also need this information to ensure that policies and regulations target the appropriate entities and to more effectively engage in preventive or corrective measures when circumstances warrant intervention. The absorption ratio, introduced by Kritzman, Li, Page, and Rigobon in 2011, provides an implied measure of systemic risk based on principal component analysis. The authors extend this methodology to determine an entity's centrality. Their centrality measure captures an entity's vulnerability to failure, its connectivity to other entities, and the risk of the entities to which it is connected. They convert this measure of centrality into a measure of systemic importance by conditioning it on periods of high systemic risk.</description><author>Kinlaw, Will; Kritzman, Mark; Turkington, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Norway Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chambers, David; Dimson, Elroy; Ilmanen, Antti
Norway's Government Pension Fund Global (GPFG) was recently ranked the largest fund on the planet. It is also highly rated for its professional, low-cost, transparent, and socially responsible approach to asset management. Investment professionals increasingly refer to Norway as being a model for managing financial assets. Chambers, Dimson, and Ilmanen present and evaluate the strategies followed by the GPFG, review its long-term performance, and describe how it responded to the financial crisis. They conclude the article with sonic lessons that investors can draw from Norway's approach to asset management, contrasting the Norway model with the Yale model of pension fund management.</description><author>Chambers, David; Dimson, Elroy; Ilmanen, Antti</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Reduction in Style Rotation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ulloa, M. Rodrigo Dupleich; Giamouridis, Daniel; Montagu, Chris
Dupleich Ulloa, Giamouridis, and Montagu investigate the potential improvement in the implementation of style rotation strategies by techniques addressing estimation errors. They select two approaches that have recently stood out in the statistics and econometrics literature and have been applied to portfolio construction. One approach builds on regularization methods, addressing estimation error by focusing on the weights of the constructed portfolios. The second method pools forecasts that are obtained across different observation windows, thus focusing on minimizing estimation error in the moments of the return distribution that may arise due to structural breaks. The authors conclude that overall benefits are derived by foregoing naive approaches, which in their dataset can be as significant as an improvement in the Information Ratio of about 54%; that is, improving from 0.65 (naive) to approximately 1 (dynamic).</description><author>Ulloa, M. Rodrigo Dupleich; Giamouridis, Daniel; Montagu, Chris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quis Pendit Ipsa Pretia: Facebook Valuation and Diagnostic of a Bubble Based on Nonlinear Demographic Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cauwels, Peter; Sornette, Didier
Cauwels and Sornette present a novel methodology to determine the fundamental value of firms in the social networking sector, motivated by recent realized IPOs and by reports that suggest sky-high valuations of firms such as Facebook, Groupon, LinkedIn Corp., Pandora Media, Inc., Twitter, and Zynga. The authors' valuation of these firms is based on two assumptions: 1) revenues and profits of a social networking firm are inherently linked to its user base through a direct channel that has no equivalent in other sectors, and 2) the growth in the number of users can be calibrated with standard logistic growth models, which allows for reliable extrapolations of the size of the business at long time horizons. Cauwels and Sornette illustrate the methodology with a detailed analysis of Facebook, one of the biggest of the social media giants. A clear signature of a change of regime, occurring in 2010 in the growth of the number of users, is observed. The change of regime is a move from a pure exponential behavior (a paradigm for unlimited growth) to a logistic function with asymptotic plateau (a paradigm for growth in competition). The authors consider three different scenarios: a base case, high-growth, and extreme-growth scenario. Using a discount factor of 5%, a profit margin of 29% and $3.50 of revenues per user per year yields a value of Facebook of $15.3 billion in the base case scenario, $20.2 billion in the high-growth scenario, and $32.9 billion in the extreme-growth scenario. According to the authors' methodology, this implies that Facebook needs to increase its profit per user before the IPO by a factor of 3 to 6 in the base case scenario, 2.5 to 5 in the high-growth scenario, and 1.5 to 3 in the extreme-growth scenario in order to meet the current, widespread high expectations. To prove the wider applicability of their methodology, the analysis is repeated for Groupon, the well-known deal-of-the-day website, that went public in November 2011. The results are in line with the Facebook analysis. Customer growth will plateau. By not taking this fundamental property of the growth process into consideration, estimates of the Facebook IPO are wildly overpriced.</description><author>Cauwels, Peter; Sornette, Didier</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Investing in Volatility Help Meet Your Portfolio Objectives?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Warren, Geoffrey J.
Warren evaluates investing in volatility products under a range of investor objectives, including risk and return at the total portfolio level, benchmark-relative performance, and liability-aware investing. He shows that the potential role for volatility exposure depends on investor circumstances. Long positions in forward variance swaps or longer-dated VIX futures can be effective for hedging equity-related risk within balanced portfolios, but do so at the cost of exacerbating benchmark-relative risk and may be of limited benefit in certain liability-aware situations. Investors best placed to capture the volatility risk premium through shorting volatility include those with higher tolerance for total portfolio and benchmark-relative risk, longer investment horizons, or interest rate sensitive liabilities.</description><author>Warren, Geoffrey J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Alpha and Beta of Risk Attribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, Ben; Menchero, Jose
Davis and Menchero present a methodology for attributing the alpha and beta components of tracking error. They define an intuitive and precise decomposition of tracking error into alpha and beta components. Their approach is completely general and is applicable to security-, sector-, and factor-based investment processes. The authors show that by following this methodology, drilldowns into tracking error at any level of granularity can be neatly decomposed into parallel alpha and beta drilldowns. They also show that factor-based risk attribution represents an important special case of the alpha and beta risk decomposition, and they demonstrate that the residual exposure-based analysis of residual risk is prone to counterintuitive attribution effects.</description><author>Davis, Ben; Menchero, Jose</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fooled by Compounding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McLean, R. David
Compounding can make things appear to be larger than they really are. This confusion can arise when the return from an event is compounded over a long holding period, and the return from compounding is described as the return from the event. In this article, McLean reviews several examples of this common mistake, which are found in a popular book on rare events, newspaper articles, investment advisors' research reports, and finance journal articles. He also shows how compounding can distort inference in event studies and in the measurement of mutual fund performance. McLean describes alternative methods of return measurement that are not affected by compounding and shows that these methods can lead to different inferences than do measures that include compounding.</description><author>McLean, R. David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resolution of Corporate Financial Distress: An Empirical Analysis of Processes and Outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, Michael; Karagozoglu, Ahmet K.; Layish, Dina Naples
In this article, Jacobs, Karagozoglu, and Naples Layish focus on determining which types of firms are able to successfully remain independent entities through the resolution of their financial distress. The authors empirically investigate the determinants of the process utilized to resolve financial distress (private work-out versus public bankruptcy filing) and also the outcome (liquidation versus reorganization). After developing various qualitative-dependent variable models, they estimate and compare several accounting and economic variables measured at the time of default that they expect can influence the resolution process and outcome. Results reveal the ordered logistic regression specification achieves the best balance between in-sample fit, consistency with financial theory, and out-of-sample classification accuracy, as compared to more elaborate techniques, such as local regression or neural networks. The authors find the public resolution process to be associated with larger firms that have less tangibility, a greater proportion of secured debt in their capital structures, or higher risk measures. The private resolution process is likelier for firms that have more total leverage, greater measures of liquidity a higher proportion of subordinated debt in their capital structures, or reside in a debtor-friendly bankruptcy court district. Regarding the resolution outcome, the authors find that firms that are more likely to be liquidated than reorganized have greater liquidity, more secured debt, lower cumulative abnormal returns on equity, higher loss given default, a less favorable auditor's opinion, or they will default in a better part of the credit cycle. Finally, firms more likely to be reorganized have greater leverage, more intangible assets, or a prepackaged bankruptcy. They conclude that their model is useful for risk managers and investors who are in the market for distressed or defaulted debt.</description><author>Jacobs, Michael; Karagozoglu, Ahmet K.; Layish, Dina Naples</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jumps and Cojumps in Subprime Home Equity Derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mizrach, Bruce
Mizrach analyzes the jump frequency in the Market ABX.HE Index of subprime home equity credit default swaps and CME housing futures. Jumps began to appear prior to 2007. The jumps are more pronounced in housing futures than in the ABX index. He explains nearly 85% of the jumps from news and housing futures. A 20-point slope in the housing futures curve leads to an expected jump of -1.4% in the BBB-ABX index.</description><author>Mizrach, Bruce</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Optimization Strategy for Enhancing the Performance of Fund-of-Funds Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larsen, Glen A.; Resnick, Bruce G.
Previous research provides evidence that much of the cross-sectional variation in equity returns can be explained by firm characteristics or sectors. One popular money management technique is to construct a portfolio (fund) using other managed portfolios (funds).The resulting overall portfolio is generally referred to as a fund-of-funds portfolio. This study by Larsen and Resnick demonstrates the potential for performance enhancement in a fund of funds when portfolio optimization techniques are employed on sector funds in order to construct the overall fund. Notably, ex ante optimization over sector funds that are constructed on the basis of market capitalization, price-to-earnings ratios, change in operating earnings, and book-to-market ratios demonstrates the potential for enhancing an overall equity fund performance relative to value-weighted and equal-weighted benchmark portfolios that are constructed from the population of stocks from which the sector portfolios are formed.</description><author>Larsen, Glen A.; Resnick, Bruce G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factor Alignment Problems and Quantitative Portfolio Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ceria, Sebastian; Saxena, Anureet; Stubbs, Robert A.
Quantitative equity portfolio management has evolved into an interdisciplinary activity that draws expertise from the fields of finance, statistics, econometrics, accounting, and optimization. Each one of these streams is a mature discipline in itself, having its own body of knowledge, and operates under assumptions that are usually well accepted within the respective communities. But when concepts from these diverse fields are applied in a common setting, there is bound to be friction among various assumptions that get further magnified due to the use of an optimizer. In this article, Ceria, Saxena, and Stubbs focus on the interaction of three key elements that are part of the quantitative portfolio management process, namely the expected returns model, the risk model, and the constraints that are used to formulate the portfolio construction problem. They generally refer to the issues caused by this interaction as factor alignment problems. The authors present a detailed investigation of these alignment problems, survey some of their common sources, analyze and document their effects on the ex post performance of optimized portfolios, and conclude with a practical and effective remedy in the form of augmented risk models.</description><author>Ceria, Sebastian; Saxena, Anureet; Stubbs, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring and Modeling Execution Cost and Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engle, Robert; Ferstenberg, Robert; Russell, Jeffrey
Financial markets arc considered to be liquid if a large quantity can be traded quickly and with minimal price impact. Although the idea of a liquid market involves both a cost as well as a time component, most measures of execution costs tend to focus on only a single number that reflects average costs and do not explicitly account for the temporal dimension of liquidity In practice, trading takes time because larger orders are often broken up into smaller transactions or because of price limits. Recent work shows that the time taken to transact introduces a risk component in execution costs. In this setting, the decision can be viewed as a risk reward trade-off faced by the investor who can solve for a mean-variance utility-maximizing trading strategy. Engle, Ferstenberg, and Russell introduce an econometric method to jointly model the expected cost and risk of the trade, thereby characterizing the mean-variance tradeoffs associated with different trading approaches, given market and order characteristics. They apply their methodology to a novel dataset and show that the risk component is a nontrivial part of the transaction decision.</description><author>Engle, Robert; Ferstenberg, Robert; Russell, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Two Things about Performance Fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kritzman, Mark
nan</description><author>Kritzman, Mark</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inconsistent by Definition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fridson, Martin
nan</description><author>Fridson, Martin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's New about the "New Normal"?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnott, Rob
nan</description><author>Arnott, Rob</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Aftermath of Investment-Grade Distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edelstein, Ariel; Phelps, Bruce D.
What should one do with investment-grade bonds that begin to trade at distressed levels? This is when a portfolio manager is compelled to make the critical decision: Sell, hold, or buy? To help managers make an objective decision, the authors carefully examine the historical evidence regarding the performance of distressed investment-grade (DIG) bonds after a distress month. The historical record shows that DIG bonds have been very strong performers. On average, the 901 DIG bonds from January 1990 to July 2011 returned 51.6% over the 24 months following their distress month. They outperformed their peers by 30.1% and earned 39.8% more than comparable Treasury bonds. After adjusting for DIG bonds' ex ante higher expected excess return volatility, the authors find that DIG bonds generated approximately 81 bps a month of additional return compared with an equal risk investment in the IG Corporate Index.</description><author>Edelstein, Ariel; Phelps, Bruce D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavioral Finance 2.0</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Bob
nan</description><author>Jones, Bob</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forget about Alpha!</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amenc, Noel; Martellini, Lionel
nan</description><author>Amenc, Noel; Martellini, Lionel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-Based Dynamic Asset Allocation with Extreme Tails and Correlations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Peng; Sullivan, Rodney N.; Ge, Yizhi
Wang, Sullivan, and Ge propose a unique dynamic portfolio construction framework that improves portfolio performance by adjusting asset allocation in accordance with a forecast of market risk. They find that modifying asset allocation according to a market risk barometer offers investors the promising opportunity to meaningfully enhance portfolio performance across market environments.</description><author>Wang, Peng; Sullivan, Rodney N.; Ge, Yizhi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation-Hedging Portfolios: Economic Regimes Matter</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Briere, Marie; Signori, Ombretta
The exceptional rise in government deficits following the subprime crisis, the recent commodity price spikes, and the increase in inflation volatility have revived the debate on medium- to long-term resurgence of inflation. Using a vector-autoregressive model, Briere and Signori investigate the relationships between asset returns and inflation and the optimal strategic asset allocation for investors seeking to hedge inflation risk in two types of macroeconomic regimes. In a volatile macroeconomic environment marked by countercyclical supply shocks, the asset classes of cash, inflation-linked bonds, and precious metals play an essential role. In a more stable environment, such as what has been called the "Great Moderation," characterized by procyclical demand shocks, the asset classes of cash and nominal bonds play the most significant role, followed by precious metals, real estate, and equities. An ambitious investor in terms of required real returns should have a larger weighting in equities, real estate, and precious metals.</description><author>Briere, Marie; Signori, Ombretta</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rebalancing and the Value Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaves, Denis B.; Arnott, Robert D.
It is amply documented that a value portfolio outperforms a growth portfolio over long spans in most markets worldwide; less well known, however, is how this outperformance is achieved. Decomposing the total returns of these strategies, Chaves and Arnott find that 1) value portfolios enjoy higher dividend income and 2) the average growth stock enjoys faster dividend growth than the average value stock, but surprisingly 3) value portfolios experience higher growth in dividends than growth portfolios. The authors argue that the first two findings are expected, but the third is not completely understood by investors. The third finding is a consequence of the nature of the rebalance rules for growth and value portfolios. Each rebalance replaces lower-yielding value stocks with new higher-yielding value stocks and replaces higher-yielding growth stocks with new lower-yielding growth stocks. It is, therefore, the act of rebalancing and reconstituting the growth and value portfolios that increases the growth rate for dividend income in value strategies and rather sharply reduces it in the case of growth strategies. Although this finding is analogous to that of Fama and French, which is reported in their 2007 "Migration" paper, Chaves and Arnott more specifically attribute much of the advantage of value strategies to the acts of reconstituting and rebalancing and their side effects on dividends. In so doing, they shed some light on the faster dividend growth of value portfolios.</description><author>Chaves, Denis B.; Arnott, Robert D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value Premium Across Countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Daehwan
The value premium varies substantially across countries. Kim explores whether the inter-country cross-sectional variation in the value premium can be predicted by the variables known to predict the intra-country time-variation in the value premium. After examining data from 23 developed markets and 13 emerging markets between 2000 and 2010, he found that the earnings-yield spread and the return dispersion have predictive power in emerging markets but not in developed markets. The earnings-growth spread was found to have no significant predictive power.</description><author>Kim, Daehwan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Exposure Targeting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sneddon, Leigh; Yukhymuk, Vyacheslav
Achieving desired exposures to information sources is critical to successful active investing. If a portfolio manager, for example, wants to increase her portfolio's exposure to a signal-how long will it take? By how much should she change the signal's weight? How will exposures to other signals change? If she turns off a signal, for how long will the exposure to it persist? Can she accelerate these shifts? These challenges can present themselves whenever markets or business conditions change. Rule-of-thumb answers can mislead as exposures are affected not only by the sequence of weight changes but also by signal speeds and correlations and by the levels of risk and turnover. Sneddon and Yukhymuk solve for the combined effects of portfolio and signal dynamics, derive explicit predictions of the resulting exposure dynamics, and provide the intuition behind these results. The solutions include cost control as well as expectations over all realizations of the signals, both current and prior. A simple but central result describes exposure shift speeds. The authors show that interactions between different features can lead to unexpected results. The information presented in this article can help a portfolio manager to predict and manage the timing and extent of a portfolio's exposure to its information sources.</description><author>Sneddon, Leigh; Yukhymuk, Vyacheslav</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Risk, Size, Style, Momentum, and Dividends: U.S. Equities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, Francis
This article investigates the historical performance of the dividend-paying equity universe within the U.S. from 2000 through 2011 and compares it to the universe of stocks that did not pay dividends. To isolate the performance of the dividend factor, the analysis controls for the following fundamental factors: market risk, size, style, momentum, and sector. Finally, the article highlights the portfolio selection implications of this research for asset managers.</description><author>Gupta, Francis</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demographics, GDP, and Future Stock Returns: The Implications of Some Basic Principles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornell, Bradford
The aging of the baby boom generation has focused investor attention on the issue of how changing demographics will affect the economy generally and the stock market specifically. One commonly expressed view is that stock returns will be depressed as baby boomers liquidate their portfolios to fund retirement. In this article, Cornell returns to basic theories of economic growth and asset pricing to disentangle the various ways in which demographics can affect future economic growth and future stock returns. He concludes that whereas the aging of the baby boom generation is indeed bad news for future economic growth, in particular, on a per capita basis, it is unlikely to lead to lower future stock returns.</description><author>Cornell, Bradford</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Volume Clock: Insights into the High-Frequency Paradigm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; de Prado, Marcos M. Lopez; O'Hara, Maureen
Over the last two centuries, technological advantages have allowed some traders to be faster than others. In this article, the authors argue that contrary to popular perception, speed is not the defining characteristic that sets high-frequency trading (HFT) apart. HFT is the natural evolution of a new trading paradigm that is characterized by strategic decisions made in a volume-clock metric. Even if the speed advantage disappears, HFT will evolve to continue exploiting structural weaknesses of low-frequency trading (LFT). LFT practitioners are not defenseless against HFT players, however, and this article offers options that can help them survive and adapt to this new environment.</description><author>Easley, David; de Prado, Marcos M. Lopez; O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Diversification Delta: A Higher-Moment Measure for Portfolio Diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vermorken, Maximilian A.; Medda, Francesca R.; Schroeder, Thomas
The concept of diversification is central in finance and has become even more so since the 2008 financial crisis. In this article, the authors introduce a new measure for diversification. The measure, referred to as "diversification delta," is nonparametric, based on higher moments, easily interpretable due to its mathematical formulation, and incorporates the advantages of the present measures of diversification while extending them. The measure is applied to infrastructure returns data in order to understand the benefits of diversifying across various infrastructure classes, gaining useful insights for infrastructure fund managers and investors.</description><author>Vermorken, Maximilian A.; Medda, Francesca R.; Schroeder, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advancing Strategic Asset Allocation in a Multi-Factor World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asl, Farshid M.; Etula, Erkko
Strategic asset allocation is arguably one of the most important, yet least advanced, aspects of investing. The authors present a new approach to strategic asset allocation that leverages the idea that long-term investment returns derive from multiple distinct sources that they call "return-generating factors." Their approach addresses four key shortcomings of traditional approaches: First, their multi-factor model helps better understand the important sources of return in today's complex investment universe, generating a substantial increase in estimation precision across asset classes and providing investors with a new way to think about portfolio diversification. Second, their robust portfolio optimization methodology seeks to explicitly account for the uncertainties inherent in the estimates of expected returns, delivering well-diversified portfolios with superior risk return characteristics. Third, the factor-based risk analytics better capture the true characteristics of asset returns, such as fat tails and increased correlations at times of crises, allowing the authors to more-accurately model the downside risks of portfolios. Finally, the factor-based simulation technique accounts for the impact of different economic conditions (e.g., low interest rates) on future portfolio returns, resulting in more-precise, forward-looking projections.</description><author>Asl, Farshid M.; Etula, Erkko</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factor-Timing Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hua, Ronald; Kantsyrev, Dmitri; Qian, Edward
In this article, the authors propose a novel framework for building a factor-timing model. They introduce the concept of Akaike's information criterion for selecting conditioning variables and evaluating various factor-timing specifications. Balancing the tradeoff between in-sample precision and complexity of the problem is the central theme of the considered methodology. In addition, the authors show how to employ information ratio quantities to track improvements in the resulting model efficacy and quantify sources of added value of factor-timing models over traditional static models.</description><author>Hua, Ronald; Kantsyrev, Dmitri; Qian, Edward</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choose Your Betas: Benchmarking Alternative Equity Index Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amenc, Noel; Goltz, Felix; Lodh, Ashish
This article clarifies that methodological choices can be made independently for two steps in the construction of alternative equity index strategies: the constituent selection and choice of a diversification-based weighting scheme. By flexibly combining the different possible choices for these steps, the authors create a large variety of strategies and test their performance and risk results. The results suggest that diversification approaches may be a superior alternative, or at least a very important complement, to pure stock selection approaches when it comes to reaching a risk return objective. Moreover, even though some argue that the risk and performance of diversification-based weighting schemes are solely driven by factor tilts, the authors show how straightforward it is to correct such tilts through the selection of stocks with appropriate characteristics while maintaining the improvement in achieving a risk return objective that is due to the respective diversification approaches.</description><author>Amenc, Noel; Goltz, Felix; Lodh, Ashish</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing Valuation Measures: A Performance Horse Race over the Past 40 Years</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gray, Wesley R.; Vogel, Jack
In this article, the authors compare the investment performance of portfolios sorted on different valuation measures. They find that EBITDA/TEV has been the best performing metric, historically, and outperforms many investor favorites, such as price-to-earnings ratio, free cash flow to total enterprise value, and book-to-market ratio. The authors also explore the investment potential of long-term valuation ratios, which replace one-year earnings with an average of long-term earnings. They find that in contrast to prior empirical work, long-tern ratios add little investment value over standard one-year valuation metrics.</description><author>Gray, Wesley R.; Vogel, Jack</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Profitability and the Valuation of the Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cruise, Bill
Many discounted cash flow models produce estimates of firm value that are implicitly based upon economically implausible perpetual forecasts of firm profitability. This discrepancy arises because standard free cash flow models leave operating profits and capital levels as free parameters. In this article, the author develops a simple model that explicitly incorporates firms' steady-state returns on invested capital into the valuation equation, thereby addressing the free-parameter problem. He provides evidence that capital growth rates are historically less volatile than free cash flow growth rates and are more useful for accurately predicting firm value within the small sample sizes typically found in practice. With several empirical tests comparing his presented model to commonly used valuation models, the author demonstrates that together these contributions result in improved accuracy and variability of valuation estimates, leading to a new method of discounted cash flow analysis that is more robust and more accurate than other commonly employed alternatives.</description><author>Cruise, Bill</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Myth of the Monkey</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Snigaroff, Robert
This article considers whether asset managers provide economic benefit even though their excess returns, on average, at best equal zero. A simple thought experiment demonstrates that they do. Although researchers have studied efficiency via competition across firms, a more general definition of market efficiency is where the industry total product reaches a maximum. Market efficiency has little to do with managers' average excess returns-that is, whether managers beat an index. This is easy to see when asset management, and financing activities in general, are modeled as a type of production function and exist as a part of the real economy.</description><author>Snigaroff, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Technical Analysis Profitable for Individual Currency Traders?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abbey, Boris S.; Doukas, John A.
In this article, the authors examine whether technical currency trading by individual currency traders is profitable. The results show technical analysis is negatively associated with performance. Furthermore, the technical trading model developed adequately describes the cross-section of returns for individual currency traders. This result arises because individual currency traders use well-known technical indicators to trade currencies, which implies that such currency traders suffer from reduced performance.</description><author>Abbey, Boris S.; Doukas, John A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Information Content of Real Estate Derivative Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bond, Shaun A.; Mitchell, Paul
The objective of this research was to assess whether forward returns implied by real estate derivative prices provide a more accurate measure of future real estate returns than a consensus forecast of industry experts. Implied returns derived from real estate derivative prices are often used by industry participants as forecasts of future returns, even though the theoretical justification for this is limited. Bond and Mitchell's analysis suggests that since the introduction of real estate derivatives in the U.K., real estate derivatives prices have provided a better indication of future returns than a consensus forecast. But most of this apparent superior performance can be attributed to publication delays with the consensus forecasts. When adjusted for publication delay, the information content of real estate derivatives is shown to be remarkably similar to the consensus forecasts. The authors also caution that as the market for real estate derivatives develops, a greater divergence may emerge between market forecasts and real estate derivatives prices.</description><author>Bond, Shaun A.; Mitchell, Paul</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage Flows and Commercial Property Price Cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clayton, Jim; Peng, Liang
In this article, Clayton and Peng hypothesize that commercial real estate value appreciation affects commercial mortgage supply, which helps constitute a feedback loop between mortgage supply and real estate values that drives real estate cycles. Clayton and Peng estimate a two-equation reduced form of a structural model of mortgage demand and supply, using quarterly U.S. data from 1978 to 2008. The results indicate that past real estate value appreciation positively affects mortgage fund flows but not mortgage interest rates, which substantiates the effect of real estate value appreciation on the supply of mortgages.</description><author>Clayton, Jim; Peng, Liang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Evaluation of Normative Commercial Real Estate Swap Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rehring, Christian; Steininger, Bertram I.
Despite the fact that commercial real estate is composed of a large proportion of investable assets, a functioning derivatives market for private real estate has only existed since early 2005 when swap contracts began to be traded in the U.K. in significant amounts. Among other concerns about commercial real estate derivatives, the pricing issue is a major obstacle for the development of the market due to the specific characteristics of appraisal-based indices used as the underlying of these derivatives. In this article, Rehring and Steininger empirically evaluate a model of normative commercial real estate swap pricing, based on private real estate market indices, by estimating future appraisal-based index returns and accounting for time-varying equilibrium risk premia. The authors analyze the differences between the U.S. and the U.K. They interpret the development of actual commercial real estate swap prices in recent years in light of calculated "fair" swap prices. Qualitatively, the estimated swap prices track actual market developments quite well, indicating that the modeled swap prices enhance our understanding of the pricing of commercial real estate swaps.</description><author>Rehring, Christian; Steininger, Bertram I.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>European CMBS Pricing: Bond, Mortgage, and Real Estate Characteristics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marcato, Gianluca; Tira, Giovanni Alberto
The recent global economic crisis is often associated with the development and pricing of mortgage-backed securities (MBS) and underlying products (i.e., subprime mortgages). In their research, Marcato and Tira use a rich database of MBS issues and present the first attempt to price commercial MBS (CMBS) in the European market. Their results are consistent with research carried out in the U.S. market. They find that multinational as well as bond-, mortgage-, and real estate-related characteristics show different degrees of significance in explaining European CMBS spreads at issuance. Multiple linear regression analysis, using a databank of CMBSs issued between 1997 and 2007, indicates a strong relationship with bond-related factors, followed by real estate and mortgage market conditions. Marcato and Tira also find that multinational factors are significant, with country of issuance, collateral location, and access to more-liquid markets all being important in explaining the cost of secured funding for real estate companies. As floater-coupon tranches tend to be riskier and exhibit higher spreads, they also estimate a model using this subset of data. The results hold and hence reinforce their findings. Finally, the authors estimate their model for both tranches A and B and find that real estate factors become relatively more important for the riskier investment products.</description><author>Marcato, Gianluca; Tira, Giovanni Alberto</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Changing Face of Real Estate Investment Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clayton, Jim; Fabozzi, Frank J.; Giliberto, S. Michael; Gordon, Jacques N.; Hudson-Wilson, Susan; Hughes, William; Liang, Youguo; MacKinnon, Greg; Mansour, Asieh
The real estate investment management industry has been undergoing a process of change over the last two decades. The market is far more transparent than it once was due to the availability of far more, and more detailed, market information. Combined with the increasing integration of real estate with the broader capital markets, this has led to a market that reacts more quickly to events, exhibits more volatility, and in which the nature of risk has changed. These ongoing changes in the market, combined with the lessons of the financial crisis, have resulted in risk management becoming a topic of primary importance in real estate investment. Changes in the nature of real estate risk and the increased emphasis on risk management have the potential to create substantial changes in the real estate investment management industry going forward. The greatest challenge for the industry will be cultural-an understanding of risk, its sources, and its management will need to become central to investment decision making.</description><author>Clayton, Jim; Fabozzi, Frank J.; Giliberto, S. Michael; Gordon, Jacques N.; Hudson-Wilson, Susan; Hughes, William; Liang, Youguo; MacKinnon, Greg; Mansour, Asieh</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Securitization Work? Economic, Structural, and Policy Considerations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Riddiough, Timothy J.
Structured asset securitization is capable of generating a number of economic benefits including liquidity provision, an increased ability to manage risk, and value enhancement through the pooling and partitioning of cash flows. But the recent financial crisis has exposed numerous structural flaws, which has led many observers to question whether asset- and mortgage-backed securities should be classified as financial weapons of mass destruction" that require strict containment and possibly even elimination. In this article, Riddiough considers the fundamental economic trade-offs associated with securitization with an eye toward policy development, concluding that asset securitization can work. Whether it actually will work depends on how policymakers respond to the significant challenges of reregulating the financial system.</description><author>Riddiough, Timothy J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploiting Property Characteristics in Commercial Real Estate Portfolio Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Plazzi, Alberto; Torous, Walter; Valkanov, Rossen
Plazzi, Torous, and Valkanov use a parametric portfolio approach to estimate optimal commercial real estate portfolio policies. They do so by relying on the NCREIF dataset of commercial properties over the sample period 1984 Q2-2009 Q1. The richness of this extensive dataset and the flexibility of the parametric portfolio approach allow the authors to consider: 1) a large cross section of individual properties across various regions and property types, 2) several property-specific conditioning variables such as cap rates, appraisal values, and vacancy rates, and 3) various macroeconomic factors. Property-specific conditioning information is found to be economically important even for portfolios that are well diversified.</description><author>Plazzi, Alberto; Torous, Walter; Valkanov, Rossen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are All Open-End Core Funds Created Equal?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fairchild, Simon; MacKinnon, Greg; Rodrigues, John
Open-end core real estate funds (OECFs) are an important component of the institutional property markets, but have received scant attention in the research literature. Fairchild, MacKinnon, and Rodrigues examine a sample of OECFs to determine if their underlying portfolios are consistent with common definitions of "core" and to what extent core funds provide beta exposure to the market. Generally, OECFs appear to hold core-type portfolios, but this is not universal. In particular, smaller funds tend to be less diversified and have higher idiosyncratic volatility. Many OECFs have a surprisingly large exposure to development projects. The authors find that leverage also plays a key role in an analysis of OECFs. While most OECF returns are driven by the broad market, OECFs are usually an aggressive play on the market, with each fund's aggressiveness determined by its leverage. Further, although the authors find evidence of persistence in OECF returns, a closer look reveals that this may be due to funds varying their capital structure over time. Overall, while most OECFs appear driven by similar factors, not all are created equal; investors should conduct careful due diligence on their OECF investments, with special attention to fund size and leverage.</description><author>Fairchild, Simon; MacKinnon, Greg; Rodrigues, John</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Accurate Are Commercial Real Estate Appraisals? Evidence from 25 Years of NCREIF Sales Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cannon, Susanne Ethridge; Cole, Rebel A.
In this study, Cannon and Cole provide new evidence on the performance measurement and reporting of commercial real estate returns. They do so by examining the accuracy of commercial real estate appraisals that occurred prior to the sale of properties from the NCREIF National Property Index (NPI) from 1984 to 2010, a period that spans two up-and-down market cycles. The authors find that, on average, appraisals are more than 12% above, or below, subsequent sales prices that take place two quarters following the appraisal. Even in a portfolio context, allowing for offsetting positive and negative differences, appraisals are off by an average 4%-5% of value, even after adjusting for capital appreciation during those two quarters. The authors also provide new evidence regarding how, and by how much, appraised values lag behind sales prices. They find that appraisals appear to lag the true sales prices, falling significantly below in hot markets and remaining significantly above in cold markets. This new evidence provides guidance to investors, regulators, and others about how to interpret real estate indices such as the NPI, which are based on appraised values, in both a rising and a falling market. Finally, the authors find that this "appraisal error" is largely systematic; they can explain more than half of the variation in the signed percentage difference in sales price and appraised value. Hence, appraisal errors are not due solely to property-specific heterogeneity.</description><author>Cannon, Susanne Ethridge; Cole, Rebel A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing Risk and Return: Evidence from a Housing Asset-Pricing Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Case, Karl; Cotter, John; Gabriel, Stuart
Case, Cotter, and Gabriel investigate the risk-return relationship in the determination of housing asset pricing. In so doing, they evaluate the behavioral hypotheses advanced by Case and Shiller in studies of boom and post-boom housing markets. The authors specify a multifactor housing asset-pricing model and evaluate whether the market factor and other measures of risk, including idiosyncratic risk, momentum, and MSA size effects, have explanatory power for metropolitan-specific housing returns. Further, they test the robustness of the asset pricing results to inclusion of controls for socioeconomic variables commonly represented in the house price literature, including changes in employment, affordability, and foreclosure incidence, and find a sizable and statistically significant influence of the market factor on MSA house price returns. Moreover, they show that market betas have varied substantially over time. Results are largely robust to the inclusion of other explanatory variables, including standard measures of risk and other housing market fundamentals. Additional tests of model validity using the Fama-MacBeth framework offer further strong support of a positive risk-and-return relationship in housing. Case, Cotter, and Gabriel's findings are supportive of the application of a housing investment risk-return framework in explanation of the variation in the metro-area cross section and time series of U.S. house price returns. Further, results strongly corroborate the Case-Shiller survey research, which indicates the importance of speculative forces in the determination of U.S. housing returns.</description><author>Case, Karl; Cotter, John; Gabriel, Stuart</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Property-Level Performance Attribution: Investment Management Diagnostics and the Investment Importance of Property Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, Tony; Geltner, David
Feng and Geltner describe a field demonstration of a new technique for property-level performance attribution based on the since-acquisition internal rate of return of the investment. The internal rate of return is parsed among the components of initial yield, cash flow change, and yield change, each of which (along with the overall internal rate of return) is compared against a NCREIF-based custom benchmark for each property over the same investment horizon. Among these three, cash flow change particularly reflects the investor's property-level operational management over the holding period. The analysis is then applied across the Client Fund's entire property portfolio to derive diagnostic indications about the strengths and weaknesses of the Fund's investment management. The technique is applied to 42 institutional-quality property investments from acquisition through disposition spanning 1983-2008. In this case, the Client Fund is found to show strength (relative to NCREIF peers) in acquisition, but relative weakness in long-term post-acquisition operational management at the property level. The authors also find wide dispersion in outcomes at the property level, with a clear management pattern in the outlier, most successful cases of superior property-level operational management. Hence, improving property-level operational management emerges in the example portfolio as a key to better overall investment performance. Feng and Geltner speculate that this pattern may often be the case in large institutional funds due to their financial strength, which draws a first look at the best deals, but is offset by disadvantages in subsequent long-run operational management and disposition.</description><author>Feng, Tony; Geltner, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting the Impact of Large Assets on Real Estate Portfolio Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Esrig, Dave; Hudgins, Michael C.; Cerreta, Luigi
In this article, Esrig, Hudgins, and Cerreta investigate if large properties have outperformed the institutional property market over time. This topic is relevant for real estate investors and portfolio managers considering property size as a way to differentiate portfolio performance. The body of academic literature on large asset performance is inconclusive due to issues in applied methodologies and definitions. This study uses a new methodology that corrects for property type, stale appraisals, and restricts "large" to the relatively selective and well-defined group that would strike a knowledgeable institutional investor as truly large. The authors also look at performance of large assets across major and non-major markets. Key findings are that large assets, as most reasonably defined, have historically outperformed other properties in the NCREIF database on an absolute and a risk-adjusted basis. This finding applies to all three sectors the authors tested: office, multifamily, and retail. Property size remains an important factor after correcting for large asset overrepresentation in six major markets.</description><author>Esrig, Dave; Hudgins, Michael C.; Cerreta, Luigi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>130/30: By How Much Will the Information Ratio Improve?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tol, Ramon; Wanningen, Christiaan
nan</description><author>Tol, Ramon; Wanningen, Christiaan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Multi-Asset Approach to Inflation Hedging for a US Investor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruno, Salvatore; Chincarini, Ludwig
nan</description><author>Bruno, Salvatore; Chincarini, Ludwig</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Avoiding a Billion Dollar Federal Financial Technology Rat Hole</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leinweber, David
nan</description><author>Leinweber, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Art of Investing According to Keynes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holder, Mark E.; Kent, Richard J.
nan</description><author>Holder, Mark E.; Kent, Richard J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Clash of the Cultures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bogle, John C.
nan</description><author>Bogle, John C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Dynamic Future for Active Quant Investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xi; Sullivan, Rodney N.
nan</description><author>Li, Xi; Sullivan, Rodney N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Determinants of the Importance of Asset Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobsen, Brian; Biwer, Thomas
nan</description><author>Jacobsen, Brian; Biwer, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Portfolio Size Effect and Lifecycle Asset Allocation Funds: A Different Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pfau, Wade D.
nan</description><author>Pfau, Wade D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Sentiment, Stock Characteristics, and Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Statman, Meir
nan</description><author>Statman, Meir</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Spread Decomposition: Decomposing Bond-Level Credit OAS into Default and Liquidity Components</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dastidar, Siddhartha G.; Phelps, Bruce D.
nan</description><author>Dastidar, Siddhartha G.; Phelps, Bruce D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fighting the Next Battle: Redefining the Inflation-Protected Portfolio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ruff, Jon; Childers, Vince
nan</description><author>Ruff, Jon; Childers, Vince</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are There Benefits from Dynamic Asset Allocation Strategies Across Hedge Funds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Switzer, Lorne N.; Omelchak, Andrey
nan</description><author>Switzer, Lorne N.; Omelchak, Andrey</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Intriguing Case of KMP and KMR</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornell, Bradford
nan</description><author>Cornell, Bradford</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence on Dynamic Loss Aversion from Currency Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Froot, Kenneth; Arabadjis, John; Cates, Sonya; Lawrence, Stephen
Currency investors exhibit a tendency to cut risk by pairing both longs and shorts following losses and a weaker tendency to add risk following gains. By differentiating between position-level, portfolio-level, and aggregate cross-portfolio losses in currency investments, the authors demonstrate that this dynamic loss aversion spans multiple frames of reference. Losses are not compartmentalized, but rather a loss in one currency may impact trading in another. The authors also show that while the impact of a loss on subsequent trading decisions does linger, the effect declines sharply after a losing position is closed.</description><author>Froot, Kenneth; Arabadjis, John; Cates, Sonya; Lawrence, Stephen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Diversity and the Performance of Actively Managed Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agapova, Anna; Ferguson, Robert; Greene, Jason
Agapova, Ferguson, and Greene examine a theoretically motivated measure of the "size effect" known as market diversity and link it to the relative returns of institutional actively managed portfolios. Market diversity reflects how disperse or concentrated capital is across firms in the market, with changes in market diversity reflecting movement of capital between relatively large firms to relatively small firms. Changes in market diversity explain a statistically and economically significant amount of variation in the relative returns of actively managed institutional large-cap strategies. The authors estimate that an increase (decrease) in market diversity of 1% leads to an average increase (decrease) in relative returns of approximately 30 basis points, with higher tracking error strategies showing relatively more sensitivity. They find that another measure of the size effect, the Fama-French small-minus-big factor, explains less of the variation in actively managed large-cap strategies' relative returns and is rejected in favor of changes in market diversity as the underlying explanatory variable for actively managed strategies' relative returns. The authors suggest that market diversity provides academics and practitioners an important measure of market conditions when evaluating the performance of actively managed portfolios.</description><author>Agapova, Anna; Ferguson, Robert; Greene, Jason</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Tactical Sector Allocation: A Quantitative Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doeswijk, Ronald; van Vliet, Pim
Doeswijk and van Vliet examine seven variables for global tactical sector allocation (GTSA) purposes. They construct 10 global sector indices over the extended sample period from 1970 to 2008, enabling them to test previously documented variables on a global basis and to examine whether they continued to work after their publication dates. Doeswijk and van Vliet document significant returns for the following strategies: momentum (1-month and 12-1 month), earnings revisions, and sell-in-May seasonal, also after their publication dates. By contrast, monetary policy and valuation (mean reversion and dividend yield) fail to predict global sector returns. The authors' out-of-sample tests reveal an average decay in performance of about one-third. A long short GTSA strategy that combines momentum with seasonal has an annual success ratio of 82% and delivers a compounded annual return of 9.9% after transaction costs. The authors believe that a global sector allocation study with such a long sample period and with such a broad range of variables has not been conducted before.</description><author>Doeswijk, Ronald; van Vliet, Pim</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Breadth, Skill, and Time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinold, Richard C.; Kahn, Ronald N.
The information ratio determines the potential of an investment process to add value, and according to the fundamental law of active management, adding value depends on a combination of skill and breadth. Grinold and Kahn use an equilibrium dynamic model to provide insight into the concept of breadth, as well as a refined notion of skill. In equilibrium, the arrival rate of new information exactly balances the decay rate of old information. Grinold and Kahn denote the information turnover rate g. It is relatively easy to measure for any investment process. If the investment process forecasts returns on N assets, the breadth of the strategy i is g . N. Skill-the correlation of forecasts and returns-increases with the return horizon for small horizons, but then asymptotically decays to zero for very long horizons. The authors' main result is that the ex ante information ratio is IR=kappa.root g.N, where kappa is a measure of skill.</description><author>Grinold, Richard C.; Kahn, Ronald N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Remembering Barbara S. Bernstein</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Allison
nan</description><author>Adams, Allison</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Auditor Independence? Time to Eliminate the Question Mark</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Polimeni, Ralph S.; Burke, Jacqueline A.
nan</description><author>Polimeni, Ralph S.; Burke, Jacqueline A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Herd on the Street</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwartz, Robert A.; Jupiter, Daniel C.; Schlumprecht, Thomas
nan</description><author>Schwartz, Robert A.; Jupiter, Daniel C.; Schlumprecht, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tactical Allocation by Credit Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fridson, Martin; Mcleod-Salmon, Camille
Tactical asset allocators operate on the assumption that if risk premiums increase, higher-rated bonds will outperform lower-rated bonds, and that if risk premiums decrease, the reverse will happen. Empirical testing shows, however, that about 30% of the time, these expected relationships break down. Drawing on a classic debate among corporate bond market participants, investors might hypothesize that tactical asset allocators can improve their results by classifying bonds according to market-based risk premiums rather than by agency-generated ratings. In the context of tactical asset allocation, however, Fridson and Mcleod-Salmon do not find the market to be a shrewder judge of credit risk than the rating agencies. The solution to the problem of perverse outcomes in credit-oriented tactical asset allocation may be to combine top-down sector selection techniques with bottom-up security selection.</description><author>Fridson, Martin; Mcleod-Salmon, Camille</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simple and Robust Risk Budgeting with Expected Shortfall</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Philips, Thomas; Liu, Michael
Portfolio managers who exploit diversified sources of alpha have traditionally allocated risk among these alpha sources using Markowitz's mean-variance paradigm. While this paradigm works well when returns are normally distributed, it is far less effective when the strategies have significant tail risk, as is often the case in fixed income. In this article, the authors describe a new risk budgeting algorithm that allocates risk among fixed-income strategies in a way that takes into account both their tracking error and their tail risk, and which charts a pragmatic middle course between the elegant simplicity of mean-variance optimization and the computational complexity of most robust risk allocation algorithms. It is, to the best of the authors' knowledge, the first robust risk budgeting algorithm that can be solved in closed form on the back of an envelope. The algorithm inherits its closed-form solvability from a pragmatic compromise the authors make they keep one foot in the "old world" by beginning with using variance as the measure of risk, and then plant the other foot firmly in the "new world" by switching at an appropriate point to using expected shortfall as the measure of risk. It works well in practice in spite of its simplicity and yields fixed-income risk allocations that reflect both a portfolio manager's and a risk manager's intuition better than does a standard mean-variance risk budget.</description><author>Philips, Thomas; Liu, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Return Expectations and P/E10</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benson, Earl D.; Bortner, Ben D.; Kong, Sophie
Benson, Bortner, and Kong estimate the return on equities using the matrix approach suggested by Bogle in 1991. In addition to Bogle's approach, the authors incorporate share repurchases as suggested by Grinold and Kroner in 2002 and by Shiller's P/E10. They demonstrate that this relatively simple approach provides reasonable estimates of subsequent 10-year returns for the S&amp;P 500 Index. The authors also focus on the relationship between the P/E10 ratio and the market's subsequent return. The authors demonstrate that when P/E10 is at low (high) levels in its historic range, the subsequent average 10-year market returns are relatively high (low or negative). When subsequent 3- and 5-year returns are examined, the relationship between P/E10 and subsequent average annual returns is even stronger. Finally, the authors' analysis suggests that the demonstrated approach may be used to estimate returns for various market sectors or indices by applying the approach to estimating the returns on three Russell indices.</description><author>Benson, Earl D.; Bortner, Ben D.; Kong, Sophie</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Hybrid Approach to Combining CART and Logistic Regression for Stock Ranking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Min; Philpotts, David; Sparks, Ross; Stevenson, Maxwell J.
The performance of a stock relative to a suitable peer group is often influenced by a multitude of factors and their interactions. Traditional parametric models, albeit very useful, are often inadequate in capturing complicated relationships. In contrast, the nonparametric decision tree technique, such as classification and regression trees (CART), is more capable of capturing any nonlinearities and high-order interactions among stock characteristics, with the additional convenience of graphically representing the model, but discontinuous and coarse-grained responses produced by CART are potentially undesirable. In contrast, traditional regression models such as logistic regression produce a smooth response surface, which is more tractable in practice. The authors use a hybrid approach that takes advantage of the strengths in both parametric (logistic regression) and nonparametric models (CART). An application of this sophisticated technique to North American defensive stocks demonstrates its usefulness.</description><author>Zhu, Min; Philpotts, David; Sparks, Ross; Stevenson, Maxwell J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Active Management Provide Investor Surplus?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobsen, Brian J.
A consumer experiences consumer surplus when she pays less than her reservation price for a product. Similarly, an investor experiences investor surplus when he would be willing to pay more than the charge to invest in a particular instrument or portfolio. Typically, a portfolio manager generates investor surplus by delivering alpha. Jacobsen formally shows in this article that a portfolio manager can also generate investor surplus by having asymmetric betas, that is, when the beta in up markets is different than the beta in down markets. Because no one forces investors to buy active management, they must perceive benefits that exceed the cost. Some of these benefits (custody, diversification, accounting, partial share ownership) are also available from passive strategies; others (expected differences in up and down market betas, alphas, optionality, cocktail party conversation) are only available from active management.</description><author>Jacobsen, Brian J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is There a Bubble in LinkedIn's Stock Price?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jarrow, Robert; Kchia, Younes; Protter, Philip
Recent academic work has developed a method to determine in real time if a given stock is exhibiting a price bubble. Currently, speculation exists in the financial press concerning the existence of a price bubble in the aftermath of the recent IPO of LinkedIn. The authors analyze stock price tick data from the short lifetime of LinkedIn stock through May 24, 2011, and find that Linkedln stock has a price bubble.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert; Kchia, Younes; Protter, Philip</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Event-Driven Trading and the "New News"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leinweber, David; Sisk, Jacob
Two information revolutions are underway in trading and investing. Most headlines focus on structured quantitative market information at ever higher frequencies, but the other technology revolution in trading and investing is driven by qualitative, textual, and relationship information. The IBM computer Watson's overwhelming Jeopardy victory demonstrated how good machines can get at this. News analysis is a focus of language technology in finance. In this article, Leinweber and Sisk include event studies and show U.S. portfolio simulation results for "pure news" signals applied over the period 2006-2009 as well as a true out-of-sample period in 2010, which indicates alpha in excess of 10% a year. The authors also describe other applications of automated qualitative analysis for information-driven social media client relations.</description><author>Leinweber, David; Sisk, Jacob</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Microstructure of the "Flash Crash": Flow Toxicity, Liquidity Crashes, and the Probability of Informed Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; de Prado, Marcos M. Lopez; O'Hara, Maureen
nan</description><author>Easley, David; de Prado, Marcos M. Lopez; O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fat-Tailed Models for Risk Estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoyanov, Stoyan V.; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Racheva-Yotova, Boryana; Fabozzi, Frank J.
nan</description><author>Stoyanov, Stoyan V.; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Racheva-Yotova, Boryana; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Contribution Is Exposure Times Volatility Times Correlation: Decomposing Risk Using the X-Sigma-Rho Formula</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menchero, Jose; Davis, Ben
nan</description><author>Menchero, Jose; Davis, Ben</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Lifecycle Strategies for Target Date Retirement Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basu, Anup K.; Byrne, Alistair; Drew, Michael E.
nan</description><author>Basu, Anup K.; Byrne, Alistair; Drew, Michael E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Allocation under Extreme Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farrell, James L.
nan</description><author>Farrell, James L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy Portfolios and Rebalancing Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leibowitz, Martin L.; Bova, Anthony
nan</description><author>Leibowitz, Martin L.; Bova, Anthony</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active Currency Investing and Performance Benchmarks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Melvin, Michael; Shand, Duncan
nan</description><author>Melvin, Michael; Shand, Duncan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minimum-Variance Portfolio Composition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, Roger; de Silva, Harindra; Thorley, Steven
nan</description><author>Clarke, Roger; de Silva, Harindra; Thorley, Steven</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Description of Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinold, Richard
nan</description><author>Grinold, Richard</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Graceful Aging of Mean-Variance Optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kritzman, Mark
nan</description><author>Kritzman, Mark</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In Diversification We Trust?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amenc, Noel; Martellini, Lionel
nan</description><author>Amenc, Noel; Martellini, Lionel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Small Firm Effect: A Financial Mirage?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Haim; Levy, Moshe
nan</description><author>Levy, Haim; Levy, Moshe</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Best Practice Investment Committees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, Charles D.
nan</description><author>Ellis, Charles D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>