<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Banking &amp; Finance19</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Is a moral disposition rewarded?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grossman, H. I.; Kim, M.
This paper explores the conditions under which a moral disposition is rewarded, in the sense of moral people being more prosperous than amoral people. The analytical framework is a general equilibrium model in which production is more lucrative for moral people than for amoral people, but in which amoral people can choose to be predators rather than producers. We find that, regardless of the advantage that moral people have in production, a moral disposition is rewarded if and only if the ratio of amoral people to moral people is large relative to a parameter that embodies the technology of predation. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grossman, H. I.; Kim, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust and efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chami, R.; Fullenkamp, C.
Agency problems within the firm are a significant hindrance to efficiency. We propose trust between coworkers as a superior alternative to the standard tools used to mitigate agency problems: increased monitoring and incentive-based pay. We model trust as mutual, reciprocal altruism between pairs of coworkers and show how it induces employees to work harder, relative to those at firms that use the standard tools. In addition, we show that employees at trusting firms have higher job satisfaction, and that these firms enjoy lower labor cost and higher profits. We conclude by discussing how trust may also be easier to use within the firm than the standard agency-mitigation tools. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chami, R.; Fullenkamp, C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trustworthiness and self-interest</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hausman, D. M.
This essay discusses the benefits to a firm from morality - specifically trustworthiness - by exploring the analogy between firms and individuals. It identifies five factors that help to align trustworthiness and the interest of an individual: (1) reputation, (2) the social limits on how much trustworthiness demands, (3) uncertainty, (4) the ambiguities of self-interest, and (5) the role of trustworthiness in constituting an individual's interest. Each of these factors has analogues in the case of a firm, and the essay suggests the slightly paradoxical conclusion that in certain environments firms may serve the interests of their stakeholders by placing moral constraints on their actions. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hausman, D. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing ethical risk: How investing in ethics adds value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chami, R.; Cosimano, T. F.; Fullenkamp, C.
In September 1999, the University of Notre Dame hosted a conference entitled "Measuring and Managing Ethical Risk: How Investing in Ethics Adds Value". The motivations for hosting the conference and the papers presented there are summarized. Several themes that are present in the papers are discussed. These include the gains from combining the anthropological approach to business ethics with the neoclassical economics approach, the central role of trust in business ethics, the role of ethics in the corporation, and the function of the legal system in setting and enforcing ethical standards for the financial system. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chami, R.; Cosimano, T. F.; Fullenkamp, C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The securities industry and the law</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bear, L. A.; Maldonado-Bear, R.
We examine the interplay of markets, ethics and law, and rising demand for ethical behavior in a market driven society coping with the promise and peril of rapid technological innovation. We analyze the market affecting role of our Common Law/Rule of Law System, its adaptability to social need, and resultant legal and regulatory action promoting adherence to the spirit as well as the letter of the law. We provide examples of manager and firm harm from sanctions imposed despite adherence to "the rules." Finally, we discuss competitive market-common law interplay in the coming era of the genome. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bear, L. A.; Maldonado-Bear, R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Grand" corruption and the ethics of global business</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rose-Ackerman, S.
The paper explores the ethical obligations of global business to refrain from corruption. Corruption is harmful for the growth prospects of host countries and can introduce inefficiencies and inequities. 1 argue that business corporations have an obligation to refrain from illegal payoffs as part of the quid pro quo implied by the laws that permit corporations to exist and to operate. The paper goes on to consider how firms might respond, and isolates situations where anti-corruption policies can be profitable for firms. It concludes with an analysis of international efforts to deter transnational bribery and with suggestions for additional international initiatives. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rose-Ackerman, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using deferred compensation to strengthen the ethics of financial regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kane, E. J.
Defects in the corporate governance of government-owned enterprises tempt opportunistic officials to breach duties of public stewardship. Corporate-governance theory suggests that incentive-based deferred compensation could intensify the force that common-law duties actually exert on regulatory managers. In principle, a forfeitable fund of deferred compensation could be combined with provisions for measuring, verifying, and rewarding multi period performance to make top regulators accountable for maximizing the long-run net social benefits their enterprise produces. Because government deposit-insurance enterprises are purveyors of credit enhancements for which private substitute and reinsurance markets exist, their performance could be measured accurately enough to make employment contracts for deposit-insurance CEOs a promising place to experiment with this kind of accountability reform. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kane, E. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign and domestic investors and tax induced ex-dividend day trading (vol 25, pg 1687, 2001)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liljeblom, E.; Lflund, A.; Hedvall, K.
nan</description><author>Liljeblom, E.; Lflund, A.; Hedvall, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dispersion measures as immunization risk measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balbas, A.; Ibanez, A.; Lopez, S.
The quadratic and linear cash flow dispersion measures M-2 and (N) over tilde are two immunization risk measures designed to build immunized bond portfolios. This paper generalizes these two measures by showing that any dispersion measure is an immunization risk measure and therefore, it sets up a tool to be used in empirical testing. Each new measure is derived from a different set of shocks (changes on the term structure of interest rates) and depends on the corresponding subset of worst shocks. Consequently, a criterion for choosing appropriate immunization risk measures is to take those developed from the most reasonable sets of shocks and the associated subset of worst shocks and then select those that work best empirically. Adopting this approach, this paper then explores both numerical examples and a short empirical study on the Spanish Bond Market in the mid-1990s to show that measures between linear and quadratic are the most appropriate. and amongst them, the linear measure has the best properties. This confirms previous studies on US and Canadian markets that maturity-constrained-duration-matched portfolios also have good empirical behavior. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Balbas, A.; Ibanez, A.; Lopez, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage bounds in markets with noisy prices and the puzzle of negative option prices implicit in bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ioffe, L. D.
The term structure of interest rates has occupied economists for many years. This is testimony to the importance of the term structure (or, equivalently, valuation operator) and to the difficulty of obtaining reliable estimates of it. Until recently, it was not possible to reconcile the theoretical existence of a multiplicity of valuation operators in an incomplete bond market and the empirical nonexistence of even a single one. MacKay and Prisman [Estimating valuation operators in incomplete market with noises: Can noise complete the market. Working paper, 1996] tackle this problem. In this paper, an amendment to and a generalization of their methodology is presented. The amendment preserves the linearity of valuation operators and allows use of efficient linear programming techniques. Further, it facilitates an admissible consideration of the puzzle of negative option prices embedded in bonds. The empirical results presented in this paper were obtained using data on extendable Government of Canada bonds. The results indicate that although the gap between the lowest and the highest prices assigned to a cash flow by different valuation operators is significant, it is not sufficient to resolve the above-mentioned puzzle. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ioffe, L. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relations among asset risk, product risk, and capital in the life insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baranoff, E. G.; Sager, T. W.
This paper explores the relation between capital and risk in the life insurance industry in the period after the adoption of life risk-based capital (RBC) regulation. To examine this issue, we use a simultaneous-equation partial-adjustment model. Three equations express the interrelations among capital and two measures of risk: product risk and asset risk. The asset-risk measure used in this paper reflects credit or solvency risk as in RBC. Product risk assessment for life insurance products is rationalized by transaction-cost economics - contractual uncertainty. A significant finding is that for life insurers the relation between capital and asset risk is positive. This agrees with prior studies for the property/casualty insurance industry and some banking studies. But the relation between capital and product risk is negative. This is consistent with the hypothesized impact of guarantee funds in other studies. The contrast between the positive relation of capital to asset risk and the negative relation of capital to product risk underscores the importance of distinguishing these two components of risk. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baranoff, E. G.; Sager, T. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Canadian treasury bill auction and the term structure of interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Godbout, L.; Storer, P.; Zimmermann, C.
This paper examines the efficiency of the Canadian treasury bill market as measured by the performance of the expectations model of the term structure of interest rates. In particular, market efficiency is shown to depend upon certain institutional features of the treasury bill auction process. Building on past work by B. Campbell and J.W. Galbraith [Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics 59 (2) (1997) 265-284]. the paper establishes links between rejections of efficiency and high absolute values of the spread between six- and three-month interest rates. The major contribution of the paper is to then show that a link exists between weeks in which spreads are large and weeks in which accepted auction yields show a large degree of dispersion. The paper discusses the implications of these findings for the term structure literature and for possible auction configurations currently under consideration in Canada and the US. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Godbout, L.; Storer, P.; Zimmermann, C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pay at the executive suite: How do US banks compensate their top management teams?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, J.; Lauterbach, B.; Schreiber, B. Z.
This study examines how a large sample of US banks compensates their top management teams (i.e., the top four to five highest ranking executives in each bank). We observe two tiers of compensation in the executive suite: the Chief Executive Officer (CEO) and the rest of the top management team. CEOs receive not only greater pay in absolute dollar, but are also rewarded more in relation to performance, as manifested in having a larger portion of their pay in performance contingent compensation. Below the CEO, top executives have similar compensation structure and pay to performance elasticities. The results are robust to a significant size effect, and alternate measures of performance. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, J.; Lauterbach, B.; Schreiber, B. Z.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market linkages: Evidence from Latin America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, G. M.; Firth, M.; Rui, O. M.
This study investigates the dynamic interdependence of the major stock markets in Latin America. Using data from 1995 to 2000, we examine the stock market indexes of Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Mexico and Venezuela. The index level series are non-stationary and so we employ cointegration analysis and error correction vector autoregressions (VAR) techniques to model the interdependencies. We find that there is one cointegrating vector which appears to explain the dependencies in prices. The results are robust to sensitivity tests based on translating indexes to US dollars (i.e., a common currency for all the markets) and to partitioning the sample into periods before and after the Asian and Russian financial crises of 1997 and 1998, respectively. Our results suggest that the potential for diversifying risk by investing in different Latin American markets is limited. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, G. M.; Firth, M.; Rui, O. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational infinitely lived asset prices must be non-stationary</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roll, R.
Rational expectations must not be expected to change. Hence, a rational expectation about a future random quantity follows a pure martingale until the uncertainty is resolved. This implies that the expectation itself could be non-stationary and, in fact, is non-stationary if the increments are iid. Most asset prices are functions of expectations about future quantities, so asset prices also could be non-stationary. This has consequences for tests based on prices rather than on returns. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roll, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Putting order in risk measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frittelli, M.; Gianin, E. R.
This paper introduces a set of axioms that define convex risk measures. Duality theory provides the representation theorem for these measures and the link with pricing rules. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Frittelli, M.; Gianin, E. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No more VaR (this is not a typo)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szego, G. P.
nan</description><author>Szego, G. P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measures of risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szego, G.
The conditions under which the classical measures of risk like the mean, the linear correlation coefficient and VaR can be used are discussed. The definition of risk measure and the main recently proposed risk measures are presented. The problems connected with co-dependence are outlined. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Szego, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The emperor has no clothes: Limits to risk modelling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danielsson, J.
This paper considers the properties of risk measures, primarily value-at-risk (VaR), from both internal and external (regulatory) points of view. It is argued that since market data is endogenous to market behavior, statistical analysis made in times of stability does not provide much guidance in times of crisis. In an extensive survey across data classes and risk models, the empirical properties of current risk forecasting models are found to be lacking in robustness while being excessively volatile. For regulatory use, the VaR measure may give misleading information about risk, and in some cases may actually increase both idiosyncratic and systemic risk. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Danielsson, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pure jump Levy processes for asset price modelling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geman, H.
The goal of the paper is to show that some types of Levy processes such as the hyperbolic motion and the CGMY are particularly suitable for asset price modelling and option pricing. We wish to review some fundamental mathematic properties of Levy distributions, such as the one of infinite divisibility, and how they translate observed features of asset price returns. We explain how these processes are related to Brownian motion, the central process in finance, through stochastic time changes which can in turn be interpreted as a measure of the economic activity. Lastly, we focus on two particular classes of pure jump Levy processes, the generalized hyperbolic model and the CGMY models, and report on the goodness of fit obtained both on stock prices and option prices. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Geman, H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>VaR and expected shortfall in portfolios of dependent credit risks: Conceptual and practical insights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frey, R.; McNeil, A. J.
In the first part of this paper we address the non-coherence of value-at-risk (VaR) as a risk measure in the context of portfolio credit risk, and highlight some problems which follow from this theoretical deficiency. In particular, a realistic demonstration of the non-subadditivity of VaR is given and the possibly nonsensical consequences of VaR-based portfolio optimisation are shown. The second part of the paper discusses VaR and expected shortfall estimation for large balanced credit portfolios. All standard industry models (Creditmetrics, KMV, CreditRisk(+)) are presented as Bernoulli mixture models to facilitate their direct comparison. For homogeneous groups it is shown that measures of tail risk for the loss distribution may be approximated in large portfolios by analysing the tail of the mixture distribution in the Bernoulli representation. An example is given showing that, for portfolios of lower quality, choice of model has some impact on measures of extreme risk. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frey, R.; McNeil, A. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Saddlepoint approximation of CreditRisk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gordy, M. B.
CreditRisk(+) is an influential and widely implemented model of portfolio credit risk. As a close variant of models long used for insurance risk, it retains the analytical tractability for which the insurance models were designed. Value-at-risk (VaR) can be obtained via a recurrence-rule algorithm, so Monte Carlo simulation can be avoided. Little recognized, however, is that the algorithm is fragile. Under empirically realistic conditions, numerical error can accumulate in the execution of the recurrence rule and produce wildly inaccurate results for VaR. This paper provides new tools for users of CreditRisk(+) based on the cumulant generating function (cgf) of the portfolio loss distribution. Direct solution for the moments of the loss distribution from the cgf is almost instantaneous and is computationally robust. Thus, the moments provide a convenient, quick and independent diagnostic on the implementation and execution of the standard solution algorithm. Better still, with the cgf in hand we have an alternative to the standard algorithm. I show how tail percentiles of the loss distribution can be calculated quickly and easily by saddlepoint approximation. On a large and varied sample of simulated test portfolios, I find a natural complementarity between the two algorithms: Saddlepoint approximation is accurate and robust in those situations for which the standard algorithm performs least well, and is less accurate in those situations for which the standard algorithm is fast and reliable. Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Gordy, M. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tail estimation and mean-VaR portfolio selection in markets subject to financial instability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Consigli, G.
Risk managers are increasingly required by international Regulatory Institutions to adopt accurate techniques for the measurement and control of portfolios financial risks. The task requires first the identification of the different risk sources affecting the portfolio and the measurement of their impact, then after: the adoption of appropriate portfolio strategies aimed at neutralising these risks. The comprehensive concept of Value-at-Risk (VaR) as a maximum tolerable loss, with a given confidence interval, has become in this regard the industry standard in risk management. In the paper we focus on the implications of different risk measurement techniques and portfolio optimisation strategies in presence of markets subject to periods of severe instability, resulting in significant deviations of financial returns from the Normality assumption typically adopted in mainstream finance. Comparative results on 1 day-VaR(99%) estimation are presented over a range of bond and equity markets with different risk profiles. The reference period of our analysis includes several market shocks and in particular the Argentinean Eurobond crisis of July 2001. The solution of an optimal portfolio problem over the crisis period is discussed within a [mean, variance, VaR99%] portfolio space, emphasising the difficulty of the portfolio's relative return maximisation problem faced by fund managers. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Consigli, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The estimation of transition matrices for sovereign credit ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Y. T.; Kiesel, R.; Perraudin, W.
Rating transition matrices for sovereigns are an important input to risk management of portfolios of emerging market credit exposures. They are widely used both in credit portfolio management and to calculate future loss distributions for pricing purposes. However, few sovereigns and almost no low credit quality sovereigns have ratings histories longer than a decade, so estimating such matrices is difficult. This paper shows how one may combine information from sovereign defaults observed over a longer period and a broader set of countries to derive estimates of sovereign transition matrices. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Hu, Y. T.; Kiesel, R.; Perraudin, W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives for effective risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danielsson, J.; Jorgensen, B. N.; de Vries, C. G.
Under the new Capital Accord, banks choose between two different types of risk management systems, the standard or the internal rating based approach. The paper considers how a bank's preference for a risk management system is affected by the presence of supervision by bank regulators. The model uses a principal-agent setting between a bank's owner and its risk management. The main conclusion is that previously unregulated institutions can be expected to switch to the lower quality standard approach subsequent to becoming regulated, i.e., the presence of regulation may induce a bank to decrease the quality of its risk management system. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Danielsson, J.; Jorgensen, B. N.; de Vries, C. G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subordinated debt, market discipline, and banks' risk taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blum, J. M.
The present paper demonstrates the ambiguous impact of subordinated debt on the risktaking incentives of banks. It is shown that in comparison with full deposit insurance, subordinated debt reduces risk only if banks can credibly commit to a given level of risk. If, however, banks are not able to commit, subordinated debt leads to an increase in risk. This is because due to limited liability banks always have an incentive to increase their risk after the interest rate is contracted in order to reduce the expected costs of debt. Rational debt holders anticipate this behavior and accordingly require a higher risk premium ex ante. The higher interest rates in turn further aggravate the excessive risk-taking incentives of banks. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blum, J. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional value-at-risk for general loss distributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rockafellar, R. T.; Uryasev, S.
Fundamental properties of conditional value-at-risk (CVaR), as a measure of risk with significant advantages over value-at-risk (VaR), are derived for loss distributions in finance that can involve discreetness. Such distributions are of particular importance in applications because of the prevalence of models based on scenarios and finite sampling. CVaR is able to quantify dangers beyond VaR and moreover it is coherent. It provides optimization short-cuts which, through linear programming techniques, make practical many large-scale calculations that could otherwise be out of reach. The numerical efficiency and stability of such calculations, shown in several case studies, are illustrated further with an example of index tracking. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rockafellar, R. T.; Uryasev, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the coherence of expected shortfall</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acerbi, C.; Tasche, D.
Expected shortfall (ES) in several variants has been proposed as remedy for the deficiencies of value-at-risk (VaR) which in general is not a coherent risk measure. In fact, most definitions of ES lead to the same results when applied to continuous loss distributions. Differences may appear when the underlying loss distributions have discontinuities. In this case even the coherence property of ES can get lost unless one took care of the details in its definition. We compare some of the definitions of ES, pointing out that there is one which is robust in the sense of yielding a coherent risk measure regardless of the underlying distributions. Moreover, this ES can be estimated effectively even in cases where the usual estimators for VaR fail. 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acerbi, C.; Tasche, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spectral measures of risk: A coherent representation of subjective risk aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acerbi, C.
We study a space of coherent risk measures Mphi obtained as certain expansions of coherent elementary basis measures. In this space, the concept of "risk aversion function" phi naturally arises as the spectral representation of each risk measure in a space of functions of confidence level probabilities. We give necessary and sufficient conditions on phi for Mphi to be a coherent measure. We find in this way a simple interpretation of the concept of coherence and a way to map any rational investor's subjective risk aversion onto a coherent measure and vice-versa. We also provide for these measures their discrete versions Mphi((N)) acting on finite sets of N independent realizations of a r.v. which are not only shown to be coherent measures for any fixed N, but also consistent estimators of Mphi for large N. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acerbi, C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected shortfall and beyond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tasche, D.
Financial institutions have to allocate so-called economic capital in order to guarantee solvency to their clients and counterparties. Mathematically speaking, any methodology of allocating capital is a risk measure, i.e. a function mapping random variables to the real numbers. Nowadays value-at-risk (VaR), which is defined as a fixed level quantile of the random variable under consideration, is the most popular risk measure. Unfortunately, it fails to reward diversification, as it is not subadditive. In the search for a suitable alternative to VaR, expected shortfall (ES) (or conditional VaR or tail VaR) has been characterized as the smallest coherent and law invariant risk measure to dominate VaR. We discuss these and some other properties of ES as well as its generalization to a class of coherent risk measures which can incorporate higher moment effects. Moreover, we suggest a general method on how to attribute ES risk contributions to portfolio components. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tasche, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CVaR models with selective hedging for international asset allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Topaloglou, N.; Vladimirou, H.; Zenios, S. A.
We develop an integrated simulation and optimization framework for multicurrency asset allocation problems. The simulation applies principal component analysis to generate scenarios depicting the discrete joint distributions of uncertain asset returns and exchange rates. We then develop and implement models that optimize the conditional-value-at-risk (CVaR) metric. The scenario-based optimization models encompass alternative hedging strategies, including selective hedging that incorporates currency hedging decisions within the portfolio selection problem. Thus, the selective hedging model determines jointly the portfolio composition and the level of currency hedging for each market via forward exchanges. We examine empirically the benefits of international diversification and the impact of hedging policies on risk-return profiles of portfolios. We assess the effectiveness of the scenario generation procedure and the stability of the model's results by means of out-of-sample simulations. We also compare the performance of the CVaR model against that of a model that employs the mean absolute deviation (MAD) risk measure. We investigate empirically the ex post performance of the models on international portfolios of stock and bond indices using historical market data. Selective hedging proves to be the superior hedging strategy that improves the risk-return profile of portfolios regardless of the risk measurement metric. Although in static tests the MAD and CVaR models often select portfolios that trace practically indistinguishable ex ante risk-return efficient frontiers, in successive applications over several consecutive time periods the CVaR model attains superior ex post results in terms of both higher returns and lower volatility. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Topaloglou, N.; Vladimirou, H.; Zenios, S. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mergers and technical efficiency in Spanish savings banks: A stochastic distance function approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cuesta, R. A.; Orea, L.
The aim of this paper is to test the temporal variation of technical efficiency of Spanish savings banks during the period 1985-1998. Furthermore, we test whether merged and non-merged firms have different levels and temporal patterns of technical efficiency. A stochastic output distance function (R.W. Shephard, Theory of Cost and Production Functions, Princeton University Press, Princeton, NJ) is employed to accommodate multiple output technology. The distance function provides the advantage that it does not need information about prices, so it can accommodate the multi-product nature of the financial sector only using the quantities as data (an important point when the assumptions about perfectly competitive markets are unlikely to be met). The temporal variation of efficiency is modeled extending the Battese and Coelli (Journal of Productivity Analysis 3 (1992) 153-169) approach in two ways: relaxing the monotonicity of the temporal variation pattern of the efficiency term, and allowing for different patterns of efficiency change between merged and non-merged firms. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cuesta, R. A.; Orea, L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring by the financial press and forced CEO turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farrell, K. A.; Whidbee, D. A.
This paper examines Wall Street Journal news stories about 79 firms that forced CEO turnover and a matched sample of firms that did not force CEO turnover. In the two years prior to turnover, firms in the forced-turnover sample were the subjects of 76% more news stories about poor firm performance despite being from the same industry, of similar size, and similar performance as a sample of matched firms. Overall, the evidence suggests that scrutiny of poor firm performance by the financial press increases the likelihood of forced CEO turnover. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Farrell, K. A.; Whidbee, D. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market volatility, excess returns, and the role of investor sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, W. Y.; Jiang, C. X.; Indro, D. C.
Using the Investors' Intelligence sentiment index, we employ a generalized autoregressive conditional heteroscedasticity-in-mean specification to test the impact of noise trader risk on both the formation of conditional volatility and expected return as suggested by De Long et al. [Journal of Political Economy 98 (1990) 703]. Our empirical results show that sentiment is a systematic risk that is priced. Excess returns are contemporaneously positively correlated with shifts in sentiment. Moreover, the magnitude of bullish (bearish) changes in sentiment leads to downward (upward) revisions in volatility and higher (lower) future excess returns. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, W. Y.; Jiang, C. X.; Indro, D. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using Bayesian variable selection methods to choose style factors in global stock return models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hall, A. D.; Hwang, S.; Satchell, S. E.
This paper investigates the presence of global style factors in global equity investment. To this end, we apply Bayesian variable selection methods from the statistics literature to give guidance in the decision to include/omit factors in a global (linear factor) stock return model. Once we have accounted for country and sector, it is possible to see which style or styles best explains current asset returns. This study does not find compelling evidence for global styles as useful explanatory factors in a fixed parameter regression model, once country and sector have been accounted for. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hall, A. D.; Hwang, S.; Satchell, S. E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The growth of US credit unions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goddard, J. A.; McKillop, D. G.; Wilson, J. O. S.
The growth of US credit unions during the 1990s is investigated empirically, using univariate and multivariate cross sectional and panel estimation techniques. Univariate tests of the law of proportionate effect suggest that in general large credit unions grew faster than their smaller counterparts. On average credit unions with above-average growth in one period tended to experience below-average growth in the next. Smaller credit unions tended to have more variable growth than large ones. While credit unions share a common co-operative philosophy, they differ in terms of age profile, scope for membership growth, charter type and financial structure and performance. In estimations of a multivariate growth model, most of these characteristics are found to have a significant influence on the size-growth relationship. While large state chartered credit unions grew faster than their smaller counterparts, the reverse was true for federally chartered credit unions. In general, if larger credit unions grew faster than smaller ones, they tended to do so for specific reasons: because their charters were less restrictive, because they were more efficient, or because they had a financial structure that was more conducive to growth. Therefore credit union growth was not 'random', but highly systematic. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goddard, J. A.; McKillop, D. G.; Wilson, J. O. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on the integrability of partial-equilibrium measures of the welfare costs of inflation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cysne, R. P.
Multidimensional measures of the welfare costs of inflation have been employed in the literature without an explicit concern of how the demand for the respective monetary assets are generated and without an investigation of the respective integrability conditions. This note establishes conditions under which such welfare measures are well defined. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cysne, R. P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economies of scale in UK building societies: A re-appraisal using an entry/exit model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drake, L.; Simper, R.
This study advances an entry/exit model to analyse the scale efficiency of UK building societies. We find that there are considerable divergences across building societies in levels of scale efficiency and also in technological change during the sample period 1992-1997. The paper also finds that scale economies and technological change estimates are dependent on whether the econometrician balances a panel data set or utilises the entry/exit model based on Dionne et. al's (1998) specification. In general, scale economies in UK building societies are found to be more significant and more pervasive than in previous studies. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Drake, L.; Simper, R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Visibility of the compass rose in financial asset returns: A quantitative study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, H. Q.; Wang, C.
The compass rose phenomenon is studied based on the random walk model of stock prices. It is found that the structure is inherently present in any financial data having a finite precision, but becomes visible only under some conditions. A quantitative description of the pattern visibility condition is given, providing a method for the interpretation of pattern appearance and a more comprehensive understanding of the compass rose phenomenon. This is achieved by defining a measure of pattern quality. The arguments and the proposed method are supported by numerical examples. One such example is the presentation of patterns in portfolios with some specific weights. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, H. Q.; Wang, C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analytic approach to credit risk of large corporate bond and loan portfolios (vol 25, pg 1635, 2001)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucas, A.; Klaassens, P.; Spreij, P.; Straetmans, S.
nan</description><author>Lucas, A.; Klaassens, P.; Spreij, P.; Straetmans, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational expectations, analysts' forecasts of earnings and sources of value gains for takeover targets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sudarsanam, S.; Salami, A.; Alexandrou, G.
Value gains to tat-get firm shareholders in takeover bids may be due to potential synergy between bidder and target and/or potential target restructuring based on new information released by the bid. Since these two models have different implications for the anticipated earnings of the target as a stand-alone entity, analysts' earnings forecast revisions (AFR) for the target during the bid may provide evidence for the new information hypothesis. For 326 UK targets of takeover bids during 1987-1993, we estimate analysts' earnings forecast revisions using the Institutional Brokers Estimate System (IBES) and relate them to bid premia paid to target shareholders. Analysts revise their forecasts significantly up on bid announcement. For failed, especially failed hostile, bids, the earnings forecast revision and bid premium are more positively correlated than for successful and friendly bids. This is consistent with the rational expectations behaviour of target shareholders modelled by Grossman and Hart [S.J. Grossman, O.D. Hart, Bell Journal of Economics 11 (1) (1980) 42; S.J. Grossman, O.D. Hart, Journal of Finance 36 (1981) 253] (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V, All rights reserved.</description><author>Sudarsanam, S.; Salami, A.; Alexandrou, G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trends in relationship lending and factors affecting relationship lending efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stanton, K. R.
This paper investigates the efficiency of relationship managers at the Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce (CIBC) one of Canada's largest banks. Data envelopment analysis (DEA) efficiency scores are analyzed using regression. The results demonstrate that managers are less efficient when facing larger numbers of loans or smaller loans, M. Berlin and L.J. Mester (On the profitability and cost of relationship lending, Working paper no. 97-43, The What-ton School, University of Pennsylvania, 1997) show that credit smoothing is generally suboptimal. A more complete explanation is obtained by taking a micro-level focus. Other results indicate that banks may improve profitability by reserving relationship lending for loans of larger size. Tests of relationships between efficiency and nonperforming loans and of the skimping hypothesis are conducted. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stanton, K. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of Italian equity funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cesari, R.; Panetta, F.
We estimate the risk-adjusted performance of Italian equity funds, using both net and gross returns (i.e., net returns plus management fees), employing single factor and multifactor benchmarks. With net returns, the funds' performance is not significantly different from zero. With gross returns, however, the performance is always positive, even when we use benchmarks which take account of the non-equity investments of the funds and measures which are not influenced by the market timing behavior of the portfolio managers. Our evidence supports the Grossman and Stiglitz's view of market efficiency, suggesting that informed investors are compensated for their information gathering. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cesari, R.; Panetta, F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An examination of cost structure and production performance of commercial banks in Singapore</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rezvanian, R.; Mehdian, S.
This paper uses a parametric approach in the framework of a translog cost function and a non-parametric approach in the framework of linear programming to examine production performance and cost structure of a sample of Singaporean commercial banks. The results of the parametric methodology suggest that the average cost curve of these banks is U shaped and there are economics of scale for small and medium-size banks. Further analysis provides evidence of economics of scope for all banks regardless of their size. The non-parametric results indicate that the Singaporean banks could have reduced cost by 43% had they all been overall efficient. The sources of this cost inefficiency seem to be caused equally by allocative and technical inefficiencies. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rezvanian, R.; Mehdian, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamic relationship between stock returns and trading volume: Domestic and cross-country evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, B. S.; Rui, O. M.
This paper examines the dynamic relations - causal relations and the sign and magnitude of dynamic effects between stock market trading volume and returns (and volatility) for both domestic and cross-country markets by using the daily data of the three largest stock markets: New York, Tokyo, and London. Major findings are as follows: First, trading volume does not Granger-cause stock market returns on each of three stock markets. Second, there exists a positive feedback relationship between trading volume and return volatility in all three markets. Third, regarding the cross-country relationships, US Financial market variables, in particular US trading volume, contains an extensive predictive power for UK and Japanese financial market variables. Fourth, sub-sample analyses show evidence of stronger spillover effects after the 1987 market crash and an increased importance of trading volume as an information variable after the introduction of options in the US and Japan. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, B. S.; Rui, O. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial compensation contract and bank bailout policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Osano, H.
Under the incomplete contract framework, we consider an optimal regulatory policy for motivating bank equity owners and bank managers to restructure the bad loans of their banks in the presence of managerial compensation contracts with stock options. The regulatory policy studied in this paper is mainly concerned with the design of repayment schedules in the scheme of injection of cash funds into insolvent banks by the regulator. We show that the regulator cannot necessarily attain the social optimal allocation by injecting cash funds into insolvent banks through the purchase of subordinated bonds with the risk-Free interest rate. However, even in that case, we also suggest that, if the regulator injects cash funds into active restructuring banks through the purchase of subordinated bonds or preferred stocks with less stringent repayment conditions and nationalizes passive restructuring banks, the regulator can attain the social optimal allocation by performing such a non-linear injection scheme under certain conditions. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Osano, H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Untitled</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altman, E.; Sarnat, M.; Saunders, A.; Szego, G.
nan</description><author>Altman, E.; Sarnat, M.; Saunders, A.; Szego, G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank capital regulation as an incentive mechanism: Implications for portfolio choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milne, A.
This paper contrasts the conventional interpretation of prudential capital regulation as a system of ex ante enforcement ('hard wired') with an alternative interpretation as a system of sanctions for ex post violation ('incentive based'). Under the incentive based interpretation risk-weightings affect portfolio choice only when assets are illiquid. Under both interpretations, the medium term impact on portfolio allocation depends upon (lie relative costs of debt and equity finance. Viewing enforcement as incentive based suggests (here is relatively less need to match risk weightings accurately to portfolio risk. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Milne, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bounds tests of the theory of purchasing power parity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coe, P. J.; Serletis, A.
In this paper we test the absolute and relative purchasing power parity (PPP) hypotheses during the recent flexible exchange rate period, using quarterly data for 21 OECD countries. In doing so, we use a new econometric technique developed by M.H. Pesaran et at. [Bounds testing approaches to the analysis of long run relationships. University of Cambridge, Department of Applied Economics, Working Paper #9907]. This approach is particularly interesting as it is capable of testing the existence of long-run relations regardless of whether the underlying variables are stationary, integrated, or mutually cointegrated. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coe, P. J.; Serletis, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money and credit in liquidity provision (vol 25, pg 2041, 2001)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Y.; Zhou, C. H. Q.
nan</description><author>Wang, Y.; Zhou, C. H. Q.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of rating agency assessments in less developed countries: Impact of the proposed Basel guidelines</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferri, G.; Liu, L. G.; Majnoni, G.
We assess the potential impact for non-high-income countries (NHICs) of linking bank capital asset requirements (CARs) to private sector ratings-as contemplated by the new Basel proposal. Specifically, we show that linking bank CARs to external ratings would have a series of undesirable effects for NHICs. First, since ratings are by far less widespread for banks and corporations in NHICs. bank CARs would be practically insensitive to improvements in the quality of assets, widening the gap between banks of equal financial strength located in higher and lower income countries. Second, bank and corporate ratings in NHICs las opposed to their homologues in high-income countries) are strongly linked to their sovereign ratings. This would expose bank capital requirements in NHICs to the same "pro-cyclical" swings, which have characterized sovereign rating revision in the: recent crisis episodes. We conclude that linking bank CARs to private sector ratings would worsen the availability and cost of credit to NHICs - with potential negative effects on the level of economic activity and suggest that a reassessment of the Basel proposal may help to avoid such undesired consequences. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G15: G18; G21.</description><author>Ferri, G.; Liu, L. G.; Majnoni, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do financial intermediaries do?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, F.; Santomero, A. M.
This paper presents evidence that the traditional banking business of accepting deposits and making loans has declined significantly in the US in recent years. There has been a switch from directly held assets to pension-funds and mutual funds. However, banks have maintained their position relative to GDP by innovating and switching from their traditional business to fee-producing activities, A comparison of investor portfolios across countries shows that households in the US and UK bear considerably more risk from their investments than counterparts in Japan, France and Germany. It is argued that in these latter countries intermediaries can manage risk by holding liquid reserves and intertemporally smoothing. However, in the US and UK competition from financial markets prevents this and risk management must be accomplished using derivatives and other similar techniques. The decline in the traditional banking business and the financial innovation undertaken by banks in the US is interpreted as a response to the competition from markets' and the decline of intertemporal smoothing. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G2; G1; E5; L2.</description><author>Allen, F.; Santomero, A. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The analytic pricing of asymmetric defaultable swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hubner, G.
Swaps where both parties are exposed to credit risk still lack convincing pricing mechanisms. This article presents a reduced-form model where the event of default is related to structural characteristics of each party. The cash flows submitted to credit risk are identified before the swap is priced. Analytical pricing formulas for interest rate and currency swaps are computed using a Gaussian model for risky bonds. Currency swaps exhibit additional correlation risk. The benefits from netting depend on the balance between exposures and market conditions in valuation. We show that sources of credit risk asymmetries are also likely to impact on credit spreads. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G13; G15; G33.</description><author>Hubner, G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International investment in financial services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, F.
This paper analyzes and models the significant components of international trade in financial services, namely, foreign direct investment in banking for the US, the UK and Germany. It distinguishes between banks' activities abroad and FDI in banking by banks and non-banks. A model for FDI in banking is proposed which contains certain explanatory variables peculiar to FDI in banking as compared to FDI in manufacturing. The components of the model of FDI in banking is different from those models designed to explain banks activities abroad. The empirical results of this study of FDI in banking indicate that bilateral trade, banks' foreign assets, the cost of capital, relative economic growth, exchange rates and FDI in non-finance industries are the major determinants of foreign investment in banking. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G15; G24.</description><author>Moshirian, F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on fair value pricing of mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhargava, R.; Dubofsky, D. A.
Mutual funds claim that they employ fair value pricing to prevent active investors from trading on their beliefs that the funds' net asset values are stale. Our results support the funds' assertions, We estimate the returns from the following active strategy: buy international open end mutual funds that do not employ fair value pricing on days that the S&amp;P500 index rises by a large amount, and/or sell them on days that the S&amp;P500 index declines by a large amount. These active strategies significantly outperform pure buy-and-hold strategies. We conclude that international mutual funds should make greater use of fair value pricing. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G20.</description><author>Bhargava, R.; Dubofsky, D. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relative informational efficiency of cash, futures, and options markets: The case of an emerging market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiang, R.; Fong, W. M.
We study the lead-lag relationships among the spot, futures, and options markets on Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index (HST). The young options market experiences thin trading, and the option returns lag the cash index returns. The more mature futures market experiences active trading. Yet its lead over the cash index appears to be less than the counterparts in other countries. A possible reason is the dominance of a few major stocks in the index; and these stocks have symmetric lead-lag relations with the futures. Furthermore, the informativeness of the non-lasting futures and options quotations seems to depend on the market maturity. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G10; G12; G13.</description><author>Chiang, R.; Fong, W. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing for long horizon UIP using PPP-based exchange rate expectations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berk, J. M.; Knot, K. H. W.
This paper revisits the uncovered interest parity relation. It supplements existing work in two ways: It focuses on long instead of short-term interest rates, and, related to that, employs exchange rate expectations derived from purchasing power parity (PPP) instead of actual outcomes. Among the major floating currencies over the period 1975-1997, the paper cannot support the notion of further increases in UIP-validation beyond that associated with the wave of financial market liberalization and deregulation in the early 1980s. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: E43; E44.</description><author>Berk, J. M.; Knot, K. H. W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of FDICIA on bank returns and risk: Evidence from the capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhigbe, A.; Whyte, A. M.
This study examines the impact of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act (FDICIA) of 1991 on bank stock returns and risk.. We find that FDICIA had a generally positive effect on bank stock returns and resulted in a significant reduction in bank risk. The extent of the risk reduction Varies based on the capitalization, size, and credit risk of the institutions with poorly capitalized, large, and high credit risk banks experiencing the greatest risk reduction. The results obtained using two separate control groups also bolster the conclusion that FDICIA's passage resulted in a significant decline in bank risk. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; G28.</description><author>Akhigbe, A.; Whyte, A. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on trading mechanism and securities' value: The analysis of rejects from continuous trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lauterbach, B.
We examine 97 stocks that moved from continuous trade back to single daily auctions. The response to exit from continuous trade is almost a mirror image of the entry response documented in Amihud et al., 1997 (Amihud, Y., Mendelson, H., Lauterbach, B., 1997. Journal of Financial Economics 45, 365-390). Upon exiting continuous trade, stock liquidity, price accuracy, and value drop. An exception is, however, identified. Ten stocks that were omitted from continuous trade within three months of their addition have negative excess returns upon entry into continuous trade and positive excess returns upon exit. These immediate rejects had relatively low volumes before entering continuous trade, which suggests that for thinly traded stocks simple unassisted continuous trade may not be optimal. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. AII rights reserved. JEL classification: G14.</description><author>Lauterbach, B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on: Capital adequacy and the information content of term loans and lines of credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andre, P.; Mathieu, R.; Zhang, P.
This study examines the information content conveyed by the disclosure of credit agreements in a Canadian setting. We argue that the introduction of the 1988-capital adequacy requirements lead banks to reduce their level of commitment at the issuance of lines of credit to avoid their inclusion in the calculation of the capital ratio. As a result, after 1988, the disclosure of lines of credit is expected to be less informative than the disclosure of term loans since banks may exert less effort to screen and monitor firms. Our results are consistent with the argument that the difference between the market reactions at the disclosure of term loans and lines of credit is significant after 1988. We also provide evidence that firm size and concentration of borrowing affect the market reaction at the disclosure of bank credit agreements. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21.</description><author>Andre, P.; Mathieu, R.; Zhang, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Standard &amp; Poor's official response to the Basel Committee's proposal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griep, C.; De Stefano, M.
The following text is Standard &amp; Poors official response to the Basel Committee's proposal, which was presented to the regulators in December 1999. Standard &amp; Poor's welcomes the opportunity to respond to the committee's proposal. The risk adjustment of capital, introduced in a simplified format in the 1988 Basel accord, was adopted by most of the world's bank regulatory regimes. The current proposal could meaningfully advance this process, a development that Standard &amp; Poor's strongly supports. (C) 2001 Standard &amp; Poors. Published by Elsevier Science B.V. JEL classification: G11; G20: G31; G33.</description><author>Griep, C.; De Stefano, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit ratings and the proposed new BIS guidelines on capital adequacy for bank credit assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altman, E. I.
nan</description><author>Altman, E. I.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generally accepted rating principles: A primer</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krahnen, J. P.; Weber, M.
Bank internal ratings of corporate clients are intended to quantify the expected likelihood of future borrower defaults. This paper develops a comprehensive framework for evaluating the quality of standard rating systems. We suggest a number of principles that ought to be met by. "good rating practice", These "generally accepted rating principles" are potentially relevant for the improvement of existing rating systems. They are also relevant for the development of certification standards for internal rating systems, as currently discussed in a consultative paper issued by the Bank for International Settlements in Basle, entitled "A new capital adequacy framework": We would very much appreciate any comments by readers that help to develop these rating standards further. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21.</description><author>Krahnen, J. P.; Weber, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis and critique of the BIS proposal on capital adequacy and ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altman, E. I.; Saunders, A.
This paper examines two specific aspects of stage 1 of the Bank for International Settlement's (BIS's) proposed reforms to the 8% risk-based capital ratio. We argue that relying on "traditional" agency ratings could produce cyclically lagging rather leading capital requirements, resulting ill an enhanced rather than reduced degree of instability in the banking and financial system. Despite this possible shortcoming, we believe that sensible risk based weighting of capital requirements is a step in the right direction. The current risk based bucketing proposal, which is tied to external agency ratings, or possibly to internal bank ratings, however, lacks a sufficient degree of granularity. In particular, lumping A and BBB (investment grade corporate borrowers) together with BE and B (below investment grade borrowers) severely misprices risk within that bucket and calls, at a minimum, for that bucket to be split into two. We examine the default loss experience on corporate bonds for the period 1981-1999 and propose a revised weighting system which more closely resembles the actual loss experience on credit assets. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Altman, E. I.; Saunders, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prototype risk rating system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crouhy, M.; Galai, D.; Mark, R.
This paper explores the traditional and prevalent approach to credit risk assessment the rating system. We first describe the rating systems of the two main credit rating agencies, Standard &amp; Poor's and Moody's. Then we show how an internal rating system in a bank can be organized in order to rate creditors systematically. We suggest adopting a two-tier rating system. First. an obliger rating that can be easily mapped to a default probability bucket. Second, a facility rating that determines the loss parameters in case of default. such as (i) "loss given default" (LGD), which depends on the seniority of the facility and the quality of the gurantees, and (ii) "usage given default" (UGD) for loan commitments, which depends on the nature of the commitment and the rating history of the borrower. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G21; G33.</description><author>Crouhy, M.; Galai, D.; Mark, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The implications of the new capital adequacy rules for portfolio management of credit assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hammes, W.; Shapiro, M.
Over the past several pears, there has been an extensive discussion among practitioners and academics about whether and how a portfolio management approach could help banks to better manage risk capital and create shareholder value. In this article, the authors argue that then are four key drivers which require banks to move from a transactional to a more portfolio management like approach when managing credit assets. These are: structural changes in the credit markets, inefficiencies of risk transfer in lending markets, ballooning debt levels in the US, and the proposed changes for capital adequacy. The authors see the latter not as a one-time change in capital adequacy rules, but more as a first step towards full convergence between risk capital and regulatory capital for credit risk. These changes require banks to accelerate their efforts to build first class portfolio management skills and capabilities. Achieving best practice credit portfolio management is rewarded with attractive opportunities for shareholder value creation and enables bank to successfully compete going forward. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G11; G20: G21.</description><author>Hammes, W.; Shapiro, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Moody's investors service response to the consultative paper issued by the Basel Committee on Bank Supervision "A new capital adequacy framework"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cantor, R.
Moody's endorses the Basel Committee's proposal to use banks' internal risk assessments to refine the Basel Accords risk weights on bank assets and commitments. External risk assessments, such as Moodys credit ratings, will likely play a supporting role as direct inputs into banks' internal rating systems and as tools for benchmarking and validating those systems. However, the widespread use of ratings in regulation threatens to undermine the quality of credit over time by increasing rating shopping, decreasing rating agency independence, and reducing incentives to innovate and improve the quality of ratings. This paper discusses how bank regulators can use external ratings in ways that mitigate the adverse incentives created by the resulting regulatory demand for rating agency services. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V, All rights reserved. JEL classification: G11; G20, G31; G33.</description><author>Cantor, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A critical review of the new capital adequacy framework paper issued by the Basle Committee on Banking Supervision and its implications for the rating agency industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linnell, I.
This paper will concentrate on two main areas. First, on the way in which the Committee intends to allocate capital by assessing risk on the basis of both external and internal ratings and, second, on how it intends to use recognised independent rating agencies. It also includes a comment on bank disclosure. The paper is written from the perspective of Fitch IBCA (FI), the world's third largest international rating agency. As a result, other institutions, possibly with a different perspective, may not agree with its contents. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G11; G20; G21: G31.</description><author>Linnell, I.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Parameterizing credit risk models with rating data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carey, M.; Hrycay, M.
Estimates of average default probabilities for borrowers assigned to each of a financial institution's internal credit risk rating grades are crucial inputs to portfolio credit risk models. Such models are increasingly used in setting financial institution capital structure, in internal control and compensation systems, in asset-backed security design, and are being considered for use in setting regulatory capital requirements for banks. This paper empirically examines properties of the major methods currently used to estimate average default probabilities by grade. Evidence of potential problems of bias, instability, and gaming is presented. With care, and perhaps judicious application of multiple methods, satisfactory estimates may be possible. In passing, evidence is presented about other properties of internal and rating-agency ratings. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G11; G20, G31: G33.</description><author>Carey, M.; Hrycay, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The use of undisclosed limit orders on the Australian Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aitken, M. J.; Berkman, H.; Mak, D.
This paper investigates the use of undisclosed limit orders on the Australian Stock Exchange (ASX). Our findings suggest that undisclosed limit orders are used to reduce the option value of limit orders. We find no evidence that undisclosed limit orders are more frequently used by informed traders than disclosed limit orders. The effects of recent changes in undisclosed order regulation are also examined. We find that the enhancement in pre-trade transparency, through tightening the undisclosed order regulation in October 1994, resulted in a significant decline in trading volume. The impact of the second regulation change in October 1996, which further tightened undisclosed order regulation, resulted in a less significant trading volume reduction. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aitken, M. J.; Berkman, H.; Mak, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Patterns of behavior of professionally managed and independent investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shapira, Z.; Venezia, I.
In this paper, we analyze the investment patterns of a large number of clients of a major Israeli brokerage house during 1994. We compare the behavior of clients making independent investment decisions to that of investors whose accounts were managed by brokerage professionals. Our main objective is to investigate whether the disposition effect (i.e., the tendency to sell winners quicker than losers), demonstrated in the US only for individual investors, also holds for professional investors. This analysis is important, as accepted financial theory predicts that prices are determined mainly by decisions made by professionals. We show that both professional and independent investors exhibit the disposition effect, although the effect is stronger for independent investors. The second objective of our study is the comparison of trade frequency, volume and profitability between independent and professionally managed accounts. We believe that these comparisons not only provide insights of their own. but also help to put the differences in the disposition effect in a wider perspective. We demonstrate that professionally managed accounts were more diversified and that round trips were both less correlated with the market and slightly more profitable than those of independent accounts. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shapira, Z.; Venezia, I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Citicorp-Travelers Group merger: Challenging barriers between banking and insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carow, K. A.
The Citicorp-Travelers Group merger increased the prospects for new legislation to remove the barriers between banking and insurance, resulting in a positive wealth effect for institutions most likely to gain from deregulation. Analysis of abnormal returns surrounding the merger show that life insurance companies and large banks (excluding Citicorp and Travelers Group) have significant stock price increases, while the returns of small banks, health insurers, and property/casualty insurers are insignificantly different from 0. This analysis provides evidence that investors expect large banks and insurance companies to receive significant benefits from recent congressional legislation removing barriers to bancassurance. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carow, K. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do investors prefer round stock prices? Evidence from Israeli IPO auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kandel, S.; Sarig, O.; Wohl, A.
We find round number clustering in orders submitted by investors in Israeli IPO auctions. Explanations offered for price clustering, such as dealer collusion or implicit agreement to simplify negotiations, cannot explain price clustering in this market. Therefore. this is direct evidence that investors prefer round numbers. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kandel, S.; Sarig, O.; Wohl, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sensitivity analyses of anomalies in developed stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durham, J. B.
The literature on anomalies in developed stock markets produces no consensus on specification. This study uses extreme bound analysis (EBA) to evaluate the robustness of 15 stock-return anomalies given data covering 16 developed markets from May 1984 to March 1999. Two factors are sturdy according to the "extreme" decision rule in the panel design - D/P and momentum. Under a less stringent EBA criterion. long-run lagged returns, country risk, and the January effect are also robust. Time-series EBA for individual markets produces one robust result according to relaxed decision rules across a majority of cases - long-run government bond yields. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Durham, J. B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Margin exceedences for European stock index futures using extreme value theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cotter, J.
Futures exchanges require a margin requirement that ensures their competitiveness and protects against default risk. This paper applies extreme value theory in computing unconditional optimal margin levels for a selection of stock index futures traded on European exchanges. The theoretical framework focuses explicitly on tail returns, thereby properly accounting for large levels of risk in measuring prudent margin levels. The paper finds that common margin requirements are sufficient for each contract, with the exception of the Norwegian OBX index, in providing equitable costs for traders. In addition, the paper shows the underestimation bias in margin levels that are calculated assuming normality. Differing margin requirements reflect the unconditional and conditional trading environments. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cotter, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic choices of quality, differentiation and pricing in financial services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mahajan, S.; Sweeney, R. J.
Two financial services firms (FSFs) produce information on future returns from risky assets, incorporate this information in a report and sell the reports to investors. The FSFs make strategic choices of the quality, differentiation and prices of their reports. Their optimal strategic choices of quality and differentiation divide the market for the report into three segments. Each FSF has a monopoly in its own segment, and the two compete head-to-head in a duopoly segment. The sizes of the monopoly segments increase with increases in quality and differentiation. An increase in differentiation reduces the size of the duopoly market, while an increase in quality has an ambiguous effect on the duopoly market: for high enough equilibrium differentiation, the size of the duopoly market decreases with an increase in quality. The non-cooperative FSFs pursue niche strategies, each focusing on a different related set of risks, in order to coordinate the contents of their reports to achieve the equilibrium degree of product differentiation. Recent years have seen a worldwide wave of financial-firm mergers and acquisitions. This paper's model suggests that in equilibrium FSFs differentiate their products and develop profitable niches; in principle, however, sufficiently strong economics of scope could lead to a small number of FSFs with little differentiation that dominate all financial services markets. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mahajan, S.; Sweeney, R. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factor models and the correlation structure of interest rates: Some evidence for USD, GBP, DEM and JPY</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lekkos, I.
The aim of this paper is to develop models for producing accurate forecasts for the correlation of spot and forward interest rates. Correlation forecasts generated from factor models, where the correlations are expressed as a function of few underlying factors, are compared to forecasts produced by less sophisticated models like the full historical and constant correlation model. Contrary to previous studies, where the selection of factors is rather arbitrary, we test two factor identification methodologies. The first is based on factor analysis and the second is based on minimising the residual cross-correlations. We show that a three-factor model, with factors identified by minimising the residual cross-correlation criterion is sufficient to describe the correlation structure of interest rates. Furthermore, we show that it might be preferable to assume that all forward rate correlations are equal rather than using a misspecified factor model and that the spot factor model developed, consistently outperformed long established models like the "Barbell" model. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lekkos, I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price and volume effects associated with derivative warrant issuance on the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Y. C.; Wei, K. C. J.
This paper examines the price and volume effects of underlying stocks around the announcement date of derivative warrants issued in Hong Kong. In general, the results indicate that underlying stocks are subject to extra buying pressure a few days before the new derivative warrant issuance, which is consistent with our hypothesis about the hedging effect created by the merchant banks that initiate the warrant issuance. Since the prices of underlying stocks peak on the first day after the warrant announcement and are stable thereafter, the information effect associated with the warrant issuance appears to be weak and does not last long. In addition, we find that underlying stocks have abnormal increases in price and volume during the last 5 minutes of trading on the warrant issuance day. This might be due to investors' buying behavior precipitated by information leakage about the successful warrant issuance and/or to the price manipulation by merchant banks in order to attain a better payoff from the warrant issuing business. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Y. C.; Wei, K. C. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal portfolio selection in a Value-at-Risk framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, R.; Huisman, R.; Koedijk, K.
In this paper, we develop a portfolio selection model which allocates financial assets by maximising expected return subject to the constraint that the expected maximum loss should meet the Value-at-Risk limits set by the risk manager. Similar to the mean-variance approach a performance index like the Sharpe index is constructed. Furthermore when expected returns are assumed to be normally distributed we show that the model provides almost identical results to the mean-variance approach. We provide an empirical analysis using two risky assets: US stocks and bonds. The results highlight the influence of both non-normal characteristics of the expected return distribution and the length of investment time horizon on the optimal portfolio selection. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campbell, R.; Huisman, R.; Koedijk, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolution of market uncertainty around earnings announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Isakov, D.; Perignon, C.
This paper investigates theoretically and empirically the dynamics of the implied volatility or implied standard deviation (ISD) around earnings announcements dates. The volatility implied by option prices can be interpreted as the level of volatility expected by the market over the remaining life of the option. We propose a theoretical framework for the evolution of the ISD that takes into account two well-known features of the instantaneous volatility: volatility clustering and the leverage effect. In this context, the ISD should decrease after an earnings announcement but the post-announcement ISD path depends on the content of the earnings announcement: good news or bad news. An empirical investigation is conducted on the Swiss market over the period 1989-1998. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Isakov, D.; Perignon, C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring performance of international closed-end funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patro, D. K.
This paper provides an empirical analysis of the performance of 45 international closed-end funds and compares alternate measures of performance using the sample of funds and 35 national market indices. The empirical evidence indicates that the risk-adjusted performance of the shares or the net asset values of the funds match the performance of their respective local market indices, as well as the world market index and do not exhibit superior timing ability. These findings are robust to conditioning on information. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Patro, D. K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Federal Reserve's operating procedure, nonborrowed reserves, borrowed reserves and the liquidity effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thornton, D. L.
Recently, a number of researchers (Christiano and Eichenbaum, 1992; Christiano et al., 1996a,b, 1997; Evans and Marshall, 1998; Strongin, 1995; Pagan and Robertson, 1995; Brunner, 1994) claim to have found evidence of a statistically significant liquidity effect in a recursive structural VAR using nonborrowed reserves (NBR). It is claimed that innovations to NBR reflect the exogenous policy actions of the Fed. This paper argues that the opposite is true. Specifically, I show that the Fed has an incentive to offset bank-initiated discount window borrowing when it implements the Federal Open Market Committee's policy directive, and that it has done so since the late 1950s. This practice has created a negative contemporaneous covariance between NBR and the funds rate that has been incorrectly attributed to the liquidity effect. By showing that these models capture the endogenous response of the Fed to bank borrowing on NBR, rather than the effect of exogenous policy actions on the funds rate, this paper also resolves the puzzle of the vanishing liquidity effect noted by Pagan and Robertson (1995) and Christiano (1995). (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Thornton, D. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign and domestic investors and tax induced ex-dividend day trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liljeblom, E.; Loflund, A.; Hedvall, K.
This paper reports evidence on the consequences of differential tax treatment for domestic and foreign owners in a market with a high degree of foreign ownership for certain stocks, the Helsinki Stock Exchange (HSE). We find that ex-dividend day ratios vary with the degree of foreign ownership, and detect significantly abnormal ex-dividend day trading volumes. The average ex-dividend price drops for high-yield, high-foreign ownership stocks are likely to lie outside no-arbitrage boundaries for domestic taxable investors. An investigation of short selling through a derivatives instrument also reveals significant excess trading volumes in ex-dividend months. The tax heterogeneity of the company's ownership structure seems to play a role in explaining deviations from dividend neutrality, more deviations are observed for companies with a more homogeneous ownership structure in terms of taxation. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liljeblom, E.; Loflund, A.; Hedvall, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor tax rationality and the relationship between dividend yields and equity returns: An explanatory note</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dempsey, M.
Recently in this journal, it is contended that the empirically observed relationship between stock returns and dividend yields cannot be reconciled with tax rationality. In response, this present note re-examines the theoretical basis for this conclusion. We conclude that the empirical evidence of market behavior may at present be interpreted as consistent with investor tax-based rationality that capitalizes the firm's earnings on an after-personal tax basis. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dempsey, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modelling S&amp;P 100 volatility: The information content of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blair, B. J.; Poon, S. H.; Taylor, S. J.
Theoretical models that relate volatility to the quantity of information are extended to a multi-asset setting and it is deduced that stock returns may or may not have incremental information when modelling index volatility, depending on the sources of information that move stock prices. The first empirical study that can help resolve this theoretical uncertainty is presented. A detailed analysis of the daily volatility of the S&amp;P 100 index from 1984 to 1998 shows there is some incremental volatility information in the returns from the 100 shares that define the index. This evidence is obtained from ARCH models that incorporate leverage effects, dummy variables for the 1987 crash and aggregate measures of stock return volatility. Significant differences between estimated volatilities are found for various stock measures and sub-periods. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blair, B. J.; Poon, S. H.; Taylor, S. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analytic approach to credit risk of large corporate bond and loan portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucas, A.; Klaassen, P.; Spreij, P.; Straetmans, S.
We derive an analytic approximation to the credit loss distribution of large portfolios by letting the number of exposures tend to infinity. Defaults and rating migrations for individual exposures are driven by a factor model in order to capture co-movements in changing credit quality. The limiting credit loss distribution obeys the empirical stylized facts of skewness and heavy tails. We show how portfolio features like the degree of systematic risk, credit quality and term to maturity affect the distributional shape of portfolio credit losses. Using empirical data, it appears that the Basle 8% rule corresponds to quantiles with confidence levels exceeding 98%. The limit law's relevance for credit risk management is investigated further by checking its applicability to portfolios with a finite number of exposures. Relatively homogeneous portfolios of 300 exposures can be well approximated by the limit law. A minimum of 800 exposures is required if portfolios are relatively heterogeneous. Realistic loan portfolios often contain thousands of exposures implying that our analytic approach can be a fast and accuratealternative to the standard Monte-Carlo simulation techniques adopted in much of the literature. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lucas, A.; Klaassen, P.; Spreij, P.; Straetmans, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency in index options markets and trading in stock baskets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ackert, L. F.; Tian, Y. S. S.
Researchers have reported mispricing in index options markets. This study further examines the efficiency of the S&amp;P 500 index options market by testing theoretical pricing relationships implied by no-arbitrage conditions. The effect of a traded stock basket, Standard and Poor's Depository Receipts (SPDRs), on the link between index and options markets is also examined. We find that pricing efficiency within option markets improves but there is little evidence to support the hypothesis that a stock basket enhances arbitrage across markets. When transactions costs and short sales constraints are included, very few violations of inter-market pricing relationships such as put-call parity are reported. However, violations of within market pricing relationships such as the box spread remain frequent. Extensive analysis suggests that the results are robust. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ackert, L. F.; Tian, Y. S. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of cost efficiency in cooperative financial institutions: Australian evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Esho, N.
Previous studies of efficiency in cooperative financial institutions assume subsidies to be a normal part of business operations. Using a sample of Australian credit unions (CUs) this paper shows that ignoring subsidies biases estimates of cost efficiency and efficiency rankings, Time varying cost efficiency is estimated using stochastic frontier and generalised WITHIN approaches and compared with the distribution free (DF) approach assuming constant efficiency. Despite significant industry rationalisation, average efficiency shows little improvement over the period 1985-1993, however efficiency rankings change considerably. Second stage regressions suggest bond type, size, age, average deposit size. and interest rate spreads an significant determinants of relative cost efficiency. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Esho, N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Productivity growth in large US commercial banks: The initial post-deregulation experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mukherjee, K.; Ray, S. C.; Miller, S. M.
We explore productivity growth for a group of 201 large US commercial banks over the initial post-deregulation period from 1984 to 1990, using data envelopment analysis (DEA). We measure productivity growth using Malmquist productivity indexes and isolate the contributions of technical change, technical efficiency change, and scale change to productivity growth. We find overall productivity growth at the rate of about 4.5% per year on average, but productivity declined by 7.61% between 1984 and 1985 and by 0.33% between 1988 and 1989. Our second-stage panel regressions reveal that larger asset size and specialization of product mix associate with higher productivity growth while higher equity to assets associates with lower productivity growth. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mukherjee, K.; Ray, S. C.; Miller, S. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does foreign entry affect domestic banking markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claessens, S.; Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Huizinga, H.
Using 7900 bank observations from 80 countries for the 1988-1995 period, this paper examines the extent and effect of foreign presence in domestic banking markets. We investigate how net interest margins, overhead, taxes paid, and profitability differ between foreign and domestic banks. We find that foreign banks have higher profits than domestic banks in developing countries, but the opposite is the case for developed countries. Estimation results suggest that an increased presence of foreign banks is associated with a reduction in profitability and margins for domestic banks. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Claessens, S.; Demirguc-Kunt, A.; Huizinga, H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Circuit theory of banking and finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bossone, B.
Drawing on monetary circuit theory, this study develops an approach to analyze the integrated functions of banking and finance in a monetary production economy. The study proposes a micro-founded, circuit-sequenced model of a decentralized-decisions economy, where production, exchange, and investment from households and firms are integrated through money creation and funds allocation operated, respectively, by banks and non-bank financial intermediaries. The model is used to draw implications on: the special nature of banks and the role of non-bank financial intermediaries; the relationship between saving and investment; and the channels through which finance may cause the circuit process to break down. The study also discusses how the circuit approach can be used for an integrated analysis of economic and financial structural change. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bossone, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decimalization, adverse selection, and market maker rents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bacidore, J. M.
I address the issue of how decimalization impacts the information acquisition decision of traders. I show that traders have less of an incentive to improve the quality of their information and, consequently, trades tend to be less informative following a reduction in the minimum tick. This result is consistent with the empirical finding that reductions in the minimum tick lead to declines in the adverse selection component, a finding counter to the theoretical predictions in the literature. This result also explains how the predicted savings from decimalization can exceed even total market maker profits. In addition, I show that even if market makers are perfectly competitive, a minimum tick can lead to multiple spread equilibria, some of which being more than one tick away from the underlying, or "no-tick", equilibrium spread. Finally, I discuss the implications of the model for payment for order flow/internalization and the existence of an optimal tick size. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bacidore, J. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparable firms and the precision of equity valuations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eberhart, A. C.
I investigate the relationship between the amount of information provided by a firm's comparables (i.e., firms in the same line of business as the firm being valued) and the precision of the firm's equity valuation. When investors have more information, previous studies argue that investors can make a more precise estimate of a firm's true equity value and this implies a lower (excess) stock return volatility around corporate events such as earnings announcements. I develop a simple model that shows a negative relationship between the amount of information provided by a firm's comparables and the firm's stock return volatility. Using alternative measures of information provided by comparables and different definitions of comparables, I consistently find a negative and significant relationship between these information measures and stock return volatility, ceteris paribus. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eberhart, A. C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of public information on investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nofsinger, J. R.
This study investigates the trading behavior of institutional and individual investors around both finn-specific news releases in the Wall Street Journal and macro-economic announcements. For the firm-specific news releases we find that investors conduct a high degree of trading around news releases, especially earnings and dividend news. Institutions buy and sell on both good and bad news, while individual investors only trade on good news. The length of the news article (visibility) is also an important attribute to motivate individual investor trading. Lastly, both institutions and individuals buy large firms after good economic news and sell large firms after bad economic news. The trading of small firms does not appear to be motivated by macro-news. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nofsinger, J. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday futures market behaviour around major scheduled macroeconomic announcements: Australian evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frino, A.; Hill, A.
This paper examines intraday futures market behaviour around major scheduled macroeconomic information announcements on the Sydney Futures Exchange (SFE). Prior literature analysing intraday price behaviour around announcements is extended to trading volume and quoted bid-ask spreads. The analysis of price volatility, trading volume and quoted bid-ask spreads indicates that the majority of adjustment to new information occurs rapidly, within 240 seconds of the scheduled time for major announcements, with some evidence of abnormal activity prior to announcements. Analysis of quoted bid-ask spreads suggests that they significantly widen in the 20 seconds prior to announcements and remain significantly wider for 30 seconds following announcements. The increase in quoted spreads is related to both expected and unexpected volatility, implying that market participants increase quoted spreads around information announcements as a consequence of adverse selection costs. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frino, A.; Hill, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks' reserve management, transaction costs, and the timing of Federal Reserve intervention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartolini, L.; Bertola, G.; Prati, A.
We use daily data on bank reserves and overnight interest rates to document a striking pattern in the high-frequency behavior of the US market for federal funds: depository institutions tend to hold more reserves during the last few days of each "reserve maintenance period", when the opportunity cost of holding reserves is typically highest. We then propose and analyze a model of the federal funds market where uncertain liquidity flows and transaction costs induce banks to delay trading and to bid up interest rates at the end of each maintenance period. In this context, the central bank's interest-rate-smoothing policy causes a high supply of liquid funds to be associated with high interest rates around reserve-settlement days. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bartolini, L.; Bertola, G.; Prati, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-varying persistence in expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Priestley, R.
This paper measures the extent to which persistence in expected returns moves asset prices. Over the period 1871-1997 persistence is found to vary greatly. For example, 1 unit of news about expected returns can have an impact between 2% and 30% on asset prices depending on the time period. Variations in persistence appear to be correlated with variations in the riskiness of the economy. That is, at times of high risk, news effects asset prices more than at times of low risk. These results have implications for the estimation of asset pricing models, tests of market efficiency and tests of present value models in general. Interestingly, we find that with the exception of the period surrounding the great depression and the second world war, volatility in stock prices is fairly constant and the time-variation in expected returns is driven by variations in the price of risk. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Priestley, R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using implied volatility on options to measure the relation between asset returns, and variability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davidson, W. N.; Kim, J. K.; Ors, E.; Szakmary, A.
Prior research has documented that volatility in financial asset markets is most directly related to trading rather than calendar days, and that there is an inverse asymmetric relation between volatility and returns in both stocks and long-term bonds. We examine these relations in 37 futures options markets representing a wide variety of asset types. Using futures prices and implied volatilities from this extensive array of markets, we confirm that in all of them, save one, market volatility is more directly related to trading days. However, the nature of the association between implied volatility and underlying asset returns varies greatly across asset categories and across exchanges. Thus, we show that findings from equity markets apparently are not generalizable to other asset classes. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Davidson, W. N.; Kim, J. K.; Ors, E.; Szakmary, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who's minding the store? Motivating and monitoring hired managers at small, closely held commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeYoung, R.; Spong, K.; Sullivan, R. J.
Small, closely held corporations must rely disproportionately on managerial share-holdings to mitigate the agency costs associated with hired managers, because market discipline and motivated outside monitors are typically absent for such firms. We study a random sample of 266 small, closely held US commercial banks with a broad range of ownership and management arrangements. Our results suggest that hiring an outside manager can improve profitability, but these gains depend on aligning hired managers with owners via managerial shareholdings. We find that over-utilizing this control mechanism results in entrenchment, while under-utilization is costly in terms of foregone profits. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeYoung, R.; Spong, K.; Sullivan, R. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting correlation among equity mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahmed, P.
Investors often buy multiple funds that are actively managed, specializing within narrowly defined market segments. To successfully implement a strategy of diversification investors must obtain accurate estimates of correlation among mutual fund returns. This paper forecasts mutual fund correlations using eight models that are broadly classified into historical, mean and index. Results indicate that estimate of future correlations from the Multi-Style Index. Dynamic and Fama-French 3-Factor models have the lowest prediction errors. Moreover, the relative ranks of Multi-Style Index and Fama-French 3-Factor models have lower dispersion across different forecasting time periods and in sub-samples of funds belonging to similar or different 'style' categories. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahmed, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interdependence and dynamics in currency futures markets: A multivariate analysis of intraday data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elyasiani, E.; Kocagil, A. E.
This paper investigates long-term interdependencies and short-term dynamics in currency futures utilizing intraday data for six major foreign currencies: the British Pound, Deutsche Mark, Swiss Franc, Australian Dollar, Canadian Dollar, and Japanese Yen. Lack of cointegration (CI) among the foreign exchange futures is found to be the prevailing mode of behavior, but some temporal deviations from the no-CI condition are detected. There is a notable overlap between detected CI relationships and the timing of policy changes, world events, and regime shifts, indicating that the observed CIs are event-driven. The robustness of the CI results is checked with respect to variations in the model, lag structure, data period, sample horizon, and currency basket grouping. Impulse-response functions (IRFs) reveal that currency markets are in general efficient and absorb new information within the day. The interdependence among currencies is found to be asymmetric. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Elyasiani, E.; Kocagil, A. E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of FDICIA and prompt corrective action on bank capital and risk: Estimates using a simultaneous equations model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, R.; Jacques, K. T.
One of the requirements of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act (FDICIA) was that bank regulators establish capital ratio zones that mandate prompt corrective action (PCA) and early intervention in troubled banks. However. prior research suggests that increases in regulatory capital standards can lead to offsetting increases in risk. This paper develops and estimates a 3SLS model to examine the simultaneous impact of PCA on both bank capital and credit risk. The results document that the FDICIA was effective in that, subsequent to its passage, US banks increased their capital ratios without offsetting increases in credit risk. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, R.; Jacques, K. T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are cash acquisitions associated with better postcombination operating performance than stock acquisitions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linn, S. C.; Switzer, J. A.
This study examines the relation between the change in operating performance of firms which merge and whether the acquiring firm offered cash or stock as the method-of-payment, We examine how operating performance changed for a sample of 413 combinations. The results indicate that the change in performance of the merged firms is significantly larger for cases in which the acquiring company offered cash as compared to stock offers, The results are not sensitive to whether the combination involved a tender offer or a negotiated merger, to offer size, industry relatedness between the bidder's and the target's businesses or bidder leverage. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V, All rights reserved.</description><author>Linn, S. C.; Switzer, J. A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dual class firms: Capitalization, ownership structure and recapitalization back into single class</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amoako-Adu, B.; Smith, B. F.
This paper analyses changes in capitalization and control of dual class firms before and after IPO, The results indicate that the combination of a large controlling shareholder with family interests, rather than concentrated ownership per se. leads to dual class capitalization. During the first 15 years post-lPO, voting leverage continuously increases as the dual class firms issue more restricted than superior voting shares, However, control changes are equally frequent fur dual and single class firms suggesting that dual dass capitalization is not used to unduly entrench management. We document disputes between restricted and superior voting shareholders to illustrate the potential corporate governance problems which are associated with dual class capitalization. As a result of these disputes, investor interest in dual class equity has decreased and there is a recent trend toward reclassification back into single class equity. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B,V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amoako-Adu, B.; Smith, B. F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Repricing and employee stock option valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corrado, C. J.; Jordan, B. D.; Miller, T. W.; Stansfield, J. J.
A repricing occurs when the issuing firm resets the strike price of an employee stock option (ESO), ESO repricings occur most frequently following a significant decline in the underlying stock price, Typically, the strike price is reset to the new stock price, We develop a new model for valuing ESOs with a repricing feature, Our valuation model is developed within a utility-maximizing framework that accounts for potentially multiple repricings, employee risk aversion, employee non-option wealth, the non-tradeability of ESOs, and the early exercise feature of ESOs, Simulations suggest that these factors can significantly affect ESO value, (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B,V, All rights reserved.</description><author>Corrado, C. J.; Jordan, B. D.; Miller, T. W.; Stansfield, J. J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Immunization derived from a polynomial duration vector in the Spanish bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Soto, G. M.
This paper focuses on the Spanish government debt market in an attempt to evaluate the immunization performance of the polynomial duration model of Chambers and Carleton (Chambers, D.R., Carleton, W.T., 1988. A generalized approach to duration. In: Chen, A.H. (Ed.), Research in Finance, vol. 7, JAI Press, Greenwich, pp. 163-181), in default-free and option-free fixed-income portfolios and to ascertain whether traditional convexity is an earnings-generating element. Empirical tests show that three constraints, namely those related to the level, slope and curvature of term structure shifts, are necessary to guarantee a return close to the target. The only exception to this rule is found in portfolios including an asset that matures near the horizon date, in which classical immunization performs properly. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science S.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Soto, G. M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Near integration, bank reluctance, and discount window borrowing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dutkowsky, D. H.; McCoskey, S. K.
This study puts forth stationarity considerations in explaining the observed breakdown between aggregate Discount Window borrowing and the spread between the Federal Funds rate and the discount rate during the post-1987 period. Tests with biweekly data indicate stationarity for adjustment borrowing, but cannot reject the unit root for the spread. The Goodfriend-Dutkowsky dynamic implicit cost formulation can accommodate the contrasting stationarity properties. Structural restrictions are compatible with stationary borrowing and a stationary or near integrated spread. While empirical findings from the static model indicate greater bank reluctance to borrow over time, the dynamic model gives considerably less support. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dutkowsky, D. H.; McCoskey, S. K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intertemporal diversification in financial intermediation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niinimaki, J. P.
This paper examines the incentive problem between a bank and depositors (or deposit insurer): limited Liability makes risk-shifting lucrative. We show how intertemporal diversification of lending decisions - i.e, bank's loan portfolio consists of overlapping Long-term loans and is thus gradually renewed - may solve the incentive problem of risk-shifting. A new (or expanding) bank sets a high-equity level and acquires depositors' confidence, Subsequently, it can allow its equity to depreciate to a permanently lower level. Depositors can control the bank by monitoring equity and realized credit losses ex post; they do not have to monitor bank's lending choices ex ante. Maturity mismatch illiquidity of long-term loans and liquidity of deposits - is optimal. The analysis call be extended more generally to the borrower-lender relationship. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Niinimaki, J. P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do contagion effects vary among bank failures?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhigbe, A.; Madura, J.
Many of the previous studies on contagion effects in the banking industry focused on the failure of a large bank to determine whether the adverse effects spread to other banks. Yet. little is known whether other publicized bank failures cause contagion effects, and why the effects may vary among bank failures. Given the changes in the banking environment over time, contagion effects could be conditioned on the characteristics of the failing bank and of the banking environment at that time. We assess 99 publicized bank failures over the 1980-1996 period, and find that contagion effects exist in general for the surviving rivals of the failed bank. The degree of contagion effects varies over time (among bank failures), and is stronger when the failed bank is a multibank holding company, when the failed bank is publicly held, when the failed bank is relatively large, when the rivals are relatively small, and when the rivals have relatively low capital levels. The contagion effects are less pronounced in the period following the passage of FIRREA. Furthermore, the total risk-shifts of surviving rival banks in response to the announcement of a failed bank are inversely related to their capital level, and total risk-shifts of rival banks are less pronounced for Failures occurring just after the passage of FIRREA. The results suggest that a bank's exposure to possible contagion effects due to a bank failure can be partially controlled by a bank's managerial policies and by regulatory policies. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akhigbe, A.; Madura, J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider trading and managerial incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, J.; Noe, T. H.
We derive conditions under which permitting manager "insiders" to trade on personal account increases the equilibrium level of output and the welfare of shareholders. These increases are produced by two effects of insider trading. First, insider trading impounds information about hidden managerial actions into asset prices. This impounding of information allows shareholders to make better personal portfolio-allocation decisions. Second, allowing insider trading can induct managers to increase, on average, the correlation between their personal wealth and firm value beyond the level dictated by the employment relationship alone. This increased correlation increases managerial incentives. When these two effects are only weakly present, permitting insider trading harms shareholders, because insider trading reduces shareholder control over the performance-compensation relationship. In addition, when managerial effort incentives are high and corporate governance costs are low. managers may prefer insider-trading restrictions because such restrictions force shareholders to offer them a larger fraction of output through the employment relationship. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B,V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hu, J.; Noe, T. H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dormancy risk and expected profits of consumer loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carling, K.; Jacobson, T.; Roszbach, K.
A bank that lends money to a household faces two types of risk, Frequently mentioned is the risk of default. Seldom referred to is the risk of an early redemption of the loan - leading to dormancy. In this paper, we model the transition of consumer loans from an active to a dormant state. To this end, we use data on 4786 individuals who were granted credit by a Swedish lending institution between September 1993 and August 1995 and estimate a semi-parametric duration model. We analyze the factors that determine the time to maturity on consumer loans and investigate the ability of the model to match the maturities observed in the data. Moreover, we derive the distribution of conditional expected durations of loans and show how a loan application can be evaluated by calculating its expected profit. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B,V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carling, K.; Jacobson, T.; Roszbach, K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interacting biases, non-normal return distributions and the performance of tests for long-horizon event studies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cowan, A. R.; Sergeant, A. M. A.
We report simulations of one-, three-, and five-year abnormal buy-and-hold stock return tests. Using benchmark portfolios purged of new-listings and rebalancing biases, we find severe misspecification of most tests, due in part to skewness. Control-firm matching also results in misspecification, particularly in large samples. We document a negative relation between skewness bias and sample size, and an overlapping-horizons bias. Both biases become more severe as the holding period lengthens. The biases interact such that tests can be well-specified in one situation but not another. A two groups test using winsorized abnormal returns yields correct specification and considerable power ill many situations. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cowan, A. R.; Sergeant, A. M. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Yield curves and international equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McCown, J. R.
This paper examines empirical evidence on the international transmission of shocks to financial asset markets. The relationships between yield curves and risk premiums of stocks for eight industrialized countries are examined. Only the stocks of the three largest economies: Germany, Japan, and the USA, show negative risk premiums during periods preceded by the inverted yield curves of their respective government bonds. This is not the case for stocks of the five smaller countries in the sample. However, four of the five smaller countries have negative risk premiums in periods preceded by inverted German or US yield curves. This is consistent with the view that a world risk factor, captured by major country yield curves, affects the pricing of assets in smaller economies. The consumption CAPM is unable to explain the phenomenon of the negative risk premiums. In almost all cases the conditional covariance between consumption growth and the risk premiums is statistically indifferent from zero. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>McCown, J. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital requirements and bank behaviour: Empirical evidence for Switzerland</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rime, B.
In recent years, regulators have increased their focus on the capital adequacy of banking institutions to enhance the stability of the financial system. The purpose of the present paper is to shed some light on whether and how Swiss Banks react to constraints placed by the regulator on their capital. Building on previous work by Shrieves and Dahl (cf. Shrieves. R.E., Dahl, D., 1992. The relationship between risk and capital in commercial banks. Journal of Banking and Finance 16, 439-357), we use a simultaneous equations model to analyse adjustments in capital and risk at Swiss banks, when those approach the minimum regulatory capital level. Our results indicate that regulatory pressure induce banks to increase their capital, but does not affect the level of risk. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rime, B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric reverting behavior of short-horizon stock returns: An evidence of stock market overreaction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nam, K.; Pyun, C. S.; Avard, S. L.
This paper investigates the uneven mean reverting pattern of monthly return indexes of the NYSE, AMEX and NASDAQ, using asymmetric non-linear smooth-transition (ANST) GARCH models. It also evaluates the extent to which time-varying volatility in the index returns support the stock market overreaction hypothesis. The models illuminate patterns of asymmetric mean reversion and risk decimation. Between 1926:01 and 1997:12, not only did negative returns reverse to positive returns quicker than positive returns reverted to negative ones, but negative returns, in fact, reduced risk premiums from predictable high volatility. The findings support the market overreaction hypotheses. The asymmetry is due to the mispricing behavior on the part of investors who overreact to certain market news. The findings also corroborate arguments for the "contrarian" portfolio strategy, (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nam, K.; Pyun, C. S.; Avard, S. L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return predictability following large price changes and information releases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pritamani, M.; Singal, V.
We examine return behavior following large price change events. Unconditional postevent abnormal returns are found to be unimportant. As we condition on other criteria related to the quality of information like volume and public announcements, the abnormal returns become large. The type of news provides further refinement. If the news relates to earnings or analyst recommendations then the 20-day abnormal returns become much larger ranging from 3% to 4% for positive events and about -2.25% for negative events. Finally, an out-of-sample trading strategy confirms investor underreaction and generates significant abnormal annualized returns of the order of 12-18%. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pritamani, M.; Singal, V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mixing and matching: Prospective financial sector mergers and market valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Estrella, A.
Which types of mergers are likely to be most productive for banks and other financial firms in the US? From a management perspective, mixing disparate firms may be difficult, but may offer significant gains from diversification. The opposite applies to matching similar firms. This paper considers life insurance, property and casualty insurance, securities, and commercial firms as potential matches for banks. It examines a measure of diversification gains from potential consolidation, based on option pricing, and a model of the "building blocks" of the industries, based on arbitrage pricing theory. The results identify potential diversification gains from virtually all combinations involving banking and insurance, which arise because common factors are combined in different ways and because insurance is already well diversified. Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Estrella, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are expansions cost effective for stock exchanges? A global perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, I.; Malkamaki, M.
This paper investigates the existence and extent of economies of scale and scope among the stock exchanges. Evidence from 38 exchanges in 32 countries and 4 continents around the world for the years 1989-1998 portrays the existence of significant economies of scale and scope. The degree of such scale and scope however differs across size and regions. The largest exchanges show an increasing trend of cost effectiveness. The exchanges in North America and Europe report substantially higher economics of scale relative to the exchanges in the Asia-Pacific regions. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasan, I.; Malkamaki, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The patterns of cross-border bank mergers and shareholdings in OECD countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Focarelli, D.; Pozzolo, A. F.
In recent years there has been a surge in mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As) in all sectors of economic activity. Cross-border operations have followed this trend, creating global companies operating in all major world markets. In this paper we study the pattern of cross-border M&amp;As in the banking industry relative to the non-financial sector of the economy and investigate which factors make it more likely that a bank will expand its activities abroad. We find that cross-border M&amp;As are rarer in banking than in other sectors, possibly owing to the importance of information asymmetries in banking relationships and to regulatory restrictions. Using data on almost 2500 banks from 29 OECD countries, we also show that the most significant features of banks with foreign equity interests relate to efficiency: banks with cross-border shareholdings are on average larger, more profitable, and based in countries with a more highly developed banking market. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Focarelli, D.; Pozzolo, A. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can mergers ensure the survival of credit unions in the third millennium?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ralston, D.; Wright, A.; Garden, K.
The survival of small financial institutions in the third millennium depends on their competitiveness against large bank rivals. Accordingly, credit unions in Australia and the United States have attempted to increase efficiency through mergers. Our paper uses the data envelopment analysis methodology to evaluate the post-merger gains in technical and scale efficiency achieved by 31 Australian credit union mergers in 1993/1994 and 1994/1995, relative to non-merging credit unions. When compared with the only US study of credit union mergers [Journal of Banking &amp; Finance 23 (1999) 367-386], our findings suggests that mergers are not associated with improvements in efficiency superior to those achieved by internal growth. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Ralston, D.; Wright, A.; Garden, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do banks have a future? A study on banking and finance as we move into the third millennium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bossone, B.
Are banks special intermediaries? Do they play any unique role in the economy? And if so, will they retain their specialness in the ever-faster changing world of finance? The rapid evolution of finance over the last two decades and the breathtaking "e-age" revolution have persuaded many that, eventually, banks will be indistinguishable from other financial intermediaries since all their functions can, at least as efficiently, be carried out by nonbanks. This study re-explores the issue of the specialness of banks in light of the large existing literature on the subject, and presents an approach which identifies the banks' specialness with their unique capacity to lend out claims on their own debt which the public accepts and uses as money. The study discusses various structural and policy implications deriving from the approach, and draws on it to point to the continuing relevance of banking in a world where nonbanks are taking business away from banks, lending to production has become relatively less important, and the use of c-money may soon be dominating financial transactions. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bossone, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The changing structure of local credit markets: Are small businesses special?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>di Patti, E. B.; Gobbi, G.
In many countries consolidation in the banking industry has reduced the number of small banks and led to significant shifts in market shares; deregulation has fostered entry in local credit markets and the expansion of branch networks, increasing competition in local markets. Small businesses are believed to be more Vulnerable to these changes, since they are more dependent on credit from local banks. In this paper we investigate the consequences of consolidation and entry for these borrowers compared with those for large firms. We employ a data set for Italy, which provides information on volumes of loans and bad loans by size of borrower with a detailed geographical partition, We Find that mergers are followed by a temporary reduction in outstanding credit to all sizes of borrowers and by an increase in bad loans, most likely due to the reassessment of banks portfolios. Entry has a relatively persistent negative impact on credit supply to small and medium-sized firms. Our results also show that concentration, branch density and the share of branches of small banks affect the volumes of credit and bad loans of small borrowers. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science BN. All rights reserved.</description><author>di Patti, E. B.; Gobbi, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are scale economies in banking elusive or illusive? Evidence obtained by incorporating capital structure and risk-taking into models of bank production</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hughes, J. P.; Mester, L. J.; Moon, C. G.
This paper explores how to incorporate banks' capital structure and risk-taking into models of production. In doing so, the paper bridges the gulf between (1) the banking literature that studies moral hazard effects of bank regulation without considering the underlying microeconomics of production and (2) the literature that uses dual profit and cost functions to study the microeconomics of bank production without explicitly considering how banks' production decisions influence their riskiness. Various production models that differ in how they account for capital structure and in the objectives they impute to bank managers - cost minimization versus value maximization - are estimated using U.S. data on highest-level bank holding companies. Modeling the bank's objective as value maximization conveniently incorporates both market-priced risk and expected cash flow into managers' ranking and choice of production plans. Estimated scale economies are found to depend critically on how banks' capital structure and risk-taking are modeled. In particular, when equity capital, in addition to debt, is included in the production model and cost is computed from the value-maximizing expansion path rather than the cost-minimizing path, banks are found to have large scale economies that increase with size. Moreover, better diversification is associated with larger scale economies while increased risk-taking and inefficient risk-taking are associated with smaller scale economics. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hughes, J. P.; Mester, L. J.; Moon, C. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The ability of banks to lend to informationally opaque small businesses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, A. N.; Klapper, L. F.; Udell, G. F.
We test hypotheses about the effects of bank size, foreign ownership, and distress on lending to informationally opaque small firms using a rich new data set on Argentinean banks, firms, and loans. We also test hypotheses about borrowing from a single bank versus multiple banks. Our results suggest that large and foreign-owned institutions may have difficulty extending relationship loans to opaque small firms. Bank distress appears to have no greater effect on small borrowers than on large borrowers, although even small firms may react to bank distress by borrowing from multiple banks, raising borrowing costs and destroying some relationship benefits. (C) 2001 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</description><author>Berger, A. N.; Klapper, L. F.; Udell, G. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction - The financial system in the third millennium: Perspectives and problems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, F.; Szego, G.
nan</description><author>Moshirian, F.; Szego, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>X-efficiency in Australian banking: An empirical investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sathye, M.
This paper empirically investigates the x-efficiency (technical and allocative) in Australian banks. A non-parametric method of Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA) has been used to arrive at the efficiency scores. Banks in this sample were found to have low levels of overall efficiency compared with the banks in the European countries and in the US. The results indicate that, as a source of overall inefficiency, the technical component was more important than the allocative component. Thus, the inefficiency in Australian banks can be attributed to wasting of inputs (technical inefficiency) rather than choosing the incorrect input combinations (allocative inefficiency). Domestic banks were found to be more efficient than foreign owned banks. The study has important implications such as guiding the government policy regarding deregulation and mergers. Since the study pinpoints the sources of inefficiency, it would also help banks with strategic planning. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. D61; G21; G34.</description><author>Sathye, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on price noises and their correction process: Evidence from two equal-payoff government bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lauterbach, B.; Wohl, A.
The study offers the most direct evidence to date on price noises in call auctions and their correction. We examine a unique sample of two identical securities (two equal-payoff Israeli government bonds) that were traded on separate yet almost simultaneous auctions on the Tel-Aviv Stock Exchange (TASE). The prices of the bonds were equal on average. However, on most of the sample days there were price differences between the bonds. Various estimates suggest that the price noise in one bond is practically uncorrelated with that of the other, and both disappear by the end of the next-day auction. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lauterbach, B.; Wohl, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Share repurchase tender offers and bid-ask spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, H. J.; Cao, C.; Choe, H.
This paper examines the impact of share repurchase tender offers on the market microstructure. We find that there is a temporary reduction in the bid-ask spread, and a temporary increase in volume and quotation depth during the offer period, Our evidence suggests that the bid-ask spread is asymmetric during the offer period with the bid-side spread smaller than the ask-side spread, The temporary reduction in the spread around offers is consistent with the competing-market-maker hypothesis which predicts that the intensified competition for the market maker raises bid prices and narrows the spread asymmetrically during the offer period. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G10; G12; G13.</description><author>Ahn, H. J.; Cao, C.; Choe, H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price volatility, welfare, and trading hours in asset markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smith, R. T.
This paper studies the consequences of opening asset markets more often for the properties of asset prices and social welfare. For all reasonable parameter values, increasing trading hours lowers average asset prices, increases unconditional asset price volatility at a given point in time, and decreases unconditional asset price volatility when averaged over the period of time that includes the additional hours that markets are open. Unconditional social welfare is increased by opening markets more often, although the welfare gains are small - well below 1% of lifetime consumption. In contrast, because expanding hours of trading affects agents' information sets, the welfare effect of more trading hours conditional on information available to agents can be large and the effect can be negative. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G10; G28; D60.</description><author>Smith, R. T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probability of call and likelihood of the call feature in a corporate bond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkar, S.
This paper suggests a new way of predicting the likelihood of a corporate bond being callable. We compute the probability that a bond, if callable, would actually be called within a certain period. We also hypothesize a positive relationship between this probability and the likelihood of the bond being issued with a call feature. Comparative static results yield the following empirical implications: the likelihood of a call feature should be an increasing function of coupon rate. corporate tax rate and leverage ratio, and a decreasing function of interest rate and firm risk (volatility). Tests with recently issued corporate bonds provide fairly strong support for the model's predictions. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G32.</description><author>Sarkar, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency of the Dojima rice futures market in Tokugawa-period Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wakita, S.
Go-integration analysis is applied to historical data (1760-1864) from the world's first well-established futures market, in rice at Dojima tin Osaka, Japan). The market shows a strong seasonal character. The summer market was strongly characterized by producers' hedging behavior, and may be called a "commodity-oriented futures market" On the other hand, the spring and autumn markets in the middle of Tokugawa era were "financial" markets, characterized by the unbiasedness hypothesis from the theory of rational expectations. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G13; N25.</description><author>Wakita, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vagabond shoes longing to stray: Why foreign firms list in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blass, A.; Yafeh, Y.
How do firms that go public decide whether to list on a major stock exchange or locally? Using a unique data set on Israeli IPOs in the US and Tel Aviv, we show that companies that list in the US are young and overwhelmingly high-tech oriented. We argue that high-quality innovative firms are willing to incur additional costs associated with listing in the US in order to reveal their value and distinguish themselves from firms that issue stock back home. Costs of listing in the US include first day underpricing and relinquishing corporate control. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G1; G15; G32.</description><author>Blass, A.; Yafeh, Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did amakudari undermine the effectiveness of regulator monitoring in Japan?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horiuchi, A.; Shimizu, K.
The principal-agent problem between the regulator, regulated banks, and taxpayers is critical to the viability of the financial system's safety net. There exists the danger that the regulator will collude with regulated banks to pursue their benefits at the expense of taxpayers, thereby reducing effectiveness of financial supervision. This paper proposes that the human relationship prevailing between the regulatory authorities and private banks referred to as "amakudari" is a form of collusion between the regulator and banks that endangers the safety net mechanism in Japan. Statistical analysis of data on regional banks shows that those banks accepting post-retirement officials from the Ministry of Finance have reduced capital adequacy levels and increased non-performing loans. Thus, the statistical result supports the hypothesis proposed in this paper. (C) 1001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Horiuchi, A.; Shimizu, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Index arbitrage with heterogeneous investors: A smooth transition error correction analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tse, Y.
The traditional index arbitrage model assumes a constant threshold mispricing between the futures and cash prices for all investors. Allowing for heterogeneity in investors' transaction costs, objectives, and capital constraints, we model the intraday mispricing of DJIA futures as a smooth transition autoregressive (STAR) process with the speed of adjustment toward equilibrium varying directly with the mispricing. We show that the observed mean reversion in mispricing changes is induced by heterogeneous arbitrageurs, instead of a statistical illusion-infrequent trading of index portfolio stocks. We further use a STAR error correction model to describe the nonlinear dynamics between the DJIA futures and index. This model describes not only which market is more informationally efficient than the other, but also the legging process - the nonsimultaneous establishing of cash and futures positions. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tse, Y.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Clicks and bricks": e-Risk Management for banks in the age of the Internet</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pennathur, A. K.
The banking industry realizes that a vital and profitable segment of its clientele demands a significant online presence that complements the traditional "bricks and mortar" presence. A virtual minefield of traditional and new issues and risks arises as banks adopt 24/7 transactional websites in their pursuit of a "clicks and bricks" strategy. Banks face operational, security, legal, and reputation risk. with their foray into online banking. An innovative and proactive approach to risk management is essential as banks move into this new territory. Recent regulatory and legislative developments suggest that as electronic banking evolves, the earlier regulatory stance of "self-regulation" appears to be changing to one of increased scrutiny. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pennathur, A. K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate and liquidity risk management and the European money supply process</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitusch, K.; Nautz, D.
The monetary setup of the European Central Bank (ECB) centers around short-term securities repurchase agreements (repos) which ensure the flexibility of its money market management. However, a flexible repo-based monetary policy exposes banks to both interest rate risk and liquidity risk. This paper investigates the consequences for the money supply process and the conduct of monetary policy. We develop a loan supply model with maturity transformation and show how banks respond when future monetary policy is expected to become tighter or more uncertain. Our results also shed light on the rationale behind the use of different pricing rules in the ECB's repo auctions. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mitusch, K.; Nautz, D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The link between bank monitoring and corporate dividend policy: The case of dividend omissions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Low, S. W.; Glorfeld, L.; Hearth, D.; Rimbey, J. N.
This study investigates whether bank monitoring influences investor response to a borrowing firm's decision to omit its dividend payments. We establish a new link between the theories of banking and dividend policy in an examination of how bank monitoring and firm dividend signals complement one another to resolve information asymmetries. Results indicate that, for small firms, investors interpret the dividend decision as a function of bank monitoring and the dividend signals taken together. Also reported are the results of tests examining the differences between the monitoring effects of banks versus public and private non-bank lenders. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Low, S. W.; Glorfeld, L.; Hearth, D.; Rimbey, J. N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns synchronization and daily correlation dynamics between international stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martens, M.; Poon, S. H.
The use of close-to-close returns underestimates returns correlation because international stock markets have different trading hours. With the availability of 16:00 (London time) stock market series, we find dynamics of daily correlation and covariance, estimated using two non-synchroneity adjustment procedures, to be substantially different from their synchronous counterparts. Conditional correlation may have different signs depending on the model and data type used. Other findings include volatility spillover from the US to the UK (and France), and a reverse spillover which is not documented before. Also, unlike previous findings, we found the increase in daily correlation is prominent only under extremely adverse conditions when a large negative return has been registered. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Martens, M.; Poon, S. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical analysis of incremental capital structure decisions under managerial entrenchment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Jong, A.; Veld, C.
We study incremental capital structure decisions of Dutch companies. From 1977 to 1996 these companies have made 110 issues of public and private seasoned equity and 137 public issues of straight debt. Managers of Dutch companies are entrenched. For this reason a discrepancy exists between managerial decisions and shareholder reactions. Confirming Zwiebel [American Economic Review (1996) 1197-1215] we find that Dutch managers avoid the disciplining role of debt allowing them to overinvest. However, the market reactions show that this overinvestment behavior is recognized. We do not find a confirmation of the adverse selection model of Myers and Majluf [Journal of Financial Economics (1984) 187-221]. This is probably due to the entrenchment of managers and the prevalence of rights issues. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Jong, A.; Veld, C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor heterogeneity, market segmentation, leverage and the equity premium puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ebrahim, M. S.; Mathur, I.
Financial economists for the past two decades have attempted to explain why the equity premium is so high, now known as the equity premium puzzle (EPP). We model investor heterogeneity, market segmentation and optimal leverage, using the time separable standard power utility, market completeness and ignoring transaction costs to explain the EPP. We explain both the EPP and the related risk-free rate puzzle without resorting to preference modification. Furthermore, we show a unique interior equilibrium for the debt ratio, contrary to the work by F. Modigliani, M.H. Miller (The cost of capital, corporation finance and the theory of investment, American Economic Review 48 (1958) 261-297; Corporate income taxes and the cost of capital, American Economic Review 53 (1963), 433-443) and S.C. Myers (Presidential address: The capital structure puzzle, Journal of Finance 39 (1984), 575-592). Our simulations show the relevance of our models. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ebrahim, M. S.; Mathur, I.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on information seasonality and the disappearance of the weekend effect in the UK stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Steeley, J. M.
The weekend effect in UK stock prices has disappeared in the 1990s. Beneath the surface however there remain systematic day-of-the-week effects only visible when returns are partitioned by the direction of the market. A systematic pattern of market wide news arrivals into the UK stock market is discovered and found to provide an explanation for these day-of-the-week effects. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Steeley, J. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crisis dynamics of implied default recovery ratios: Evidence from Russia and Argentina</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Merrick, J. J.
This paper extracts both the implied default recovery ratio and the risk-neutral default probability term structure for Russian Federation and Republic of Argentina US dollar Eurobonds during the 1998 Russian default crisis. This crisis provides a unique window into the impact of changing default probabilities and recovery ratio assumptions on credit-sensitive sovereign bond prices. For the Russian Eurobonds, the sample paths suggest a two-phase crisis revaluation. Shifts in default probabilities account for most of the initial price collapse. Marked decreases in the implied default recovery ratio dominate the second phase. Investors never cut their recovery value assumptions for Argentine debt. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Merrick, J. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money and credit in liquidity provision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Y.; Zhou, H. Q.
This paper studies the liquidity provision in a model where the roles of money are challenged by other financial instruments. Alternative to money, credit can be used as means of payment and rate dominating assets are available to serve as stores of value. Two features are found to be crucial in rendering money valuable in this environment: information asymmetry in credit trading relationship and uncertainty in individuals' liquidity demand. In general, the model economy can display a payment mechanism of money-only, credit-only, or mixed-use of money and credit in transactions, depending on the severity of the information asymmetry. The optimal quantity of money in our paper is shown to contrast those in other monetary models. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Y.; Zhou, H. Q.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of credit spreads with jump risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhou, C. S.
Default risk analysis is important for valuing corporate bonds, swaps, and credit derivatives and plays a critical role in managing the credit risk of bank loan portfolios. This paper offers a theory to explain the observed empirical regularities on default probabilities, recovery rates, and credit spreads. It incorporates jump risk into the default process. With the jump risk, a firm can default instantaneously because of a sudden drop in its value. As a result, a credit model with the jump risk is able to match the size of credit spreads on corporate bonds and can generate various shapes of yield spread curves and marginal default rate curves, including upward-sloping, downward-sloping, flat, and hump-shaped, even if the firm is currently in a good financial standing. The model also links recovery rates to the firm value at default so that the variation in recovery rates is endogenously generated and the correlation between recovery rates and credit ratings before default reported in Altman [J. Finance 44 (1989) 909] can be justified. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhou, C. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing Hang Seng Index options around the Asian financial crisis - A GARCH approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duan, J. C.; Zhang, H.
This paper investigates how well the Hang Seng Index options, the most important class of option contracts traded in Hong Kong, are priced using the GARCH approach. We calibrated the GARCH parameters using the call and put option data and used them to price options in the subsequent weeks. We found the GARCH model performs very well in comparison with the Black-Scholes model even after allowing for a smile/smirk adjustment. Its superior performance was also evident both before and during the recent Asian financial turmoil. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duan, J. C.; Zhang, H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reading PIBOR futures options smiles: The 1997 snap election</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coutant, S.; Jondeau, E.; Rockinger, M.
In this paper, we compare various methods that extract a Risk Neutral Density (RND) out of PIBOR interest-rate futures options and we investigate how traders react to a political event. Our benchmark model derives from A. Brace, D. Gatarek, M. Musiela [Mathematical Finance 7 (1997) 127-155]. We also consider a mixture of log-normals (as in W.R. Melik, C.P. Thomas, Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 32 (1997) 91-116), an Hermite expansion (as in P. Abken, D.B. Madan, S. Ramamurtie, Estimation of risk-neutral and statistical densities by Hermite polynomial approximation: with an application to Eurodollar Futures Options, Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta, 1996), and a method based on Maximum Entropy (according to P. Buchen, M. Kelly, Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 31 (1996) 143-159). We take care of the early exercise feature and we show how to approximate RNDs for a fixed time to maturity. The various methods generate similar RNDs. A daily panel of options running from February 1997 to July, 1997 reveals that operators expected the snap election a few days before the official announcement was made and that a substantial amount of political uncertainty subsisted even a month after the elections. Uncertainty evolved with polls forecasts of the future government. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Coutant, S.; Jondeau, E.; Rockinger, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing vulnerable European options when the option's payoff can increase the risk of financial distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klein, P.; Inglis, M.
We extend the results of Johnson and Stulz (Johnson, H., Stulz, R., 1987. Journal of Finance 42, 267-289) and Klein (Klein, P.C., 1996. Journal of Banking and Finance 20, 1211-1229) for valuing European options subject to the risk of financial distress on the part of the option writer. Our model incorporates a default boundary which depends on the potential liability of the written option as in Johnson and Stulz (1987), and also on the option writer's other liabilities as in Klein (1996). As in both of these papers, the pay-out ratio in the event of financial distress is linked to the assets of the option writer, and the correlation between the assets of the option writer and the asset underlying the option is explicitly modeled. Although no analytical solution is available, we illustrate the importance of this approach through examples, which are evaluated numerically. We also develop an approximate analytical solution, which works well in most situations. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Klein, P.; Inglis, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A critique on the theory of financial intermediation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scholtens, B.; van Wensveen, D.
This comment discusses the review by Franklin Alien and Anthony Santomero of the theory of financial intermediation in the 20th anniversary special issue of the Journal of Banking and Finance. We do not fully agree with their view that risk management is only of recent importance to the financial industry and with putting central the concept of participation costs. We suggest how the theory of financial intermediation might be developed further in order to understand present-day phenomena in the financial services sector. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JLSL classtfication: E51; G10; G20; L23.</description><author>Scholtens, B.; van Wensveen, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do constraints improve portfolio performance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grauer, R. R.; Shen, F. C.
The discrete-time dynamic investment model, using only historical data in various asset-allocation settings, often produces significant abnormal returns. However, the model does not choose the diversified portfolios that theory suggests it should. Therefore, in this paper, we compare the investment policies and returns of the model with and without constraints on the mix of risky assets. The constraints lead to appreciably more diversification and less realized risk, but only at the cost of less realized return. Visual comparisons of compound return-standard deviation plots and statistical comparisons of Jensen's alpha suggest that the reduction in return is not worth the reduction in risk. For more risk-averse investors, ex post utility and certainty equivalent returns suggest that it is. The results, however, illustrate the problems associated with using ex post utility to measure performance. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G11.</description><author>Grauer, R. R.; Shen, F. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading volume and autocorrelation: Empirical evidence from the Stockholm Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Safvenblad, P.
In accordance with studies for other markets, Swedish index returns exhibit high autocorrelation, (a) after days of above average performance of the stock market, (b) after low absolute returns, (c) when trading volume is low, and (d) following Fridays. Contrary to the non-synchronous trading and the transaction cost hypotheses, all results extend to individual stock returns. It is concluded that autocorrelation patterns are related to the trading patterns of individual investors, and not the cross-security information processing of the market. In particular, the observed autocorrelation structure corresponds to feedback trading. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.Y. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14.</description><author>Safvenblad, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>SETS, arbitrage activity, and stock price dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, N.; van Dijk, D.; Franses, P. H.; Lucas, A.
This paper provides an empirical description of the relationship between the trading system operated by a stock exchange and the trading behaviour of heterogeneous investors who use the exchange. The recent introduction of SETS in the London Stock Exchange provides an excellent opportunity to study the impact of an electronic trading system upon traders who use the exchange. Using the cost-of-carry model of futures prices we estimate (non-linearly) the transaction costs and trade speeds faced by arbitragers who take advantage of mispricing of FTSE 100 futures contracts relative to the spot prices of the stocks that make up the FTSE100 stock index. We divide the sample period into pre-SETS and post-SETS sample periods and conduct a comparative study of arbitrager behaviour under different trading systems. The results indicate that there has been a significant reduction in the level of transaction costs faced by arbitragers and in the degree of transaction cost heterogeneity. Finally, generalised impulse response functions show that both spot and futures prices adjust more quickly in the post-SETS period. These results suggest that both spot and futures markets have become more efficient under SETS. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: C14; C32.</description><author>Taylor, N.; van Dijk, D.; Franses, P. H.; Lucas, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information-signaling and competitive effects of foreign acquisitions in the US</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhigbe, A.; Martin, A. D.
The stock price effects for the domestic competitors of foreign acquisition targets in the US are found to be significantly positive. These results imply that signals of favorable industry conditions conveyed through cross-border acquisitions dominate any perceived changes in competitive balance. Consistent with the information-signaling hypothesis, the stock price effects are more favorable for relatively small competitors, for rivals with stock returns that are highly correlated with the target's stock returns, when the targets experience favorable stock price effects, in technologically-intense industries, for rivals with poor prior performance, and with related acquisitions. Consistent with the competitive hypothesis, the stock price effects are less favorable with high degrees of financial leverage and when the acquirers already have a presence in the US. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: F23; G34.</description><author>Akhigbe, A.; Martin, A. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An exploratory analysis of the order book, and order flow and execution on the Saudi stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Al-Suhaibani, M.; Kryzanowski, L.
The microstructure of the Saudi Stock Market (SSM) under the new computerized trading system, ESIS, is described, and order and other generated data sets are used to examine the patterns in the order book, the dynamics of order how, and the probability of executing limit orders. Although the SSM has a distinct structure, its intraday patterns are surprisingly similar to those found in other markets with different structures. We find that liquidity, as commonly measured by width and depth, is relatively low on the SSM. However, liquidity is exceptionally high when measured by immediacy. Limit orders that are priced reasonably, on average, have a short duration before being executed, and have a high probability of subsequent execution. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G15.</description><author>Al-Suhaibani, M.; Kryzanowski, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price transmission dynamics between ADRs and their underlying foreign securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, M.; Szakmary, A. C.; Mathur, I.
This paper extends previous research by considering three pricing factors for American Depository Receipts (ADRs): the price of the underlying shares in the local currency, the relevant exchange rate, and the US market index. Using both a vector autoregressive (VGR) model with a cointegration constraint and a seemingly-unrelated regression (SUR) approach, we examine the relative importance of, and the speed of adjustment of ADR prices to, these underlying factors. Our results show that while the price of the underlying shares is most important, the exchange rate and the US market also have an impact on ADR prices. While the bulk of the shocks to the pricing factors are reflected in the ADRs within the same calendar day, there are indications that the adjustments are not completed until the following day. Curiously, the ADRs appear to initially overreact to the US market index but underreact to changes in underlying share prices and exchange rates. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G15; C22; F23.</description><author>Kim, M.; Szakmary, A. C.; Mathur, I.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The risk of foreign currency contingent claims at US commercial banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaudhry, M. K.; Christie-David, R.; Koch, T. W.; Reichert, A. K.
This study investigates the relationship between market-based measures of risk and foreign currency contingent claims activity at US commercial banks. Specifically, four types of foreign currency contingent claims are examined: purchased foreign currency option contracts, foreign-exchange swaps, commitments to purchase foreign currency and Forward contracts. Within the context of the Comptroller of the Currency's (OCC's) Banking Circular 277, we differentiate between the risk exposure of dealer banks and non-dealer banks. Empirical results suggest that (i) the use of options tends to increase all market-based measures of bank risk, (ii) swaps are used primarily for risk-control purposes and (iii) the use of forward contracts and currency commitments contributes mildly, if at all, to any type of risk. There is some evidence that swaps activity at dealer banks increases unsystematic risk. Otherwise, dealer and non-dealer banks appeal to similarly manage foreign currency risk. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21.</description><author>Chaudhry, M. K.; Christie-David, R.; Koch, T. W.; Reichert, A. K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical test of agency cost reduction using interest rate swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harper, J. T.; Wingender, J. R.
This paper tests a model based on Wall's (Wall, L., 1989. Journal of Banking and Finance 13, 261-270) hypothesis of agency cost reduction using interest rate swaps. We find a significant positive relationship between the risk of the firm and the reduction of agency costs measured by the continuously compounded excess return (CAR) of the firm, Our findings are consistent with Wall's hypothesis and other theories of swap transactions and in explaining the existence and growth of the swap market. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V, All rights reserved. JEL classification: D80; G10; G14.</description><author>Harper, J. T.; Wingender, J. R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>After-tax term structures of real interest rates: Inferences from the UK linked and non-linked gilt markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aziz, A. R.; Prisman, E. Z.
This study estimates the after-tax term structure of real interest rates using the prices of UK linked and non-linked gilts over the period from 25 January 1986 until 25 October 1993. The impact of differential taxation and the existence of "noise" in observed market prices is found to produce a significant impact on the parameter estimation of term structure models when compared to methods, such as Brown and Schaefer (Brown, R,, Schaefer, S,, 1994. Journal of Financial Economics 35, 1-42), that did not. Two major observations can be made regarding the estimates for spot real interest rates. Firstly, the volatility of the short-term rate is much lower than that found by Brown and Schaefer (1994) which provides a better fit with the predictions of the CIR single factor model for interest rates. Secondly, consistent with Rumsey (Rumsey, J., 1993. An impact of the assumptions about taxes on the estimation of the properties of interest rates, Working Paper), there appears to he some evidence to suggest that single factor interest rate models produce a better fit to interest rates on an after-tax basis than on a before tax basis. (C) 2000 Published by Elsevier Science B.V, All rights reserved. JEL classification: G10.</description><author>Aziz, A. R.; Prisman, E. Z.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification and the value of internal capital markets: The case of tracking stock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, M. T.; Mauer, D. C.
Diversified firms trade at a discount relative to comparable portfolios of stand-alone firms. One explanation is that these firms have inefficient internal capital markets. We examine the link between firm value and the value of internal capital markets using a new form of corporate restructuring called tracking stock, We present a model that illustrates that the announcement effect of a tracking stock equity restructuring conveys information about the market's assessment of the value of a firm's internal capital market. We develop a measure of the profitability of the internal capital market, and we find a strong positive relation between it and tracking stock announcement effects, a finding consistent with our model. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14; G30; G32; G34.</description><author>Billett, M. T.; Mauer, D. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changes in systematic risk following global equity issuance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ramchand, L.; Sethapakdi, P.
This paper examines changes in systematic risk following global equity issues by US firms. Models of market segmentation show that if international capital markets are not fully integrated and demand curves for securities are downward sloping, firms issue equity at higher pl ices by issuing in multiple markets compared to issuance on a single domestic market, This would imply a reduction in the firm's cost of capital and an increase in firm value. Using a sample of global equity offers during 1986-1993, we find that US firms that issue equity abroad experience a decline in systematic risk subsequent to issuance, After controlling for size, volume, and leverage effects, we find that this decline in systematic risk is larger in magnitude for global compared to a control sample of domestic equity issues. The larger the proportion of the offer sold abroad and the larger the increase in trading volume, the bigger the decline in systematic risk, Using a two-factor global risk model we find that while firms issuing equity abroad experience a decline in the domestic component of systematic risk, the foreign component increases. Overall, however, the net effect is a decline in the cost of capital. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: F30; G15.</description><author>Ramchand, L.; Sethapakdi, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of deregulation on price and non-price competition in the Portuguese deposits market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Pinho, P. S.
The Portuguese deposits market experienced a pronounced deregulation phase from 1986 to 1992. During that period the situation moved from a highly regulated market in which Government-controlled institutions accounted for more than 90% of the market, to a complete integration into the fully liberalised European Internal Market. This paper studies the evolution of market power and non-price competition during that deregulation process. Using panel data, a system of three equations was estimated representing optimality decisions for deposit rates, advertising expenditures and branches, An important conclusion is that interest rate and entry deregulation were associated with an increase in both price and non-price competition. The small foreign-owned banks were found to have virtually no market power in deposits. On the other hand, although no direct relationship between market power and market share was found, significant market power was detected for the wholesale and banks that existed since before the Revolution. Thus, mergers between large banks are not likely to directly increase market power for the participating firms. although the association found between market power. and concentration suggests that such mergers may increase the banking industry's profits. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21.</description><author>de Pinho, P. S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectations and learning in Iowa</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bondarenko, O.; Bossaerts, P.
We study the rationality of learning and the biases in expectations in the Iowa Experimental Markets. Using novel tests developed in (Bossaerts, P., 1996. Martingale restrictions on equilibrium security prices under rational expectations and consistent beliefs. Caltech working paper; Bossaerts, P., 1997. The dynamics of equity prices in fallible markets. Caltech working paper), learning in the Iowa winner-take-all markets is found to be in accordance with the rules of conditional probability (Bayes' law). Hence, participants correctly update their beliefs using the available information. There is evidence, however, that beliefs do not satisfy the restrictions of rational expectations that they reflect the factual distribution of outcomes. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: C90; D84; G14.</description><author>Bondarenko, O.; Bossaerts, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate control, bank risk taking, and the health of the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, R. C.; Fraser, D. R.
We present evidence that managerial shareholdings are an important determinant of bank risk-taking. Managerial shareholdings are positively related to total and firm specific risk in the late 1980s when banking was relatively less regulated and when the industry was under considerable financial stress. However, following legislation in 1989 and 1991 designed to reduce risk-taking and also reflecting substantial improvements in bank franchise value, managerial shareholdings and total and firm specific risk became negatively related in the early 1990s. In contrast, systematic risk was unrelated to managerial ownership in both periods. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anderson, R. C.; Fraser, D. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is there an optimal size for the financial sector?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santomero, A. M.; Seater, J. J.
This paper derives the optimal size of the financial sector using a general equilibrium framework that is an extension of the paper of Holmstrom and Tirole (1997) [Quarterly Journal of Economics 112, 663-691]. We show that the financial sector has a unique optimal size relative to the size of the economy as a whole. Creating and maintaining this sector requires diversion of some physical capital from production of output to monitoring that production. However, the efficiency gain in output production brought about by monitoring warrants the diversion. It is also found that the optimal size of the financial sector is independent of the state of the economy and does not vary over the business cycle. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: E44; E42; E51; G2.</description><author>Santomero, A. M.; Seater, J. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value at risk models for Dutch bond portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vlaar, P. J. G.
This study investigates the consequences of dynamics in the term structure of Dutch interest rates for the accurateness of value-at-risk models. Therefore, value-at-risk measures are calculated using both historical simulation, variance-covariance and Monte Carlo simulation methods. For a ten days holding period, the best results were obtained for a combined variance-covariance Monte Carlo method using a term structure model with a normal distribution and GARCH specification. Term structure models with a t-distribution or with cointegration performed much worse. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: E43; G28.</description><author>Vlaar, P. J. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Compensation vouchers and equity markets: Evidence from Hungary</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chun, R. M.
One of Hungary's policies during the transition from a centrally planned to a market economy was the issue of compensation vouchers - a unique security designed both as a privatization mechanism and as a form of restitution for Hungarian citizens who suffered property losses in post-war nationalizations. The coupons were actively traded on the Budapest Stock Exchange (BSE). This paper examines the intertemporal behavior of the Hungarian voucher and equity markets in an effort to assess the efficiency of these markets and to gauge the degree of interaction between the two different assets. Evidence from variance ratio tests indicates that stock and voucher trading are each individually weakly efficient. Furthermore, vector autoregressions and cointegration methods show that there is little detectable intermarket interaction: a result which is consistent with joint efficiency. Thus, although the Hungarian equity market is small, it appears to function remarkably well. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14; L33; O16.</description><author>Chun, R. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday price reversals for index futures in the US and Hong Kong</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fung, A. K. W.; Mok, D. M. Y.; Lam, K.
We observe intraday price reversals following large price changes at the opening of the S&amp;P 500 Futures market and the HSI Futures market. We note that the magnitude of subsequent price reversals is positively related to the initial price changes, and that the price reversals are not caused by a bid-ask spread, or by panic among investors. We also note that such price reversals can be exploited to give rise to profitable opportunities after transaction costs, even though these may not be very significant. This study shows that investor overreaction may be a universal phenomenon and irrational investor behavior like overreaction may also exist among groups of sophisticated investors. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14; G15.</description><author>Fung, A. K. W.; Mok, D. M. Y.; Lam, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are bank profits so persistent? The roles of product market competition, informational opacity, and regional/macroeconomic shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, A. N.; Bonime, S. D.; Covitz, D. M.; Hancock, D.
We investigate how banking market competition, informational opacity, and sensitivity to shocks have changed over the last three decades by examining the persistence of firm-level rents. We develop propagation mechanisms with testable implications to isolate the sources of persistence. Our analysis suggests that different processes underlie persistence at the high and low ends of the performance distribution. Our tests suggest that impediments to competition and informational opacity continue to be strong determinants of persistence; that the reduction in geographic regulatory restrictions had little effect on competitiveness; and that persistence remains sensitive to regional/macroeconomic shocks. The findings also suggest reasons for the recent record profitability of the industry. (C) 2000 Published by Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, A. N.; Bonime, S. D.; Covitz, D. M.; Hancock, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special issue on public debt management, financial markets and policy issues and competition among financial systems and bank-firm relationship after Euro - Editorial introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mergers and shareholder wealth in European banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cybo-Ottone, A.; Murgia, M.
We study the stock market valuation of mergers and acquisitions in the European banking industry. Based on a sample of very large deals observed from 1988 to 1997 we document that, on average, at the announcement time the size-adjusted combined performance of both the bidder and the target is statistically significant and economically relevant. Although our sample shows a great deal of cross-sectional variation, the general results are mainly driven by the significant positive abnormal returns associated with the announcement of domestic bank to bank deals and by product diversification of banks into insurance. On the contrary, we found that M&amp;A with securities firms and concluded with foreign institutions did not gain a positive market's expectation. Our results are remarkably different from those reported for US bank mergers. We explain our different results as stemming from the different structure and regulation of EU banking markets, which are shown to be more similar between them than as compared with the US one. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; G34.</description><author>Cybo-Ottone, A.; Murgia, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default risk and optimal debt management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drudi, F.; Giordano, R.
The role of movements in real rates in explaining the relationship between long- and short-term interest rates is explored within a model of optimal government debt management. The government's incentives to resort in the future to inflation and ex post debt taxation in order to reduce the real value of its nominal liabilities have an impact on term premia and hence on the short-long spread. In particular? default risk and, consequently, long-term interest rates increase with the size of outstanding debt and the level of real rates; in the presence of short maturities, indexed debt and anti-inflationary governments. Optimal maturity either lengthens or shortens with inflation risk, depending on the time profile of government expenditure, while it always lengthens with default risk, However, when the stock of debt is extremely large the compensation for default risk required by the agents on long-term bonds may be so high that only shortterm debt can be issued. The implications of this model are consistent with the observed behavior of risk premia in some highly indebted countries. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. H63; H43.</description><author>Drudi, F.; Giordano, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"The first shall be last". Size and value strategy premia at the London Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bagella, M.; Becchetti, L.; Carpentieri, A.
The paper analyses the determinants of cross-sectional stock returns at the London Stock Exchange in the last 26 years. It finds that portfolio strategies based on low values of earning per share (EPS), market to book value (MTBV), market Value (MV) and return on equity (ROE) significantly outperform the index. Do size and value (S&amp;V) strategy premia disappear when risk-adjusted or do they reveal gains from trading against noise, near rational, liquidity or "weak-hearted" traders? We find that the significance of cross-sectional determinants of these strategies is not absorbed by ex post betas. They are not riskier in terms of monthly return standard deviations, covariation with GDP growth and their premia do not disappear when survivorship bias is taken into account. Portfolio mean monthly returns (MMRs), regressed on several risk factors in 3-CAPM models, confirm that S&amp;V strategy premia persist when risk adjusted. Empirical results also mark the difference between ROE and MTBV portfolios, on the one side, and MV and EPS portfolios, on the other. Descriptive statistics on preformation and postformation returns, average balance sheet values and preformation standard deviations clearly show that ROE and MTBV portfolios have a common financial distress factor and are then more exposed to systematic risk. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G11.</description><author>Bagella, M.; Becchetti, L.; Carpentieri, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From value at risk to stress testing: The extreme value approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longin, F. M.
This article presents an application of extreme value theory to compute the value at risk of a market position. In statistics, extremes of a random process refer to the lowest observation (the minimum) and to the highest observation (the maximum) over a given time-period. Extreme value theory gives some interesting results about the distribution of extreme returns. In particular, the limiting distribution of extreme returns observed over a long time-period is largely independent of the distribution of returns itself. In financial markets, extreme price movements correspond to market corrections during ordinary periods, and also to stock market crashes, bond market collapses or foreign exchange crises during extraordinary periods. An approach based on extreme values to compute the VaR thus covers market conditions ranging from the usual environment considered by the existing VaR methods to the financial crises which are the focus of stress testing. Univariate extreme value theory is used to compute the VaR of a fully aggregated position while multivariate extreme value theory is used to compute the VaR of a position decomposed on risk factors, (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved, JEL classification: C51; G28.</description><author>Longin, F. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is there a tradeoff between bank competition and financial fragility?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koskela, E.; Stenbacka, R.
We use a model of mean-shifting investment technologies to study the relationship between market structure, risk taking and social welfare in lending markets. Introduction of loan market competition is shown to reduce lending rates and to generate higher investments without increasing the equilibrium bankruptcy risk of borrowers. Hence, there need not be a tradeoff between lending market competition and financial fragility. Such a tradeoff may not emerge either when banks compete by conditioning interest rates on investment volumes irrespectively of whether credit rationing takes place or not. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: 21; G33; G34.</description><author>Koskela, E.; Stenbacka, R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of market segmentation on stock prices: The China syndrome</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Q.; Tong, W. H. S.
China has an A-share market that is open only to local investors and a B-share market that is open only to foreign investors. Contrary to what has been observed in other markets with a similar segmented structure, the China B shares trade at a discount relative to the A shares. We show that the phenomenon can still be explained by basic economic principles. Specifically, the existence of the H-share and the "red-chip" markets in Hong Kong provide good substitutes for the B-share market. We find that when more H shares and red chips are listed in Hong Kong, the B-share discount becomes larger. This is consistent with the model of differential demand elasticity proposed by Stulz and Wasserfallen (Stulz, R., Wasserfallen, W., 1995. Review of Financial Studies 8, 1019-1057). (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G10; G15.</description><author>Sun, Q.; Tong, W. H. S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A synthetic factor approach to the estimation of value-at-risk of a portfolio of interest rate swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niffikeer, C. I.; Hewins, R. D.; Flavell, R. B.
In this paper we decompose the interest rate swap yield curves of 10 major currencies into their common factors and find that the first two factors, interpreted as parallel shift and rotation, explain between 97.1% and 98.6% of the variation in the interest rate swap rates across all 10 currencies. The main contribution of the paper however is that we then model these two factors as simplified synthetic factors so that they may be used to develop an innovative approach to the computation of Value-at-Risk (VaR) for a portfolio of interest rate swaps. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G13; G15; G21; G28.</description><author>Niffikeer, C. I.; Hewins, R. D.; Flavell, R. B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity markets and growth: Cross-country evidence on timing and outcomes, 1980-1995</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rousseau, P. L.; Wachtel, P.
The rapid expansion of organized equity exchanges in both emerging and developed markets has prompted policymakers to raise important questions about their macroeconomic impact, yet the need to focus on recent data poses implementation difficulties for econometric studies of dynamic interactions between stock markets and economic performance in individual countries, This paper overcomes some of these difficulties by applying recent developments in the analysis of panels with a small time dimension to estimate vector autoregressions for a set of 47 countries with annual data for 1980-1995, After describing recent theories on the role of stock markets in growth and considering a pure cross-sectional empirical approach, our panel VARs show leading roles for stock market liquidity and the intensity of activity in traditional financial intermediaries on per capita output. The findings underscore the potential gains associated with developing deep and liquid financial markets in an increasingly global economy. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V, All rights reserved. JEL classification: E44; G15; O40.</description><author>Rousseau, P. L.; Wachtel, P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership, managerial control and the governance of companies listed on the Brussels stock exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Renneboog, L.
This paper examines how corporate control is exerted in companies listed on the Brussels Stock Exchange. There are several alternative corporate governance mechanisms which may play a role in disciplining poorly performing management: blockholders (holding companies, industrial companies, families and institutions), the market for partial control, debt policy, and board composition. Even if there is redundancy of substitute forms of discipline, some mechanisms may dominate. We find that top managerial turnover is strongly related to poor performance measured by stock returns, accounting earnings in relation to industry peers and dividend cuts and omissions. Tobit models reveal that there is little relation between ownership and managerial replacement, although industrial companies resort to disciplinary actions when performance is poor. When industrial companies increase their share stake or acquire a new stake in a poorly performing company, there is evidence of an increase in executive board turnover, which suggests a partial market for control. There is little relation between changes in ownership concentration held by institutions and holding companies, and disciplining. Still, high leverage and decreasing solvency and liquidity variables are also followed by increased disciplining, as are a high proportion of non-executive directors and the separation of the functions of CEO and chairman. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G3; G32; G38.</description><author>Renneboog, L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital markets in Central and Eastern Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blasko, M.
nan</description><author>Blasko, M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How did bank holding companies prosper in the 1990s?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stiroh, K. J.
This paper examines the improved performance of US bank holding companies (BHCs) from 1991 to 1997. Analysis of cost and profit functions using several alternative output specifications suggests that the gains were primarily due to productivity growth and changes in scale economies. Various econometric methodologies yield productivity growth of about 0.4% per year and the optimal size seems to have increased in the 1990s era of deregulation, technological change, and financial innovation. Estimates of both productivity growth and economies of scale are robust across traditional and non-traditional output specifications. Despite the overall success, however, substantial cost and profit inefficiency existed for BHCs of all sizes in the 1990s. These efficiency estimates are particularly sensitive to the output specification and failure to account for non-traditional activities like off-balance sheet (OBS) items leads profit efficiency, but not cost efficiency, to be understated for the largest BHCs. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; D21.</description><author>Stiroh, K. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment opportunities, free cash flow and market reaction to international joint ventures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, S. S.; Ho, K. W.; Lee, C. F.; Yeo, G. H. H.
This paper examines the role of investment opportunities and foe cash flow in explaining the source of the wealth effect of international joint ventures. We document that firms with promising investment opportunities have significantly positive response to announcements of international joint venture investments, whereas firms with poor investment opportunities have unfavorable response to such announcements. In contrast, we find that free cash how does not explain the cross-sectional differences in abnormal returns associated with the announcements of international joint ventures. Thus, our results show support for the investment opportunities hypothesis but no support for the free cash flow hypothesis. These findings hold even after controlling for other potential explanatory variables. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, S. S.; Ho, K. W.; Lee, C. F.; Yeo, G. H. H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The components of bid-ask spreads on the London Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menyah, K.; Paudyal, K.
The objective of this paper is to estimate the cost components of the bid-ask spread on the London Stock Exchange using intraday data. The findings are unambiguous in isolating the three cost components of quoted spreads. They are, therefore, consistent with the earlier work of Stoll based on the quote driven Nasdaq market (Stoll, H., 1989. Journal of Finance 44, 753-776), Additionally, the three spread components vary with the liquidity of the stocks measured by the minimum number of shares market makers are obliged to trade. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Menyah, K.; Paudyal, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of captive insurer formation on stock returns: An empirical test from the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, M.; Hillier, D.
This paper examines the stock market impact of captive insurance subsidiary formation on parent companies in the United Kingdom (UK) corporate sector. We report that the formation of an insurance captive has no effect on the financial, systematic and unsystematic risks of the parent company, irrespective of the parent's market capitalisation. In addition? there is weak evidence that the market has a negative view of the captive insurance decision. Finally, our results indicate that financial risk, agency costs of free cash flow, asymmetric information and market power have no effect on the stock market's reaction to the captive formation decision. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, M.; Hillier, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation of adjustable rate mortgages with automatic stretching maturity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chow, Y. F.; Huang, C.; Liu, M.
In Hong Kong, 35% of residential mortgage loans are adjustable rate mortgages with variable tenor (VRT). That is, with a change in interest rates, the loan adjusts its maturity and principal payment such that the monthly installment remains the same. In other words, instead of bearing a volatility on monthly payments as in a fixed-tenor variable payment (VRP) mortgage, VRT mortgagors bear interest rate risk by bearing a tenor risk. In this paper, we analyze the valuation of this type of mortgages and the results are compared with the conventional VRP mortgages. We find VRT loans are less expensive from a borrower's perspective than VRP loans, but the difference between the loans becomes less significant if a tenor cap is added to the VRT loan. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chow, Y. F.; Huang, C.; Liu, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric information, dividend reductions, and contagion effects in bank stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessler, W.; Nohel, T.
In an environment of asymmetric information, banks face information externalities due to their role as intermediaries of information. In particular, bank insiders will possess private information from monitoring loan customers. Accordingly, outsiders may interpret changes in a bank's financial policy as signals about the quality of its loan portfolio and to the extent that the assets (loans) of different banks are viewed as similar, they will interpret such signals as pertaining to non-announcing banks as well leading to contagion effects. We test for the presence of contagion effects in stock returns associated with announcements of dividend cuts by money-center banks. We find that dividend cuts induce negative abnormal returns in the stocks of non-announcing money-center banks and to a lesser extent in the stocks of large regional banks. The observed contagion effects appear consistent with informed rather than contagious panic behavior because these effects are systematically related to risks that are common to all affected banks. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bessler, W.; Nohel, T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default risk and optimal debt management (vol 24, pg 861, 2000)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drudi, F.; Giordano, R.
nan</description><author>Drudi, F.; Giordano, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A word of caution on calculating market-based minimum capital risk requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brooks, C.; Clare, A. D.; Persand, G.
This paper demonstrates that the use of GARCH-type models for the calculation of minimum capital risk requirements (MCRRs) may lead to the production of inaccurate and therefore inefficient capital requirements. We show that this inaccuracy stems from the fact that GARCH models typically overstate the degree of persistence in return volatility. A simple modification to the model is found to improve the accuracy of MCRR estimates in both back- and out-of-sample tests. Given that internal risk management models are currently in widespread usage in some parts of the world (most notably the USA), and will soon be permitted for EC banks and investment firms, we believe that our paper, should serve as a valuable caution to risk management practitioners who are using, or intend to use this popular class of models. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V, All rights reserved. JEL classification. C14; C15; G13.</description><author>Brooks, C.; Clare, A. D.; Persand, G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political elections and the resolution of uncertainty: The international evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pantzalis, C.; Strangeland, D. A.; Turtle, H. J.
We investigate the behavior of stock market indices across 33 countries around political election dates during the sample period 1974-1995. We find a positive abnormal return during the two-week period prior to the election week. The positive reaction of the stock market to elections is shown to be a function of a country's degree of political, economic and press freedom, and a function of the election timing: and the success of the incumbent in being re-elected. In particular, we find strong positive abnormal returns leading up to the elections (i) in less free countries won by the opposition, and (ii) called early and lost by the incumbent government. These results are consistent with the uncertain information hypothesis (UIH) of Brown et al. (Brown, K.C., Harlow, W.V., Tinic, S.M., 1988. Journal of Financial Economics 22, 355-385) and the model of election behavior of Harrington (Harrington, J.E,, 1993. The American Economic Review 83, 27-42). (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G14; G15.</description><author>Pantzalis, C.; Strangeland, D. A.; Turtle, H. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency and risk in Japanese banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altunbas, Y.; Liu, M. H.; Molyneux, P.; Seth, R.
This paper investigates the impact of risk and quality factors on banks' cost by using the stochastic cost frontier methodology to evaluate scale and X-inefficiencies, as well as technical change for a sample of Japanese commercial banks between 1993 and 1996, Loan-loss provisions are included in the cost frontier model to control for output quality, with a financial capital and a liquidity ratio included to control risk. Following the approach suggested in Mester (1996) we show that if risk and quality factors are not taken into account optimal bank size tends to be overstated. That is, optimal bank size is considerably smaller when risk and quality factors are taken into account when modelling the cost characteristics of Japanese banks. We also find that the level of financial capital has the biggest influence on the scale efficiency estimates. X-inefficiency estimates, in contrast, appear less sensitive to risk and quality factors. Our results also suggest that scale inefficiencies dominate X-inefficiencies. These are important findings because they contrast with the results of previous studies on Japanese banking. In particular, the results indicate an alternative policy prescription, namely, that the largest banks should shrink to benefit from scale advantages. It also seems that financial capital has the largest influence on optimal bank size. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; D21; G23.</description><author>Altunbas, Y.; Liu, M. H.; Molyneux, P.; Seth, R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of the affiliation of banking and commerce on the firm's investment and the bank's risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, S.
This paper examines how the affiliation of banking and commerce affects the firm's investment efficiency and the bank's risk exposure. The bank's holding of a borrowing firm's equity reduces the agency conflict between the firm and the bank, but increases the monitoring need of uninformed debtholders. Thus, the firm's investment efficiency is maximized when the bank's equity share is between zero and its debt share. The bank's risk exposure can increase in two ways. With a large equity share, the bank has more incentives to allow the firm to undertake risky projects. The firm, when it has control over the bank, may force the bank to finance its risky projects. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; G28.</description><author>Park, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An examination of herd behavior in equity markets: An international perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, E. C.; Cheng, J. W.; Khorana, A.
We examine the investment behavior of market participants within different international markets (i.e,, US, Hong Kong, Japan, South Korea, and Taiwan), specifically with regard to their tendency to exhibit herd behavior. We find no evidence of herding on the part of market participants in the US and Hong Kong and partial evidence of herding in Japan. However, for South Korea and Taiwan, the two emerging markets in our sample, we document significant evidence of herding. The results are robust across various size-based portfolios and over time. Furthermore, macroeconomic information rather than firm-specific information tends to have a more significant impact on investor behavior in markets which exhibit herding. In all five markets, the rate of increase in security return dispersion as a function of the aggregate market return is higher in up market, relative to down market days. This is consistent with the directional asymmetry documented by McQueen et al. (1996) (McQueen, G,, Pinegar, M.A., Thorley, S., 1996. Journal of Finance 51, 889-919). (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G15.</description><author>Chang, E. C.; Cheng, J. W.; Khorana, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuing the strategic option to sell life insurance business: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klumpes, P. J. M.; Shackleton, M. B.
We present a simple put option pricing procedure within an asset-liability valuation model that call be used to estimate the incentives facing stock-based life insurance firms to voluntarily sell their businesses under various operating and regulatory conditions. Estimates are derived for samples of 11 sold firms and 24 continuing Australian life insurance companies over a period of industry consolidation. The put option values interact with other actuarial and accounting components of the fair value of these life insurance firms and are used to assess the effectiveness of accounting and actuarial measures of capital, under static or dynamic based solvency testing models. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. G22.</description><author>Klumpes, P. J. M.; Shackleton, M. B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fiscal policy, debt management and exchange rate credibility: Lessons from the recent Italian experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amato, A.; Tronzano, M.
This paper explores some potential determinants of exchange rate credibility with reference to the Italian experience of the 1990s, The analysis relies on a nonlinear framework emphasizing shifts between credible and non-credible states, and assuming a significant degree of persistence in the above regimes. Almost all fiscal and debt management indicators display significant effects on devaluation expectations. The main policy implications of the paper are that a restrictive fiscal stance, a lengthening of average debt maturity and an increase in the share of foreign-denominated debt are crucial to stabilize the Lira exchange rate and to qualify Italy in the former group of countries which will join EMU. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: E62; E65; F31.</description><author>Amato, A.; Tronzano, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank competition and ECB's monetary policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bagliano, F. C.; Dalmazzo, A.; Marini, G.
In a model of oligopolistic competition in the banking sector, we analyse how the monetary policy rule chosen by the Central Bank can influence the incentive of banks to set high interest rates on loans over the business cycle. We exploit the basic model to investigate the potential impact of EMU implementation on collusion among banks. In particular, we consider the possible effects of the European Central Bank's policy criteria with regard to the cost of credit in national markets. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. D43; E52; G21.</description><author>Bagliano, F. C.; Dalmazzo, A.; Marini, G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest-rate derivatives and bank lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brewer, E.; Minton, B. A.; Moser, J. T.
We study the relationship between bank participation in derivatives contracting and bank lending for the period 30 June 1985 through the end of 1992. Since 1985 commercial banks have become active participants in the interest-rate derivative products markets as end-users, or intermediaries, or both. Over much of this period significant changes were made in the composition of bank portfolios. We find that banks using interest-rate derivatives experience greater growth in their commercial and industrial (C&amp;I) loan portfolios than banks that do not use these financial instruments. This result is consistent with the model of Diamond (Review of Economic Studies 51, 1984, 393-414) which predicts that intermediaries' use of derivatives enables increased reliance on their comparative advantage as delegated monitors. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brewer, E.; Minton, B. A.; Moser, J. T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on market response to corporate loan announcements in Canada</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aintablian, S.; Roberts, G. S.
This note validates the key results of prior studies of bank loan announcement effects using a common data set drawn from the Canadian capital market. Announcements of bank loans are associated with positive abnormal returns significantly higher than for private placements and loan syndications. Announcement effects are most pronounced when monitoring is most intense and when an announcement signals that the bank's private information is favorable. Conclusions of prior studies on bank loan announcements, conducted exclusively on US data, are robust for a different banking system. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aintablian, S.; Roberts, G. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider trading and the voluntary disclosure of information by firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayanan, R.
We examine the voluntary disclosure policy of a firm where the manager has private information and opportunities to trade on it. The equilibrium disclosure policy ranges from full disclosure to partial disclosure to nondisclosure depending on whether the manager's pay-performance sensitivity is high, medium or low, respectively. In the partial disclosure equilibrium, good news is more likely to be disclosed early than bad news and insiders are more likely to sell than buy shares, two results for which there is ample empirical support. The likelihood and amount of voluntary disclosure increases with the manager's pay-performance sensitivity, firm quality, and the number of insiders privy to the information and decreases with market liquidity. Stringent enforcement of insider trading regulations induces more disclosure by firms whereas the short sales prohibition on insiders induces less disclosure. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Narayanan, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Operating leases and the assessment of lease-debt substitutability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beattie, V.; Goodacre, A.; Thomson, S.
Operating leases are estimated in the current paper to be approximately thirteen times larger than finance leases, on average. In recognition of this, the paper investigates the degree of substitutability between leasing and non-lease debt using a comprehensive measure of leasing, improving on the partial measures used in prior research. Operating lease liabilities are estimated using the 'constructive capitalisation' approach suggested by Imhoff, Lipe and Wright (1991, Accounting Horizons 5, pp. 51-63), modified to incorporate company-specific and UK-relevant assumptions. The results imply that leasing and debt are partial substitutes, with fl of leasing displacing approximately pound 0.23 of non-lease debt, on average, consistent with the argument that lessors bear some risks which are not inherent in debt contracts. These findings suggest that substitution effects are not uniform across lease types. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beattie, V.; Goodacre, A.; Thomson, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common stock returns and international listing announcements: Conditional tests of the mild segmentation hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doukas, J.; Switzer, L. N.
Recent theoretical work on mild segmentation suggests that tests of dual listing should be conducted as joint tests: (a) a test of changes in market integration that may affect asset returns through investors portfolio reallocations as the choice set changes, and (b) a test of changing risk premium/information effects. Previous empirical studies on common stocks have been unable to identify significant positive abnormal returns associated with international listing. However, such studies have not formally tested for changes in market integration through time. In addition, they have not examined announcement dates, which should be the focal point in testing for valuation effects. Unlike previous studies, our analysis concentrates on both the period surrounding the earliest public announcements by Canadian companies of their intentions to seek a US listing for their common shares on the NYSE, AMEX, or NASDAQ as well as the date of US listing during the period 1985-96, This period encompasses significant changes in the regulatory environment which might be perceived to enhance the integration of the two markets. Relying on a conditional asset pricing model subject to time-varying volatility, the results of this study fail to support the view that market integration has increased between the Canadian and US stock markets over the 1985-96 period. The significantly positive announcement effects of Canadian stock listings in the US stock market are consistent with the view that the two markets remain mildly segmented despite the elimination of several institutional changes that should have enhanced capital market integration between the two stock markets. Our evidence also implies that firms operating in mildly segmented capital markets can attain a lower risk premium through international stock listings. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doukas, J.; Switzer, L. N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How the environment determines banking efficiency: A comparison between French and Spanish industries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dietsch, M.; Lozano-Vivas, A.
This paper investigates the influence the environmental conditions have on the cost-efficiency of French and Spanish banking industries. We propose a new methodology for cross-country comparisons of efficiency using a parametric approach. In particular, the specific environmental conditions of each country play an important role in the definition and specification of the common frontier of different countries. Our results suggest that, without environmental variables, the cost-efficiency scores of Spanish banks are quite low compared to those of the French banks. However, when environmental variables are included in the model, the differences between both banking industries are reduced substantially. Overall, our results demonstrate that environmental variables contribute significantly to the difference in efficiency scores between the two countries. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification. O2; G2; G21; F36; L5.</description><author>Dietsch, M.; Lozano-Vivas, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comparative analysis of current credit risk models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crouhy, M.; Galai, D.; Mark, R.
The new BIS 1998 capital requirements for market risks allows banks to use internal models to assess regulatory capital related to both general market risk and credit risk for their trading book. This paper reviews the current proposed industry sponsored Credit Value-at-Risk methodologies. First, the credit migration approach, as proposed by JP Morgan with CreditMetrics, is based on the probability of moving from one credit quality to another, including default, within a given time horizon. Second, the option pricing, or structural approach, as initiated by KMV and which is based on the asset value model originally proposed by Merton (Merton, R., 1974. Journal of Finance 28, 449-470). In this model the default process is endogenous, and relates to the capital structure of the firm. Default occurs when the value of the firm's assets falls below some critical level. Third, the actuarial approach as proposed by Credit Suisse Financial Products (CSFP) with CreditRisk+ and which only focuses on default. Default for individual bonds or loans is assumed to follow an exogenous Poisson process. Finally, McKinsey proposes CreditPortfolioView which is a discrete time multi-period model where default probabilities are conditional on the macro-variables like unemployment, the level of interest rates, the growth rate in the economy, ... which to a large extent drive the credit cycle in the economy. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved. JEL classification: G21; G28; G13.</description><author>Crouhy, M.; Galai, D.; Mark, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>