<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Banking &amp; Finance3</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Family control and loan collateral: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Xiaofei; Tian, Gary Gang
Using a sample of 612 listed Chinese non-SOEs from 2006 to 2009, we show that the use of collateral is higher in family-controlled firms. This effect is more pronounced when family firms have a larger control ownership wedge, family representation in management, and are led by a descendant chairman/CEO. We further document that having multiple large shareholders, paying higher dividends, having completed the split-share structure reform and being located in provinces with more competitive credit markets can mitigate the incentive of controlling families to engage in expropriation and reduce the level of collateral required. Overall, we contend that in China, the risk of expropriation associated with family control leads to an increased credit risk and, in turn, higher collateral being required by banks. Crown Copyright (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pan, Xiaofei; Tian, Gary Gang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of social screening on bond mutual fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henke, Hans-Martin
This study measures the financial impact of screening for environmental, social and governance criteria on corporate bond portfolios. Specifically, the risk-adjusted financial performance of 103 socially responsible bond funds in the US and the Eurozone is compared with a matched sample of conventional funds. During the period 2001-2014, socially responsible bond funds outperform by one-half of one percent annually. An evaluation of fund holdings and a performance-attribution analysis suggest that this outper-formance is directly related to the mitigation of ESG risks, which is achieved by the exclusion of corporate bond issuers with poor corporate social responsibility activities. A separation of crisis and non-crisis periods further indicates that the outperformance is especially likely to occur during recessions or bear market periods. We confirm this crisis-related return effect from a sample of socially screened bond indices. Moreover, our results are robust to alternative definitions of sustainability, survivorship bias, fund characteristics and stable in the US and Eurozone sub-samples. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Henke, Hans-Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating the robustness of UK term structure decompositions using linear regression methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malik, Sheheryar; Meldrum, Andrew
Dynamic no-arbitrage affine term structure models (ATSMs) have become the standard framework for monetary policy-makers to decompose long-term bond yields into expectations of future short-term risk-free interest rates and the term premia that compensate investors in long-term bonds for risk. This paper presents estimates of ATSMs for the UK and explores how much weight users of these models can place on point estimates of term premia. Over much of the period since the early 1990s, broad movements in estimated premia are robust across a wide range of reasonable specifications. But there is substantial model and parameter uncertainty associated with these models and estimates of the time-series dynamics of yields may be biased in short samples. This model uncertainty is greater towards the end of our sample period, when bond yields have been well below historically normal levels. (C) 2016 The Bank of England. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malik, Sheheryar; Meldrum, Andrew</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do asset prices have to say about risk appetite and uncertainty?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, Geert; Hoerova, Marie
Building on intuition from the dynamic asset pricing literature, we uncover unobserved risk aversion and fundamental uncertainty from the observed time series of the variance premium and the credit spread while controlling for the conditional variance of stock returns, expectations about the macroeconomic outlook, and interest rates. We apply this methodology to monthly data from both Germany and the US. We find that the variance premium contains a substantial amount of information about risk aversion whereas the credit spread has a lot to say about uncertainty. We link our risk aversion and uncertainty estimates to practitioner and "academic" risk aversion indices, sentiment indices, financial stress indices, business cycle indicators and liquidity measures. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Hoerova, Marie</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systematic multi-period stress scenarios with an application to CCP risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Genaro, Alan
In the aftermath of the financial crisis of 2007-2008 regulators in multiple jurisdictions have laid the foundation of new regulatory standards aiming at strengthening systemic resilience. Among different initiatives, mandatory central clearing of standardized OTC derivatives has been one of the most prominent. Because OTC derivatives entail default management procedures that are far more complex than listed derivatives, risk management procedures have to follow suit. The recent paper by Vicente et al. (2015) propose an innovative way to calculate margin requirements by using multi-period robust optimization (RO) methods that accounts for important differences between OTC and listed derivatives default procedures. Motivated by this methodology, this paper proposes a hybrid framework to construct discrete uncertainty sets, in which each element of this set can be seen as multi-period stress scenarios, which are necessary to solve the RO problem faced by the Central Counterparty (CCP). When applied to determine the margin requirements, the present method provides both qualitative and quantitative results that outperform other robust optimization models such as Ben-Tal and Nemirovski (2000) and Bertsimas and Pachamanova (2008). (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Genaro, Alan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the risk-return trade-off with overlapping data inference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hedegaard, Esben; Hodrick, Robert J.
Investigations of the basic risk-return trade-off for the market return typically use maximum likelihood estimation (MLE) with a monthly or quarterly horizon and data sampled to match the horizon even though daily data are available. We develop an overlapping data inference methodology for such models that uses all of the data while maintaining the monthly or quarterly forecasting period. Our approach recognizes that the first order conditions of MLE can be used as orthogonality conditions of the generalized method of moments (GMM). While parameter estimates from the different non-overlapping monthly samples that start on different days vary substantively, a formal test does not reject parameter equality and constrained estimation of the risk-return trade-off produces a statistically significant value of 3.35 in post-1955 data. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hedegaard, Esben; Hodrick, Robert J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An econometric evaluation of bank recapitalization programs with bank- and loan-level data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nakashima, Kiyotaka
Public capital injections into the banking system are a comprehensive policy program aimed at reducing the financial risks faced by capital-injected banks, thereby stimulating their lending and profitability. This paper evaluates empirically Japan's two large-scale capital injections in 1998 and 1999. We begin by extracting the treatment effects of the public injections from bank-level panel data. Using a difference-in-difference estimator in two-way fixed-effects regression models, we find that the public injections significantly reduced the financial risks faced by the capital-injected banks but did not stimulate their lending or profitability. Next, we investigate what factors impeded bank lending after the public injections. using a matched sample of Japanese banks and their borrowers. By employing three-way fixed-effects regression models corresponding to the matched sample, we provide evidence that the deterioration of borrowers' creditworthiness inhibited not only the injected banks but also the noninjected banks from lending more. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nakashima, Kiyotaka</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of corporate bond granularity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Norden, Lars; Roosenboom, Peter; Wang, Teng
We investigate whether and how firms manage their rollover risk by having a dispersed bond maturity structure (granularity). Granularity can be achieved or maintained by frequently issuing sets of bonds with different maturities. We find that firms with higher granularity have higher availability of financing, lower cost of financing, lower financial constraints and lower stock return volatility. The effects are stronger for firms that face higher rollover risk. The evidence suggests that spreading out bond maturities is an effective corporate policy to manage rollover risk. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Norden, Lars; Roosenboom, Peter; Wang, Teng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate finance and the governance implications of removing government support programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacob, Martin; Johan, Sofia; Schweizer, Denis; Zhan, Feng
Governments worldwide spend trillions of dollars on business support programs. This article examines the implications to investors of phasing out one of these subsidy programs. Our setting takes advantage of a unique quasi-natural experiment, where tax subsidies for Canadian labour-Sponsored Venture Capital Corporations (LSVCCs) were phased out in one province but not in others. Using a difference-in-differences setting, we show that fund performance-unrelated to the tax credit-decreased substantially following the enactment of the phase-out. We further show empirically that LSVCC managers continued to charge venture capital-like management fees, despite the fact that their investment strategies become more similar to mutual funds. Our data strongly support the idea that investors in companies and/or funds that unexpectedly lose government support face significant financial costs. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacob, Martin; Johan, Sofia; Schweizer, Denis; Zhan, Feng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bribe payments under regulatory decentralization: Evidence from rights offering regulations in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Ye; An, Yunbi; Zhang, Jinqing
This paper investigates why and how firms' bribe payments vary as a result of the interaction between firms and local public officials under the decentralized regulatory system for rights offerings implemented prior to 2001 in China. Using the gap between the estimated and reported total direct costs of rights offerings as a measure of firms' bribes payments in the process of rights offering applications under this system, we find that bribe payments are positively related to local governments' control rights, firms' opportunity costs of refusing to pay bribes, and the severity of firms' Jensen agency problems. We further show that after termination of the regulatory system, firms' bribe payments are substantially reduced, and local governments' control rights as well as the severity of firms' Jensen agency problems can no longer explain the variation in bribe payments. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Ye; An, Yunbi; Zhang, Jinqing</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do carbon prices and price volatility change?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibrahim, Boulis Maher; Kalaitzoglou, Iordanis Angelos
An asymmetric information microstructural pricing model is proposed in which price responses to information and liquidity vary with every transaction. bid-ask quotes and price components account for learning by incorporating changing expectations of the rate of transacted volume (trading intensity) and the risk level of incoming trades. Analysis of European carbon futures transactions finds expected trading intensity to simultaneously increase the information component and decrease the liquidity component of price changes, but at different rates. This explains some conflicting results in prior literature. Further, the expected persistence in trading intensity explains the majority of the autocorrelations in the level and the conditional variance of price change; helps predict hourly patterns in returns, variance and the bid-ask spread; and differentiates the price impact of buy versus sell and continuing versus reversing trades. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ibrahim, Boulis Maher; Kalaitzoglou, Iordanis Angelos</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are foreign IPOs really foreign? Price efficiency and information asymmetry of Chinese foreign IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tourani-Rad, Alireza; Gilbert, Aaron; Chen, Jun
We investigate the informational risk and price efficiency of Chinese firms undertaking a foreign IPO on the Hong Kong stock exchange between 1996 and 2012. Specifically, using intraday tick data, we examine the spreads, asymmetric information component of the bid-ask spread, autocorrelations of intraday returns, variance ratios and return predictability of the order flow for foreign IPO firms. We contrast these measures against those of comparable IPO firms on both the Chinese stock exchanges and the Hong Kong stock exchange matched based on the year of IPO, industry and firm size. We find that while the foreign IPO firms largely operate in China, they are generally perceived as having a similar level of information asymmetry and price efficiency as Hong Kong IPO firms. In contrast, IPOs on the Chinese exchanges have much higher proportions of information asymmetry in their spreads and lower price efficiency than foreign IPO firms. Our findings are generally robust to the use of the Heckman two-stage procedure that controls for potential self-selection bias. Our results provide further evidence that it is the location of trading that is important for pricing of firms rather than the location of their business. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tourani-Rad, Alireza; Gilbert, Aaron; Chen, Jun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The systemic risk of European banks during the financial and sovereign debt crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Black, Lamont; Correa, Ricardo; Huang, Xin; Zhou, Hao
European banks became a source of risk to global financial markets during the financial crisis and attention to the European banking sector increased during the sovereign debt crisis. To measure the systemic risk of European banks, we calculate a distress insurance premium (DIP), which integrates the characteristics of bank size, probability of default, and correlation. Based on this measure, the systemic risk of European banks reached its height in late 2011 around (sic)500 billion. We find that this was largely due to sovereign default risk. The DIP methodology is also used to measure the systemic contribution of individual banks. This approach identifies the large systemically important European banks, but Italian and Spanish banks as a group notably increased in systemic importance during the sample period. Bank-specific fundamentals like capital-asset ratios predict the one-year-ahead systemic risk contributions. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Black, Lamont; Correa, Ricardo; Huang, Xin; Zhou, Hao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transaction costs, liquidity risk, and the CCAPM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Weimin; Luo, Di; Zhao, Huainan
In this paper, we make a liquidity adjustment to the consumption-based capital asset pricing model (CCAPM) and show that the liquidity-adjusted CCAPM is a generalized model of Acharya and Pedersen (2005). Using different proxies for transaction costs such as the effective trading costs measure of Hasbrouck (2009) and the bid-ask spread estimates of Corwin and Schultz (2012), we find that the liquidity-adjusted CCAPM explains a larger fraction of the cross-sectional return variations. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Weimin; Luo, Di; Zhao, Huainan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-performing loans, moral hazard and regulation of the Chinese commercial banking system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Dayong; Cai, Jing; Dickinson, David G.; Kutan, Ali M.
Non-performing loans (NPLs) represent a major obstacle to the development of banking sector. One of the key objectives of the banking sector reforms in China has therefore been to reduce the high level of NPLs. To do so, Chinese regulatory authorities have injected significant capital into the banking system and scrutinized NPLs since 2003. This paper examines the impact of NPLs on bank behavior in China. Using a threshold panel regression model-and a dataset covering 60 city commercial banks, 16 state-owned banks and joint-stock banks, and 11 rural commercial banks during 2006-2012, we test whether lending decisions of Chinese banks exhibit moral hazard. The results support the moral hazard hypothesis, suggesting that an increase in the NPLs ratio raises riskier lending, potentially causing further deterioration of the loan quality and financial system instability. Policy implications of findings are evaluated. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhang, Dayong; Cai, Jing; Dickinson, David G.; Kutan, Ali M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of the sentiment index</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sibley, Steven E.; Wang, Yanchu; Xing, Yuhang; Zhang, Xiaoyan
The widely-used Baker and Wurgler (2006) sentiment index is strongly correlated with business cycle variables, especially the short interest rate and Lee (2011) liquidity risk factor. The power of the sentiment index to predict cross-sectional stock returns is mainly driven by its information content related to these business cycle variables. About 63% percent of the total variation in the investor sentiment index can be explained by well-known, contemporaneous risk/business cycle variables. We decompose the widely used investor sentiment index into two components: one related to standard risk/business cycle variables and the other unrelated to those variables. We show that the power of the sentiment index to predict cross-sectional stock returns is mainly driven by the risk/business cycle component, while the residual component has little significance in predicting cross-sectional stock returns. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sibley, Steven E.; Wang, Yanchu; Xing, Yuhang; Zhang, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early influences on saving behaviour: Analysis of British panel data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Sarah; Taylor, Karl
Using data from the British Household Panel Survey and Understanding Society, we examine the saving behaviour of individuals over time. Initially, we explore the determinants of the saving behaviour of children aged 11-15. Our findings suggest that parental allowances/pocket money (earnings from part-time work) lower (increase) the probability that a child saves. There is also evidence that the financial expectations of the head of household have an influence on their offspring's saving behaviour, where children of optimistic parents have a lower probability of saving by approximately 2 percentage points. However, there is no evidence of an intergenerational correlation in savings behaviour: the saving behaviour of parents appears to have no bearing on the saving decisions of their offspring. We then go on to explore the implications of the saving behaviour of children for their savings decisions in later life, specifically when observed in early adulthood. We find that having saved as a child has a large positive influence both on the probability of saving on a monthly basis and on the amount saved as an adult. This finding is robust to alternative empirical strategies including IV analysis where the most conservative estimates show that having saved as a child increases the probability of saving during adulthood by 12 percentage points. (C) 2015 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Brown, Sarah; Taylor, Karl</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the impact of changes in aggregate bank capital requirements on lending and growth during an upswing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Noss, Joseph; Toffano, Priscilla
This paper estimates the effect of changes in banks' capital requirements on lending by studying the joint dynamics of the historic aggregate capital ratio of the UK banking system and a set of macro-financial variables. This is achieved by means of sign restrictions that attempt to identify shocks in past data that match a set of assumed directional responses of other variables to future changes in capital requirements aimed at increasing the resilience of the banking system to losses during an upswing. This may provide policy-makers with a plausible 'upper bound' on the short-term effects of future increases in macroprudential capital requirements in certain states of the UK economic cycle. An increase in the aggregate bank capital requirement during an economic upswing is associated with a reduction in lending, with a larger effect on lending to corporates than on that to households. The impact on GDP growth is statistically insignificant. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Noss, Joseph; Toffano, Priscilla</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment-cash flow sensitivity under changing information asymmetry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chowdhury, Jaideep; Kumar, Raman; Shome, Dilip
Empirical studies on whether investments are sensitive to cash flows in imperfect markets often report conflicting results and have been criticized on conceptual and methodological grounds. Our study mitigates some of these problems using a research design that relates changes in investment-cash flow sensitivity to changes in the bid-ask spread measure of information asymmetry surrounding (i) implementation of the Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) Act and (ii) deregulation of firms in the Transportation, Telecommunication, and Petroleum and Natural Gas industries. Consistent with our hypotheses, we find that information asymmetry decreases following SOX and that there is a corresponding decrease in the investment-cash flow sensitivity, pre-to post-SOX. Further, greater decreases in information asymmetry following SOX are associated with greater decreases in investment-cash flow sensitivity. The results for the deregulation sample are also consistent with our hypothesis, wherein we observe an increase in information asymmetry and corresponding increase in the investment-cash flow sensitivity following deregulation. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chowdhury, Jaideep; Kumar, Raman; Shome, Dilip</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does the market variance risk premium vary over time? Evidence from S&amp;P 500 variance swap investment returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Konstantinidi, Eirini; Skiadopoulos, George
We explore whether the market variance risk premium (VRP) can be predicted. We measure VRP by distinguishing the investment horizon from the variance swap's maturity. We extract VRP from actual S&amp;P 500 variance swap quotes and we test four classes of predictive models. We find that the best performing model is the one that conditions on trading activity. This relation is also economically significant. Volatility trading strategies which condition on trading activity outperform popular benchmark strategies, even once we consider transaction costs. Our finding implies that broker dealers command a greater VRP to continue holding short positions in index options in the case where trading conditions deteriorate. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Konstantinidi, Eirini; Skiadopoulos, George</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity trading and the allocation of market data revenue</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caglio, Cecilia; Mayhew, Stewart
Revenues generated from the sales of consolidated data represent a substantial source of income for U.S. stock exchanges. Until 2007, consolidated data revenue allocated in proportion to the number of reported trades. This allocation rule encouraged market participants to break up large trades and execute them in multiple pieces. Exchanges devised revenue-sharing and rebate programs that rewarded order-flow providers, and encouraged algorithmic traders to execute strategies involving large numbers of small trades. We provide evidence that data revenue allocation influenced the trading process, by examining trading activity surrounding various events that changed the marginal data revenue per trade. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Caglio, Cecilia; Mayhew, Stewart</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and hedging American and hybrid strangles with finite maturity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abdou, Souleymane Laminou; Moraux, Franck
This paper introduces variants of strangles, called Euro-American or hybrid strangles, and it promotes a new numerical pricing technique. We highlight and compare the properties of European, American, and hybrid strangles with pricing and hedging in mind. The new quadrature approach we propose can account for systems of coupled integral equations that locate the early exercise boundaries of finite-lived contracts. We show that this method is efficient, accurate, and fast for pricing all types of early exercisable strangles. Other advantages of this technique are that it avoids the non-monotonic gradient problem faced by others and it allows users to control for errors. We then investigate the hedging of all strangles, we derive analytical expressions for some Greek parameters, and we stress how these parameters can differ (or not) from each other. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abdou, Souleymane Laminou; Moraux, Franck</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of euro area sovereign CDS and their relation with government bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fontana, Alessandro; Scheicher, Martin
We compare the market pricing of euro area government bonds and the corresponding Credit Default Swaps (CDSs). In particular, we analyse the "basis" defined as the difference between the premium on the CDS and the credit spread on the underlying bond. Our sample of weekly data covers the period from January 2007 to December 2012 and contains several episodes of sovereign market distress. Overall, we observe a complex relationship between the derivatives market and the underlying cash market characterised by sizable deviations from the no-arbitrage relationship (i.e. basis equal to zero). We show that short-selling frictions explain the persistence of positive basis deviations while funding frictions explain the persistence of negative basis deviations which are observed for countries with weak public finances. Moreover, we show that the "flight-to-quality/liquidity" phenomenon in bond markets is a key driver of the large positive basis of better rated countries. (C) 2015 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. This is an open access article under the CC BY license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</description><author>Fontana, Alessandro; Scheicher, Martin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unexpected shortfalls of Expected Shortfall: Extreme default profiles and regulatory arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koch-Medina, Pablo; Munari, Cosimo
The purpose of this paper is to dispel some common misunderstandings about capital adequacy rules based on Expected Shortfall. We establish that, from a theoretical perspective, Expected Shortfall based regulation can provide a misleading assessment of tail behavior, does not necessarily protect liability holders' interests much better than Value-at-Risk based regulation, and may also allow for regulatory arbitrage when used as a global solvency measure. We also show that, for a value-maximizing financial institution, the benefits derived from protecting its franchise may not be sufficient to disincentivize excessive risk taking. We further interpret our results in the context of portfolio risk measurement. Our results do not invalidate the possible merits of Expected Shortfall as a risk measure but instead highlight the need for its cautious use in the context of capital adequacy regimes and of portfolio risk control. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koch-Medina, Pablo; Munari, Cosimo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fragility, stress, and market returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Dave; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara
We propose a novel risk measure that relates to subsequent negative conditional stock market returns. Our risk measure considers both the fragility and stress of the market. Fragility is measured by the Fragility Index developed by Berger and Pukthuanthong (2012) and market stress is based on several economic variables. Results show that incorporating both market stress and fragility improves the information content of a risk measure. Our risk measure relates to poor subsequent monthly market returns. We show the risk measure contains predictive information in a purely ex-ante specification. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Dave; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shadow economies at times of banking crises: Empirics and theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colombo, Emilio; Onnis, Luisanna; Tirelli, Patrizio
This paper investigates the response of the shadow economy to banking crises. Our empirical analysis, based on a large sample of countries, suggests that the informal sector is a powerful buffer, which expands at times of banking crises and absorbs a large proportion of the fall in official output. To rationalise our evidence, we build a dynamic stochastic general equilibrium model which accounts for financial and labour market frictions and for nominal rigidities. In line with the empirical literature on the shadow economy, we assume that in the informal sector access to external finance is limited, and the production technology is relatively more labour intensive. Following a banking shock in the official sector, the model predicts a large negative transmission to the unofficial economy that substantially dampens the overall effect of the shock. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Colombo, Emilio; Onnis, Luisanna; Tirelli, Patrizio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic shocks, forward-looking dynamics, and the behavior of hedge funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Racicot, Francois-Eric; Theoret, Raymond
We investigate how hedge funds' strategies react, as a group, to macroeconomic risk and uncertainty. Adopting the methodology of Beaudry et al. (2001), we track the behavior of the cross-sectional dispersions of hedge fund strategies' returns, market betas and alphas over the business cycle. The pattern of strategies' betas supports Beaudry et al.'s conjecture: hedge funds reduce their risk-taking (betas) during times of macroeconomic uncertainty, which makes their strategies more homogeneous and thus contributes to increased systemic risk in the financial system. However, the cyclical behavior of the cross-sectional dispersions of strategies' returns and strategies' alphas is not in line with Beaudry et al.'s conjecture. These dispersions tend to increase during episodes of rising macroeconomic uncertainty, which suggests the prevalence of the Black's (1976) leverage effect during financial turmoil and the fact that the exposure of hedge fund strategies to risk factors is quite different from each other. Finally, although remaining important, procyclicality seems to have declined through time in the hedge fund industry, which suggests that a learning process is at play. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Racicot, Francois-Eric; Theoret, Raymond</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downside and upside risk spillovers between exchange rates and stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reboredo, Juan C.; Rivera-Castro, Miguel A.; Ugolini, Andrea
We examined downside and upside risk spillovers from exchange rates to stock prices and vice versa for a set of emerging economies. We characterized the dependence structure between currency and stock returns using copulas and computed downside and upside value-at-risk and conditional value-at-risk. We documented a positive relationship between stock prices and currency values in emerging economies with respect to the US dollar and the euro, with downside and upside spillover risk effects transmitted both ways. Finally, we also documented asymmetries in upside and downside risk spillovers and asymmetric differences in the size of risk spillovers when the domestic currency values against the US dollar and the euro. Our results, consistent with flight-to-quality phenomena, have implications for downside and upside risk management of international investor portfolios in emerging markets. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Reboredo, Juan C.; Rivera-Castro, Miguel A.; Ugolini, Andrea</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flight-to-quality and correlation between currency and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cho, Jin-Wan; Choi, Joung Hwa; Kim, Taeyong; Kim, Woojin
We document that capital flows in and out of emerging or developed markets are sensitive to global equity market conditions. Capital tends to move out of emerging into developed countries in global down markets, leading to depreciation (appreciation) of emerging (developed) currencies. This generates a positive (negative) correlation between currency and equity in emerging (developed) markets which is amplified by the magnitude of the capital movement. We also verify that hedging currency risks may undo the natural hedge and increase the total return volatility under negative correlation. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cho, Jin-Wan; Choi, Joung Hwa; Kim, Taeyong; Kim, Woojin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A test of efficiency for the S&amp;P 500 index option market using the generalized spectrum method</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Henry H.; Wang, Kent; Wang, Zhanglong
This paper examines the efficiency of the S&amp;P 500 options market by testing the martingale properties of the Model-Free Forward Variance (MFFV) time series using the Generalized Spectral Test (GST). Based on a sample from January 1, 1996 to May 31, 2010, our tests show robust evidence that the S&amp;P 500 options market is not efficient. By examining the subsamples before and after the 2008 financial crisis, we find this options market inefficiency is mainly driven by the outbreak of the subprime crisis. Our diagnostic tests further indicate that this inefficiency is due to the skewness-in-mean effect of forward variance. Specifically, the skewness-in-mean effect is weakened once we account for the S&amp;P 500 index jump effects. Hence, we can establish a link between jumps and options market inefficiency. Finally, we find that the lagged skewness of the forward variance can help forecasting the forward variance both in sample and out-of-sample. The economic significance of this forecasting ability is further highlighted by the performance of a trading strategy based on forward variance. In sum, out study provides robust evidence and a trading implication on testing the S&amp;P 500 options market efficiency. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Henry H.; Wang, Kent; Wang, Zhanglong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm geographic dispersion and financial analysts' forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Platikanova, Petya; Mattei, Marco Maria
Using a text-based measure of geographic dispersion that captures the economic ties between a firm and its geographically distributed economic interests, this study provides evidence that financial analysts issue less accurate, more dispersed and more biased earnings forecasts for geographically dispersed firms. We observe the degree to which a firm has an overlapping distribution of economic centers in comparison to industry competitors and suggest that geographically similar firms have lower information gathering costs and thereby more precise earnings forecasts. Empirical evidence supports this prediction. We further find that the geographic dispersion across the U.S. is less likely to affect forecast precision when a firm has economic activities in states with highly correlated local shocks. Our findings suggest that the effect of geographic dispersion is more pronounced for soft-information environments where information is more difficult to make impersonal by using technological advances. Consistent with the information asymmetry argument, we find that geographically dispersed firms have less comparable and more discretionary managed earnings, have less extensive than industry competitors segment information, are more likely to restate sale segment information, and issue annual and quarterly filings with a delay. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Platikanova, Petya; Mattei, Marco Maria</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relation between sovereign credit rating revisions and economic growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chen, Hsien-Yi; Chang, Chong-Chuo; Yang, Shu-Ling
A country's economic growth exhibits a significant response to sovereign rating changes: a one-notch upgrade (downgrade) causes an increase (decline) of about 0.6% (0.3%) in re-rated countries' five-year average annual growth rates. The results hold after accounting for other determinants of economic growth and potential endogeneity problems, and are robust to the use of quarterly data. Changes in country rating affect economic growth via the interest-rate and capital-flow channels: narrower sovereign bond yield spreads and increased capital inflows are associated with upgrades, which stimulate re rated countries' economic performance, and the converse holds for downgrades. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chen, Hsien-Yi; Chang, Chong-Chuo; Yang, Shu-Ling</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An efficient and functional model for predicting bank distress: In and out of sample evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cleary, Sean; Hebb, Greg
We examine the failures of 132 U.S. banks over the 2002-2009 period using discriminant analysis and successfully distinguish between banks that failed and those that didn't 92% of the time using in-sample quarterly data. Our two most important variables are related to bank capital and loan quality, as one might expect; although bank profitability is also important. The resulting model is then used out-of-sample to examine the failure of 191 banks during 2010-11, with predictive accuracy in the 90-95% range. Our results demonstrate that our model can also easily be applied to a large number of firms (even those that don't fail) and does an excellent job of distinguishing healthy from distressed banks. Combining this effectiveness with its ease of implementation makes it very functional. Such a model should be of obvious interest to regulators, analysts, and all those with a direct interest in assessing bank financial health. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cleary, Sean; Hebb, Greg</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting distress in European SME portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Filipe, Sara Ferreira; Grammatikos, Theoharry; Michala, Dimitra
In this paper, we examine idiosyncratic and systematic distress predictors for small and medium sized enterprises (SMEs) in Europe over the period 2000-2009. We find that SMEs across European regions are vulnerable to common idiosyncratic factors but systematic factors vary. Moreover, systematic factors move average distress rates and small SMEs are more vulnerable to these factors compared to large SMEs. By including many very small companies in the sample, our models offer unique insights into the European small business sector. By exploring distress in a multi-country setting, the models uncover regional vulnerabilities. Finally, by incorporating systematic dependencies, the models capture distress co-movements. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Filipe, Sara Ferreira; Grammatikos, Theoharry; Michala, Dimitra</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Description-text related soft information in peer-to-peer lending - Evidence from two leading European platforms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dorfleitner, Gregor; Priberny, Christopher; Schuster, Stephanie; Stoiber, Johannes; Weber, Martina; de Castro, Ivan; Kammler, Julia
We examine the relation of soft factors that are derived from the description texts to the probability of successful funding and to the default probability in peer-to-peer lending for two leading European platforms. We find that spelling errors, text length and the mentioning of positive emotion evoking keywords predict the funding probability on the less restrictive of both platforms, which even accepts applications without credit scores. This platform also shows a better risk-return profile. Conditional on being funded, text-related factors hardly predict default probabilities in peer-to-peer lending for both platforms. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dorfleitner, Gregor; Priberny, Christopher; Schuster, Stephanie; Stoiber, Johannes; Weber, Martina; de Castro, Ivan; Kammler, Julia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the information content of short-selling metrics using daily disclosures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Do, Binh Huu; Gray, Philip; Manton, Tom
As a consequence of the 2008 financial crisis, the Australian regulator mandated daily reporting and disclosure of both short flow and short interest at an individual stock level. This provides a unique opportunity to study the nature and source of information embedded in each metric. Our empirical findings are consistent with short sellers being heterogeneous with respect to their information. Short flow is strongly related to recent returns and buy-order imbalance, and both anticipates and reacts to price relevant announcements. In contrast, short interest is related to the mispricing of firm fundamentals. The distinct differences in the nature of information embedded in the two metrics provide an economic rationale for both the unique ability of each metric to predict returns and the future horizons over which the information is relevant. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Do, Binh Huu; Gray, Philip; Manton, Tom</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do hedge funds dynamically manage systematic risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Namvar, Ethan; Phillips, Blake; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Rau, P. Raghavendra
Defining systematic risk management (SRM) skill as persistently low fund systematic risk, we find evidence of time varying allocation of hedge fund management effort across the business cycle. In weak market states, skilled managers focus on minimization of systematic risk via dynamic reallocations across asset classes at the cost of fund alpha and foregoing market timing opportunities. As markets strengthen, attention shifts to asset selection within consistent asset classes. The superior performance of low systematic risk funds previously documented arises due to the superior asset selection ability of managers in strong market states. Incremental allocations by investors arise due to this superior performance and not due to recognition of SRM skill. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Namvar, Ethan; Phillips, Blake; Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Rau, P. Raghavendra</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The white squire defense: Evidence from private investments in public equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Hsu, Ching-Yu; Huang, Chia-Wei
Firms can effectively stave off outside takeover bids using private investments in public equity (PIPEs) when they face strong takeover pressure. Greater takeover pressure makes PIPE issuers more likely to grant investors large blocks of shares, price discounts, generous dividends, and board seats. Takeover pressure also encourages issuers to place more shares with friendly investors such as managerial investors and strategic alliance investors. The evidence is consistent with the regular methods of the white squire defense. PIPEs can be a preferred method in the choice of a white squire defense when poorly performing and highly overleveraged firms face severe takeover pressure. There is a negative relation between takeover probability and post-issue performance of issuers, which supports the managerial entrenchment hypothesis over the shareholder interest hypothesis. Therefore PIPEs can increase, not mitigate, agency problems. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Sheng-Syan; Hsu, Ching-Yu; Huang, Chia-Wei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do outside directors influence the financial performance of risk-trading firms? Evidence from the United Kingdom (UK) insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Mike; Jiang, Wei
We examine the relation between outside board directors and six measures of financial performance using panel data for 1999-2012 drawn from the UK's property-casualty insurance industry. We find that the proportion of outsiders on the board is unrelated to performance; rather it is outsiders' financial expertise that has the most significant financial performance impact. In addition, superior performance can also be related to the financial expertise of inside directors, thereby reinforcing the importance of board-level financial expertise in the insurance industry. Our results have potential commercial and/or policy implications. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, Mike; Jiang, Wei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting realized volatility in a changing world: A dynamic model averaging approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Yudong; Ma, Feng; Wei, Yu; Wu, Chongfeng
In this study, we forecast the realized volatility of the S&amp;P 500 index using the heterogeneous autoregressive model for realized volatility (HAR-RV) and its various extensions. Our models take into account the time-varying property of the models' parameters and the volatility of realized volatility. A dynamic model averaging (DMA) approach is used to combine the forecasts of the individual models. Our empirical results suggest that DMA can generate more accurate forecasts than individual model in both statistical and economic senses. Models that use time-varying parameters have greater forecasting accuracy than models that use the constant coefficients. The superiority of time-varying parameter models is also found in volatility density forecasting. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Yudong; Ma, Feng; Wei, Yu; Wu, Chongfeng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supply-chain spillover effects of IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kutsuna, Kenji; Smith, Janet Kiholm; Smith, Richard; Yamada, Kazuo
We use the IPOs of supply-chain partners as precipitating events and test for positive spillovers on private firms (the "IPO spillover hypothesis"). A trading partner's IPO may benefit its suppliers through increased demand and its customers by reducing an input-related growth constraint. A newly public firm may also transmit additional liquidity to trading partners through trade credit practices. Using Japanese data on important relationships between IPO firms and their private suppliers and customers, we find that suppliers and customers experience significantly higher rates of growth in revenue, cash balances, and PP&amp;E than do other private firms. The paper appears to be the first to document real and financial effects of positive liquidity shocks on supply-chain partners. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kutsuna, Kenji; Smith, Janet Kiholm; Smith, Richard; Yamada, Kazuo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Religion and bank loan terms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Wen; Hu, Maggie
We examine whether religion affects the terms of bank loans. We hypothesize that lenders value the traits of religious adherents, such as risk aversion, ethical behavior and honesty, and thus offer favorable loan terms to religious borrowers. Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that corporate borrowers located in counties with a high level of religiosity are charged lower interest rates, have larger loan amounts and fewer loan covenants. These results suggest that the corporate culture of borrowers influences the availability and cost of bank loans. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Wen; Hu, Maggie</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The influence of FOMC member characteristics on the monetary policy decision-making process</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smales, Lee A.; Apergis, Nick
This paper provides new empirical evidence on a monetary policy committee with heterogeneous members whose decisions affect the efficacy of monetary policy. It thereby provides a link between the literature on monetary policy committees and central bank monetary policy implementation through monetary rules. Using a novel dataset of the idiosyncratic characteristics of FOMC members, over the period from August 1979 to February 2014, the empirical findings show that characteristics such as education, age, and, to a lesser extent, work experience are not important in understanding the FOMC decision-making process. Instead, the results point to the importance of time spent within the Federal Reserve System, tenure on the FOMC itself, and the influence of the Chair in shaping the decision making process. The results are expected to have implications for the capacity of economic agents, as well as various markets in the economy, to more readily interpret public (monetary policy) information that reaches them. This makes the monetary policy decision process less noisy and thus enhances the capability of agents and markets to attach the correct weight to this information. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Smales, Lee A.; Apergis, Nick</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank business models, regulation, and the role of financial market participants in the global financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clare, Andrew; Duygun, Meryem; Gulamhussen, Mohamed Azzim; Pozzolo, Alberto Franco
nan</description><author>Clare, Andrew; Duygun, Meryem; Gulamhussen, Mohamed Azzim; Pozzolo, Alberto Franco</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives cross-border M&amp;As in commercial banking?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gulamhussen, Mohamed Azzim; Hennart, Jean-Francois; Pinheiro, Carlos Manuel
Using a gravity model, we analyze the determinants of the probability that commercial banks in 89 acquiring countries and 118 target countries will undertake M&amp;As over a 30-year period (1981-2010) and of the value of these M&amp;As. We find that the value of cross-border M&amp;As increases with the size of the acquiring country, and that both the probability and value of M&amp;As vary positively with the depth of the financial market in acquirer countries and the presence of corporate and non-corporate customers from acquiring countries in target countries, and negatively with the geographic, psychic, and time zone distances between acquirer and target countries. Our study highlights the role of non-corporate customers and of psychic distance in the cross-border expansion of commercial banks through M&amp;As. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gulamhussen, Mohamed Azzim; Hennart, Jean-Francois; Pinheiro, Carlos Manuel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum and downside risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Min, Byoung-Kyu; Kim, Tong Suk
We examine whether time-variation in the profitability of momentum strategies is related to variation in macroeconomic conditions. We find reliable evidence that the momentum strategy exposes investors to greater downside risk. Momentum strategies deliver economically large and statistically reliable negative profits in bad economic states when the expected market risk premium is high, whereas positive profits in good economic states when the expected market risk premium is low. Our results are robust to alternative constructions of momentum portfolios, out-of-sample estimation of the expected market risk premium, and after controlling for the January effect, lagged market return, and investor sentiment. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Min, Byoung-Kyu; Kim, Tong Suk</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active risk management and banking stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Silva Buston, Consuelo
This paper analyzes the net impact of two opposing effects of active risk management at banks on their stability: higher risk-taking incentives and better isolation of credit supply from varying economic conditions. We present a model where banks actively manage their portfolio risk by buying and selling credit protection. We show that anticipation of future risk management opportunities allows banks to operate with riskier balance sheets. However, since they are better insulated from shocks than banks without active risk management, they are less prone to insolvency. Empirical evidence from US bank holding companies broadly supports the theoretical predictions. In particular, we find that active risk management banks were less likely to become insolvent during the crisis of 2007-2009, even though their balance sheets displayed higher risk-taldng. These results provide an important message for bank regulation, which has mainly focused on balance-sheet risks when assessing financial stability. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Silva Buston, Consuelo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodities momentum: A behavioral perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bianchi, Robert J.; Drew, Michael E.; Fan, John Hua
The growth in commodity-related investments has sparked interest in the performance of momentum strategies in these markets. This paper introduces a behavioral proxy of the 52-week high and low momentum that explains a significant proportion of the variation of conventional momentum returns after controlling for commodity specific risk factors. Our findings show that the 52-week high strategy generates significant profits after accounting for transaction costs. We report that the 52-week high strategy is a better predictor of returns than conventional momentum. Our findings suggest that term structure and hedging pressure risk factors provide only a partial explanation of the results. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bianchi, Robert J.; Drew, Michael E.; Fan, John Hua</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managers set the tone: Equity incentives and the tone of earnings press releases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arslan-Ayaydin, Ozgur; Boudt, Kris; Thewissen, James
Earnings press releases, as a timely vehicle for communicating a firm's performance to third parties, can be used by managers to influence the perception of the firm's achievements. Taking the stock price reaction to the tone of earnings press releases at earnings announcements into account, we argue that equity based incentives induce managers to inflate the tone. We further posit that the impact of tone on the abnormal stock returns at the earnings announcements depends on the magnitude of the equity-based incentives. Based on over 26,000 earnings press releases of S&amp;P1500 firms between 2004Q4 and 2012Q4, we find that the tone of earnings press releases tends to be more positive when the managerial portfolio value is more closely tied to the firm's stock price. We also find that investors react proportionally less to the tone as managers' equity incentives increase. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arslan-Ayaydin, Ozgur; Boudt, Kris; Thewissen, James</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating corporate bonds and analyzing claim holders' decisions with complex debt structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Liang-Chih; Dai, Tian-Shyr; Wang, Chuan-Ju
Although many different aspects of debt structures such as bond covenants and repayment schedules are empirically found to significantly influence values of bonds and equity, many theoretical structural models still oversimplify debt structures and fail to capture phenomena found in financial markets. This paper proposes a carefully designed structural model that faithfully models typical complex debt structures containing multiple bonds with various covenants. For example, the ability for an issuing firm to meet an obligation is modeled to rely on its ability to meet previous repayments, and the default trigger is shaped according to the characteristics of its debt structure such as the amount and schedule of bond repayments. Thus our framework reliably provides theoretical insight and concrete quantitative measurements consistent with extant empirical research such as the shapes of yield spread curves under various firm's financial statuses, and the impact of payment blockage covenants on newly-issued and other outstanding bonds. We also develop the forest, a novel quantitative method to handle contingent changes in the debt structure due to premature bond redemptions. A forest consists of several trees that capture different debt structures, for instance those before or after a bond redemption. This method can be used to analyze how poison put covenants in the target firm's bonds influence the bidder's costs of debt financing for a leveraged buyout, or investigate how the presence of wealth transfer among the remaining claim holders due to a bond redemption influences the firm's call policy, or further reconcile conflicts among previous empirical studies on call delay phenomena. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Liang-Chih; Dai, Tian-Shyr; Wang, Chuan-Ju</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exposure to intimate partner violence and repayment of microcredit: Evidence from field experiments in Bangladesh</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shahriar, Abu Zafar M.
This paper investigates the impact of intimate partner violence on poor women's repayment behavior in microcredit. In a laboratory-based field experiment, we extended collateral-free small loans to 485 currently married women in rural Bangladesh and observed their repayment decisions over multiple loan cycles. In a post-experiment survey, we asked subjects about their experience of spousal violence. We find that women who experienced physical or sexual violence in the last 12 months are more likely to strategically default on their loans relative to those who did not experience such violence. We conducted several robustness tests, and the results suggest that the negative correlation between victimization and loan repayment rates is unlikely to be explained by selection into victimization, non-random underreporting of violence, or the subjects' attitude toward risk. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shahriar, Abu Zafar M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Some defaults are deeper than others: Understanding long-term mortgage arrears</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, Robert; McCann, Fergal
The 2007-2008 financial crisis yielded a significant number of delinquent mortgage loans, which ordinarily would have faced foreclosure and repossession. However, given the negative externalities of repossession, policy response has shifted towards forbearance and mortgage modification, which has led to longer spells in default for delinquent mortgage holders. It is therefore imperative to move beyond binary models of default towards an understanding of the factors that drive the depth of default spells. Exploiting a highly detailed dataset on financially distressed households in Ireland in 2012 and 2013, we are able to identify the impact of a range of current household-level factors, generally not available in loan-level studies of mortgage default, on the probability of entering early and deep states of mortgage default. Our results suggest that high loan-to-value ratios, consumer credit growth, shocks to mortgage affordability and unemployment should all trigger serious concerns among policy makers regarding subsequent stability in the mortgage market, with these measures all shown to have differentially large impacts on entry to deep, relative to early-stage arrears. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kelly, Robert; McCann, Fergal</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial innovation: The bright and the dark sides</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Chen, Tao; Lin, Chen; Song, Frank M.
Based on data from 32 countries over the period 1996-2010, this paper is the first to assess the relationship between financial innovation, on the one hand, and bank growth and fragility, as well as economic growth, on the other hand. We find that different measures of financial innovation, capturing both a broad concept and specific innovations, are associated with faster bank growth, but also higher bank fragility and worse bank performance during the recent crisis. These effects are stronger in countries with larger securities markets and more restrictive regulatory frameworks. In spite of these seemingly ambiguous findings, our evidence points to a positive net effect of financial innovation on economic growth: financial innovation is associated with higher growth in countries and industries with better growth opportunities. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Chen, Tao; Lin, Chen; Song, Frank M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxing banks: An evaluation of the German bank levy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buch, Claudia M.; Hilberg, Bjoern; Tonzer, Lena
Bank distress can have severe negative consequences for the stability of the financial system. Regimes for the restructuring and resolution of banks, financed by bank levies, aim at reducing these costs. This paper evaluates the German bank levy, which has been implemented since 2011. Our analysis offers three main insights. First, revenues raised through the levy were lower than expected. Second, the bulk of the payments were contributed by large commercial banks and by the central institutions of savings banks and credit unions. Third, for those banks, which were affected by the levy, we find evidence for a reduction in lending and higher deposit rates. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buch, Claudia M.; Hilberg, Bjoern; Tonzer, Lena</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit constraints and the international propagation of US financial shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Metiu, Norbert; Hilberg, Bjoern; Grill, Michael
This paper investigates whether credit constraints in the US economy amplify the international propagation of US financial shocks. We model the dynamics of the US economy jointly with global macroeconomic and financial variables using a threshold vector autoregression. This model captures regime-specific dynamics conditional on the severity of credit constraints in the US economy. We identify three main episodes of tight credit in US financial history over the past thirty years. These occur in the late-1980s, in the early 2000s, and during the 2007-09 financial crisis. We find that US financial shocks are associated with a significant contraction in global economic activity in times of tight credit. By contrast, there is little impact of US financial shocks on the global economy in normal times. This asymmetry highlights an international dimension of the US financial accelerator mechanism. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Metiu, Norbert; Hilberg, Bjoern; Grill, Michael</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation uncertainty, market sentiment and the informativeness of institutional trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Lisa; Goh, Jeremy; Chiyachantana, Chiraphol
Prior studies indicate that institutional investors are informed, in the sense that their trades predict price changes. In this study we show that return predictive ability of institutions arises (after controlling for size, book-to-market, and momentum) mainly from institutional sales of hard-to-value stocks during periods of positive market sentiment. These results support the notion that these stocks tend to be overvalued during periods of bullish market sentiment, and institutions contribute to market efficiency by identifying and trading on these overpriced stocks. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yang, Lisa; Goh, Jeremy; Chiyachantana, Chiraphol</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credible reforms and stock return volatility: Evidence from privatization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cosset, Jean-Claude; Some, Hyacinthe Y.; Valery, Pascale
In this paper we investigate how privatization affects stock return volatility. A credible privatization builds investors' confidence through a reduction in political risk. In particular, a privatization program that is maintained over time signals credibility, which reduces political risk and in turn volatility. We further show that privatization is associated with lower idiosyncratic volatility mainly among developed markets, while it is associated with lower systematic volatility in developing markets. Additional tests suggest that the reduction in volatility is greater when privatization sales are carried out through the stock market than through asset sales. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cosset, Jean-Claude; Some, Hyacinthe Y.; Valery, Pascale</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating Value-at-Risk forecasts: A new set of multivariate backtests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wied, Dominik; Weiss, Gregor N. F.; Ziggel, Daniel
We propose two new tests for detecting clustering in multivariate Value-at-Risk (VaR) forecasts. First, we consider CUSUM-tests to detect non-constant expectations in the matrix of VaR-violations. Second, we propose chi(2)-tests for detecting cross-sectional and serial dependence in the VaR-forecasts. Moreover, we combine our new backtests with a test of unconditional coverage to yield two new back tests of multivariate conditional coverage. Results from a simulation study underline the usefulness of our new backtests for controlling portfolio risks across a bank's business lines. In an empirical study, we show how our multivariate backtests can be employed by regulators to backtest a banking system. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wied, Dominik; Weiss, Gregor N. F.; Ziggel, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ireland's 2010 EU/IMF intervention: Costs and benefits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Bekkum, Sjoerd
This paper examines the costs and benefits of the EU/IMF rescue package for Ireland, on November 29, 2010. We analyze the costs of the intervention and the subsequent increase in value of debt and/or equity issued by Irish banks, the Irish government, and European banks with substantial holdings of Irish debt. The total initial value increase around the announcement amounts to epsilon 5.59bln at a realized taxpayers' cost of epsilon 4.23bln. While the value increase depends on somewhat generous assumptions, it further increases by epsilon 2.8bln up to Ireland's exit in December 2013. About epsilon 3.1bln of the value created indirectly supports the European banking sector, indicating that substantial benefits arise from systemic risk containment. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>van Bekkum, Sjoerd</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Customer concentration and corporate tax avoidance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Henry He; Lobo, Gerald J.; Wang, Chong; Xie, Hong
Firms with a concentrated corporate customer base need to hold more cash and have a stronger incentive to manage earnings upwards. Since tax planning can increase both cash flow and accounting earnings, firms with a concentrated customer base may be more likely to engage in tax avoidance. We find evidence of a positive association between the level of corporate customer concentration and the extent of tax avoidance. In addition, we find that the positive relation between corporate customer concentration and tax avoidance is more pronounced when a firm has a lower Market Share in its industry, enjoys less revenue diversification, and engages less in real earnings management. In contrast to corporate major customers, governmental major customers provide stable cash flow to suppliers, which is likely to alleviate supplier firms' need for tax avoidance. We find that firms engage in lower levels of tax avoidance when they have a governmental major customer, and that this association is less pronounced under Democratic presidencies. Taken together, our findings indicate that a firm's customer concentration (i.e., corporate and governmental major customers) has a significant effect on the extent to which it avoids taxes. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Henry He; Lobo, Gerald J.; Wang, Chong; Xie, Hong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage risks, debt literacy and financial advice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Ooijen, Raun; van Rooij, Maarten C. J.
A limited understanding of mortgage contracts and the risks involved may have contributed to the outbreak of the 2007-2008 financial crisis. We developed a special questionnaire relating mortgage loan decisions to financial knowledge and financial advice. Our results demonstrate that homeowners appear to be well aware of mortgage risks. Large loans relative to home value are perceived as riskier, as are loans with large mortgage payments relative to income and loans linked to investment vehicles. Homeowners with riskier mortgages indicated that they could encounter financial problems should house prices or their income decline. Homeowners with relatively low debt literacy are more likely to take out traditional mortgages with principal repayments over the maturity of the loan. Riskier mortgages are more prevalent among homeowners with a better understanding of loan contracts. Financially less sophisticated homeowners consulting mortgage brokers, too, hold riskier mortgages. 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>van Ooijen, Raun; van Rooij, Maarten C. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and risk management in the credit card industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butaru, Florentin; Chen, Qingqing; Clark, Brian; Das, Sanmay; Lo, Andrew W.; Siddique, Akhtar
Using account-level credit card data from six major commercial banks from January 2009 to December 2013, we apply machine-learning techniques to combined consumer tradeline, credit bureau, and macroeconomic variables to predict delinquency. In addition to providing accurate measures of loss probabilities and credit risk, our models can also be used to analyze and compare risk management practices and the drivers of delinquency across banks. We find substantial heterogeneity in risk factors, sensitivities, and predictability of delinquency across banks, implying that no single model applies to all six institutions. We measure the efficacy of a bank's risk management process by the percentage of delinquent accounts that a bank manages effectively, and find that efficacy also varies widely across institutions. These results suggest the need for a more customized approached to the supervision and regulation of financial institutions, in which capital ratios, loss reserves, and other parameters are specified individually for each institution according to its credit risk model exposures and forecasts. (C) 2016 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Butaru, Florentin; Chen, Qingqing; Clark, Brian; Das, Sanmay; Lo, Andrew W.; Siddique, Akhtar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash flow news, discount rate news, and momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Celiker, Umut; Kayacetin, Nuri Volkan; Kumar, Raman; Sonaer, Gokhan
We examine the effect of aggregate cash flow news and discount rate news on momentum returns. We find that momentum profits are higher following aggregate positive cash flow news, even in down markets or low sentiment periods. This finding expands on the evidence in Cooper et al. (2004) that momentum is significant only when past market returns are non-negative and in Antoniou et al. (2013) that momentum is weaker when sentiment is pessimistic. We find that the higher momentum profits during aggregate positive cash flow news periods are primarily driven by the losers continuing to underperform in subsequent periods. Our findings are consistent with the Hong and Stein (1999) model in the sense that gradual diffusion of contradictory news is accentuated when change in wealth is positive and relatively more permanent. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Celiker, Umut; Kayacetin, Nuri Volkan; Kumar, Raman; Sonaer, Gokhan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market makers' optimal price-setting policy for exchange-traded certificates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baller, Stefanie; Entrop, Oliver; McKenzie, Michael; Wilkens, Marco
This paper presents the first theoretical model of the profit maximizing price-setting policy for the issuers of exchange-traded retail certificates. Unlike previous theoretical microstructure models, the market considered is unique in that the market makers do not face significant inventory costs or risk from informed traders. The model derives the time structure of the optimal markups over a certificate's fair theoretical value and its relationship with optimal spreads, unhedgeable risk faced by the issuer and investors' buying and selling decisions. It shows that (i) the optimal markups decrease inter-temporally, (ii) issuers adjust the markups according to investors' demand, (iii) unhedgeable risk results in higher markups and influences their time structure, (iv) the markups and the spread are negatively related. Using data from the German market for leverage certificates, we find strong empirical support for the model derived hypotheses, except for (iv). We find spreads exhibit little variation and this suggests that mark ups and spreads are not substitute profit sources for issuers in this market. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baller, Stefanie; Entrop, Oliver; McKenzie, Michael; Wilkens, Marco</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Excess value and restructurings by diversified firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hovakimian, Gayane
We examine whether restructuring decisions by diversified firms are related to their excess values. We find that changes in diversification level, measured as changes in the number of segments or number of industries, are positively and significantly associated with excess values. Further, at lower levels of excess values, firms are significantly more likely to increase focus than maintain their existing levels of diversification and, at higher levels of excess values, they are significantly more likely to diversify further than maintain or reduce their current levels of diversification. These findings indicate that excess value variations are meaningful and predict restructuring decisions. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hovakimian, Gayane</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Voluntary monthly earnings disclosures and analyst behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsao, Shou-Min; Lu, Hsueh-Tien; Keung, Edmund C.
We examine how voluntary monthly earnings disclosures relate to monthly analyst behavior. We focus on the number of analysts following a firm and several properties that characterize analysts' earnings forecasts for the upcoming annual earnings. We find firms that disclose monthly earnings attract more analysts, have more accurate and less dispersed analyst earnings forecasts, and have lower overall uncertainty and less commonality of information in analysts' earnings forecasts. In addition, the effect of monthly earnings disclosure on analyst behavior is more pronounced for the firms that regularly disclose monthly earnings. Our results are consistent with the notion that an important role played by a voluntary increase in reporting frequency is to trigger the generation of idiosyncratic information by financial analysts. In other words, analysts tend to complement rather than substitute for firm-provided voluntary disclosures. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tsao, Shou-Min; Lu, Hsueh-Tien; Keung, Edmund C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock returns and future tense language in 10-K reports</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karapandza, Rasa
This paper shows that firms talking less about the future in their annual reports generate positive abnormal returns of about 5% annually. I measure how much companies talk about the future in their annual 10-K reports by the frequency of the verbs will, shall, and going to. The evidence favors a risk-based interpretation: firms that use less future tense in their report offer higher returns since they are riskier. These results are consistent with finance theories stating that investors need to be rewarded for holding stocks of firms that put less information about the future in the marketplace. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Karapandza, Rasa</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reducing the impact of real estate foreclosures with Amortizing Participation Mortgages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wojakowski, Rafal M.; Ebrahim, M. Shahid; Shackleton, Mark B.
We employ Amortizing Participation Mortgage (APM) to offer a novel ex post tenegotiation method of a foreclosure. APM belongs to the family of home loan credit facilities advocated in the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act 2010. In our framework,, APMs reduce the endemic agency costs of debt by improving affordability. These benefits increase the demand for real estate in bust times and reduce fragility of the financial system thereby preventing foreclosures. We evaluate APMs in a stochastic control framework and provide solutions for an optimal amortization schedule. We generalize our approach to partially amortizing and commercial mortgages which encompass balloon payments. Finally, we provide concrete numerical examples of home loan modifications. We also offer detailed sensitivity analysis to market parameters such as house price volatility and interest rates. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wojakowski, Rafal M.; Ebrahim, M. Shahid; Shackleton, Mark B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited deposit insurance coverage and bank competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shy, Oz; Stenbacka, Rune; Yankov, Vladimir
Deposit insurance designs in many countries place a limit on the coverage of deposits in each bank. However, no limits are placed on the number of accounts held with different banks. Therefore, under limited deposit insurance, some consumers open accounts with different banks to achieve higher or full deposit insurance coverage. We compare three regimes of deposit insurance: no deposit insurance, unlimited deposit insurance, and limited deposit insurance. We show that limited deposit insurance weakens competition among banks and reduces total welfare relative to no or unlimited deposit insurance. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Shy, Oz; Stenbacka, Rune; Yankov, Vladimir</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do traders strategically time their pledges during real-world Walrasian auctions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eaves, James; Williams, Jeffrey; Power, Gabriel J.
Experimental research suggests the Walrasian tatonnement auction encourages traders to under-reveal preferences, even encouraging initial pledges contrary to true desires, because pledges are not binding. We analyze the timing and characteristics of individual pledges and trades during 9604 auctions for redbeans conducted by the Tokyo Grain Exchange. We find no evidence of contrarian pledging and little evidence of under-revelation - as many traders over-reveal as under-reveal. Most traders pledge seriously from the beginning. Despite the considerable heterogeneity in pledging behavior across individual traders, these differences appear to have no relationship with traders' profits, nor do they appear to affect the achievement of equilibrium. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Eaves, James; Williams, Jeffrey; Power, Gabriel J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pricing of different dimensions of liquidity: Evidence from government guaranteed bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Black, Jeffrey R.; Stock, Duane; Yadav, Pradeep K.
There are three important dimensions of liquidity: trading costs, depth, and resiliency. We investigate the relevance of each of these three dimensions of liquidity - separately and in conjunction - for the pricing of corporate bonds. Unlike previous studies, our sample allows us to cleanly separate the default and non-default components of yield spreads. We find that each of the above three dimensions of liquidity are priced factors. Overall, in our sample, a one standard deviation change in trading costs, resiliency, and depth measures lead to a change in non-default spreads of 5.00 basis points, 2.27 basis points, and 1.27 basis points, respectively. We also find that both bond-specific and market-wide dimensions of liquidity are priced in non-default spreads. Finally, we find that there does exist in some periods a small residual non-default yield spread that is consistent with an additional "flight-to-extreme-liquidity" premium reflecting investor preference for assets that enable quickest possible disengagement from the market when necessary. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Black, Jeffrey R.; Stock, Duane; Yadav, Pradeep K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US bank credit spreads during the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spencer, Peter
This paper argues that first passage time models are likely to better than affine hazard rate models in modelling stressed credit markets and confirms their superior performance in explaining the behavior of Credit Default Swap rates for the major US banking groups over the period of the financial crisis. Affine models find it hard to deal with periods of exceptionally high or low default risk given their assumption of a constant rate of mean reversion in the hazard rate. In contrast, first passage time models are specified in terms of the distance to default rather than the hazard rate. The persistence of shocks varies with the distance to default, allowing the default curve to invert sharply (compress) when the distance to default is low (high). I use an empirical version of the Collin-Dufresne et al. (2003) model, which contains a smoothing parameter that allows it to control the relative effect of these shocks on the short spreads and can be interpreted as an information lag. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Spencer, Peter</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivatives usage, securitization, and the crash sensitivity of bank stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trapp, Rouven; Weigss, Gregor N. F.
We show that the information on derivatives usage and securitization activities of U.S. banks as disclosed in their pre-crisis 10-K filings explains extreme equity returns of banks during the financial crisis. Stocks of banks that had previously disclosed a more extensive use of financial derivatives and loan securitization were more likely to experience extreme losses. Our findings are consistent with investors viewing banks that used derivatives for non-hedging purposes as highly vulnerable to the crisis. Moreover, banks which had significant securitization activities and were thus potentially exposed to under-capitalized risks from conduits possess a higher vulnerability of their equity to market downturns. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Trapp, Rouven; Weigss, Gregor N. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The predictive performance of commodity futures risk factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahmed, Shamim; Tsvetanov, Daniel
This paper investigates the time-series predictability of commodity futures excess returns from factor models that exploit two risk factors the equally weighted average excess return on long positions in a universe of futures contracts and the return difference between the high- and low-basis portfolios. Adopting a standard set of statistical evaluation metrics, we find weak evidence that the factor models provide out-of-sample forecasts of monthly excess returns significantly better than the benchmark of random walk with drift model. We also show, in a dynamic asset allocation environment, that the information contained in the commodity-based risk factors does not generate systematic economic value to risk-averse investors pursuing a commodity stand-alone strategy or a diversification strategy. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahmed, Shamim; Tsvetanov, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sensitivity to investor sentiment and stock performance of open market share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liang, Woan-lih
This paper finds that stocks of repurchasers with high sensitivity to investor sentiment are more likely to be mispriced. Thus, such repurchases are followed by superior post-buyback stock performance. This abnormal return associated with sensitivity to sentiment cannot be explained by other undervaluation factors: book-to-market or prior return effects. My results are robust with factor model analysis and controls for contamination effects. I conclude that this sentiment-driven undervaluation may result from the difficulty to value and/or limits to arbitrage rather than investor overreaction. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liang, Woan-lih</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State ownership, cross-border acquisition, and risk-taking: Evidence from China's banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Wenyu; Yang, Jiawen
Does state ownership breed risk-taking behavior in commercial banks? This paper examines this issue using a panel of Chinese banks. We find that state-ownership is in general associated with higher risks. In addition, we find that banks controlled by the central government have the highest credit risk, while those owned by local governments have the lowest capital adequacy ratio and liquidity ratio. By compiling a complete list of cross-border acquisitions in China's banking sector, we investigate the impact of foreign acquisition on state-owned banks' risk-taking using differences-in-differences and matching estimators. We find that foreign acquisition has a reducing effect on state-owned banks' risk-taking and this effect is particularly significant for banks that are controlled by central or local government. We also find that this risk-reducing effect depends on the percentage of foreign ownership, the local business involvement of the foreign investors, and the number of foreign members on the banks' boards of directors. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhu, Wenyu; Yang, Jiawen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product diversification and bank performance: Does ownership structure matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saghi-Zedek, Nadia
Using detailed data on control chains of 710 European commercial banks, we test whether the presence of some categories of controlling shareholders affects product diversification performance. We find that when banks have no controlling shareholder or have only family and state shareholders activity diversification yields diseconomies. However, as long as the control chain involves banking institutions, institutional investors, industrial companies or any other combination of these shareholder categories, banks benefit from diversification economies: they display higher profitability, lower earnings volatility and lower default risk. This is potentially because such categories of shareholders bring additional skills to manage diverse activities. A further exploration shows that such mitigating roles are greater for domestic and diversified shareholders. Our findings provide insights on why banks suffer from greater activity diversification and have several policy implications. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Saghi-Zedek, Nadia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bullish/bearish/neutral strategies under short sale restrictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, Kwangil; Kang, Jangkoo; Lee, Soonhee
This study investigates the effects of short sale restrictions by extending the model of Dridi and Germain (2004) and infers informed traders' strategies and the relation between order imbalance and price thereunder. The results are generally in line with the empirical evidence documented in the literature and are summarized as follows: First, seller-initiated trading incurs a greater price reaction. Second, short sale restrictions shift the skewness of asset returns. Third, the restrictions can stimulate investors to acquire information or increase each individual trader's order flow under the bullish and neutral signals as well as the bearish signal, which is yet to be explored empirically. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bae, Kwangil; Kang, Jangkoo; Lee, Soonhee</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading book and credit risk: How fundamental is the Basel review?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Laurent, Jean-Paul; Sestier, Michael; Thomas, Stephane
Within the new Basel regulatory framework for market risks, non-securitization credit positions in the trading book are subject to a separate default risk charge (formally incremental default risk charge). Banks using the internal model approach are required to use a two-factor model and a 99.9% VaR capital charge. This model prescription is intended to reduce risk-weighted asset variability, a known feature of internal models, and improve their comparability among financial institutions. In this paper, we analyze the theoretical foundations and relevance of these proposals. We investigate the practical implications of the two-factor and correlation calibration constraints through numerical applications. We introduce the Hoeffding decomposition of the aggregate unconditional loss to provide a systematic-idiosyncratic representation. In particular, we examine the impacts of a J-factor correlation structure on risk measures and risk factor contributions for long-only and long-short credit-sensitive portfolios. (C) 2016 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license.</description><author>Laurent, Jean-Paul; Sestier, Michael; Thomas, Stephane</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment-cash flow sensitivity and financial constraints: Evidence from unquoted European SMEs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mulier, Klaas; Schoors, Koen; Merlevede, Bruno
We contribute to the financial constraints literature and the investment-cash flow sensitivity debate by defining a new and simple index of firm level financial constraints for unquoted European SMEs. Firms that are constrained according to our index pay higher interest rates on their debt. An exogenous financial supply shock reveals that our index also captures financial constraints in terms of the volume of credit. Our index outperforms existing indices in capturing financial constraints of unquoted SMEs. Finally, employing our proposed index to identify financially constrained firms and using firm-level employment growth as a control for investment opportunities, we find that constrained firms display the highest investment-cash flow sensitivities. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mulier, Klaas; Schoors, Koen; Merlevede, Bruno</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of non-interest income on bank risk in Australia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williams, Barry
The relationship between bank revenue composition and bank risk in Australia is modeled using data drawn from Australian bank confidential regulatory returns. It is found that those banks with lower levels of non-interest income and higher revenue concentration are less risky, consistent with previous international evidence. Evidence is also found supportive of increased risk due to too-big-to-fail effects, with this risk increase being offset by a decline in large bank risk after the crisis of 2007-2008. Non-interest income is generally found to be risk increasing, but some types of non-interest income are risk reducing when bank specialization effects are considered. It is also found that the 2008 financial crisis changed some aspects of the relationship between bank risk and revenue composition. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Williams, Barry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment risk allocation and the venture capital exit market: Evidence from early stage investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaplinsky, Susan; Gupta-Mukherjee, Swasti
This study provides evidence on how venture capitalists' (VCs') allocations of capital to riskier investments, as measured by the proportion of early versus late-stage investment in an industry, are linked to exit market conditions. Prior research has primarily focused on how VCs adjust aggregate investment to public equity market conditions. We develop a more inclusive measure of exit market conditions that accounts for recent secular changes that have affected the industry return structure, specifically, the sharp rise in the number of failures and M&amp;A relative to IPO exits. We show that the dollars gained relative to dollars lost in recent exits and failures are significantly positively related to VCs' allocations to early-stage companies over the period 1990-2008. The changes in allocations are large enough to have an effect on the availability of funding for early stage companies. In sum, our evidence shows that exit market conditions have a significant and economically meaningful influence on VCs' allocations to riskier investments. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chaplinsky, Susan; Gupta-Mukherjee, Swasti</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign debt ratings and stock liquidity around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Kuan-Hui; Sapriza, Horacio; Wu, Yangru
This paper studies the impact of sovereign debt rating changes on liquidity for stocks from 40 countries for the period 1990-2009. We find that sovereign rating changes significantly affect stock liquidity. The impact is stronger for downgrades than for upgrades, and is nonlinear in event size. The loss of investment grade has a particularly strong negative impact on stock liquidity. We also find that some stock characteristics and country legal and macroeconomic environment are important in explaining the differences in the impact of sovereign credit rating changes on stock liquidity across countries. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Kuan-Hui; Sapriza, Horacio; Wu, Yangru</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Family control and corporate social responsibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Wang, He; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.
We investigate the impact of family control on corporate social responsibility (CSR) performance. Using newly collected data on the ultimate ownership structure of publicly traded firms in nine East Asian economies, we find that family-controlled firms exhibit lower CSR performance, consistent with the expropriation hypothesis of family control. The negative relationship between family control and CSR is robust to alternative measures of family control, different components of CSR, as well as to endogeneity tests, subsample tests, and alternative estimation methods. We further find that CSR underperformance concentrates in family firms with greater agency problems and in countries with weaker institutions. Moreover, the underperformance of East Asian family firms holds when controlling for the effects of other large shareholders and when comparing with family firms from other countries. These findings contribute to understanding the determinants of CSR and highlight the importance of corporate governance and the institutional environment in improving CSR performance of family-controlled firms. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Wang, He; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The policy impact of new rules for loan participation on credit union returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goenner, Cullen F.
In recent years, credit unions have increasingly purchased loan-participation agreements in order to diversify their loan portfolios and manage loan growth. Responding to high charge-off rates for these loans and concern for systemic risk, the National Credit Union Administration imposed in 2013 new rules on federally insured credit unions that limited the purchase of loan participations from a single originator to the greater of $5 million or 100% of net worth. This study uses a difference-in-difference framework to examine the effect the policy had on returns. As a result of the policy change, credit unions with a high share of net worth in loan participations earned, on average, a return on assets 47 basis points less than their counterparts. Further, we find evidence that suggests these lower returns were driven by a decline in participation loans with recourse provisions, liquidity issues, and relatively higher interest expenses. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Goenner, Cullen F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The sensitivity of VPIN to the choice of trade classification algorithm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poeppe, Thomas; Moos, Sebastian; Schiereck, Dirk
The VPIN metric (Easley et al. 2012b) aims to detect and predict the toxicity of order flow. This paper examines the sensitivity and robustness of VPIN to the choice of trade classification scheme, which is the major input used to compute VPIN. We compare deterministic trade-by-trade classification approaches with results computed using a newly proposed heuristic approach, bulk volume classification. We find substantial differences for all levels of aggregation: trade classification, order imbalance, VPIN and identifying "toxic periods". We also find that the detection of toxic periods does not yield consistent results in more than 60% of cases. But regression analysis can identify volume and return volatility as parameters that contribute to higher levels of sensitivity. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Poeppe, Thomas; Moos, Sebastian; Schiereck, Dirk</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock return predictability and investor sentiment: A high-frequency perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Licheng; Najand, Mohammad; Shen, Jiancheng
We explore the predictive relation between high-frequency investor sentiment and stock market returns. Our results are based on a proprietary dataset of high-frequency investor sentiment, which is computed based on a comprehensive textual analysis of sources from news wires, internet news sources, and social media. We find substantial evidence that intraday S&amp;P 500 index returns are predictable using lagged half-hour investor sentiment. The predictive power is also found in other stock and bond index ETFs. We document that this sentiment effect is independent of the intraday momentum effect, which is based on lagged half-hour returns. While the intraday momentum effect only exists in the last half hour, the sentiment effect persists in at least the last two hours of a trading day. From an investment perspective, high-frequency investor sentiment also appears to have significant economic value when evaluated with market timing trading strategies. We find evidence that the return predictability is most likely driven by the trading activities of noise traders. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Licheng; Najand, Mohammad; Shen, Jiancheng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic risk, costly arbitrage, and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Jie; Han, Bing
We test a new cross-sectional relation between expected stock return and idiosyncratic risk implied by the theory of costly arbitrage. If arbitrageurs find it more difficult to correct the mispricing of stocks with high idiosyncratic risk, there should be a positive (negative) relation between expected return and idiosyncratic risk for undervalued (overvalued) stocks. We combine several well-known anomalies to measure stock mispricing and proxy stock idiosyncratic risk using an exponential GARCH model for stock returns. We confirm that average stock returns monotonically increase (decrease) with idiosyncratic risk for undervalued (overvalued) stocks. Overall, our results support the importance of idiosyncratic risk as an arbitrage cost. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cao, Jie; Han, Bing</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debit card and demand for cash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>David, Bounie; Abel, Francois; Patrick, Waelbroeck
Despite the growing importance of the debit card in most developed countries, there are relatively few academic studies that analyze the impact of such evolution on the demand for cash. Beyond data availability, this research is complicated by the fact that the debit card provides two services for consumers - cash withdrawal and payment - that have contrasting effects on cash holdings and cash usage. Using micro-level data, we estimate the impacts of both services on the demand for cash by comparing the cash holdings and cash usage of three populations, namely non-cardholders, ATM-only cardholders, and debit cardholders. Controlling for various individual and network characteristics as well as a possible endogeneity issue, we find that the negative effect of the payment service on the demand for cash dominates the positive effect of the cash withdrawal service resulting in an overall negative impact of the debit card on the demand for cash. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>David, Bounie; Abel, Francois; Patrick, Waelbroeck</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit derivatives as a commitment device: Evidence from the cost of corporate debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Gi H.
When a firm writes incomplete debt contracts, its limited ability to commit to not strategically default and renegotiate its debt requires the firm to pay higher yields to its creditors. Hedged by credit derivatives, creditors have stronger bargaining power in the case of debt renegotiation, which ex-ante demotivates the firm to default strategically. In this paper, I aim to investigate theoretically and empirically whether credit derivatives could help reduce the cost of debt contracting stemming from the possibility of strategic default. I find that firms with a priori high strategic default incentives experience a relatively large reduction in their corporate bond spreads after the introduction of credit default swaps (CDS) written on their debt. This result is robust to controlling for the endogeneity of CDS introduction, My finding is consistent with the presence of CDS reducing the strategic default-related cost of corporate debt, suggesting the beneficial role of credit derivatives as a commitment device for the borrower to repay the lender. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Gi H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst coverage and corporate tax aggressiveness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Arthur; Francis, Bill B.; Wu, Qiang; Zhao, Yijiang
We examine the impact of analyst coverage on corporate tax aggressiveness. To address endogeneity concerns, we perform a difference-in-differences analysis using a setting which causes exogenous decreases in analyst coverage. Our tests identify a negative causal effect of analyst coverage on tax aggressiveness, suggesting that higher analyst coverage constrains corporate tax aggressiveness. Further cross-sectional variation tests find that this constraining effect on tax aggressiveness is more pronounced in firms with lower investor recognition and firms with more opaque information environments. Our results are consistent with the notion that higher analyst coverage increases the visibility of aggressive tax planning behavior as well as heightens analysts' demand for more transparent information, which in turn reduces tax aggressiveness. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allen, Arthur; Francis, Bill B.; Wu, Qiang; Zhao, Yijiang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Locus of control and savings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cobb-Clark, Deborah A.; Kassenboehmer, Sonja C.; Sinning, Mathias G.
This paper analyzes the relationship between individuals' locus of control and their savings behavior, i.e. wealth accumulation, savings rates, and portfolio choices. Locus of control is a psychological concept that captures individuals' beliefs about the causal relationship between their own behavior and life events. We find that households with an internal reference person (a main respondent who believes that he/she can generally control relevant aspects of life) save more in terms of levels and, in some cases, as a percentage of their permanent incomes. Although the locus-of-control gap in savings rates is largest among rich households, the gap in wealth accumulation is particularly large for poor households. Finally, our findings indicate that households with an internal reference person are in a better position to save in forms that are harder to access (such as pension wealth) than otherwise similar households with an external reference person. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cobb-Clark, Deborah A.; Kassenboehmer, Sonja C.; Sinning, Mathias G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic consequences of deregulation: Evidence from the removal of voting cap in Indian banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghosh, Chinmoy; Hilliard, James; Petrova, Milena; Phani, B. V.
We examine the effect of the 2005 Banking Regulation Amendment Bill and the 2011 Banking Laws Amendment Bill proposals for removal of the 10 percent voting rights cap in Indian Banks. The 2011 Banking Laws Bill was first introduced in 2005, but lapsed with the dissolution of the 14th Lok Sabha. The Bill was passed in December 2012 and raised the voting cap in private sector banks from 10 to 26 percent. We present evidence that the removal of the voting cap enhances the value of votes of bank stocks by reducing the wedge between cash-flow and control rights, thus increasing monitoring and the probability of takeover. Post-deregulation analysis reveals that the passage of the Bill was followed by increasing blockholders' number and percentage of shares held in larger and government banks. Furthermore, a stronger negative relationship between banks' profitability and size, as well as share of non-performing loans is observed. This study makes an important contribution to the growing literature on the valuation impact and efficiency gains of liberalization of ownership restrictions in emerging markets, as well as the rich literature on corporate governance and control relating to the value of voting privilege in companies with disparate voting rights. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ghosh, Chinmoy; Hilliard, James; Petrova, Milena; Phani, B. V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of failed takeovers in the banking sector: Deal or country characteristics?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caiazza, Stefano; Pozzolo, Alberto Franco
The consolidation process which characterized the banking industry in the last decades has been widely analyzed, but very few studies have investigated the reasons which bring a number of announced deals to failure. We fill this gap in the literature analyzing the characteristics of failed M&amp;A operations in a large sample, including all the major domestic and cross-border deals in the banking sector announced worldwide between 1992 and 2010. The results show that the most important factors which determine the failure of an announced operation are deal specific characteristics, in particular the hostility of the bidder and the presence of multiple potential acquirers. Moreover, lengthier negotiations have a lower probability of success. Contrary to expectations, cross-border operations are more likely to be successfully completed than domestic ones. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Caiazza, Stefano; Pozzolo, Alberto Franco</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do banks make the trade-offs among risks? The role of corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hsiao-Jung; Lin, Kuan-Ting
This study analyzes the role of corporate governance in the relationship among credit, interest rate, and liquidity risks encountered by banks. In particular, the study investigates how banks make the trade-offs among these risks under the maturity transformation business model. The sample consists of banks in 43 countries over the period of 2002-2010. Results show that credit, interest rate, and liquidity risks are related to one another, and that the interactions among them can be reduced by corporate governance and regulations. During the regular yield curve spread (YCS) period, management-controlled banks take less credit risk and even less liquidity risk whereas shareholder-controlled banks encounter more liquidity risk as they pursue more interest rate risk. During the inverted YCS period, management-controlled banks still opt for less credit risk-taking, but shareholder-controlled banks are greatly exposed to risks and should thus be monitored by concerned authorities. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Hsiao-Jung; Lin, Kuan-Ting</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Chasing trends at the micro-level: The effect of technical trading on order book dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiarella, Carl; Ladley, Daniel
Technical traders attempt to exploit trends in market prices and the order flow. Despite this little is known about how these traders behave in a micro-structure context. We consider a model of an order book based financial market. The market contains two groups: informed traders and technical traders. A numerical technique is used to identify a Markov perfect equilibrium of the trading game and so determine the optimal strategies. We find that technical trading rules are profitable and allow traders to increase their returns. The effect of technical traders on the market, however, is ambiguous. They decrease volatility and pricing errors but also increase trading costs despite primarily acting as liquidity suppliers. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiarella, Carl; Ladley, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economic value of controlling for large losses in portfolio selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dias, Alexandra
Research on asset pricing has shown that investor preferences include asymmetry and tail heaviness which affects the composition of optimal portfolios. This article investigates the out-of-sample economic value of introducing the risk of very large losses in portfolio selection. We combine mean-variance analysis with conditional Value-at-Risk using the subadditivity property of conditional Value-at-Risk, and we introduce a two stage method that preserves diversification while controlling for large losses. We find that strategies that account both for variance and the probability of large losses outperform efficient mean-variance portfolios, during and after the global financial crisis. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Dias, Alexandra</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trademarking activities and total factor productivity: Some evidence for British commercial banks using a metafrontier approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duygun, Meryem; Sena, Vania; Shaban, Mohamed
In this paper, we compute a non-parametric Metafrontier Malmquist index to evaluate the Total Factor Productivity (TFP) change among UK-based trademarking and non-trademarking commercial banks between 2005 and 2013. The use of the metafrontier approach allows us to: a) identify the drivers of TFP growth for each group of banks, b) compare the TFP growth of each group to the TFP growth experienced by the whole industry, and c) assess the extent to which the former catches up with the latter measured along the metafrontier. Our results suggest that TFP has been increasing among trademarking banks up to the onset of the financial crisis but this process has since reversed. The catch-up indexes suggest that both groups of banks were catching up with the metafrontier up to the financial crisis although the drivers of this process differed between the two groups. After the financial crisis, improvements in technology have been driven by a small number of commercial banks i.e. the non-trademarking banks. These results suggest that a large section of the commercial banking sector has not been able to overcome the effects of the financial crisis. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Duygun, Meryem; Sena, Vania; Shaban, Mohamed</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disagreement versus uncertainty: Evidence from distribution forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kruger, Fabian; Nolte, Ingmar
We use a cross-section of economic survey forecasts to predict the distribution of US macro variables in real time. This generalizes the existing literature, which uses disagreement (i.e., the cross-sectional variance of survey forecasts) to predict uncertainty (i.e., the conditional variance of future macroeconomic quantities). Our results show that cross-sectional information can be helpful for distribution forecasting, but this information needs to be modeled in a statistically efficient way in order to avoid overfitting. A simple one-parameter model which exploits time variation in the cross-section of survey point forecasts is found to perform well in practice. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V, All rights reserved.</description><author>Kruger, Fabian; Nolte, Ingmar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What is the impact of bankrupt and restructured loans on Japanese bank efficiency?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mamatzakis, Emmanuel; Matousek, Roman; Vu, Anh Nguyet
The Japanese banking system provides a distinctive platform for the examination of the long-lasting effect of problem loans on efficiency. We measure technical efficiency by modifying a translog enhanced hyperbolic distance function with two undesirable outputs, identified as problem loans and problem other earning assets. Our unique database allows us to distinguish between bankrupt and restructured loans to investigate the underlying causality between these loans and efficiency. From the flexible panel vector autoregression specification, primary results reveal that bankrupt loans have a positive impact on efficiency related to the "moral hazard, skimping" hypothesis, with the causality originating from bankrupt loans. In contrast, findings for the relationship between restructured loans and efficiency support the "bad luck" hypothesis. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mamatzakis, Emmanuel; Matousek, Roman; Vu, Anh Nguyet</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank integration and co-movements across housing markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milcheva, Stanimira; Zhu, Bing
This paper investigates whether bank integration measured by cross-border bank flows can capture the co-movements across housing markets in developed countries by using a spatial dynamic panel model. The transmission can occur through a global banking channel in which global banks intermediate wholesale funding to local banks. Changes in financial conditions are passed across borders through the banks' balance-sheet exposure to credit, currency, maturity, and funding risks resulting in house price spillovers. While controlling for country-level and global factors, we find significant co-movement across housing markets of countries with proportionally high bank integration. Bank integration can better capture house price co-movements than other measures of economic integration. Once we account for bank exposure, other spatial linkages traditionally used to account for return co-movements across region such as trade, foreign direct investment, portfolio investment, geographic proximity, etc. - become insignificant. Moreover, we find that the co-movement across housing markets decreases for countries with less developed mortgage markets characterized by fixed mortgage rate contracts, low limits of loan-to-value ratios and no mortgage equity withdrawal. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Milcheva, Stanimira; Zhu, Bing</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multivariate moments expansion density: Application of the dynamic equicorrelation model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niguez, Trino-Manuel; Perote, Javier
In this study, we propose a new semi-nonparametric (SNP) density model for describing the density of portfolio returns. This distribution, which we refer to as the multivariate moments expansion (MME), admits any non-Gaussian (multivariate) distribution as its basis because it is specified. directly in terms of the basis density's moments. To obtain the expansion of the Gaussian density, the MME is a reformulation of the multivariate Gram-Charlier (MGC), but the MME is much simpler and tractable than the MGC when positive transformations are used to produce well-defined densities. As an empirical application, we extend the dynamic conditional equicorrelation (DECO) model to an SNP framework using the MME. The resulting model is parameterized in a feasible manner to admit two-stage consistent estimation and it represents the DECO as well as the salient non-Gaussian features of portfolio return distributions. The in- and out-of-sample performance of a MME-DECO model of a portfolio of 10 assets demonstrate that it can be a useful tool for risk management purposes. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Niguez, Trino-Manuel; Perote, Javier</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How capital regulation and other factors drive the role of shadow banking in funding short-term business credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duca, John V.
This paper empirically analyzes how capital regulation, risk, and other factors altered the relative use of shadow banking-funded, short-term business debt since the early 1960s. Results indicate that the share was affected over the long run not only by changing information and reserve requirement costs, but also by shifts in relative regulation of bank versus nonbank credit-sources such as Basel I in 1990 and reregulation in 2010. In the short-run, the shadow bank share rose when deposit interest rate ceilings were binding on traditional banks, the economic outlook improved, or risk premia declined, and fell when event risks arose. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duca, John V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jump and variance risk premia in the S&amp;P 500</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neumann, Maximilian; Prokopczuk, Marcel; Simen, Chardin Wese
We analyze the risk premia embedded in the S&amp;P 500 spot index and option markets. We use a long time series of spot prices and a large panel of option prices to jointly estimate the diffusive stock risk premium, the price jump risk premium, the diffusive variance risk premium and the variance jump risk premium. The risk premia are statistically and economically significant and move over time. Investigating the economic drivers of the risk premia, we are able to explain up to 63% of these variations. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Neumann, Maximilian; Prokopczuk, Marcel; Simen, Chardin Wese</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>National culture and the cost of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chui, Andy C. W.; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.; Zhou, Gaoguang
This study investigates how Schwartz's cultural dimensions of embeddedness and mastery affect the corporate cost of debt through bankruptcy risk and sensitivity to agency activity channels. Using data from 33 countries, we find a strong and robust negative relation between embeddedness and the cost of debt. The estimated relation between mastery and the corporate cost of debt is negative and significant in most of the tests. Further analyses reveal that the development of financial intermediation and the enforcement of insider trading law moderate the relation between culture and the cost of debt. Confirming our hypotheses, we document that embeddedness is negatively related to bankruptcy risk and sensitivity to agency activity. We find that mastery is positively related to bankruptcy risk across countries as well, but this relation is weaker. We also show that mastery is positively related to sensitivity to agency activity among countries with highly leveraged firms. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chui, Andy C. W.; Kwok, Chuck C. Y.; Zhou, Gaoguang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structure and estimation of Levy subordinated hierarchical Archimedean copulas (LSHAC): Theory and empirical tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Wenjun; Wang, Chou-Wen; Tan, Ken Seng
Levy subordinated hierarchical Archimedean copulas (LSHAC) are flexible models in high dimensional modeling. However, there is limited literature discussing their applications, largely due to the challenges in estimating their structures and their parameters. In this paper, we propose a three-stage estimation procedure to determine the hierarchical structure and the parameters of a LSHAC. This is the first paper to empirically examine the modeling performances of LSHAC models using exchange traded funds. Simulation study demonstrates the reliability and robustness of the proposed estimation method in determining the optimal structure. Empirical analysis further shows that, compared to elliptical copulas, LSHACs have better fitting abilities as well as more accurate out-of-sample Value-at-Risk estimates with less parameters. In addition, from a financial risk management point of view, the LSHACs have the advantage of being very flexible in modeling the asymmetric tail dependence, providing more conservative estimations of the probabilities of extreme downward co-movements in the financial market. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhu, Wenjun; Wang, Chou-Wen; Tan, Ken Seng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local bank competition and small business lending after the onset of the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saaskilahti, Jaakko
This paper examines whether the effects of the financial crisis on the volumes and prices of small business loans depended on the pre-crisis local competitive environment. To address this question, I employ a unique data set on Finnish cooperative banks. I find that the monthly volumes of new business loans decreased and the average loan margins increased after the onset of the crisis. The decrease in volumes and the increase in margins were greater in local banking markets that were more competitive before the crisis. The results for the loan margins are more robust than those obtained for the volumes. Auxiliary analyses suggest that the greater effects in the more competitive markets are due to competition leveling therein more after the onset of the crisis. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Saaskilahti, Jaakko</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information stages in efficient markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>AitSahlia, Farid; Yoon, Joon-Hui
Market efficiency, in its strong form, asserts that asset prices fully reflect all available information. The classical event study methodology attempts to make explicit this link by assuming rigid and universal pre-event, event, and post-event periods. As an alternative, our framework captures the progressive diffusion of information around events as well as the overlapping impacts of separate events. We also illustrate that our approach captures mean-reversion of expected returns and increased volatility around announcement dates. These features reflect latent regime switches and are associated with semi-strong market efficiency. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>AitSahlia, Farid; Yoon, Joon-Hui</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiperiod portfolio optimization with multiple risky assets and general transaction costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mei, Xiaoling; DeMiguel, Victor; Nogales, Francisco J.
We analyze the optimal portfolio policy for a multiperiod mean-variance investor facing multiple risky assets in the presence of general transaction costs. For proportional transaction costs, we give a closed form expression for a no-trade region, shaped as a multi-dimensional parallelogram, and show how the optimal portfolio policy can be efficiently computed for many risky assets by solving a single quadratic program. For market impact costs, we show that at each period it is optimal to trade to the boundary of a state-dependent rebalancing region. Finally, we show empirically that the losses associated with ignoring transaction costs and behaving myopically may be large. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mei, Xiaoling; DeMiguel, Victor; Nogales, Francisco J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock ownership guidelines for CEOs: Do they (not) meet expectations?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benson, Bradley W.; Lian, Qin; Wang, Qiming
This paper examines the determinants and the effects of CEO stock ownership guideline adoption, differentiating Not-meet/Meet adopters - those setting the guideline above below the CEO's stock ownership at the time of adoption. While Meet adoption is mainly determined by factors related to stakeholder management, we find that Not-meet adoption is associated with factors related to both incentive alignment and stakeholder management. CEO ownership increases and CEO incentive alignment improves for Not-meet firms. But CEO ownership and incentives are unchanged for Meet firms following guideline adoption. We find no evidence that CEO compensation changes abnormally after adoption. Not-meet firms have larger improvement in operating performance and better stock performance than Meet firms. We provide evidence that the motives and the effects of guideline adoption depend on the level of the ownership restriction relative to the CEO's ownership at the time of adoption. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benson, Bradley W.; Lian, Qin; Wang, Qiming</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing financial stability: The Capital and Loss Assessment under Stress Scenarios (CLASS) model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirtle, Beverly; Kovner, Anna; Vickery, James; Bhanot, Meru
The CLASS model is a top-down capital stress testing framework that uses public data, simple econometric models and auxiliary assumptions to project the effect of macroeconomic scenarios on U.S. banking firms. Through the lens of the model, we find that the total banking system capital shortfall under stressful macroeconomic conditions began to rise 4 years before the financial crisis, peaking in the fourth quarter of 2008. The capital gap has since fallen sharply, and is now significantly below pre-crisis levels. In the cross-section, banking firms estimated to be most sensitive to macroeconomic conditions also have higher capital ratios, consistent with a "precautionary" view of bank capital, though this behavior is evident only since the crisis. We interpret our results as evidence that the resiliency of the U.S. banking system has improved since the financial crisis, and also as an illustration of the value of stress testing as a macroprudential policy tool. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hirtle, Beverly; Kovner, Anna; Vickery, James; Bhanot, Meru</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks and capital requirements: Channels of adjustment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Benjamin H.; Scatigna, Michela
Bank capital ratios have increased steadily since the financial crisis. For a sample of 101 large banks from advanced and emerging economies, retained earnings account for the bulk of their higher risk-weighted capital ratios, with reductions in risk weights playing a lesser role. On average, banks continued to expand their lending in real terms, though lending contracted among European banks. Lower dividend payouts and (for advanced economy banks) wider lending spreads have contributed to banks' ability to use retained earnings to build capital. Banks that came out of the crisis with higher capital ratios and stronger profitability were able to expand lending more. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cohen, Benjamin H.; Scatigna, Michela</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank size, capital, and systemic risk: Some international evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Laeven, Luc; Ratnovski, Lev; Tong, Hui
This paper studies the significant variation in the cross-section of standalone and systemic risk of large banks during the recent financial crisis to identify bank specific factors that determine risk. We find that systemic risk grows with bank size and is inversely related to bank capital, and this effect exists above and beyond the effect of bank size and capital on standalone bank risk. Our results contribute to the ongoing debate on the merits of imposing systemic risk-based capital requirements on banks. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Laeven, Luc; Ratnovski, Lev; Tong, Hui</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank capital and uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Valencia, Fabian
Financial frictions in raising external finance can induce banks to self-insure against future shocks through holding more bank capital. As uncertainty about future losses increases, the above reasoning implies that they would choose to increase their capital position. This paper tests this hypothesis in a dataset with U.S. Commercial Banks by exploiting a cross-sectional variation in uncertainty to explain the distribution of bank capital ratios. I find statistically significant and robust evidence in support of a self-insurance mechanism. A counterfactual experiment suggests that a decline in uncertainty to its lowest level generates an average reduction in bank capital ratios of up to 2 percentage points. Furthermore, uncertainty explains, on average, about half of banks regulatory capital buffers. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Valencia, Fabian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do corporate policies follow a life-cycle?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faff, Robert; Kwok, Wing Chun; Podolski, Edward J.; Wong, George
We examine whether corporate investment, financing, and cash policies are interdependent and follow a predictable pattern in line with the firm life-cycle. We find that investments and equity issuance decrease with firm life-cycle, while debt issuance and cash holdings increase in the introduction and growth stages and decrease in the mature and shake-out/decline stages of the firm's life-cycle. These results are robust after using various proxies for life-cycle and controlling for firm, CEO and board level characteristics. Collectively, our results show that corporate policies follow a firm life-cycle. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Faff, Robert; Kwok, Wing Chun; Podolski, Edward J.; Wong, George</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On stability of operational risk estimates by LDA: From causes to approaches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhou, Xiaoping; Durfee, Antonina V.; Fabozzi, Frank J.
The stability of estimates is critical when applying advanced measurement approaches (AMA) such as loss distribution approach (LDA) for operational risk capital modeling. Recent studies have identified issues associated with capital estimates by applying the maximum likelihood estimation (MLE) method for truncated distributions: significant upward mean-bias, considerable uncertainty about the estimates, and non-robustness to both small and large losses. Although alternative estimation approaches have been proposed, there has not been any comprehensive study of how alternative approaches perform compared to the MLE method. This paper is the first comprehensive study on the performance of various potentially promising alternative approaches (including minimum distance approach, quantile distance approach, scaling-based bias correction, upward scaling of lower quantiles, and right-truncated distributions) as compared to MLE with regards to accuracy, precision and robustness. More importantly, based on the properties of each estimator, we propose a right-truncation with probability weighted least squares method, by combining the right-truncated distribution and minimizing a probability weighted distance (i.e., the quadratic upper-tail Anderson-Darling distance), and we find it significantly reduces the bias and volatility of capital estimates and improves the robustness of capital estimates to small losses near the threshold or moving the threshold, demonstrated by both simulation results and real data application. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhou, Xiaoping; Durfee, Antonina V.; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Profit shifting and tax response of multinational banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Merz, Julia; Overesch, Michael
This paper analyzes multinational banks' response to taxation. For the empirical analysis we use firm level bank data from the Bankscope database. We find significant tax effects on reported profits of bank subsidiaries. The magnitude for the tax response of reported profits doubles the effects found in previous studies for non-financial MNCs. Additional analysis reveals that the response to tax incentives differs across business types. The tax elasticity of revenues generated by interest-bearing activities is less responsive compared to other activities. Results also reveal significant tax effects on loan loss provisions. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Merz, Julia; Overesch, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Voluntary disclosure of corporate venture capital investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mohamed, Abdulkadir; Schwienbacher, Armin
In this paper, we investigate drivers of corporate venture capital investment announcements. Consistent with voluntary information disclosure theories, we find that a public announcement is less likely to be made when the start-up firm is in the seed stage but more likely when the parent company is large, active in concentrated markets and in non-high-tech industries; spends heavily on internal R&amp;D and capital expenditures; has low leverage ratio; and faces more information asymmetry problems. In addition, corporate venture capital programs managed externally disclose more often than internal programs. We find that parent companies facing more severe asymmetric information problems enjoy the highest abnormal returns in response to announcements. This study contributes to the literature on voluntary information disclosure in that it evidences that larger corporations use disclosure of some of their investments in innovative startups strategically as a way to convey valuable information to the market. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mohamed, Abdulkadir; Schwienbacher, Armin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing effects when competitors arrive: The case of discount certificates in Germany</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schertler, Andrea
This article investigates how overpricing of outstanding certificates, also called master certificates, changes when competing products that duplicate the features of master certificates are issued. I argue that competition effects may be reverted and overpricing may increase rather than decrease after competitors arrive, when retail investors fail to detect implications of credit risk differences on certificates' values. Using difference-in-differences estimations on matched samples, I find that overpricing of master certificates decreases after the competing products have been issued, but only when the master issuer's credit risk is lower than that of the duplicate issuer, while it increases when the credit risk difference is positive. These findings are robust to controlling for retail investors' demand in various ways. Thus, the study indicates that retail investors' failure to detect the value implications of issuers' credit risk can undermine product competition. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schertler, Andrea</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of news articles and corporate disclosure on credit risk valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsai, Feng-Tse; Lu, Hsin-Min; Hung, Mao-Wei
In this study, we investigate how qualitative information in newspapers and corporate filings affects credit risk valuation in the credit default swap (CDS) market. We adopted news coverage and news sentiment to quantify text information from news articles and quantified the qualitative risk disclosures of individual firms in their corporate filings (i.e., Form 10-K and 10-Q). Our empirical study, based on 13 years of CDS data, provides several conclusions. First, more news coverage and negative news sentiment increase credit risk. Second, a higher overall volume of risk factor disclosure in corporate public filings is linked to a higher credit risk for debt issuers. Moreover, financial risk has the strongest effect among the five types of risk disclosures we considered. Overall, our results suggest that text information from newspapers and corporate filings contains incremental informational content for firms' credit risk evaluations. These two information sources play distinctive roles in signaling issuers' future credit conditions. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tsai, Feng-Tse; Lu, Hsin-Min; Hung, Mao-Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the uncertainty of firm-level fundamentals help explain cross-sectional differences in liquidity commonality?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Isshaq, Zangina; Faff, Robert
Our goal is to better understand the economic sources of commonality in liquidity. To this end, we argue that a firm with low (high) volatility in its "fundamental" profitability will have a higher (lower) liquidity commonality because it is more (less) likely to serve as reference stock in the setting of cross-asset learning about fundamentals. As predicted, we find that commonality in liquidity is negatively related to profitability volatility. This negative relation holds after controlling for correlated trading, size, book-to-market effects, idiosyncratic volatility, stock returns, and managerial income smoothing. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Isshaq, Zangina; Faff, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An index-based measure of liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chacko, George; Das, Sanjiv; Fan, Rong
The liquidity shocks of '08-'09 revealed that measures of liquidity risk being used in most financial institutions turned out to be woefully inadequate. The construction of long-short portfolios based on liquidity proxies introduces errors such as extraneous risk factors and hedging error. We develop a new measure for liquidity risk using exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that attempts to minimize this error. We form a theoretically-supported measure that is long ETFs and short the underlying components of that ETF, i.e., long and short a similar set of underlying securities with the same weights. Pricing discrepancies between the long and short positions are driven by liquidity differences between the ETF and its underlying components. Constructing liquidity risk factors in a number of markets, we undertake several tests to validate our new liquidity metric. The results show that our illiquidity measure is strongly related to other measures of illiquidity, explains bond index returns, and reveals a systematic illiquidity component across fixed-income markets. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chacko, George; Das, Sanjiv; Fan, Rong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial constraints and international trade with endogenous mode of competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouet, Antoine; Vaubourg, Anne-Gael
The paper examines how financial constraints affect firms' decisions to export when the mode of intrasectoral competition is endogenous. We propose an extension of Neary and Tharakan's (2012) model, in which firms resort to external funders to finance investments in production capacities. Sectors differ in financial constraint and the cost of capital increases with the level of financial constraint. We first show that a weaker financial constraint allows firms to adopt a Cournot (rather than a Bertrand) pricing scheme and generate a high duopoly profit. Consequently, less financially constrained sectors are more likely to export. We also exhibit a new transmission channel of financial crisis. By increasing the financial cost of exporting and making it more difficult to engage in a Cournot behavior, a financial shock reduces both the intensive and extensive margins of trade. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bouet, Antoine; Vaubourg, Anne-Gael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does pricing affect investors' product choice? Evidence from the market for discount certificates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Entrop, Oliver; Fischer, Georg; McKenzie, Michael; Wilkens, Marco; Winkler, Christoph
This paper examines the choices of retail investors in the market for structured financial products with a focus on implicit and explicit pricing components. We evaluate more than 72,000 single stock discount certificates on a daily basis from 2004 through 2008. The certificates are quoted an average of 0.58% above their fair value before the financial crisis, increasing to 1.24% during 2008. Although credit risk explains a major part (39%) of the certificates' overpricing, we find that issuer default risk does not have any influence on investors' product choices. Instead, retail investors are strongly influenced by irrational factors such as issuer and product familiarity. Finally, investors are found to make poor product choices (in terms of bid/ask spreads and markups over fair value), resulting in significant losses. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Entrop, Oliver; Fischer, Georg; McKenzie, Michael; Wilkens, Marco; Winkler, Christoph</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>TARP and the long-term perception of risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Semaan, Elias; Drake, Pamela Peterson
The Capital Purchase Program (CPP) was intended to enhance capital and preserve lending capacity of banks, but the role of this program in affecting the risk of participating banks has been unresolved. We address this issue by investigating the market's long-term perception of risk for financial institutions participating in the CPP. Leading up to and including the crisis, the systematic and idiosyncratic variances of the stock returns of all financial firms increased; following CPP, the relative idiosyncratic risk of CPP participants remained higher than for those not participating in CPP for four years following CPP. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Semaan, Elias; Drake, Pamela Peterson</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management, capital structure, and the role of institutional environments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>An, Zhe; Li, Donghui; Yu, Jin
This paper examines the effect of earnings management on financial leverage and how this relation is influenced by institutional environments by employing a large panel of 25,777 firms across 37 countries spanning the years 1989-2009. We find that firms with high earnings management activities are associated with high financial leverage. More importantly, this positive relation is attenuated by strong institutional environments. Our results lend strong support to the notions that (1) both corporate debt and institutional environments can be served as external control mechanisms to alleviate the agency cost of free cash flow; and (2) it is less costly to rely on institutional environments than debt. After meticulously addressing the possible endogeneity issues and conducting various robustness tests, our main conclusions remain confirmed. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>An, Zhe; Li, Donghui; Yu, Jin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit and liquidity in interbank rates: A quadratic approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dubecq, Simon; Monfort, Alain; Renne, Jean-Paul; Roussellet, Guillaume
A bank that lends on the unsecured market requires compensations for facing the default risk of the borrowing bank (credit risk) and the risk associated to its own future funding needs (liquidity risk). In this paper, we propose a quadratic term-structure model of the spreads between unsecured and risk free interbank rates. Our no-arbitrage econometric framework allows us to decompose the term structure of spreads into credit and liquidity components and to identify risk premia associated with each of these two risks. Our results suggest that, over the period 2012-2013, most of the reduction in interbank spreads comes from a decrease in liquidity-related risk components. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dubecq, Simon; Monfort, Alain; Renne, Jean-Paul; Roussellet, Guillaume</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-term industry reversals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Yuliang; Mazouz, Khelifa
This study investigates whether, how and why industry performance can drive long-term return reversals. Using data from the UK, we find that firms in losing industries significantly outperform those in winning industries over the subsequent five years. These industry reversals remain strong and persistent after controlling for stock momentum, industry momentum, seasonal effects and traditional risk factors. We find a strong influence of past industry performance on stock return reversals. Our results also show that past industry performance is the driving force behind long-term reversals. Specifically, we find that industry components drive stock reversals, while past stock performance does not explain industry reversals. Further analysis suggests that industry reversals are present in both good and bad states of the economy and are stronger in industries with high valuation uncertainty. This implies that industry reversals are more likely to be a result of mispricing. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Yuliang; Mazouz, Khelifa</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The social costs and benefits of too-big-to-fail banks: A "bounding" exercise</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyd, John H.; Heitz, Amanda
While the policy of too-big-to-fail has received wide attention in the literature, there is little agreement regarding economies of scale for financial firms. We take the stand that systemic risk increases when the larger players in the financial sector have a larger share of output. Calculations indicate that the cost to the macro-economy due to increased systemic risk is always much larger than the potential benefit due to scale economies. When distributional and intergenerational issues are considered, the potential benefits to economies of scale are unlikely to ever exceed the potential costs due to increased risk of a banking crisis. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boyd, John H.; Heitz, Amanda</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Out of sight, out of mind? On the risk of sub-custodian structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Droll, Thomas; Podlich, Natalia; Wedow, Michael
We analyse sub-custodian chains using a unique data set from a survey. Our key question is whether there is evidence for moral hazard in the delegation of asset safe-keeping to sub-custodians. Sub custodian chains can be relatively long and frequently reach across several countries. The risk that securities are lost or the return to their owners delayed is not negligible. Our findings highlight that foreign or better informed banks are associated with shorter sub-custodian chains. Better capitalised banks seem to have longer, but safer sub-custodian chains. Our findings support the view that central securities depositories (CSDs) play a beneficial role in the management of sub-custodian structures. A CSD as the first sub custodian reduces the country risk in sub-custodian structures. When we analyse the choice of a CSD, we find that better capitalised, larger and foreign banks are less likely to rely on CSDs as their first sub custodian. (V) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Droll, Thomas; Podlich, Natalia; Wedow, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do traders choose dark markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garvey, Ryan; Huang, Tao; Wu, Fei
We examine U.S. equity trader use of dark and lit markets. Marketable orders executed in the dark have lower information content and smaller fill rates. Dark orders take longer to execute, but they execute at more favorable prices. Traders are more likely to go dark when the bid-ask spread is wider and those with higher dark participation are more sophisticated. Although market regulators have expressed concern over the rise in dark trading, our results indicate that dark markets provide important benefits to traders that lit markets do not. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garvey, Ryan; Huang, Tao; Wu, Fei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial development and the effectiveness of monetary policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ma, Yong; Lin, Xingkai
This paper investigates the relationship between financial development and the effectiveness of monetary policy using panel data from 41 economies. The results show that the effects of monetary policy on output and inflation are significantly and negatively correlated with financial development, indicating that the effectiveness of monetary policy declines as the financial system becomes more developed. This finding is robust across all the different specifications and estimation methods examined. Our paper provides new evidence and insights to the long-standing debate on the relationship between financial development and the effectiveness of monetary policy. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ma, Yong; Lin, Xingkai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foster-Hart optimal portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anand, Abhinav; Li, Tiantian; Kurosaki, Tetsuo; Kim, Young Shin
We reinvestigate the classic portfolio optimization problem where the notion of portfolio risk is captured by the "Foster-Hart risk" a new, bankruptcy-proof, reserve based measure of risk, extremely sensitive to left tail events (Foster and Hart, 2009). To include financial market frictions induced by market microstructure, we employ a general, ex-ante transaction cost function with fixed, linear and quadratic penalty terms in the objective function. We represent the US equity market by the Dow Jones Industrial Average (DJIA) index and study the performance of the Foster-Hart optimal DJIA portfolio. In order to capture the skewed and leptokurtotic nature of real life stock returns, we model the returns of the DJIA constituents as an ARMA-GARCH process with multivariate "normal tempered stable" innovations. We demonstrate that the Foster-Hart optimal portfolio's performance is superior to those obtained under several techniques currently in use in academia and industry. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anand, Abhinav; Li, Tiantian; Kurosaki, Tetsuo; Kim, Young Shin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Myopic loss aversion and stock investments: An empirical study of private investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Boram; Veld-Merkoulova, Yulia
Myopic loss aversion was suggested by Benartzi and Thaler (1995) as an explanation for the equity premium puzzle. Its main prediction is that loss averse investors, who evaluate their investment performance too frequently and therefore often observe small losses on their stock portfolios, would invest too little in equity. We investigate the link between myopic loss aversion and actual investment decisions of individual investors, using survey data. Our results are consistent with the predictions of Benartzi and Thaler. Higher myopic loss aversion is associated with lower stock investment as a share of total assets. Investors tend to evaluate their stock portfolio performance too often, which contributes to the prevalence of myopic loss aversion. The effect of myopia is most apparent when investors both evaluate their portfolios frequently and trade stocks regularly. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Boram; Veld-Merkoulova, Yulia</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme risk modeling: An EVT-pair-copulas approach for financial stress tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koliai, Lyes
This paper presents a semi-parametric copula-GARCH risk model for financial return series with a stress testing perspective. The marginal distributions of the returns are specified using the Extreme Value Theory (EVT), putting a specific emphasis on extreme returns. The joint distribution is then built up using the pair-copulas theorem, based on the marginal distributions and the pair dependence structures. The model performance is assessed for three sets of assets, namely equity indices, exchange rates, and commodity prices. The empirical results support a better static and dynamic properties of the presented model compared to most common specifications used in practice. The proposed model and the alternative specifications are then carried out to perform stress testing exercises on hypothetical portfolios, where financial returns are considered as risk factors. The results show that the use of a wide range of risk models produce significantly different results, in terms of the corresponding stress scenario and in the corresponding impact on the portfolios. Hence, considering flexible and consistent specifications, as in the proposed model, allows ensuring a better credibility of the stress scenario and enhances the usefulness of the stress testing results. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koliai, Lyes</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Characteristics-based portfolio choice with leverage constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ammann, Manuel; Coqueret, Guillaume; Schade, Jan-Philip
We show that the introduction of a leverage constraint improves the practical implementation of characteristics-based portfolios. The addition of the constraint leads to significantly lower transaction costs, to a reduction of negative portfolio weights, and to a decrease in volatility and misspecification risk. Furthermore, it allows investors to implement any desired level of leverage. In this study, we include 12 characteristics, thereby extending the classical size, book-to-market and momentum paradigm. We report several key indicators such as the proportion of negative weights, Sharpe ratio, volatility, transaction costs, the transaction cost-adjusted certainty equivalent returns, and the Herfindahl-Hirschman index. Analyzing the sensitivity of these key indicators to the choice of multiple combinations of the 12 characteristics, to risk aversion, and to estimation sample size, we show that constrained policies are much less sensitive to these parameters than their unconstrained counterparts. Finally, for quadratic utility, we derive a semi-closed analytical form for the portfolio weights. Overall, we provide a comprehensive extension of characteristics-based portfolio choice and contribute to a better understanding and implementation of the allocation process. (C) 2015 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Ammann, Manuel; Coqueret, Guillaume; Schade, Jan-Philip</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO inside debt and corporate debt maturity structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dang, Viet A.; Phan, Hieu V.
This paper examines the relation between chief executive officer (CEO) inside debt holdings and corporate debt maturity. We provide robust evidence that inside debt has a positive effect on short-maturity debt and that this effect is concentrated in financially unconstrained firms that face lower refinancing risk. Our analysis further shows that CEO inside debt helps reduce the cost of debt financing. Overall, our results indicate that managerial holdings of inside debt facilitate access to external debt financing and reduce refinancing risk, thus incentivizing managers to use less costly shorter term debt. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dang, Viet A.; Phan, Hieu V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictability in bond returns using technical trading rules</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shynkevich, Andrei
The predictability of future returns on bond portfolios at daily frequency is investigated using, a large universe of mechanical trading rules that have been popularized in literature on equity and currency markets. The predictability in returns is inversely related to interest rate risk but positively related to default risk. The return predictability is more sensitive to fluctuations in the economic business cycle rather than changes in the Federal Reserve's monetary policy. Returns on portfolios of Treasury bonds are more predictable during the restrictive monetary policy regime, whereas returns on both Treasury bonds and corporate bonds exhibit much better predictability during the economic expansions rather than recessions. The predictability of returns in various segments of the U.S. bond market has declined over time. Findings for the predictability in the highly liquid bond exchange-traded funds are largely in line with the original results of the predictability in bond portfolio returns. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shynkevich, Andrei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Qualified residential mortgages and default risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Floros, Ioannis; White, Joshua T.
The Dodd-Frank Act tasks regulators with defining a Qualified Residential Mortgage (QRM) as an exemption from risk retention for residential "mortgage-backed securities. Congress instructs regulators to consider factors that result in lower levels of historic default in defining a QRM. We analyze non-agency loans and find credit scores and loan-to-value ratios are among the most significant predictors of default, even when controlling for risky loan products and loose underwriting standards. Importantly, credit scores and loan-to-value ratios better tradeoff the benefit of reduced default risk with the cost of limiting access to capital than most factors, yet are absent from the final QRM definition. Our results have important implications for current and future policy on residential mortgage securitization, risk retention, and disclosure. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Floros, Ioannis; White, Joshua T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does institutional shareholder activism stimulate corporate information flow?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prevost, Andrew K.; Wongchoti, Udomsak; Marshall, Ben R.
Activist shareholders have an incentive to communicate and cooperate with other major However, the impact of their activity on information flow surrounding targeted firms is largely We explore this aspect using a prolific proponent: labor unions. Following the mailing of proxies ing union-sponsored shareholder proposals, trading volume increases significantly and at-issue spreads of targeted firms are lower compared to matched firms. Subsequent difference-in analyses show that stock prices of targeted firms become more informative as a result of firming the intuition that activism results in a reduction of differential information between vestors. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Prevost, Andrew K.; Wongchoti, Udomsak; Marshall, Ben R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systematic limited arbitrage and the cross-section of stock returns: Evidence from exchange traded funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeLisle, R. Jared; McTier, Brian C.; Smedema, Adam R.
We propose a parsimonious, comprehensive proxy for innovations in limited arbitrage: innovations in ETFs' premium. Consistent with a common component, we confirm limited arbitrage factors, LAFs, constructed from ETFs' premium innovations spanning four asset classes are correlated. Further, we find that equity LAFs are negatively priced in the cross-section of stock returns. Our pricing tests also confirm that LAFs provide pricing information beyond well-known limits of arbitrage: illiquidity and idiosyncratic volatility. Overall, our findings suggest that limited arbitrage risk is priced and LAF is a relevant risk factor. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeLisle, R. Jared; McTier, Brian C.; Smedema, Adam R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Basel II affect the market valuation of discretionary loan loss provisions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hamadi, Malika; Heinen, Andreas; Linder, Stefan; Porumb, Vlad-Andrei
We use a sample of banks from 24 European countries to investigate whether the adoption of the Basel II Capital Accord in 2008 affects the market valuation of discretionary loan loss provisions (DLLPs). Although Basel II lowers the incentives of internal ratings-based (IRB) banks to recognize income-increasing DLLPs in an opportunistic manner, it has no such impact on the remaining banks, which adopt the Standardized methodology. We use this setup in a difference-in-difference (DiD) design, where Standardized banks act as a control group. Our evidence supports the three hypotheses that, for IRB relative to Standardized banks, Basel II is associated with (i) less income-increasing DLLPs and (ii) less income-smoothing via DLLPs, which enhances the informational content of DLLPs about future loan losses and leads to (iii) higher market valuation of DLLPs. Our findings are timely and have policy implications for future regulatory developments in the banking industry. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hamadi, Malika; Heinen, Andreas; Linder, Stefan; Porumb, Vlad-Andrei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk protection from risky collateral: Evidence from the euro bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helberg, Stig; Lindset, Snorre
This paper studies empirically how collateral protects the market value of defaultable bonds from changes in risk. We construct a measure of the risk protection from collateral, and estimate it under different economic conditions. Using yields from the euro bond market, we find that the risk protection from collateral is conditional, significantly stronger in both general and issuer-specific bad states. However, the collateral is risky, and a fall in the collateral value clearly lowers the risk protection. Consequently, the correlation between the bad state and the collateral value is crucial when assessing the risk reducing properties of collateral. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Helberg, Stig; Lindset, Snorre</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are there exploitable trends in commodity futures prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Yufeng; Hu, Ting; Yang, Jian
We provide evidence that a simple moving average timing strategy, when applied to portfolios of commodity futures, can generate superior performance to the buy-and-hold strategy. The outperformance is very robust. It can survive the transaction costs in the futures markets, it is not concentrated in a particular subperiod, and is robust to short-sale constraints, alternative specifications of the moving average lag length, alternative construction of the continuous time-series of futures prices, and impact from data mining. The outperformance of the timing strategy is not driven by the backwardation and contango. It is stronger during recession and can not be explained by macroeconomic variables. Finally, we confirm that the outperformance of the moving average timing strategy in the commodity futures comes from the successful market timing. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Han, Yufeng; Hu, Ting; Yang, Jian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information role of advisors in mergers and acquisitions: Evidence from acquirers hiring targets' ex-advisors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Xin; Shekhar, Chander; Tam, Lewis H. K.; Yao, Jiaquan
We examine the information role of financial advisors by focusing on mergers and acquisitions in which acquiring firms hire target firms' ex-advisors. We document that by employing targets' ex-advisors, acquirers pay lower takeover premiums and secure a larger proportion of merger synergies. The corresponding targets exhibit lower announcement returns and are less likely to be propositioned by competing bidders. These results indicate that acquirers take advantage of value-relevant information about targets through targets' ex-advisors, and achieve bargaining advantages in deal negotiations. In contrast, we document no discernible value effects when targets hire acquirers' ex-advisors, suggesting that the information role of acquirers' ex-advisors hired by targets is weaker than that of targets' ex-advisors hired by acquirers. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Xin; Shekhar, Chander; Tam, Lewis H. K.; Yao, Jiaquan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Religiosity and the cost of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hanwen; Huang, Henry He; Lobo, Gerald J.; Wang, Chong
In a cross-country setting, we document that stronger religiosity is associated with lower loan interest spread. In addition, we show that this negative association is more pronounced in countries with weaker creditor rights, suggesting that religious values play a more significant role in constraining opportunistic behavior in a weaker legal environment. Our analysis reveals that stronger religiosity is also related to other favorable terms in loan contracting, such as larger facility amount, use of accounting-based performance pricing, and lower upfront fee. Corroborating our cross-country findings, we also show that in the U.S. setting, firms in regions with stronger religiosity enjoy lower loan interest spread. Our study contributes to understanding the important role religiosity plays in debt financing. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Hanwen; Huang, Henry He; Lobo, Gerald J.; Wang, Chong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Greed or good deeds: An examination of the relation between corporate social responsibility and the financial performance of US commercial banks around the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornett, Marcia Millon; Erhemjamts, Otgontsetseg; Tehranian, Hassan
We examine the relation between banks' corporate social responsibility (CSR) and financial performance in a context of the recent financial crisis. We find that banks, in general, appear to be rewarded for being socially responsible as financial performance is positively and significantly related to CSR scores. We find that the biggest banks pursue socially responsible activities to a significantly greater extent than smaller banks. Further, the largest banks see a steep increase in CSR strengths and a steep drop in CSR concerns after 2009. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cornett, Marcia Millon; Erhemjamts, Otgontsetseg; Tehranian, Hassan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does director-level reputation matter? Evidence from bank loan contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Zhijun; Song, Byron Y.; Tian, Zhimin
This paper investigates whether the reputation of non-CEO inside director matters in bank loan contracting. We posit that reputable inside directors (RIDs) can improve the quality of borrowers' financial reporting and reduce agency risk in loan contracting. Based on a regression analysis of 5104 loan facilities during 1999-2007, we find that borrowers with RIDs enjoy lower loan interest rates and fewer restrictive covenants, and are less likely to have loans secured by collateral, than borrowers without RIDs. Our empirical results also show that RIDs help to obtain favorable loan terms mainly through alleviating ex-ante information asymmetry between borrowers and lenders. Further categorizing RIDs into CFO directors and other inside directors, we find that the effects of RIDs on loan spread and collateral requirements are significant for both CFO directors and other inside directors, while other inside directors have a more significant impact on financial covenants than CFO directors. Our findings are robust to controlling for RID characteristics and independent director reputation, and addressing the endogeneity concerns of RIDs, as well as the joint determination of various loan contracting terms. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Zhijun; Song, Byron Y.; Tian, Zhimin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Riding the swaption curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duyvesteyn, Johan; de Zwart, Gerben
We conduct an empirical analysis of the term structure in the volatility risk premium in the fixed income market by constructing long-short combinations of two at-the-money straddles for the four major swaption markets (USD, JPY, EUR and GBP). Our findings are consistent with a concave, upward-sloping maturity structure for all markets, with the largest negative premium for the shortest term maturity. The fact that both delta-vega and delta-gamma neutral straddle combinations earn positive returns that seem uncorrelated suggests that the term structure is affected by both jump risk and volatility risk. The results seem robust for macroeconomic announcements and the specific model choice to estimate the risk exposures for hedging. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duyvesteyn, Johan; de Zwart, Gerben</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity-adjusted Intraday Value at Risk modeling and risk management: An application to data from Deutsche Borse</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dionne, Georges; Pacurar, Maria; Zhou, Xiaozhou
This paper develops a high-frequency risk measure: the Liquidity-adjusted Intraday Value at Risk (LIVaR). Our objective is to explicitly consider the endogenous liquidity dimension associated with order size. By reconstructing the open Limit Order Book of Deutsche Borse, changes in the tick-by-tick (ex-ante) frictionless return and actual return are modeled jointly. The risk related to the ex-ante liquidity premium is then quantified. Our model can be used to identify the impact of ex-ante liquidity risk on total risk, and to provide an estimation of the VaR for the actual return at a point in time. In our sample, liquidity risk can account for up to 32% of total risk depending on order size. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dionne, Georges; Pacurar, Maria; Zhou, Xiaozhou</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pre-auction short positions and impacts on primary dealers' bidding behavior in US Treasury auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tchuindjo, Leonard
We model the uniform-price US Treasury security auction as a static symmetric game with incomplete information in which each player is a primary dealer who submits a demand schedule given two independent sources of private information: her/his pre-auction short position of the auctioned security and her/his valuation of this security. Under the assumptions of constant marginal value and additive separability of the demand schedule, we obtain closed-form solutions for the dealer's optimal demand schedule, and we find that her/his pre-auction short position impacts her/his bidding behavior in three ways. First, the primary dealer's demand for the auctioned security increases with her/his pre-auction short position. Second, the primary dealer's differential bid shading decreases with her/his pre-auction short position. Third, primary dealers with higher pre-auction short positions assign lower values to the auctioned security. Based on our findings, we propose policy recommendations that would allow the US Treasury to increase taxpayers' revenue. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tchuindjo, Leonard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamical macroprudential stress testing using network theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy-Carciente, Sary; Kenett, Dror Y.; Avakian, Adam; Stanley, H. Eugene; Havlin, Shlomo
The increasing frequency and scope of financial crises have made global financial stability one of the major concerns of economic policy and decision makers. This has led to the understanding that financial and banking supervision has to bethought of as a systemic task, focusing on the interdependent relations among the institutions. Using network theory, we develop a dynamic model that uses a bipartite network of banks and their assets to analyze the system's sensitivity to external shocks in individual asset classes and to evaluate the presence of features underlying the system that could lead to contagion. As a case study, we apply the model to stress test the Venezuelan banking system from 1998 to 2013. The introduced model was able to capture monthly changes in the structure of the system and the sensitivity of bank portfolios to different external shock scenarios and to identify systemic vulnerabilities and their time evolution. The model provides new tools for policy makers and supervision agencies to use for macroprudential dynamical stress testing. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Levy-Carciente, Sary; Kenett, Dror Y.; Avakian, Adam; Stanley, H. Eugene; Havlin, Shlomo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>European financial market dependence: An industry analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Wang, Yaw-Huei
This paper uses a copula model to investigate the degree and determinants of European market dependence across 10 industries in 12 Euro zone and 8 non-Euro zone stock markets during the period 1992-2011. Most of the industries in Euro countries show a dependence increase with the Euro-area after the introduction of the Euro. The effects are strongest in countries with larger market capitalization and in the Financials, Industrials, Consumer Goods, Utilities, Technology and Telecommunications industries. Overall, the export intensity, interest rate sensitivity and competitiveness of an industry and the financial development and economic openness of a country are the most important determinants of changes in equity market dependence. The period around the Lehman collapse also shows higher equity market dependence between European countries, while the lower dependence increase during the period of the recent European sovereign debt crisis suggests that country-specific factors may matter more than before. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Wang, Yaw-Huei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On luck versus skill when performance benchmarks are style-consistent</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agyei-Ampomah, Sam; Clare, Andrew; Mason, Andrew; Thomas, Stephen
We firmly believe that style-appropriate, investible benchmarks not only provide a more parsimonious way of describing manager performance, but also better aligns performance evaluation with the real world performance targets of fund managers'. It is against such benchmarks that managers should be judged. With this principle foremost in our approach, we use style-consistent benchmarks to determine whether any observed alpha produced by a sample of U.S. equity funds is due to skill or to luck. We find that different segments of the market, ranging from large-cap growth to small-cap value, exhibit different levels of skill and luck. Our results also show that the use of standard multi-factor models underestimates managerial ability and overstates the proportion of funds whose abnormal performance can be attributed to chance rather than to skill, when compared against the use of style-consistent practitioner benchmarks. We also find that a single factor performance evaluation model that uses Russell Style indices consistent with the style orientation of a fund and market practice provides a parsimonious way of accounting for fund performance. Finally, our findings should be of particular relevance in mutual fund markets where the risk factors commonly used in the academic literature to evaluate manager performance - SMB, B/M, MOM and others - are not readily available. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agyei-Ampomah, Sam; Clare, Andrew; Mason, Andrew; Thomas, Stephen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ex ante CEO severance pay and risk-taking in the financial services sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Kareen; Jha, Ranjini; Pacharn, Parunchana
We examine 533 CEO severance contracts for financial services firms from 1997 to 2007 and find that ex ante severance pay is positively associated with risk-taking after controlling for the incentive effects provided by equity-based compensation. We report a positive causal relation between the amount of severance pay and risk-taldng using popular market-based risk measures as well as the distance-to-default and the Z-score. We also find that severance pay encourages excessive risk-taking using metrics such as tail risk and asset quality. Our results are consistent with the risk-shifting argument and provide support for recent reforms on severance pay in the financial sector. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Kareen; Jha, Ranjini; Pacharn, Parunchana</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation targeting: Is IT to blame for banking system instability?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fazio, Dimas M.; Tabak, Benjamin M.; Cajueiro, Daniel O.
In light of the financial crisis, the practice of inflation targeting (IT) has been blamed for authorities' failure to respond to the increase in financial systemic risk and to the development of asset bubbles. However, utilizing a rich database containing nearly 5500 commercial banks from 70 countries (among which, 22 are IT) for the period 1998-2012, this paper argues that on average, inflation targeting national banking systems (i) are more stable; (ii) possess sounder systemically important banks; and (iii) are less distressed than (or at least as distressed as) other banks during periods of global liquidity shortages. Our results are robust to a series of tests, such as when we compare countries with the same legal origins or control for the delegation of bank supervision responsibility to bodies other than the central bank. Overall, we conclude that IT cannot be blamed for contributing to financial fragility. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fazio, Dimas M.; Tabak, Benjamin M.; Cajueiro, Daniel O.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Self-monitoring or reliance on media reporting: How do financial market participants process central bank news?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hayo, Bernd; Neuenkirch, Matthias
We study how financial market participants process news from four major central banks the Bank of England (BoE), the Bank of Japan (BoJ), the European Central Bank (ECB), and the Federal Reserve (Fed)-using a novel survey of 195 financial market participants from around the world. Our results indicate that, first, respondents rely more on media reports of central bank events than they do on self-monitoring. The only exceptions are interest rate decisions in the respondent's home region. In general, the Fed is watched most closely, followed by the ECB, the BoJ, and the BoE. Second, ordered probit estimations reveal that the perceived reliability of media coverage is negatively associated with degree of self-monitoring and positively related to the probability of using media reports, particularly in the case of asset managers. The perceived importance of central bank events is positively related to the degree of self-monitoring in the case of traders. Finally, portfolio managers tend to self-monitor their home central bank significantly more often than other central banks. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hayo, Bernd; Neuenkirch, Matthias</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can implied volatility predict returns on the currency carry trade?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Egbers, Tom; Swinkels, Laurens
Currency carry strategies have long positions in currencies with a high interest rate and short positions in currencies with a low interest rate. Currency carry strategies have generated about 5.4% return per annum (Sharpe ratio: 0.57) over the period December 1996 to May 2014. However, during the recent financial crisis, the carry strategy suffered losses of up to 20% on invested capital. We investigate whether investors could have used the implied option volatility index on the US equity market (the VIX) or the option implied volatility index from G7 currencies (the VXY) to time the currency carry trade. We examine a large set of timing strategies and find that for some specific settings excess returns can be as large as 2.5% per annum. However, when we take into account that we investigated many trading strategies, these excess returns turn out not to be statistically significant. Hence, our findings cast doubt on implied volatility as a stand-alone timing indicator for currency carry trading in real-life portfolio decisions. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Egbers, Tom; Swinkels, Laurens</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting contagion in a multivariate time series system: An application to sovereign bond markets in Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blatt, Dominik; Candelon, Bertrand; Manner, Hans
This paper proposes an original three-part sequential testing procedure (STP) with which to test for contagion using a multivariate model. First, conditional on breaks in the conditional mean, the procedure identifies distinct structural breaks in the volatility of a given set of countries. A further structural break test applied to the correlation matrix identifies and then dates the potential contagion mechanisms. As a third element, the STP tests for the distinctiveness of the break dates previously found. As a result of using multi-dimensional data, the STP has high testing power and is able to locate the dates of contagion more precisely. The application to European long-term interest rates shows that immediate contagion from Greece does not take place, but the dynamic spillovers are shown to increase after controlling for breaks in the different model parameters. For other countries we find evidence of both contagion and flight-to-quality mechanisms. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blatt, Dominik; Candelon, Bertrand; Manner, Hans</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Yes, one-day international cricket 'in-play' trading strategies can be profitable!</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Norton, Hugh; Gray, Steve; Faff, Robert
In this study, we employ a Monte Carlo simulation technique for estimating the conditional probability of victory at any stage in the first or second innings of a one-day international (ODI) cricket match. This model is then used to test market efficiency in the Betfair 'in-play' market for large sample of ODI matches. We find strong evidence of overreaction in the first innings. A trading strategy of betting on the batting team after the fall of a wicket produces a significant profit of 20%. We also find some evidence of underreaction in the second innings although it is less economically and statistically significant than the first innings overreaction. We also implement trades when the discrepancy between the probability of victory implied by current market odds differs substantially from the odds estimated by our Monte Carlo simulation model. We document a number of trading strategies that yield large statistically significant positive returns in both the first and second innings. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Norton, Hugh; Gray, Steve; Faff, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long memory and regime switching: A simulation study on the Markov regime-switching ARFIMA model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shi, Yanlin; Ho, Kin-Yip
Recent research argues that if the cause of confusion between long memory and regime switching were properly controlled for, they could be effectively distinguished. Motivated by this idea, our study aims to distinguish between them of financial series. We firstly model long memory and regime switching via the Autoregressive Fractionally Integrated Moving Average (ARFIMA) and Markov Regime-Switching (MRS) models, respectively. Their finite-sample properties and the confusion are investigated via simulations. To control for the cause of this confusion, we propose the MRS-ARFIMA model. A Monte Carlo study shows that this framework can effectively distinguish between the pure ARFIMA and pure MRS processes. Furthermore, MRS-ARFIMA outperforms the ordinary ARFIMA model for data simulated from the MRS-ARFIMA process. Finally, empirical studies of hourly and five-minute Garman-Klass and realized volatility of the FTSE index is conducted to demonstrate the advantages and usefulness of the proposed MRS-ARFIMA framework compared with the ARFIMA and MRS models in practice. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shi, Yanlin; Ho, Kin-Yip</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Linear programming-based estimators in nonnegative autoregression</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Preve, Daniel
This note studies robust estimation of the autoregressive (AR) parameter in a nonlinear, nonnegative AR model driven by nonnegative errors. It is shown that a linear programming estimator (LPE), considered by Nielsen and Shephard (2003) among others, remains consistent under severe model misspecification. Consequently, the LPE can be used to test for, and seek sources of, misspecification when a pure autoregression cannot satisfactorily describe the data generating process, and to isolate certain trend, seasonal or cyclical components. Simple and quite general conditions under which the LPE is strongly consistent in the presence of serially dependent, non-identically distributed or otherwise misspecified errors are given, and a brief review of the literature on LP-based estimators in nonnegative autoregression is presented. Finite-sample properties of the LPE are investigated in an extensive simulation study covering a wide range of model misspecifications. A small scale empirical study, employing a volatility proxy to model and forecast latent daily return volatility of three major stock market indexes, illustrates the potential usefulness of the LPE. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Preve, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factor models for binary financial data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perez, M. Fabricio; Shkilko, Andriy; Sokolov, Konstantin
Researchers are often interested in modeling binary decisions made by firms (e.g., the yes or no decisions to split the shares, initiate a dividend, or acquire another firm) as functions of economy-wide variables (common factors). Although factor models for continuous dependent variables are used widely, the toolkit of a financial researcher does not contain a generally accepted methodology that allows estimating factor models for binary dependent variables. In this paper, we study such a methodology. Using simulations, we identify data characteristics that allow for reliable estimates of factor parameters and conclude that the methodology is appropriate for the panel datasets of the type often used in finance. As an illustration, we use the methodology to address a currently debated issue of common factors in firms' decisions to split their shares. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Perez, M. Fabricio; Shkilko, Andriy; Sokolov, Konstantin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transmission channels of systemic risk and contagion in the European financial network</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paltalidis, Nikos; Gounopoulos, Dimitrios; Kizys, Renatas; Koutelidakis, Yiannis
We investigate systemic risk and how financial contagion propagates within the euro area banking system by employing the Maximum Entropy method. The study captures multiple snapshots of a dynamic financial network and uses counterfactual simulations to propagate shocks emerging from three sources of systemic risk: interbank, asset price, and sovereign credit risk markets. As conditions deteriorate, these channels trigger severe direct and indirect losses and cascades of defaults, whilst the dominance of the sovereign credit risk channel amplifies, as the primary source of financial contagion in the banking network. Systemic risk within the northern euro area banking system is less apparent, while the southern euro area banking system is more prone and susceptible to bank failures provoked by financial contagion. By modelling the contagion path the results demonstrate that the euro area banking system insists to be markedly vulnerable and conducive to systemic risks. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Paltalidis, Nikos; Gounopoulos, Dimitrios; Kizys, Renatas; Koutelidakis, Yiannis</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Guest editors' introduction: Special issue of Journal of Banking and Finance on recent developments in financial econometrics and applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayan, Paresh Kumar; Nielsen, Morten Orregaard
nan</description><author>Narayan, Paresh Kumar; Nielsen, Morten Orregaard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does labour regulation affect technical and allocative efficiency? Evidence from the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mamatzakis, Emmanuel; Tsionas, Mike G.; Kumbhakar, Subal C.; Koutsomanoli-Filippaki, Anastasia
In light of the ongoing restructuring of the European banking industry and the challenging macroeconomic environment, banks have increased their efforts to reduce operating costs. Yet, the institutional features that affect banks' ability to adjust costs and in particular personnel expenses, which comprise a significant part of banks' non-interest cost structure, have not been adequately studied. This paper investigates the effect of labour market institutions and regulations on bank performance in 15 European countries over the period 2005-2010, using the Fraser index for labour regulation and its disaggregated sub-components. We propose a novel methodology to measure performance, based on the seminal work of Kumbhakar and Tsionas (2005), which allows the estimation of technical and allocative efficiency and the examination of the effect of labour market regulations in a single stage. Results indicate the existence of a positive relationship between the liberalisation of EU labour markets and allocative efficiency, while the effect on technical efficiency appears to be negative, although not statistically significant. When looking at the disaggregated components of the labour index, we further confirm that different forces are at play. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mamatzakis, Emmanuel; Tsionas, Mike G.; Kumbhakar, Subal C.; Koutsomanoli-Filippaki, Anastasia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the price impact of trades in a high-frequency microstructure model with jumps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jondeau, Eric; Lahaye, Jerome; Rockinger, Michael
We estimate a general microstructure model of the transitory and permanent impact of order flow on stock prices. Jumps are detected in both the transaction price (observation equation) and fundamental value (state equation). The model's parameters and variances are updated in real time. Prices can be altered by both the size and direction of trades, and the effects of buy-initiated and sell-initiated trades are different. We estimate this model using tick-by-tick data for 12 large-capitalization stocks traded on the Euronext-Paris Bourse. We find that, at tick frequency, the overnight return, the intraday jumps, and the continuous innovations represent approximately 7%, 8.5%, and 36.7% of the total variation of stock returns. The microstructure model explains on average 47.7% of the total variation. Once jumps are filtered and parameters are estimated in real time, we also find that the price impact of trades is symmetric on average. However, the price of highly liquid stocks with a large proportion of sell-initiated orders tends to be more sensitive to buy trades, whereas the price of less liquid stocks with a large proportion of buy-initiated orders tends to be more sensitive to sell trades. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jondeau, Eric; Lahaye, Jerome; Rockinger, Michael</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New methodology for constructing real estate price indices applied to the Singapore residential market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Liang; Phillips, Peter C. B.; Yu, Jun
This paper develops a new methodology for constructing a real estate price index that utilizes all transaction price information, encompassing both single-sales and repeat-sales. The method is less susceptible to specification error than standard hedonic methods and is not subject to the sample selection bias involved in indexes that rely only on repeat sales. The methodology employs a model design that uses a sale pairing process based on the individual building level, rather than the individual house level as is used in the repeat-sales method. The approach extends ideas from repeat-sales methodology in a way that accommodates much wider datasets. In an empirical analysis of the methodology, we fit the model to the private residential property market in Singapore between Q1 1995 and Q2 2014, covering several periods of major price fluctuation and changes in government macroprudential policy. The index is found to perform much better in out-of-sample prediction exercises than either the S&amp;P/Case-Shiller index or the index based on standard hedonic methods. In a further empirical application, the recursive dating method of Phillips et al. (2015a,b) is used to detect explosive behavior in the Singapore real estate market. Explosive behavior in the new index is found to arise two quarters earlier than in the other indices. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Liang; Phillips, Peter C. B.; Yu, Jun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who lends to riskier and lower-profitability firms? Evidence from the syndicated loan market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iosifidi, Maria; Kokas, Sotirios
This paper exploits a unique data set on bank-firm relationships based on syndicated loan deals to examine the effect of banks' credit risk and capital on firms' risk and performance. Our data set is a multilevel cross-section, which essentially allows controlling for all bank and firm characteristics through respective fixed effects, thus avoiding concerns regarding omitted variables. We find that banks with higher credit risk are associated with more risky firms, with lower profitability and market value. In turn, we find that banks with higher risk-weighted capital ratios lend to riskier firms with less market value. Our results are indicative of a strong adverse selection mechanism and highlight the need to monitor the risky banks more closely, especially as we consider large and influential syndicated loan deals. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Iosifidi, Maria; Kokas, Sotirios</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multi-factor volatility and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhongzhi; Zhu, Jie; Zhu, Xiaoneng
In light of inconclusive evidence on the relation between market volatility and stock returns, this paper proposes a multi-factor volatility model and examines its impact on cross-sectional pricing. We also evaluate the out-of-sample performance and economic significance of multi-factor volatility. We find that conditional variances of the size and value dynamic factor earn significant and positive variance risk premia. In addition, multi-factor volatility can significantly improve the out-of-sample return predictability with a positive economic gain in asset allocation. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Zhongzhi; Zhu, Jie; Zhu, Xiaoneng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of ratings-contingent regulation on international bank lending behavior: Evidence from the Basel 2 Accord</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, Iftekhar; Kim, Suk-Joong; Wu, Eliza
We investigate the effects of credit ratings-contingent financial regulation on foreign bank lending behavior. We examine the sensitivity of international bank flows to debtor countries' sovereign credit rating changes before and after the implementation of the Basel 2 risk-based capital regulatory rules. We study the quarterly bilateral flows from G-10 creditor banking systems to 77 recipient countries over the period Q4:1999 to Q2:2013. We find direct evidence that sovereign credit re-ratings that lead to changes in risk-weights for capital adequacy requirements have become more significant since the implementation of Basel 2 rules for assessing banks' credit risk under the standardized approach. This evidence is consistent with global banks acting via their international lending decisions to minimize required capital charges associated with the use of ratings-contingent regulation. We find no evidence to suggest that banking regulation induced foreign lending has heightened the perceived sovereign credit risks of recipient countries. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasan, Iftekhar; Kim, Suk-Joong; Wu, Eliza</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which continuous-time model is most appropriate for exchange rates?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erdemlioglu, Deniz; Laurent, Sebastien; Neely, Christopher J.
This paper evaluates the most appropriate ways to model diffusion and jump features of high-frequency exchange rates in the presence of intraday periodicity in volatility. We show that periodic volatility distorts the size and power of conventional tests of Brownian motion, jumps and (in)finite activity. We propose a correction for periodicity that restores the properties of the test statistics. Empirically, the most plausible model for 1-min exchange rate data features Brownian motion and both finite activity and infinite activity jumps. Test rejection rates vary over time, however, indicating time variation in the data generating process. We discuss the implications of results for market microstructure and currency option pricing. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Erdemlioglu, Deniz; Laurent, Sebastien; Neely, Christopher J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank risk, financial stability, and the role of regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos
nan</description><author>Delis, Manthos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Central bank independence, financial supervision structure and bank soundness: An empirical analysis around the crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doumpos, Michael; Gaganis, Chrysovalantis; Pasiouras, Fotios
Over the last fifteen years, many countries introduced reforms into the supervisory architecture of their financial sector. However, there is no evidence on whether specific supervisory arrangements were more successful than others during the crisis. Empirical evidence on the topic is in general scarce and there are reasonable theoretical arguments for and against alternative approaches. Similarly, while the effect of central bank independence on price stability has attracted a lot of attention, our knowledge with regards to its effect on bank soundness remains limited. Using a large sample of commercial banks operating in various countries over the period 2000-2011, this paper investigates whether and how bank soundness is influenced by central bank independence, central bank involvement in prudential regulation, and supervisory unification. We find that central bank independence exercises a positive impact on bank soundness, which in the case of smaller banks is enhanced during the crisis. Supervisory unification and the central bank involvement appear to mitigate the adverse effects of the crisis. The power of the supervisory authorities and bank size also appear to be conditional factors. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doumpos, Michael; Gaganis, Chrysovalantis; Pasiouras, Fotios</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On comparing zero-alpha tests across multifactor asset pricing models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Moor, Lieven; Dhaene, Geert; Sercu, Piet
Evaluating competing multifactor asset pricing models involves comparing the statistical significance of their mean pricing errors (alphas). Unfortunately, this comparison favors imprecisely estimated models because p-values tend to be higher in more noisy models. To avoid false impressions of relative success at tests for zero mean pricing errors, we develop a notion of comparative p-values and suggest comparing these instead of the raw p-values. This comparison gives more precisely estimated models a fairer chance or, equivalently, quantifies how much easier it is for imprecisely estimated models, by comparison, to pass the test. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>De Moor, Lieven; Dhaene, Geert; Sercu, Piet</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default and prepayment modelling in participating mortgages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Varli, Yusuf; Yildirim, Yildiray
Since the 2008 financial crisis, the mortgage market has been renovating its tools and instruments in order to avoid a new crisis. One such innovative instrument is the participating mortgage, in which the lender gains part of the net operating income and/or future appreciation. In this paper, we establish a financing model for participating mortgages, incorporating early termination options such as default and two prepayment clauses, defeasance and prepayment penalty. Later, we illustrate a detailed sensitivity analysis of the model. The values of early termination options depend on the choice of parameters in the model, as well as the term structure of short term rates. Finally, we show that a participation rate of 11.24% results in zero mortgage interest rate using the parameters in our simulation. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Varli, Yusuf; Yildirim, Yildiray</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of assets-in-place on corporate financing and investment decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clausen, Saskia; Flor, Christian Riis
In a dynamic setting with asymmetric information we consider firms' debt-equity choice and investment timing. We extend recent research by adding an abandonment option and assets-in-place and we show that these extensions make debt more attractive. This implies, e.g., that mature firms (with larger assets in-place) mainly use debt financing, whereas young high-growth firms (without assets-in-place) frequently use equity financing and signal their type by early investment. Simulation analyses confirm this and our model is thus able to explain empirical patterns which contradict the static pecking order theory. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Clausen, Saskia; Flor, Christian Riis</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are classical option pricing models consistent with observed option second-order moments? Evidence from high-frequency data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Audrino, Francesco; Fengler, Matthias R.
As a means of validating an option pricing model, we compare the ex-post intra-day realized variance of options with the realized variance of the associated underlying asset that would be implied using assumptions as in the Black and Scholes (BS) model, the Heston, and the Bates model. Based on data for the S&amp;P 500 index, we find that the BS model is strongly directionally biased due to the presence of stochastic volatility. The Heston model reduces the mismatch in realized variance between the two markets, but deviations are still significant. With the exception of short-dated options, we achieve best approximations after controlling for the presence of jumps in the underlying dynamics. Finally, we provide evidence that, although heavily biased, the realized variance based on the BS model contains relevant predictive information that can be exploited when option high-frequency data is not available. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Audrino, Francesco; Fengler, Matthias R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Costs of capital and public issuance choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lamoureux, Christopher G.; Nejadmalayeri, Ali
The choices of firms raising external capital conform to standard static choice theory in that the higher the (relative) cost of an alternative-both at the overall market level and at the firm level the less attractive is that alternative. Price elasticities of demand are smaller for more profitable and tangible firms, and larger for larger and more liquid firms. Firm fixed effects account for one-third of the explained choice variation of multiple issuers. Short-term debt is more attractive when the yield curve is steeply sloped, but the demand for equity is inelastic with respect to the market price-earnings multiple. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lamoureux, Christopher G.; Nejadmalayeri, Ali</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Repurchase behavior of individual investors, sophistication and regret</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Magron, Camille; Merli, Maxime
This study uses a database of over 6 million trades from a large European brokerage house to investigate the stock repurchase behavior of individual investors from 1999 to 2006. Running survival analysis techniques, we show at an individual level that the duration between a sale and a repurchase is shorter when the investor has had a positive experience with the stock or when the stock has lost value since being sold. More sophisticated investors are significantly less prone to this behavior. Our findings emphasize the importance of regret in financial decisions. Public and private information, tax considerations and contrarian strategy do not drive repurchase behavior. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Magron, Camille; Merli, Maxime</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How are market preferences shaped? The case of sovereign debt of stressed euro-area countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mamatzakis, Emmanuel; Tsionas, Mike G.
This paper reveals the underlying market preferences for sovereign debt of distressed euro area countries. We employ a generalised flexible market loss, as it nests both the linear and the non-linear form, as a function of the 'basis', the difference between sovereign bond spread and the Credit Default Swap. Our evidence shows that market preferences lean towards pessimism for some countries, in particular Greece. Those preferences do not remain stable over time as they shift further towards pessimism post the Greek bail out in spring 2010. As part of sensitivity analysis we apply a multivariate loss function to account for contagion effects in forming market preferences among different sovereign bonds. We also examine the impact of specific financial and fiscal governance factors on market preferences. Our results suggest that the market closely monitor fiscal fundamentals so as to shape preferences. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mamatzakis, Emmanuel; Tsionas, Mike G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of conventional and unconventional monetary policy on investor sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lutz, Chandler
This paper examines the relationship between monetary policy and investor sentiment across conventional and unconventional monetary policy regimes. During conventional times, we find that a surprise decrease in the fed funds rate leads to a large increase in investor sentiment. Similarly, when the fed funds rate is at its zero lower bound, research results indicate that expansionary unconventional monetary policy shocks also have a large and positive impact on investor mood. Together, our findings highlight the importance of both conventional and unconventional monetary policy in the determination of investor sentiment. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lutz, Chandler</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A semiparametric conditional capital asset pricing model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Zongwu; Ren, Yu; Yang, Bingduo
This paper proposes using a functional coefficient regression technique to estimate time-varying betas and alpha in the conditional capital asset pricing model (CAPM). Functional coefficient representation relaxes the strict assumptions regarding the structure of betas and alpha by combining the predictors into an index. Appropriate index variables are selected by applying the smoothly clipped absolute deviation penalty. In such a way, estimation and variable selection can be done simultaneously. Based on the empirical studies, the proposed model performs better than the alternatives in explaining asset returns and we find no strong evidence to reject the conditional CAPM. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cai, Zongwu; Ren, Yu; Yang, Bingduo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Futures hedging with Markov switching vector error correction FIEGARCH and FIAPARCH</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dark, Jonathan
Markov switching vector error correction asymmetric long memory volatility models with fat tailed innovations are proposed. Bivariate two state versions of the models are applied to a futures hedge of the S&amp;P500. Regime switches occur between high and low cost of carry states via changes in the error correction term or basis. Regime identification is therefore dominated by switches in the mean, not volatility. Relative to a number of alternatives, the proposed models provide superior out of sample forecasts of the covariance matrix particularly for horizons greater than 10 days ahead. When hedging, Markov switching with long memory improves the tail risk of hedged returns beyond 10 day horizons, however there is mixed support for models with volatility asymmetries. These findings have important implications for the development of multivariate models and other applications including portfolio management, spread option pricing and arbitrage. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dark, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does one size fit all? Determinants of insurer capital structure around the globe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altuntas, Muhammed; Berry-Stoelzle, Thomas R.; Wende, Sabine
As financial markets become more global, the question arises whether any country specific considerations are still relevant for insurance companies' capital structure. This research examines this question with firm-level data across a broad range of countries including those in developing markets. What we find is that the optimal capital structure of insurance companies is not homogeneous across countries. We find that country-level factors explain a substantial fraction of the cross-sectional variation in insurance companies' capitalization levels. Our results add to the current policy discussion on global regulatory capital requirements. If insurer capital structure is not homogeneous across countries, a global capital standard if desired should take differences in the institutional environments across countries into account to avoid market distortions. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Altuntas, Muhammed; Berry-Stoelzle, Thomas R.; Wende, Sabine</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option valuation with observable volatility and jump dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Feunou, Bruno; Jeon, Yoontae
Under very general conditions, the total quadratic variation of a jump-diffusion process can be decomposed into diffusive volatility and squared jump variation. We use this result to develop a new option valuation model in which the underlying asset price exhibits volatility and jump intensity dynamics. The volatility and jump intensity dynamics in the model are directly driven by model-free empirical measures of diffusive volatility and jump variation. Because the empirical measures are observed in discrete intervals, our option valuation model is cast in discrete time, allowing for straightforward filtering and estimation of the model. Our model belongs to the affine class enabling us to derive the conditional characteristic function so that option values can be computed rapidly without simulation. When estimated on S&amp;P500 index options and returns the new model performs well compared with standard benchmarks. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Feunou, Bruno; Jeon, Yoontae</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Connecting the dots: Econometric methods for uncovering networks with an application to the Australian financial institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anufriev, Mikhail; Panchenko, Valentyn
This paper connects variance-covariance estimation methods, Gaussian graphical models, and the growing literature on economic and financial networks. We construct the network using the concept of partial correlations which captures direct linear dependence between any two entities, conditional on dependence between all other entities. We relate the centrality measures of this network to shock propagation. The methodology is applied to construct the perceived network of publicly traded Australian banks and their connections to domestic economic sectors and international markets. We find strong links between the big four Australian banks, real estate and other sectors of the economy, and determine which entities play a central role in transmitting and absorbing the shocks. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anufriev, Mikhail; Panchenko, Valentyn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Panzar-Rosse revenue test and market power in banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shaffer, Sherrill; Spierdijk, Laura
The Panzar-Rosse H statistic is a commonly used measure of market power in banking. It is widely believed that H &gt; 0 is inconsistent with significant market power. This study rigorously disproves that perception. Instead, the possibility of H &gt; 0 under conditions of substantial market power turns out robust to the timing of banks' actions, relative costs, choice of strategic variable, degree of product differentiation, strategy (static or dynamic), and degree of heterogeneity in banks' conduct (collusive versus fringe), and hence may be common in practice. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shaffer, Sherrill; Spierdijk, Laura</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A utility- and CPT-based comparison of life insurance contracts with guarantees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, An; Hentschel, Felix; Klein, Jakob K.
Some recent literature studies whether contracts including financial guarantees can be preferred by a utility-maximizing investor. The main result for contracts exposed solely to financial risk (e.g. Doskeland and Nordahl, 2008; Dichtl and Drobetz, 2011) is that expected utility theory (EUT) fails to interpret demand for guarantees, while cumulative prospect theory (CPT) is able to support the demand. While the development of the financial market has a significant impact on the portfolio choice, some other non-financial risk might play an important role too. In the present paper, we take life insurance products as an example, where the long term nature of these contracts places a special emphasis on the uncertain lifetime of the investor. We incorporate the mortality risk and investigate its effect on the attractiveness of contracts offering minimum interest rate guarantees to EUT- and CPT-investors. For this purpose, we introduce two approaches for the consideration of multiple risk sources within CPT. We illustrate the theoretical framework with numerous simulations and our numerical results show that a long-term risk-averse EUT-investor prefers products with guarantees. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, An; Hentschel, Felix; Klein, Jakob K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposit interest rate ceilings as credit supply shifters: Bank level evidence on the effects of Regulation Q</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koch, Christoffer
How did deposit interest rate ceilings, an important feature of the U.S. regulatory regime until the mid-1980s, affect individual banks' lending and the transmission of monetary policy to credit? I estimate the effect of deposit rate ceilings inscribed in Regulation Q on commercial banks' credit growth using a historical bank level data set starting in 1959. Banks' credit growth contracted sharply when legally fixed deposit rate ceilings were binding. Interaction terms with monetary policy suggest that the policy impact on bank level credit growth was non-linear and significantly larger when rate ceilings were in place. Bank size and capitalization mitigate these effects. At the bank level, short-term interest rates exceeding the legally fixed deposit rate ceilings identify policy induced credit supply shifts that disappeared with deposit rate deregulation and thus weakened the bank lending channel substantially since the early 1980s. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Koch, Christoffer</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan Loss Provisioning Rules, Procyclicality, and Financial Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agenor, Pierre-Richard; Zilberman, Roy
Interactions between loan-loss provisioning regimes and business cycle fluctuations are studied in a dynamic stochastic general equilibrium model with credit market imperfections. With a specific provisioning system, provisions are triggered by past due payments. With a dynamic system, both past due payments and expected losses over the whole business cycle are accounted for, and provisions are smoothed over the cycle. Numerical experiments with a parameterized version of the model show that a dynamic provisioning regime can be highly effective in mitigating procyclicality of the financial system. The results also indicate that the combination of a credit gap-augmented Taylor rule and a dynamic provisioning system with full smoothing may be the most effective way to mitigate real and financial volatility associated with financial shocks. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agenor, Pierre-Richard; Zilberman, Roy</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing price growth and the cost of equity capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ding, Xiaoya; Ni, Yang; Rahman, Abdul; Saadi, Samir
Building on recent research linking changes in housing prices to investors' degree of risk aversion, we posit that there is a negative relation between growth in housing prices and a firm's cost of equity capital. Consistent with our hypothesis, we find that firms located in states with positive growth rates in housing prices exhibit lower costs of equity capital. We also observe that the effect of changes in housing prices is mainly driven by smaller firms. This housing effect is not only statistically significant but also economically important. Our results hold across various measures of growth rates in housing prices and are robust to controlling for potential biases due to measurement errors in estimating the implied cost of equity capital. This study is the first to establish an association between growth rates in housing prices and firms' cost of equity capital. It also contributes to the emerging literature on the economic importance of a firm's geographic location. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ding, Xiaoya; Ni, Yang; Rahman, Abdul; Saadi, Samir</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-term options: Clienteles, market segmentation, and event trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chatrath, Arjun; Christie-David, Rohan A.; Miao, Hong; Ramchander, Sanjay
We compare clientele and information share in weekly- (Weeklys) and monthly-expiring options (Monthlys) on the S&amp;P 500 index. Striking dissimilarities between the two instruments are found, most apparent being the much smaller trade size and substantially higher implied volatility in Weeklys, consistent with both speculation and event trading. Additionally, the price discovery contribution of Weeklys, albeit modest when compared to the underlying index itself, is substantially larger than that of Monthlys. The cumulative evidence points to an increasingly segmented options market. Thus, studies employing only standard options to investigate price discovery will likely underestimate the informational role of options. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chatrath, Arjun; Christie-David, Rohan A.; Miao, Hong; Ramchander, Sanjay</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing bank competition for consumer loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolt, Wilko; Humphrey, David
Based on frontier analysis, we derive inferences of bank consumer loan competition from estimating a revenue-cost 'competition efficiency' (CE) frontier. The competitiveness of the $400 billion U.S. bank consumer loan market is then assessed by comparing results from our frontier CE measure with other competition measures, such as HHI, Lerner Index, and H-Statistic. These measures are weakly related to one another and only half of them identify banks with the highest loan price as also being the least competitive. This is the opposite of what is expected. Using the frontier CE measure, the most and least competitive banks are not located in the most populous states and the largest banks are underrepresented. Overall, the HHI should not be used to indicate competition. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bolt, Wilko; Humphrey, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The perennial challenge to counter Too-Big-to-Fail in banking: Empirical evidence from the new international regulation dealing with Global Systemically Important Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moenninghoff, Sebastian C.; Ongena, Steven; Wieandt, Axel
This paper provides evidence on how the new international regulation on Global Systemically Important Banks (G-SIBS) impacts the market value of large banks. We analyze the stock price reactions for the 300 largest banks from 52 countries across 12 relevant regulatory announcement and designation events. We observe that the new regulation negatively affects the value of the newly regulated banks, yet that the official designation of banks as "globally systemically important" itself has a partly offsetting positive impact. A cross-sectional analysis of the valuation effects with respect to, for example, government ownership of banks supports the view that the positive reaction to these designations can be attributed to a Too-Big-to-Fail (TBTF) perception by investors. The fact that these valuation effects emerge from a regulation specifically designed to reduce the costs and risks of Too-Big-to-Fail demonstrates the inherently paradoxical nature of the new regulation. These results further suggest that even though the individual components of the regulation have been effective, revealing the identities of G-SIBs eliminated ambiguity about the presence of government guarantees, and thereby may have run counter to the regulators' intent to contain the effects of TBTF. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moenninghoff, Sebastian C.; Ongena, Steven; Wieandt, Axel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>As told by the supplier: Trade credit and the cross section of stock returns (vol 60, pg 296, 2015)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goto, Shingo; Xiao, Gang
nan</description><author>Goto, Shingo; Xiao, Gang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The strategic role of reinsurance in the United Kingdom's (UK) non-life insurance market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Upreti, Vineet; Adams, Mike
Using panel data for five main lines of insurance in the United Kingdom's (UK) non-life insurance market we demonstrate that by increasing the level of reinsurance, primary insurers increase their product market share at the expense of less reinsured rivals. We also observe that the influence of reinsurance and other financial variables on insurers' growth in product-market share differs across lines of insurance business. We conclude that reinsurance performs an important strategic function in insurance markets through its impact on product-market outcomes in competitive insurance markets. Additionally, we find that leverage is the most important factor affecting product-market share at the aggregate business level of the insurance firm. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Upreti, Vineet; Adams, Mike</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The liquidity premium in CDS transaction prices: Do frictions matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gehde-Trapp, Monika; Guenduez, Yalin; Nasev, Julia
Based on individual CDS transactions cleared by the Depository Trust &amp; Clearing Corporation, we show that illiquidity strongly affects credit default swap premiums. We identify the following effects: first, transaction direction affects prices, as buy (sell) orders lead to premium increases (decreases). Second, larger transactions have a higher price impact. This finding stands in stark contrast to corporate bond markets. Third, traders charge higher premiums as a price for liquidity provision, not as compensation for asymmetric information. Fourth, buy-side investors pay significantly higher prices than dealers for demanding liquidity. Finally, inventory risk seems to matter little in explaining liquidity premiums. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gehde-Trapp, Monika; Guenduez, Yalin; Nasev, Julia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trend definition or holding strategy: What determines the profitability of candlestick charting?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Tsung-Hsun; Chen, Yi-Chi; Hsu, Yu-Chin
We ask what determines the profitability of candlestick trading strategies. Is it the definition of trend and/or the holding strategy that one uses in candlestick charting analysis? To answer this, we systematically consider three definitions of trend and four holding strategies. Applying candlestick trading strategies to the DJIA component data, we find that regardless of which definition of trend is used, eight three-day reversal patterns with a Caginalp-Laurent holding strategy are profitable when we set the transaction cost at 0.5% and after we account for data-snooping bias, while the patterns with a Marsha ll-Young-Rose holding strategy are not profitable. For sensitivity analysis, we also find that our results are not qualitatively changed on a lower transaction cost of 0.1%, or when we conduct the subsample analyses based on three equal periods and three distinct market conditions. When considering a more volatile market, evidence in favor of candlestick trading strategies is strengthened. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lu, Tsung-Hsun; Chen, Yi-Chi; Hsu, Yu-Chin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling interest rate volatility: A Realized GARCH approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Shuairu; Hamori, Shigeyuki
We propose using a Realized GARCH (RGARCH) model to estimate the daily volatility of the short-term interest rate in the euro-yen market. The model better fits the data and provides more accurate volatility forecasts by extracting, additional information from realized measures. In addition, we propose using the ARMA-Realized GARCH (ARMA-RGARCH) model to capture the volatility clustering and the mean reversion effects of interest rate behavior. We find the ARMA-RGARCH model fits the data better than the simple RGARCH model does, but it does not provide superior volatility forecasts. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tian, Shuairu; Hamori, Shigeyuki</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>